<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 10:22:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Jerusalem U.S.-Israel Strategic Partnership Joint&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/the-jerusalem-u-s-israel-strategic-partnership-joint-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The leaders of the United States and Israel, President Biden and Prime Minister Lapid, met in Jerusalem on 14 July 2022, and adopted the following Joint Declaration on the US-Israel Strategic Partnership: The United States and Israel reaffirm the unbreakable bonds between our two countries and the enduring commitment of the United States to Israel’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The leaders of the United States and Israel, President Biden and Prime Minister Lapid, met in Jerusalem on 14 July 2022, and adopted the following Joint Declaration on the US-Israel Strategic Partnership:</p>



<p>The United States and Israel reaffirm the unbreakable bonds between our two countries and the enduring commitment of the United States to Israel’s security. Our countries further reaffirm that the strategic U.S.-Israel partnership is based on a bedrock of shared values, shared interests, and true friendship. Furthermore, the United States and Israel affirm that among the values the countries share is an unwavering commitment to democracy, the rule of law, and the calling of “Tikkun Olam,” repairing the world. The leaders express appreciation to former Prime Minister Bennett, who led the most diverse government in Israel’s history, and under whose leadership this extraordinary partnership has continued to grow stronger.</p>



<p>Consistent with the longstanding security relationship between the United States and Israel and the unshakeable U.S. commitment to Israel’s security, and especially to the maintenance of its qualitative military edge, the United States reiterates its steadfast commitment to preserve and strengthen Israel’s capability to deter its enemies and to defend itself by itself against any threat or combination of threats. The United States further reiterates that these commitments are bipartisan and sacrosanct, and that they are not only moral commitments, but also strategic commitments that are vitally important to the national security of the United States itself.</p>



<p>The United States stresses that integral to this pledge is the commitment never to allow Iran to acquire a nuclear weapon, and that it is prepared to use all elements of its national power to ensure that outcome. The United States further affirms the commitment to work together with other partners to confront Iran’s aggression and destabilizing activities, whether advanced directly or through proxies and terrorist organizations such as Hezbollah, Hamas, and Palestinian Islamic Jihad.</p>



<p>The United States and Israel note that nothing better reflects the steadfast and bipartisan support of the United States to Israel’s security than the unprecedented Memoranda of Understanding on security assistance signed by successive U.S. administrations over the last few decades, and that these arrangements demonstrate in word and deed that the United States considers Israel’s security essential to U.S. interests and an anchor of regional stability.</p>



<p>The United States strongly supports implementing the terms of the current historic $38 billion Memorandum of Understanding in full, which honors the United States’ enduring commitment to Israel’s security, as well as its conviction that a follow-on MOU should address emerging threats and new realities. In addition, the United States is committed to seeking additional missile defense assistance in excess of MOU levels, in exceptional circumstances such as the hostilities with Hamas over eleven days in May 2021. Israel appreciates the U.S. commitment to the MOU and for providing an additional $1 billion over MOU levels in supplemental missile defense funding following the 2021 conflict. Further, the countries express enthusiasm to move forward the U.S.-Israel defense partnership through cooperation in cutting-edge defense technologies such as high energy laser weapons systems to defend the skies of Israel and in the future those of other U.S. and Israel security partners.</p>



<p>Israel thanks the United States for its ongoing and extensive support for deepening and broadening the historic Abraham Accords. The countries affirm that Israel’s peace and normalization agreements with the United Arab Emirates, Bahrain, and Morocco constitute a critical addition to Israel’s strategic peace treaties with Egypt and Jordan, all of which are important to the future of the Middle East region and to the cause of regional security, prosperity, and peace. The countries note that the historic Negev Summit, initiated and hosted by Prime Minister Lapid, was a landmark event in joint U.S.-Israeli efforts to build a new regional framework that is changing the face of the Middle East.</p>



<p>The United States and Israel welcome in this regard the meeting held in Manama, Bahrain on June 27th, forming the Negev Forum on regional cooperation. The United States welcomes these developments and is committed to continue playing an active role, including in the context of President Biden’s upcoming visit to Saudi Arabia, in building a robust regional architecture; to deepen the ties between Israel and all of its regional partners; to advance Israel&#8217;s regional integration over time; and to expand the circle of peace to include ever more Arab and Muslim States.</p>



<p>The United States and Israel also welcome the opportunity to participate in a quadrilateral (hybrid) meeting, together with the leaders of India and the United Arab Emirates, in the context of the I2U2 initiative, bringing together these four countries to advance cooperation in economy and strategic infrastructure, and demonstrating the importance of this new partnership, first launched by their Foreign Ministers in October 2021.</p>



<p>The United States and Israel reiterate their concerns regarding the ongoing attacks against Ukraine, their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and affirmed the importance of continued humanitarian assistance to the people of Ukraine.</p>



<p>The United States and Israel affirm that they will continue to work together to combat all efforts to boycott or de-legitimize Israel, to deny its right to self-defense, or to unfairly single it out in any forum, including at the United Nations or the International Criminal Court. While fully&nbsp;respecting the right to freedom of expression, they firmly reject the BDS campaign. The two countries will use the tools at their disposal to fight every scourge and source of antisemitism and to respond whenever legitimate criticism crosses over into bigotry and hatred or attempts to undermine Israel’s rightful and legitimate place among the family of nations. In this context, they express their deep concern over the global surge in antisemitism and reassert their commitment to counter this ancient hatred in all of its manifestations. The United States is proud to stand with the Jewish and democratic State of Israel, and with its people, whose uncommon courage, resilience, and spirit of innovation are an inspiration to so many worldwide.</p>



<p>The United States and Israel commit to continuing to discuss the challenges and opportunities in Israeli-Palestinian relations. The countries condemn the deplorable series of terrorist attacks against Israeli citizens in recent months and affirm the need to confront radical forces, such as Hamas, seeking to inflame tension and instigate violence and terrorism. President Biden reaffirms his longstanding and consistent support of a two-state solution and for advancing toward a reality in which Israelis and Palestinians alike can enjoy equal measures of security, freedom and prosperity. The United States stands ready to work with Israel, the Palestinian Authority, and regional stakeholders toward that goal. The leaders also affirm their shared commitment to initiatives that strengthen the Palestinian economy and improve the quality of life of Palestinians.</p>



<p>The United States and Israel enjoy extensive bilateral cooperation and dialogue between their two countries in many critical spheres – from groundbreaking collaboration in science and technology, to unique intelligence sharing and joint military exercises, to shared efforts in confronting pressing global challenges such as climate change, food security, and healthcare. To complement the extensive existing scientific and technological cooperation between their two countries, and to bring their cooperation to a new height, the leaders launched a new U.S.-Israel Strategic High-Level Dialogue on Technology to form a U.S.-Israel technological partnership in critical and emerging technologies, as well as in areas of global concern: pandemic preparedness, climate change, artificial intelligence, and trusted technology. This new technological partnership will be designed to boost the countries’ mutual innovation ecosystems and address geostrategic challenges.</p>



<p><a>In this same spirit, </a>the United States and Israel affirm their commitment to continue their shared and accelerated efforts to enable Israeli passport holders to be included in the U.S. Visa Waiver Program as soon as possible, as well as their support for increased collaboration on operational cyber exchange and on combatting cybercrime. The leaders state that all of these initiatives, and countless other joint endeavors, undertaken between their peoples at every level of government and civil society demonstrate that the U.S.-Israel strategic partnership is indispensable and makes an outsized contribution not only to the good of American and Israeli citizens but also to the good of the Middle East and of the world.</p>



<p>With this record of remarkable achievement and with a sense of the incredible promise that the unparalleled U.S.-Israel relationship holds for the future, the United States and Israel warmly welcome entering the 75th year of this extraordinary partnership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Signed at Jerusalem on the 14<sup>th</sup> day of the July, 2022, which corresponds to the 15<sup>th</sup> day of Tamuz, 5782, in the Hebrew calendar, in duplicate in the English language.</p>



<p>Joseph R. Biden Jr. </p>



<p>President of the United States of America   </p>



<p>Yair Lapid</p>



<p>Prime Minister of the State of Israel</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement of the Leaders of India, Israel, United Arab Emirates, and the United&#160;States&#160;(I2U2)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/joint-statement-of-the-leaders-of-india-israel-united-arab-emirates-and-the-united-states-i2u2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 14, 2022, we, the Heads of Government of India, Israel, the United Arab Emirates (UAE), and the United States, convened for the first leaders’ meeting of the “I2U2” Group.&#160; This unique grouping of countries aims to harness the vibrancy of our societies and entrepreneurial spirit to tackle some of the greatest challenges confronting&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 14, 2022, we, the Heads of Government of India, Israel, the United Arab Emirates (UAE), and the United States, convened for the first leaders’ meeting of the “I2U2” Group.&nbsp; This unique grouping of countries aims to harness the vibrancy of our societies and entrepreneurial spirit to tackle some of the greatest challenges confronting our world, with a particular focus on joint investments and new initiatives in water, energy, transportation, space, health, and food security.<br>&nbsp;<br>We intend to mobilize private sector capital and expertise to modernize infrastructure, advance low carbon development pathways for our industries, improve public health and access to&nbsp; vaccines, advance physical connectivity between countries in the Middle East region, jointly create new solutions for waste treatment, explore joint financing opportunities, connect our startups to I2U2 investments, and promote the development of critical emerging and green technologies, all while ensuring near- and long-term food and energy security.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We reaffirm our support for the Abraham Accords and other peace and normalization arrangements with Israel. &nbsp;We welcome the economic opportunities that flow from these historic developments, including for the advancement of economic cooperation in the Middle East and South Asia, and in particular for the promotion of sustainable investment amongst the I2U2 partners. We also welcome other new groupings of countries, such as the Negev Forum for regional cooperation, that recognize the unique contributions of each partner country, including Israel’s ability to serve as an innovation hub connecting new partners and hemispheres to strategically address challenges that are too great for any one country to manage alone.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today’s inaugural I2U2 leaders meeting focused on the food security crisis and clean energy.&nbsp; The leaders discussed innovative ways to ensure longer-term, more diversified food production and food delivery systems that can better manage global food shocks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>To this end, the I2U2 leaders highlighted the following initiatives:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Food Security:</strong>&nbsp; The UAE – home to the International Renewable Energy Agency (IRENA) and host of COP28 in 2023 – will invest $2 billion USD to develop a series of integrated food parks across India that will incorporate state-of-the-art climate-smart technologies to reduce food waste and spoilage, conserve fresh water, and employ renewable energy sources.&nbsp; India will provide appropriate land for the project and will facilitate farmers’ integration into the food parks.&nbsp; U.S. and Israeli private sectors will be invited to lend their expertise and offer innovative solutions that contribute to the overall sustainability of the project.&nbsp; These investments will help maximize crop yields and, in turn, help tackle food insecurity in South Asia and the Middle East.<br></li><li><strong>Clean Energy:</strong>&nbsp; The I2U2 Group will advance a hybrid renewable energy project in India’s Gujarat State consisting of 300 megawatts (MW) of wind and solar capacity complemented by a battery energy storage system.&nbsp; The U.S. Trade and Development Agency funded a feasibility study for the $330 million USD project.&nbsp; UAE-based companies are exploring opportunities to serve as critical knowledge and investment partners.&nbsp; Israel and the United States intend to work with the UAE and India to highlight private sector opportunities.&nbsp; Indian companies are keen to participate in this project and contribute to India’s goal of achieving 500 GW of non-fossil fuel capacity by 2030.&nbsp; Such projects have the potential to make India a global hub for alternate supply chains in the renewable energy sector.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>The leaders expressed their determination to leverage well-established markets to build more innovative, inclusive, and science-based solutions to enhance food security and sustainable food systems.  The leaders also welcomed India’s interest in joining the United States, the UAE, and Israel in the Agriculture Innovation Mission for Climate initiative (AIM for Climate).  They affirmed that these are only the first steps in a long-term strategic partnership to promote initiatives and investments that improve the movement of people and goods across hemispheres, and increase sustainability and resilience through collaborative science and technology partnerships.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call Previewing Day Two of the President&#8217;s Trip to the Middle&#160;East</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/13/background-press-call-previewing-day-two-of-the-presidents-trip-to-the-middle-east/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 8:00 P.M. IDT MODERATOR:&#160; Good evening, everyone.&#160; Apologies for our delay in this, and we appreciate everyone&#8217;s flexibility and bearing with us.&#160; And thank you for joining our NSC background call to preview day two of the President&#8217;s trip to the Middle East. As a reminder of the ground rules, this call will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>8:00 P.M. IDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; Apologies for our delay in this, and we appreciate everyone&#8217;s flexibility and bearing with us.&nbsp; And thank you for joining our NSC background call to preview day two of the President&#8217;s trip to the Middle East.</p>



<p>As a reminder of the ground rules, this call will be on background with the contents attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; It is under embargo until 6:00 a.m. Israeli Standard Time tomorrow morning, which is 11:00 p.m. Eastern Time for those of you who are back in the States.</p>



<p>For your awareness but not for your reporting, our two speakers today are [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll kick it over to [senior administration official] for &#8212; as our SAO number one.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey, good evening, everybody.&nbsp; Thanks for hanging in there with us, and I apologize for the delay.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just going to do a quick recap of today, and then I&#8217;m going to turn it over to my colleague to talk a little bit more detail about tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think as you all know, we arrived this afternoon, Israeli time.&nbsp; This is the President&#8217;s 10th trip to Israel.&nbsp; He&#8217;s known and had a relationship with every single Israeli prime minister since Golda Meir.&nbsp; So he very much felt in many ways like he was coming home.</p>



<p>Two big muscle movements today.&nbsp; The first was right at the airport where he had a chance to get a briefing from the Israeli Defense Minister, Benny Gantz, who walked him through the Israel Iron Dome technology and system, and also talked to him a little bit about a new promising technology they call Iron Beam, which uses lasers.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a program that Israel was doing in conjunction with the United States Department of Defense, specifically the Missile Defense Agency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So a pretty impressive technology.&nbsp; The President had a chance to actually see it up close and personal outside the briefing room, and had a chance to talk to the men and women from both armed forces who are working to develop this technology and advance this particular defensive capability.</p>



<p>Worth noting that the Biden administration has provided Israel now with $4.8 billion for its security; that includes $1 billion to help replenish Israel&#8217;s Iron Dome.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the highest-ever total in a single year.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s been a real priority for President Biden to help secure that funding following the conflict in May ‘21 with Hamas in Gaza.</p>



<p>And then, of course, the next big muscle movement today was the visit to Yad Vashem, a memorial that the President knows well.&nbsp; And he was able to lay a wreath and then meet with a couple of Holocaust survivors &#8212; a sort of deeply personal, deeply touching but, the President believes, also a very, very important way to start this visit off.</p>



<p>And so that was today, and I&#8217;ll pass it off to my colleague who will give you a better sense of what tomorrow is going to look like.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; So, great to be here, everybody.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, the President will start the day meeting with Israel&#8217;s Prime Minister, Yair Lapid.&nbsp; And this will be a significant bilateral meeting we&#8217;re really looking forward to.</p>



<p>They will discuss a number of issues: of course, President Biden&#8217;s and the United States’ strong support for Israel; their ironclad support for Israel&#8217;s security &#8212; what you heard the President speak to today quite, I think, pointedly, given that this is his first visit here to Israel as President; how to counter Iran&#8217;s destabilizing activities &#8212; of course, we have very close security cooperation and coordination with the Israelis on a host of security efforts here in the region.&nbsp; The Ukraine &#8212; the war on Ukraine, and the need to help the Ukrainians in the face of Russia&#8217;s aggressive war is a theme.&nbsp; And, of course, as you heard from the President today, in his opening remarks after landing, how to preserve prospects here for a two-state solution &#8212; something he&#8217;s believed in his entire life.</p>



<p>The President and the Prime Minister will sign a new joint declaration reaffirming the unbreakable bonds between our countries and expanding on the longstanding security relationship between the United States and Israel.</p>



<p>This declaration is pretty significant, and it includes a commitment to never allow Iran to acquire a nuclear weapon and to address Iran’s destabilizing activities, particularly threats to Israel.</p>



<p>Of course, the keystone U.S. support for Israel’s security is the memorandum of understanding that was originally finalized in 2016 when the President was vice president.&nbsp; And the declaration that will be signed tomorrow will note our ongoing support for that memorandum and support for extending it at an appropriate time.</p>



<p>The declaration will also emphasize support for the Abraham Accords and expanding Israel&#8217;s integration into the region, which of course is a theme of this trip.&nbsp; And it will reiterate our shared concerns about a number of global challenges, from food security, to the situation in Ukraine, and of course, support for Ukraine&#8217;s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp; And, of course, Israel voted with much of the world in the U.N. General Assembly back in March, condemning Russia&#8217;s aggressive war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>We will also tomorrow launch a new U.S.-Israel High-Level Strategic Dialogue on Technology.&nbsp; And this was released today, so some of you may have it.&nbsp; But the strategic dialogue, which has been going on for some time and we&#8217;ve now formalized it, is really designed to elevate cooperation between Israel and the United States in four key fields: its technology for future &#8212; current and future challenges such as pandemic preparedness; climate Technology, using climate to affect &#8212; using technology to affect the climate crisis; artificial technology; and other trusted technology ecosystems.</p>



<p>This is really important because Israel, as you know, has such an innovative and remarkable tech sector, as do we.&nbsp; And we want their tech sector to be connected with ours and looking west as we look to build the technology apparatus for the future.</p>



<p>So we think this new tech dialogue that was now formalized is quite important as we position ourselves for the future.</p>



<p>The President will then participate in the first I2U2 summit with the leaders of Israel, India, and the UAE.&nbsp; And this grouping of countries is unique in how they can work together to tackle global challenges.&nbsp; And a focus tomorrow will be on the food security crisis and also on advancing clean energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think it&#8217;s an interesting moment to be in the Middle East because, of all the global challenges and crises, very few of them, if any, are really emanating here from the Middle East region.&nbsp; And, in fact, countries here in the Middle East region are lending their resources, their ingenuity, their innovation to actually try to tackle those challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this unique grouping of countries tomorrow &#8212; with the UAE and Israel kind of serving as really innovation, entrepreneurial hubs, linking hemispheres &#8212; will focus quite a bit on the food security challenge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ll have a $2 billion project, which the UAE is helping to fund, for agricultural parks in India, which is focused on the food security challenge, among some other things that will be announced.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>The President will then meet with President Herzog at his residence, and they will discuss in a bilateral setting a number of issues, including the important regional diplomacy President Herzog has done recently at Jordan, Turkey, UAE, among others; of course, advancing the shared goals of Israel&#8217;s further integration into the region and stability here in this region.</a></p>



<p>As is traditional for U.S. leaders, the President will meet the leader of the opposition, Benjamin Netanyahu.&nbsp; They, of course, go back many years and know each other well.&nbsp; And we are clear, during this visit, that the relationship between the United States and Israel is about the countries, our strategic partnership as two states, not about individual leaders.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sure they will discuss many of the same topics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, the President greatly looks forward to meeting some of U.S. athletes competing in the Maccabiah Games and viewing a portion of the opening ceremony.&nbsp; This connection between Israel and the American Jewish diaspora is, of course, a very important one with very strong links, and we look forward to highlighting that.</p>



<p>I previewed briefly, before turning it to questions &#8212; we also have a very full morning the next day with a visit to the West Bank and East Jerusalem; to the East Jerusalem Hospital, where we&#8217;ll be announcing a significant funding package for East Jerusalem Hospital Network; and, of course, an important meeting with President Abbas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think some significant announcements coming then, such as enhancing Palestinian economic opportunities, including with development of 4G capabilities, both in Gaza and the West Bank, and some other things that we&#8217;ll be talking about on the Palestinian file as we head into the following morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, I think we can take it &#8212; take some questions, and I thank you for listening to the opening.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; We’ll ask you to indicate that you have a question by raising the “Raise Your Hand” feature on Zoom.</p>



<p>We’ll start off with Chris Megerian from AP.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; I was wondering if you could talk a little bit about what it&#8217;s like to be &#8212; for the President to be visiting Israel at this time politically.&nbsp; Obviously, when President Biden was invited, the previous government was in charge, and now it&#8217;s sort of an interim period where there&#8217;s a lot of uncertainty about who will be leading Israel in the future.&nbsp; How is that, you know, coloring the President&#8217;s visit and impacting his plans for the trip?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; (Speaker muted.)&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>And so, I think it really doesn&#8217;t affect the trip much at all.&nbsp; I think, as I mentioned in my opening, this is a state-to-state relationship.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a strategic relationship.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a relationship that is, as the President mentioned today in his opening after arriving, is “bone deep.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I think we feel good about where the Iraq &#8212; sorry, the Israeli government is right now.&nbsp; And I think the meeting with Prime Minister Lapid tomorrow and the signing of the declaration, I think, is a great opportunity to strengthen those bonds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But of course, the Israeli political system is &#8212; you know, who their leaders are is up to the Israelis.&nbsp; And our relationship is with countries, not leaders.&nbsp; And that has been a theme of ours, I think, since Joe Biden entered office and it remains so.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], my apologies, you were accidentally muted for the first about 15 seconds of your answer if there’s anything you wanted to add.&nbsp; My apologies on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know what I said in the first 15 seconds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And sorry, everyone.&nbsp; Next, we will go to Justin Sink from Bloomberg.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Jake mentioned on the plane that there would be a significant announcement on food security as part of the I2U2 virtual meeting tomorrow, so I was wondering if you could preview that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then the other thing that obviously got a lot of attention heading in was the extent to which the President would be doing sort of personal interactions with Israeli leaders.&nbsp; We saw that go from sort of fist bumps at the beginning to embraces and handshakes towards the end.&nbsp; And so, if there&#8217;s anything fresh you wanted to say on that, we’d be interested.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so on food security, as I think I previewed, there will be &#8212; it&#8217;s a $2 billion project that the UAE is funding for agricultural parks in India.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have some more details about it tomorrow.&nbsp; And Israel lending some of its technological expertise and then also some support from the U.S. private sector.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s a pretty unique, collaborative effort that we think really gets to one of the key challenges that the world is facing today.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;ll have some more to say about that tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it&#8217;s about how these interesting groupings of countries and pulling people together and pulling ideas together, pulling governments together, pulling private sectors together is really the way, we believe, to go about tackling some of these challenges.&nbsp; So that will be a theme tomorrow.</p>



<p>Look, I think, as we&#8217;ve said, we are &#8212; anyone in this traveling party, we’re under heightened COVID protocols.&nbsp; That remains the case.&nbsp; As those of you traveling with us know, we&#8217;re testing every morning.&nbsp; And given the new variant, that remains the case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we never put out guidance that nobody would shake hands or anything else.&nbsp; The President today, I think, did a combination, as President Biden often does, of different sorts of greetings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President is going to be meeting a host of leaders over the course of these three days &#8212; I think 13 &#8212; 12 heads of state, 13 leaders, plus their ministers, deputies, everything else.&nbsp; So I think there will be a lot of meetings, and we will follow the protocols in every capital where we are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, the President will do his greetings.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; I just &#8212; we don&#8217;t really make too much into this.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve really been focused on spending a lot of time here with the President, preparing for this trip &#8212; the substance, the diplomacy, what&#8217;s coming out of the trip &#8212; more so than the particular form of greeting.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next we’ll go to Felicia Schwartz with the FT.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; Going back to the joint declaration and what you&#8217;re going to say on Iran, just more broadly, in your meetings with the Israelis, is there some sort of ask on your part?&nbsp; They don&#8217;t agree with you that there should be time to let these negotiations play out, so I&#8217;m wondering if you&#8217;re asking them to give you more time.&nbsp; Or &#8212; and then, just more broadly, how tense would you say</p>



<p>your talks with the Israelis over Iran are, especially as compared with, let&#8217;s say, 2015, during the Obama administration?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, Felicia &#8212; I would not describe them as tense.&nbsp; We are in a constant dialogue with the Israelis up and down our national security teams.&nbsp; And I think what you’ll see in the joint declaration is a pledge and a commitment never to allow Iran to acquire a nuclear weapon and that we&#8217;re prepared to use all elements of our national power to ensure that outcome.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s something the President himself has spoken to recently.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also, you know, commit to working together when it comes to trying to confront Iran&#8217;s aggression and destabilizing activities here in the region.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something that we&#8217;re very well coordinated with the Israeli government on.</p>



<p>I would just say on this issue: You know, our &#8212; where we are right now &#8212; the door is open to diplomacy.&nbsp; If Iran wants to sign the deal that’s been negotiated in Vienna, we&#8217;ve been very clear we&#8217;re prepared to do that.&nbsp; At the same time, if they&#8217;re not, we’ll continue to increase our sanctions pressure.&nbsp; We’ll continue to increase Iran&#8217;s diplomatic isolation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President mentioned in his op-ed on Friday, when we entered office, the United States was isolated on this issue.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve now rebuilt a coalition against Iran.&nbsp; We had 30 countries join us to condemn Iran&#8217;s lack of participation with the IAEA regarding its past nuclear activities.&nbsp; And frankly, this is something also, of course, that we discuss with the Israelis constantly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I actually think we have a pretty good meeting of the minds with the Israelis on where we are on this issue.&nbsp; And of course, this will also be a topic when we&#8217;re in Saudi Arabia and for the GCC+3 Summit on Saturday.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next, we&#8217;ll go to the line of Ben Samuels with Haaretz.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; So you mentioned Ukraine would be a topic of conversation.&nbsp; So, Israel has notably been reluctant to send weapons to Ukraine at risk of alienating Russia and jeopardizing its freedom of movement in Syria, even though it&#8217;s a large source of humanitarian aid.&nbsp; So is the President planning on pushing Israel to start sending weaponry?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, thanks for the question.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to go into specific forms of support.&nbsp; I think, in the joint declaration, there&#8217;s a &#8212; you know, a strong, mutual understanding about the concerns about Russia&#8217;s ongoing attack against Ukraine.&nbsp; And of course, Israel, again, joined in the U.N. General Assembly with a very strong condemnation of Russia&#8217;s invasion.</p>



<p>And so I think we&#8217;ve &#8212; Israel has done quite a bit.&nbsp; And I think they just announced yesterday &#8212; Minister of Defense Gantz &#8212; about protective gear, other forms of humanitarian aid.&nbsp; And, of course, we welcome that.&nbsp; And I think there are some specific needs we might discuss with the Israelis, but I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of those conversations.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next we’ll go to Jeremy Diamond with CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official], thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about Iran.&nbsp; We know that CENTCOM has been conducting review on how to deter and, if necessary, respond to Iranian threats.&nbsp; Do you plan to share anything from that review with the Israelis tomorrow?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And more broadly, do you expect that you&#8217;re going to get more on the same page with Israel about how to move forward on the Iranian issue?&nbsp; And are there any assurances that you’re prepared to provide for the Israelis to assuage them of their concerns about these negotiations?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Again, I leave it to the Israelis to discuss where they think we are in Iran.&nbsp; I think we have, as I mentioned, a pretty good meeting of the minds right now.&nbsp; And the joint declaration that will come out tomorrow I think will reflect some of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I thought if you really focus in on the event today with Iron Dome and Iron Beam technology, I mean, Iron Dome really came about through a collaborative U.S.-Israeli effort going all the way back to when President Biden was vice president in 2011 or so.&nbsp; And obviously, it has developed in this extraordinary technology in which 90 percent of threats &#8212; yeah, sorry &#8212; nine- &#8212; I&#8217;m talking on an iPhone here, so sometimes it looks like it&#8217;s off, but it&#8217;s not.&nbsp; Ninety percent of the 4,000 rockets launched from Gaza during the conflict last year were actually taken down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now the Iron Beam technology &#8212; and of course, we&#8217;re now entering beginning discussions about the possibility of some co-development projects with our industry and Israel&#8217;s on this type of technology &#8212; is truly extraordinary and is the wave of the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think our cooperation &#8212; the defense sector is about as good as it&#8217;s ever been.&nbsp; You mentioned CENTCOM.&nbsp; Having Israel a part of CENTCOM has just really been, I think, a force multiplier for us<a>, and allowing us to better integrate, organize, share information across the board here in the region has really been &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen it with my own eyes.&nbsp; But I won&#8217;t speak to any particular CENTCOM assessments or anything like that.<br><br>But I think we are very closely tied with the Israelis and their national security team on how we see the threats; how to confront them and how to combat them; and how to make sure, first and foremost, we&#8217;re helping the Israelis wherever we can with their national security.</a></p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And we have time for a couple more, and then we&#8217;ll have to end it.&nbsp; Next, we’ll go to Aurelia End with AFP.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for &#8212; you can hear me?&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes, we can hear you, Aurelia.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Just to follow up on the Iron Beam, can you be, maybe, a little bit more specific about how the administration will support the development of that technology?&nbsp; And what, you know, possibilities of “core developments” &#8212; I think that&#8217;s the words you used &#8212; you are seeing?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so I&#8217;m not &#8212; some of it, I think, was discussed today.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure how much of it was public.&nbsp; I was there for &#8212; a lot of it, of course, was not public.</p>



<p><br>But, look, our industry is developing these technologies in a way that we think is quite encouraging.&nbsp; The tests are working.&nbsp; And then Israel&#8217;s technology, similarly.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s similar to how Iron Dome came to be.&nbsp; And we think, you know, moving forward and finding a way to cooperate in these cutting-edge defense technologies such as these high-energy laser weapons systems, which defend the skies of Israel and the future of those of other, frankly, U.S. security partners over time, really is the way of the future.<br><br>I think you&#8217;ll sense on this trip, throughout, Israel positioning the U.S. and our partners for the future.&nbsp; And I think the Iron Dome, Iron Beam was a theme of that.</p>



<p><br>The technology dialogue, which was announced and we formalize tomorrow, was a theme of that.&nbsp; The joint declaration that will be signed tomorrow is a theme of that.&nbsp; And a number of things we’re announcing for the Palestinians, some of which I previewed similarly.&nbsp; And also, at the summit and at the stop in Saudi Arabia, I think a number of initiatives about really positioning and anchoring ourselves for the future.&nbsp; And Iron Beam really does that.<br><br>But I don&#8217;t want to get into the specific &#8212; you know, how the technology works or anything.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not the expert.&nbsp; But I will say we are cooperating quite closely.&nbsp; And we now have the authority and the approvals for &#8212; to begin discussions about how we can get into co-development to this type of technology.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s a great sign.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Next, we&#8217;ll do Jacob Magid from Times of Israel.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I just wanted to follow up on 4G.&nbsp; Is there any specific in terms of &#8212; is it just an announcement or is there a step planning to be taken?&nbsp; As I think the Israelis notified the Palestinians in November that there was going to be movement on this, and there really hasn&#8217;t been anything since.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just to follow up, is this the new model to kind of focus on economic matters rather than political ones in terms of Palestinians?</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, thanks, Jacob.&nbsp; It’s a great question.&nbsp; We’ll have more to say about it on the day after tomorrow when we&#8217;re &#8212; when we’re in East Jerusalem and we&#8217;re in Bethlehem.<br><br>But yeah, it&#8217;s a commitment to really begin the immediate steps to begin the canvassing to how we get 4G both to the West Bank and Gaza with the rollout by the end of 2023.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s the goal.&nbsp; And so I think that is a really important step, obviously, for the Palestinians &#8212; for the economic vibrancy and opportunities for Palestinians.<br><br>But no, it does not &#8212; it&#8217;s not an either/or.&nbsp; It does not mean that we&#8217;re doing that and we therefore think we don&#8217;t need to find a way forward on a political horizon &#8212; things we&#8217;ve talked about before and that the President mentioned right after landing here today.<br><br>So it&#8217;s really not an either/or, but it&#8217;s really about bolstering the digital economy to improve Palestinian economic growth and opportunities.&nbsp; But it doesn&#8217;t take the place of obviously a need, ultimately, for a political horizon here.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; And I apologize, folks, we only have time for one more question.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll go to Alex Ward from Politico.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Just on that, what are your, sort of &#8212; maybe two questions.&nbsp; What are your prospects right now for &#8212; how dead is the two-state solution process, which you mentioned something you&#8217;re interested in doing, but how defunct is it really, in your assessment?<br><br>The other thing is: In the joint declaration, it sounds like a lot of the same stuff &#8212; right? &#8212; opposing Iran, working together, being close.&nbsp; Is there any sort of new policy development in that section of the joint declaration or any sort of new way forward?&nbsp; Or is it mostly reaffirming previous stances?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, on the first question, I think we&#8217;ve been &#8212; since we came into office &#8212; and I have to say, having dealt with this from day one, I mean, the relations between the U.S. and the Palestinians had almost been entirely severed, so we had to reestablish those relationships.&nbsp;<br><br>We turned back on funding for the Palestinians &#8212; almost half a billion dollars so far.&nbsp; And we began to encourage the reestablishment of political connections between the Israelis and the Palestinians, beyond just the security realm.<br><br>But we&#8217;ve also been very clear, including after the Gaza conflict, that we are not going to come in with a top-down peace plan, because we don&#8217;t believe that that would be the best approach and it would set expectations that would probably fall flat.<br><br>But we&#8217;ve also said all the time, and I think there&#8217;s some encouragement here, that if the two parties are prepared to talk, we will be there, and we will be there to help.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the fact that Prime Minister Lapid spoke with President Abbas just the other day &#8212; that&#8217;s the first contact at that level in five years.&nbsp; And so &#8212; and we had a good meeting today with the Minister of Defense Gantz about his contacts as well.<br><br>So these are things we want to help move forward.&nbsp; But again, we&#8217;re very realistic about it.&nbsp; And I think your question prefaces some of that.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re trying to do what we can to try to get a bit of a foundation in place to make some progress.&nbsp; And I think you&#8217;ll really hear the President speak to that not only tomorrow, but also when he&#8217;s in East Jerusalem and when he&#8217;s in Bethlehem.</p>



<p><br>The second question on the declaration &#8212; so you&#8217;ll see the declaration tomorrow.&nbsp; A lot of it is a reaffirmation.&nbsp; Of course, it&#8217;s a reaffirmation of the importance of the MOU that was put in place when President Biden was vice president, but also the commitment to look at the future and that we recognize the need for, ultimately, another MOU when the MOU ultimately expires.<br><br>But I think you&#8217;ll see a lot in there about &#8212; that will look familiar, but also, I think, a lot that will look new.&nbsp; And I think unique to President Biden&#8217;s experience here in Israel, which he spoke to today &#8212; and I&#8217;ve been around President Biden a lot, of course, over the last 18 months, but then before that.&nbsp; I mean, he really &#8212; Israel truly is in his soul.<br><br>When he says this relationship is “bone deep,” he means it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really a part of his not only professional life, but going all the way back to his childhood, as he spoke to today upon landing here on his first visit to Israel as President.<br><br>So it&#8217;s an important time, strategic moment for our country with opportunities, but also, I think, an important time and a poignant one for President Biden.&nbsp; And as I think you&#8217;ve seen the statements from Israeli leaders up and down the political spectrum here, they very much recognize that.<br><br>So we&#8217;re really thrilled to be here.&nbsp; We think we have some good opportunities.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more to say about them tomorrow and the next day.<br><br>So thank you so much.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; And thank you, everyone, for joining our background call this evening.&nbsp; My apologies we weren&#8217;t able to get to everyone with hands raised, but feel free to reach out to us individually afterwards.&nbsp; You know where to find me if you have any follow-up questions.<br><br>Again, to reiterate the ground rules: This call was held on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; It is embargoed until 6:00 a.m. IST tomorrow morning, or 11:00 p.m. Eastern tonight.<br><br>Thank you very much, and I hope everyone has a wonderful evening.</p>



<p><br>8:27 P.M. IDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEC Director Deese Statement on Panasonic Energy Announcement in&#160;Kansas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/13/nec-director-deese-statement-on-panasonic-energy-announcement-in-kansas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 23:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s announcement that Panasonic Energy plans to invest $4 billion and create 4,000 jobs in a lithium-ion battery factory in De Soto, Kansas, is the latest example that the Biden-Harris economic strategy to bring manufacturing jobs back home is working. Over the last year, construction of new manufacturing facilities has increased by 116 percent. Industrial&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s announcement that Panasonic Energy plans to invest $4 billion and create 4,000 jobs in a lithium-ion battery factory in De Soto, Kansas, is the latest example that the Biden-Harris economic strategy to bring manufacturing jobs back home is working. Over the last year, construction of new manufacturing facilities has increased by 116 percent. Industrial production is at a record high. And since President Biden took office, we’ve added 574,000 manufacturing jobs, including more manufacturing jobs created in 2021 than in any year in nearly 30 years. America is making things again.</p>



<p>The announcement is also another proof point of the success of the Administration&#8217;s efforts to create more resilient and secure supply chains and outcompete the rest of the world in the technologies of the future. Executive Order 14017,<em>America’s Supply Chains</em>, signed in February 2021, initiated a whole-of-government strategy to secure critical supply chains, including electric vehicle batteries and the critical minerals that go into them. This announcement by Panasonic builds on more than a year of progress building an end-to-end American supply chain for lithium-ion batteries, a market currently dominated by China. Just last month, Stellantis and Samsung announced a $2.5 billion joint venture to manufacture batteries in Kokomo, Indiana. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provided nearly $7 billion to strengthen the battery supply chain, including $6 billion through the Department of Energy for battery material processing, battery manufacturing, and recycling. These funds will support good jobs in leading edge industries in communities across the country.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, President Biden invoked the Defense Production Act to authorize investment in the sustainable extraction, processing, and recycling of critical battery minerals—lithium, cobalt, nickel, graphite, and manganese. In April, the Department of Energy Loan Program Office issued its first conditional loan commitment through the Advanced Technology Vehicle Manufacturing program in more than a decade—$107 million to Syrah Technologies to produce graphite for electric vehicle batteries.</p>



<p>And as President Biden has said, any company investing in the United States would benefit greatly from entering into partnerships with some of the most highly skilled, dedicated, and engaged workers in the world—American union workers.</p>



<p>The future of transportation is electric. President Biden’s industrial strategy is ensuring that future is built here in America by all of America’s workers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/13/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-74/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 21:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[     Margaret R. Guzman, of Massachusetts, to be United States District Judge for the District of Massachusetts, vice Timothy S. Hillman, retired. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Kymberly Kathryn Evanson, of Washington, to be United States District Judge for the Western District of Washington, vice Ricardo S. Martinez, retiring. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Jamal N. Whitehead, of Washington, to be United States&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>     Margaret R. Guzman, of Massachusetts, to be United States District Judge for the District of Massachusetts, vice Timothy S. Hillman, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kymberly Kathryn Evanson, of Washington, to be United States District Judge for the Western District of Washington, vice Ricardo S. Martinez, retiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jamal N. Whitehead, of Washington, to be United States District Judge for the Western District of Washington, vice Richard A. Jones, retiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Robert Stewart Ballou, of Virginia, to be United States District Judge for the Western District of Virginia, vice James P. Jones, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jamar K. Walker, of Virginia, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Virginia, vice Raymond A. Jackson, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jorge A. Rodriguez, of New York, to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of New York, vice David M. Hurd, retiring.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Biden after Senate Confirmation of Michael Barr to the Federal&#160;Reserve</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/13/statement-from-president-biden-after-senate-confirmation-of-michael-barr-to-the-federal-reserve/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 21:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Federal Reserve plays the primary role in fighting inflation and regulating financial institutions. Today’s confirmation of Michael Barr as Vice Chair for Supervision of the Federal Reserve is important progress for my plan to tackle inflation and for sound oversight as we transition to steady and stable growth. The Senate has now confirmed my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Federal Reserve plays the primary role in fighting inflation and regulating financial institutions. Today’s confirmation of Michael Barr as Vice Chair for Supervision of the Federal Reserve is important progress for my plan to tackle inflation and for sound oversight as we transition to steady and stable growth. The Senate has now confirmed my full slate of nominees, a historic and experienced group that includes Jerome Powell, Dr. Lael Brainard, Dr. Lisa Cook, and Dr. Philip Jefferson. They bring the skill and knowledge needed at this critical time for our economy and families across the country to fight inflation, to ensure ordinary Americans get a fair shake, and to protect the stability of our economy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Appoints Cancer Panel Members and Cancer Cabinet Unveils Priority&#160;Actions</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/13/fact-sheet-president-biden-appoints-cancer-panel-members-and-cancer-cabinet-unveils-priority-actions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 21:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57394</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to appoint Dr. Mitchel Berger, Dr. Carol Brown, and Dr. Elizabeth Jaffee to the President’s Cancer Panel. The three are distinguished members of the scientific, research, and public health communities appointed by the President to advise him on barriers to and opportunities for progress in reducing the burden&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to appoint Dr. Mitchel Berger, Dr. Carol Brown, and Dr. Elizabeth Jaffee to the President’s Cancer Panel. The three are distinguished members of the scientific, research, and public health communities appointed by the President to advise him on barriers to and opportunities for progress in reducing the burden of cancer.</p>



<p>In addition, First Lady Jill Biden, Cabinet Members, and Biden-Harris Administration leadership are holding a Cancer Cabinet meeting today to unveil priority actions and new members, advancing the President’s vision for ending cancer as we know it. The Cancer Cabinet has identified priorities to: (1) close the screening gap, (2) understand and address environmental exposure, (3) decrease the impact of preventable cancers, (4) bring cutting edge research through the pipeline to patients and communities, and (5) support patients and caregivers. This Cancer Cabinet also added the Departments of Commerce and Labor, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the White House Gender Policy Council.</p>



<p>Since the Cancer Cabinet’s prior meeting, additional steps that mark progress for the millions of Americans facing a cancer diagnosis have been announced by the Biden-Harris Administration including: the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) issuing more than $200 million in grants to advance national cancer prevention and control through cancer screening programs reaching every state, U.S. territories, and tribal organizations; the Centers for Medicaid &amp; Medicare Services (CMS) launching a new model to deliver patient-centered care that improves outcomes and reduces the cost of cancer care; the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) announcing the extension of a program to fast-track cancer immunotherapy applications; the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) pursuing steps to significantly reduce tobacco-related morbidity and mortality in the United States as part of cancer prevention efforts, and announcing that for the first time in over 50 years, the White House will host a Conference on Hunger, Nutrition, and Health and release a national, whole-of-government strategy to end hunger and reduce diet-release disease (which includes some cancers) this September. &nbsp;</p>



<p>In February, President Biden reignited the Cancer Moonshot with renewed White House leadership and new ambitious goals: to reduce the death rate from cancer by at least 50 percent over the next 25 years, and improve the experience of people and their families living with and surviving cancer –&nbsp;and, by doing this and more, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/fact-sheet-president-biden-reignites-cancer-moonshot-to-end-cancer-as-we-know-it/">end cancer as we know it today</a>. In March, in his first State of the Union Address, President Biden highlighted the Cancer Moonshot as part of his Unity Agenda for the nation. The White House convened the Cancer Cabinet to establish a prioritized agenda across government including the development of new interagency programs and collaborations and announced <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2022/03/17/fact-sheet-white-house-announces-initial-steps-for-reignited-cancer-moonshot/">initial steps for the Cancer Moonshot</a>.</p>



<p>To add your story, ideas, or new actions and collaborations, engage with us at: whitehouse.gov/cancermoonshot.</p>



<p><strong><u>Appointment of President’s Cancer Panel</u></strong></p>



<p>President Bidenselected <strong>new members of the President’s Cancer Panel</strong>, a volunteer panel of experts who advise the President on how to use the resources of the federal government, particularly through the cancer research program, to make progress for people facing a cancer diagnosis and to reduce the burden of cancer on the American population:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Dr. Elizabeth M. Jaffee,</strong> to serve as Chair, is an internationally recognized expert in cancer immunology and pancreatic cancer. She is the Deputy Director of the Sidney Kimmel Comprehensive Cancer Center at Johns Hopkins, Co-Director of the Skip Viragh Pancreatic Cancer Center, and Associate Director of the Bloomberg Kimmel Institute for Cancer Immunotherapy. Jaffee is a Past President of the American Association for Cancer Research. She has served on a number of committees at the National Cancer Institute, including co-chair of the Blue Ribbon Panel that provided scientific advice to then-Vice President Biden’s Moonshot Initiative and as Past Chair of the National Cancer Advisory Board. She is the inaugural Director of the new Convergence Institute at Johns Hopkins. She was recently elected to the National Academy of Medicine and is a Fellow of the Academy of Immuno-Oncology, a Fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, a Fellow of the American Association of Cancer Research, and a Fellow of the American College of Physicians.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Dr. Mitchel Berger</strong> is a Neurological Surgeon who has spent his entire career taking care of and operating on patients with brain tumors. In addition, he has been funded by the National Institutes of Health and National Cancer Institute (NCI) to conduct basic science research in brain tumor biology including the molecular markers that determine the growth and treatment patterns of these tumors. For 20 years, Berger has been the Principal Investigator for Brain SPORE (Specialized Program of Research Excellence), funded by NCI, and he directs the University of California San Francisco (UCSF) Brain Tumor Center, composed of its NeuroOncology Clinical Trials Program and Brain Tumor Research Center. Previously, he served as Chair of the Department of Neurological Surgery at UCSF and following 23 years of service in this capacity remains a full time Professor of Neurological Surgery at UCSF. Berger also served as the President of two leading national organizations, the American Association of Neurological Surgeons and the Society of NeuroOncology. He served as a member of the Blue Ribbon Panel for the Cancer Moonshot Initiative led by then-Vice President Biden under the direction of President Obama.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Dr. Carol Brown</strong> is a board-certified gynecologic oncologist who is the Senior Vice President and Chief Health Equity Officer at Memorial Sloan Kettering (MSK) Cancer Center and the incumbent of the Nicholls-Biondi Chair for Health Equity. Brown’s career is focused on three areas: providing high-quality and compassionate surgical care to women with gynecologic cancer; eliminating cancer health disparities; and promoting public policy to increase awareness, improve care, and increase research funding for gynecologic and other cancers. As MSK’s Chief Health Equity Officer, Brown addresses cancer disparities that exist due to racial, ethnic, cultural, or socioeconomic barriers, and is responsible for center-wide initiatives to achieve health equity for medically underserved populations. This includes efforts to increase participation in clinical trials such as the Cancer Health Equities Research Program, a unique partnership between MSK investigators and community oncologists to bring MSK clinical trials to underserved patients at their local institutions. Brown’s national leadership positions include serving as the 50<sup>th</sup> President of the Society of Gynecologic Oncology (SGO), former Co-Chair of the NRG Oncology Health Disparities Committee, and as a member of the American College of Surgeons Board of Regents. Brown was the first Black female to lead the SGO, an organization whose 2,000 members are dedicated to caring for women with gynecologic cancers and advancing research in the field.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Priority Actions for the Cancer Cabinet</u></strong></p>



<p>When President Biden re-ignited the Cancer Moonshot, he announced seven pillars that define how we know cancer today to provide a shared agenda on which to make progress. This includes possibilities for progress in cancer early detection, prevention, equity, precision medicine, rare and childhood cancer, supporting patients and caregivers, and learning from patients. The Cancer Cabinet outlined the following priority actions on which agencies are working together and through their own programming to make progress on this vision for ending cancer as we know it.&nbsp;</p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong>Close the Screening Gap:</strong> Americans missed nearly 10 million cancer screenings as compared to prior years due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Through targeted and coordinated programs, we should cut that deficit by providing access to more cancer screening opportunities and expand equitable access to cancer early detection.</li></ol>



<ul><li><strong>Understand and Address Environmental and Toxic Exposures: </strong>Studies have shownthat exposure to some environmental contaminants and toxic chemicals can lead to a higher risk of certain types of cancer. Through a robust scientific research and regulatory agenda, the United States can do more to understand the impact of environmental exposure in an effort to better regulate and eliminate exposures related to cancer.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Decrease the Impact of Preventable Cancers: </strong>Thanks to scientific advancements, there are more tools today than ever before to prevent cancer. There are also healthy lifestyle choices like nutrition, tobacco cessation, others as well as tools such as the HPV vaccine and Hepatitis C antivirals that can prevent cervical, head and neck, and liver cancer, respectively. Additionally, advances in colonoscopy technology enable detection and removal of pre-cancerous growths to prevent the development of colon cancer in more individuals. Additional efforts are needed to expand access to these cancer-prevention approaches along with public health campaigns and community health efforts to ensure these preventative tools are reaching all populations. In doing so, there is opportunity to nearly or wholly eliminate certain cancer types.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Bring Cutting Edge Research Through the Pipeline to Patients and Communities: </strong>The development and deployment of new ways to prevent, detect, and treat cancer will be necessary to increase cancer survival rates. In order to reach the goal of better targeting treatments to the right patients and designing new approaches to drive progress for some of the deadliest and rare cancers, including childhood cancers, investment and innovation in cancer research programs is essential.&nbsp; In addition, we must support the pipeline from discovery to clinical research that involves more populations, and ensure treatment innovations reach patients in communities across the United States.</li></ul>



<p><strong>5) Support Patients and Caregivers: </strong>Cancer can be overwhelming to any person or family and gaps in support can lead to gaps in quality care. The Biden-Harris Administration seeks to make the experience around cancer – from screening, to getting a diagnosis, to treatment, care and survivorship – easier on those living with cancer and their caregivers. That means supporting people as they navigate through these steps, making it easier for people to access screening and diagnostics, bringing trials and quality care closer to home, providing patients and caregivers with the data and knowledge they need to make informed care decisions, and giving people with cancer and the people who care for them a seat at the table to improve our oncology system.</p>



<p><strong><u>Expanded Cancer Cabinet Delivers on Cancer Moonshot Goals</u></strong></p>



<p>Today, President Biden’s vision for an all-of-government response to the goals of the Cancer Moonshot expands to include <strong>the U.S. Departments of Labor and Commerce, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), and the White House Gender Policy Council</strong>. This new leadership brings new capacity from, for example, the Department of Labor to support patients and caregivers with knowledge and resources regarding their rights to take time related to a cancer diagnosis as well as advancing a regulatory agenda to further protect workers in different settings. The Department of Commerce brings new perspectives and capabilities to speed innovation through the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) and the advanced manufacturing and research capabilities of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). NASA’s expertise in radiation and extreme environment provides the ability to support ground-breaking research, including on the International Space Station, expanding the tools we have to find new approaches to prevent, detect, and treat cancer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additional Cancer Cabinet announcements to support progress as part of the Cancer Moonshot include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) Improves Access to Colon Cancer Screening</strong></li></ul>



<p>To reduce barriers to getting a colonoscopy, <a href="https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/press-releases/cms-proposes-physician-payment-rule-expand-access-high-quality-care">CMS is proposing</a> that a follow-up colonoscopy to an at-home test be considered, for coverage purposes, a “preventive service,” which means that cost sharing would be waived for people with Medicare. Additionally, Medicare is proposing to cover the service for individuals 45 years of age and above, in line with the newly-lowered age recommendation (down from age 50) from the United States Preventative Services Task Force. Colon and rectal cancer were the second-leading cause of cancer deaths in the United States in 2020, with higher colorectal cancer death rates for Black and American Indian and Alaskan Native individuals.</p>



<ul><li><strong>CMS Launches New Model to Improve Patient Care and Outcomes, Reduce Costs: </strong>Last week, <a href="https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/fact-sheets/enhancing-oncology-model">CMS launched a new, voluntary Enhancing Oncology Model (EOM)</a> designed to test how to best place cancer patients at the center of the care team that provides high-value, equitable, evidence-based care. The EOM aims to improve care coordination, quality, and health outcomes for patients, while also holding oncology practices accountable for total costs of care to make cancer care more affordable and accessible for beneficiaries and Medicare. This model incorporates many lessons learned from the Oncology Care Model (OCM) – which launched as part of the Cancer Moonshot in 2016 – in addition to feedback from the oncology community, including OCM participants, patient advocacy groups, oncology professional associations, and others.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>USPTO Announced Further Extending the Fast-Track Program for Cancer Products: </strong>The <a href="https://www.uspto.gov/subscription-center/2022/uspto-extends-cancer-immunotherapy-pilot-program-until-september-30-2022">USPTO announced a further extension</a> of its <em>Patents for Patients</em> or <em>Cancer Immunotherapy Pilot Program,</em> which provides special status to high-priority innovations in cancer treatment. The USPTO first implemented the program in June 2016, in support of the Cancer Moonshot initiative. This program provides a fast-track review for cancer immunotherapy-related patent applications without the need for applicants to pay a petition fee. Under this program, patent applications pertaining to cancer immunotherapy are advanced out of turn for examination, resulting in their accelerated review, cutting in half the time it takes to review patent applications pertaining to cancer immunotherapy.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) Provides More Than $200M for Evidence-Based Cancer Screening Programs:</strong> In June, the CDC <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2022/p0608-cancer-award.html">announced first-year funding awards of $215 million</a> in a 5-year, $1.1 billion investment into three national programs to prevent and control cancer. Eighty-six unique recipients from state, local, tribal, and territorial public health organizations and academic institutions received funding, representing all states, the District of Columbia, 18 tribal organizations, five U.S. territories, and three freely-associated states. Funded programs will demonstrate how proven strategies advance health equity and build capacity in cancer prevention and control. Outcomes include improving the provision of clinical preventive services; facilitating planning among partners to promote evidence-based strategies in communities; and improving cancer surveillance.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>About the Cancer Cabinet</u></strong></p>



<p>When President Biden re-ignited the Cancer Moonshot in February 2022, he announced a whole- of-government response, including the formation of a Cancer Cabinet to be convened by the White House, bringing together departments, agencies, and other White House components across government to address cancer on multiple fronts. Initially, these included the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), Department of Defense (DOD), Department of Energy (DOE), Department of Agriculture (USDA), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), National Institutes of Health (NIH), National Cancer Institute (NCI), Food and Drug Administration (FDA), Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), Domestic Policy Council (DPC), Office of the First Lady (OFL), Office of the Vice President (OVP), Office of Management and Budget (OMB), Office of Legislative Affairs (OLA), Office of Public Engagement (OPE), along with additional members, as needed, to help establish and make progress on Cancer Moonshot goals.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Names Twenty-Second Round of Judicial&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/13/president-biden-names-twenty-second-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 20:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing six new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country —&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing six new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>For example, if confirmed, this slate would include:</p>



<ul><li>The first Hispanic judge to serve on the U.S. District Court for the District of Massachusetts</li><li>The first Hispanic judge to serve on the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of New York</li><li>The first openly LGBTQ Article III judge to serve in the state of Virginia</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s twenty-second round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his ninth slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 118.</p>



<p>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies. And he has won confirmation of the most lower court judges for the first year of a presidency since the Kennedy Administration.</p>



<p><strong><u>District Court Press Bios</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Judge Margaret R. Guzman: Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of Massachusetts</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Margaret R. Guzman has served as a judge on the Ayer District Court in Middlesex County, Massachusetts since 2017. From 2009 to 2017, she served as a judge on the Massachusetts Trial Court. From 2005 to 2009, Judge Guzman was a solo practitioner. She previously served as a public defender for the Massachusetts Committee for Public Counsel Services from 1992 to 2005. Judge Guzman received her J.D. from Boston University School of Law in 1992 and her B.A. from Clark University, with honors, in 1989.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>Kymberly Evanson: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Kymberly Evanson is a partner at Pacifica Law Group in Seattle, Washington, where she has worked since 2011.&nbsp;Ms. Evanson was an associate attorney at K&amp;L Gates in Seattle, Washington from 2009 to 2011. She served as a law clerk for Judge Emmet Sullivan on the United States District Court for the District of&nbsp; Columbia from 2007 to 2008. Ms. Evanson received her J.D. from Georgetown University Law Center in 2007 and her B.A. from Seattle University in 1999.</p>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong><u>Jamal Whitehead: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Jamal Whitehead is a shareholder at Schroeter Goldmark &amp; Bender in Seattle, Washington, where he has worked since 2016.&nbsp; From 2014 to 2016, Mr. Whitehead was an Assistant United States Attorney for the Western District of Washington.&nbsp;From 2010 to 2014, he was a Senior Trial Attorney in the Seattle Field Office of the United States Equal Employment Opportunity Commission.&nbsp; From 2007 to 2010, Mr. Whitehead worked as an associate at Garvey Schubert Barer (now Foster Garvey) in Seattle, Washington.&nbsp;He received his J.D. from Seattle University School of Law in 2007 and his B.A. from the University of Washington in 2004.</p>



<ol type="1" start="4"><li><strong><u>Judge Robert Stewart Ballou: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Western District of Virginia</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Robert Stewart Ballou has served as a United States Magistrate Judge for the Western District of Virginia since 2011. Prior to joining the bench, Judge Ballou was a partner at Johnson, Ayers &amp; Matthews in Roanoke, Virginia, where he worked from 1992 to 2011. From 1988 to 1991, Judge Ballou was an associate at Christian, Barton, Epps, Brent &amp; Chappell in Richmond, Virginia. Judge Ballou served as a law clerk for Judge Peter Beer on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana from 1987 to 1988. Judge Ballou received his J.D. in 1987 and his B.A in 1984, both from the University of Virginia.</p>



<ol type="1" start="5"><li><strong><u>Jamar K. Walker: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Jamar K. Walker has served as an Assistant United States Attorney for the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Virginia since 2015. From 2012 to 2015, Mr. Walker was an associate at Covington &amp; Burling in Washington, D.C.. He served as a law clerk for Judge Raymond A. Jackson on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia from 2011 to 2012. Mr. Walker received his B.A. from the University of Virginia in 2008 and his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 2011.</p>



<ol type="1" start="6"><li><strong><u>Jorge Alberto Rodriguez: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Northern District of New York</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Jorge Alberto Rodriguez has served as an Assistant Attorney General in the Office of the Attorney General of New York since 2014. Mr. Rodriguez was an associate at Deily &amp; Glastetter in Albany from 2010 to 2014 and at Mahoney &amp; Keane in New York City from 2005 to 2010.&nbsp;He received his J.D. in 2004 and B.A. in 2000, both from Vanderbilt University.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Listening Session withDomestic Violence and Sexual Assault&#160;Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/13/readout-of-white-house-listening-session-withdomestic-violence-and-sexual-assault-organizations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 17:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Officials from the White House Gender Policy Council, Office of Public Engagement, and Office of the Vice President convened a listening session on the impact that abortion bans and other restrictions have on survivors of sexual assault and/or domestic violence and their ability to access reproductive health care. The advocates and leaders who participated represented&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Officials from the White House Gender Policy Council, Office of Public Engagement, and Office of the Vice President convened a listening session on the impact that abortion bans and other restrictions have on survivors of sexual assault and/or domestic violence and their ability to access reproductive health care. The advocates and leaders who participated represented national, state-wide, and local organizations that provide services, support, and advocacy for survivors. They shared insights from service providers working with survivors in states where abortion is now banned, or severely curtailed, following the Supreme Court’s ruling in <em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization</em>. They also discussed the ways in which restrictions on survivors’ most personal health care decisions violate their privacy and create additional safety concerns for victims of domestic violence and sexual assault. Advocates also raised the disproportionate impact that these state bans have on survivors from historically marginalized or underserved communities.</p>



<p>While critical of the abortion bans in several states that have no exceptions for rape or incest, advocates also highlighted how those that do have such limited exceptions also fail to meet the needs of survivors; most victims of sexual violence do not report it, nor should they have to in order to be able to access a full range of reproductive health care options, including abortion.&nbsp; Advocates who work with survivors of sexual and domestic violence indicated how concepts such as bodily autonomy and consent are crucial to the work of preventing sexual violence. They emphasized that taking away survivors’ right to make decisions about their own reproductive health further compounds the trauma they experience, and has long-term implications. Advocates also highlighted how crucial it is to protect the confidentiality and autonomy of all survivors in order to protect their safety and well-being.</p>



<p>White House officials thanked the leaders and advocates for their dedication to helping survivors of domestic violence and sexual assault. They underscored the President’s commitment to supporting all survivors in their ability to access services, safety, justice, and healing, as well as his commitment to defending reproductive rights for all Americans.</p>



<p>Organizations that participated in the listening session included:</p>



<ul><li>National Alliance to End Sexual Violence</li><li>National Network to End Domestic Violence</li><li>National Coalition Against Domestic Violence</li><li>Esperanza United</li><li>New Mexico Coalition of Sexual Assault Programs</li><li>Ohio Alliance to End Sexual Violence</li><li>Metropolitan Organization to Counter Sexual Assault, Kansas City, MO</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the American Rescue Plan Workforce Development&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/13/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-american-rescue-plan-workforce-development-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 17:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57385</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 11:28 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning, everyone.  Good morning.  Thank you, Se- &#8212; AUDIENCE MEMBER:  Good morning! THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good mor- &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; good morning. What an array of extraordinary American leaders.  So, thank you all for being here and for the work you’re doing every day. And, Secretary Walsh,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>South Court Auditorium<br><em>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br><br>11:28 A.M. EDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning, everyone.  Good morning.  Thank you, Se- &#8212;<br> <br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:  Good morning!<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good mor- &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; good morning.<br> <br>What an array of extraordinary American leaders.  So, thank you all for being here and for the work you’re doing every day.<br> <br>And, Secretary Walsh, I want to thank you for that introduction, but mostly I want to thank you for the work that you have done your entire career.<br> <br>And as he said, he and I have been traveling the country together, and he is an extraordinary fighter for the working people of America.<br> <br>It is also good to be here with Gene Sperling.  And he has &#8212; as I mentioned to many of the leaders earlier, he has been working day and night to coordinate with you to ensure that the American people benefit directly from the American Rescue Plan.  So, Gene, I want to thank you for your leadership.<br> <br>And I want to also recognize a longstanding public servant and leader, Governor Roy Cooper, along with Governor Tom Wolf, who has done an extraordinary job during difficult times. <br> <br>So, thank you all, and to all of the local and state elected leaders for being here today.<br> <br>Before I begin, I will address this month&#8217;s CPI report.<br><br>There is no question that we still have work to do.  But it is important to note that these numbers do not fully reflect the recent drop in gas prices.<br> <br>Average national gas prices have fallen every day for nearly 30 days.  Since mid-June, prices are down 40 cents a gallon.<br> <br>Fighting inflation is one of our administration&#8217;s top economic priorities, which is why we have taken action to lower the cost of living for Americans &#8212; millions of Americans.<br> <br>We are releasing 1 million barrels of oil a day from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve to lower prices at the pump.<br> <br>We reduced high-speed Internet bills for millions of Americans.<br><br>And we passed a tax cut to give working families up to $8,000 a year, which means giving folks more room in their budgets to buy food, medication, and school supplies for their children.<br> <br>President Joe Biden and I are always fighting to make sure that working families can get ahead and stay ahead.  And that is why we continue to call on Congress to pass legislation to lower the price of prescription drugs, of healthcare, and the other everyday essentials that will meet the needs of American families.  And so, helping working families is why we are here today.<br><br>When President Biden and I took office, our nation was facing its worst economic crisis in generations.  We all remember: Millions of jobs had been lost.  Millions of small businesses closed.  Millions of families pushed right to the edge.  But we were not deterred.  These leaders were not deterred.<br> <br>From day one, President Biden and I knew that to overcome these historic economic challenges, we needed to make an historic investment in our nation&#8217;s working families.  We needed to build an economy that works for working people.<br> <br>And that is why, with your help, we fought for and passed the American Rescue Plan, which included, among many things, a $40 billion investment in workforce development.<br> <br>Just think about that.  When we talk about an investment in workforce development, that is about a direct investment in working people in America.  It’s a direct investment in human capacity.  And for that reason, I know we’re all excited about what it means and the potential for where this will go for generations of workers in America.<br><br>So today it is an honor to gather with a group of leaders who are putting ARP dollars to work in communities across our nation &#8212; governors and mayors, city commissioners and county executives, workers and labor leaders.<br> <br>With your help, we are creating good-paying jobs in small towns and big cities; jobs for nurses and doctors; jobs for steelworkers, pipefitters, and engineers.<br><br>Together, we are investing in training programs and apprenticeships that give workers the skills they need to take on the jobs with better wages and better benefits &#8212; in particular, workers from underrepresented backgrounds.<br> <br>Together, we are expanding access to transportation.  It seems like maybe it’s a small issue; it’s a big issue.  You need to get to go and need to be able to get where you need to go to do the work and get home.<br><br>So we have expanded access to transportation, including what we need to invest in public transit, understanding that the infrastructure in our country around public transit is and has been in disrepair in many areas of our country.  And so that is the investment that we have put in there.<br><br>And together, we are fighting to improve and expand our childcare and healthcare workforce so that everyone who needs better care can have access to better care, no matter where they live and no matter how much money they make.<br> <br>That includes 8 million Americans who are part of the so-called sandwich generation, which means they’re right there in the middle, taking care of both their children and their parents.  And that includes people with mental and physical disabilities so they can access the critical care and support they need to succi- &#8212; -ceed and to thrive &#8212; to succeed and to thrive.<br> <br>Together, we are doing so much important and impactful work.  And we have, therefore, convened this summit with these extraordinary leaders so they can share their stories and share the stories of the people they represent, and so we can discuss how we can continue to work together on behalf of the working people of our nation.<br> <br>I have seen firsthand how much is possible when we collaborate across lines that relate to the direct benefit of the people of our nation.<br><br>In fact, earlier this year, I visited a union training facility in Milwaukee, Wisconsin.  It’s called <s>WRPT</s> [WRTP]| BIG STEP.<br> <br>At BIG STEP, I met workers who had received training to remove and replace the lead pipes and service lines that are poisoning our communities.  It was truly an inspiration.<br> <br>As a result of their training, those workers can now access good-paying union jobs &#8212; jobs they can raise a family on, jobs they can build a future on, jobs that are helping us build a better future for our entire nation.<br> <br>Today, as many as 10 million homes and 400,000 schools and childcare facilities receive their water through lead pipes.  Graduates of BIG STEP are already removing lead pipes in Milwaukee &#8212; we have leaders from Milwaukee with us here today &#8212; and in communities across America.<br><br>BIG STEP is one of hundreds of job training facilities around our nation that received funding through the ARP.  Here with us today is Lindsay Blumer, President of <s>WRPT</s> [WRTP]| BIG STEP.  Where is &#8212; Lindsay, where are you?  There you are. <br> <br>And, Lindsay, and all of the leaders here, I want to thank you for all that you have done to make real the promise of the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>Since President Joe Biden and I took office, we have accomplished so much with your help, but we still have more to do.<br> <br>We must continue our work together to build a nation where every worker is treated with dignity, where every community is safe and healthy, and where every child can reach their God-given potential.  Because every person in our nation, no matter where they start, deserves the opportunity to succeed and to thrive.<br> <br>That is the future we are all fighting for, and that is the future our administration is fighting for &#8212; a future that we will all build together.<br> <br>God bless you.  And God bless the United States of America.  Thank you all.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br><br>                              END                11:36 A.M. EDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
