<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 21:27:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Trucking Action Plan to Strengthen Our Nation’s Supply&#160;Chains</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/04/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-trucking-action-plan-to-strengthen-our-nations-supply-chains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 21:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 2:08 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I think she can do anything she wants, don’t you?&#160; Well, hello, everyone.&#160; It’s an honor to welcome you to the White House out on the lawn here.&#160; I heard that helicopter going by.&#160; I was hoping the helo wasn’t going to land.&#160; (Laughter.) Maria, thanks for sharing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>South Lawn</em></p>



<p>2:08 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think she can do anything she wants, don’t you?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, hello, everyone.&nbsp; It’s an honor to welcome you to the White House out on the lawn here.&nbsp; I heard that helicopter going by.&nbsp; I was hoping the helo wasn’t going to land.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Maria, thanks for sharing your story.</p>



<p>And my buddy, Patrick Murphy, former Assistant Secretary &#8212; Secretary of the Army as well as a former congressman.  And the boy stays in shape, man.  Huh?  Look at him.  (Laughter.)  I tell you &#8212;</p>



<p>CHAIR MURPHY:&nbsp; I’m trying to (inaudible) you, sir.&nbsp; I (inaudible) you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I tell you what, man, I &#8212; and I want to thank you for being here, man.&nbsp; Nobody worked harder as a congressman or Acting Secretary of the Army to connect veterans to opportunity, and that’s what it’s all &#8212; been all about for you.</p>



<p>And I want to thank another veteran who knows a thing or two about laying the foundation for good jobs and the transportation sector: Secretary Buttigieg.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I &#8212; he says, “Go Navy.”&nbsp; He says, “Go Army.”&nbsp; I used to say, “Go Navy,” but then my son got a Bronze Star in the Army and I decided I couldn’t say it anymore.&nbsp; So I just say, “Go American forces.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to recognize &#8212; he couldn’t be here today, but Marty Walsh, the Secretary of the &#8212; of Labor.&nbsp; And he’s doing an outstanding job helping to lead this effort alongside Pete &#8212; Secretary Buttigieg.</p>



<p>And, you know, I want to welcome members of Congress who are here today as well.&nbsp; Tammy, how are you, Tammy?&nbsp; Good to see you.&nbsp; Tammy Baldwin, by the way.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, Congressman Pete DeFazio.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Laura Underwood &#8212; where’s Laura?&nbsp; There she is, right there &#8212; right in front.&nbsp; Good to see you, Laura.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I want to particularly shout out to the new President of the Teamsters, Sean O’Brien.&nbsp; Stand up, man; I want them to see you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; As &#8212; as they say in parts of Wilmington, Delaware, “These guys brung me to the dance” 35 years ago &#8212; 40 years ago.</p>



<p>And also, I want to say a quick hi to a pal.&nbsp; And you’ve been a pal.&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; thank you for being here and getting things done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, in addition to all that, there’s an outfit called &#8212; you’ve probably heard of them &#8212; the United Mine Workers.&nbsp; Yeah, well, you know, they got the president here too.&nbsp; Mr. President, where are you?&nbsp; Where is he sitting?&nbsp; He was here.&nbsp; A lot of truckers in the United Mine Workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At any rate, folks, I spend a lot of time talking about the economy and the record-breaking economic comeback we’re &#8212; experienced because of all of you sitting out there in those chairs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I want to talk with people who are &#8212; who are making the comeback possible &#8212; people like Maria, who you just heard from, and her son Roman who’s going there pretty soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all those truck drivers and their families that are here today, I want to thank you all to &#8212; you keep &#8212; what you’re doing to keep America moving, because that’s literally what you’re doing, especially these last two years helping carry the nation, literally, on your backs.</p>



<p>You learned, on Friday, the economy created 431,000 jobs in March.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; A record.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the course of my presidency, the economy has now created 7.9 million jobs.&nbsp; More jobs in the first 14 months than any President ever &#8212; (applause) &#8212; in large part of all of you.&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>Unemployment is at 3.6 percent, down from 6.4 when we took office.&nbsp; The fastest decline in unemployment at the start of any presidential term ever recorded.</p>



<p>And after a long stretch, Americans are back to work.&nbsp; Americans are back to work.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>An economy has gone from being on the mend to being on the move.&nbsp; And the economy we’re building &#8212; we’re building a strong economy, one where hardworking Americans can live with dignity, support their families, build a better life, and a better life for their children as well.</p>



<p>All of you here today are people our economy should be built around because you all &#8212; you all are the people who literally make it run.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; You literally make it run.</p>



<p>I have nothing against investment bankers.&nbsp; They could all retire and nothing much would change.&nbsp; You all quit, everything comes to a halt.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; Come to a literal halt.</p>



<p>During the pandemic, a lot of Americans have been introduced to a term you all know well &#8212; and Pete used it: supply chains.&nbsp; A simple term.&nbsp; A supply chain is a journey &#8212; the journey of a product to get to a customer’s doorstep.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it is.</p>



<p>And during the pandemic, those chains were interrupted.&nbsp; Factory closures around the world &#8212; not just in the United States, around the world &#8212; caused backups and delays because of COVID.</p>



<p>At the same time, because of the strength and speed of our recovery, Americans had more money in their pockets than they had in a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During the pandemic, they wanted to spend that money not on restaurants or vacations, which are now coming back as well, but on hard goods.</p>



<p>They wanted home improvements, televisions, and automobiles &#8212; things that had to be transported.&nbsp; The very products that slow down by disruptions of the supply chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Demand was high.&nbsp; Supply was interrupted.&nbsp; And the recipe for higher prices and long delays &#8212; that’s exactly what we saw not only here, but all around the world.</p>



<p>So, we knew we needed every tool at our disposal to address the problem.&nbsp; And the best way to do it was to invest in people who make the supply chain run.&nbsp; Trucking moves about 70 percent &#8212; about 70 percent of all the goods in this country.&nbsp; Seventy percent.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And truck drivers are facing real challenges.&nbsp; The average driver waits four and a half hours for their truck to be loaded and unloaded during an eleven-hour shift &#8212; and 40 percent of their day.&nbsp; And often, they don’t get paid for that wait time.</p>



<p>Back in 1978, the average truck driver&#8217;s pay was $34 &#8212; was $34 an hour in today’s dollars.&nbsp; Last year, it was $25 an hour, nearly a 30 percent decline.&nbsp; In this iconic American industry, it’s getting harder and harder to raise a family with dignity and pride that you deserve.&nbsp; And it’s no surprise so many drivers left their jobs.</p>



<p>The workforce is getting older &#8212; not that I am, but they are.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I used to drive a truck; it&#8217;s a long story.&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>It’s getting har- &#8212; and I thought I was going to get to drive one of these suckers today, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; anyway, it&#8217;s another story, too.</p>



<p>But, look, it&#8217;s getting harder and harder to recruit new drivers, particularly women and people of color, to an industry that this nation and our economy desperately needs at full strength.</p>



<p>The good news is that since I took office, we’ve begun to turn things around.&nbsp; In fact &#8212; and 2021 was the best year for trucking employment since 1994.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There are now 35,000 more trucking jobs than there were before the pandemic.</p>



<p>But we all know that we need to move faster getting more people working in this industry, in jobs they can rely on and raise a family on.</p>



<p>That’s why last December we brought together industry and labor to tackle the problem facing drivers, and we listened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when we heard that there were long wait times in many states for people wanting to get their commercial driver’s licenses &#8212; their CDLs &#8212; we took action.&nbsp; We provided technical assistance as well as $57 million in federal funds to help states issue these CDLs faster.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’m proud to report: Because of Pete and others, so far in 2022, we’re issuing CDLs at double the rate of last year &#8212; 120,000 in January and February alone.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also know that the key ingredient to getting and keeping more drivers was increasing training programs like the registered apprenticeships approved by the Department of Labor &#8212; programs that allow aspiring drivers to learn while &#8212; earn while they learn, while making this essential job more attractive for potential drivers regardless of age, background, and gender.</p>



<p>The program has proven to be &#8212; improve safety and better working conditions and better pay and benefits.</p>



<p>Typically, it takes about eight months to create a registered apprenticeship program.&nbsp; But because of Pete and others and this Department of Labor, we were able to cut the red tape.&nbsp; And now it takes as little as two days.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>As a result, in the last 90 days, 100 major employers have launched new registered apprenticeship programs &#8212; UPS, Domino’s, Pepsi, Albertsons, and more; along with the trade associations, like the American Trucking Association, the National Minority Trucking Association, the Food Industry Association, and others.</p>



<p>What that all adds up to is a strong foundation for the work ahead: a pipeline of hardworking men and women from all backgrounds, highly trained and highly motivated to get behind the wheel, including a whole lot of veterans, thanks to the veterans trucking initiative known as “Taskforce Movement” by Patrick Murphy &#8212; led by Patrick Murphy.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, by the way, I&#8217;d say, parenthetically: If you can handle a tank, if you can handle an armored personnel carrier, you sure in hell can handle one of these suckers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And an awful lot of well-known people also.</p>



<p>The idea &#8212; I remember &#8212; I&#8217;m going to just digress for one second.&nbsp; I &#8212; I got a commercial license because my dad used to run an automobile agency.&nbsp; And I used to have to go up to the body shop up in Philadelphia from Wilmington. &nbsp;And when they&#8217;d order a trailer or a cab, I&#8217;d just &#8212; they’d sell the cab.&nbsp; And so, I had to have a licensed to be able to drive it up and back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, during the truckers strike years later, when I was a young senator, I was &#8212; there was a guy who ran steel from Deemer Steel out to Ohio.&nbsp; And so, I decided to ride out with him to see what it was like in the strike.&nbsp; And I was driving, going through Shiloh, Ohio, and &#8212; and we &#8212; he was &#8212; his handle was “Big 10”.&nbsp; And I remember every &#8212; all the trucks stops were being blockaded at the time during the strike.</p>



<p>And he &#8212; he called, and he said, “Big 10 wanting to come in.”&nbsp; I forget exactly how he said it.&nbsp; And the &#8212; and the only woman truck driver I ever knew I met that day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She said, “This is Big Mama.&nbsp; No room.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Swear to God, true story.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Swear to God.&nbsp; He said, “I’ve got a United States senator driving my truck.”&nbsp; She said, “I got the damn president in mine.&nbsp; So what?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’ll never forget that.&nbsp; I was a very powerful guy.</p>



<p>Anyway &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; that was the first woman trucker I met.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But look, the Labor and &#8212; Labor and Transportation Departments are working closely with industry to tackle issues facing women in trucking, recruit and retrain more women drivers so we can draw more Americans to work with increased wages, reduced wait times, and improved safety, and so much more.</p>



<p>Folks, there’s a heck of a lot more we have to do.&nbsp;&nbsp; A lot more we have to do.&nbsp; Secretary Buttigieg laid out some of the steps we’re taking to make these jobs more attractive for more Americans.&nbsp; And it’s all centered around listening to you, the drivers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, you’ve got to keep it &#8212; we’ve got to keep it going.&nbsp; We’re building a better economy around American manufacturing and American supply chains.&nbsp; And thanks to the Infrastructure Law &#8212; and it wasn’t my law; it was a bipartisan &#8212; one of the few great bipartisan things we&#8217;ve done this year &#8212; we’re making the largest investment in American roads and bridges since, literally, the creation of the Interstate Highway System.&nbsp; And that means a bright future for American trucking.</p>



<p>This &#8212; this country will be counting on you more than it ever has.&nbsp; So we should be able to &#8212; you should be able to count on us to keep investing in you and your families.&nbsp; That’s exactly what we’re going to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m looking forward to all of the progress we’re going to make together.&nbsp; And I want to thank you all.&nbsp; Thank you for being here.&nbsp; Thank you for what you do.&nbsp; Thank your families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And may God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>   2:20 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the COVID-&#8288;19 Bipartisan Funding&#160;Proposal</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/04/statement-from-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-covid-19-bipartisan-funding-proposal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 21:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are grateful for the Senate’s work on a bipartisan plan to help meet some of the country’s COVID-19 response needs.  The Administration requested $22.5 billion to continue to provide critical protections like vaccines, boosters, treatments, and tests to people here at home and for help putting shots in arms around the world. Every dollar&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We are grateful for the Senate’s work on a bipartisan plan to help meet some of the country’s COVID-19 response needs.  The Administration requested $22.5 billion to continue to provide critical protections like vaccines, boosters, treatments, and tests to people here at home and for help putting shots in arms around the world. Every dollar we requested is essential and we will continue to work with Congress to get all of the funding we need. But time is of the essence.  We urge Congress to move promptly on this $10 billion package because it can begin to fund the most immediate needs, as we currently run the risk of not having some critical tools like treatments and tests starting in May and June.  We will continue to work with Congress to fund our remaining domestic needs and will work with Senators Schumer and Romney – and others &#8212; to build bipartisan support for a package to fund our global COVID-19 response.  We must continue our work to vaccinate the world both because it is the right thing to do, and also, because as it is critical to reducing the risk of new variants, which in turn is critical to the safety of the American people.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/04/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-61/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 20:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Naz Durakoğlu, of New Jersey, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Legislative Affairs), vice Mary Elizabeth Taylor, resigned. Dean R. Thompson, of Maryland, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Nepal. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Naz Durakoğlu, of New Jersey, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Legislative Affairs), vice Mary Elizabeth Taylor, resigned.</p>



<p>Dean R. Thompson, of Maryland, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Nepal.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden After Marine One&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/04/remarks-by-president-biden-after-marine-one-arrival-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 16:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50496</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fort Lesley J. McNairWashington, D.C. 10:30 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I have one comment to make before I start the day.&#160; You may remember I got criticized for calling Putin a war criminal.&#160; Well, the truth of the matter &#8212; you saw what happened in Bucha.&#160; This warrants him &#8212; he is a war criminal.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Fort Lesley J. McNair<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>10:30 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I have one comment to make before I start the day.&nbsp; You may remember I got criticized for calling Putin a war criminal.&nbsp; Well, the truth of the matter &#8212; you saw what happened in Bucha.&nbsp; This warrants him &#8212; he is a war criminal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we have to gather the information, we have to continue to provide Ukraine with the weapons they need to continue the fight, and we have to get all the detail so this can be an actual &#8212; have a wartime trial.</p>



<p>This guy is brutal.&nbsp; And what&#8217;s happening in Bucha is outrageous, and everyone’s seen it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll &#8212; I&#8217;ll &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you agree that it&#8217;s genocide?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I think it is a war crime.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are you going to do about it, sir?&nbsp; Are you going to do more sanctions on Russia?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m seeking more sanctions, yes.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll have time to announce that to you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you actually hold Putin accountable, though?&nbsp; You called him a war criminal.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He should be held accountable.</p>



<p>QCan you actually hold him accountable without sanctions?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, no &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What else can you do?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no &#8212; go &#8212; go &#8212; the war crimes tri- &#8212; yes, I’m going to continue to add sanctions.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What kind of sanctions, Mr. President?&nbsp; What are you thinking?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ll let you know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>10:31 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-&#8288;Harris Action Plan for Building Better School&#160;Infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/04/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-action-plan-for-building-better-school-infrastructure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris to Outline Actions for Bolstering Clean School Infrastructure and Transportation to Support Student Learning and Health&#160;Administration Launches $500 million Grant Program from Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Program to Save Schools Money with Energy Upgrades Today, Vice President Kamala Harris is announcing the&#160;Biden-Harris Action Plan for Building Better School Infrastructure&#160;to upgrade our public schools&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Harris to Outline Actions for Bolstering Clean School Infrastructure and Transportation to Support Student Learning and Health</em><br>&nbsp;<br><em>Administration Launches $500 million Grant Program from Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Program to Save Schools Money with Energy Upgrades</em></p>



<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris is announcing the&nbsp;<strong>Biden-Harris Action Plan for Building Better School Infrastructure</strong>&nbsp;to upgrade our public schools with modern, clean, energy efficient facilities and transportation—delivering health and learning benefits to children and school communities, saving school districts money, and creating good union jobs. The action plan activates the entire federal government in leveraging investments from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and American Rescue Plan to advance solutions including energy efficiency retrofits, electric school buses, and resilient design.<br><br>The&nbsp;<a href="https://k12.designprinciples.org/">science of learning and development</a>&nbsp;has shown that students need school environments filled with safety, belonging, and health to learn and thrive. Yet many schools rely on outdated heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC) systems that make classrooms less comfortable and may pose health risks to students and teachers exposed to contaminants or particles in the air that can trigger allergies or asthma attacks and potentially spread infectious diseases – including COVID-19. Dirty diesel buses pose additional health risks for students on board and the neighborhoods they travel through — and exhaust from idling buses can pollute the air around schools.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/iaq-schools/reference-guide-indoor-air-quality-schools">Studies show</a>&nbsp;that poor air quality inside classrooms takes a toll on student concentration and performance, and diesel exhaust exposure is linked to increased school absences. Reducing this pollution will provide better health and educational outcomes — particularly in low-income communities and communities of color that have long faced underinvestment and the burden of high pollution.<br><br>The action plan will save schools and taxpayers money. Public K-12 districts spend roughly $8 billion a year on energy bills — the second largest expense after teacher salaries. Energy efficiency improvements to HVAC systems, lighting, insulation, and other energy upgrades can not only protect the health of our children, but also unlock significant savings to go toward students and learning. Off-the-shelf improvements can provide energy savings of 10 to 30 percent and broader upgrades can unlock even more savings for years to come – all while creating opportunities for good paying union jobs for electricians, carpenters, painters, sheet metal workers, plumbers and pipefitters, and more.<br><br>The Administration is seizing the opportunity to align classrooms with the science of learning and development to improve educational equity and environmental justice. The new actions build on President Biden signing the American Rescue Plan into law one year ago, which helped reopen more than 99% of schools with resources to put in place critical health and safety measures like ventilation improvements to make in-person learning safe and accessible for students and educators.<br><br>The Biden-Harris Action Plan for Building Better School Infrastructure will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Invest in More Efficient, Energy-Saving School Buildings:&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Energy (DOE) is launching a $500 million grant program through President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to make public schools more energy efficient. This new program will lower energy costs, improve air quality, and prioritize schools most in need, enabling schools to focus more resources on student learning.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Improve Classroom Air Quality through the American Rescue Plan:&nbsp;</strong>The Administration is supporting states, school districts, and local communities in leveraging American Rescue Plan Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief resources to address school infrastructure needs—like repairing, upgrading, or replacing of ventilation systems; purchasing air filters and portable air cleaning devices; and fixing doors and windows so that schools can stay open for in-person learning. Additionally, the Department of Treasury will soon release additional information to help school districts understand how they can use State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds for a range of air quality and other school facility improvements, including energy efficiency.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Help Schools Access Resources and Best Practices:&nbsp;</strong>The White House is releasing a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/White-House-School-Infrastructure-Toolkit-04.04.22.pdf">toolkit</a>&nbsp;to help schools and school districts access available funding, as well as technical assistance opportunities and planning tools to help schools improve air quality, energy efficiency, and more. This new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/White-House-School-Infrastructure-Toolkit-04.04.22.pdf">toolkit</a>&nbsp;will further support school participation in the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/17/fact-sheet-biden-administration-launches-effort-to-improve-ventilation-and-reduce-the-spread-of-covid-19-in-buildings/">Clean Air in Buildings Challenge</a>, which the Administration recently launched to reduce the spread of COVID-19 and improve indoor air quality in buildings of all kinds, including schools. The Department of Energy is also announcing the inaugural honorees of the Efficient and Healthy Schools Campaign, which provides technical assistance to school districts seeking to implement high-impact indoor air quality and efficiency improvements that will reduce energy bills and improve student and teacher health. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Expand Clean and Safe School Transportation:&nbsp;</strong>The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), with support from the Department of Energy (DOE), is releasing&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/cleanschoolbus/prepare-clean-school-bus-funding">new online resources</a>&nbsp;to help school districts and other eligible recipients prepare for the $5 billion Clean School Bus Program created by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law—with the first opportunity to fund clean and electric buses opening later this spring. The DOE is working closely with the EPA to develop targeted technical assistance programs that assist school districts in implementing clean and electric buses effectively into their fleets–starting with a technical assistance video series on electric buses. To support projects that help students safely walk and bike to school, the Department of Transportation (DOT) has provided state and local governments with&nbsp;<a href="https://safety.fhwa.dot.gov/hsip/legislation_guidance/">new guidance</a>&nbsp;to access $90 billion in available federal funding, including Bipartisan Infrastructure Law programs.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Support for Rural, Tribal, and Puerto Rican Schools:&nbsp;</strong>The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) is announcing its full commitment to use its array of rural development loan and grant programs to support electric school bus acquisition, charging station infrastructure, energy efficiency investments at schools, and broadband and distance learning in rural school districts – to accelerate the shift from dirty fuel sources toward school facilities and vehicles powered by clean electricity. DOE is partnering with the Department of the Interior’s Bureau of Indian Education (BIE) to improve the state of our federally-operated schools. And the Administration’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/20/readout-of-the-first-meeting-of-the-white-house-working-group-on-puerto-rico/">Working Group on Puerto Rico</a>&nbsp;has prioritized supporting school reconstruction.</li></ul>



<p>Today’s announcements build on ongoing efforts to support students, including the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/16/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-lead-pipe-and-paint-action-plan/">Biden-Harris Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan</a>&nbsp;to reduce lead exposure in 400,000 schools and child care facilities and the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2021/12/02/delivering-on-justice40/">Justice40 Initiative</a>, which agencies are implementing to deliver 40 percent of the benefits of federal climate and clean energy investments to disadvantaged communities.</p>



<p><strong>Investments to Improve School Energy Efficiency and Indoor Air Quality</strong></p>



<p>The Administration is advancing a suite of investments to upgrade our K-12 public school facilities, many of which face maintenance backlogs and are long overdue for new equipment. While teachers and education leaders have long raised concerns about the level of comfort and air quality in our classrooms, the pandemic has laid bare disparities in access to healthy facilities, including modern, efficient, and clean HVAC systems. Outdated, inefficient buildings also saddle underserved school districts with higher energy bills and generate significant greenhouse gas emissions, keeping them in a cycle of underfunding operations and overpaying maintenance costs. This Action Plan will help schools make facility improvements that simultaneously deliver health protections, savings, and climate benefits.<br><br>Today, the Department of Energy (DOE) released a <strong>Request for Information to launch its new $500 million grant program for energy improvements at public school facilities, </strong>funded by President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The projects funded by these grants will improve the quality of the air our students and educators breathe while reducing energy costs and freeing up local funds to invest more in education. These grants can support comprehensive energy efficiency audits and building retrofits, HVAC and lighting upgrades, clean energy installation, and more—along with training to help staff maintain these improvements over the long-term. DOE will prioritize projects in rural and high-poverty schools, and support leveraging of additional private, philanthropic, and public funding to maximize the benefits of these grants. In step with the Administration’s priority to create good union jobs accessible to all workers, the DOE will work to promote high quality labor and equity standards into school improvement grants. The RFI solicits input from schools and other stakeholders on important design considerations to ensure the grant program achieves the greatest reach and impact.<br><br>The Administration is also leveraging the American Rescue Plan, which President Biden signed into law one year ago, to address a range of health and safety issues in schools. The <strong>American Rescue Plan’s Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief program has provided $122 billion </strong>to states and districts to help schools stay open and address the significant academic and mental health needs of students resulting from the pandemic. Additionally, the <strong>American Rescue Plan also includes</strong> <strong>$350 billion in State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds</strong> to support a wide range of pandemic response and recovery efforts, including school improvements to ventilation and building energy systems that reduce energy costs and support healthy environments. And, according to <a href="https://www.future-ed.org/financial-trends-in-local-schools-covid-aid-spending/">independent analysis</a>, school districts are already planning to spend $15 billion of these funds to address facilities issues impacting student and staff health and safety, such as improving indoor air quality. <strong>The Department of Treasury will soon provide additional clarity </strong>to help recipients of State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds understand how they can partner with local education agencies to use more of these funds for building upgrades and construction, including pre-project development costs, such as building assessments, energy audits, and feasibility studies. The Department of Education continues to outline how states and districts can use its funds for repairs and renovations, including improving indoor air quality through HVAC upgrades and door and window replacement, and ensuring clean drinking water in schools.</p>



<p><strong>New Resources and Recognition to Support Schools</strong><br>To help schools access funding sources and technical assistance opportunities, <strong>the White House is releasing a </strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/White-House-School-Infrastructure-Toolkit-04.04.22.pdf"><strong>toolkit mapping out available resources across the federal government for school infrastructure upgrades</strong></a>. By compiling resources and programs from across the federal government, this toolkit will help state and local officials find the support they need for building assessments, air quality improvements, energy efficiency upgrades, lead removal, resilience planning, and more. It builds on the Administration’s priority on improving indoor air quality through the <a href="https://www.epa.gov/indoor-air-quality-iaq/clean-air-buildings-challenge">Clean Air in Buildings Challenge</a>, to help reduce the spread of COVID-19 in buildings and to deliver better health outcomes and protection for all building occupants.<br><br>To support and uplift schools and districts undertaking this critical work, <strong>the Administration is announcing the first round of honorees as part of the </strong><a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/buildings/efficient-and-healthy-schools"><strong>Efficient and Healthy Schools Campaign</strong></a><strong>,</strong> which provides technical assistance to school districts seeking to implement high-impact indoor air quality and efficiency improvements that will reduce energy bills and improve student and teacher health. This innovative campaign has a goal of reaching 5,000 schools by the end of 2022. To date, 26 school districts across 16 states have joined or are prepared to join the campaign—representing over 1,500,000 students in 2,600 individual schools—more than half way toward the campaign’s goal.<br><br>Today, the Campaign announced its first round of awards to eight school districts for their best-in-class efforts across four categories: Efficient HVAC Technologies, Inspection &amp; maintenance, Ongoing Monitoring &amp; Analytics, and Team Approach to Support Strategic Investments. The inaugural honorees include:</p>



<ul><li>Adams 12 Five Star Schools, CO&nbsp;</li><li>Boulder Valley School District, CO</li><li>Charleston County School District, SC</li><li>Columbia Public Schools, MO</li><li>Davis School District, UT</li><li>Greenville County Schools, SC</li><li>Mariposa County Unified School District, CA</li><li>Newark Board of Education, NJ</li></ul>



<p>DOE is also accelerating a range of grants, technical assistance, and lending to support schools along each step of the school improvement process. These efforts include the&nbsp;<a href="https://betterbuildingssolutioncenter.energy.gov/challenge/sector/k-12-school-districts">Better Buildings Challenge and its K-12 Sector</a>&nbsp;partnerships; DOE’s new tool—<a href="https://eprojectbuilder.lbl.gov/about">eProject eXpress</a>—that can support state and local governments and K-12 schools in project management for energy saving performance contracts, and help leverage financing to maximize impact; and DOE’s Loan Programs Office&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/lpo/renewable-energy-efficient-energy-projects-loan-guarantees">Renewable Energy and Efficient Energy Solicitation</a>&nbsp;that can be accessed by schools to provide up to $3 billion in loan guarantees for retrofit projects.<br><br>And to ensure that schools are supported in creating healthy, safe, sustainable, 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century learning environments,<strong>&nbsp;the Department of Education is proposing a new Office of Infrastructure and Sustainability</strong>, as part of the President’s FY2023 Budget.&nbsp;This office would oversee a proposed National Clearinghouse on School Infrastructure and Sustainability and administer the ongoing U.S. Department of Education&nbsp;<a href="https://www2.ed.gov/programs/green-ribbon-schools/index.html">Green Ribbon Schools recognition award</a>. The proposed National Clearinghouse on School Infrastructure and Sustainability would provide technical assistance and training to state and local education agencies on issues related to educational facility planning, design, financing, construction, improvement, operation, and maintenance, including green building design and operation practices consistent with the Administration’s commitment to tackling the climate crisis. The Clearinghouse would also develop resources and assemble best practices on issues related to ensuring equitable access to healthy, educationally adequate and environmentally and fiscally sustainable public-school facilities and grounds. To set the stage for this new office, the Department of Education recently named a Special Advisor for Infrastructure and Sustainability to spearhead agency-wide consideration of how existing programs might support school sustainability and infrastructure.<br><br>These actions build on the Biden-Harris Administration’s&nbsp;<strong>Clean Air in Buildings Challenge</strong>, which calls on all building owners and operators, schools, colleges and universities, and organizations of all kinds to adopt key strategies to improve indoor air quality in their buildings and reduce the spread of COVID-19.&nbsp;It serves as a call to action to assess indoor air quality and make ventilation and air filtration improvements to help keep occupants safe. The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) published a best practices&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/system/files/documents/2022-03/508-cleanairbuildings_factsheet_v5_508.pdf">guide</a>&nbsp;for improving indoor air quality and reducing the risk of spreading dangerous airborne particles.<br><br><strong>Clean and Safe School Transportation</strong><br>School buses safely transport more than 25 million children every day across America. However, diesel exhaust from buses produces particulate matter and other pollutants that can cause lung damage and aggravate asthma and other health problems in children. Through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, the Environmental Protection Agency and the Department of Transportation, with support and technical assistance from the Department of Energy, are making historic investments in cleaner school buses and safer school transportation routes.</p>



<p>Today, the Environmental Protection Agency is building public awareness for the new $5 billion&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/cleanschoolbus/">Clean School Bus Program</a>&nbsp;created by President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. Throughout the next month,&nbsp;<strong>EPA will&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.epa.gov/cleanschoolbus/prepare-clean-school-bus-funding"><strong>regularly post new online resources and webinars</strong></a><strong>&nbsp;for the Clean School Bus Program to help school districts&nbsp;</strong>and other eligible recipients prepare for the first round of applications. These resources build upon EPA’s public education and outreach effort, to gather ideas and increase awareness within communities and school districts, particularly for lower-resourced schools—in support of the President’s Justice40 commitment.</p>



<p><strong>The Department of Transportation is helping communities take advantage of funding to support safer routes to schools made available by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</strong>.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/mission/health/Safe-Routes-to-School-Programs">The Safe Routes to School</a>&nbsp;(SRTS) program at DOT helps communities plan, design, and construct infrastructure projects that increase healthy transportation choices and substantially improve the ability of students to walk and bicycle safely to school—particularly in communities underserved by safe transportation options. Since 2015, the SRTS program has supported over $1 billion in safe school route projects benefiting nearly 7 million students across more than 17,000 schools—a third of which were in disadvantaged communities and Title I schools.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law expanded the eligibility of the SRTS program to schools through 12<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;grade and added eligibility for safe school route projects through the nearly $17 billion-per-year Highway Safety Improvement Program—including for use in training and education.</p>



<p><strong>Support for Rural, Tribal, and Puerto Rican Schools</strong><br>The U.S. Department of Agriculture announced today a new commitment to support school facility and vehicle electrification, including school buses. In support of this commitment,&nbsp;<a href="https://go.usa.gov/xzzhy">USDA released a new guidance</a>&nbsp;that informs how Rural Development programs can support rural electric cooperatives to advance electrification projects for schools and other public facilities and vehicles.</p>



<p>These funding and assistance programs can support rural utilities like those in <a href="https://be-league.org/buses" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a newly formed Electric Cooperative School Bus Initiative </a>, a collaboration of more than 350 local distribution cooperatives across 32 states, providing educational and administrative support to help rural communities access funding for electric school buses and school bus infrastructure.</p>



<p>Additionally, DOE is partnering with the Department of the Interior’s Bureau of Indian Education (BIE) to improve the state of our federally-operated schools. Aligning with the President’s Justice 40 Initiative, the DOE Federal Energy Management Program (FEMP) is assisting BIE to initiate a set of pilot assessments in Tribal schools for energy efficiency and indoor air quality projects.</p>



<p>The Administration’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/20/readout-of-the-first-meeting-of-the-white-house-working-group-on-puerto-rico/">Working Group on Puerto Rico</a>&nbsp;has prioritized supporting school reconstruction efforts on the island. Agencies collaborated&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2022/01/21/us-departments-homeland-security-and-education-release-toolkit-federal-resources.">on a toolkit</a>&nbsp;in both English and Spanish outlining federal resources available to help Puerto Rico recover and rebuild safe, healthy and modernized school facilities. Agencies have also provided technical assistance to Puerto Rican officials on how they can leverage multiple funding streams to rebuild, repair, and modernize their schools.<br><br><strong>Support for Training and Workforce Development</strong><br>School improvements provide critical training opportunities for building an effective workforce. Large school projects often last multiple years and draw upon a large mix of trades. This continuity of training and employment makes them ideal opportunities for pre-apprenticeship and apprenticeship programs that lead directly to good-paying careers. And when done alongside the President’s Justice40 Initiative, these investments will prioritize under-resourced schools while also investing in communities that can benefit from long-term training and employment.</p>



<p><strong>The Department of Labor’s Good Jobs Initiative is supporting federal agency partners as they embed job quality and equity policies into their infrastructure investments.</strong>&nbsp; The Good Jobs Initiative is supporting federal agency partners as they work to leverage their infrastructure investments to provide meaningful opportunities for all communities to enter good paying union careers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The wide array of federal offerings can support initiatives such as the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cjnrc.org/carbon-free-and-healthy-schools/">Carbon Free and Healthy Schools campaign</a>&#8211;which is led by labor unions in collaboration with students, parents, and climate advocates across the country&#8211;to create safe, healthy, and cost-effective school environments through building retrofits and solarization, while supporting strong labor standards and robust worker training opportunities. The campaign is currently working with school districts representing more than five million students across Texas, California,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.oneillinois.com/stories/2020/12/22/iea-joins-climate-jobs-illinois">Illinois</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.carbonfreehealthyschoolsnyc.org/">New York</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://ctclimateandjobs.org/carbon-free-healthy-schools/">Connecticut</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://climatejobsri.org/green-and-healthy-schools/">Rhode Island</a>, Michigan, Maine, and Wisconsin, with more state campaigns in formation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration’s Unprecedented Actions to Expand and Improve Trucking&#160;Jobs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/04/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-unprecedented-actions-to-expand-and-improve-trucking-jobs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since Day 1, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken on the supply chain disruptions and price increases resulting from the decades-long lack of investment in the nation’s goods movement supply chain. The Administration enacted the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to bring our infrastructure to the 21st century, worked with ports to clear the docks and gets good&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since Day 1, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken on the supply chain disruptions and price increases resulting from the decades-long lack of investment in the nation’s goods movement supply chain. The Administration enacted the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to bring our infrastructure to the 21<sup>st</sup> century, worked with ports to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/nec/briefing-room/2022/01/20/a-record-year-for-americas-ports-and-a-look-to-the-year-ahead/">clear the docks</a> and gets good moving, launched <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-new-initiative-to-improve-supply-chain-data-flow/">a pilot initiative</a> to create the digital infrastructure to connect key stakeholders in the supply chain, and more. The result is a modern goods movement system that boosts American competitiveness and cuts families’ costs.<br><br>Trucking moves 72 percent of goods in America and is a lynchpin in our goods movement supply chain. Trucking costs <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=NEHY">grew more than 20 percent last year</a> as a surge in demand for goods caused by the pandemic confronted a decline in trucking employment that preceded the pandemic. The low supply of drivers is driven by high turnover and low job quality. Turnover in trucking routinely <a href="https://www.trucking.org/news-insights/turnover-remained-unchanged-large-truckload-fleets-fourth-quarter#:~:text=For%20the%20full%20year%2C%20the,72%25%20in%20the%20previous%20year.">averages 90 percent</a> for some carriers and drivers <a href="https://transportation.house.gov/imo/media/doc/2021-11-17%20Hearing%20Testimony%20-%20David%20HC%20Correll%20UPDATED.pdf">spend about 40 percent of their workday</a> waiting to load and unload goods &#8211; &nbsp;hours that are typically unpaid. Many truckers are not directly employed and operate as independent small businesses, bearing the burden of leasing, gas, insurance, and maintenance costs themselves. These financial burdens cause many to leave the profession. Trucking also draws on an older, heavily male workforce—the median age is <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat18b.htm">four years higher</a> than the overall workforce and <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat18.htm">almost 90 percent</a> of the industry is men—which adds to its recruiting challenges.<br><br>Last December, the Administration confronted these challenges head on.&nbsp; The U.S. Department of Transportation and the U.S. Department of Labor <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/16/fact-sheet-the-biden-%E2%81%A0harris-administration-trucking-action-plan-to-strengthen-americas-trucking-workforce/">launched a Trucking Action Plan</a> to increase the supply of truck drivers by creating new pathways into the profession, cutting red tape to expand high quality training through Registered Apprenticeship, and laying the foundation for improving job quality to keep people in the profession.<br><br><strong>Major Achievements of Biden Effort to Expand and Improve Trucking Jobs:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Getting Americans Working in Better Trucking Jobs: Since President Biden took office, we have seen historic increases in trucking employment with 2021 registering as the best year for trucking employment growth since 1994 and December 2021-February 2022 as the best three-month stretch for long distance truck hiring since the 1990s. And frontline truckers’ real wages grew this year despite elevated inflation.<br></li><li>Cutting red-tape in Commercial Driver’s licensing: DOT gave states the tools to more than double new commercial driver’s license issuances in January and February 2022 compared to January and February 2021. States have issued more than 876,000 CDLs since January 2021.<br></li><li>Scaling Registered Apprenticeships in trucking to improve retention: Over 100 employers including Domino’s, Frito-Lay, and UPS launched Registered Apprenticeship programs in 90 days as DOL cut the amount of time it takes to a launch a program from months to as little as 48 hours. This could result in more than 10,000 additional apprentices.<br></li><li>Helping connect veterans to trucking careers: The trucking industry partnered with leading Veterans Service Organizations to launch <em>Task Force Movement: Life-Cycle Pathways for Veterans and Military into Trucking,</em> chaired by former Congressman and veteran Patrick Murphy, to support the recruitment and retention of veterans and military family members.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Since the launch of the plan in December, the Administration hosted seven listening sessions with over 100 participants. Continuing to listen and work with drivers is a pillar of the Administration’s work to address job quality in the DOL and DOT’s <em>Driving Good Jobs Initiative</em>. This initiative supports the trucking workforce by creating a task force on truck leasing arrangements, launching a Women of Trucking Advisory Board, and more. The Administration is also committed to addressing core job quality challenges from misclassification to hours of service to workplace safety.</p>



<p><strong>Getting Americans to Work in Better Trucking Jobs</strong><br>When President Biden took office, there were 30,000 fewer trucking jobs than in February 2020 and trucking employment had been falling even before that. But last year’s historic job growth across the economy resulted in 2021 registering as the best year for trucking job growth since 1994. Trucking employment now exceeds its pre-pandemic level by 35,000 and is higher than it was before it began to decline in 2019. Trucking employment growth over the last year was strongest in California where it exceeded 10 percent as well as Missouri, New Jersey, Ohio, and Washington where it exceeded 8 percent.</p>



<p>Long-distance truck driving has been the sector of trucking facing the most challenges, but we are now seeing fresh momentum there: December through February was the best three-month stretch for long-distancing trucking employment growth since the 1990s (data are currently only available through February).</p>



<p><strong>Cutting Red Tape: More than Doubling Commercial Driver’s License Processing Compared to 2021</strong><br>The Administration and U.S. Department of Transportation worked with states and Governors to accelerate CDL processing. DOT announced over $57 million in funding available to help states expedite CDLs, coordinated waivers, sent all 50 states a toolkit detailing specific actions to expedite licensing and worked hand-in-hand with states to address challenges. This resulted in a 112 percent increase in CDL processing in January and February 2022 compared to January and February 2021. States have issued more than 876,000 CDLs since January 2021.</p>



<p><strong>Scaling Apprenticeships: Moving the Market on How Truckers are Recruited, Trained, and Retained</strong><br>The Departments of Labor and Transportation launched the <a href="https://www.apprenticeship.gov/90-day-trucking-apprenticeship-challenge" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">90 Day Trucking Apprenticeship Challenge</a> to jumpstart this proven workforce strategy in trucking.</p>



<ul><li>Over 100 employers across trucking, food and grocery, and the oil and gas industries launched Registered Apprenticeship programs in 90 days. This includes Domino’s, Frito-Lay, UPS, states and national partners such as FASTPORT and the International Brotherhood of the Teamsters. This proven earn and learn model of workforce training will help employers and labor develop and retain a skilled workforce. Apprentices are already hitting the road with NFI and Total Transportation each hiring over 50 apprentices after launching new programs under the Apprenticeship Challenge.</li></ul>



<p>With these 100 employers and 7 trade associations now offering apprenticeships, we have nearly doubled the number of programs nationwide. This could, in turn, double the number of registered apprenticeships in 2022 and result in more than 10,000 new registered apprenticeships. As a point of comparison, annual trucking employment growth averaged 24,000 in the decade before the pandemic.</p>



<ul><li>Through the Apprenticeship Challenge, industry associations are now leading on the expansion of trucking apprenticeships and will be across the U.S. for years to come. This includes the American Trucking Association, the National Tank Truck Association, FMI (the Food Industry Association), the National Minority Trucking Association, the North American Punjabi Trucking Association, and the Truckload Carriers Association. And the Trucking Alliance, where every member carrier – among the largest long-haul companies that collectively employ more than 80,000 drivers &#8211; committed to offer truck driver registered apprenticeships in more than 200 apprenticeship locations in 36 states across the country.<br></li><li>Over 70 additional employers of all sizes and industry segments including Sysco and WM (Waste Management Inc.) are in the process of developing and launching apprenticeship programs.<br></li><li>DOT <a href="https://www.fmcsa.dot.gov/safedriver">launched the <em>Safe Driver Apprenticeship Pilot</em></a>, established through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, to safely connect American adults under the age of 21 to good-paying jobs in the trucking industry through Registered Apprenticeship.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Connecting Veterans to Trucking: Forging Partnerships to Help Veterans and Transitioning Service Members Enter Trucking</strong><br>The Administration worked with Veterans Service Organizations and related associations representing more than 4 million veterans and military family members to create ways for the industry to attract, train, place, and retain veterans in trucking jobs. This builds on the already strong connection between veterans and trucking as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2019/06/america-keeps-on-trucking.html#:~:text=At%20least%20one%20in%2010,a%20disability%20than%20other%20workers.">at least one in ten truckers are veterans</a>, which is double the rate of workers overall.</p>



<ul><li>The trucking industry partnered with leading Veterans Service Organizations like the Veterans of Foreign Wars, the American Legion, and the Union Veterans Council to launch <em>Task Force Movement: Life-Cycle Pathways for Veterans and Military into Trucking,</em> chaired by former Congressman and veteran Patrick Murphy, to support the recruitment and retention of veterans and military family members in trucking.<br></li><li>DOL partnered with FASTPORT to connect transitioning service members with apprenticeship and employment opportunities in the trucking industry, while DOD has committed to improve its credentialing programs for all service members—200,000 of whom <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/vets/programs/tap#:~:text=Every%20year%2C%20approximately%20200%2C000%20men,the%20military%20to%20civilian%20transition">transition out of military service each year</a>.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Continuing the <em>Driving Good Jobs</em> Initiative to Improve the Quality of Trucking Careers</strong><br>The Administration launched the new <em>Driving Good Jobs</em>&nbsp;initiative between DOL and DOT to commit to ongoing work to ensure trucking jobs are good jobs. Over the last 90 Days, the Administration held a number of listening sessions and engagements with drivers, unions and worker centers, industry, and advocates to ensure their voices and experiences are shaping future actions across key areas. The initiative will maintain a focus on:</p>



<ul><li><strong><em>Ensuring a safe and inclusive industry for women</em></strong>: Expanding opportunities for women in trucking, including by creating safe and inclusive work environments, is critical for increasing trucking supply. This includes:<br></li><li>The <em>Women of Trucking Advisory Board </em>will review and report on challenges facing woman drivers and those interested in joining the profession, such as on-the-job safety risks, mentorship, quality training, and opportunities for advancement. &nbsp;DOT <a href="https://www.fmcsa.dot.gov/newsroom/fmcsa-announces-call-applications-women-trucking-advisory-board">has begun</a> soliciting nominations.<br></li><li>The Administration is announcing a Day of Action in April, coinciding with Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month, to raise awareness and advocate for the prevention of sexual assault and sexual harassment in trucking. We will call on industry to commit to actions to promote safe training and work environments including zero-tolerance policies for sexual assault, improving sexual harassment training, and more.<br></li><li>The Administration is taking steps to ensure drivers entering the profession have a safe environment. DOT is now highlighting whistleblower and coercion protections for individuals facing sexual harassment and unsafe training conditions in its Entry Level Driver Training Program FAQ, which will be distributed to the 11,000 training providers. DOL is identifying employers in the trucking industry that have built supportive and inclusive workplaces for women and developing a “train the trainer” module for new Registered Apprenticeships sponsors who would receive a “seal of approval” upon completion to indicate training programs follow model gender-responsive training standards.<br></li><li><strong><em>Truck Leasing:</em></strong> DOT, DOL, and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), have stood up a Truck Leasing Task Force to address predatory truck leasing arrangements and identify actions that could make leases more equitable and transparent.&nbsp; The Task Force will review and report on<strong> c</strong>ommon leasing arrangements, arrangements that result in outsize and unanticipated debt for incoming drivers, and more.<br></li><li><strong><em>Detention Time and Compensation Studies: </em></strong>DOT released a scope of work to study driver detention time &#8212; the loading and unloading time that is often unpaid — and its impact on safety and compensation. This study will provide a detailed understanding of wait time’s effects on drivers across jurisdictions and industry sectors. DOT is also partnering with the National Academies of Science to study the impact various methods of driver compensation have on safety and retention.<br></li><li><strong><em>Truck Parking: </em></strong>Lack of truck parking across the country is about more than just inconvenience, it impacts safety and retention as exhausted drivers have nowhere to rest. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law (BIL) provides funding in at least five programs that states can use to address truck parking while requiring states to include an analysis of truck parking needs in their State freight plans, laying the foundation to understand local needs.<br></li><li><strong><em>Strengthening workplace safety and worker’s rights: </em></strong>DOL and DOT will continue coordination on critical truck driver labor, employment and safety protections, including releasing new guidance and information for drivers about their workplace rights, and employers about their obligations. Additionally, they are conducting joint outreach and education to employers and drivers about these rights and responsibilities under federal wage and hour law. &nbsp;The Administration is committed to addressing core challenges, such as worker misclassification, while expanding high-road employer practices to build a next generation trucking workforce.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Mass Shooting in&#160;Sacramento</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/03/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-mass-shooting-in-sacramento/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 01:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, America once again mourns for another community devastated by gun violence. In a single act in Sacramento, six individuals left dead and at least a dozen more injured. Families forever changed. Survivors left to heal wounds both visible and invisible. I want to thank the first responders in Sacramento, and all those across the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, America once again mourns for another community devastated by gun violence. In a single act in Sacramento, six individuals left dead and at least a dozen more injured. Families forever changed. Survivors left to heal wounds both visible and invisible.</p>



<p>I want to thank the first responders in Sacramento, and all those across the United States, who act every day to save lives. We know these lives were not the only lives impacted by gun violence last night. And we equally mourn for those victims and families who do not make national headlines.</p>



<p>But we must do more than mourn; we must act. That is why my Administration has taken historic executive action to implement my comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy — from standing up gun trafficking strike forces to helping cities across the country expand community violence interventions and hire more police officers for community policing.</p>



<p>We also continue to call on Congress to act. Ban ghost guns. Require background checks for all gun sales. Ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines. Repeal gun manufacturers’ immunity from liability. Pass my budget proposal, which would give cities more of the funding they need to fund the police and fund the crime prevention and intervention strategies that can make our cities safer. These are just a few of the steps Congress urgently needs to take to save lives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the Commissioning Commemoration Ceremony of the USS&#160;Delaware</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/02/remarks-by-president-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-commissioning-commemoration-ceremony-of-the-uss-delaware/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 19:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50432</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Port of WilmingtonWilmington, Delaware 11:50 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; My name is Joe Biden.&#160; I am Jill’s husband.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; It’s always a good day when I get to celebrate Delaware or spend time with service members and their families or introduce Jill.&#160; That’s a trifecta in my family.&#160; Governor Carney, Senator Carper, Senator Coons, Congresswoman&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Port of Wilmington<br>Wilmington, Delaware</p>



<p>11:50 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; My name is Joe Biden.&nbsp; I am Jill’s husband.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>It’s always a good day when I get to celebrate Delaware or spend time with service members and their families or introduce Jill.&nbsp; That’s a trifecta in my family.&nbsp;<br><br>Governor Carney, Senator Carper, Senator Coons, Congresswoman Blunt Rochester, Secretary Del Toro, Commander Horton, and all the crew members and families of the USS Delaware: I’m genuinely honored to be with you.&nbsp;<br><br>This latest ship to carry the USS Delaware is part of a long &#8212; the name &#8212; is part of a long tradition of serving our nation proudly and strengthening our nation’s security &#8212; the security of the United States of America &#8212; not just us, but our Allies and partners around the world as well.&nbsp; In fact, it’s already been doing that for some time.<br><br>So I just want to say thank you to everyone &#8212; to everyone involved in bringing this submarine into service: for those who laid the keel, for those sailors who will crew it and all &#8212; through all the years to come.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I want you to know that I’ve had an incredible partner.&nbsp; Jill has watched over the progress of the USS Delaware for years.<br><br>The daughter of a Navy signalman during World War Two, the mother of a member of the Delaware National Guard, the grandmother of children who experienced having their father deployed away from home for a year at a time.&nbsp; She always holds our military and their families in her heart.&nbsp; And that is not hyperbole; that’s real.<br><br>And I’m deeply proud of the work she is doing as First Lady with Joining Forces initiative she started with Michelle Obama when&nbsp;<s>she</s>&nbsp;[I] was Vice President and now carries on.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>As First Lady, she doesn’t &#8212; she’s been to more military installations around the world.&nbsp; She’s hosted more than 20 events for military families.&nbsp;<br><br>And she’s working &#8212; working to expand economic opportunities for military spouses who &#8212; by the way, in the words of Keats, “They also serve who only stand and wait.”&nbsp; And a submariner’s spouse stands and waits a lot.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And to help military kids for the support they need.&nbsp; And to make sure survivors and caregivers have the resources they deserve.<br><br>It’s a true passion for Jill and for our entire family.<br><br>As your Commander-in-Chief, I believe it is our sacred obligation as a nation to prepare and equip those troops that we send into harm’s way and to care for them and their families when they return home.&nbsp;<br><br>Now &#8212; now it’s my honor to introduce your First Lady, the sponsor of this great vessel, Jill Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I must admit, I never get tired of saying that.<br><br>As this ship’s sponsor, it’s my pleasure to welcome so many distinguished guests, and especially the Secretary of the Navy and Admirals Gilday and Caudle.<br><br>Commander Horton, Senior Chief Grammer, and the entire crew of the USS Delaware, it’s an honor to share this special day with you and your families.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I especially want to welcome some of my good friends from Delaware Boots on the Ground.&nbsp; You know, working with you connected me to a community of incredible military families.&nbsp; And all these years later, your work continues to inspire me, and I hope you can see your influence in our Joining Forces initiative.<br><br>So, where are my Delaware Boots on the Ground members today?&nbsp; Where are they sitting?&nbsp;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; They’re down.<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; They’re down.&nbsp; They’re down.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Wow, you’re down there?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The state of Delaware has loved the Bidens and cheered for us in most of our triumphant moments.&nbsp; It has carried us through the darkest times in our lives with a kindness that asks for nothing in return.&nbsp;<br><br>Delaware is family.<br><br>I’ll never forget the pride I felt when I stood at the Pentagon with Secretary of the Navy Ray Mabus, as well as you, Tom, to announce that I would be this ship’s sponsor.&nbsp; The USS Delaware was nothing more than a drawing then.&nbsp;<br><br>In 2016, my grandson, Hunter, joined me for the keel laying.&nbsp; And I think he felt the important connection that our family has to service then, and it was such a special moment for both of us.&nbsp;<br><br>Then, in 2018, I traveled to Newport News for the christening &#8212; seeing that simple drawing come to life in a shower of champagne.&nbsp; And I saw the truth of what Secretary Mabus said when it all began, that this vessel will always uphold the First State’s motto of “liberty and independence.”<br><br>So it’s difficult to put into words how much it means to be a part of the USS Delaware family.&nbsp; It is an incredible honor that I take seriously.&nbsp; I have cherished getting to know this community &#8212; from bowling with you at Newport News, to spending time with your families at Fort Groton for the holiday last December.<br><br>I’ve seen the heart of this crew, and it makes me feel both proud and humbled to be your shipmate for life.<br><br>Today’s celebration, like so many things in the past few years, is just a bit out of the ordinary.<br><br>At the beginning of the pandemic, the Delaware became the first ship ever commissioned while underwater, underway.&nbsp; It was a challenge to put a ship in service in the middle of a global pandemic, but you rose to the occasion as you always do.<br><br>Even if we are a little delayed in our celebration, today marks the beginning of an incredible journey: this ship’s long and faithful service to our country.<br><br>We may not know what’s to come, but we do know this: The challenges will be met with the honor, distinction, and valor of the 125 sailors who serve on her decks.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You will lead with unparalleled character and courage.<br><br>Of course, commissionings also mark a beginning for the families of the sailors, as well.&nbsp; Though the spouses and the children, parents and siblings with us today will stay on dry land, a piece of their hearts will sail away again and again.&nbsp; You too have a mission; you too serve our nation.<br><br>And as we look at this warship, we see its steel bulkheads and unbreakable hull.&nbsp; We see that it’s strong enough to withstand the most crushing pressure and slip silently through the deadliest waters.&nbsp;<br><br>And yet, so much of its power is unseen: the engines and sonar, the rudders that give it direction and purpose.<br><br>You, the families of this crew, may not wear a uniform, but with your love and support and with your sacrifice and devotion, you are as critical to our mission as the rudder is to this submarine.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Sailors, as you venture to new waters, know that the families who remain ashore will not be forgotten by your President or by me.&nbsp; We are working every day to honor the sacrifices that all of you make.<br><br>When our son, Beau, deployed to Iraq, another military mom shared with me a prayer &#8212; one I said every night while he was deployed.&nbsp; And it goes like this:<br>&nbsp;May the deep waters bring you more solace than strife.<br><br>May the friendships you find warm the cold walls of this vessel with laughter.&nbsp;<br><br>May you feel the glow of each goodbye embrace long after the horizon has lost the shore.&nbsp; May that light illuminate even the dimmest berthing.<br><br>May you always return home safely to the arms of the people who love you most.<br><br>And may God bless our troops and your families no matter where your journey takes you.&nbsp;<br><br>Amen.&nbsp;<br>Governor Carney, Senators Carper and Coons, Congresswoman Blunt Rochester, thank you for this celebration today.<br><br>And to our sailors: Thank you for your service and sacrifice.&nbsp; Thank you for allowing me to be your shipmate for life.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Everybody is here?&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR CHIEF PETTY OFFICER GRAMMER:&nbsp; Yes, ma’am.<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>Okay, shipmates: Officers and crew of the USS Delaware, man our ship and bring her to life!<br><br>USS DELAWARE CREW:&nbsp; Aye aye, ma’am!<br><br>12:01 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden Marking the Occasion of&#160;Ramadan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/statement-by-president-biden-marking-the-occasion-of-ramadan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50378</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I extend our best wishes to Muslim communities here in the United States and around the world on the beginning of the blessed month of Ramadan. For so many around the globe, including fellow Americans all across the country, this sacred month is a time for reflection and spiritual growth. Communities come together&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I extend our best wishes to Muslim communities here in the United States and around the world on the beginning of the blessed month of Ramadan.</p>



<p>For so many around the globe, including fellow Americans all across the country, this sacred month is a time for reflection and spiritual growth. Communities come together to practice forgiveness and resilience, to show compassion and generosity of spirit to those in need, of giving, and to celebrate the many blessings of life with loved ones.</p>



<p>This year, the simple act of breaking the fast will be an even more poignant reminder of the joys of health, family, and community.&nbsp; And we will continue to hold in our hearts all those families grieving a lost loved one who are facing an empty chair at the table.</p>



<p>As we continue to rebuild from the pandemic, we must also continue all of our efforts to stand with all those who are suffering and vulnerable around the world, those who are facing persecution or hardship.&nbsp; As the Holy Qur’an teaches, “whoever does even an atom’s weight of good will see its results.”</p>



<p>Every day, we see heartbreaking accounts of lost lives and the images of families and children struggling to survive. These tragedies remind us of our common humanity—and the common teaching of all great faiths, including Islam—that we should always do unto others as we would have done unto us. During this holy month, as Muslims everywhere honor God’s great mercy let us also renew our shared commitment to show kindness, mercy, and understanding to one another.&nbsp; Let us honor the simple yet profound truth that all people are equal in dignity and rights. That’s why the United States will continue to speak out for human rights everywhere&#8211;including for Uyghurs in China, Rohingya in Burma, and other Muslim communities all over the world.</p>



<p>From the Biden family to yours, and from the People’s House to your own homes, Jill and I wish you and your loved ones a blessed and prosperous month. <em>Ramadan Kareem</em>!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Diplomacy in the Middle East&#160;Region</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-diplomacy-in-the-middle-east-region/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 23:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50426</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we approach the Holy Month of Ramadan this weekend, we welcome the proactive diplomacy underway with our friends and partners across the Middle East region.  These efforts are central to President Biden’s agenda of forging a more secure and integrated Middle East region through a combination of deterrence against adversaries and diplomacy wherever possible&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As we approach the Holy Month of Ramadan this weekend, we welcome the proactive diplomacy underway with our friends and partners across the Middle East region.  These efforts are central to President Biden’s agenda of forging a more secure and integrated Middle East region through a combination of deterrence against adversaries and diplomacy wherever possible to reduce tensions and de-escalate ongoing conflicts.   </p>



<p>This approach was manifest this week.  </p>



<p>On Monday, Secretary of State Blinken attended a historic meeting in Israel together with the Foreign Ministers of Bahrain, Egypt, Israel, Morocco, and UAE.  This group of countries agreed to form permanent working groups with an aim to improve security and livelihoods across the region.  We now aim to further expand this circle of like-minded states.  Today’s conclusion of a Free Trade Agreement between the UAE and Israel exemplifies the new opportunities that are emerging in the region and upon which our administration is working to facilitate and strengthen.  </p>



<p>Secretary Blinken also visited Ramallah, where he reaffirmed President Biden’s commitment to doing all that we can to ensure Israelis and Palestinians share equal measures of freedom, dignity, security and prosperity.  Later in the week, King Abdullah II hosted the first-ever visit by an Israeli head of state, President Isaac Herzog, to Jordan.  We are grateful for the visionary role of these leaders and for the important role that King Abdullah II plays as custodian over the Holy Sites in Jerusalem, particularly over the upcoming Holy Days.</p>



<p>We also stand by our friends who face threats from terrorists, as seen over the past week in Israel.  President Biden spoke with Prime Minister Bennett on Wednesday and offered all appropriate assistance in the wake of these barbarous attacks against innocent civilian.  Our entire administration stand behind our Israeli allies as they work to confront threats to their citizens.  </p>



<p>Ending the war in Yemen has been a consistent focus of our administration over the past year.  Today, after months of relentless UN-led diplomacy backed by the United States and our partners, the UN’s Special Envoy to Yemen  announced a 60-day truce under which military operations will cease and restrictions on the flow of goods and people into and out of Yemen will ease.  President Biden welcomed this initiative and commended the leadership of Saudi Arabia and Oman in helping to finalize it.  We are hopeful that this initiative will establish a new foundation for political talks and a lasting settlement to end the suffering of the Yemeni people once and for all. </p>



<p>Even as we work to end the war in Yemen, there can be no doubt about President Biden’s commitment to supporting the defense of our partners, including the UAE and Saudi Arabia.  Earlier this week, the Treasury Department announced significant new sanction designations against Iran’s missile procurement network pursuant to Executive Order 13382, which targets weapons of mass destruction proliferators and their supporters.  We will continue to use all appropriate authorities to hold Iran and its proxy groups accountable for threats against our friends and partners.   </p>



<p>As this past week has shown, diplomacy is forging opportunities to secure a more peaceful and prosperous region even as we work to deter and counter threats against our partners and interests.  The United Stands will stand with its friends – and we are hopeful that this upcoming Holy Month of Ramadan will bring comfort and peace to peoples across the Middle East region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
