<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 21:28:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate, on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Central African&#160;Republic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-central-african-republic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 21:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.  In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the Central African Republic declared in Executive Order 13667 of May 12, 2014, is to continue in effect beyond May 12, 2022.<br><br>The situation in and in relation to the Central African Republic has been marked by a breakdown of law and order; intersectarian tension; the pervasive, often forced recruitment and use of child soldiers; and widespread violence and atrocities, including those committed by Kremlin-linked and Yevgeniy Prigozhin-affiliated entities such as the Wagner Group.  These dynamics threaten the peace, security, or stability of the Central African Republic and the neighboring states, and continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.  Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13667 with respect to the Central African Republic.                                </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely, <br>                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Stabilization of&#160;Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/09/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-stabilization-of-iraq-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 21:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52804</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On May 22, 2003, by Executive Order 13303, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701&#160;et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States posed by obstacles to the orderly reconstruction of Iraq, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On May 22, 2003, by Executive Order 13303, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701&nbsp;<em>et seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States posed by obstacles to the orderly reconstruction of Iraq, the restoration and maintenance of peace and security in the country, and the development of political, administrative, and economic institutions in Iraq.</p>



<p>The obstacles to the orderly reconstruction of Iraq, the restoration and maintenance of peace and security in the country, and the development of political, administrative, and economic institutions in Iraq continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp;For this reason, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13303, as modified in scope and relied upon for additional steps taken in&nbsp;Executive Order 13290 of March 20, 2003,&nbsp;Executive Order 13315 of August 28, 2003, Executive Order 13350 of July 29, 2004,&nbsp;Executive Order 13364 of November 29, 2004, Executive Order 13438 of July 17, 2007, and Executive Order 13668 of May 27, 2014, must continue in effect beyond May 22, 2022.&nbsp;&nbsp;Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency with respect to the stabilization of Iraq declared in Executive Order 13303.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register</em>&nbsp;and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,    <br>May 9, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate, on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Stabilization of&#160;Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-actions-of-the-government-of-syria-notice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 21:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker:&#160;(Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the&#160;Federal Register&#160;and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker:&nbsp;(Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register</em>&nbsp;and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp;&nbsp;In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register</em>&nbsp;for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the stabilization of Iraq declared in Executive Order 13303 of May 22, 2003 &#8212; as modified in scope and relied upon for additional steps taken in&nbsp;Executive Order 13290 of March 20, 2003,&nbsp;Executive Order 13315 of August&nbsp;28, 2003, Executive Order 13350 of July 29, 2004,&nbsp;Executive Order 13364 of November 29, 2004, Executive Order 13438 of July 17, 2007, and Executive Order 13668 of May&nbsp;27,&nbsp;2014 &#8212;&nbsp;is&nbsp;to continue in effect beyond May 22, 2022.</p>



<p>Obstacles to the orderly reconstruction of Iraq, the restoration and maintenance of peace and security in the country, and the development of political, administrative, and economic institutions in Iraq continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp;Therefore, I have determined that it is&nbsp;necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13303 with respect to the stabilization of Iraq.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sincerely,&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of The National Emergency with Respect to the Actions of the Government of&#160;Syria</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-actions-of-the-government-of-syria-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On May 11, 2004, pursuant to his authority under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) and the Syria Accountability and Lebanese Sovereignty Restoration Act of 2003 (Public Law 108-175), the President issued Executive Order 13338, in which he declared a national emergency with respect to the actions of the Government&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On May 11, 2004, pursuant to his authority under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) and the Syria Accountability and Lebanese Sovereignty Restoration Act of 2003 (Public Law 108-175), the President issued Executive Order 13338, in which he declared a national emergency with respect to the actions of the Government of Syria.&nbsp; The national emergency was modified in scope and relied upon for additional steps taken in Executive Order 13399 of April 25, 2006, Executive Order 13460 of February 13, 2008, Executive Order 13572 of April 29, 2011, Executive Order 13573 of May 18, 2011, Executive Order 13582 of August 17, 2011, Executive Order 13606 of April 22, 2012, and Executive Order 13608 of May 1, 2012.</p>



<p>The President took these actions to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by the actions of the Government of Syria in supporting terrorism, maintaining its then-existing occupation of Lebanon, pursuing weapons of mass destruction and missile programs, and undermining United States and international efforts with respect to the stabilization and reconstruction of Iraq.</p>



<p>The regime&#8217;s brutality and repression of the Syrian people, who have called for freedom and a representative government, not only endangers the Syrian people themselves, but also generates instability throughout the region.&nbsp; The Syrian regime&#8217;s actions and policies, including with respect to chemical weapons and supporting terrorist organizations, continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; As a result, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13338, which was expanded in scope in Executive Order 13572, and with respect to which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13399, Executive Order 13460, Executive Order 13573, Executive Order 13582, Executive Order 13606, and Executive Order 13608, must continue in effect beyond May 11, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared with respect to the actions of the Government of Syria.</p>



<p>In addition, the United States condemns the brutal violence and human rights violations and abuses of the Assad regime and its Russian and Iranian enablers. &nbsp;The United States calls on the Assad regime, and its backers, to stop its violent war against its own people, enact a nationwide ceasefire, facilitate the unhindered delivery of humanitarian assistance to all Syrians in need, and negotiate a political settlement in Syria in line with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2254.&nbsp; The United States will consider changes in policies and actions of the Government of Syria in determining whether to continue or terminate this national emergency in the future.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>May 9, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate, on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Actions of the Government of&#160;Syria</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-actions-of-the-government-of-syria-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52801</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.  In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the actions of the Government of Syria declared in Executive Order 13338<a> </a>of May 11, 2004 &#8212; as modified in scope and relied upon for additional steps taken in Executive Order 13399 of April 25, 2006, Executive Order 13460 of February 13, 2008, Executive Order 13572 of April 29, 2011, Executive Order 13573 of May 18, 2011, Executive Order 13582 of August 17, 2011, Executive Order 13606 of April 22, 2012, and Executive Order 13608 of May 1, 2012 &#8212; is to continue in effect beyond May 11, 2022.</p>



<p>The regime&#8217;s brutality and repression of the Syrian people, who have called for freedom and a representative government, not only endangers the Syrian people themselves, but also generates instability throughout the region.&nbsp; The Syrian regime&#8217;s actions and policies, including with respect to chemical weapons and supporting terrorist organizations, continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States. &nbsp;For these reasons, I&nbsp;have determined that it is necessary to continue in effect the&nbsp;national emergency declared in Executive Order 13338 with respect to Syria.</p>



<p>In addition, the United States condemns the brutal violence and human rights violations and abuses of the Assad regime and its Russian and Iranian enablers. &nbsp;The United States calls on the Assad regime, and its backers, to stop its violent war against its own people, enact a nationwide ceasefire, facilitate the unhindered delivery of humanitarian assistance to all Syrians in need, and negotiate a political settlement in Syria in line with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2254.&nbsp; The United&nbsp;States will consider changes in policies and actions of&nbsp;the Government of Syria in determining whether to continue or&nbsp;terminate this national emergency in the future.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Funding for COVID-&#8288;19 and&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-funding-for-covid-19-and-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ten days ago, I sent to Congress an urgent proposal to provide needed military, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  The plan was substantial in size, because the need is substantial:  we must stand by Ukraine as it defends itself from Russian aggression. The need is also urgent: I have nearly exhausted the resources given to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Ten days ago, I sent to Congress an urgent proposal to provide needed military, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  The plan was substantial in size, because the need is substantial:  we must stand by Ukraine as it defends itself from Russian aggression.<br> <br>The need is also urgent: I have nearly exhausted the resources given to me by a bipartisan majority in Congress to support Ukraine’s fighters.  This aid has been critical to Ukraine’s success on the battlefield.  We cannot allow our shipments of assistance to stop while we await further Congressional action.  We are approximately ten days from hitting this critical deadline. <br> <br>I am pleased that, in my conversations with Congressional leaders, there appears to be strong support for the proposal I submitted, and Congress is likely to pass it in substantially the form I proposed.  I urge them to do so, and again, I urge them to do so quickly. <br> <br>Previously, I had recommended that Congress take overdue action on much needed funding for COVID treatments, vaccines and tests, as part of the Ukraine Supplemental bill.  However, I have been informed by Congressional leaders in both parties that such an addition would slow down action on the urgently needed Ukrainian aid – a view expressed strongly by several Congressional Republicans.  We cannot afford delay in this vital war effort.  Hence, I am prepared to accept that these two measures move separately, so that the Ukrainian aid bill can get to my desk right away.<br> <br>However let me be clear:  as vital as it is to help Ukraine combat Russian aggression, it is equally vital to help Americans combat COVID.  Without timely COVID funding, more Americans will die needlessly.  We will lose our place in line for America to order new COVID treatments and vaccines for the fall, including next-generation vaccines under development, and be unable to maintain our supply of COVID tests.  In the fall, if we are hit by new variants, it will be too late to get the tools needed for protection – critical treatments that will be available in Europe, but not the United States.  In addition, our effort to help lower-income countries get COVID vaccines into arms will stall. <br> <br>So I call on Congress to pass the Ukrainian Supplemental funding bill immediately, and get it to my desk in the next few days.  And then, I urge Congress to move promptly on the COVID funding bill.  This virus knows no borders; we must continue to save lives here at home and around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-65/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Donald R. Cravins, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary of Commerce for Minority Business Development.&#160; (New Position) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Rebecca Lee Haffajee, of Massachusetts, to be an Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Services, vice Richard G. Frank. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; David P. Pekoske, of Maryland, to be Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration for a term&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Donald R. Cravins, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary of Commerce for Minority Business Development.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rebecca Lee Haffajee, of Massachusetts, to be an Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Services, vice Richard G. Frank.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; David P. Pekoske, of Maryland, to be Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration for a term of five years.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hugo F. Rodriguez, Jr., of Pennsylvania, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Nicaragua.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden at Signing of S. 3522, the “Ukraine Democracy Defense Lend-Lease Act Of&#160;2022”</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-s-3522-the-ukraine-democracy-defense-lend-lease-act-of-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 3:08 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, welcome, folks.&#160; Today I’m joined by Senator Cardin &#8212; Ben Cardin; Elissa Slotkin; and the Congresswoman Victoria Spatz &#8212; Spartz, excuse me, who &#8212; I was just talking to her about still having family back in Ukraine.&#160; God love you.&#160;&#160; I &#8212; we’re going to &#8212; I’m&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>3:08 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, welcome, folks.&nbsp; Today I’m joined by Senator Cardin &#8212; Ben Cardin; Elissa Slotkin; and the Congresswoman Victoria Spatz &#8212; Spartz, excuse me, who &#8212; I was just talking to her about still having family back in Ukraine.&nbsp; God love you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; we’re going to &#8212; I’m about to sign a bill that these folks are responsible &#8212; and, of course, the Vice President, excuse me.&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The &#8212; I’m signing a bill that provides another important tool in our efforts to support the government of Ukraine and the Ukrainian people in their fight to defend their country and their democracy against Putin’s brutal war.&nbsp; And it is brutal.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank members of Congress here for getting this passed and everyone who supported the bill.&nbsp; And the bill demonstrates that support for Ukraine is pivotal at this moment.</p>



<p>Every day, Ukrainians pay with their lives, and they fight along &#8212; and the atrocities that the Russians are engaging in are just beyond the pale.&nbsp; And the cost of the fight is not cheap, but caving to aggression is even more costly.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re staying in this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, we celebrated VE Day &#8212; Victory in Europe Day &#8212; marking the end of a transition of the devastation as a consequence of World War Two and Allied nations’ defeat of the scourge of fascism in Europe.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, Europe is honoring another important day on the anniversary.&nbsp; On May 9th, 1950, just years after the end of World War Two, Europe began to work to strengthen the bonds of unity among the nations, particularly the economic unity and the shared economic prosperity.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The idea ultimately grew into the &#8212; what is now a 27-nation European Union &#8212; an economic powerhouse and a global force for peace and close partners of all &#8212; on all the issues we face.</p>



<p>And it really has &#8212; I&#8217;ve said from the very beginning: It&#8217;s &#8212; it’s something that is good for everyone.&nbsp; It brings these countries together in ways that &#8212; and they cooperate closely economically.&nbsp; They also cooperate in other ways.&nbsp; And you’ve seen it in their support for Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with Putin’s war once more bringing wanton destruction into Europe, and to &#8212; to reaffirm the enduring commitment to the future grounded in democracy, human rights, and peaceful resolution to disagreements, I&#8217;m now going to sign this bill.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, I thank my colleagues who are standing behind me.&nbsp; And &#8212; because it really matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(The bill is signed.)</p>



<p>There you go.  Done.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>3:13 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden on the Affordable Connectivity&#160;Program￼</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/09/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-affordable-connectivity-program%ef%bf%bc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rose Garden 1:47 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; Welcome to the sunny Rose Garden.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you. That old saying, “All that needs to be said has already been said, but I’m going to say it again.”&#160; (Laughter.) Look, Alisha, thank you very much for your story. And I wanted&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rose Garden</p>



<p>1:47 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; Welcome to the sunny Rose Garden.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>That old saying, “All that needs to be said has already been said, but I’m going to say it again.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Look, Alisha, thank you very much for your story.<br><br>And I wanted to &#8212; I want to thank the Vice President, Vice President Harris, for leading this effort and this administration on this issue.&nbsp;<br><br>And I’m proud to announce today that our administration has brought together Democrats, Republicans, the private sector to lower the high-speed Internet costs for tens of millions of Americans.<br><br>You know, but before we get into the details, I want to talk about why this matters.&nbsp; You already know that, actually, from hearing my two colleagues speak before me.<br><br>But here in the United States of America, how many times have you seen a mom or a dad drive up to a parking lot outside a McDonald’s and &#8212; just so they could get connected to the Internet so their kid could do their homework during the pandemic, literally?&nbsp; It’s just not right.&nbsp; It’s not who we are.<br><br>And we saw, during the pandemic, how essential high-speed Internet really is in allowing seniors to connect with their doctors through telemedicine, as the Vice President referenced, when it wasn’t safe to go in person; allowing students to keep learning back when schools were closed; allowing millions of &#8212; millions workers to do their job remotely; allowing small businesses to stay afloat on the strength of their online sales; allowing farmers to use precision agriculture technology to improve their yields; and allowing countless families to stay connected to the people they love, even when they weren’t able to get together.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, the need for high-speed Internet is &#8212; is a little bit like what used to be probably what my grandfather talked about: needing to have a telephone.&nbsp; It’s pretty consequential.&nbsp; And it’s only going to keep growing, this need.&nbsp; High-speed Internet is not a luxury any longer, it’s a necessity.&nbsp;<br><br>And that’s why the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law included $65 billion to make sure we expand access to broadband Internet in every region of the country &#8212; urban, suburban, and rural &#8212; everywhere &#8212; everywhere &#8212; (applause) &#8212; so every household in America can get connected.<br><br>By &#8212; by expanding access it’s only &#8212; it’s only part of the challenge, though, as was referenced by the Vice President.&nbsp; It was about affordability as well.&nbsp; And today, too many families simply can’t afford to get connected, even if there’s access to get connected.&nbsp; So they go without high-speed Internet or they sacrifice other necessities in order to make it work.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why &#8212; that’s why, in November, when we passed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill, we also created something called the Affordable Connectivity Program.&nbsp; I refuse to call it the “ACP.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I am so tired of acronyms in Washington.&nbsp; I can’t stand it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I cannot stand it.&nbsp; But I’m going to have to learn, aren’t I?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Here’s how it works: If your household income is twice the federal poverty level or less &#8212; that’s about $55,000 per year for a family of four or $27,000 for an individual &#8212; or a member of your household is on Medicaid or Supplemental Security Income or a number of other programs, you’re eligible to &#8212; for affordably connect &#8212; the Affordable Connectivity Program.&nbsp;<br><br>Nearly 40 percent of the households in America qualify.&nbsp; And if you qualify, you’re going to get a $30 credit per month toward your Internet bill, which me- &#8212; which most folks &#8212; will mean they get on for nothing.&nbsp; Look &#8212; zero.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Let me explain: In the past, 30 bucks a month meant you had to settle for a slow Internet service, unless you wanted to pay a heck of a lot more out of pocket.&nbsp; But over the last few months, my administration has worked closely with Internet providers &#8212; this is a case where big business stepped up &#8212; urging them to cut their prices and raise their &#8212; their speeds.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m trying to get others to do the same thing with inflation but that &#8212; these guys are the best.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Well, look, we secured commitments from 20 providers &#8212; most of whom are here in the garden today.&nbsp; Going to lower prices for high-speed Internet for tens of millions of households.&nbsp; So, now families who are eligible can select a plan from pr- &#8212; a participating provider and receive high-speed Internet at no cost, in most cases.<br><br>These include providers like AT&amp;T.&nbsp; Is AT&amp;T here?&nbsp; Thank you, man.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>AT&amp;T, Comcast &#8212; Comcast, where are you?&nbsp; Stand up, man.&nbsp; Let them see you.&nbsp; Frontier, Spectrum, and Verizon.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;You’re really changing people’s lives.&nbsp; You really are.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Along with smaller providers serving rural areas, like Jackson Energy Authority in Tennessee and Ideatek in Kansas.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Are you guys here?&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>All told, providers taking part &#8212; you know, everybody &#8212; it’s &#8212; you’re going to cover about 80 percent of the United States’ population, including about half the rural population.&nbsp; Each of the &#8212; each of them has committed to offering families who use this program at least one high-speed plan that is fully covered.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, Verizon lowered the price of its high-speed service from $40 a month to $30 a month.&nbsp; Spectrum doubled the speed of its $30-a-month plan for eligible households.&nbsp; And we made sure that there would be no hidden fees, no tricks.&nbsp; This is straight stuff.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This means fast Internet, good download speeds, with no data caps and no extra fees for millions of American families.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And it’s going to change people’s lives.&nbsp; You know, in &#8212; from rural Appalachia to Brooklyn to the Black Belt.&nbsp; Families who have struggled to get the Internet that they need &#8212; even getting &#8212; finding if they could connect to it, let alone if they could afford it &#8212; for schoolwork, telemedicine, standing a &#8212; starting a business, and so much more &#8212; and will finally get connected reliably and affordably.<br><br>And I want to thank the companies who are working with us to deliver this for all families.&nbsp; It’s a big deal.&nbsp; And this is a great example of what we can achieve if the federal government and the private sector work together to solve serious problems.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And this is &#8212; not only is it this great news for family budgets, it also means more jobs, more new small businesses, more connectivity.&nbsp; So many people in so many communities that have been left behind.&nbsp; Already, more than 11.5 million have signed up and are on the program.&nbsp; Thousands more are signing up each day.&nbsp; And you can get started by taking advantage of this &#8212; in this new phase today.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re &#8212; but we urge &#8212; there’s about 30 million additional people who are eligible for this plan that basically get free Internet and good Internet.&nbsp; We want each of you &#8212; each and every one of you to take advantage of the chance and cut your Internet cost.</p>



<p>To find out if you’re eligible, you can dial 877-384-2575.&nbsp; Now, if you got that, you’re way ahead of me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; 877-384-2575, and &#8212; for English or Spanish.</p>



<p>Or if you’re able to get onto the Internet, just visit, Get- &#8212; just go to GetInternet.gov, and you’ll be able to connect as well.<br><br>You know, we’re also working with local, state, and federal agencies, as well as local and national organizations, to help get more eligible families enrolled so they can get connected.&nbsp; You got to know how to know, as a friend of mine used to say.&nbsp; You know, this program is a big deal.&nbsp; It’s the only one &#8212; only one piece of work that we’re doing to try to bring down the cost of high-speed Internet to every single American.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re also promoting the &#8212; competition.&nbsp; More than 65 million Americans live in a place with only one high-speed Internet provider.&nbsp; Research shows that when you live somewhere with limited Internet options, you pay five times more on average than families that have more choices.&nbsp; That’s what the lack of cont- &#8212; lack of competition does: It raises the prices you pay.&nbsp; So, we’re working to fix that problem as well.<br><br>For example, my administration is taking steps to put a stop to the exclusive deals that landlords make with Internet companies.&nbsp; Because [of] those sweetheart arrangements, millions of Americans who live in apartment buildings only have one Internet option.&nbsp; And they &#8212; they can stop &#8212; if they can stop those exclusive deals, then families will have options to choose a provider that they want, and that means companies will have to compete for their business, which in turn means lower prices.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In addition, more than 30 million Americans live in places where the speeds are too slow or where there is no broadband and there&#8217;s no infrastructure at all.&nbsp; That’s especially true in rural communities.&nbsp; And as I said at the start: Thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we’re delivering high-speed Internet infrastructure to every part of the country.&nbsp; And I mean that literally &#8212; every part of the country.&nbsp;<br><br>The bottom line is this: My top priority is fighting inflation and lowering prices for families and the things they need.&nbsp; Today’s announcement is going to give millions of families a little more &#8212; a little more breathing room to help them pay their bills.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You know, we worked with Democrats and Republicans and business and non-profits to make this happen.&nbsp; And we’re going to keep working to fight inflation and lower cost of &#8212; to all American families for a lot of other things as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But again, I want to thank the businesses that are here today.&nbsp; I want to thank the Internet companies &#8212; or the providers.&nbsp; It really matters.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to change people’s lives.&nbsp;<br><br>And, by the way, you know, one of the things that is &#8212; it’s a totally different subject, and I&#8217;m just going to touch it for a second.&nbsp; There&#8217;s an awful lot of growing data that what&#8217;s happened because of COVID and other things &#8212; the mental health problems are &#8212; have become a serious problem.&nbsp; Feeling left out, feeling you can&#8217;t participate, not knowing what to do.<br><br>I know &#8212; and Vivek Murthy, the Surgeon General, is going to talk about this in another context.&nbsp; But, you know, I really think that just knowing that you belong, knowing and feeling that you can get access to what other people get on a regular basis will make a big difference for people.&nbsp;<br><br>So, God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; And all the members of Congress who made this happy &#8212; I was going to name each one of you, and I was told don’t, because people who aren’t here wanted to be here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I &#8212; but I think I should name you anyway, shouldn’t I?&nbsp; I mean &#8212; no?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t know, man.&nbsp;&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>They’re all in the front here, and they&#8217;re all doing a hell of a job.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>I started off – and I had the list, I said, “Give me the…”&nbsp; And I started off with saying, “Cheri Bustos.”&nbsp; And they said, “Wait, there&#8217;s a lot of people who aren’t here.&nbsp; Don’t do it.”&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; But I &#8212; and the people who are here are, you know,&nbsp;John Hickenlooper, Cheri Bustos, Dan Kildee &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; Debbie Dingell, Tom O’Halleran, Eliza [sic] Slotkin &#8212; excuse me, Elissa Slotkin, and &#8212; and Representative Stansbury.&nbsp; So &#8212; but there&#8217;s a lot more to it, but anyway.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; It’s going to make a big difference.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.&nbsp; And stick around and sunbathe.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>2:00 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris Reduce High-Speed Internet Costs for Millions of&#160;Americans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/fact-sheet-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-reduce-high-speed-internet-costs-for-millions-of-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration Secures Commitments from 20 Internet Providers to Cut Prices and Increase Speeds High-speed internet service is no longer a luxury—it’s a necessity. But too many families go without high-speed internet because of the cost or have to cut back on other essentials to make their monthly internet service payments. Lowering prices—including the cost&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration Secures Commitments from 20 Internet Providers to Cut Prices and Increase Speeds</em></p>



<p>High-speed internet service is no longer a luxury—it’s a necessity. But too many families go without high-speed internet because of the cost or have to cut back on other essentials to make their monthly internet service payments. Lowering prices—including the cost of high-speed internet service—is President Biden’s top priority. Today, President Biden and Vice President Harris are announcing that they have secured private sector commitments that will lower high-speed internet costs for millions of American families.</p>



<p>As part of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, the President and Vice President worked with Democrats and Republicans to create the Affordable Connectivity Program (ACP), which allows tens of millions of American households to reduce their internet service costs by up to $30/month (or $75/month on Tribal lands). To ensure the most efficient use of those public dollars and to deliver maximum cost savings to families, the Biden-Harris Administration has secured commitments from 20 leading internet providers—covering more than 80% of the U.S. population across urban, suburban, and rural areas—to either increase speeds or cut prices, making sure they all offer ACP-eligible households high-speed, high-quality internet plans for no more than $30/month.</p>



<p>From large providers like AT&amp;T, Comcast, and Verizon serving dozens of states, to smaller providers serving rural areas like Jackson Energy Authority in Tennessee and Comporium in North Carolina, the commitments will allow tens of millions of ACP-eligible households to receive high-speed internet at no cost.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is also launching a comprehensive effort to make sure as many ACP-eligible households as possible take advantage of this new program by:</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Launching GetInternet.gov:</u></strong> <a href="http://www.GetInternet.gov">GetInternet.gov</a> is a simple, easy-to-use website with details on how Americans can sign up for ACP and find participating internet providers in their area.<br></li><li><strong><u>Reaching out to eligible households through federal agencies:</u></strong> Households qualify for ACP based on their income or through their participation in one of several other federal programs, like Pell Grants, Medicaid, or Supplemental Security Income. Agencies that manage these programs will be coordinating an effort to reach out to households that qualify for ACP through programs they help administer.&nbsp;For example, the Social Security Administration will email all 1.6 million Supplemental Security Income recipients who have a “My Social Security” account, letting them know that they are eligible for the Affordable Connectivity Program.<br></li><li><strong><u>Partnering with states and cities:</u></strong> The Administration is partnering with states and cities to spread the word as well. For example, Michigan, Massachusetts, Philadelphia, Mesa, Arizona, and New York City will text millions of eligible households.<br></li><li><strong><u>Collaborating with public interest organizations:</u></strong> Public interest organizations, including the United Way, Goodwill, Catholic Charities USA, and UnidosUS, will train their national networks to conduct direct enrollment and outreach. And Propel, a mission-driven financial technology company, will provide information via the Providers app to connect more than 5 million low-income families with the program.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Today’s announcement is just one part of the President’s strategy for lowering the cost of high-speed internet for all Americans. New <a href="https://www.ntia.doc.gov/category/grants">grant</a> <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/coronavirus/assistance-for-state-local-and-tribal-governments/capital-projects-fund#:~:text=The%20American%20Rescue%20Plan%20provides,to%20the%20public%20health%20emergency.">programs</a> <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/coronavirus/assistance-for-state-local-and-tribal-governments/state-and-local-fiscal-recovery-funds">providing</a> tens of billions of dollars for broadband infrastructure construction will require providers to offer affordable internet options. New rules will soon require providers to display a “<a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-acts-empower-broadband-consumers-through-transparency-0">Broadband Nutrition Label</a>” that will make it easier to comparison shop for the best deal on internet. The FCC has adopted rules to ban sweetheart deals between internet providers and landlords that restrict the internet options available to millions of Americans who live <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-acts-increase-broadband-competition-apartment-buildings-0">in apartment buildings</a>. And the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/competition/">competition agenda</a> is focused on providing Americans with more good options for internet service where they live—driving down prices and increasing the quality of service.<br><br><strong><u>THE AFFORDABLE CONNECTIVITY PROGRAM (ACP)</u></strong><br>President Biden and Vice President Harris worked with Democrats and Republicans to create the Affordable Connectivity Program (ACP)—the largest high-speed internet affordability program in our nation’s history. Experts estimate that <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/610831a16c95260dbd68934a/t/6272e30e12eafe18e06dec58/1651696399310/Broadband-Connectivity-Fact-Sheet-CPSP-2022.pdf">48 million households</a>—or nearly 40% of households in the country—qualify for the ACP either because their income is at or below 200% of the Federal Poverty Level, or because a member of the household meets one of the other criteria below:</p>



<ul><li>Participates in one of the following programs:<ul><li>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as Food Stamps</li><li>Medicaid</li><li>Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC)</li><li>Supplemental Security Income (SSI)</li><li>Federal Public Housing Assistance (FPHA)</li><li>Veterans Pension and Survivors Benefit</li><li>Free and Reduced-Price School Lunch Program or School Breakfast Program, including at U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) Community Eligibility Provision schools</li><li>Federal Pell Grant (received in the current award year)</li><li>Lifeline</li><li>Certain Tribal assistance programs, including Bureau of Indian Affairs General Assistance, Head Start (only households meeting the income qualifying standard), Tribal Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (Tribal TANF), and Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations<br></li></ul></li><li>Meets the eligibility criteria for a participating broadband provider’s existing low-income internet program.</li></ul>



<p>Under the terms of the ACP, an eligible household that signs up for the program will receive a discount of up to $30/month on any internet service plan a participating provider offers. Households on Tribal Lands are eligible for a discount of up to $75/month. As of now, more than 1,300 internet service providers participate in the program, and more than 11.5 million households have signed up to receive the ACP benefit.<br><br><strong><u>NEW PRIVATE SECTOR COMMITMENTS</u></strong><br>To make the most of this program, the Biden-Harris Administration asked participating internet service providers to either reduce prices and or raise speeds to offer ACP-eligible households a high-speed internet plan for no more than $30/month. For these purposes, the Administration views a sufficiently high-speed plan as one that offers download speeds of at least 100 Megabits per second everywhere that the provider’s infrastructure is capable of it. That’s fast enough for a typical family of four to work from home, do schoolwork, browse the web, and stream high-definition shows and movies. In addition, the Administration asked providers to offer such plans with no fees and no data caps.</p>



<p>For example, as part of this initiative, Verizon lowered the price for its Fios service from $39.99/month to $30/month for a plan that delivers download and upload speeds of at least 200 Megabits per second, and Spectrum doubled the speed of the $30/month plan it makes available to ACP participants from 50 to 100 Megabits per second (download).</p>



<p>Each of the following companies committed to offer all ACP-eligible families at least one high-speed plan for $30/month or less, with no additional fees and no data caps.</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.allocommunications.com/community-connect-residential/">Allo Communications</a></li><li><a href="https://info.cincinnatibell.com/acp">AltaFiber</a> (and <a href="https://hawaiiantel.com/acp">Hawaiian Telecom</a>)</li><li>Altice USA (<a href="https://www.optimum.com/affordable-connectivity-program">Optimum</a> and <a href="https://www.suddenlink.com/affordable-connectivity-program">Suddenlink</a>)</li><li><a href="https://www.astound.com/acp">Astound</a></li><li><a href="http://www.att.com/acp">AT&amp;T</a></li><li><a href="https://www.breezeline.com/acp">Breezeline</a></li><li><a href="https://www.internetessentials.com/">Comcast</a></li><li><a href="https://www.comporium.com/affordable-connectivity-program-connected-package/">Comporium</a></li><li><a href="https://www.getfrontierfiber.com/acp-offer#3UP">Frontier</a></li><li><a href="https://ideatek.com/low-income-assistance/">IdeaTek</a></li><li><a href="https://www.cox.com/residential/internet/low-cost-internet-plans.html">Cox Communications</a></li><li><a href="http://www.eplusbroadband.com/acp">Jackson Energy Authority</a></li><li>Mediacom </li><li><a href="https://mlgc.com/acp/">MLGC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.spectrum.com/cp/broadband-get-qualified?p1=1-877-958-7103&amp;opredirect=acp">Spectrum</a> (Charter Communications</li><li><a href="https://starry.com/acp/">Starry</a></li><li><a href="https://www.verizon.com/home/fios-forward">Verizon</a> (Fios only)</li><li><a href="https://www.vermontel.com/acp">Vermont Telephone Company</a></li><li><a href="http://www.vexusfiber.com/acp">Vexus Fiber</a></li><li><a href="https://www.wowway.com/affordable-connectivity-program">Wow!</a> Internet, Cable, and TV</li></ul>



<p>These companies serve urban, suburban, and rural communities across the country. Collectively, they offer high-speed internet services in areas in which over 80% of the U.S. population lives, including nearly 50% of the rural population. The Biden-Harris Administration is grateful for the efforts of these companies, and encourages additional internet service providers to join this effort to close the digital divide by offering high-speed, low-cost plans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
