<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 20:50:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-60/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 20:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Candace A. Bond, of Missouri, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Trinidad and Tobago. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Timmy T. Davis, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Candace A. Bond, of Missouri, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Trinidad and Tobago.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Timmy T. Davis, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the State of Qatar.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Michael J. Lombardo, of California, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2022, vice Maria Rosario Jackson, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Michael J. Lombardo, of California, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2028.&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Nasser H. Paydar, of Indiana, to be Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, Department of Education, vice Robert L. King.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Puneet Talwar, of the District of Columbia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Morocco.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Status of the Country’s Fight Against&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/30/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-status-of-the-countrys-fight-against-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 19:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 1:40 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Today, I’d like to update you all on where we stand on COVID-19.&#160; Because of the strategy we executed over the past year on vaccinations, testing, treatments, and more, we’re now in a new moment in this pandemic. It does not mean&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>1:40 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Today, I’d like to update you all on where we stand on COVID-19.&nbsp;<br><br>Because of the strategy we executed over the past year on vaccinations, testing, treatments, and more, we’re now in a new moment in this pandemic.<br><br>It does not mean that COVID-19 is over; it means that COVID-19 no longer controls our lives.&nbsp; That’s what it means.&nbsp;<br><br>Cases are ticking up as we thought they might.&nbsp; But now, thanks to the foundation we’ve laid, America has the tools to protect people &#8212; all the people.<br><br>And, you know, as we’ve done from day one, my administration is making it easier than ever for Americans to access these tools.<br><br>Today, I&#8217;m announcing the launch of COVID.gov &#8212; COVID.gov &#8212; a one &#8212; (clears throat) &#8212; excuse me, a one-stop shop where anyone in America can find what they need to navigate the virus: free vaccines and boosters, free at-home tests, high-quality masks.&nbsp; And for the latest information about the level of COVID-19 spread in your community, you can get that immediately.<br><br>Now, you’ll also be able to find our new test-to-treat locations, which I announced in my State of the Union Address.&nbsp; These are pharmacies and other places in your neighborhood where you can get tested.&nbsp; And if you&#8217;re positive, you can get lifesaving treatments all in one stop.<br><br>We’ve already stood up 2,000 test-to-streat [sic] sites &#8212; test-and-treat sites across the country.<br><br>We’re also nearly at &#8212; we have nearly 200 sites just to serve military families and veterans communities as well.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve done &#8212; what we’ve done throughout the pandemic, we’ve ensured there are &#8212; these locations are at the hardest-hit, hardest-to-reach communities as well.<br><br>The bottom line: No longer will Americans have to scour the Internet to find vaccines, treatments, tests, or masks.&nbsp; It’s all there.&nbsp; And just go visit COVID.gov &#8212; COVID.gov.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And let me remind you: When I took office about 14 months ago, the pandemic was raging, the economy was reeling, and the deficit was soaring.&nbsp; Most schools were closed.&nbsp; We didn’t have enough vaccines.&nbsp; The unemployment claims were sky high.&nbsp;<br><br>And then we got to work, and we delivered: enough vaccines for every American months ahead of schedule, effective treatments, at-home tests that are free and accessible.<br><br>Over 99 percent of our schools are open again.&nbsp; Businesses are open again.&nbsp; And because of how we responded, we created more jobs last year than ever before &#8212; 6.7 million jobs.<br><br>And by the way, we did it while cutting the deficit &#8212; the largest one-year deficit reduction in American history.&nbsp; Say that again: The largest one-year deficit reduction in American history.&nbsp;<br><br>But none of that happened by accident.&nbsp; We were able to do it because we coordinated across the government, partnered with state and local leaders, governors on both sides of the aisle, and the private sector to leverage every resource we had to fight against this virus.<br><br>We left no stone unturned.&nbsp; And we were able to do it because Congress worked with us and provided us the necessary funding.<br><br>But now, just as we’ve reached the critical turning point in this fight, Congress has to provide the funding America needs to continue to fight COVID-19.<br><br>We’re alr- &#8212; we’re already seeing the consequences of congressional inaction.&nbsp; The monoclonal antibod- &#8212; take monoclonal antibodies, for example.&nbsp; They’ve helped save lives.&nbsp; This isn’t partisan; it’s medicine.<br><br>But Congress hasn’t provided enough money to keep purchasing these monoclonal bo- &#8212; antibodies.&nbsp; We’ve had to cancel planned orders and cut the supply we’re sending to the states.&nbsp; Without more funding, we’ll start to run out of them by the end of May &#8212; the end of May.<br><br>We’ve also had to scale back our plan to purchase more preventive therapies for Americans who are immunocompromised &#8212; critical tools to protect the most vulnerable among us.&nbsp; Without more funding, we risk running out of the supply by this fall.<br><br>The same is true of testing.&nbsp; It took months to ramp up our testing capacity.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Omicron &#8212; we saw how vital &#8212; and with Omicron, we saw how vital it was&nbsp;<s>and</s>&nbsp;[that] we have enough tests on hand to weather the surge.&nbsp;&nbsp;But without funding, we’re not going to be able to sustain the testing capacity beyond the month of June.&nbsp; And if we fail to invest, we leave ourselves vulnerable if another wave of the virus hits.<br><br>Look, on vaccines &#8212; a most important tool in this fight &#8212; we’re also running a risk.<br><br>Yesterday, the Food and Drug Administration &#8212; the FDA &#8212; and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention –- the CDC &#8212; authorized a fourth shot for those 50 years and older.<br><br>We know boosters are critical to providing an additional level of protection.&nbsp; That’s why I plan to get my second booster today right here after I’m done speaking.<br><br>If you haven’t gotten your first booster, please don’t wait.&nbsp; Do it today.<br><br>Those who are 50 and older, as well as those who are immunocompromised, can now get it &#8212; get even more protection than they have from the initial first doses.&nbsp; We have enough supply to give booster shots to those newly eligible individuals.<br><br>But if Congress fails to act, we won’t have the supply we need this fall to ensure that shots are available, free, easily accessible for all Americans.<br><br>Even worse, if we need a different vaccine for the future to combat a new variant, we’re not going to have enough money to purchase it.&nbsp; We cannot allow that to happen.</p>



<p>Congress, we need to secure additional supply now.&nbsp; Now.&nbsp; We can’t wait until we find ourselves in the midst of another surge to act.&nbsp; It’ll be too late.<br><br>And we also need this &#8212; this funding to continue our efforts to vaccinate the world &#8212; commitments we made.&nbsp; It’s critical to our ability to protect against new variants.&nbsp; There’s no wall that you can build high enough to keep out a virus.<br><br>Congress needs to act now, please.<br><br>Let me close with this: I’ve worked so hard to get our lives &#8212; we’ve worked so hard to &#8212; we, all of us, have worked so hard to get our lives back.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We’re summoning every ounce of American resilience; pulled every lever of our government; called upon the goodness, decency, and patriotism of the American people; and, together, we turned an unthinkable pain into an extraordinary progress and purpose.&nbsp; Americans are back to living their lives again.&nbsp; We can’t surrender that now.&nbsp;<br><br>Congress, please act.&nbsp; You have to act immediately.&nbsp; The consequences of inaction are severe.&nbsp; They’ll only grow with time, but it doesn’t have to be that way.</p>



<p>We’ve proven what we can do when we work together.&nbsp; So, I urge Democrats and Republicans to get this done with urgency.<br><br>Let’s stand united.&nbsp; Let’s continue to pull together.&nbsp; Let’s get this done.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; And God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.<br><br>And now I’m going to get my second booster shot.<br>(The President moves to a chair to receive the booster shot.)<br><br>I’m not sure why I’m doing it on stage.&nbsp; Just to prove I&#8217;m getting it, I guess.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what is the danger of Putin being left in the dark by his military advisors?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m reluctant to comment on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you comment on the declassified intelligence that he doesn&#8217;t trust his military leadership, since it is declassified?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I can&#8217;t.<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, is the U.S. willing to provide security guarantees to Ukraine as part of peace talks?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m feeling great.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the U.S. willing to provide security guarantees to Ukraine as part of peace talks with Russia?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, are you going to extend Title 42?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have a decision on that soon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, the difference between rich and poor countries on vaccination, will it impact your &#8212; the fight against COVID here?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry &#8212;<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The difference between &#8212; the gap &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Somebody asked about the vaccines, which is relevant.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For kids under five, is there &#8212; are there enough funds to provide them vaccines for free?<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>(The President receives the booster shot.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How does it feel, Mr. President?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Wonderful.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>No, I have to admit to you, I&#8217;ve always thought that it discourages people getting a vaccination when they watch people get a needle in their arm.&nbsp; So I apologize if I discouraged them.&nbsp; It didn&#8217;t hurt a bit, and I was able to roll my sleeve up.<br><br>And thank you all so very much.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you meet with Trevor Reed&#8217;s parents?&nbsp; Will you meet with Trevor Reed&#8217;s parents, Mr. President, while they&#8217;re here in Washington?&nbsp; They say that you promised them a meeting.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to see if I can get to see them.&nbsp; They&#8217;re good &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re good people.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t &#8212; we&#8217;re trying to work that out.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>1:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Transgender Day Of Visibility,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/30/a-proclamation-on-transgender-day-of-visibility-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 19:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA A PROCLAMATION To everyone celebrating Transgender Day of Visibility, I&#160;want you to know that your President sees you.&#160; The First Lady, the Vice President, the Second Gentleman, and my entire Administration see you for who you are &#8212; made in the image of God and deserving&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">A PROCLAMATION</p>



<p>To everyone celebrating Transgender Day of Visibility, I&nbsp;want you to know that your President sees you.&nbsp; The First Lady, the Vice President, the Second Gentleman, and my entire Administration see you for who you are &#8212; made in the image of God and deserving of dignity, respect, and support. &nbsp;On this day and every day, we recognize the resilience, strength, and joy of&nbsp;transgender, nonbinary, and gender nonconforming people.&nbsp; We celebrate the activism and determination that have fueled the fight for transgender equality.&nbsp; We acknowledge the adversity and discrimination that the transgender community continues to face across our Nation and around the world.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Visibility matters, and so many transgender, nonbinary, and gender nonconforming Americans are thriving.&nbsp; Like never before, they are sharing their stories in books and magazines; breaking glass ceilings of representation on television and movie screens; enlisting &#8212; once again &#8212; to serve proudly and openly in our military; getting elected and making policy at every level of government; and running businesses, curing diseases, and serving our communities in countless other ways.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Despite this progress, transgender Americans continue to face discrimination, harassment, and barriers to opportunity. &nbsp;Transgender women and girls &#8212; especially transgender women and girls of color &#8212; continue to face epidemic levels of violence, and 2021 marked the deadliest year on record for transgender Americans. &nbsp;Each of these lives lost was precious. &nbsp;Each of them deserved freedom, justice, and joy. &nbsp;We must honor their lives with action by advancing equity and civil rights for all transgender people.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the past year, hundreds of anti-transgender bills in States were proposed across America, most of them targeting transgender kids. &nbsp;The onslaught has continued this year. &nbsp;These&nbsp;bills are wrong. &nbsp;Efforts to criminalize supportive medical care for transgender kids, to ban transgender children from playing sports, and to outlaw discussing LGBTQI+ people in&nbsp;schools undermine their humanity and corrode our Nation&#8217;s values.&nbsp; Studies have shown that these political attacks are damaging to the mental health and well-being of transgender youth, putting children and their families at greater risk of&nbsp;bullying and discrimination.</p>



<p>     My entire Administration is committed to ensuring that transgender people enjoy the freedom and equality that are promised to everyone in America.  That is why I signed an Executive Order Preventing and Combating Discrimination on the Basis of Gender Identity or Sexual Orientation.  We are expanding Federal non-discrimination protections; promoting strategies to address violence against the transgender community and advance gender equity and equality; and disseminating new resources to enhance inclusion, opportunity, and safety for transgender people.  Additionally, Americans will soon be able to select more inclusive gender markers on their passports.  I continue to call on the Congress to swiftly pass the bipartisan Equality Act, which will ensure that LGBTQI+ individuals and families cannot be denied housing, employment, education, credit, and more because of who they are or who they love.  We will continue to work to help transgender people around the world live free from discrimination and violence.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this Transgender Day of Visibility, we honor transgender people who are fighting for freedom, equality, dignity, and respect.&nbsp; We also celebrate the parents, teachers, coaches, doctors, and other allies who affirm the identities of their transgender children and help these young people reach their potential.&nbsp; Transgender people are some of the bravest Americans I know, and our Nation and the world are stronger, more vibrant, and more prosperous because of them. &nbsp;To transgender Americans of all ages, I want you to know that you are so brave. &nbsp;You belong. &nbsp;I have your back.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim March 31, 2022, as Transgender Day of Visibility. &nbsp;I call upon all Americans to join us in lifting up the lives and voices of transgender people throughout our Nation and to work toward eliminating discrimination against all transgender, gender nonconforming, and nonbinary people &#8212; and&nbsp;all people.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirtieth day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on César Chávez Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/30/a-proclamation-on-cesar-chavez-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 19:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50108</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA A PROCLAMATION Today we celebrate the life and legacy of César Estrada Chávez, a champion for social justice and advocate for hardworking people who build and sustain our Nation.  Born into poverty and raised by migrant workers, Chávez courageously dedicated his life to improving conditions for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">A PROCLAMATION</p>



<p>Today we celebrate the life and legacy of César Estrada Chávez, a champion for social justice and advocate for hardworking people who build and sustain our Nation.  Born into poverty and raised by migrant workers, Chávez courageously dedicated his life to improving conditions for workers across the country.  Chávez witnessed firsthand the inequities of an economy that only served those at the top and left millions of hardworking Americans behind.  Today, as we continue to build an economy from the bottom up and the middle out and that rewards work and not just wealth, we stand on the shoulders of César Chávez and carry forward his fight to advance the rights and dignity of working people and fulfill the promise of America for all Americans.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When César Chávez founded the United Farm Workers of America alongside Dolores Huerta, he drew national attention to&nbsp;the many agricultural workers who experience inhumane working conditions and unlivable wages. &nbsp;Through strikes, marches, and boycotts, he inspired millions of people across the country to fight for safe and healthy workplaces, better wages, improved workplace protections from sickness and disability, and other core rights and protections.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the process, Chávez inspired generations of people across all backgrounds, ages, and industries to organize, bargain, and expand opportunity for workers and their families. &nbsp;His devotion to &#8220;La Causa&#8221; brought hope to workers and Latinos across the Nation &#8212; and his fight for justice, equality, and dignity gave workers and Latinos everywhere a voice. &nbsp;Today, we&nbsp;must summon the same courage and moral clarity to carry his legacy forward so that everyone has a fair shot at the American dream.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That is why my Administration continues to urge the Congress to pass the Protecting the Right to Organize Act and the Farm Workforce Modernization Act &#8212; so farmworkers can bargain collectively, obtain legal status, and have better working conditions.&nbsp; It is why I fought hard to pass the American Rescue Plan early in my Administration to ensure Latino workers, families, and small businesses had the protections and financial support they needed to pay rent and put food on their table. &nbsp;It is why I appointed Marty Walsh, a former union leader, to lead the Department of Labor &#8212; because he understands how union workers hold this country together. &nbsp;It&nbsp;is&nbsp;why my Administration created an historic Task Force on&nbsp;Worker Organizing and Empowerment &#8212; because I believe in empowering workers to organize and providing those that put food on our table an earned pathway to citizenship.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As our Nation celebrates César Chávez&#8217;s 95th birthday, let&nbsp;us keep the lessons he taught in our minds and the values he&nbsp;lived by in our hearts:&nbsp; the power of workers to bargain for a&nbsp;better deal, strength in the face of extraordinary adversity, and the conviction to fight for what we believe in.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When I became President, I proudly placed a bust of César Chávez in the Oval Office &#8212; a constant reminder of the enduring values he embodied, the vision of freedom he fought for, and his commitment to social justice and equal dignity that we must uphold each and every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>     NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 31, 2022, as César Chávez Day.  I call upon all Americans to observe this day as a day of service and learning, with appropriate service, community, and education programs to honor César Chávez&#8217;s enduring legacy. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this</p>



<p>thirtieth day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at Greater Washington Inclusive Growth&#160;Announcement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/30/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-greater-washington-inclusive-growth-announcement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:14 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning, everyone.&#160; Good morning.&#160; You know, it&#8217;s so wonderful &#8212; we all love homecomings, don&#8217;t we?&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And this is a homecoming for me to be on this stage at Cramton Auditorium at Howard University. Dr. Frederick, I want to thank you for always warmly welcoming us to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:14 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s so wonderful &#8212; we all love homecomings, don&#8217;t we?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And this is a homecoming for me to be on this stage at Cramton Auditorium at Howard University.<br><br>Dr. Frederick, I want to thank you for always warmly welcoming us to this incredible place.&nbsp; In this very auditorium, I have memories of so many moments in my life, including the day that I was here in the back of the room for freshman orientation.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And in many ways, including my family, this is where it all started.<br><br>So, thank you, all, very much.&nbsp; It&#8217;s wonderful to be here with you all today.<br><br>Ellis Carr, thank you for that introduction and for your extraordinary leadership.&nbsp; We had some time, all of us, backstage to talk about the work that you all are doing, and I cannot thank you enough.<br><br>And Wayne Frederick, I want to just thank you again for all that you do to lead this venerable institution.&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s so much about Howard University and all of our universities, our colleges, our community colleges that really do highlight what this is about, what this topic is about &#8212; which is creating a place and an environment where the talent of our nation can be nurtured and supported and encouraged.<br><br>That really is the essence of what we&#8217;re doing today, and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re talking about today.<br><br>And this, of course, is an institution that since its founding, has worked to advance &#8212; as we are doing, all of us, today &#8212; inclusion, growth, and equity in our country.<br><br>Today, we are, of course, joined by the Secretary of Commerce, Gina Raimondo &#8212; thank you for your work, Madam Secretary; and the Administrator of our Small Business Administration, Isabel Guzman.&nbsp; And thank you.&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;ve known Isabel&#8217;s work &#8212; I&#8217;m going to say the Administrator&#8217;s work since her work in California, and you have a longstanding track record of supporting and encouraging community strength and growth.&nbsp; And so, I thank you for that.<br><br>And we are, of course, honored to be joined as well by a number of extraordinary leaders from the Greater Washington Partnership &#8212; leaders who have dedicated themselves to advancing economic development and economic opportunity for all our communities.<br><br>So, thank you all for your leadership and for being here today.<br><br>I believe America is a nation that is driven by the ambition and aspirations of her people.&nbsp; And our economy, to a great extent, therefore is driven by the ambition and aspiration of our small businesses.<br><br>Small-business owners work morning and night to transform an idea into a reality.&nbsp; And that energy, of course, drives our entire nation forward.&nbsp; It creates jobs.&nbsp; It drives innovation.&nbsp; It accelerates economic growth.<br><br>And in America today, too many small businesses and too many entrepreneurs are also being left behind.<br><br>So, to start and grow a business, as we all know, entrepreneurs with these incredible ideas, with ambition and aspiration &#8212; well, to actually put it into effect, they need capital.&nbsp; Capital to buy inventory, to rent a storefront, to pay their employees.&nbsp; They need financial services to help run the daily operations of their business and to invest in the future.<br><br>But far too many entrepreneurs are unable to access this essential support.<br><br>Consider: Black entrepreneurs are three times more likely to report that they did not apply for credit for fear of being turned away by a bank.<br><br>Black and Latino entrepreneurs are rejected at a much higher rate when applying for small-business loans from traditional financial institutions, even when they have credit profiles similar to other applicants.<br><br>People who live in rural areas, including many Native Americans, often lack access to traditional banking services of any kind.<br><br>And many Asian American business owners, in particular immigrant business owners, face language barriers that limit their opportunity and ability to access capital and banking services.&nbsp;<br><br>And let us acknowledge that when we think of the importance, the relevance, and the strength of traditional banks, we must also acknowledge that they’ve not always necessarily seen the vision of small-business owners who are women, small-business owners of color, rural small-business owners, and small-business owners who serve low-income communities.<br><br>Community lenders, on the other hand, were created to see that vision.&nbsp; Community lenders, known as CDFIs and MDIs, predominantly serve overlooked and underserved communities.<br><br>The people who run these institutions &#8212; and here’s where the magic lies &#8212; the people, Senator, who run these institutions &#8212; because we’ve worked together; Senator Cardin is right here in the front row &#8212; often live and work in those communities.<br><br>I’m going to repeat that: The people who run these institutions often live and work in those very communities.&nbsp; They know the people they are lending too.&nbsp; They understand their needs and their challenges and their strengths.&nbsp; And so, when they make a loan, they personally feel the positive impact of that loan.&nbsp; They feel it firsthand because they’re there. And so, community lenders can often see the potential that others might overlook.<br><br>Last year, for example &#8212; and I’ve been traveling the country meeting with our incredible small-business owners, but I’ll share with you one story because it is also in the place where I was born: Oakland, California. &nbsp;<br><br>But, last year, I met with a small-business owner.&nbsp; Her name is Reign, and she owns a catering company in Oakland, California.&nbsp; And when she started out &#8212; she was telling me about how she needed a van.&nbsp; And so, she went to a traditional bank and filled out an application for a loan, and she was rejected.<br><br>And she told me about a word that she heard then that I have heard many small-business owners tell me they were presented with as something that was supposed to describe themselves that they had never heard before.&nbsp; That word is “unbankable.”&nbsp; I’ve heard so many small-business owners tell me they were told, as though this is their identity, that they were “unbankable.”<br><br>So, Reign, not being deterred by a word &#8212; (laughter) &#8211;went to a community lender.&nbsp; And that lender, of course, saw her vision to build a catering company that made fresh, local, and sustainable food, cooked with love and served with care.&nbsp; And they, of course, gave Reign that loan to buy that van.<br><br>And, today, Reign runs one of the most successful catering businesses in Oakland.&nbsp; She has catered for clients from the mayor to the Golden State Warriors &#8212; yes &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; from Google to Stanford University.<br><br>So, Reign&#8217;s story is just one of so many.<br><br>Since I took office, I have consulted with some of the most active community lenders in our nation.&nbsp; And I have seen the tremendous difference that these lenders are making in communities across our country.<br><br>Latino communities in urban neighborhoods &#8212; like Columbia Heights, right here in Washington, D.C. &#8212; and rural communities across the country &#8212; like those in Oregon, like Native communities in South Dakota, and Black communities in the Mississippi Delta.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, I’m heading to Mississippi on Friday to be with Bill Bynum.<br><br>Expanding our nation&#8217;s investment in community lenders has been a priority of mine and ours for years.&nbsp; In fact, when I was Senator, together my colleague, the great senator from Maryland, and so many others &#8212; we helped secure $12 billion for community lenders as part of a COVID-19 relief bill.<br><br>And now, with extraordinary partners such as the Secretary of the Treasury, Janet Yellen; Secretary Raimondo; Administrator Guzman, our administration is working to broaden the reach of community lenders.<br><br>And that brings me to one of the reasons that I’m here today, which is to share with you the development of all of this work.<br><br>In 2011, the Small Business Administration launched the Community Advantage pilot loan program.&nbsp; It was a pilot.&nbsp; Through this program, the SBA partially guarantees loans made by community lenders.<br><br>It allows community lenders to make more investments in underserved communities and to make entrepreneurs loans that others might have deemed too risky &#8212; entrepreneurs like Reign.<br><br>Since its founding, the Community Advantage program has helped launch businesses, create jobs, and drive innovation across our nation.&nbsp;<br><br>Originally, the program was scheduled to expire this fall.&nbsp; But today, I am proud to announce that we are extending the Community Advantage program until 2024.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we are expanding it so we will expand the number of lenders in the program and increase the amount of money that they can lend.&nbsp; So, this, of course, means that more small businesses will be able to benefit from the program.<br><br>And, of course, our work collectively is not going to stop there.&nbsp; Since the President and I took office, we have held roundtables, listening sessions, and one-on-one consultations with business owners and community leaners [sic] &#8212; leaders.&nbsp;<br><br>I was saying to the folks who are in the front row here that, you know, the experience that I&#8217;ve had, I know we all have, is, our small-business owners &#8212; they&#8217;re not only leaders in business: They are civic leaders.&nbsp; They are community leaders.&nbsp; They are the ones who sponsor the local softball league.&nbsp; They are the ones who mentor and hire people from the community.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the role models.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>So, when we talk about extending and expanding this program, all of that we have in mind.<br><br>And to better understand, then, how programs like these can serve our best communities, in terms of the best and the brightest, this is the work that we are doing.<br><br>And today, informed by all of those conversations, we are announcing a number of improvements also &#8212; because we heard from folks when we had these meetings &#8212; so, a number of improvements to the Community Advantage program.<br><br>So, for example, we are simplifying program requirements so lenders can devote more of their resources to serving their borrowers and spend less time on the paperwork.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get rid of some of that bureaucracy.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There&#8217;s the lender section.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And we are updating program rules to allow those people who are borrowing to restructure their debt if they fall behind on payments.<br><br>You know, during the pandemic, community lenders demonstrated again and again how much good they do in their communities.&nbsp; So these reforms are intended to make it easier for more lenders to connect with more small businesses who need to borrow or make a loan.&nbsp; And this, of course, will unleash economic opportunity in communities around our country.<br><br>So, the bottom line is this: When small-business owners have the support they need, they create jobs.&nbsp; When small-business owners have the support they need, they drive innovation and inspire innovation.&nbsp; And they grow, as a result of all of that, our entire economy.<br><br>When we talk about how we are doing as a nation and the strength of our nation; and we look to, as a measure of that, the strength of our economy, then we must ask: How are our small businesses doing, and are we doing enough for them?<br><br>Because after all, the answer to all of that will lead us to also understanding: When they do well, it benefits us all.<br><br>And so, let us continue to all work together to address the inequities that stand in the way of the ambition and the aspirations of our communities.<br><br>Let us continue in the mission of encouraging the ambition and the aspiration.&nbsp; And that brings me, of course, before I conclude my comments, to the mission of the Greater Washington Partnership.<br><br>The $4.7 billion investment announced today, over $600 million of which will go to community lenders, is a major step forward not only for the Capital region and the people of this region, but, by example, the role modeling you are doing will benefit people around the country.<br><br>It is truly a model.&nbsp; And it is a model that can and should be replicated around our nation.<br><br>Our collective goal is to create an economy in which every person, wherever they live, has the opportunity to succeed and to thrive.<br><br>Thank you all very much.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 11:30 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Zelenskyy of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-zelenskyy-of-ukraine-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 16:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50070</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden spoke today with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine about the ongoing work by the United States and its allies and partners to deliver military, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and to impose severe costs on Russia for its brutal aggression against Ukraine. The leaders discussed how the United States is working around the clock to fulfill the main security&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden spoke today with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine about the ongoing work by the United States and its allies and partners to deliver military, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and to impose severe costs on Russia for its brutal aggression against Ukraine. The leaders discussed how the United States is working around the clock to fulfill the main security assistance requests by Ukraine, the critical effects those weapons have had on the conflict, and continued efforts by the United States with allies and partners to identify additional capabilities to help the Ukrainian military defend its country. In addition, President Biden informed President Zelenskyy that the United States intends to provide the Ukrainian government with $500 million in direct budgetary aid. He also reviewed the additional sanctions and humanitarian assistance announced last week. President Zelenskyy updated President Biden on the status of Ukraine’s negotiations with Russia. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency With Respect to Significant Malicious Cyber-Enabled&#160;Activities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-significant-malicious-cyber-enabled-activities-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 15:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; On April 1, 2015, by Executive Order 13694, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701&#160;et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by the increasing prevalence and severity of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On April 1, 2015, by Executive Order 13694, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701&nbsp;<em>et seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by the increasing prevalence and severity of malicious cyber‑enabled activities originating from, or directed by persons located, in whole or in substantial part, outside the United States.&nbsp; On December 28, 2016, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13757 to take additional steps to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13694.</p>



<p>These significant malicious cyber-enabled activities continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on April 1, 2015, must continue in effect beyond April 1, 2022. &nbsp;Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1&nbsp;year the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13694.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"><br>                                JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"> <br><br>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>    March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress, on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to South&#160;Sudan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-south-sudan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 15:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:&#160;&#160;Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act, (50&#160;U.S.C.&#160;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&#160;a&#160;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&#160;the Federal&#160;Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act, (50&nbsp;U.S.C.&nbsp;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&nbsp;a&nbsp;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&nbsp;the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13664 of April 3, 2014, with respect to South Sudan is to continue in effect beyond April 3, 2022.</p>



<p>The situation in and in relation to South Sudan, which has been marked by activities that threaten the peace, security, or stability of South Sudan and the surrounding region, including widespread violence and atrocities, human rights abuses, recruitment and use of child soldiers, attacks on peacekeepers, and obstruction of humanitarian operations, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.  Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13664 with respect to South Sudan.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to South&#160;Sudan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-south-sudan-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 15:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 3, 2014, by Executive Order 13664, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the situation in and in relation to South Sudan,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On April 3, 2014, by Executive Order 13664, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the situation in and in relation to South Sudan, which has been marked by activities that threaten the peace, security, or stability of South Sudan and the surrounding region, including widespread violence and atrocities, human rights abuses, recruitment and use of child soldiers, attacks on peacekeepers, and obstruction of humanitarian operations.</p>



<p>The situation in and in relation to South Sudan continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on April 3, 2014, must continue in effect beyond April 3, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13664.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.<br>                                </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br> March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency With Respect to Significant Malicious Cyber-Enabled&#160;Activities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-significant-malicious-cyber-enabled-activities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 15:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&#160;U.S.C.&#160;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&#160;a&#160;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&#160;the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C.&nbsp;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&nbsp;a&nbsp;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&nbsp;the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13694 of April 1, 2015, with respect to significant malicious cyber-enabled activities, is to continue in effect beyond April 1, 2022.</p>



<p>Significant malicious cyber-enabled activities originating from, or directed by persons located, in whole or in substantial part, outside the United States continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States. &nbsp;Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13694 with respect to significant malicious cyber-enabled activities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
