<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 19:09:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Appointments to Boards and&#160;Commissions</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/president-biden-announces-key-appointments-to-boards-and-commissions-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles: Margaret Aitken Haggerty, Member and Chair, Commission on Presidential Scholars Jennifer D. Bishop, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars Kenneth Vernon Brittingham, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars Clifford K. Chiu, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars Mary Quinn Delaney,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Margaret Aitken Haggerty, Member and Chair, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Jennifer D. Bishop, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Kenneth Vernon Brittingham, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Clifford K. Chiu, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Mary Quinn Delaney, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Ryan D. Easterly, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Peter Van D. Emerson, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Antonio Farias, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Neil J. Horgan, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Frank F. Islam, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Cynthia Jackson Hammond, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Dan J. Kessler, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Domenika Lynch, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Sarah McBride, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Rodin A. Mehrbani, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Brian O’Dwyer, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Stephanie Robinson, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Kurt Russell, Sr., Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Juan Antonio Sepúlveda, Jr., Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Terrance Blackman Stroud, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Jason Sung Won Yoon, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li></ul>



<p>The Commission on Presidential Scholars is a group of eminent private citizens appointed by the President to select and honor the Presidential Scholars. Commissioners are selected from across the country, representing the fields of education, medicine, law, social services, business, and other professions. The Commissioners make the final selection of the 161 Presidential Scholars. The Scholars demonstrate exceptional accomplishments in academics, the arts, career and technical education and an outstanding commitment to public service.<br><br><strong>Margaret Aitken Haggerty, Member and Chair, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Margaret Aitken Haggerty is a seasoned communications professional who works with local, national, and international businesses and nonprofit organizations, providing them with strategic communication counsel, crisis communication planning, messaging strategy, and media intervention. Prior to founding her own firm, for more than a decade Aitken served as the Spokesperson and Press Secretary for then-Senator, now President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Throughout her career, she has collaborated with and advised top government officials, political candidates, and business executives and has served on the boards of several philanthropic organizations.<br><br>Aitken is a native Delawarean and resides in Wilmington with her husband Chris, and sons Ronan and Cullen. She is a graduate of the University of Delaware and holds a master’s degree in Communication and Media Studies from Johns Hopkins University.<br><br><strong>Jennifer D. Bishop, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Born in Chicago, Illinois and raised in Atlanta, Georgia, Dr. Jennifer Bishop has wide-ranging experience as an entrepreneur, author, speaker, philanthropist, and faith and community leader. In addition to serving as Chief Executive Officer for the Savannah Communications Group, BishopSpeaks, and Grace Academy Child Development Center, Bishop also serves in the non-profit sector as Chief Executive Officer for RARE Leaders and the APEX Institute. She is currently seated as the Chairwoman for the City of Columbia Commercial Revolving Loan Fund Committee. Bishop earned her Bachelor of Arts in History and Master of Public Administration at Savannah State University and her Ph.D. in Organizational Leadership from Columbia International University. Bishop has committed herself to expanding educational opportunities through her professional activity as well as working with organizations like the Children’s Trust of South Carolina, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc., and Jack &amp; Jill of America. Making her home in Columbia, South Carolina, Bishop is married to Dr. Aaron Bishop, and they are the proud parents of one son, Peyton.<br><br><strong>Kenneth Vernon Brittingham, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Ken Brittingham is a leader in learning whose working life has been devoted to improving the quality of education for children, youth, families, and adult learners. As a counselor, school psychologist, principal, school superintendent, state education director, and technical college board Vice Chairman and Board President, Brittingham has provided leadership at the elementary, middle school, high school, higher education, and state education department levels. His lifetime work has centered on creating the conditions where all learners achieve at high levels. At the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction, he served as the State Director of the Bureau of Exceptional Children and co-authored a statewide distributed book on improving career development programs in local schools. He has a bachelor’s degree in Industrial Technology, a masters in school counseling, and a masters in school psychology. His Doctorate of Philosophy was earned at the University of Wisconsin, and he was invited to the American Association of Educational Research annual convention to present his dissertation on improving school community relationships.<br><br><strong>Clifford K. Chiu, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Clifford K. Chiu serves as a senior adviser to Vista Equity Partners and its executive committee. Chiu sits as a corporate director on the boards of Aquia, Allvue Systems, Apptio, Finastra, Fusion Risk Management, Logic Monitor, Securonix, and TIBCO, as well as a senior adviser to Neuberger Berman in Hong Kong. He is a member of the National Committee on United States-China Relations and a public appointee on the advisory panel of Cyberport Hong Kong. With a career spanning over four decades, Chiu was a partner of Kohlberg Kravis Roberts &amp; Co. where he founded and led capital raising and investor relations for the Asia Pacific region. He was previously at JP Morgan Asset Management and at Salomon Smith Barney/Citigroup and its predecessors based in New York, Hong Kong, and Tokyo.<br><br>Chiu is a director or trustee of the Seton Fund, Greater Austin Asian Chamber of Commerce, Health Alliance for Austin Musicians, and St. James Settlement. A lifelong champion of education and healthcare, Chiu has served on the global advisory boards of the Weingarten Learning Resources Center at the University of Pennsylvania and of the University of Chicago Booth School of Business where in 2015 he was appointed the first “distinguished executive-in-residence” at its Hong Kong campus. Through the Clinton Global Initiative, Chiu launched a 2015 commitment to action, “K-12 Learning Through Global Connectivity” in language arts and STEM skills. Chiu also endowed annual scholarships at his alma maters Chicago Booth and the University of Pennsylvania as well as the Hong Kong University Medical School, Pomona College, and the Tuck School of Business at Dartmouth. Chiu has partnered with Dell Seton and Ascension Seton Medical Centers in student mental health, underinsured COVID-19 pandemic patients, and maternal morbidity. Chiu proudly underwrote Stop AAPI Hate&#8217;s first-ever impact report (“Turning a Moment into a Movement”) that was released in January 2022.<br><br><strong>Mary Quinn Delaney, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Quinn Delaney is the Founder and Board Chair of Akonadi Foundation, located in Oakland, California, which supports the development of powerful social change movements to eliminate structural racism and create a racially just society. Delaney has spent over thirty-five years working in social change philanthropy.<br><br>In addition to Akonadi Foundation, she currently serves on the boards of East Bay Community Foundation, the Oakland Museum of California, Planned Parenthood Action Fund, Women Donors Network Action, and Smart Justice California, which works on criminal justice reform. Over the years, she has served on many other boards, including the ACLU of Northern California, Community Change, the Democracy Alliance, Tides Foundation, and Pitzer College. In 2019, Delaney was appointed to the California Commission on the Status of Women and Girls where she continues to serve as a Commissioner championing the power and strength of women and girls. She is married to Wayne Jordan and has two adult sons and two grandchildren.<br><br><strong>Ryan D. Easterly, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Ryan Easterly serves as executive director of the WITH Foundation. An experienced grantmaker, strategist, and advocate, Easterly lives and works at the intersections of race, class, disability, and sexual orientation and is driven by a desire to effect meaningful change. Before joining WITH, he served on its Board of Directors, which advanced his commitment to disability justice and the need for broader access to comprehensive healthcare for adults with developmental disabilities. Easterly has worked in the federal sector and within community outreach and advocacy efforts. He is a co-founder and previous director of Northern California Community Relations at MySupport, Inc. As manager of the National Youth Transitions Initiative for The HSC Foundation, a Washington, DC operating foundation of a health system for children and young adults with complex medical needs, he provided funding and programmatic support for a grantee and collaborative network serving young people with disabilities and young veterans. Easterly also worked at the U.S. Department of Labor’s Office of Disability Employment Policy.<br><br>Easterly regularly advises on issues such as community participatory grantmaking, inclusive philanthropy, leadership development, employment, and healthcare impacting communities of color, the foster care system, and the LGBTQ+ community. He is a member of the Presidents’ Council on Disability Inclusion in Philanthropy, the Disability &amp; Philanthropy Forum Steering Committee, and co-chairs Exponent Philanthropy’s Disability Funders Peer Circle. Easterly hails from Alabama, and after moving to the West Coast, often wonders when he will find his next glass of sweet tea.<br><br><strong>Peter Van D. Emerson, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Peter Van D. Emerson is an entrepreneur in business and public policy. He is co-founder of KAPE International, LLC, a global strategic communications firm, an Advisor on Policy for the Division on Addiction, Cambridge Health Alliance, a teaching affiliate of Harvard Medical School, and Chairman, College Task Force on College Gambling and Alcohol Policies. As a teaching assistant at Harvard College, he was twice awarded a Certificate of Distinction in Teaching. Emerson works with students on the critical challenges of addiction and mental health.<br><br>Emerson has served on the Board of Visitors for the University of North Carolina-Wilmington. He was elected to the American Academy of Underwater Sciences and The Explorers Club. Emerson served on the Ocean Futures’ Board and the Advisory Committee for the NY Aquarium, part of the Wildlife Conservation Society. His previous public service includes the National Advisory Committee on Oceans and Atmosphere and the President’s Commission on White House Fellowships. Emerson received a BA from New York University, <em>magna cum laude,</em> and a MPA from the Harvard Kennedy School.<br><br><strong>Antonio Farias, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Antonio Farias serves as the Vice Chancellor for Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion responsible for driving and developing initiatives that build on and advance CU Denver’s commitment to equity and justice. Farias joined CU Denver from the University of Florida, where he served as its inaugural Chief Diversity Officer and Senior Advisor to the President. There he oversaw university-wide efforts to advance The Big I.D.E.A! – Inclusion, Diversity, Equity, &amp; Access. Farias worked closely with cabinet members, deans, and a network of campus diversity liaisons embedded in the leadership teams of each college and business unit, who advanced I.D.E.A. within their respective micro cultures. Farias was previously Vice President for Equity and Inclusion at Wesleyan University and, before that, the inaugural Chief Diversity Officer for the U.S. Coast Guard Academy. He has bachelor’s and master’s degrees from the University of California, Berkeley and a Master of Fine Arts from the University of California, Riverside. He worships his daughter, reenergizes through a plant-based diet, runs ultra-marathons to test the limits of WHY, fly fishes to commune with the divine, and believes failure is the greatest teacher. He is currently failing to publish his first novel.<br><br><strong>Neil J. Horgan, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Horgan was born in Chester, Pennsylvania and raised in Wilmington, Delaware, and is a graduate of Archmere Academy. He earned a Bachelor’s of Science in Business Administration from Georgetown University with a major in Accounting and a Master of Taxation from Villanova University. Horgan is presently the Vice President for Finance and Chief Financial Officer at Villanova University. He lives in Havertown, PA with his wife Kathryn and their two children. Horgan previously served on the Board of Directors of the Mercy Health System of Southeastern Pennsylvania.<br><br><strong>Frank F. Islam, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Frank Islam is an entrepreneur, philanthropist, and civic leader with a special commitment to civic, educational, and artistic causes. He currently heads the FI Investment Group, a private investment holding company that he founded after he sold his information technology firm, the QSS Group, in 2007. Islam serves and has served on numerous boards and advisory councils including the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, the U.N. Foundation, the U.S. Institute of Peace, and the Woodrow Wilson Center. He has also served or serves on boards and councils at several universities including John Hopkins, American University, George Mason University, the University of Maryland, and Harvard University.<br><br>Islam has written two well-regarded books on the American condition: <em>Working the Pivot Points: To Make America Work Again</em> and <em>Renewing the American Dream: A Citizen’s Guide for Restoring Our Competitive Advantage</em>. He blogs regularly on Medium and was a contributor to the Huffington Post for nearly a decade. In 2018, Islam established the Frank Islam Institute for 21<sup>st</sup> Century Citizenship which maintains a website and publishes a monthly newsletter featuring articles and other material directed at addressing the civic engagement deficit and challenges to democracy in the U.S. and internationally. Islam received his B.S. and M.S. in Computer Science from the University of Colorado at Boulder.<br><br><strong>Cynthia Jackson Hammond, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Dr. Cynthia Jackson Hammond is President of the Council for Higher Education Accreditation (CHEA). As President, she has led several initiatives including the development and adoption of CHEA’s value statement on diversity, equity, and inclusion and an enhanced focus on service to CHEA’s over 1,900 member institutions. Jackson Hammond has been a member of the higher education community for more than 30 years. Her professional career has included tenured and administrative positions at universities throughout the United States, including the University of Louisiana Monroe, California State University Dominguez Hills, Delaware State University, the University of North Carolina Charlotte, Winston-Salem State University, and Coppin State University. Most recently, she completed her tenure as President of Central State University in Ohio. She holds graduate degrees in Communications, Counseling Education, Student Personnel Services, and Higher Education Administration.<br><br>Jackson Hammond has served on many national boards including the Thurgood Marshall College Fund, NCAA Division II Presidents Council, the American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, and the Council for Higher Education Accreditation. She has appeared several times on Capitol Hill providing testimony regarding the status of 1890 Land-Grant institutions. Throughout her career, Jackson Hammond has been committed to advancing college success, equity, and integrity in higher education. She is an ardent advocate for quality assurance and transparency in higher education.<br><br><strong>Dan J. Kessler, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Dan Kessler is the Co-Founder and Managing Partner of K2 Developers, a company developing and repurposing existing buildings into dignified, economical housing for essential workers in ski, sand, and entertainment destinations across the United States. Working with K2, a public REIT and an investment fund, Kessler has worked to close $4 billion and 10 million square feet of real estate transactions. Prior to co-founding K2 Developers, Kessler worked in hospitality in executive leadership programs at Marriott International and MGM Resorts International in Las Vegas.<br><br>Kessler’s civic activity began with his days as a White House Intern for President Obama. He is currently a Political Partner with the Truman National Security Project and a New Leaders Council Fellow. Kessler has received various awards and recognitions, including a 40Under40 Award from both the Philadelphia Business Journal and City &amp; State Pennsylvania, and received a 30Under30 Award from Politics PA. Kessler was invited by The Council of Europe and delivered a speech at the World Forum for Democracy in Strasbourg, France, where his grassroots engagement strategy placed second amongst thousands for the “Democracy Innovation Award” and was published in MIT Sloan Experts. Kessler graduated with his MBA from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology’s Sloan School of Management and BBA<em>, summa cum laude</em>, from The George Washington University School of Business.<br><br><strong>Domenika Lynch, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Domenika Lynch is the Executive Director of the Aspen Institute Latinos and Society Program, with the mission of empowering Latino communities and promoting long-term economic growth and resiliency. Over the course of two decades in leadership roles, Lynch has overseen strategic planning, policy advocacy, and public affairs campaigns for nonprofits and corporations, increasing donor and stakeholder support and raising millions of dollars for organizational endowments.<br><br>Prior to joining the Aspen Institute, Lynch served as president and CEO of the Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute, the preeminent Latino Leadership Institute founded by Hispanic members of Congress in Washington, DC. She previously spent more than a decade as executive director of the Latino Alumni Association at the University of Southern California. Her professional breadth extends into the corporate sector, with previous leadership positions at Bank of America and Univision. Lynch currently serves on the Board of Directors of the Congressional Management Foundation and serves on Bank of America’s National Community Advisory Council, which advises the bank on community development, environmental, and consumer policy issues. She also serves on the Council on Underserved Communities, which provides the U.S. Small Business Administration with input, advice, and recommendations on strategies to help strengthen competitiveness and sustainability for small businesses in underserved communities. A graduate of the USC Price School of Public Policy, Lynch holds a master’s degree from the USC Rossier School of Education. She is the proud parent of her son Jacob, also a USC alumnus.<br><br><strong>Sarah McBride, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Senator Sarah McBride represents the First Senate District in the Delaware Senate. McBride serves as the chair of the Health and Social Services Committee, where she has championed health care reforms that lower costs, expand access, and improve quality. In just her first term, McBride successfully passed paid family and medical leave in the First State, marking the largest expansion of Delaware&#8217;s social safety net in decades. Prior to her service in the state senate, McBride was a national leader in the fight for LGBTQ equality and served as the spokesperson for the Human Rights Campaign. When she was elected, McBride became the first openly transgender state senator in American history.<br><br><strong>Rodin A. Mehrbani, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Rudy Mehrbani is the senior director of the Governance Program at Democracy Fund, an independent foundation. Mehrbani is also a senior practitioner fellow at the University of Chicago’s Center for Effective Government. He was previously a senior fellow and senior counsel at the Brennan Center for Justice, a nonpartisan law and policy center, where he worked to protect voting rights and directed the National Task Force on Rule of Law and Democracy. From 2016 to 2021, he was a member of the J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board, where he served as the Board’s vice chair from 2019 to 2020.<br><br>Mehrbani served in a variety of senior roles in the Obama-Biden Administration. From 2016 to 2017, he was an Assistant to the President and Director of the Presidential Personnel Office in the White House. In that role, he was also a member of the White House Transition Coordinating Council. He was the General Counsel of the Peace Corps from 2014 to 2016, serving as the principal legal officer and a senior advisor to the Director of the Peace Corps. Before that, he served as an Associate Counsel and Special Assistant to the President in the White House Counsel’s Office. Earlier in his career, Mehrbani was a litigation associate at Kirkland &amp; Ellis LLP. He received a BA from Emory University and a JD from the University of Virginia School of Law.<br><br><strong>Brian O’Dwyer, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Brian O’Dwyer has distinguished himself in the law and education. He is a founder of the Emerald Isle Immigration Center dedicated to providing assistance to all immigrants. His work in promoting peace in Ireland was acknowledged when he was named Grand Marshall of the New York Saint Patrick’s Day Parade. A longtime advocate for equal access to higher education, he has served as Chair of the CUNY Law School Foundation, Chair of the Advisory Council of the George Washington University Graduate School of Political Management, and Board Member of Dublin City University Educational Trust.<br><br>O’Dwyer has earned an AB and LLM from the George Washington University, a JD from Georgetown University, and an MA from Middlebury College. He is a member of Sigma Delta Pi national Spanish honorary and has been awarded the honorary degrees of Doctor of Philosophy from Dublin City University and Doctor of Humane Letters from Middlebury College.<br><br><strong>Stephanie Robinson, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Stephanie Robinson is a Board Member and advisor to educational, healthcare, and cultural organizations. She currently serves as a publicly-elected Trustee for the Ross School District in California, a position she has held since 2015, and as a Director and Vice Chair of the MarinHealth Foundation. Previously, Robinson worked as a Vice President in Health Care Investment Banking at Bankers Trust and as a management consultant at the Boston Consulting Group. She is active in local, state, and national politics as a fundraiser, community organizer, and voter protection volunteer. She holds an MBA from Harvard Business School, a JD from Harvard Law School, and a BA from UC Berkeley in Economics.<br><br><strong>Kurt Russell, Sr., Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Kurt Russell, the 2022 National Teacher of the Year, is a veteran teacher at Oberlin High School in the Oberlin City Schools district who believes education can transform students’ lives. For the past twenty-five years, Russell has included cultural relevance in the curriculum for the 9<sup>th</sup>-12<sup>th</sup> grade classes he teaches: African American History, U.S. History, IB History of the Americas, and Race, Gender, and Oppression. Russell received the teacher of the year awards from the Oberlin Heritage Center and the Oberlin Chapter of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. In addition to teaching history classes, Russell also serves as a lead teacher at Oberlin High School and advisor for the Black Student Union, Student Council, and Junior Class.<br><br><strong>Juan Antonio Sepúlveda, Jr., Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Sepúlveda currently serves as the President’s Special Advisor for Inclusive Excellence and the Ron Calgaard Distinguished Professor of Practice in the Political Science Department at Trinity University in San Antonio, Texas. Prior to Trinity, he was Senior Vice President of Station Services at PBS, where he collaborated with more than 160 PBS stations across the country to strengthen their connections to their local communities and to each other as a national public media network. Sepúlveda joined PBS from the Democratic National Committee, where he was Senior Advisor for Hispanic Affairs helping re-elect President Barack Obama with record-level Hispanic support. In 2008, Sepúlveda served as the Texas State Director for the Obama for America campaign.</p>



<p>In the Obama-Biden Administration, Sepúlveda served as Executive Director of the White House Initiative on Educational Excellence for Hispanics, where he designed and led the first-ever White House Hispanic Policy Conference along with a series of White House Hispanic Community Action Summits. His national strategy consulting organization, the Common Enterprise, which grew out of a national Rockefeller Foundation initiative, took him to more than 35 states where he worked with communities in urban and rural settings. Sepúlveda was the third Latino awarded a Rhodes Scholarship. He graduated from Harvard College with a Bachelor of Arts in Government. He also holds a Master of Arts in Politics, Philosophy &amp; Economics from The Queen’s College, Oxford University, a Juris Doctorate from Stanford Law School, and has been admitted to the Texas Bar.<br><br><strong>Terrance Blackman Stroud, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Terrance Blackman Stroud is a Deputy Commissioner at the New York City Department of Social Services leading the Office of Training &amp; Workforce Development, which manages the development and implementation of the agency’s learning strategy. Stroud serves on the National Staff Development Training Association’s Executive Advisory Council and the Public Sector Network’s Leadership Advisory Board. He is also one of the Tri-chairs of the American Public Human Services Association’s Equity Diversity and Inclusion Peer Community.<br><br>Stroud is a fourth-generation educator whose focus is on the intersection of academic institutions and the global workforce. He is a New York-based adjunct faculty member at Indiana University Bloomington. He is the inaugural Global Affairs Fellow at the Hamilton Lugar School of Global and International Studies where he leads the Global Leaders and Professionals Program. In addition, Stroud is an Adjunct Professor of Law overseeing the Maurer School of Law’s New York Externship Program and is the first Black recipient of the Adjunct Faculty Teaching Award. Stroud is a graduate of Brooklyn Technical High School, Brooklyn College, and Indiana Maurer School of Law.<br><br><strong>Jason Sung Won Yoon, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Jason Yoon has dedicated much of his career to supporting the talent and creativity of America’s young people. He has served as the executive director of New Urban Arts, a nationally recognized nonprofit youth arts studio (winner of a 2009 National Arts and Humanities Youth Program Award); the Director of Education at the Queens Museum, a museum renowned for its commitment to art, education, and social justice; and the executive director of Atlas: DIY, a nonprofit that worked with immigrant youth through legal services, educational programs, and leadership development. For several years, he also taught art and social change in Goucher College’s MA program in Cultural Sustainability. Currently, Yoon is working on several personal creative writing projects and as the interim development manager for Sakhi for South Asian Women, a groundbreaking gender justice organization. Yoon has a Bachelor of Fine Arts from the Rhode Island School of Design and a Masters in Public Administration from NYU’s Wagner School of Public Service.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Signs Executive Order Creating a Presidential Emergency&#160;Board </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/president-biden-signs-executive-order-creating-a-presidential-emergency-board/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order establishing a Presidential Emergency Board, effective July 18, 2022, to help resolve an ongoing dispute between major freight rail carriers and their unions. Keeping supply chains running means keeping America’s railways running. In making the decision to create the Presidential Emergency Board, the President has considered input from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order establishing a Presidential Emergency Board, effective July 18, 2022, to help resolve an ongoing dispute between major freight rail carriers and their unions.<br><br>Keeping supply chains running means keeping America’s railways running. In making the decision to create the Presidential Emergency Board, the President has considered input from relevant stakeholders. The President’s goal is to make sure America’s freight rail system continues to run without disruption, delivering the items that our families, communities, farms and businesses rely on.<br><br>The Presidential Emergency Board will provide a structure for workers and management to resolve their disagreements.  The Board will investigate the dispute and, within 30 days of its establishment, deliver a report recommending how the dispute should be resolved.<br><br>By statute, the Executive Order triggers a “cooling off” period intended to keep the parties working toward a negotiated settlement.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Establishing an Emergency Board to Investigate Disputes Between Certain Railroads Represented by the National Carriers’ Conference Committee of the National Railway Labor Conference and Their Employees Represented by Certain Labor&#160;Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/15/executive-order-on-establishing-an-emergency-board-to-investigate-disputes-between-certain-railroads-represented-by-the-national-carriers-conference-committee-of-the-national-railway-labor-co/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Disputes exist between certain railroads represented by the National Carriers&#8217; Conference Committee of the National Railway Labor Conference and their employees represented by certain labor organizations. &#160;The railroads and labor organizations involved in these disputes are designated on the attached list, which is made part of this order. The disputes have not heretofore been&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Disputes exist between certain railroads represented by the National Carriers&#8217; Conference Committee of the National Railway Labor Conference and their employees represented by certain labor organizations. &nbsp;The railroads and labor organizations involved in these disputes are designated on the attached list, which is made part of this order.</p>



<p>The disputes have not heretofore been adjusted under the provisions of the Railway Labor Act, as amended, 45 U.S.C. 151-188 (RLA).</p>



<p>I have been notified by the National Mediation Board that in its judgment these disputes threaten substantially to interrupt interstate commerce to a degree that would deprive a section of the country of essential transportation service.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, by the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including section 10 of the RLA (45 U.S.C. 160), it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1. &nbsp;Establishment of Emergency Board (Board). &nbsp;There is established, effective 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on July 18, 2022, a Board composed of a chair and two other members, all of whom shall be appointed by the President to investigate and report on these disputes. &nbsp;No member shall be pecuniarily or otherwise interested in any organization of railroad employees or any carrier. &nbsp;The Board shall perform its functions subject to the availability of funds.</p>



<p>Sec. 2. &nbsp;Report. &nbsp;The Board shall report to the President with respect to the disputes within 30 days of its creation.</p>



<p>Sec. 3. &nbsp;Maintaining Conditions. &nbsp;As provided by section 10 of the RLA, from the date of the creation of the Board and for 30 days after the Board has submitted its report to the President, no change in the conditions out of which the disputes arose shall be made by the parties to the controversy, except by agreement of the parties.</p>



<p>Sec. 4. &nbsp;Records Maintenance. &nbsp;The records and files of the Board are records of the Office of the President and upon the Board&#8217;s termination shall be maintained in the physical custody of the National Mediation Board.</p>



<p>Sec. 5. &nbsp;Expiration. &nbsp;The Board shall terminate upon the submission of the report provided for in section 2 of this order.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 15, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/statement-by-president-joe-biden-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 18:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57661</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Action on climate change and clean energy remains more urgent than ever. &#160; So let me be clear:&#160; if the Senate will not move to tackle the climate crisis and strengthen our domestic clean energy industry, I will take strong executive action to meet this moment.&#160; My actions will&#160;create jobs, improve our energy security, bolster&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Action on climate change and clean energy remains more urgent than ever. &nbsp;</p>



<p>So let me be clear:&nbsp; if the Senate will not move to tackle the climate crisis and strengthen our domestic clean energy industry, I will take strong executive action to meet this moment.&nbsp; My actions will&nbsp;create jobs, improve our energy security, bolster domestic manufacturing and supply chains, protect us from oil&nbsp;and gas&nbsp;price hikes in the future, and address climate change.&nbsp;&nbsp;I will not back down:&nbsp;the opportunity to create jobs and build a clean energy future is too important to relent.</p>



<p>Health care is also critical.  After decades of fierce opposition from powerful special interests, Democrats have come together, beaten back the pharmaceutical industry and are prepared to give Medicare the power to negotiate lower drug prices and to prevent an increase in health insurance premiums for millions of families with coverage under the Affordable Care Act.  Families all over the nation will sleep easier if Congress takes this action.  The Senate should move forward, pass it before the August recess, and get it to my desk so I can sign it.</p>



<p>This will not only lower the cost of prescription drugs and health care for families, it will reduce the deficit and help fight inflation.</p>



<p>I want to thank Leader Schumer for his dogged and determined effort to produce the strongest possible bill to bring down costs, reduce the deficit, and combat the climate crisis while boosting our energy security – even offering significant compromises to try to reach an agreement.&nbsp; I also want to thank Speaker Pelosi for her leadership &#8211; thanks to her hard work, the House passed a strong bill on climate change and reducing costs last year.&nbsp; Now, Congress must act quickly and get legislation to my desk to deliver for American families.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Jeddah, Saudi&#160;Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/15/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-jeddah-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 16:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Jeddah, Saudi Arabia 4:50 P.M. AST MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Okay, I just have a few things at the top.&#160; Welcome aboard our historic flight from Israel to Saudi Arabia.&#160; As you all have heard us say many times before, this will be the first time a President has ever flown from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Jeddah, Saudi Arabia</p>



<p>4:50 P.M. AST</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, I just have a few things at the top.&nbsp; Welcome aboard our historic flight from Israel to Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; As you all have heard us say many times before, this will be the first time a President has ever flown from Israel to Jeddah, and we are glad to have you with us as we make this histori- &#8212; historic trip on Air Force One.</p>



<p>It follows the monumental decision to open Saudi airspace to all civilian carriers without discrimination, a decision that includes flights to and from Israel.&nbsp; We commend that progress, which is the result of President Biden’s persistent and principled diplomacy with Saudi Arabia over many months.&nbsp; That paves the way for a more integrated, stable, and secure Middle East.</p>



<p>Now, with that, I will give you National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I’ll be very brief and then take your questions.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll be landing soon in Jeddah.&nbsp; The President, tonight, will have bilateral engagements with the Saudi leadership, and then tomorrow he&#8217;ll have bilateral engagements with the leadership of Egypt, the UAE, and Iraq, and then participate in the GCC+3 Summit, at which he will lay out clearly and substantively his vision and his strategy for America&#8217;s engagement in the Middle East.</p>



<p>As he has said on this trip, he&#8217;s intent on ensuring that there is not a vacuum in the Middle East for China and Russia to fill, that American leadership and an American engagement will be a feature of U.S. policy in this region, and that we intend to play a critical role in this strategically vital region on an ongoing basis.</p>



<p>He will cover the waterfront in both his bilateral and multilateral engagements, from security to economics, to regional integration, to cooperation on the big global challenges of our time, to human rights and forcefully advocating for America&#8217;s values and for the President&#8217;s personal priorities.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ll see all of that unfold over the course of the next 24 hours before we get on the flight home.</p>



<p>And with that, I&#8217;d be happy to take your questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you expecting any agreements on increased production of oil to result from this meeting?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We will discuss energy security at this meeting.&nbsp; The President discusses it when he&#8217;s in Europe, when he&#8217;s in Asia, and he certainly will be discussing it here in the Middle East and here in Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>Just to take a step back: Before we announced the trip, you saw an announcement from OPEC+ on accelerating and increasing production.&nbsp; We will discuss the issue here, and we are hopeful that we will see additional actions by OPEC+ in the coming weeks.</p>



<p>And if you recall, when I spoke at the podium on Monday, somebody asked me how do you measure progress on the energy question, and I said it&#8217;ll be measured over the course of weeks.</p>



<p>That has been our plan going in.&nbsp; That is our plan on this plane.&nbsp; That will be our plan coming out.</p>



<p>So I don&#8217;t think you should expect a particular announcement here bilaterally because we believe any further action taken to ensure that there is sufficient energy to protect the health of the global economy will be done in the context of OPEC+.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But on the visit in the West Bank today, I don&#8217;t think he mentioned his pledge from the campaign on reopening the U.S. Consulate in East Jerusalem.&nbsp; Was that &#8212; why didn&#8217;t he talk about that issue?&nbsp; And was that &#8212; did he talk to President Abbas about that in their private meeting?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; He did speak with President Abbas about his consistent policy, from when he was candidate to as President over the last 18 months, to reopen the consulate.&nbsp; That continues to be the U.S. position, and we continue to engage with both the Israelis and Palestinians on the issue.&nbsp; And we spoke with both the Israelis and Palestinians on the issue on this trip.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, a follow-up to that.&nbsp; My colleague was told by a Palestinian official there, locally on the ground, that the reason the United States and the Palestinians were unable to put out a joint statement is because there was disagreements that East Jerusalem should be referred to as the future capital of a Palestinian state, and I wanted to hear what you all say.&nbsp; That was what we &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; First, in general, I don&#8217;t want to characterize diplomatic discussions that are private.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I think that that is not an accurate reflection of the back-and-forth that led to a decision that was reached really rapidly &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t like a lot of to-ing and fro-ing &#8212; that the best way for us to articulate the President&#8217;s vision and our vision with respect to the stop in Bethlehem was for us to put out our own statement, a statement that the Palestinian leadership very much welcomed and praised to us.&nbsp; So that was just how we chose to proceed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can I ask you: Does the President plan, when he&#8217;s meeting Saudi officials, to raise the issue of U.S. Saudi citizens under arrest under travel ban in Saudi Arabia and other specific cases you have in mind?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; You heard the President yesterday say that he doesn&#8217;t preview the specific points he is going to raise in a meeting with anyone on this trip or other trips.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You also heard him say yesterday that he always raises human rights, and that will be no different on this trip.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve heard him in the past say that cases of American citizens are a priority for him everywhere and they&#8217;re a priority for us in Saudi just as they are in many other countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I won&#8217;t go further than that today other than to lay out those basic principles.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where he is as he heads into these meetings.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Khashoggi, to follow up on what Steve asked him at the press conference yesterday: His widow left meetings with U.S. officials with the understanding that the President would raise his specific case with MBS.&nbsp; But yesterday, it seemed like the President was dancing around it a little bit, saying, “I&#8217;m never shying away from raising human rights.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Does that mean he&#8217;s not going &#8212; can you just, like, explain and clarify?&nbsp; Is he going to &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s wrong to say the President was dancing around it.&nbsp; The President made two very direct, very clear statements, which should come as no surprise to you all who travel with him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First statement: He doesn&#8217;t describe the details of what he is going to raise in meetings, particularly before he&#8217;s had them, because he wants to go have those meetings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second statement: He always raises issues of human rights, and this will be no different.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s what he said yesterday.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I&#8217;m saying today.&nbsp; And that will be the case on his trip.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But why not just say that he&#8217;s going to bring it up &#8212; that he&#8217;s going to bring up Jamal Khashoggi’s case?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; As I said, the President believes very strongly that his ability to be effective as a leader and his ability to engage effectively diplomatically depends on his ability to be able to have direct diplomacy without playing out all of these issues in the press.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, what he will stand behind and send a very clear message on, and did yesterday, is the proposition that fundamental issues of human rights are going to be on the agenda.&nbsp; He is going to raise them.&nbsp; He is going to be the way he always is, which is direct, straightforward, and candid.&nbsp; And then, after the meetings conclude, he&#8217;ll make a determination about how he wants to characterize that to all of you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, how firm were the demands of the Saudis that President Biden make this trip to pay &#8212; provide presidential, personal attention to the Crown Prince, given their frustration that he, in their words, maligned the Kingdom during the campaign, describing it as a “pariah”?&nbsp; Take us behind the scenes of that and his desire, or lack of desire, to have to make this visit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The trip did not emerge as a request.&nbsp; The trip emerged as a strategic decision the President made to make sure that the United States was firmly planting its flag in this region for the long term because of the President&#8217;s view that, at this point, you cannot break apart geographies and choose to focus only in some places and not in others, and his view that the Middle East remains a strategically vital region.&nbsp; And as he has said, he&#8217;s not going to leave an American vacuum here to China and Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President also, from the very beginning of his term &#8212; not just in the last few weeks or in the last few months &#8212; has directed a policy of recalibrating, not rupturing, the relationship with Saudi Arabia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s not a line that just appeared in his op-ed two weeks ago.&nbsp; That was our position in the opening 60 days of the administration when we took steps in relation to the Khashoggi report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there&#8217;s been some, I think, revisionist history around the idea that he&#8217;s just alighted upon this approach.&nbsp; In fact, it&#8217;s been the approach since the beginning of the administration: recalibrate, not rupture.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, then his view was: “In order for me to effectively engage and advocate for a sustained and sustainable and effective American strategy in the Middle East, I want to gather the leaders, nine of them.”&nbsp; And Saudi Arabia is, in fact, the host of the GCC.&nbsp; So, this will be the natural location to hold that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, of course, if you come to a summit being hosted by a country, a bilateral program with that country is de rigueur.&nbsp; It would be odd not to go ahead and have that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s how the logic train unfolded.&nbsp; So, he is looking forward to engaging on a substantive basis to advance American interests with the Saudi leadership tonight and then looking forward to the broader summit tomorrow, because he believes that at the end of that, the strategic position of the United States both regionally and globally will be enhanced.&nbsp; And the countries who are most nervous and, at some level, opposed to what he&#8217;s doing are Russia, China, and Iran.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he wanted to make this trip all along: yes or no?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t know about what you mean by “all along.”&nbsp; Because &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; From the beginning of his term, this has been a priority to go to Saudi?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m (inaudible) &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m asking.&nbsp; I’m asking.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; And just to be clear, what I was saying from the beginning of his term was that his policy direction was “recalibrate, not rupture.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The question of the trip really emerged earlier this year when we were looking at an arc of engagement globally that included a trip to the Indo-Pacific in May on the heels of a special summit with ASEAN; a trip to Europe for the G7 and NATO in June; the Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles in June; and then the African Leaders Summit, which will take place later this year in Washington.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What&#8217;s left out of that arc is the Middle East.&nbsp; And so, the President directed his team to think about an approach that would get him to the Middle East in a way where he could effectively engage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That was some months ago.&nbsp; And so, since then, we have been engaged, yes, with the Saudis, but with other countries as well, to pull together all of the elements of this trip.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yesterday, the President referred to the fact that he would not wait indefinitely for the Iranians to come to the table for this nuclear deal.&nbsp; Can you help clarify what that means?&nbsp; I mean, there&#8217;s no doubt that some of the GCC countries are also equally concerned about Iranians obtaining a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve said before, and it&#8217;s consistent with what the President said yesterday: We&#8217;re not circling a date on the calendar.&nbsp; The deal is on the table.&nbsp; Should the Iranians choose to take it, we&#8217;re ready for a compliance-for-compliance return.<br><br>But we&#8217;re also not waiting to continue to impose economic pressure on Iran &#8212; further economic pressure on Iran to include two rounds of sanctions designations that we have done to enforce the sanctions and crack down on smuggling and deprive Iran of sources of revenue.<br><br>We&#8217;ll continue to do that, even as we work at the negotiating table to try to produce a return to the JCPOA.<br><br>But as I said, this will not stay open indefinitely and we&#8217;re not circling a date on the calendar.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, to follow up on what you were saying earlier about the summit tomorrow and the President looking to put his imprint on the region, is he looking to come in just to make his case to the leaders?&nbsp; Is he looking for a specific commitment?&nbsp; Like, what is his mindset going into this?</p>



<p><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think his mindset is twofold.&nbsp; One, you know Joe Biden; he feels very strongly about direct engagement, so he wants the opportunity to sit around the table with these leaders and hear from them and be able to share his views in full so they understand where he&#8217;s coming from and he understands where they&#8217;re coming from.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s the first thing.<br><br>The second thing is there are very specific steps that they will be discussing tomorrow.&nbsp; Some involve regional integration, including Iraq&#8217;s integration in the region, including deepening economic integration among some of the key states that will be sitting around that table.<br><br>A stronger GCC after a period of real rift and division in the GCC, that will be discussed; tighter coordination and collaboration when it comes to Iran and its various destabilizing activities; support from the GCC for the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment so that our high-standards alternative for global infrastructure investment gets the backing of countries that have a lot to bring to the table as we look to do digital infrastructure, energy infrastructure, and other forms of infrastructure projects around the world.<br><br>That&#8217;s just some of the specifics that will be discussed tomorrow.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have communiqués for both the GCC and the GCC+3 that will lay out what the leaders have agreed.&nbsp; And then the President&#8217;s own words, the speech that he will give sitting at that table, I think, is worth paying close attention to because it will outline the Biden strategy for the Middle East.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a strategy fit for purpose for 2022 as opposed to the two decades of major land wars that the U.S. fought in this region over the &#8212; you know, over the course of the 2000s.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, Khashoggi’s fiancée said going and doing this trip is backsliding on human rights.&nbsp; One, what do you say to her?&nbsp; And, two, the families have asked for specific things for the &#8212; for the President to bring up.&nbsp; Does he intend to bring up, including where his remains are?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, my heart, as all of your hearts, goes out to the family of Jamal Khashoggi.&nbsp; He was murdered in a brutal and grisly way.&nbsp; When this administration came in, we moved to take action.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked through the set of actions that we took over the course of the past few days.&nbsp; And the President remains firmly committed to advancing the cause of human rights in general and in particular.<br><br>And so you will see him speaking, over the next day, publicly on the issue of human rights.&nbsp; And he will, of course, also engage privately on the issue of human rights, and the United States will continue to try to move the ball forward on what is, for Joe Biden, a hallmark of his career from the time he was a senator, from the time he was vice president, and now, during the time he is president.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ll give the same answer to you that I gave before, which is he is going to have a conversation on fundamental issues of human rights in Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; And the specifics of that, I&#8217;m not going to go beyond where he was yesterday.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, to follow up to that though &#8212; okay, point taken, you don&#8217;t want to, you know, get ahead of the President.&nbsp; Can we, you know, get a commitment that the President then can read out what he said to us?&nbsp; Because, you know, if you are making &#8212;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m not totally sure I understand the question.&nbsp; What do you mean &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he taking &#8212; is he taking questions in Saudi Arabia from the press?&nbsp; So far, it doesn&#8217;t seem like there&#8217;s an opportunity.&nbsp; But if you don&#8217;t want to get ahead of him, we would like to ask him about this meeting after.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; look, I&#8217;m not the person you should talk to about the question of communications protocols and so forth.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll leave that to others.<br><br>I don&#8217;t know &#8212; if we&#8217;re negotiating commitments, I &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I stayed up all night last night negotiating various commitments government-to-government, and I&#8217;ll just stay in my lane and do those negotiations and let others negotiate on this point.<br><br>Like I said, the President will decide himself how he wants to characterize these meetings, and I&#8217;ll let him do that after he&#8217;s had them.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did the President mean yesterday when he said the last administration, in his words, “walked away” from the Middle East, when only a day earlier he had praised the previous administration for the Abraham Accords?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I missed the first half of the question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did the President mean yesterday when he said that the last administration had “walked away” from the Middle East, when only a day earlier he had praised the last administration for the Abraham Accords?</p>



<p><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; He was referring to a series of steps that he thinks were wrong and that he has taken a different approach on as President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He walked away from the two-state &#8212; they &#8212; I’m sorry, the last administration walked away from the two-state solution in any serious contemplation or consideration.&nbsp; It walked away from the Palestinians, cutting off all funding to them, which we have restored.&nbsp; It basically walked away from diplomatic ties with the Palestinians, which the President has obviously restored, and you saw that at the highest level with his meeting with Abu Mazen today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The previous administration walked away from the Iran nuclear deal, and in doing so, walked away from our allies &#8212; with whom we had been united &#8212; so that it was the U.S. who was isolated on the Iranian nuclear issue, not Iran.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the last administration walked away from diplomacy when it came to ending the war in Yemen.&nbsp; This President reengaged on that, and now we have a 15-week truce, the longest peaceful period in that conflict in several years.</p>



<p>And in Saudi Arabia, he will seek to deepen and extend that truce and start working towards a wider settlement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s just some of what he was referring to.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, just one question about ener- &#8212; sorry, on &#8212; one question about energy.&nbsp; The Russians have been buying fuel oil from Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; Is the President going to ask the Saudis to limit those exports to Russia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; He will have a broad conversation about energy security, especially in the context of Russia&#8217;s war in Ukraine.&nbsp; And true to form, I&#8217;m not going to speak specifically about what it is that he&#8217;s going to raise.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One about normalization with the Palestinians, just the dynamic of what&#8217;s going on with Israel, moving even when what you guys, I&#8217;m sure, are going to be talking about with the Saudis.&nbsp; But what does that dynamic mean for the Palestinians?&nbsp; And was there any nudge that it&#8217;s time to sort of move things along on the Palestinian side so you&#8217;re not left behind?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President made the case to President Abbas that Israel&#8217;s deeper integration into the region is not inconsistent with but rather can be very much reinforcing of progress on the Israel-Palestinian track.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s told President Abbas that the United States is going to do what it can to preserve the long-term possibility of the two-state solution to support diplomatic efforts to move in that direction and to waste no time in directly providing various forms of assistance to the Palestinian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, they had a healthy and robust conversation about the broader issue of regional peace as it connects to the bilateral track between Israel and the Palestinians.&nbsp; And the President has conviction that actually these two things can be mutually reinforcing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we anticipate seeing any additional steps towards Israeli-Saudi normalization during this trip?&nbsp; I know there was talk obviously of the Red Sea islands.&nbsp; Are there additional steps that were taken?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think, first, the airspace is cool.&nbsp; Okay, people?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So it’s the &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I also clarify: Is the airspace only &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Hol- &#8212; hol- &#8212; hold on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I just &#8212; I just want to clarify that, because there was talk about direct flights possibly taking like Arab-Israel pilgrims for Hajj.&nbsp; Is it just the airspace?&nbsp; Just so I can clarify that.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’ll let the Saudis speak to the Hajj issue because that’s something they obviously are the custodians of.&nbsp; So it wouldn&#8217;t be appropriate for me to make an announcement on that front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But back to the airspace being cool, this is the first public step that Saudi Arabia has taken vis-à-vis Israel.&nbsp; And in that regard, it is historic.&nbsp; It is on a path that we hope will eventually lead to normalization.&nbsp; But it is the first step, and the first step is a big step.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beyond that, I do think we will have further things to say about issues related to promoting peace in the region on this stop, but I will not get ahead of the President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The war in Yemen &#8212; are you expecting, like, statements or commitments regarding the war in Yemen?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think we expect to see commitments in respect to working to deepen and extend the ceasefire, and then to work through how to turn that ceasefire into something permanent.&nbsp; I won&#8217;t go into more detail now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, can I ask about Iraq and their anti-normalization law?&nbsp; Is that something the President is going to bring up with them?&nbsp; And then, how does that affect your efforts for this regional cooperation?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; My expectation is that in the meeting with Prime Minister Kadhimi, the main<a> focus will be on a core set of very familiar issues to the President, because he’s been dealing with this for a long time.&nbsp; I can’t say whether or not that issue will come up in the meeting.</a></p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, one more on energy, and switching gears a little bit.&nbsp; With the news that the Italian prime minister is resigning, and obviously a big supporter of the oil price cap, can you talk about the dynamics there, if you see a path forward?&nbsp; Is that at all impacted by that news &#8212; and discussions?&nbsp; I know you talked about it on the plane &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, the European Union is very committed and actively working on this &#8212; because we&#8217;re going back and forth with them daily, along with the UK &#8212; that&#8217;s all I can say.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t really speculate about the internal dynamics.</p>



<p>I would say that President Biden has deep, profound respect for Prime Minister Draghi.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s obviously following very closely the unfolding back-and-forth in Rome.&nbsp; And, you know, we&#8217;ll see what happens.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I follow up on gas?&nbsp; If I may, how concerned are you about the various Gazprom announcements regarding the gas supply to Europe?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, we have warned for a long time about Russia weaponizing energy, about Russia being a totally unreliable supplier of gas.&nbsp; And this is why we&#8217;re working so closely with the European Union to fully and finally end their dependence on Russian energy.</p>



<p>Now, that doesn&#8217;t happen overnight, but it does require the concerted, common effort of the United States and many other countries working to help increase supply to Europe.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing that.&nbsp; And, frankly, we&#8217;re doing that along with partners in Asia and partners in the Middle East.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll keep at it.</p>



<p>I should let you guys get after Karine on some stuff.&nbsp; So, I’ll &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Enjoy the cool airspace.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Okay, I don&#8217;t have anything else at the top, so fly it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, (inaudible) take inflation.&nbsp; You guys sort of prepped us the inflation number would be high; it was even higher than the White House and analysts anticipated &#8212; 9.1 percent right now.&nbsp; I want your reaction to that.&nbsp; And separately, the White House&#8217;s reaction to Joe Manchin basically saying he&#8217;s not going to do anything on energy, climate.&nbsp; The reconciliation plan on those topics?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll start with the last one first.&nbsp; Look, as you&#8217;ve heard us say many times before, we&#8217;re just not going to negotiate in public.</p>



<p>As it comes to climate change and the President&#8217;s climate change plan and how he&#8217;s going to get there, the President has always been very clear that he&#8217;s going to use every tool in his toolbox, every authority that he has, to make sure that we deal with the climate change &#8212; the climate crisis that we are currently in.&nbsp; But as far as the negotiations, I&#8217;m just not going to say much more about that in public.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he disappointed?&nbsp; Is he excited?&nbsp; I mean, he&#8217;s got to have some reaction.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a major announcement on a key issue in his agenda.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m just not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp; I’m not &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he get a heads up, did the White House get a heads up from Manchin?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And secondly, does the White House and the President specifically &#8212; do you guys think Manchin is on the level with these negotiations?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; we&#8217;re still part of these negotiations.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to say much more about it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to do this in public.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he give you a heads up, though?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to share any &#8212; much more about it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How about a reaction to the inflation figures?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’ll answer&nbsp;&#8212; okay, here we go.&nbsp; So as you &#8212; as you said, Peter, we have been talking about the CPI number, the inflation number that came out a couple of days ago.&nbsp; We feel, yes, it is elevated.&nbsp; We have &#8212; you all have probably seen &#8212; seen our economic team out there on some &#8212; on your network, I&#8217;m sure, Peter, talking about this.</p>



<p>Look, what we believe &#8212; and I had said this as well a couple of days ago &#8212; is that the data is outdated.&nbsp; It did not include the 30 days &#8212; the 30-day period, where you saw gas prices actually going down.&nbsp; We saw that &#8212; we saw gas prices go at least 40 percent down per gallon, which is important to note.&nbsp; We also saw the oil per barrel has gone down about $20.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, look, we understand the American public are feeling it and they&#8217;re feeling the inflation, they&#8217;re feeling the gas prices, and there&#8217;s more work to do.&nbsp; But we have seen some decrease.&nbsp; And if you look at core inflation, it is at 6 percent.&nbsp; And that is important to note as well, because as we have been saying that we&#8217;re going to see that moderate &#8212; the experts saying that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, look, we&#8217;re going to continue to do the work.&nbsp; And this is why &#8212; you know, this is why we feel that Congress needs to act.&nbsp; We need to continue to push forward and lower prices for Americans when it comes to drug prices, when it comes to energy.</p>



<p>And so we&#8217;re going to continue to have those negotiations, and we&#8217;re going to continue to make sure that we call on Congress to act.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, on that, you have two big legislative proposals that you tout as, you know, helping with inflation &#8212; obviously, reconciliation and then the China bill, the USICA bill.&nbsp; Both are obviously intertwined, and both seem to just be going nowhere right now.</p>



<p>With, you know, reconciliation &#8212; if Manchin gets what he wants &#8212; being slimmed down so much, and you guys touting the national security reasons for why to pass USICA, is it worth sacrificing that if you could have it done faster?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because McConnell clearly is &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m glad you asked that question.&nbsp; We think it&#8217;s a false choice to have to pick one or the other.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; You look at reconciliation: Experts have said that it will &#8212; it will help fight inflation, not just for the moment but for the long haul.&nbsp; And that matters.</p>



<p>When you look at USICA, BIA, the COMPETES bill, we have to continue &#8212; we have to be able to compete against China.&nbsp; We have to be able to have those manufacturing jobs.&nbsp; That is so critical, and that is key.&nbsp; And also, this is &#8212; we can&#8217;t allow Republicans to play games with our national security.&nbsp; It is incredibly important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s not about one or the other.&nbsp; We feel that what<a></a> &#8212; like, what Republicans like Cornyn and Mitch McConnell, what they&#8217;re doing is offering a false choice.<br><br>Now, to add, as we&#8217;re talking about USICA and BIA, there is bipartisan support.&nbsp; There is bipartisan support there.&nbsp; And so we appreciate the Republicans who are trying to work with us to get this done.<br><br>So, again, we want to see this done by this month, and we&#8217;re going to continue to have those conversations to get that done.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I see what you’re saying, but it just doesn&#8217;t seem like you guys &#8212; you&#8217;re saying the Republicans are giving you a false choice, but at this point, you know, Manchin is sort of like throwing a wrench in one bill, and Republicans are just pretty much united, it seems like, against USICA.&nbsp; So if you have to pick one bill, it &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you’re not picking one bill, it seems.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We&#8217;re saying it&#8217;s a false choice.&nbsp; We &#8212; we’re saying, “Now or never, we got to get these done.”<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you could get no bill.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well &#8212; well, you’re so dark, Jenny.&nbsp; Geez.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I mean, we got to keep pushing, right?&nbsp; This is about delivering for the American people.&nbsp; This is what we need to do.&nbsp; This is what the President wants to do.<br><br>We feel the COMPETES bill is not just about manufacturing and competing against &#8212; against countries like China, as I&#8217;ve mentioned, but it&#8217;s also a national security issue.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re calling out is Republicans like Mitch McConnell, like Cornyn, and saying to them this is not &#8212; we should not be playing games here.</p>



<p><br>And on reconciliation: Look, we&#8217;re going to have those &#8211;continue to have those negotiations.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m just not going to talk about it in public.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to try and get those done.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You don&#8217;t want to say if you&#8217;re confident in those negotiations?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’m just &#8212; I’m just saying we&#8217;re not &#8212; I&#8217;m just not going to &#8212; to give any character- &#8212; characterize where we are with the negotiations.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask on Secret Service?&nbsp; As you&#8217;ve seen the headlines recently, the most recent is that all of their text messages from January 5th and 6th of 2020 were erased.&nbsp; They say it was a part of a routine procedure.&nbsp; But, obviously, it&#8217;s concerning, given all that data that could give better detail to what happened behind the scenes as it relates to the investigation.<br><br>Does the White House have any thoughts on that?&nbsp; Has the President reached out to the Secret Service?&nbsp; Does he have faith in the Secret Service Director?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the Secret Ser- &#8212; this is a Secret Service matter.&nbsp; We&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re just not going to comment on it.&nbsp;<br><br>I saw, as you mentioned, they’ve ma- &#8212; they’ve put out &#8212; I think, last night, they put out their statement on this.&nbsp; And so I&#8217;m just going to refer you to the Secret Service.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not something that I&#8217;m going to comment from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, over the last few months &#8212; on inflation &#8212; sorry, I was just &#8212; for the last few months on inflation, though, it seems like we&#8217;ve had fairly high numbers, and we just keep reaching four-decade highs, four-decade highs.<br><br>Is it &#8212; I guess as we think about, like, what should people expect, is it your guys&#8217; assessment that we&#8217;re now at peak inflation?&nbsp; And, I guess, what are you guys advising that Americans ought to anticipate?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I’m going to let the economists speak to where we are, if it&#8217;s &#8212; where inflation &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the administration has no advice?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I’m going to say more.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’m just not going to step into that lane.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I will say is: We have said, and the President has said directly himself, that inflation is an economic &#8212; economic priority for him.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to do everything that he can to fight inflation.<br><br>We have talked about the steps that he has taken when it comes to gas.&nbsp; We have talked about what &#8212; what he has said about the Federal Reserve and giving them their independence and their space to be able to do the monetary policy that they feel that they&#8217;re going to do, and they are committed to fighting inflation.<br><br>We&#8217;re calling on Congress and working with Congress on both reconciliation, as Jenny was just asking me, and BIA.&nbsp; And we feel that that will have an effect on inflation.<br><br>And let&#8217;s not forget the gas tax holiday, which we continue to call on Congress, because we feel, when it comes to gas prices, we feel that they can do that at any time.&nbsp; And that 18 cents &#8212; and you see state gov- &#8212; states, whether it’s Republican or Democrat, also doing their gas tax holiday, and it&#8217;s been effective for them.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s another, potentially, 30 cents.<br><br>All of those things will have an effect.<br><br>Look, again, this is a top priority for the President, and he&#8217;s going to continue to do everything &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you expecting a better number next month, since gas prices are going down a little bit?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to predict.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just looking &#8212; we&#8217;re just looking at the last 30 days.&nbsp; And what we saw from that data, which didn&#8217;t include how gas prices has gone down by almost 40 cents, which is a real &#8212; a real thing to kind of flag and speak to.<br><br>I just &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to spe- &#8212; speak to the next 30 days.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should Americans be prepared, though, for like &#8212; I mean, should Americans be prepared for what inevitability, I guess?&nbsp; Like, are we talking about an inflation situation over the course of the next year?&nbsp; Like, is there any sense of preparedness you can give Americans?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I’ll go back to what I said earlier, how experts have said that they believe their &#8212; they believe, like, core inflation will moderate.&nbsp; And I said that we see it at 6 percent now, so that is a good sign.<br><br>So I&#8217;ll just, again, leave it to the expert and just le- &#8212; and just lean on to the data that we do know, as far as we&#8217;re &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Karine, the President said today that he was reiterating his commitment to press freedom.&nbsp; Does that mean in Saudi Arabia, in front of these leaders of countries that don&#8217;t have as many press freedoms, will he take questions from the press and encourage the other leaders to take questions from the press?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, the President, as he said &#8212; he said this yesterday, and you heard Jake say this: He has a long history when it comes to human rights.&nbsp; You know, this is something that he has spoken to, including press freedoms, as a senator, as a vice president, and now as a president.<br><br>He clearly took questions yesterday.&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s a question of press access for this trip.&nbsp; I can assure you that you guys will have access to the bi- &#8212; the bilat.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll be able to do the lovely pool sprays for that.&nbsp; The working meetings, there&#8217;ll be pool sprays for that.&nbsp; And so the President wants to be transparent, and you will hear from him on these next couple of days.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are any Israeli officials traveling aboard Air Force One right now to Saudi Arabia to participate in these meetings of any kind?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t have &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any names to read out on any officials that are on this &#8212; on &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If there are any, will you let us know?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; If there were &#8212; there &#8212; I&#8217;m just saying &#8212; I guess the answer is no, there is not.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The answer is no?&nbsp; Fine.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I get one more eco in?&nbsp; Obviously, for Bloomberg.&nbsp; China&#8217;s economic growth numbers were really bad for the second quarter.&nbsp; I&#8217;m curious what the White House thinks: if you see China&#8217;s slowdown increasing the risk of a global recession, how that impacts U.S. growth and inflation.<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I saw that &#8212; I saw that report yesterday as well.&nbsp; Let me just connect with the economic team, and I just want to make sure I give you the right information on that one.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, thanks.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>&nbsp;END&nbsp; 5:24 P.M. AST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the American Federation of Teachers 2022&#160;Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/15/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-american-federation-of-teachers-2022-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 16:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Boston, MA Good morning, it’s wonderful to be back in Boston and with you, my fellow educators, my family. Isn’t it nice to be back in person?! Randi, one of the things I love most about you is how you show up for people. When there’s a problem, you find a solution. When someone’s in need,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Boston, MA</p>



<p>Good morning, it’s wonderful to be back in Boston and with you, my fellow educators, my family. Isn’t it nice to be back in person?!<br> <br>Randi, one of the things I love most about you is how you show up for people. When there’s a problem, you find a solution. When someone’s in need, you ask: How can I help?<br> <br>And it’s what makes you such a powerful leader here at AFT. So, thank you for your friendship. Thank you for caring. Thank you for putting this organization first every day.<br> <br>It’s always an honor to share a stage with Senator Warren and our great Secretary of Labor, Marty Walsh—and I had the chance to travel here with Senator Markey and Congresswoman Presley.<br> <br>Like some of you, I just got an email this week asking me to sign my contract for next semester. And it made me think about the first one I signed 38 years ago.<br> <br>Looking back, it’s hard to believe anyone could be that excited to scribble a name on a line—but I was. It felt like so much more than just an employment contract—it felt like becoming the person I was meant to be.<br> <br>Do you remember that moment? When you first decided to take this path?<br> <br>To be a teacher. It isn’t an easy job. So, why do we do it?<br> <br>For me, I thought about just how much books had shaped me—how I loved falling into them and escaping or learning something new. And it broke my heart that there were people who didn’t know that joy. I realized that it was a gift I could give to someone. That I could teach someone else to read.<br> <br>And I bet that you have a similar story—a moment when you realized that you wanted to be the person to open up the world for someone else, to give the smile that helps that student find the confidence she didn’t know was inside her, to be the one who says, “It’s OK, we’ll figure it out together.”<br> <br>We believe that there is something profoundly optimistic about education.<br> <br>To answer this call of service is, in itself, an act of hope. And we need that hope now more than ever.<br> <br>As Randi said yesterday, teaching has become so much harder. But you don’t quit. You show up to work with a granola bar because you know someone may come to class hungry.<br> <br>You keep your voice calm when you explain active shooter drills and how to stay quiet when they hide under desks—even though a part of you breaks into pieces each time.<br> <br>You tell your students that change is possible, even though you know that the young women looking up at you with those hopeful eyes have lost rights that they don’t even understand yet.<br> <br>You turn down the news on TV telling you about people who want to stop you from doing your job, put your shoulders back, and focus on your students. <br> <br>There is so much weight on all of you—but you carry it. Our schools are where policies become people. And educators are at the center of it all.<br> <br>And we’re not alone. Healing is hopeful as well. As Joe always says, “If there are any angels in heaven, they are all nurses.” America is so grateful for the sacrifices you’ve made.<br> <br>I’m proud of what Joe’s done in these last two years: From historic investments to re-open schools, to addressing the mental and academic needs of our students, to signing the bipartisan gun bill and defending women’s reproductive health care, to delivering on the promise of loan forgiveness for public servants.<br> <br>In fact, almost 150,000 public servants have already received loan forgiveness because of changes our Administration has made.<br> <br>The president that you elected is working every day to keep his promises—but we need partners who will join him. Because we believe that AR-15s, the weapon that tore apart 19 children and two teachers in their classroom, have no place on our streets.<br> <br>We believe women should be able to make their own decisions about their own bodies and pregnancies.<br> <br>Ending child poverty, providing affordable child care and free community college are not divisive issues, they should not be red or blue.<br> <br>Our government represents the will of the people.<br> <br>And that’s why the people need to get involved. Teachers. Nurses. Higher education and health care workers, public servants. All of us.<br> <br>Yes, we need to vote—in races at every single level. And we need to remember that voting is the bare minimum.<br> <br>We have to get involved in the local governments that decide how cities plan their budgets and protect their students.<br> <br>We have to speak up for justice and equity. All of us have a “Teacher voice” for when things go off the rails—and now is the time to use it.<br> <br>We have to come together—as AFT always has—and demand that we be heard. <br> <br>I’ll be there beside you, every step of the way. <br> <br>Now, it’s going to be difficult. We know that. But we do this work because we believe that a better world is possible—and we know that we are the ones who make that future real.<br> <br>Underestimate the power of this coalition at your own risk. We will fight for the communities we care about and we will never give up.<br> <br>Because that’s who we are: Optimists. True believers. Fighters. And that’s what we do, every day, in little ways and in big ones: We change the world.<br> <br>So, let’s get to work.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on  National Atomic Veterans Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/a-proclamation-on-national-atomic-veterans-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 14:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On National Atomic Veterans Day, we recognize the brave service of America&#8217;s Atomic Veterans.  We renew our commitment to supporting Atomic Veterans and to preserving their stories, so that Americans will always remember both their crucial role in our history and our aspiration for a world without nuclear weapons.  &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; The military personnel who participated&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On National Atomic Veterans Day, we recognize the brave service of America&#8217;s Atomic Veterans.  We renew our commitment to supporting Atomic Veterans and to preserving their stories, so that Americans will always remember both their crucial role in our history and our aspiration for a world without nuclear weapons. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The military personnel who participated in nuclear testing between 1945 and 1962, served in the Armed Forces in or around Hiroshima and Nagasaki through mid-1946, or were held as prisoners of war in or near Hiroshima or Nagasaki stand among our bravest heroes. &nbsp;Many&nbsp;of&nbsp;these veterans stepped forward to defend our democratic values and helped to end the deadliest conflict in history.&nbsp; Yet, despite their service in uniform, Atomic Veterans were prevented from discussing the nature of their service &#8212; including with their families.&nbsp; Although many Atomic Veterans developed serious health conditions due to radiation exposure, they were unable to seek medical care or disability compensation from the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for injuries and diseases associated with their exposure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Decades later, when the United States Congress repealed the Nuclear Radiation and Secrecy Agreements Act, veterans exposed to radiation through their service-related activities were finally able to break their silence and qualify for select VA benefits and services.&nbsp; Tragically, many Atomic Veterans passed away without ever receiving the health care they deserved and without their families knowing the true extent of their service.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our Nation has many obligations, but only one sacred obligation: &nbsp;to prepare and equip the troops that we send into harm&#8217;s way and to care for them when they return home, as well as their families, caregivers, and survivors.&nbsp; For far too long, our Nation failed in our sacred obligation to our Atomic Veterans.&nbsp; It is a mistake our country must never repeat.&nbsp; I am committed to ensuring that all of our Nation&#8217;s veterans and their families, caregivers, and survivors have timely access to the services, medical care, and benefits that they deserve &#8212; including addressing the health effects of exposures to environmental toxins and harmful substances, such as the toxic fumes from burn pits. &nbsp;Since taking office, we have made several improvements to how we identify and address potential service-connected conditions, and the First Lady and I are personally committed to ensuring that all our veterans and their families, caregivers, and survivors receive the benefits and services they have earned.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On National Atomic Veterans Day, we honor the Atomic Veterans who sacrificed on behalf our Nation.&nbsp; Our Atomic Veterans are patriots, and their bravery and service will always&nbsp;be remembered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim July 16, 2022, as National Atomic Veterans Day.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this day with appropriate ceremonies and activities that honor our Nation&#8217;s Atomic Veterans whose brave service and sacrifice played an important role in the defense of our Nation.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fifteenth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-seventh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Captive Nations Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/15/a-proclamation-on-captive-nations-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America has firmly set its sights on the ideals of freedom, democracy, equality, liberty, and justice for all.  We have never fully lived up to that founding promise, but we have never walked away from it either.  These core values have also moved us to support people around the world &#8212; especially those who live&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America has firmly set its sights on the ideals of freedom, democracy, equality, liberty, and justice for all.  We have never fully lived up to that founding promise, but we have never walked away from it either.  These core values have also moved us to support people around the world &#8212; especially those who live under oppressive regimes &#8212; so that they can freely exercise their rights.  As a long-standing democracy, the United States carries a responsibility to show the world how representative governance delivers benefits for all people.  During Captive Nations Week, we reaffirm our commitment to supporting and amplifying the voices of the courageous individuals around the world who are striving to advance the universal principles of freedom, democracy, justice, and the rule of law while living under oppression.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, defending democracy is more vital and more urgent than ever.&nbsp; Around the world, we bear witness to alarming trends &#8212; autocratic nations brutally invading the territory of their neighbors, backsliding of democratic values, intrusive digital surveillance, widespread human rights abuses, and increasing acts of transnational repression.&nbsp; These practices and policies imperil the essential work of activists, journalists, and defenders of human rights, and they oppress average citizens.&nbsp; Increasingly, repressive regimes in Russia, Iran, Belarus, Syria, Cuba, Venezuela, Nicaragua, the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea, the People&#8217;s Republic of China, and elsewhere are seeking to subjugate not only those within their own borders but also those in other countries. &nbsp;They reach across borders to surveil, harass, threaten, and even kill human rights defenders, media workers, and civilians in other sovereign nations.&nbsp; It is an outrage and an affront to the rules-based order that underwrites international peace and security. &nbsp;The world&#8217;s democracies must stand together and show the strength of our resolve to put an end to these injustices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the first Summit for Democracy in December 2021 and the ongoing Year of Action, the United States launched an effort to bring together governments around the world to counter authoritarianism, defend democracy, and safeguard the human rights and fundamental freedoms that foster peace, security, and prosperity.&nbsp; Collectively, we are working to bolster sustainable and independent media, protect and support civil society, and insist on the rule of law and accountability for those who commit abuses.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As Russia relentlessly wages its brutal and unprovoked war against the people of Ukraine, our Nation has led a global response to hold Russia accountable and denounce its inhumanity and its contempt for international law.&nbsp; We honor the valor and sacrifice of the people of Ukraine, who have reminded the world through their courage of the universal yearning for freedom. &nbsp;We will continue to stand with them as they defend their country, their liberty, and their democracy.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During Captive Nations Week, we stand in solidarity with the brave human rights and pro‑democracy advocates around the world &#8212; many of whom risk their lives each day to protect the rights of others.&nbsp; We remain committed to ensuring that all those who are oppressed around the globe are heard, supported, and protected.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May Captive Nations Week reinvigorate our efforts to live up to our ideals by championing justice, dignity, and freedom for all.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Congress, by joint resolution approved July 17, 1959 (73 Stat. 212), has authorized and requested the President to issue a proclamation designating the third week of July of each year as &#8220;Captive Nations Week.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim July 17 through July 23, 2022, as Captive Nations Week.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to reaffirm our commitment to championing those around the world who are working, often at great personal risk, to secure liberty and justice for all.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fifteenth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-seventh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at East Jerusalem Hospital Network&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/15/remarks-by-president-biden-at-east-jerusalem-hospital-network-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Augusta Victoria HospitalJerusalem, Israel 10:57 A.M. EEST&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; My name is Joe Biden.&#160; I am Jill Biden&#8217;s husband.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; She has been here twice before me.&#160; And before I begin, I&#8217;d like to say that &#8212; there&#8217;s an old expression: &#8220;Hope springs eternal.&#8221; I &#8212; my background and the background of my family is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Augusta Victoria Hospital<br>Jerusalem, Israel</p>



<p>10:57 A.M. EEST&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; My name is Joe Biden.&nbsp; I am Jill Biden&#8217;s husband.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; She has been here twice before me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And before I begin, I&#8217;d like to say that &#8212; there&#8217;s an old expression: &#8220;Hope springs eternal.&#8221;</p>



<p>I &#8212; my background and the background of my family is Irish American, and we have a long history of &#8212; not fundamentally unlike the Palestinian people with Great Britain and their attitude toward Irish-Catholics over the years, for 400 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my colleagues, when I was a U.S. senator, used to always joke with me that I was always quoting Irish poets when I was on the floor of the Senate.&nbsp; And they thought I did it because I&#8217;m Irish.&nbsp; That’s not the reason I did it; I did it because they&#8217;re the best poets in the world.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a great poem from &#8220;The Cure at Troy” &#8212; a paragraph.&nbsp; It goes like this &#8212; and it&#8217;s classically Irish, but it also could fit Palestinians.&nbsp; It says:</p>



<p><em>“History [teaches us not to] hope</em></p>



<p><em>On this side of the grave.</em></p>



<p><em>But then, once in a lifetime</em></p>



<p><em>[That] longed-for tidal wave</em></p>



<p><em>Of justice [rises] up,</em></p>



<p><em>And hope and history rhyme.”</em></p>



<p>&#8220;Hope and history rhyme.&#8221;&nbsp; It is my prayer that we&#8217;re reaching one of those moments where hope and history rhyme.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; are there any nurses in the room?&nbsp; Because if there are not, I&#8217;m going home. (Laughter.)</p>



<p>If there are any angels in Heaven &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; no, no, no, I mean this sincerely from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp; My wife and daughter were killed and my boys were trapped in a vehicle for three hours when a tractor trailer hit them.&nbsp; And doctors saved their lives, but the nurses made them want to live, and cared for them every day, and knew &#8212; knew when they were ready and when they weren&#8217;t ready.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I was making a speech and I had a terrible headac- &#8212; (coughs) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; a terrible headache.&nbsp; And &#8212; sorry &#8212; (takes a sip of water) &#8212; (coughs) &#8212; I swallowed wrong.&nbsp; I had a terrible headache.&nbsp; This was years ago.&nbsp; And I did a very stupid thing: I got on an aircraft and I flew home.&nbsp; It turned out I had two cranial aneurysms, and I got rushed to a hospital in the middle of a snowstorm for a nine-and-a-half-hour operation that saved my life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then I had the second operation; they found an aneurysm on the other side of my brain.&nbsp; I joke: The reason they went in twice to take the top of my head off is because they couldn’t find a brain the first time.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And in between, I had a major embolism that almost killed me.&nbsp; Nothing unusual that other people haven’t gone through.&nbsp; But I look back on it, and I don’t think you nurses are nearly appreciated enough.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I found was: You lie in the ICU &#8212; and I have not said this publicly before &#8212; and you look at the monitors, and you know if the line goes flat, you&#8217;re dead.&nbsp; You don’t know what each monitor is, but you know.&nbsp; And I really mean it &#8212; it&#8217;s true.&nbsp; But you just get tired.&nbsp; Even when you&#8217;re not in pain, you just want to quit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the nurses at Walter Reed Hospital would come up, they&#8217;d rub my face, they&#8217;d whisper in my ear.&nbsp; They&#8217;d get close and tell me, &#8220;It&#8217;s going to be okay.&#8221;</p>



<p>They made a difference in my life.</p>



<p>My son spent a year in Iraq.&nbsp; He was the attorney general of the state of Delaware.&nbsp; He should be the man standing here and talking to you as President, not me.&nbsp; He came home because he &#8212; his &#8212; where he slept for a year in Iraq was about 150 yards from a burn pit where they burned everything from fuel to garbage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He went &#8212; the fittest guy in his regiment, in his outfit, and came home with stage four glioblastoma.&nbsp; I watched for 14 months the nurses take care of him &#8212; the doctors as well &#8212; but every day &#8212; every single day.</p>



<p>And so I really mean it from the bottom of my heart: Nurses &#8212; doctors are critical; I&#8217;m not in any way diminishing the role of a doctor.&nbsp; But nurses &#8212; nurses give you as much hope &#8212; male and female &#8212; as anybody else does.</p>



<p>I want to thank the CEO and everyone at East Jerusalem Hospital Network for welcoming me this morning.&nbsp; This is the first time I had the opportunity to see for myself the outstanding work that you do here, that I’ve heard about for such a long time.</p>



<p>My wife, Jill, visited in both 2010 and 2016, and I&#8217;m honored to be able to see firsthand the service and the quality of care you provide the Palestinian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These hospitals are the backbone of the Palestinian healthcare system.&nbsp; People turn to you in their moment of need, as you well know, with their children who are sick, with a loved one who’s injured.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When they get that cancer diagnosis &#8212; the most feared word, I think, in all languages is when the doctor looks at you and says, “It&#8217;s cancer.”&nbsp; They don&#8217;t know what to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You not only care for them, you guide them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the same [for] people all over the world.&nbsp; In that moment, all that matters is that you’ve got someone that you can turn to and radiates hope and help.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why the United States, through the Agency for International Development, has been so proud &#8212; has been proud to support this network of hospitals with $85 million since 2014.&nbsp; It’s part of our commitment to support health and dignity to the Palestinian people.&nbsp; Maybe the most overused phrase &#8212; word in the English language for the Irish is “dignity.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>My dad used to say, “Everyone, no matter what their circumstance, is entitled to be treated with dignity.”&nbsp; Dignity.</p>



<p>And dealing with the COVID-19 pandemic took a hard toll here, as it did in so many communities around the world.&nbsp; So, today, I&#8217;m pleased to announce the United States is committing an additional $100 million to support these hospitals, your staffs, and &#8212; that work for the Palestinian people.</p>



<p>This is a multiyear commitment in both resources and expertise.&nbsp; When I was Vice President, I asked the President, then Barack Obama &#8212; I asked him whether or not I could start what we called a Cancer Moonshot.&nbsp; I visited every major cancer hospital in the world, with one exception &#8212; and I mean it literally.&nbsp; Because there&#8217;s so much &#8212; so much we’re just on the edge of being able to discern.&nbsp; We&#8217;re so close, dealing with so many cancers.</p>



<p>When I got elected President, I announced that one of my goals was to change cancer as we know it so it was no longer viewed by many people, as it is, as a death sentence but as a disease that can either be cured or lived with.</p>



<p>**3</p>



<p>**12:30-end</p>



<p>And we started this Cancer Moonshot with billions of dollars at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Within our National Institute of Health, I set up a provision where, like within the Defense Department &#8212; there&#8217;s a special office in the Defense Department that’s nothing but looking at breaking technologies, whether it&#8217;s &#8212; just across the board.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where the Internet came from.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, we’re doing the same thing at the National Institute of Health, just focusing on cancer.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; This one provision.</p>



<p>It represents our investment in the future.&nbsp; As your &#8212; this &#8212; hopefully, this $100 million will generate other large contributions from other countries, focusing on the health of the Palestinian people so they&#8217;ll continue to have access to the best available care, so they know they have somewhere to turn for help.&nbsp; They have navigators that can help them through the process.<br><br>Those of you who have been on the other side of a diagnosis know the most frightening thing is: When you get the word, whatever it is, you can hardly listen.&nbsp; You need a navigator.&nbsp; You need someone to help you walk through the pieces, help you figure out how to deal with the treatment you&#8217;re going to have once you&#8217;re out of the hospital and need treatment.<br><br>Working together, it is my prayer the United States will both help relieve the hospital&#8217;s burden of debt and support for targeted infrastructure upgrades and key reforms in patient care to ensure long-term financial stability.<br><br>We also welcome the $25 million contribution from the UAE, and I encourage other nations around the region and around the world to step up as well with their own contributions to support the vital work that&#8217;s being done here.<br><br>Palestinians and Israelis deserve equal measure of freedom, security, prosperity, and dignity.&nbsp; And access to healthcare when you need it is essential to living a life of dignity for all of us.<br><br>The United States will continue to work with the Palestinian leadership, with the government of Israel, and with all our international partners to ensure that East Jer- &#8212; East Jerusalem’s Hospital Network retains sustainable, remains available, and is able to provide high-quality care that the Palestinian people deserve.<br><br>I could say much more, but if my mother were here, she’d look at me and say, “Joey, hush up.&nbsp; You’ve spoken too long.”<br><br>But I want to thank you again for welcoming me &#8212; welcoming me today.&nbsp; Most importantly, thank you for taking care of all the patients &#8212; all the patients whose lives you make better.<br><br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m finished.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If you have a question about hospitals &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; I’ll answer it; if you don’t, I&#8217;ll do it privately.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I am American Palestinian from New Jersey, Bergen County, and I vote for you.&nbsp; I am a head nurse of pediatric intensive care unit at Makassed Hospital.&nbsp; Thank you for your support, but we need more justice, more dignity.&nbsp; And thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, folks.&nbsp; Appreciate it very, very much.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>11:11 A.M. EEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Abbas of the Palestinian National Authority in Joint Press Statement &#124; Bethlehem, West&#160;Bank</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/15/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-abbas-of-the-palestinian-national-authority-in-joint-press-statement-bethlehem-west-bank/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Muqata’a Presidential CompoundBethlehem, West Bank 1:24 P.M. EEST PRESIDENT ABBAS:  (As interpreted.)  Formidable President Biden, we welcome you as a dear guest of Palestine, in the city of Bethlehem, the cradle of our Lord Jesus Christ, on your official visit, which expresses your interest in achieving peace in the land of peace. And today&#8217;s meeting,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Muqata’a Presidential Compound<br>Bethlehem, West Bank</p>



<p>1:24 P.M. EEST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT ABBAS:  (As interpreted.)  Formidable President Biden, we welcome you as a dear guest of Palestine, in the city of Bethlehem, the cradle of our Lord Jesus Christ, on your official visit, which expresses your interest in achieving peace in the land of peace.</p>



<p>And today&#8217;s meeting, our meeting, was an opportunity to discuss consolidating our military relations between the countries and peoples, and to review what the U.S. can contribute to prepare the atmosphere for a political horizon for a just, comprehensive, durable peace.</p>



<p>We have stressed to Mr. President Biden on the importance of reestablishing the foundations upon which the peace process was based &#8212; that is based on the international legitimacy resolutions and on the basis of the two-state solution along the 1967 borders.</p>



<p>Mr. President, after 74 years of the Nakba displacement and occupation, isn&#8217;t it not the time for this occupation to end and for our steadfast people, again, to gain their freedom and independence, and for the hopes of our young men and women, whom we cherish and trust their creativity, to achieve a promising future without occupation?</p>



<p>In this regard, we say that the key to peace and security in our region begins with recognizing state of Palestine and enabling the Palestinian people to obtain their legitimate rights in accordance with international legitimacy resolutions, and ending all the permanent status issues, including the Palestinian refugees issue.</p>



<p>And the way to that begins with ending the Israeli occupation of our land, the land of state of Palestine, with East Jerusalem as its capital, on the 1967 borders.</p>



<p>Mr. President, we have respected the resolutions of international legitimacy and signed agreements, and we have committed ourselves to renouncing violence and fighting terrorism in our region and the world.</p>



<p>We look forward to steps from the U.S. administration to strengthen bilateral relations by reopening the U.S. consulate in East Jerusalem, removing the PLO from the U.S. terrorist list. We are not terrorists. And also, we look forward to reopening PLO office in Washington. And we are ready to work within the framework of partnership and cooperation in order to remove any obstacles to achieving that.</p>



<p>Mr. President, we look forward to the efforts of your administration to turn the page on the Israeli occupation of our land and the acts of racial discrimination, apartheid against our people; and to stop unilateral actions that undermine the two-state solution.</p>



<p>We look forward to these efforts to stop settlement and settler violence; and respect of the historical situation in the Islamic and Christian holy sites and the Hashemite custodianship; and stopping the expulsion of Palestinians, demolishing houses, homes, and storming the cities, villages, and camps; and stopping the daily killing and arrests on daily basis; and holding the killers of the martyr journalist, Shireen Abu Akleh &#8212; they need to be held accountable.</p>



<p>Because the continuation of all of that will lead to escalation on the one hand and loss of hope for a better tomorrow on the other.</p>



<p>Mr. President, if Israel wants to be a compliant state, it cannot continue to act as a state above law. And this calls for Israel to end its occupation of the land of state of Palestine with East Jerusalem as its capital on the 1967 borders.</p>



<p>Only then, Israel will be accepted to live in peace, security, and good neighborhood with the countries and peoples of the region based on the Arab Peace Initiative. The opportunity for the two-state solution on the 1967 borders may be available today only, but we don’t know what will happen later.</p>



<p>Therefore, I take this opportunity on the occasion of the visit of Your Excellency to the region to say that I extend my hand to the leaders of Israel to make peace for the (inaudible). And this has happened much before. Before Oslo Accords, we have been extending our hands for peace with all the Israeli leaders for a better future for the future generations and for all the peoples of the region.</p>



<p>Mr. President, we welcome you again. And our confidence in you and your administration is very great. And we assure you of our readiness to work with you, hand in hand, in order to achieve comprehensive and just peace based on international legitimacy and the Arab Peace Initiative and the signed agreements between us and Israel.</p>



<p>There are agreements that we need to respect in a way &#8212; in a manner that guarantees security, peace, stability, and lasting prosperity for all the countries in the region.</p>



<p>Mr. President, peace begins with Palestine and Jerusalem. From here, peace starts. We extend our hands for peace and to work with you, Mr. President, to achieve it.</p>



<p>Peace be upon you. (In Arabic.) Thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Mr. President, President Abbas, thank you very much and to your colleagues with whom I had the opportunity to meet as well.</p>



<p>And it’s good to see you again, my friend. We’ve known each other for a long time. And I’m very proud to be with you today as President of the United States. And I can &#8212; we can count ourselves among the earliest supporters of a two-state solution.</p>



<p>As I stand with you today, now as President of the United States, my commitment to that goal of a two-state solution has not changed in all these years.</p>



<p>Two states along the 1967 lines, where mutually agreed-to swaps, remain the best way to achieve equal measure of security, prosperity, freedom, and democracy for the Palestinians as well as Israelis.</p>



<p>The Palestinian people deserve a state of their own that’s independent, sovereign, viable, and contiguous. Two states for two peoples, both of whom have deep and ancient roots in this land, living side by side in peace and security. Both states fully respecting the equal rights of the other citizens. Both peoples enjoying equal measure of freedom and dignity. That’s what this is fundamentally all about.</p>



<p>Every person has a right to be treated with dignity. It’s simply basic. I know that the goal of the two states seems so far away while indignities like restrictions on movement and travel or the daily worry of your children’s safety are real and they are immediate.</p>



<p>The Pales- &#8212; the Palestinian people are hurting now. You feel &#8212; you can just feel it, your grief and frustration. In the United States, we can feel it.</p>



<p>But we’ve never give up on the work of peace. You know, there must be a political horizon that the Palestinian people can actually see or at least feel. We can’t allow the hopelessness to steal away the future that so many have worked toward for so long.</p>



<p>So even if the ground is not ripe at this moment to restart negotiations, the United States and my administration will not give up on trying to bring the Palestinians and Israelis and both sides closer together.</p>



<p>I do believe that in this moment when Israel is improving relations with its neighbors throughout the region, we can harness that same momentum to reinvigorate the peace process between the Palestinian people and the Israelis.</p>



<p>I recognize how hard all these challenges must be and will be to work through. Above all, there must be an end to the violence that has devastated too many families.</p>



<p>It’s heart-wrenching that so many Palestinians and Israelis have lost their life just this year. And the United States has suffered loss as well, including the killing of Shireen Abu Alkeh &#8212; Alkehli [Akleh].</p>



<p>And she was an American &#8212; an American citizen and a proud Palestinian. And she was performing very vital work on an independent media and vital work of democracy.</p>



<p>Her death is an enormous loss to the essential work of sharing with the world the story of the Palestinian people.</p>



<p>I hope that her legacy &#8212; her legacy will inspire more young people to carry on her work of reporting the truth and telling stories that are too often overlooked.</p>



<p>The United States will continue to insist on a full and transparent accounting of her death, and we will continue to stand up for media freedom everywhere in the world.</p>



<p>President Abbas, in the past, we met in Ramallah, but today, in the Palestinian city of Bethlehem, a place of enormous<br>significance in my faith as well &#8212; the birthplace of Jesus Christ.</p>



<p>This is the city that lives in the hearts of millions of Christians and is a reminder of God’s great gift to the world and our renewed and redemption in Christ.</p>



<p>Muslim and Jews also have an intense and deep connection to this land, particularly in Jerusalem.</p>



<p>Jerusalem is central to the national visions of both Palestinians and Israelis &#8212; to your histories, to your faiths, to your futures.</p>



<p>Jerusalem must be a city for all its people &#8212; its holy sites preserving the status quo, with the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan continuing to serve as custodian.</p>



<p>And throughout this Holy Land, which is filled with so many places of meaning and significance to Muslims, Christians, and Jews, we must all be free to practice our faiths in peace, in safety, and in dignity.</p>



<p>We cannot wait for a peace agreement to be reached or for every issue to be resolved to deliver on the needs of the Palestinian people that exist today, as I speak.</p>



<p>The best way to feed the flame of hope is to demonstrate that things can be better. And, President Abbas, the United States is a partner in this work to improve the day-to-day lives of the Palestinian people.</p>



<p>That’s why, when I came to office, I reserved the policy &#8212; I reversed the policies of my predecessor and resumed aid to the Palestinians &#8212; more than a half a billion dollars in [since] 2021.</p>



<p>That’s support for the economic development of the Palestinian people, to strengthen Palestinian security, to provide food for people to eat, to respond to the pandemic, including donating more than one million doses of COVID-19 [vaccine] to the West Bank and Gaza.</p>



<p>It also includes more than $400 million in humanitarian assistance to Palestinian refugees through the United [Nations] Relief and Works Agency &#8212; the UNRWA.</p>



<p>And today, I’m announcing the United States is going to provide an additional $200 million to the UNRWA so it can continue its vital work of helping the most vulnerable Palestinians, especially Palestinian children.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, and I &#8212; we decided &#8212; and this morning, I announced an additional $100 million in support of healthcare services for Palestinians throughout East Jerusalem Hospital Network.</p>



<p>We were &#8212; we were engaging with Israel around ways<br>to spur greater Palestinian economic growth, including by implementing 4G mobile networks, increasing the supply of renewable energy, improving freedom of movement for Palestinians, both people and goods.</p>



<p>These are the kinds of issues that progress can make life better for people right away, and we should be about it right away.</p>



<p>And the Palestinian Authority has important work to do as well, if you don’t mind my saying.</p>



<p>Now is the time to strengthen Palestinian institutions, to improve governance, transparency, and accountability.</p>



<p>All of this work is critical. And it will help build a society that can support a successful, democratic future, and a future Palestinian state. And the United States will work with you, President Abbas, at every step.</p>



<p>So thank you again for welcoming me and my delegation &#8212; the Secretary of State, National Security Advisor, and others &#8212; to visit with you.</p>



<p>I hope our visit is the start of a new and reinvigorated dialogue between the Palestinian Authority, the United States &#8212; and between the Palestinian &#8212; countries and counties throughout &#8212; and countries throughout the region, including Israel.</p>



<p>So let’s work together to show the people of the region, especially young people &#8212; young people &#8212; that the future can be better than it is today.</p>



<p>I thank you all very much. And may God protect us all. Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>END 1:40 P.M. EEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
