<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 21:03:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>February 2022 Visitor Log&#160;Records Posted</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/disclosures/2022/05/31/february-2022-visitor-log-records-posted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Disclosures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54476</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the White House released visitor log records generated in February 2022. This set includes 2155 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 44752. These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the White House released visitor log records generated in February 2022. This set includes 2155 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 44752.</p>



<p>These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first administration to post visitor log records from its first full year in office.</p>



<p>To learn more about the policy, read our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/voluntary-disclosure/">voluntary disclosure policy</a>. To view visitor log records, view our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/disclosures/visitor-logs/">disclosure page</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Adjusting Imports Of Steel into the United&#160;States</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-adjusting-imports-of-steel-into-the-united-states-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 19:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54394</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1. &#160;On January 11, 2018, the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) transmitted to the President a report on the Secretary&#8217;s investigation into the effect of imports of steel mill articles (steel articles) on the national security of the United States under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended (19 U.S.C. 1862).&#160; The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1. &nbsp;On January 11, 2018, the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) transmitted to the President a report on the Secretary&#8217;s investigation into the effect of imports of steel mill articles (steel articles) on the national security of the United States under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended (19 U.S.C. 1862).&nbsp; The Secretary found and advised the President of his opinion that steel articles are being imported into the United States in such quantities and under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security of the United States.</p>



<p>2. &nbsp;In Proclamation 9705 of March 8, 2018 (Adjusting Imports of Steel Into the United States), the President concurred in the Secretary&#8217;s finding that steel articles, as defined in clause 1 of Proclamation 9705, as amended by clause 8 of Proclamation 9711 of March 22, 2018 (Adjusting Imports of Steel Into the United States), are being imported into the United States in such quantities and under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security of the United&nbsp;States, and decided to adjust the imports of those steel articles by imposing a 25&nbsp;percent ad valorem tariff on such articles imported from all countries except Canada and Mexico. &nbsp;The proclamation further stated that any country with which we have a security relationship is welcome to discuss with the United States alternative ways to address the threatened impairment to the national security caused by imports from that country, and noted that, should the United States and any such country arrive at a satisfactory alternative means to address the threat to the national security such that the President determines that imports from that country no longer threaten to impair the national security, the President may remove or modify the restriction on steel articles imports from that country and, if necessary, adjust the tariff as it applies to other countries, as the national security interests of the United&nbsp;States require.</p>



<p>3. &nbsp;The United States has successfully concluded discussions with the United Kingdom (UK) on satisfactory alternative means to address the threatened impairment to the national security posed by imports of steel articles and derivative steel articles from the UK. &nbsp;The United States and the UK have agreed to expand coordination involving trade remedies and customs matters, monitor bilateral steel and aluminum trade, cooperate on addressing non-market excess capacity and carbon intensity in these sectors, annually review their arrangement and their ongoing cooperation, and ensure that steel articles exports from the UK to the United States under the applicable tariff-rate quota for steel articles are not supported by market-distorting practices.</p>



<p>4. &nbsp;The United States will implement a number of actions, including a tariff-rate quota that restricts the quantity of steel articles and derivative steel articles imported into the United States from the UK without the application of the tariff proclaimed in Proclamation 9705. &nbsp;Under the arrangement, steel articles that are melted and poured in the UK and imported from either the UK or further processed in the European Union, conferring European Union country of origin, and subsequently imported into the United States from the European Union are eligible for in-quota treatment. &nbsp;In my judgment, these measures will provide an effective, long-term alternative means to address any contribution by UK steel articles and derivative steel articles imports to the threatened impairment to the national security by restraining steel articles and derivative steel articles imports to the United States&nbsp;from the UK, limiting transshipment, discouraging excess steel capacity and production, and strengthening the United States-UK partnership. &nbsp;In light of this agreement, I have determined that imports of specified volumes of eligible steel articles and derivative steel articles from the UK will no longer threaten to impair the national security and have decided to exclude such imports from the UK up to a designated quota from the tariff proclaimed in Proclamation 9705. &nbsp;The United States will monitor the implementation and effectiveness of the tariff-rate quota and other measures agreed upon with the UK in addressing our national security needs, and I may revisit this determination, as appropriate.</p>



<p>5. &nbsp;I conclude that the UK presents a special case because of the unique nature of the special relationship that exists between the United States and the UK.&nbsp; The United States has a deep security relationship with the UK, including a shared commitment to mutual support in addressing national security concerns, particularly through security, defense, and intelligence partnerships; a strong economic and strategic partnership; and a shared commitment to addressing global excess capacity in steel production.</p>



<p>6. &nbsp;The alternative means, including the tariff-rate quota, advance the recommendations contained in the Secretary&#8217;s January 2018 report. &nbsp;The agreed-upon aggregate tariff-rate quota volume specified in the agreement between the United States and the UK, totaling 500,000 metric tons, is consistent with the objective of reaching and maintaining a sufficient capacity utilization rate in the domestic steel industry and reflects the continued importance of the special relationship that exists between the United States and the UK.</p>



<p>7. &nbsp;In light of my determination to adjust the tariff proclaimed in Proclamation 9705 as applied to eligible steel articles and derivative steel articles that are melted and poured in the UK and imported from either the UK or the European Union, I have considered whether it is necessary and appropriate in light of our national security interests to make any corresponding adjustments to such tariff as it applies to other countries. &nbsp;I have determined that it is necessary and appropriate, at this time, to maintain the current tariff level as it applies to other countries.</p>



<p>8. &nbsp;Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended, authorizes the President to adjust the imports of an article and its derivatives that are being imported into the United States in such quantities or under such circumstances as&nbsp;to threaten to impair the national security.</p>



<p>9. &nbsp;Section 604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended (19&nbsp;U.S.C. 2483), authorizes the President to embody in the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTSUS) the substance of statutes affecting import treatment, and actions thereunder, including the removal, modification, continuance, or imposition of any rate of duty or other import restriction.</p>



<p>Now, Therefore, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN Jr., President of the United&nbsp;States of America, by the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended, section 301 of title 3, United States Code, and section&nbsp;604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended, do hereby proclaim as follows:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (1) &nbsp;To establish a tariff-rate quota on imports of steel articles that are melted and poured in the UK and imported from either the UK or the European Union as set forth in paragraph 4 of this proclamation, U.S. Note 16 of subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS is amended as provided for in the Annex to this proclamation.&nbsp; Imports of steel articles that are melted and poured in the UK and from either the UK or the European Union in excess of the tariff-rate quota quantities shall remain subject to the duties imposed by clause 2 of Proclamation 9705, as amended.&nbsp; The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the United States Trade Representative, shall recommend to the President, as warranted, updates to the in-quota volumes contained in the Annex to this proclamation. &nbsp;Steel articles that are melted and poured in the UK and from either the UK or the European Union imported under an exclusion granted pursuant to clause 3 of Proclamation 9705, as amended, shall count against the in-quota volume of the tariff-rate quota established in clause 1 of this proclamation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (2) &nbsp;Clause 2 of Proclamation 9705, as amended, is revised to read as follows:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8220;(2)(a) &nbsp;In order to establish certain modifications to the duty rate on imports of steel articles, subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS is modified as provided in the Annex to this proclamation and any subsequent proclamations regarding such steel articles.<br>(b) &nbsp;Except as otherwise provided in this proclamation, or in notices published pursuant to clause 3 of this proclamation, all steel articles imports covered by heading 9903.80.01, in subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS, shall be subject to an additional 25 percent ad valorem rate of duty with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, as follows:&nbsp; (i) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on March 23, 2018, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, South Korea, and the member countries of the European Union; (ii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2018, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, and South Korea; (iii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August&nbsp;13,&nbsp;2018, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, South Korea, and Turkey; (iv) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on May 20, 2019, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, South Korea, and Turkey; (v) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on May 21, 2019, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea; (vi) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern standard time on January 1, 2022, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea, and except the member countries of the European Union through 11:59 p.m. eastern standard time on December 31, 2023, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.80.65 through 9903.81.19, inclusive; (vii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on April&nbsp;1,&nbsp;2022, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea, and except the member countries of the European Union through 11:59 p.m. eastern standard time on December 31, 2023, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.80.65 through 9903.81.19, inclusive, and from Japan, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.81.25 through 9903.81.80, inclusive; and (viii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, South Korea, and Ukraine, and except the member countries of the European Union through 11:59 p.m. eastern standard time on December 31, 2023, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.80.65 through 9903.81.19, inclusive, and from Japan and the UK, for steel articles covered by subheadings 9903.81.25 through 9903.81.78 and heading 9903.81.80, and from the member countries of the European Union, for steel articles covered by heading 9903.81.81. &nbsp;Further, except as otherwise provided in notices published pursuant to clause 3 of this proclamation, all steel articles imports from Turkey covered by heading 9903.80.02, in subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS, shall be subject to a 50 percent ad valorem rate of duty with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 13, 2018, and prior to 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on May 21, 2019. &nbsp;All steel articles imports covered by heading 9903.80.61, in subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS, shall be subject to the additional 25 percent ad valorem rate of duty established herein with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern time on the date specified in a determination by the Secretary granting relief. &nbsp;These rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported steel articles, shall apply to imports of steel articles from each country as specified in the preceding three sentences.&#8221;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (3)&nbsp; The first two sentences of clause 1 of Proclamation 9980 of January 24, 2020 (Adjusting Imports of Derivative Aluminum Articles and Derivative Steel Articles Into the United&nbsp;States), are revised to read as follows:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8220;In order to establish increases in the duty rate on imports of certain derivative articles, subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS is modified as provided in Annex I and Annex II to this proclamation. &nbsp;Except as otherwise provided in this proclamation, all imports of derivative aluminum articles specified in Annex I to this proclamation shall be subject to an additional 10 percent ad valorem rate of duty, and all imports of derivative steel articles specified in Annex II to this proclamation shall be subject to an additional 25 percent ad valorem rate of duty, with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, as<br>follows:&nbsp; (i) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern standard time on February 8, 2020, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, the Commonwealth of Australia (Australia), Canada, and the United Mexican States (Mexico) and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea; (ii) on or after 12:01&nbsp;a.m. eastern standard time on January 1, 2022, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, and Mexico and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, Mexico, and South Korea; (iii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on April 1, 2022, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, and Mexico and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, Japan, Mexico, and South Korea; (iv) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, and Mexico, and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, Japan, Mexico, and South Korea, and except from Ukraine through 11:59 p.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2023; and (v) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, Mexico, and the UK, and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, Japan, Mexico, South Korea, and the UK, and except from Ukraine through 11:59 p.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2023.&#8221;<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; (4) &nbsp;Steel articles eligible for treatment under clause 1 of this proclamation must be melted and poured in the UK in order to receive such treatment. &nbsp;Steel articles melted and poured in the UK that are further processed in a member country of the European Union, conferring country of origin in a member country of the European&nbsp;Union, and subsequently imported into the United States is also eligible for treatment under clause 1 of this proclamation as set forth in the Annex to this proclamation. &nbsp;The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the United States Trade Representative, is authorized to take such actions as are necessary to ensure compliance with this requirement.&nbsp; Failure to comply could result in applicable remedies such as the collection of the tariff set forth in clause 2 of Proclamation 9705, or penalties under United States law.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (5) &nbsp;In the case of any known UK steel producer that is owned or controlled by a company registered in the People&#8217;s Republic of China or a Chinese entity, and which exports steel to the United States under the applicable tariff-rate quota, the UK agreed to provide an attestation to the United States annually, based on an annual strategic audit conducted by an independent third party, to the effect that there is no evidence of market-distorting practices by that producer in the UK that would materially contribute to non-market excess capacity of steel.&nbsp; If the attestation is not provided annually as set out in the Annex to this proclamation, the Secretary may temporarily deny access for any UK steel producer to the in‑quota rate for the applicable tariff-rate quota.&nbsp; The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the United States Trade Representative, is authorized to take such actions as are necessary to ensure compliance with the actions regarding attestations set forth in the Annex to this proclamation.&nbsp; If an attestation is not provided as set forth in the Annex to this proclamation, it could result in collection of the tariff set forth in clause 2 of Proclamation 9705.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (6) &nbsp;The modifications to the HTSUS made by clause 1 of this proclamation shall be effective with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, and shall continue in effect, unless such actions are expressly reduced, modified, or terminated.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (7) &nbsp;Any imports of steel articles from the UK and steel articles that are melted and poured in the UK that are further processed in a member country of the European Union, conferring country of origin in a member country of the European Union, that were admitted into a U.S. foreign trade zone under &#8220;privileged foreign status&#8221; as defined in 19 CFR 146.41, prior to 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, shall be subject upon entry for consumption made on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, to the provisions of the tariff‑rate quota in effect at the time of the entry for consumption.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (8) &nbsp;Any provision of previous proclamations and Executive&nbsp;Orders that is inconsistent with the actions taken in&nbsp;this proclamation is superseded to the extent of such inconsistency.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Adjusting Imports of Aluminum Into the United&#160;States</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-adjusting-imports-of-aluminum-into-the-united-states-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 19:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; &#160; 1. &#160;On January 19, 2018, the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) transmitted to the President a report on the Secretary&#8217;s investigation into the effect of imports of aluminum articles on the national security of the United States under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended (19&#160;U.S.C. 1862).&#160; The Secretary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 1. &nbsp;On January 19, 2018, the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) transmitted to the President a report on the Secretary&#8217;s investigation into the effect of imports of aluminum articles on the national security of the United States under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended (19&nbsp;U.S.C. 1862).&nbsp; The Secretary found and advised the President of his opinion that aluminum articles are being imported into the United States in such quantities and under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security of the United&nbsp;States.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 2. &nbsp;In Proclamation 9704 of March 8, 2018 (Adjusting Imports of Aluminum Into the United States), the President concurred in the Secretary&#8217;s finding that aluminum articles are being imported into the United States in such quantities and under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security of the United States, and decided to adjust the imports of aluminum articles by imposing a 10 percent ad valorem tariff on such articles imported from all countries except Canada and Mexico. &nbsp;The proclamation further stated that any country with which we have a security relationship is welcome to discuss with the United States alternative ways to address the threatened impairment of the national security caused by imports from that country, and noted that, should the United States and any such country arrive at a satisfactory alternative means to address the threat to the national security such that the President determines that imports from that country no longer threaten to impair the national security, the President may remove or modify the restriction on aluminum articles imports from that country and, if necessary, adjust the tariff as it applies to other countries, as the national security interests of the United&nbsp;States require.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 3. &nbsp;The United States has successfully concluded discussions with the United Kingdom (UK) on satisfactory alternative means to address the threatened impairment to our national security posed by aluminum articles imports from the UK.&nbsp; The&nbsp;United&nbsp;States and the UK have agreed to expand coordination involving trade remedies and customs matters, monitor bilateral steel and aluminum trade, cooperate on addressing non-market excess capacity and carbon intensity in these sectors, annually review their arrangement and their ongoing cooperation, and confer on market-distorting influence or ownership in the steel and aluminum industries. The United States will monitor the implementation and effectiveness of the measures agreed upon with the UK in addressing our national security needs, and I may revisit this determination, as appropriate.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 4.&nbsp; The United States will implement a number of actions, including a tariff-rate quota that restricts the quantity of aluminum articles imported into the United States from the UK without the application of the tariff proclaimed in Proclamation 9704. &nbsp;Under the arrangement, aluminum articles, except semi‑finished wrought aluminum articles, that are&nbsp;accompanied by a certificate of analysis&nbsp;are eligible for in-quota treatment.&nbsp; In order to be eligible for in-quota treatment, semi-finished wrought aluminum articles must be accompanied by a certificate of analysis and must not contain primary aluminum from the People&#8217;s Republic of China, the Russian Federation, or the Republic of Belarus. &nbsp;In my judgment, these measures will provide an effective, long-term alternative means to address any contribution by UK aluminum articles imports to the threatened impairment to our national security by restraining aluminum articles imports to the United States&nbsp;from the UK, limiting transshipment, and discouraging excess capacity and excess aluminum production. &nbsp;In light of this agreement, I have determined that specified volumes of eligible aluminum articles imports from the UK will no longer threaten to impair the national security and have decided to exclude such imports from the UK up to a designated quota from the tariff proclaimed in Proclamation 9704. &nbsp;The United States will monitor the implementation and effectiveness of the tariff-rate quota and other measures agreed upon with the UK in addressing our national security needs, and I may revisit this determination, as appropriate.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 5. &nbsp;The alternative means, including the tariff-rate quota, are consistent with the recommendations specified in the original investigation into the effect of imports of aluminum articles on the national security of the United States under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended. &nbsp;The agreed-upon aggregate tariff-rate quota volume, totaling 900 metric tons of unwrought aluminum, 11,400&nbsp;metric tons of semi-finished wrought aluminum other than foil, and 9,300 metric tons of foil, is consistent with the objective of reaching and sustaining a sufficient capacity utilization rate in the domestic aluminum industry.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 6.&nbsp; In light of my determination to adjust the tariff proclaimed in Proclamation 9704 as applied to eligible aluminum articles imports from the UK, I have considered whether it is necessary and appropriate in light of our national security interests to make any corresponding adjustments to such tariff as it applies to other countries. &nbsp;I have determined that it is necessary and appropriate, at this time, to maintain the current tariff level as it applies to other countries.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 7. &nbsp;Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended, authorizes the President to adjust the imports of an article and its derivatives that are being imported into the United States in such quantities or under such circumstances as&nbsp;to threaten to impair the national security.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 8. &nbsp;Section 604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended (19&nbsp;U.S.C. 2483), authorizes the President to embody in the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTSUS) the substance of statutes affecting import treatment, and actions thereunder, including the removal, modification, continuance, or imposition of any rate of duty or other import restriction.<br>Now, Therefore, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United&nbsp;States of America, by the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended, section 301 of title 3, United States Code, and section&nbsp;604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended, do hereby proclaim as follows:<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (1) &nbsp;To establish a tariff-rate quota on imports of eligible aluminum articles from the UK as set forth in paragraph 4 of this proclamation, U.S. Note 19 of subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS is amended as provided for in the Annex to this proclamation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Imports of aluminum articles from the UK in excess of the tariff-rate quota quantities shall remain subject to the duties imposed by clause 2 of Proclamation 9704, as amended. &nbsp;The Secretary, in consultation with the United States Trade Representative and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall recommend to the President, as warranted, updates to the in-quota volumes contained in the Annex to this proclamation. &nbsp;Aluminum articles from the UK imported under an exclusion granted pursuant to clause 3 of Proclamation 9704, as amended, shall count against the in-quota volume of the tariff-rate quota established in clause 1 of this proclamation.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (2)&nbsp; Clause 2 of Proclamation 9704, as amended, is further amended in the second sentence by deleting &#8220;and&#8221; before &#8220;(h)&#8221; and inserting before the period at the end: &nbsp;&#8220;, and (i) &nbsp;on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Canada, Mexico, and from the member countries of the European Union through 11:59 p.m. eastern standard time on December 31, 2023, and from the United&nbsp;Kingdom, for aluminum articles covered by headings 9903.85.25 through 9903.85.44, inclusive.&#8221;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (3) &nbsp;Aluminum articles eligible for treatment under clause 1 of this proclamation must be accompanied by a certificate of analysis in order to receive such treatment.&nbsp; Eligible semi‑finished wrought aluminum articles must not contain primary aluminum from the People&#8217;s Republic of China, the Russian Federation, or the Republic of Belarus. &nbsp;The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the United States Trade Representative, is authorized to take such actions as are necessary to ensure compliance with this requirement. &nbsp;Failure to comply could result in applicable remedies or penalties under United States law.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (4) &nbsp;The modifications to the HTSUS made by clause 1 of this proclamation shall be effective with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, and shall continue in effect, unless such actions are expressly reduced, modified, or terminated.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (5) &nbsp;Any imports of aluminum articles from the UK that were admitted into a U.S. foreign trade zone under &#8220;privileged foreign status&#8221; as defined in 19 CFR 146.41, prior to 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, shall be subject upon entry for consumption made on or after 12:01&nbsp;a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, to the provisions of the tariff-rate quota in effect at the time of the entry for consumption.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (6) &nbsp;Any provision of previous proclamations and Executive&nbsp;Orders that is inconsistent with the actions taken in&nbsp;this proclamation is superseded to the extent of such inconsistency.</p>



<p>      IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.<br>                              </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Immigrant Heritage Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-immigrant-heritage-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 19:47:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is a Nation of immigrants &#8212; shaped by the courageous people from around the world who leave their homes, lives, and loved ones to seek refuge and opportunity on our shores. &#160;Their sacrifices and entrepreneurial spirit have contributed to the rich tapestry that has defined the character of our country for generations.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States is a Nation of immigrants &#8212; shaped by the courageous people from around the world who leave their homes, lives, and loved ones to seek refuge and opportunity on our shores. &nbsp;Their sacrifices and entrepreneurial spirit have contributed to the rich tapestry that has defined the character of our country for generations. &nbsp;Since our founding, the very idea of America as a Nation of limitless possibilities has been nurtured and advanced by immigrants. &nbsp;During National Immigrant Heritage Month, we honor the contributions of immigrants to our great Nation and celebrate their profound impact.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Immigrants fuel our economy and work in every profession, including health care, public service, law, education, engineering, construction, caregiving, manufacturing, service, agriculture, and countless other industries. &nbsp;They create new businesses, small and large, and generate millions of jobs in America. &nbsp;They are essential workers, providing critical services during COVID-19 and serving on the frontlines of research for vaccines and treatments. &nbsp;Immigrants have also helped the United States lead the world in science, technology, and innovation while contributing to the arts, culture, and government. &nbsp;They bring new traditions, customs, and perspectives that keep American innovation dynamic.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration is committed to ensuring that our immigration system is&nbsp;accessible&nbsp;and&nbsp;humane.&nbsp; I have called on the Congress to pass long-overdue legislation to comprehensively reform our immigration system.&nbsp; Through multiple Executive Orders, I have also directed agencies across the Federal Government to remove barriers that improperly impede access to immigration benefits and to assure fair and timely adjudication of those benefits.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; An important part of our commitment is recognizing that, too often, immigrants face discrimination, xenophobia, and violence.&nbsp; Hate and fear are being given too much oxygen by those who pretend to love America but do not understand America.&nbsp; To confront the dangerous ideology of hate requires caring about all people &#8212; including our Nation&#8217;s immigrants.&nbsp; After all, the fundamental promise of America is that all of us are created equal and deserve to be treated equally throughout our lives. &nbsp;As a Nation, we have never fully lived up to that promise, but we have never walked away from it either. &nbsp;That is why my Administration will continue to use every tool at our disposal to ensure that all immigrants feel safe, valued, and respected. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States has long been a refuge for those seeking safe haven. &nbsp;In the wake of World War II, we opened our doors to hundreds of thousands fleeing the devastation in Europe and the horrors of the Holocaust. &nbsp;After the Vietnam War and other conflicts in Southeast Asia, we formed the United States Refugee Admissions Program, which has welcomed more than 3&nbsp;million people fleeing persecution and war since 1980. &nbsp;More&nbsp;recently, we welcomed tens of thousands of Afghans and their families who served honorably alongside American forces, and we are now welcoming thousands of Ukrainians fleeing Russia&#8217;s invasion. &nbsp;My Administration continues to extend Temporary Protected Status for vulnerable migrant populations throughout the world who cannot safely return to their countries of origin.&nbsp; Furthermore, my Administration is committed to promoting naturalization and breaking down barriers to United States citizenship for all eligible candidates &#8212; a promise that honors our Nation&#8217;s values and makes us more secure and prosperous.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When someone becomes a United States citizen, it gives them the opportunity to fully participate in and contribute their unique talents to our American story. &nbsp;Each generation of immigrants has made our Nation stronger and reaffirmed that diversity is &#8212; and always has been &#8212; our greatest strength. &nbsp;This National Immigrant Heritage Month, we honor our immigrants and recommit to remaining a country worthy of their dreams and aspirations, a Nation true to our enduring values, and a democracy that forever stands as a beacon of hope to the world.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as National Immigrant Heritage Month. &nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to learn more about the history of our Nation&#8217;s diverse and varied immigrant communities and to observe this month with appropriate programming and activities that remind us of the values of diversity, equity, and inclusion.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Meeting With Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen and Federal Reserve Chair Jerome&#160;Powell</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/31/remarks-by-president-biden-before-meeting-with-treasury-secretary-janet-yellen-and-federal-reserve-chair-jerome-powell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 19:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54408</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 1:37 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I have a very brief statement. First, I want to begin by congratulating Mr. Chairman on his recent confirmation for a second term, along with Drs. Brainard and Cook and Jefferson &#8212; recent confirmations. And I’m meeting with the Chairman today and with Secretary Yellen to discuss my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>1:37 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I have a very brief statement.</p>



<p>First, I want to begin by congratulating Mr. Chairman on his recent confirmation for a second term, along with Drs. Brainard and Cook and Jefferson &#8212; recent confirmations.</p>



<p>And I’m meeting with the Chairman today and with Secretary Yellen to discuss my top priority, and that is addressing inflation and &#8212; and the &#8212; in order to transition from a historic recovery to a steady growth that works for American families. </p>



<p>(Clears throat.)&nbsp; Excuse me.</p>



<p>And my plan is to address inflation.&nbsp; It starts with a simple proposition: Respect the Fed and respect the Fed’s independence, which I have done and will continue to do.</p>



<p>My job as President is not to nominate highly &#8212; not only nominate highly &#8212; highly qualified individuals for that institution, but to give them the space they need to do their job.&nbsp; I’m not going to interfere with their critically important work.</p>



<p>The Fed has dual responsibilities: One, full employment.&nbsp; Two, stable prices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Chair Powell and other leaders of the Fed have noted, at this moment, they have a laser-focus on addressing inflation, just like I am.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with a larger complement of board members now confirmed, I know we’ll use those tools of monetary policy to address the rising prices for the American people.</p>



<p>So, I look forward to Chairman Powell’s continued leadership at the Fed.&nbsp; And I look forward to the Senate considering my final nominee to the board, Michael Barr, in the near future.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why we’re meeting, folks, and thank you for coming in.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;1:39 P.M. EDT&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Meeting with Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New&#160;Zealand</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/31/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-jacinda-ardern-of-new-zealand/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 19:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 12:50 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Great.&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks everyone for joining.&#160; Sorry for the delay.&#160; The meeting went a little bit over.&#160; So just to quickly go over the ground rules for this: This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&#160; The contents of this call are embargoed until the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>12:50 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks everyone for joining.&nbsp; Sorry for the delay.&nbsp; The meeting went a little bit over.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So just to quickly go over the ground rules for this: This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker on the call is [senior administration official].&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to have some short remarks at the top, and then we&#8217;ll take some questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, [senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thank you very much.&nbsp; And I appreciate all of you for joining.&nbsp; The meeting went, actually, significantly longer than expected, and so I apologize for those of you who were kept waiting.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;ll try and keep this relatively short and take some questions.</p>



<p>The President and the Prime Minister met for well over an hour.&nbsp; The conversation was very warm, very direct, and there was a great understanding between the two of them, as you would expect.&nbsp; And there really was discussion about the shared vision for the Indo-Pacific and the importance, in particular, of stepping up engagement with the Pacific Island states.&nbsp; But really, discussion covered the broader Indo-Pacific region and the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The two leaders discussed the many ways in which we work together already on a variety of regional and global issues, but also ways in which we can step up our cooperation, in particular, to support the Pacific Island states as they face tremendous challenges from a variety of fronts &#8212; including, obviously, recovering from COVID and the economic impacts of the COVID pandemic, as well as climate change and other challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They discussed the work that the United States and New Zealand do together on a range of issues, including how we cooperate on addressing common challenges in the broader Indo-Pacific region, including &#8212; and how we&#8217;re working together on the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which the President announced last week in Tokyo; as well as dealing with and addressing the climate crisis &#8212; ways in which we share visions for where the region &#8212; what the region can be doing to better support some of those vulnerable countries that are dealing with challenges caused by the climate crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They also, as you would expect, discussed countering terrorism and dealing with radicalization, and ways in which that has fed violence, and the nexus with online as well as offline issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think that they also had some fairly detailed discussions about the importance of in-person engagement with the Pacific Island leaders, and the importance of continue &#8212; the United States working closely with New Zealand and other partners as we continue to step up our efforts to engage more effectively in the Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they &#8212; there was also discussion of the shared history and shared perspectives and the ways in which United States and New Zealand have worked together over the years to deal with common challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that the &#8212; you know, things that really stood out were just the warmth, the intimacy, the alignment on a variety of issues, the shared concern about the challenges caused by extremism, and particularly the online nexus, but more broadly, how to deal with the challenges of domestic violence and &#8212; or &#8212; sort of violence and terrorism domestically as well as internationally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that the context for this is obviously the administration&#8217;s focus on the Indo-Pacific, which I&#8217;m sure all of you have seen both from the recent engagements in Washington with the ASEAN &#8212; the U.S.-ASEAN special summit, as well as the President&#8217;s trip to Korea and Japan last week, the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, and the Quad meeting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think the discussion with Prime Minister Ardern really further highlighted the breadth and depth of the shared concerns about changes and challenges in the region and the fact that New Zealand continues to be a very close and very important U.S. partner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that this is also in the context of &#8212; the fact that the United States is a Pacific nation, and the region remains an enduring foreign policy priority for the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, you know, in addition to the examples I just cited, we&#8217;ve been working on stepping up our engagement in the Pacific and doing this in close &#8212; with close consultation with New Zealand, as well as other important partners and Pacific Island states themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You will have seen that Secretary Blinken announced &#8212; visited Fiji in February.&nbsp; He was the first U.S. Secretary of State to visit there in 36 years.&nbsp; While there, he rolled out the U.S. Indo-Pacific Strategy, which we think &#8212; you know, it was a very important signal to do that in the Pacific and in Fiji.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He also announced that the U.S. intends to open an embassy in the Solomon Islands in Honiara and that the U.S. is working to expand our diplomatic footprint and presence throughout the region and to better harness and work with the programs that we do have that are both regional and global, as well as our direct engagements in the region, and to work more closely with partners.</p>



<p>Last year in August 2021, the President became the first U.S. president to ever address the Pacific Islands Forum leaders meeting.&nbsp; And this was &#8212; the meeting was remote but the President took great satisfaction in that address, which we believe strengthened the engagement and relationship with the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think that as part of our focus on the Pacific, we recognize the tremendous importance of concluding negotiations with the freely associated states of the Republic of Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and Palau.&nbsp; And in order to do that and to be able to regain momentum on that and to try and conclude these agreements which we believe are vital for the United States as well as for the countries concerned, the President appointed Ambassador Joseph Yun as Special Presidential Envoy for Compact Negotiations.&nbsp; And this was only the third Special Presidential Envoy designation in the administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Also recognizing the tremendous demand and something that New Zealand and other countries have been very clear in the importance of trying to address this challenge of trying to provide better maritime domain awareness of capability throughout the region but particularly in the Pacific, we announced the Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness at the Quad meeting in Tokyo last week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This program and this partnership will offer a near real-time, integrated and cost-effective maritime domain awareness picture and will transform the ability of partners in the Pacific Islands, Southeast Asia, the Indian Ocean region to fully monitor the waters in their exclusive economic zones, which we believe both helps them in terms of their own interests but also helps strengthen the ability to deliver a free and open Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>The administration is working closely also with traditional partners in the region &#8212; including Australia, New Zealand, Japan, France, the United Kingdom &#8212; on climate, maritime security, infrastructure, education, and post-COVID economic recovery issues.</p>



<p>And you may have seen that, just last week, we announced Fiji as the 14th founding partner for the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which will help set the rules for the digital economy; strengthen supply chains and lower costs, as well as tackling corruption that drags down our economies, our companies, and our workers; and then try and work more effectively to address the challenge of climate change and decarbonization while also trying to seize the economic potential benefits that come from that.</p>



<p>You will be seeing a joint statement that goes into more detail on the U.S.-New Zealand partnership and the issues that we&#8217;ve been working on as part of this visit.&nbsp; And I think that reflects the extraordinary closeness and &#8212; of the relationship, the progress has been made over the years, and the fact that New Zealand remains a very close and important partner to the United States, and that the leaders have a very, very close relationship that is really based on shared perspectives on the world, as well as an understanding of the importance of working together.</p>



<p>So, with that, let me take some questions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for taking my call.&nbsp; I have two questions about the meeting.&nbsp; The first one is: Did the leaders discuss this economic and security deal that has been attempted by China and, so far, rejected by the Pacific Island countries?&nbsp; Is this something that the U.S. is concerned about?&nbsp; What are you planning to do to increase engagement in the region beyond what you&#8217;ve just outlined?</p>



<p>And then, the second question is: Did the leaders discuss New Zealand&#8217;s military support for Ukraine?&nbsp; I understand, so far, they&#8217;ve given support for training soldiers.&nbsp; Did the Prime Minister indicate whether &#8212; or did the President encourage the Prime Minister to consider sending heavy weapons to Ukraine as well?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; So, on the first question, the two leaders discussed the importance of our respective engagement in the Pacific, and they discussed the challenges that the region faces, including the climate crisis as well as recovering from COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They discussed the &#8212; they did not get into specific details about efforts by other countries, but they did discuss the importance of working together to present an affirmative vision for the region, as well as solidifying the traditional areas of cooperation and building new ones.</p>



<p>In the context of Ukraine, there &#8212; they did not get into specifics.&nbsp; There was &#8212; the President expressed great appreciation for New Zealand&#8217;s strong support for Ukraine in the face of the brutal Russian invasion and the importance of working together, as well as with the rest of the international community, to ensure support for Ukraine.</p>



<p>The President made clear his appreciation of the very significant steps that Ukraine is &#8212; that New Zealand has taken for this, and that this reflects very strong leadership on the part of the Prime Minister.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Yes, hi.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; I just wanted to follow up on that last question and ask whether there &#8212; you know, there are any specific plans to step &#8212; you know, when the United States talks about the need to step up its game and for its allies and partners to do the same.&nbsp; Were there any specific steps that were discussed?</p>



<p>On the &#8212; also, on (inaudible), it seems that he was quite disparaging about IPEF (inaudible) China.&nbsp; I was wondering if you can comment on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, about the New Zealand Prime Minister&#8217;s view that while IPEF is all very well, it would be better if the United States rejoined what is now CPTPP.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thank you.&nbsp; So I think that &#8212; a couple of things.&nbsp; First, with regard to IPEF, you know, we believe that this is a very significant step.&nbsp; And we are very pleased at the extraordinarily strong interest from throughout the region.&nbsp; It is &#8212; you know, fro- &#8212; I think, to us, it is interesting that, on one hand, that we have heard some disparagement of IPEF from China and then also some complaints that it doesn&#8217;t incl- &#8212; that China hasn&#8217;t been invited.</p>



<p>I think that our view is that IPEF is about working together to support a free and open Indo-Pacific, and that it is &#8212; that it is open to countries who support a free and open Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And that we are very pleased &#8212; there has been &#8212; the interest that there has been from so many countries to join and that &#8212; that have been the chosen to be founding members.</p>



<p>I think that, you know, we also remember that, you know, there was similar disparagement at one point about the Quad, and the Quad turned out not to be (inaudible).&nbsp; And that, you know, we are interested in seeing how things evolve with the perceptions of IPEF.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that what we are pleased by is that the countries that have &#8212; that are participating clearly are very enthusiastic about the basic principles behind it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With regard to discussions on CPTPP, I think the Prime Minister has made her views very clear.&nbsp; I think in this meeting, there was discussion about the importance of economic engagement.&nbsp; And I would note that we&#8217;re announcing the resumption of the TIFA discussions between the U.S. &#8212; or consultations between the U.S. and New Zealand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that there is &#8212; there&#8217;s also &#8212; you know, she was very clear in her support and New Zealand&#8217;s &#8212; how pleased New Zealand is to be a founding member of IPEF and the importance of affirmative U.S. economic engagement in the region.</p>



<p>I think that the &#8212;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], are you still there?&nbsp; [Senior administration official], are you still there?</p>



<p>OPERATOR:&nbsp; Let me check.&nbsp; We may have lost him.&nbsp; He has disconnected from the call.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Could we just pause for a few minutes?&nbsp; Let me try to see what happened here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>OPERATOR:&nbsp; Certainly.</p>



<p>And he is back.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, I&#8217;m back.&nbsp; So sorry about that.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So I think that on the &#8212; on the other questions about the economic partnership, I think that the two leaders did discuss the importance of broader economic engagement in the region and the importance of continuing to work very closely together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note that we&#8217;re very grateful for New Zealand&#8217;s advice as we worked on the development of IPEF.&nbsp; nd New Zealand&#8217;s, you know, extreme sophistication and experience on regional economic and trade issues was particularly valuable in that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I apologize again for getting cut off.&nbsp; So hopefully that answered your question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp; So, two sperate questions.&nbsp; The first: When you were talking before, you said they did not discuss specific efforts from other countries.&nbsp; Was that in relation to China?</p>



<p>And secondly, with the Maritime Awareness Initiative out of the Quad, was there any sort of indication that New Zealand might be invited into such an agreement?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, just on the AUKUS arrangement between Australia and the U.S., was there any discussion around how New Zealand might be able to have some involvement in arrangements like that?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, let me start off on &#8212; you know, again, there was a general discussion about the challenges that the Pacific region faces.&nbsp; There weren&#8217;t &#8212; there was not a specific discussion about any specific initiatives that are coming out from any other countries. But I think there&#8217;s a general awareness of the need to make sure that we step up our efforts and our cooperation.</p>



<p>In terms of what that means, I think that it is about several different things.&nbsp; One is expanding U.S. engagement in the region.&nbsp; And as I mentioned, there was discussion about the importance of in-person meetings at the leader level.</p>



<p>There also was a discussion about expanding U.S. diplomatic presence and also looking to step up the various types of engagement on things having to do with climate, recovery from COVID, preparation for next pandemic, and, I think, a great deal of commonality of views.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think that in terms of the questions about the maritime domain awareness initiatives, I think that at this point that &#8212; we did not have discussions &#8212; or there was not a specific discussion about how New Zealand is going to play into that, but it was very clear that New Zealand is very supportive of the initiative.</p>



<p>In terms of AUKUS, there was no specific discussion about AUKUS itself, but this is something that is discussed in the &#8212; but part of that is because it had been addressed in the joint statement.&nbsp; And I think that there is a &#8212; I think an awareness of the potential that AUKUS offers as a platform for perhaps opening up other apertures for cooperation in the future.</p>



<p>And I think that more broadly, there was support for the importance of greater engagement by outside partners, as we see in AUKUS, in terms of trying to ensure a free and open Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Did the two leaders discuss gun control?&nbsp; And in particular, did the Prime Minister urge President Biden to embrace the gun buyback programs and a ban on assault weapons like New Zealand has done in the last few years?&nbsp; And could you just give us a sense of what that conversation was like if &#8212; if they did discuss the Uvalde situation?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Look, they discussed domestic extremism and the challenges that poses.&nbsp; And the Prime Minister discussed the Christchurch Call to Action and the responses that New Zealand had done after the tragic attack in Christchurch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They just &#8212; they both share a very strong concern about the slaughter of innocents that these kinds of extremist attacks pose.&nbsp; There was &#8212; she did not urge the President to any specific course of action, but there was discussion about the challenges that these &#8212; and the horrible cost of these kinds of attacks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that there is a &#8212; you know, she was &#8212; she offered her sympathy, and the President appreciated that very much.&nbsp; It was very clear that, you know, she has, as you would expect, a particular understanding of the extraordinarily difficult challenges that these kinds of attacks pose both at the &#8212; you know, in terms of the actual victims, but then, more broadly, the longer-term consequences for survivors and first responders.</p>



<p>So, it was a very &#8212; it was a very powerful discussion. But it was not one where she urged a particular course of action on the President, but rather expressed a broad understanding for what the United States is going through.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; All right, well, thanks everyone for joining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And the embargo on the contents of the call will lift as soon as the call is over.</p>



<p>Thanks for joining.&nbsp; If you have any more questions, let me know.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 1:12 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Caribbean-American Heritage Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-caribbean-american-heritage-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 18:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America&#8217;s strength has always been rooted in our diversity.  Since our Nation&#8217;s founding, generation after generation of immigrants have helped build this country, and the prosperity and opportunity that draw so many immigrants to America would not be possible without the contributions and legacies of Caribbean Americans.  Today, millions of Caribbean Americans strengthen our country&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America&#8217;s strength has always been rooted in our diversity.  Since our Nation&#8217;s founding, generation after generation of immigrants have helped build this country, and the prosperity and opportunity that draw so many immigrants to America would not be possible without the contributions and legacies of Caribbean Americans.  Today, millions of Caribbean Americans strengthen our country through their vibrant cultures, traditions, languages, and values.  In recognition of National Caribbean-American Heritage Month, we honor the immeasurable ways Caribbean Americans have added to our American dream. </p>



<p>This month, our Nation also celebrates the extraordinary leadership and achievements of Vice President Kamala Harris, the first Black American of Jamaican heritage to hold this high office.  I am also honored to celebrate alongside brilliant and dedicated public servants of Caribbean heritage &#8212; including Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona, Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro Mayorkas, and Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice. </p>



<p>Every day, we see the invaluable contributions Caribbean American communities have made to our country.&nbsp; Our Nation has seen the persistence and character of generations of Caribbean Americans who have fought for equity and equality despite continued discrimination and hardship.&nbsp; In addition, public servants like our Nation&#8217;s first Supreme Court Justice of Puerto&nbsp;Rican descent, Sonia Sotomayor, and the late General Colin Powell, the son of Jamaican immigrants and the first Black&nbsp;Secretary of State, have made essential contributions to American society and blazed new trails in service to the American people.&nbsp; Caribbean American entrepreneurs, scientists, medical professionals, teachers, artists, police officers, athletes, and contributors in every field have also left a&nbsp;lasting impact on our society.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In spite of innumerable achievements and undeniable contributions, too many Caribbean Americans continue to face systemic barriers to success.&nbsp; Caribbean Americans have been impacted by systemic racism and disparities in opportunity.&nbsp; My&nbsp;Administration has taken a whole-of-government approach to advancing racial justice and equity in order to begin healing those wounds and strengthening opportunity for all.&nbsp; We will continue to use every tool at our disposal to ensure that every American &#8212; no matter who they are or where they come from &#8212; has equal access to the American dream.</p>



<p>During this National Caribbean-American Heritage Month, we&nbsp;honor the generations of Caribbean Americans who have built our Nation, shaped our progress, and strengthened our national character.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim June 2022 as National Caribbean-American Heritage Month.&nbsp; I encourage all Americans to join in celebrating the history, culture, and achievements of Caribbean Americans with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Ocean Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-ocean-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 18:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; From the air we breathe to the food we eat, our magnificent ocean touches every aspect of our lives. &#160;It helps regulate the climate, supports millions of jobs, and serves as a place for exploration, commerce, and recreation. &#160;As it sustains and connects us, the ocean is woven into the cultures of local and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; From the air we breathe to the food we eat, our magnificent ocean touches every aspect of our lives. &nbsp;It helps regulate the climate, supports millions of jobs, and serves as a place for exploration, commerce, and recreation. &nbsp;As it sustains and connects us, the ocean is woven into the cultures of local and Indigenous coastal and island communities. &nbsp;During National Ocean Month, we celebrate the beauty and bounty of our ocean and reaffirm our commitment to protecting and conserving our marine environments for a sustainable future.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fifty years ago, our Nation enacted laws that created a robust foundation for environmental protection: &nbsp;the Clean Water Act, the Coastal Zone Management Act, the Marine Mammal Protection Act, and the National Marine Sanctuaries Act. &nbsp;Through these laws, we have protected our coastlines, safeguarded marine wildlife, sustained fisheries, and improved water quality. &nbsp;Today, the United States is a global leader in protecting and using precious marine resources in a responsible and sustainable way &#8212; but there is still more work to be done.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Earlier this year, my Administration released a sobering report on sea level rise caused by climate change. &nbsp;Addressing this issue requires collaboration and commitment. &nbsp;Working with State, Tribal, Territorial, and local partners, we will co-develop ocean-based climate solutions, including the United States Ocean-Climate Action Plan, which will help us mitigate and adapt to the effects of the climate crisis.&nbsp; To guide our understanding of the ocean, coasts, and climate change, we must also invest in science and solutions that recognize and elevate Indigenous and local knowledge.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is a critical step forward in providing resources to enhance ocean and coastal observation, mapping, and forecasting &#8212; tools that will greatly improve the resilience of our coastal infrastructure and shorelines.&nbsp; The Natural Capital Accounts and National Nature Assessment I announced on Earth Day will also help us understand the ocean&#8217;s value to our economy, health, climate, and national security. &nbsp;My Administration is developing a National Ocean Plan to develop the ocean economy and create good-paying American jobs while protecting vital marine ecosystems. &nbsp;Toward that aim, we are already deploying offshore wind energy and joining international initiatives to manage the planet&#8217;s ocean equitably and sustainably.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are also working to restore coastal habitats and ecosystems with nature-based solutions that protect coastal communities from flooding and storms. &nbsp;These investments go hand-in-hand with my Administration&#8217;s America the Beautiful Initiative, which set a national goal to voluntarily conserve and restore at least 30 percent of United States lands and waters by 2030.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In taking these steps, we recognize that access to our ocean and its benefits have not always been equally distributed. &nbsp;Communities of color, Indigenous communities, and low-income communities have often been shut out from ocean-related opportunities while shouldering disproportionate climate burdens.&nbsp; My Administration is committed to delivering climate justice, expanding access to ocean opportunities, and diversifying ocean workforces.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During National Ocean Month, as we celebrate the beauty and power of our ocean, let us remember our shared responsibility to protect and preserve it.&nbsp; Together, let us recommit to caring for our ocean and enhancing its economic and ecological sustainability for generations to come.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as National Ocean Month. &nbsp;I call upon Americans to take action to protect, conserve, and restore our ocean and coasts.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Homeownership Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-homeownership-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 18:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; &#160;For many Americans, a home is more than just a residence. &#160;It is a place that instills a sense of pride, security, and comfort that, no matter what challenges in life arise, they have somewhere to go and call their own. &#160;Whether owning or renting, a home is where we can live with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;For many Americans, a home is more than just a residence. &nbsp;It is a place that instills a sense of pride, security, and comfort that, no matter what challenges in life arise, they have somewhere to go and call their own. &nbsp;Whether owning or renting, a home is where we can live with dignity and watch our families grow. &nbsp;During National Homeownership Month, we recognize the importance of housing and reaffirm our commitment to ensuring that everyone has a place to call home.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Every American should be able to afford to rent or own a home of their own.&nbsp; Yet across the country, the price of housing &#8212; both for renters and homebuyers &#8212; is increasing, making it harder for people to find an affordable home.&nbsp; Our Nation is facing a housing shortage that is driving up prices &#8212; and with housing prices near record highs, too many families are unable to make other important investments, such as furthering their education or saving for retirement.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Throughout the pandemic, my Administration has helped people who have struggled, through no fault of their own, stay in their homes by providing financial relief to help pay the mortgage or the rent.&nbsp;&nbsp;To tackle the root causes of housing affordability, my Administration released a Housing Supply Action Plan, aimed at closing the nationwide shortfall of housing for purchase and rent in 5 years through a variety of measures: &nbsp;incentivizing States and localities to create the conditions for more housing, improving financing tools for a wider range of housing arrangements, enhancing existing forms of financing for housing construction, and addressing other barriers to housing supply and affordability, such as supply chain issues due to the pandemic.&nbsp;&nbsp;My budget also includes investments to address the critical shortage of affordable housing and provide first-generation down payment assistance to&nbsp;aspiring homeowners.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Homeownership is a major source of generational wealth for many Americans &#8212; it is a central part of the American dream. &nbsp;But for too many Americans &#8212; especially Black and Brown Americans &#8212; homeownership and the opportunity to build and pass down wealth through it are unattainable. &nbsp;Longstanding inequities in the housing system, from disinvestment to redlining and mis-valuation of homes in communities of color, have locked out entire generations from the American dream and the opportunity to build generational wealth.&nbsp; Housing also opens up opportunities that are tied to where one lives, and it is our shared responsibility to ensure that everyone has equitable access to those opportunities &#8212; from education and stable employment to quality health care and healthy food.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration is committed to ending unlawful housing discrimination and advancing equity for underserved communities.&nbsp; Toward that aim, we have launched an aggressive effort to combat racial discrimination in housing.&nbsp; I also remain committed to expanding access to homeownership opportunities for first-time home buyers and minority homebuyers while ensuring that Black and Brown families receive a fair appraisal for their homes. &nbsp;Through the Property Appraisal and Valuation Equity Action Plan, we have developed the most wide-ranging set of Federal reforms in history to ensure that the color of a person&#8217;s skin does not determine the value of their home.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;As we mark National Homeownership Month, we recognize the importance of housing for all Americans. &nbsp;Whether owning, renting, or aspiring to do either, we renew our commitment to lowering costs and expanding access to safe, affordable homes that all Americans need and deserve.&nbsp;&nbsp;Together, we can ensure that every American has a safe place to call home.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as National Homeownership Month. &nbsp;I&nbsp;call upon the people of this Nation to safeguard the American Dream by ensuring that everyone has access to an affordable home in a community of their choice.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/31/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-jacinda-ardern-of-new-zealand-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 11:15 A.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, good morning, everybody. &#160;And it’s good to see a not-so-old but a good friend here.&#160; Prime Minister, welcome to the White House.&#160; And we last saw each other at the launch of the Indo-Pacific Framework &#8212; PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&#160; Yes. PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; &#8212; which is, I think,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>11:15 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, good morning, everybody. &nbsp;And it’s good to see a not-so-old but a good friend here.&nbsp; Prime Minister, welcome to the White House.&nbsp; And we last saw each other at the launch of the Indo-Pacific Framework &#8212;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; which is, I think, a fairly big deal for all of us, and we need your guidance.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re &#8212; and, you know, it&#8217;s a pleasure to see you in person.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You understand that your leadership has taken on a critical role in this global stage &#8212; and it really has &#8212; galvanizing action on climate change; the global effort to curb violence, extremism, and online, like happened in Christchurch.</p>



<p>And &#8212; you know, we want to be &#8212; I want to work with you on that effort.&nbsp; And I want to talk to you about what those conversations were like, if you&#8217;re willing.</p>



<p>The United States is, you know &#8212; it’s just been &#8212; there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s an expression by an Irish poet that says, “Too long a suffering makes a stone of the heart.”&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s an awful lot of suffering.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been &#8212; I &#8212; I&#8217;ve been to more mass shooting aftermaths than, I think, any President in American history, unfortunately.&nbsp; And it’s &#8212; it’s just &#8212; so much of it is &#8212; much of it is preventable, and the devastation is &#8212; is amazing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday &#8212; or not &#8212; the day before, I was up &#8212; I was down in Texas.&nbsp; And people sat in a room &#8212; about 250 of them in a large room &#8212; with me for almost four hours.&nbsp; Not &#8212; nobody left.&nbsp; They waited until aft- &#8212; until I spoke to every single person in that room.&nbsp; Every single person, they waited to the very end.&nbsp; And the &#8212; they &#8212; the pain is palpable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you’ve been one of our closest partners with a long history and friendship.&nbsp; Eighty years ago, Marines landed in New Zealand before embarking on &#8212; into the Pacific Theater in World War Two.&nbsp; And I think I told you, when I met my &#8212; my &#8212; two of my mother&#8217;s brothers who were in the Pacific &#8212; they used to be able to deploy at the same time in those days, in World War Two.&nbsp; And one was shot down in New Guinea.&nbsp; And they never found the body.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, it’s &#8212; the history goes back a long way &#8212; a long way.</p>



<p>And I want to, by the way, recognize New Zealand’s significant support for Ukraine, as a lot of Indo-Pacific countries are doing now.&nbsp; And &#8212; because this is more than just a regional war going on.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I look forward to our conversations today.&nbsp; We have a lot to talk about.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m really, really delighted to have you here &#8212; really.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And can I say, Mr. President, thank you, so much &#8212; so much &#8212;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; You &#8212; you can do anything you want.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And we really welcome this opportunity.</p>



<p>As you&#8217;ve said, we&#8217;ve spoken on several occasions.&nbsp; And what stood out to me on both those occasions were we traversed such similar issues, and not &#8212; not least, of course, our shared history.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You speak of your uncle&#8217;s service in the Pacific; my grandfather served in the Pacific.&nbsp; And I think that speaks to the personal connection but also the depth of our friendship and relationship as two countries.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are in an incredibly difficult international environment.&nbsp; But also, domestically, it is extraordinarily challenging as well.&nbsp; And can I bring the sincere condolences of the people of Aotearoa New Zealand for what you have experienced in Texas and in New York?&nbsp; And it&#8217;s been devastating to see the impact on those communities.</p>



<p>Our experience, of course, in this regard, is our own.&nbsp; But if there&#8217;s anything that we can share that would be of any value, we are here to share it.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, the work you’re doing with tech companies is really important, and I want &#8212;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Absolutely.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; to work with you there as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; And I absolutely look forward to updating you on some of the conversations we&#8217;ve had this week because I hold hope that we can make progress.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also wanted just to acknowledge your leadership in bringing to the table the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.&nbsp; And whilst, of course, we are significant advocates for the CPTPP, the IPEF presents a significant opportunity to build the economic resilience of our region.&nbsp; So, I look forward to having a bit of a discussion about that opportunity as well.</p>



<p>I also want to acknowledge your significant leadership on Ukraine and how important that has been not only to us as we&#8217;ve looked to play a role as well, but globally as we look to make sure that we strengthen the international response to what is a threat to our values and, of course, the territorial sovereignty of Ukraine.</p>



<p>I do want to finish on a note of optimism.&nbsp; Climate change also is one of the greatest threats that we face.&nbsp; And I believe that, in you, not only have we seen the leadership but the opportunity that exists between our nations to work together on this incredibly difficult issue that will only be resolved if we work together.</p>



<p>So, thank you.&nbsp; With &#8212; as you&#8217;ve seen, we&#8217;ve got a lot to discuss, so &#8212;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We’ve got a lot to do.&nbsp; And I want to emphasize the last point you made: “working together.”</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Absolutely.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We are not coming to dictate or lay down the law.&nbsp; We &#8212;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; we have more work to do in those Pacific Islands as well.&nbsp; I mean, we’ve &#8212; and so, we talked at length about &#8212; in the past about my trip to Japan and Korea and then dealing with the Quad.&nbsp; And so &#8212; but I think there&#8217;s a lot of opportunity &#8212;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Yeah, I agree.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; to make the world safer and deal with the environment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; I agree.&nbsp; I agree.&nbsp; So, thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, will you meet with Senator McConnell on guns?&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I will meet with the Congress on guns.&nbsp; I promise you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>11:22 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
