<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 17:30:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre Aboard Air Force One En Route Allentown, PA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/28/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-aboard-air-force-one-en-route-allentown-pa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Allentown, Pennsylvania 11:45 A.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &#160;I’ve never done this on the small plane before, so bear with me. &#160;Hey, everybody.&#160; Good to see everyone.&#160; Welcome to our flight to Lehigh, Pennsyl &#8212; Valley, today in Pennsylvania. As you all know, today we announced a proposed Buy American rule.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Allentown, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>11:45 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &nbsp;I’ve never done this on the small plane before, so bear with me. &nbsp;Hey, everybody.&nbsp; Good to see everyone.&nbsp; Welcome to our flight to Lehigh, Pennsyl &#8212; Valley, today in Pennsylvania.</p>



<p>As you all know, today we announced a proposed Buy American rule.&nbsp; The President believes that when we spend American taxpayer dollars, it should support American workers and business.</p>



<p>In Lehigh Valley today, he will talk about the importance of this Buy American policy to support and grow more American companies and put more American workers in good-paying union jobs, strengthen American manufacturing, and secure critical supply chains while confronting the climate crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During his trip, the President will visit the Lehigh Valley Operations manufacturing facility for Mack Trucks.&nbsp; There are more than 1,500 Mack trucks in the federal fleet, used by both military and civilian agencies.&nbsp; And the President will receive a briefing on the Mack Trucks’ electrical dump truck.</p>



<p>Every Mack truck built for the North American market gets its start at the companies cab and vehicle assembly plant in the lower Macu- &#8212; Macungie township &#8212; I know I messed that up; apologies to Pennsylvania and that township.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ability to build and sell these new trucks would be helped by the President’s proposed investment in Buy American production incentives for domestic electric vehicle manufacturing.</p>



<p>Today, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, CFBP [CFPB], is launching a new rental assistant finder for Americans who may be behind on their rent.&nbsp; You can go to ConsumerFinance.gov/RentHelp and input location information to find local rental assistance programs in the area and apply for assistance.</p>



<p>Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, billions of dollars in federal rental assistance is available to renters who are behind on housing costs and for landlords who have struggled during the pandemic.</p>



<p>Private-sector companies from PayPal and Square, Lyft, and GoFundMe, to nonprofits including United Way, the National Low Income Housing Coalition, and Bread for the World will join with the Biden-Harris administration to raise awareness for this new and important tool, as well as the resources available to assist tenants and landlords.</p>



<p>And as we announced last week, in June, over $1.5 billion was distributed to renters and landlords more than previous &#8212; the previous five months.</p>



<p>And with that, Josh, do you want to kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Two subject areas. &nbsp;First, we know that the administration is considering a vaccine mandate for federal employees.&nbsp; Can you give us any guidance in terms of how you&#8217;re defining federal employees?&nbsp; Does that include military, contractors? &nbsp;Would visitors to federal agencies also fall under that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, Josh, let me first say that, you know, our goal as a federal employer is to keep our employees safe and to also save lives.&nbsp; That is the number-one goal that we have here.</p>



<p>While no decision has been finalized, I will say that the attestation of vaccination for federal employees is one option under strong consideration.&nbsp; So, attestation &#8212; what we mean by that is confirming &#8212; which means confirming vaccination status or abiding by stringent COVID-19 protocols, like mandatory mask wearing, even in communities not with high or subsequent substantial spread, and regular testing.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also said requirements for vaccination may be under consideration for certain entities within the government.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates to preview on that front today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned that imposing a mask mandate could exacerbate divisions in the United States that have already been so present in terms of vaccination rates?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me just &#8212; like I said, they’re &#8212; right now we are &#8212; have many options that we&#8217;re looking under consideration.</p>



<p>But let me just step back, because I think &#8212; I want to take this opportunity, with the CDC mask guidance that was given &#8212; again, not a mandate, as you know, but a guidance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, yesterday the CDC did exactly what it was &#8212; it&#8217;s supposed to do.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sure you all saw &#8212; are tracking what the public health experts have said &#8212; said this as &#8212; said as much.&nbsp; The message is simple: If you are in an area where Delta is surging, you should mask up indoors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CDC has to adapt to the virus.&nbsp; And unfortunately, because not enough Americans have stepped up to get vaccinated, they had to provide new guidance to help save lives, especially for those immunocompromised and children, children who &#8212; especially those children who are 11 and under who do not have &#8212; are not able to get vaccinated at this time.&nbsp; So, this is critical.</p>



<p>Again, we want to make sure we&#8217;re saving lives.&nbsp; The CDC guidance was done nonpartisan. &nbsp;It was done as they are looking through guidance, and to really meet the moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re dealing with a virus, as you all know, that&#8217;s unprecedented.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no playbook for this virus.&nbsp; And again, we need to make sure that we&#8217;re saving lives.&nbsp; And we are going to continue to do everything that we can to make sure people are getting vaccinated.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, why would the White House be confident that people in these red zones now will listen to this new mask guidance if they&#8217;ve shrugged off the vaccination message from the White House, if they&#8217;ve shrugged off mask guidance before?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why are you so confident now?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, Karen, let me first say that the CDC is a &#8212; is a body that is highly respected.&nbsp; It is a body that people look towards.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re right &#8212; you know, we &#8212; we are &#8212; we are going to make sure that we go community by community.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure the CDC is going to have a communication &#8212; you know, kind of apparatus of communication with local governments on how to best do this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this was &#8212; this needed to happen.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; They are following the science.&nbsp; We have said this all along.&nbsp; The science is the North Star.&nbsp; We have to listen to public health experts.&nbsp; And, right now, again, we&#8217;re trying to make sure that we&#8217;re saving lives.</p>



<p>But, again, we need to make sure that people who are not vaccinated get vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. HAYES:&nbsp; We have to stop because we have to land.&nbsp; They&#8217;re making us sit down because we have to land.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; Sorry, guys.</p>



<p>11:52 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe Biden on the Passing of Former Wyoming Senator Mike Enzi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-former-wyoming-senator-mike-enzi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For twelve years, I had the privilege of serving with Mike Enzi in the United States Senate. While we sat on different sides of the aisle, I always saw him first as a public servant who conducted himself with decency, honor, and integrity. The Eagle Scout and National Guardsman, the small business owner and small-town&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For twelve years, I had the privilege of serving with Mike Enzi in the United States Senate. While we sat on different sides of the aisle, I always saw him first as a public servant who conducted himself with decency, honor, and integrity.<br><br>The Eagle Scout and National Guardsman, the small business owner and small-town mayor, the state legislator who became a U.S. Senator — Mike never forgot where he came from, and never forgot the people of his beloved Wyoming who placed their trust in him election after election.<br><br>Jill and I are saddened to learn of his passing, and our prayers are with his wife Diana, their children and grandchildren, and his countless friends, colleagues, and staff.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Companies, Non-Profits, Government Agencies Answer Biden-Harris Call: Make Combined Commitment to Alert Tens of Millions of Americans to Emergency Rental Assistance</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/fact-sheet-companies-non-profits-government-agencies-answer-biden-harris-call-make-combined-commitment-to-alert-tens-of-millions-of-americans-to-emergency-rental-assistance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25203</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Major companies, non-profits, and government agencies from the Social Security Administration to the Department of Veterans Affairs, to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention have answered the Biden-Harris Administration’s Call to Action to spread the word and alert Americans that emergency rental assistance is available.&#160; The combined commitments announced today – part of an&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Major companies, non-profits, and government agencies from the Social Security Administration to the Department of Veterans Affairs, to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention have answered the Biden-Harris Administration’s Call to Action to spread the word and alert Americans that emergency rental assistance is available.&nbsp; The combined commitments announced today – part of an ongoing all-out push to make sure tenants and landlords take advantage of federal rental assistance to help cover rent, utilities, and other housing costs and keep people in their homes – could reach tens of millions of Americans.</p>



<p>The continued call to action coincides with the launch of a new rental assistance finder produced by the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB). Americans who may be behind on rent can go to <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/coronavirus/mortgage-and-housing-assistance/renter-protections/find-help-with-rent-and-utilities/?utm_source=vanity&amp;utm_medium=outreach&amp;utm_campaign=renthelp">ConsumerFinance.gov/RentHelp</a> and input information on their location to find local rental assistance programs in their area and apply for assistance.</p>



<p>Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, billions of dollars in federal rental assistance is available to renters who are behind on&nbsp;housing costs,&nbsp;as well as landlords who have struggled during the pandemic. The Administration is building on a whole-of-government effort and engaging a wide variety of stakeholders to spread awareness of the CFPB’s new tool, as well as the resources available to assist tenants and landlords.</p>



<p>Emergency rental assistance is available to tenants in all 50 states, Washington, D.C., territories, and in Tribal areas, and will continue to be available after the expiration of the CDC eviction moratorium on August 1, 2021. The continued Call to Action builds on the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initiatives-to-promote-housing-stability-by-supporting-vulnerable-tenants-and-preventing-foreclosures/">groundwork laid over the past several months</a> by the Administration to engage renters and landlords, including hosting two virtual convenings with thousands of participants to share best practices on eviction prevention and build local plans of action, streamline guidance for the rental assistance program to make it easier and more efficient, and engage agencies across the federal government to help get the word out to households in need.</p>



<p>For more general information about the Emergency Rental Assistance program, <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/coronavirus/mortgage-and-housing-assistance/renter-protections/emergency-rental-assistance-for-renters/?utm_source=paypal&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=era_outreach">visit the unified federal housing assistance portal hosted by the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</a>.</p>



<p>Agencies across the federal government, non-profit groups, faith-based organizations, and private sector companies are responding to the Biden-Harris Administration’s call to action to raise awareness. We expect that these efforts will reach tens of millions of Americans.</p>



<p><strong>Private sector and non-profit commitments include:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>PayPal</strong>, where many pay their rent and monthly bills, will include messaging on emergency rental assistance and a link to the CFPB look-up tool in their PayPal and Venmo apps and on paypal.com.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Square, Inc.</strong> will provide information about the CFPB tool and emergency rental assistance on Cash App – a popular place to pay rent and bills that as of December 2020 had more than 36 million monthly transacting active customers &#8211; and on their Square Seller Community platform.</li><li><strong>GoFundMe </strong>will send direct emails to roughly 20,000 people who have recently started fundraising campaigns in the “food, rent, or monthly bills” category on the GoFundMe site.</li><li><strong>Lyft </strong>will spread the word about emergency rental assistance and the new CFPB tool via a blog post for the Lyft Community.</li><li><strong>Avail</strong>, a property management application that touches landlords and renters, will send emails directly to their users and will post a banner on their website with an anticipated reach of at least 21,000 people per week.</li><li><strong>Propel,</strong> a mission-driven financial technology company, will connect more than 5 million low-income families to resources to help them receive emergency rental assistance.</li><li><strong>National Apartment Association </strong>will send an alert to their 90,000 members nationwide.</li><li><strong>National Multifamily Housing Coalition </strong>will share the CFPB tool with their 10,000 members through emails and a newsletter.</li><li><strong>The National Low Income Housing Coalition </strong>will include a link to the CFPB tool on their website, place an article about the tool and emergency rental assistance in their newsletter which is distributed to 135,000 people, and will brief stakeholders on their weekly call.</li><li><strong>United Way</strong> will raise awareness through their state associations and by sharing the information with the United Way Financial Stability Cohort.</li><li><strong>The Arc</strong>, a non-profit dedicated to promoting and protecting human rights of people with intellectual and developmental disabilities, will send an email with the information to their 600 national chapters.</li><li><strong>Children’s Defense Fund </strong>will share the information with their state offices and will publish a blog post promoting the CFPB tool.</li><li><strong>Operation HOPE</strong>, a non-profit organization dedicated to poverty alleviation and financial inclusion for low and moderate-income youth and adults, will share the CFPB tool and information on emergency rental assistance with a network of over 180 community-based financial coaches and will include the information in their weekly news briefing which reaches over 60,000 people.</li><li><strong>Bread for the World</strong>, a faith-based organization dedicated to poverty and hunger alleviation, will host regional events throughout the country with local faith leaders and churches to educate them about emergency rental assistance.</li></ul>



<p>This Call to Action remains open to everyone – other companies, non-profits, faith-based organizations, and more can answer the Call to Action by leveraging their own communications channels to spread the word.</p>



<p><strong>Commitments from the Administration include:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Veterans Affairs </strong>is sharing the information in a newsletter that reaches 12 million veterans.</li><li><strong>The Social Security Administration </strong>is creating a new, special web page in both English and Spanish dedicated to emergency rental assistance and linking to the CFPB tool.</li><li><strong>The U.S. Department of Agriculture </strong>is building off of previous outreach efforts by sending letters to 65,000 people who live in USDA multi-family properties who are not receiving rental assistance; sharing information with Food Nutrition Service Regional Leads who will then share information with State Departments of Social Services that work with SNAP recipients; and holding a webinar in the coming weeks to provide background on emergency rental assistance.</li><li><strong>The Department of Health and Human Services</strong> is leveraging the communications channels of several of its operating divisions to spread awareness. Specifically: <ul><li>The Administration for Community Living (ACL) is sharing the information about emergency rental assistance with 200,000 community-based organizations that serve people with disabilities and older adults, many of whom are low income and at higher risk for eviction.</li></ul><ul><li>The Administration for Children and Families (ACF) is amplifying the existence of emergency rental assistance and the new CFPB tool with program grantees who can pass along information in the communities they serve.</li></ul><ul><li>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) is sharing the information about emergency rental assistance with healthcare providers and local health departments, and is putting the information on the CDC’s COVID-19 website.</li></ul><ul><li>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) is incorporating messaging around the CFPB tool and emergency rental assistance into call center scripts and will share with partners via their listserv.</li></ul><ul><li>Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) is promoting the CFPB tool and emergency rental assistance via the Maternal and Child Health Bureau and the Federal Office of Rural Policy.</li></ul><ul><li>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) is sending emergency rental assistance information to state offices of mental health and homelessness coordinators throughout the country that work with the Projects for Assistance in Transition for Homelessness (PATH) program. The PATH program provides support to individuals with serious mental illness who are experiencing homelessness.</li></ul></li><li><strong>The Department of the Treasury </strong>is sharing the CFPB tool with state and local governments and tribes who are administering emergency rental assistance programs.</li><li><strong>The Department of Housing and Urban Development</strong> is hosting webinars for non-profit groups and faith-based organizations and is developing their own website to distribute information on emergency rental assistance.</li><li><strong>The U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness </strong>is distributing information about emergency rental assistance through a newsletter that reaches over 34,000 people.</li><li><strong>The Census Bureau </strong>will share the CFPB tool and information on emergency rental assistance with members of their Census Counts and States Count lists. The Census Counts list includes over 60 national organizations with a deep investment in meeting the needs of marginalized communities and the States Count list includes partners in all 50 states plus the District of Columbia.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Security Memorandum on Improving Cybersecurity for Critical Infrastructure Control Systems</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/national-security-memorandum-on-improving-cybersecurity-for-critical-infrastructure-control-systems/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 13:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Protection of our Nation&#8217;s critical infrastructure is a responsibility of the government at the Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial levels and of the owners and operators of that infrastructure.&#160; The cybersecurity threats posed to the systems that control and operate the critical infrastructure on which we all depend are among the most significant and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Protection of our Nation&#8217;s critical infrastructure is a responsibility of the government at the Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial levels and of the owners and operators of that infrastructure.&nbsp; The cybersecurity threats posed to the systems that control and operate the critical infrastructure on which we all depend are among the most significant and growing issues confronting our Nation.&nbsp; The degradation, destruction, or malfunction of systems that control this infrastructure could cause significant harm to the national and economic security of the United States.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section&nbsp;1.</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Policy.</span>&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to safeguard the critical infrastructure of the Nation, with a particular focus on the cybersecurity and resilience of systems supporting National Critical Functions, defined as the functions of Government and the private sector so vital to the United States that their disruption, corruption, or dysfunction would have a debilitating effect on national security, economic security, public health or safety, or any combination thereof.&nbsp;<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.&nbsp;2.</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Industrial Control Systems Cybersecurity Initiative.</span>&nbsp; Accordingly, I have established an Industrial Control Systems Cybersecurity Initiative (Initiative), a voluntary, collaborative effort between the Federal Government and the critical infrastructure community to significantly improve the cybersecurity of these critical systems.&nbsp; The primary objective of this Initiative is to defend the United&nbsp;States&#8217; critical infrastructure by encouraging and facilitating deployment of technologies and systems that provide threat visibility, indications, detection, and warnings, and that facilitate response capabilities for cybersecurity in essential control system and operational technology networks.&nbsp; The goal of the Initiative is to greatly expand deployment of these technologies across priority critical infrastructure.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.&nbsp;3.</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Furthering the Industrial Control Systems Cybersecurity Initiative.&nbsp;</span> The Initiative creates a path for Government and industry to collaborate to take immediate action, within their respective spheres of control, to address these serious threats.&nbsp; The Initiative builds on, expands, and accelerates ongoing cybersecurity efforts in critical infrastructure sectors and is an important step in addressing these threats.&nbsp; We cannot address threats we cannot see; therefore, deploying systems and technologies that can monitor control systems to detect malicious activity and facilitate response actions to cyber threats is central to ensuring the safe operations of these critical systems.&nbsp; The Federal Government will work with industry to share threat information for priority control system critical infrastructure throughout the country.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Initiative began with a pilot effort with the Electricity Subsector, and is now followed by a similar effort for natural gas pipelines.&nbsp; Efforts for the Water and Wastewater Sector Systems and Chemical Sector will follow later this year.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Sector Risk Management Agencies, as defined in section&nbsp;9002(a)(7) of Public Law 116-283, and other executive departments and agencies (agencies), as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, shall work with critical infrastructure stakeholders and owners and operators to implement the principles and policy outlined in this memorandum.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.&nbsp;4.</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity Performance Goals.&nbsp;</span> Cybersecurity needs vary among critical infrastructure sectors, as do cybersecurity practices.&nbsp; However, there is a need for baseline cybersecurity goals that are consistent across all critical infrastructure sectors, as well as a need for security controls for select critical infrastructure that is dependent on control systems.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Pursuant to section 7(d) of Executive Order 13636 of&nbsp;February 12, 2013 (Improving Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity), the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce (through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology) and other agencies, as appropriate, shall develop and issue cybersecurity performance goals for critical infrastructure to&nbsp;further a common understanding of the baseline security practices that critical infrastructure owners and operators should follow to protect national and economic security, as well&nbsp;as public health and safety.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;This effort shall begin with the Secretary of Homeland&nbsp;Security issuing preliminary goals for control systems&nbsp;across critical infrastructure sectors no later than September&nbsp;22,&nbsp;2021, followed by the issuance of final cross-sector control system goals within 1 year of the date of this memorandum.&nbsp; Additionally, following consultations with relevant agencies, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue sector-specific critical infrastructure cybersecurity performance goals within 1 year of the date of this memorandum.&nbsp; These performance goals should serve as clear guidance to owners and operators about cybersecurity practices and postures that the American people can trust and should expect for such essential services.&nbsp; That effort may also include an examination of whether additional legal authorities would be beneficial to enhancing the cybersecurity of critical infrastructure, which is vital to the American people and the security of our Nation.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.&nbsp;5.</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline">General Provisions.</span>&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of&nbsp;Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with&nbsp;applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations, where funding assistance may be required to implement control system cybersecurity recommendations.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United&nbsp;States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on Improving Cybersecurity of U.S. Critical Infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/28/background-press-call-on-improving-cybersecurity-of-u-s-critical-infrastructure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[6:02 P.M. EDT&#160;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Thank you. &#160;Hey, everyone.&#160; Thank you for joining us on a 6:00 p.m. on a Tuesday evening.&#160; So, you’re joined by senior administration officials today to give you an embargoed preview of a step we’re announcing tomorrow to protect the cybersecurity of our critical infrastructure.&#160; This is embargoed until 9:00&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>6:02 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you. &nbsp;Hey, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us on a 6:00 p.m. on a Tuesday evening.&nbsp; So, you’re joined by senior administration officials today to give you an embargoed preview of a step we’re announcing tomorrow to protect the cybersecurity of our critical infrastructure.&nbsp; This is embargoed until 9:00 a.m. Eastern tomorrow, Wednesday, July 28.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just for your awareness and not for reporting, you’re joined by [senior administration official].&nbsp; I’m going to turn it over to [senior administration official] to kick us off.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; It’s good to be here with you today.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I’ll walk you through an update on our efforts to protect U.S. critical infrastructure from the growing, persistent, and sophisticated threats, and talk about the specific effort we will be rolling out tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, first, just to kind of put in context the administration’s overall approach to cybersecurity, as I’ve talked about in the past, our approach to addressing cyber threats have three lines of effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>First: Modernizing our defenses.&nbsp; Modernizing national defenses, federal government, state and local government critical infrastructure, incentives to the broader private sector, so that they’re modern enough to meet the threat.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second: Rebuilding our presence on the international stage.&nbsp; The work we’re doing to build coalitions &#8212; for example, to counter ransomware.&nbsp; The outreach we’re doing, you saw in the G7, where we brought countries together &#8212; the recent attribution of the Hafnium incident, MSS, with a very large number of countries joining us.&nbsp; We’re really putting a focus on collective defense and on moving out together with other countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, then, finally: Ensuring the nation is postured to compete.&nbsp; And that deals with ensuring we have all instruments of national power needed and the policies to enable their use as needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, today, I will preview a rollout we have tomorrow that further advances our efforts in the first category to modernize the nation’s defenses, specifically by defending critical infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, those of you who have reported on critical infrastructure know that federal cybersecurity regulation in the U.S. is sectoral.&nbsp; We have a patchwork of sector-specific statutes that have been adopted piecemeal, typically in response to discrete security threats in particular sectors that gained public attention.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our current posture is woefully insufficient given the evolving threat we face today.&nbsp; We really kicked the can down the road for a long time.&nbsp; The administration is committed to leveraging every authority we have, though limited, and we’re also open to new approaches, both voluntary and mandatory.<br>&nbsp;<br>Responsible critical infrastructure owners and operators should be following voluntary guidance as well as mandatory requirements in order to ensure that the critical services the American people rely on are protected from cyber threats.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, here is the new information:<br>&nbsp;<br>Tomorrow morning, the President will sign a National Security Memorandum on “Improving Cybersecurity for Critical Infrastructure Control Systems,” which addresses cybersecurity for critical infrastructure and implements long-overdue efforts to meet the threats we face.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the National Security Memorandum will direct the Department of Homeland Security’s CISA and the Department of Commerce’s NIST, in collaboration with other agencies, to develop cybersecurity performance goals for critical infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, it’ll formally establish the President’s Industrial Control System Cybersecurity Initiative.&nbsp; As you recall, the ICS initiative is a voluntary, collaborative effort between the federal government and the critical infrastructure community to facilitate the deployment of technology and systems that provide threat visibility, indicators, detections, and warnings.<br>&nbsp;<br>You’ll recall we launched the initiative in mid-April with an Electricity Subsector pilot, and already over 150 electricity utilities representing almost 90 million residential customers are either deploying or have agreed to deploy control system cybersecurity technologies.&nbsp; These are the technologies that, had they been in place, would have blocked what occurred at Colonial Pipeline in that they connect the operational technology side of the network to the IT side of the network.&nbsp; The action plan for natural gas pipelines is underway, and additional initiatives for other sectors will follow later this year.<br>&nbsp;<br>So this a public-private initiative effort with a focus to roll out these very specific technologies voluntarily, by the private sector, in close cooperation to really ensure we get those protections in place within the voluntary model that is in place for our cybersecurity for critical infrastructure today.<br>&nbsp;<br>The point we want to make is: The federal government cannot do this alone.&nbsp; Securing our critical infrastructure requires a whole-of-nation effort, and industry has to do their part.&nbsp; These may be voluntary, but we hope and expect that all responsible critical infrastructure owners and operators will apply them.&nbsp; We can’t stress it enough that they owe that to the Americans that they serve for these critical services to have more resilience.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as we’ve said, we’re exploring everything we can do to mandate strengthening of cybersecurity standards.&nbsp; You saw, last week, DHS’s Transportation Security Administration announced the second Security Directive for critical pipeline owners and operators.&nbsp; It will require owners and operators of pipelines that transport hazardous liquids and natural gas to implement a number of urgently needed protections, including implementing specific mitigation measures to protect against ransomware attacks and other known threats, IT and OT, within prescribed timeframes; developing and implementing a cybersecurity contingency and recovery plan; conducting an annual cybersecurity architecture design review.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, again, the federal government can’t do this alone, and securing our critical infrastructure requires a whole-of-nation effort.&nbsp; This National Security Memorandum, the ICS Cybersecurity Initiative, TSA’s Security Directives, and foundationally, the President’s Executive Order on Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity that he signed back in May all are parts of our focused and aggressive continuing effort to address these significant threats to our nation within that first line of modernizing defense of our cybersecurity &#8212; of the administration’s cybersecurity strategy.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, with that, I’ll pause, and I’m really looking forward to hearing your questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; So you said you&#8217;re exploring ways to mandate cyber protections for critical infrastructure.&nbsp; Do you think that the federal government does not have sufficient authorities right now?&nbsp; And do you need Congress to do something to give you those authorities to expand protections into sectors that don’t currently have it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, we have a patchwork of sector-specific statutes today that really have been adapted piecemeal.&nbsp; And we feel that the administration &#8212; the government&#8217;s responsibility is to feel confident that critical services that the American public rely on have the modernized defenses to ensure that they can continue to deliver the critical services they do.&nbsp; And the current patchwork of sector-specific statutes does not enable us to say we have confidence that there is cybersecurity thresholds in place with regard to practices and with regard to technology, governance, and practices.&nbsp; That is something that will likely require the Hill to partner with us to address.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re just beginning, you know, the first steps, and the first step is really articulating that today&#8217;s patchwork of sector-specific approaches, state-level approaches, certainly is not enabling us to meet the threat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I just &#8212; I&#8217;ll expand on that for a moment because I suspect many of you have that question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So essentially today, you know, there&#8217;s no strategic, coordinated requirement for the cybersecurity of critical infrastructure.&nbsp; To the extent, as I noted, there are mandatory cybersecurity requirements.&nbsp; They&#8217;re either sector specific &#8212; finance and chemical; they&#8217;re mandated under state or local law, like electricity ones; or they’re limited and piecemeal &#8212; water and bulk electricity are two that we’ve put a lot of work into studying in the last few weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, short of legislation, there isn&#8217;t a comprehensive way to require deployment of security technologies and practices that address, really, the threat environment that we face.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m curious, to the extent that these industries and sectors are aware that something might be coming from the administration, what sort of response and reaction have you gotten to the collaboration and the notion that they should be strengthening their defense along the lines of what the administration envisions?&nbsp; Do you anticipate any sort of pushback?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;That’s a really good question, Eric.&nbsp; Thank you for it.&nbsp; So, a big part of our approach has been actively engaging the private sector in new and innovative ways.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the President&#8217;s Industrial Control System Cybersecurity Initiative is a great example where, you know, we have the Department of Energy work very closely with the electricity subsector ISAC and identify the most critical utilities &#8212; those that serve the largest number of Americans, et cetera.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then we kicked off the pilot effort that saw, as I mentioned, over 150 electricity utilities and almost 90 million customers, you know, agreeing to deploy or having already deployed control system cybersecurity technologies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to that, we brought in a number of CEOs of utilities and pipelines to brief them on the threats so that they had the same information we had regarding the sense of urgency we feel to address the cybersecurity threat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think what we&#8217;re seeing &#8212; and I think &#8212; the final thing I would say is, in the executive order, as you saw, we really ate our own dog food in that the federal government said, &#8220;We&#8217;re going to roll out these five critical cybersecurity technologies, and we&#8217;re going to do it on a rapid timeframe.”&nbsp; Encryption rolled out, for example, within six months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I think we&#8217;re showing a willingness to do the work we need to do, and I think we&#8217;re showing a willingness to share information in new ways, come up with voluntary ways, but also making clear that given the criticality of the threat, we need to move with urgency and we need to look at all options &#8212; voluntary and mandatory &#8212; to achieve the rapid progress we need.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; I want to ask about, kind of, how you see this specific announcement having an impact, because I (inaudible) to understand it &#8212; I might be getting this wrong: Largely, this is an announcement about a voluntary public-private initiative, but it&#8217;s also kind of a larger commentary on where things are now from a standards and regulatory standpoint.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So is the idea in making this announcement to signal to these sectors that regulation could be on the way and so it&#8217;s best to start moving now in terms of their defenses?&nbsp; Or like &#8212; I&#8217;m trying to understand exactly what the purpose is, as far as your message.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; So, first, it&#8217;s the President.&nbsp; It’s the President using his position to say: Cybersecurity is a focus; we must move with urgency; the federal government cannot do this alone.&nbsp; You know, almost 90 percent of critical infrastructure in the U.S. is owned and operated by the private sector.&nbsp; And securing critical infrastructure needs a whole-of-nation effort.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So the first piece it says is: We are going to do our part by outlining performance controls that cover all critical infrastructure, that say these are the thresholds that we expect responsible owners and operators to go, and start moving there voluntarily, because that is the threshold that we as a government expect our private-sector owners and operators to meet.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And clearly, you know, we&#8217;re saying, as well, that the absence of a strategic, coordinated requirement to the cybersecurity of critical infrastructure and the absence of mandated cybersecurity requirements for critical infrastructure is what, in many ways, has brought us to the level of vulnerability we have today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re committed to addressing it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re starting with voluntary, as much as we can, because we want to do this in full partnership.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we&#8217;re also pursuing all options we have in order to make the rapid progress we need.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Evening.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; So, at the end of the Bush administration &#8212; not to, you know, date me going through briefings like this &#8212; there was a fairly similar discussion about public-private issues.&nbsp; And then, of course, in Congress, during the Obama administration, there was the failure of a cyber bill that was opposed, not merely on cybersecurity, obviously, but that would have sort of more mandated public-private elements.&nbsp; And then, in the Trump administration, there was the bulk-power order that came out, I think, just last year.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, my broader question to you is: What makes this effort different from the last three administrations trying to grapple with it, other than its comprehensiveness?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, specifically, can you tell us: Does the bulk-power order that that President Trump signed still exist?&nbsp; Did you learn from that, that it actually made any difference?&nbsp; Because that sounds to me like the closest experiment in this.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, thank you, David.&nbsp; Why is this night different from any other night?&nbsp; Well done.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say you are exactly right.&nbsp; You know, there have been multiple prior efforts to address &#8212; let&#8217;s &#8212; taking a step back &#8212; you know, multiple administrations have recognized that there are no mandated authorities to mandate cybersecurity requirements for critical infrastructure, and they&#8217;ve done their best within that.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I know, in my own career, I&#8217;ve led multiple public-private partnership efforts &#8212; right? &#8212; to try to do the kinds of things to get the sector to move.&nbsp; And there are various reasons why not: Sometimes it&#8217;s costly.&nbsp; Sometimes these sectors are regulated.&nbsp; So, unless public utilities commissions approve rate increases, they feel their costs aren&#8217;t recoverable.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that&#8217;s why, you know, we&#8217;ve tried a number of things here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I mentioned the ICS Initiative because that was where we really took a very innovative approach of identifying the most critical companies; engaging key leaders in the sector to help us; using the ISAC to bring companies together &#8212; you know, having this regular rhythm of weekly check-ins to really drive that progress.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re also saying &#8212; so that &#8212; so this NSM and the fact that it&#8217;s, you know, being announced by the President, in the context of TSA&#8217;s recent mandates that they occurred; in the context of our openly saying that we really are committed to addressing the limited and piecemeal regulation; in the context of the current environment where the threat is known and seen by critical infrastructure owners and private sectors.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, you look at Colonial Pipeline, you look at the JBS Foods, you look at Kaseya &#8212; there&#8217;s now a different threat.&nbsp; The threats that many people have talked about have become real.&nbsp; So, we believe these goals will be viewed differently, and we believe that we&#8217;re making clear that critical infrastructure should adopt these measures.&nbsp; The President is essentially saying, &#8220;We expect responsible owners and operators to meet these performance goals.&nbsp; We will look to you to implement this.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, we&#8217;re also going to be looking at all options, including working with the Congress to ensure that we can have the confidence we need to &#8212; that these critical services are protected for the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Hey, there.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; So, like, along the lines of &#8220;all possible options,&#8221; we all know the vast majority of ransomware attacks exploit vulnerabilities that have already been published in the National Vulnerability Database, and the issue is that operators haven&#8217;t implemented a patch.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think in a lot of cases, certainly the cases of &#8212; not necessarily critical infrastructure providers, but some infrastructure providers, like schools and hospitals, and possibly some critical infrastructure providers, they would say the reason they can&#8217;t implement the patches is because they can&#8217;t get the new operating system; they can&#8217;t get the new operating system because they don&#8217;t have the new hardware, and they need money.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, is there any efforts &#8212; is there any appetite to possibly award funds or grants for new IT modernization equipment to help some providers to meet these goals?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That’s a really good question &#8212; right? &#8212; because the goals &#8212; the cybersecurity performance goals are goals that they drive adoption &#8212; right? &#8212; of effective practices and control.&nbsp; And one great one could be critical patch &#8212; you know, critical vulnerabilities.&nbsp; Those with the higher CVE scores, you know, are patched within some set time period quickly, because of the risk there.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, you know, some of what we&#8217;ve been looking at is, for example &#8212; and I love your question &#8212; is for some regulated sectors: you know, public utility commissions, other entities.&nbsp; Who sets those rates so that they can recover costs?&nbsp;&nbsp; And, you know, similarly, FERC and some of the regulators &#8212; bringing them in, sharing the information regarding the threats, helping them understand so they&#8217;re a part of the story.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;ve been investing a lot of time in understanding the incentives and understanding the barriers and looking at what can be done across grants, across potential tax credits, across, potentially, you know, performance incentive mechanisms.&nbsp; Cyber insurance is a really interesting mechanism as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, each of those things we&#8217;re looking at and exploring &#8212; no announcements yet &#8212; but to really understand, you know, how to accelerate voluntary adoption.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this tonight.&nbsp; I apologize for asking something that&#8217;s not directly on topic, but we did hear from the President today on a number of cyber issues, and he made some pretty strong comments about Russia and how they&#8217;re already interfering in the 2020 &#8212; 2022 Midterm Elections.&nbsp; He called it &#8220;a clear violation of sovereignty.&#8221;&nbsp; So I wanted to ask you to expand on that, if you could, in what you’re seeing in terms of these Russian tactics for 2022 &#8212; what they&#8217;re doing, what response there has been, where that and what channels that response has been given.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Alex.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not prepared to speak more to that issue this evening, but we&#8217;ll be happy to at some point.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not prepared to speak to that more in detail.<br>&nbsp;<br>OPERATOR:&nbsp; I&#8217;m now happy to turn it back to [senior administration official] for any closing remarks.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining us today.&nbsp; Just a reminder that this call is embargoed until tomorrow, Wednesday, July 28th, until 9:00 a.m. Eastern.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you have any other questions or follow-ups, please feel free to reach out.&nbsp; Thank you for your time.<br>&nbsp;<br>6:20 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Announces Further Actions to Protect U.S. Critical Infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/fact-sheet-biden-administration-announces-further-actions-to-protect-u-s-critical-infrastructure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden Administration continues to take steps to safeguard U.S. critical infrastructure from growing, persistent, and sophisticated cyber threats. Recent high-profile attacks on critical infrastructure around the world, including the ransomware attacks on the Colonial Pipeline and JBS Foods in the United States, demonstrate that significant cyber vulnerabilities exist across U.S. critical infrastructure, which is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden Administration continues to take steps to safeguard U.S. critical infrastructure from growing, persistent, and sophisticated cyber threats. Recent high-profile attacks on critical infrastructure around the world, including the ransomware attacks on the Colonial Pipeline and JBS Foods in the United States, demonstrate that significant cyber vulnerabilities exist across U.S. critical infrastructure, which is largely owned and operated by the private sector. As we have seen, the degradation, destruction, or malfunction of systems that control this infrastructure can have cascading physical consequences that could have a debilitating effect on national security, economic security, and the public health and safety of the American people.</p>



<p>Currently, federal cybersecurity regulation in the United States is sectoral. We have a patchwork of sector-specific statutes that have been adopted piecemeal, as data security threats in particular sectors have gained public attention. Given the evolving threat we face today, we must consider new approaches, both voluntary and mandatory. We look to responsible critical infrastructure owners and operators to follow voluntary guidance as well as mandatory requirements in order to ensure that the critical services the American people rely on are protected from cyber threats.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, President Biden is signing a National Security Memorandum (NSM) on “Improving Cybersecurity for Critical Infrastructure Control Systems,” which addresses cybersecurity for critical infrastructure and implements long overdue efforts to meet the threats we face. The NSM:</p>



<ul><li>Directs the Department of Homeland Security’s Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) and the Department of Commerce’s National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), in collaboration with other agencies, to develop cybersecurity performance goals for critical infrastructure. We expect those standards will assist companies responsible for providing essential services like power, water, and transportation to strengthen their cybersecurity.<br></li><li>Formally establishes the President’s Industrial Control System Cybersecurity (ICS) Initiative. The ICS initiative is a voluntary, collaborative effort between the federal government and the critical infrastructure community to facilitate the deployment of technology and systems that provide threat visibility, indicators, detections, and warnings. The Initiative <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/20/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-the-biden-administrations-efforts-to-protect-u-s-critical-infrastructure/">began in mid-April</a> with an Electricity Subsector pilot, and already over 150 electricity utilities representing almost 90 million residential customers are either deploying or have agreed to deploy control system cybersecurity technologies. The action plan for natural gas pipelines is underway, and additional initiatives for other sectors will follow later this year.</li></ul>



<p>Last week, the Department of Homeland Security’s Transportation Security Administration (TSA) announced a second Security Directive for critical pipeline owners and operators.&nbsp; Following the ransomware attack on a major petroleum pipeline in May 2021, <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2021/05/27/dhs-announces-new-cybersecurity-requirements-critical-pipeline-owners-and-operators">TSA issued an initial Security Directive</a> requiring critical pipeline owners and operators to report cybersecurity incidents, designate a Cybersecurity Coordinator, and conduct a review of their current cybersecurity practices. This second Security Directive will require owners and operators of pipelines that transport hazardous liquids and natural gas to implement a number of urgently needed protections, including:</p>



<ul><li>Implementing specific mitigation measures to protect against ransomware attacks and other known threats to information technology and operational technology systems within prescribed timeframes.<br></li><li>Developing and implementing a cybersecurity contingency and recovery plan.<br></li><li>Conducting an annual cybersecurity architecture design review.</li></ul>



<p>The Federal Government cannot do this alone and securing our critical infrastructure requires a whole-of-nation effort. This NSM, the ICS Cybersecurity Initiative, TSA’s Security Directives and the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/12/fact-sheet-president-signs-executive-order-charting-new-course-to-improve-the-nations-cybersecurity-and-protect-federal-government-networks/">Executive Order on Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity</a> are parts of a focused and aggressive continuing effort to address these significant threats to our nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Issues Proposed Buy American Rule, Advancing the President’s Commitment to Ensuring the Future of America is Made in America by All of America’s Workers</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-issues-proposed-buy-american-rule-advancing-the-presidents-commitment-to-ensuring-the-future-of-america-is-made-in-america-by-all-of-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration will increase American-made content in federal purchases and bolster critical supply chains The President believes that when we spend American taxpayers’ dollars, it should support American workers and businesses. In his first week in office, President Biden signed Executive Order 14005, Ensuring the Future is Made in All of America by All of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration will increase American-made content in federal purchases and bolster critical supply chains</em></p>



<p>The President believes that when we spend American taxpayers’ dollars, it should support American workers and businesses. In his first week in office, President Biden signed Executive Order 14005, <em>Ensuring the Future is Made in All of America by All of America’s Workers</em>, launching a whole-of-government initiative to strengthen the use of federal procurement to support American manufacturing.</p>



<p>Since January, the Biden-Harris Administration has made significant progress implementing the President’s vision. In April, the President <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-27/biden-names-trade-expert-drake-as-made-in-america-director">opened</a> his new Made in America Office. The Office reviews proposed waivers of Made-in-America laws and helps agencies use taxpayer dollars to support U.S. manufacturing.</p>



<p>The Made in America Office issued new waiver guidance to fulfill the President’s commitment to scrutinize and reduce waivers to Made-in-America laws. The guidance lays out a whole of government agenda to maximize the use of taxpayer dollars on domestic products and services to strengthen our industrial base and create good-paying, union jobs for Americans.</p>



<p>Today, the President is announcing another significant step in fulfilling his commitment: the most robust changes to the implementation of the Buy American Act in almost 70 years. His proposal would increase U.S. content in the products the federal government buys and support the domestic production of products critical to our national and economic security.</p>



<p>With $600 billion in annual procurement spending, almost half of which is in manufactured products from helicopter blades to trucks to office furniture, the Federal government is a major buyer in a number of markets for goods and services, including the single largest purchaser of consumer goods in the world. Leveraging that purchasing power to shape markets and accelerate innovation is a key part of the Biden <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/commentary/transcript/brian-deese-on-bidens-vision-for-a-twenty-first-century-american-industrial-strategy/">industrial strategy</a> to grow the industries of the future to support U.S. workers, communities, and firms. As the pandemic has demonstrated, federal procurement can strengthen the resiliency of domestic supply chains, and reduce the risk of Americans being adversely impacted by the actions of competitor nations during a time of crisis.</p>



<p>Today’s Notice of Proposed Rulemaking marks just the first set of proposed reforms to procurement policy under the Biden-Harris Administration to ensure taxpayer dollars help America’s businesses compete in strategic industries and help ensure America&#8217;s workers thrive.</p>



<p>The proposed rule directs the following changes to strengthen Buy American requirements:</p>



<ul><li><strong>“Make Buy American Real” and close loopholes by raising the domestic content threshold. </strong>The Buy American statute says products bought with taxpayer dollars must “substantially all” be made in the U.S. However, today, products could qualify if just 55%&#8211;just over half—of the value of their component parts was manufactured here. The NPRM proposes an immediate increase of the threshold to 60% and a phased increase to 75%. This proposal would close a problematic loophole in the current regulation, while also allowing businesses time to adjust their supply chains to increase the use of American-made components. If adopted, this change would create more opportunities for small- and medium-sized manufacturers and their employees, including small and disadvantaged enterprises, from all parts of the country. To support this work, the Small Business Administration has created a new manufacturing office in its federal contracting division.</li><li><strong>Strengthens domestic supply chains for critical goods with new price preferences. </strong>As the pandemic made clear, supply chain disruptions can impact the health, safety, and livelihoods of Americans—leaving us without access to critical goods during a crisis. Some products are simply too important to our national and economic security to be dependent on foreign sources. The NPRM proposes applying enhanced price preferences to select critical products and components identified by the Critical Supply Chain review, mandated under E.O. 14017, and the pandemic supply chain strategy called for under E.O. 14001. These preferences, once in place, would support the development and expansion of domestic supply chains for critical products by providing a source of stable demand for domestically produced critical products.</li><li><strong>Increases transparency and accountability in Buy American rules.</strong> Reporting challenges have hampered implementation of Buy American rules for decades. Currently, contractors only tell the government if they meet the content threshold rather than reporting the total domestic content in their products. The NPRM proposes to establish a reporting requirement for critical products. The new reporting requirement would bolster compliance with the Buy American Act and improve data on the actual U.S. content of goods purchased. More complete and accurate data would be used to target future improvements to support America’s entrepreneurs, farmers, ranchers, and workers— and along the way, create good jobs and resilient communities.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>THE BIDEN ADMINISTRATION IS ALREADY BUYING AMERICAN</u></strong></p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has not waited for new rules to go into place in order to Buy American. At his first Cabinet meeting, the President made it clear that supporting U.S.-based manufacturing through procurement was a top priority. Agencies have delivered.</p>



<p>As part of the whole-of-government initiative, today, agencies are highlighting more than $2 billion in new purchases to support the manufacturing of innovative technologies and products in America.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Energy</strong> acquired new electric vehicles for its fleet, all of which were manufactured in the US or have batteries that were produced at US facilities. The Department will also purchase steel products, advanced computing, and hazardous materials isolation equipment manufactured in Texas, Iowa, Idaho, Louisiana, South Carolina, Ohio, Connecticut and Wisconsin.</li><li><strong>The General Services Administration (GSA)</strong> worked with 8(a) small business to procure energy efficient technologies for federal facilities. These contracts are a part of GSA’s Green Proving Ground program, which tests emerging technologies at federal facilities in order to help them scale and become viable in the market.</li><li><strong>The Department of Defense</strong> funded prototypes to sustainably source critical minerals and to create a new training hub with the Department of Energy to increase the productivity of the U.S. machine tool base.</li><li><strong>NASA</strong> added new project recipients to its programs to rapidly acquire lunar delivery services from American companies to further U.S. capabilities for science, exploration, or commercial development of the Moon and to demonstrate a commercially-developed habitable space station elements with the potential to transition to free-flying, self-sustaining commercial destinations in low earth orbit.</li><li><strong>The Office of Naval Research</strong> issued Phase 1 awards for a Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) project to accelerate the pace, security and quality of autonomous vehicles.</li><li><strong>The Department of Labor</strong> purchased $1.5 million of Made in America products, spanning a range of needs from office furniture to state of the art testing equipment to ensure America’s mines and other workplaces are safe.</li><li><strong>The Army Corps of Engineers</strong> Mississippi Valley Division issued over $42 million in new contracts to help make communities more storm and flood resistant and to improve the flow of goods along the Mississippi River to support the region’s manufacturers.</li></ul>



<p>These purchases are aligned with the President’s commitment in his Build Back Better legislative proposal to strengthen R&amp;D, manufacturing and grow jobs in the industries of the future, including through a $48 billion commitment to federal procurement of clean energy and clean technologies.</p>



<p>The President’s COVID-19 response has also advanced his Buy American strategy by increasing U.S. capacity to produce critical products.</p>



<ul><li>In March, the Department of Defense and Department of Health and Human Services procured over $22 million in American-made cloth face masks for communities hard-hit by the pandemic.</li><li>In May and June, the Department of Defense purchased more than $1.8 billion in U.S.-made COVID treatment and testing supplies.</li><li>In addition, since February, we have invested more than a billion dollars in expanding American production capacity for critical pandemic response throughout the healthcare supply chain to meet current and future needs.</li></ul>



<p>The President’s Build Back Better agenda will continue this work through its call for $30 billion to prevent and prepare for future pandemics.</p>



<p>Beyond direct purchasing, the Biden-Harris Administration is making investments in workforce training and small business supports that will bolster the President’s Made in America agenda. As noted above, SBA has created a new manufacturing office to help small manufacturers access federal contracts, financing, and business development support. The office will coordinate activities across the Agency in response to the President’s Executive Orders on Made-in-America, supply chain resiliency, and racial equity.</p>



<p>The Department of Labor invested $430 million in workforce training and apprenticeships in June this year, including grantees focused on bolstering the domestic manufacturing workforce. The funding supports programs across the country, including in Colorado, Texas, California, Michigan, Idaho and Nevada. These investments will ensure that as the manufacturing sector expands, workers will be able to transition quickly and succeed in good-quality jobs.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>###</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Senior Advisor and Chief Spokesperson Symone Sanders on Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with Tribal leaders and Leaders from American Indian and Alaska Native Communities about Voting Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/statement-from-senior-advisor-and-chief-spokesperson-symone-sanders-on-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-tribal-leaders-and-leaders-from-american-indian-and-alaska-native-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today Vice President Kamala Harris hosted a discussion in her ceremonial office to engage with Tribal leaders and leaders from American Indian and Alaska Native communities about voting rights. She was joined by Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland. The Vice President thanked the participants for their work to protect voting rights, and they discussed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today Vice President Kamala Harris hosted a discussion in her ceremonial office to engage with Tribal leaders and leaders from American Indian and Alaska Native communities about voting rights. She was joined by Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland. The Vice President thanked the participants for their work to protect voting rights, and they discussed ways to make voting more accessible.<br>&nbsp;<br>During the meeting, the leaders shared how Native Americans have long faced challenges to exercise their fundamental right to vote&#8211;from the long distance voters must travel to reach their polling places to anti-voter laws that directly impact Tribal communities. The leaders also shared how they are engaging voters&#8211;and in particular young voters&#8211;in their communities, by connecting the issues they care about to their vote.<br>&nbsp;<br>In her role leading the Biden-Harris Administration’s efforts on voting rights, the Vice President is working with a broad coalition to protect and strengthen the right to vote. The Vice President has convened Americans from all walks of life to share their stories and provide input – including a meeting the Vice President held last week with poll workers to hear about their experiences helping voters cast their ballot and have their ballots counted.<br>&nbsp;<br>The leaders who participated in today’s meeting included:</p>



<ul><li>Secretary Deb Haaland, (Pueblo of Laguna)</li><li>President Kevin Killer, (Oglala Lakota Nation) (SD)</li><li>Allie Young, (Dine’ or Navajo Nation) (AZ)</li><li>Chairwoman Shelly Fyant, (Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes) (Bitterroot-Salish) (MT)</li><li>Julie Kitka, (President of the Alaska Federation of Natives) (Chugach Eskimo Village of Nuchek) (AK)</li><li>Prairie Rose Seminole, (Three Affiliated Tribes of Mandan Hidatsa and Arikara) (ND)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at the Office of the Director of National Intelligence</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/27/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-office-of-the-director-of-national-intelligence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 23:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Counterterrorism CenterLiberty Crossing Intelligence CampusMcLean, Virginia THE PRESIDENT:&#160; It’s an honor to be here.&#160; I guess you all are the ones that lost the lottery, huh?&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; You had to be here in person.&#160;Well, I&#8217;d like to thank Director Haines and Director of the National Counterterrorism Center, Christy Abizaid, for showing me around the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">National Counterterrorism Center<br>Liberty Crossing Intelligence Campus<br>McLean, Virginia</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s an honor to be here.&nbsp; I guess you all are the ones that lost the lottery, huh?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You had to be here in person.<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, I&#8217;d like to thank Director Haines and Director of the National Counterterrorism Center, Christy Abizaid, for showing me around the watch floor.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, the main reason I came &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; is to say thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; The American people, almost by definition, are not able to know what you do.&nbsp; And you devote so much of your time, your effort, and many of you end up risking your lives in the Intelligence Community to do things to make sure that your families and people back here are safe &#8212; make a difference.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you&#8217;d be amazed &#8212; as I traveled the world as Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee or member of the Intelligence Committee for all those years, or as Vice President of the United States dealing with national security issues, or as President of the United States &#8212; how many of now my foreign counterparts thank you for what you do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d like to introduce you, by the way, to my National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan.&nbsp; Jake, would you stand up?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, the leaders of many of our intelligence agencies are here today.&nbsp; And I thank you for your diligence and keeping our country safe, and your commitment to supporting your teams.&nbsp; Because, if there’s anything, a team sport is what y’all are doing if there&#8217;s going to be anything that’s going to be accomplished.<br>&nbsp;<br>Because the people I most want to honor and thank today are the intelligence professionals whose names the public is never, ever going to know, never have any notion of what you’ve done for us: the analysts; the linguists; the collectors and field officers; scientists; support staff; so many others who are real experts, whose careers started much longer before my administration and whose service to our nation is going to extend well beyond my presidency.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, you&#8217;re the eyes and ears around the world &#8212; in the frontlines of our national defense, and in many cases, for the world, through us.&nbsp; And you serve the American people no matter which political party holds power in Congress or the White House.&nbsp; It’s so vital &#8212; so vital that you are and should be totally free of any political pressure or partisan interference.&nbsp; That’s basic.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to be absolutely clear that my administration is getting us back to the basics.&nbsp; To the basics.&nbsp; I promise you:&nbsp; You will never see a time, while I&#8217;m President of the United States, when my administration in any way tries to affect or alter your judgments about what you think the situation we face is.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll never politicize the work you do.&nbsp; You have my word on that.&nbsp; It’s too important for our country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Getting back to basics also making &#8212; to make sure the IC scrupulously acts within the legal constraints and abides by our strong traditions of internal and congressional oversight, including respect for whistleblower protections.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it also means understanding that much of the work you must do is in secret but necessary and for the sake of safety.&nbsp; But we should strive to be as open as possible with the American people about the nature of the threats we face and just how serious they are &#8212; and they are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Every one of you joined up because you believe in being part of something that’s bigger than yourself, especially you guys and women in uniform &#8212; bigger than yourself.&nbsp; You’re patriots.&nbsp; It’s a word that we use lightly, but I mean it.&nbsp; It’s not &#8212; it’s not &#8212; I don’t use it lightly.&nbsp; I really don’t.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My son, who spent a year in Iraq and died, he was a patriot.&nbsp; He wasn’t just somebody else.&nbsp; You all are patriots.&nbsp; You risk your lives and your sacred honor for all that we need to have done for us.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you believe in the American idea.&nbsp; And living up to that idea is embracing democratic values that are our greatest strength at the end of the day, leading not just by the example of our power, but by the power of your example.&nbsp; The power of your example.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to thanking you for your bravery, integrity, and your sacrifices, I want to make it clear to everyone here today and to the members of the Intelligence Community working around the globe that you have my full confidence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s doesn’t mean I don’t question what you send me.&nbsp; That meant &#8212; doesn’t mean &#8212; it’s not that I &#8212; I &#8212; you know, I&#8217;m not a new guy on the block in terms of these issues.&nbsp; But one of the reasons I question is to push &#8212; push you to the limits to determine just how certain you are about what you&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; Lots of times, the only honest answer: “We’re not certain.&nbsp; We’re not certain, but this is what our best judgment is.”<br>&nbsp;<br>I know &#8212; I really do &#8212; know how hard the work you do is.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been doing this for a long, long time before I became President.&nbsp; I know there’s no such thing as 100 percent certainty in the intelligence world.&nbsp; Occasionally that happens, but rarely, rarely, rarely.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I also know that your work is invaluable to our ability to make informed, strategic national security decisions.&nbsp; And I just had an interesting meeting, as you all know, with my very close friend, Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I can tell &#8212; one thing: I&#8217;ve been dealing with world leaders a long, long time.&nbsp; And just like all of you men and women, you can sort of sense somebody else after a while.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He knows that you&#8217;re better than his team, and it bothers the hell out of him.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; And he, as a consequence of you, think we have capacities he may even exaggerate.&nbsp; That’s a good thing.&nbsp; That’s a good thing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, one of the things I miss most during the four years between my time serving as Vice President and being a professor in a college &#8212; and I mean this sincerely: From the time I was 31 years old, every morning I woke up and got in the train to come to &#8212; I commuted every day from Delaware after my wife and daughter were killed.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d come every day, and one of the things I would get &#8212; I&#8217;d get a brief in the morning.&nbsp; And I was more informed than 99 percent of the American people.&nbsp; You know what I miss most, for real, from those four years of being a professor?&nbsp; The PDB.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, you think I&#8217;m joking.&nbsp; I am not.&nbsp; A sense of knowing where all the pieces were.&nbsp; Whether we had it all down, we knew where all the pieces were.&nbsp; We knew where the pieces were.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so now I have access again &#8212; and to the chagrin of many of you, I read it in detail.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I ask questions of my briefers and follow up with my team.&nbsp; And I ask each of you the same thing I asked Director Haines, &#8220;Just give it to me straight.&#8221;&nbsp; I&#8217;m not looking for pablum; I&#8217;m looking for straight-from-the-shoulder assessments.&nbsp; And when you&#8217;re not sure, say you&#8217;re not sure.&nbsp; But give me your best judgment of what you think is &#8212; your best judgment is better than almost anybody else&#8217;s judgment in the whole world &#8212; even if the news is hard, even if the news is bad.<br>&nbsp;<br>I can’t make the decisions I need to make if I&#8217;m not getting the best unvarnished, unbiased judgments you can give me.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not looking to hear nice things.&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking to hear what you think to be the truth.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I greatly appreciate just how much work goes into the analysis that the IC produces and the tactical and intelligence supporting our warfighters and the superb effort to ensure our IT, our human capital, and the facilities are the best in the world.&nbsp; Because, again, without knowing what &#8212; without you telling me, I don’t know enough to know what to ask for from the Congress &#8212; how much money we need, what we need to focus on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It’s a massive, coordinated, global effort to pull together reliable intelligence in a timely way.&nbsp; And all of you, no matter which agency you work for, are part of one team with one shared mission: keeping America strong and secure in the world, or simply making sure your families are safe.&nbsp; It gets down to basic things.&nbsp; Just really basic things.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, for most of the last 20 years, much of the work has been focused on counterterrorism, making sure the United States doesn’t experience another horror like occurred on September the 11th.&nbsp; And that work has to continue and evolve to address the changing shape of terrorism as we find it today.&nbsp;<br>And that’s no great insight on my part, it&#8217;s going to change significantly more.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to change significantly more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I always get kidded by my colleagues when I served in the Senate for 36 years for quoting Irish poets.&nbsp; They think I quoted Irish poets because I&#8217;m Irish.&nbsp; That’s not the reason I quote them; they&#8217;re simply the best poets in the world.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And there&#8217;s a famous poem written by &#8212; that says, &#8220;All has changed, changed utterly.&nbsp; A terrible beauty has been born.&#8221;&nbsp; The world is changing so rapidly &#8212; technologically and in terms of alliances and human intercourse &#8212; that war is going to change across the board in the next 10 years than in the last 50 years.&nbsp; That’s not hyperbole; that&#8217;s a fact.<br>&nbsp;<br>If I talked to you 15 years ago about hypersonic flight, you&#8217;d look at me like I was crazy.&nbsp; So much is going to change and that’s going to put an enormous burden on you to stay ahead of the curve.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really going to get tougher.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we have the best folks in the world.&nbsp; And one of the things that I think &#8212; and I don’t want to get off too far afield here, but one of the things that is really important is &#8212; our greatest strength, in fact, is our diversity, bringing completely different perspectives to it.&nbsp; And I really mean that.&nbsp; That’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not trying to be &#8220;Kumbaya, everybody get along.&#8221;&nbsp; It&#8217;s just a fact.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a fact.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, threats that are more geographically dispersed than they were 20 years ago are going to continue to require our vigilance.&nbsp; And we have to continue our efforts to better understand some of the hardest and most important intelligence targets we face as a nation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, you know, we also need to make sure that we’re positioning ourselves to stay ahead of security challenges that will stretch the IC in new ways it has never been stretched before.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, we’ve seen how cyber threats, including ransomware attacks, increasingly are able to cause damage and disruption to the real world. &nbsp;I can&#8217;t guarantee this, and you&#8217;re as informed as I am, but I think it&#8217;s more likely we&#8217;re going to end up &#8212; well, if we end up in a war, a real shooting war with a major power, it&#8217;s going to be as a consequence of a cyber breach of great consequence. &nbsp;And it&#8217;s increasing exponentially &#8212; the capabilities.<br>&nbsp;<br>When I was with Mr. Putin, who has a real problem &#8212; he is &#8212; he&#8217;s sitting on top of an economy that has nuclear weapons and oil wells and nothing else.&nbsp; Nothing else.&nbsp; Their economy is &#8212; what? &#8212; the eighth smallest in the world now &#8212; largest in the world?&nbsp; He knows &#8212; he knows he&#8217;s in real trouble, which makes him even more dangerous, in my view.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Take a look at China.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spent more time with Xi Jinping as a world leader than anyone else has.&nbsp; I spent 25 hours alone with him when I was Vice President because it was important that, according to President Obama, that someone knew who the new guy coming on board was, and it couldn’t be the President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I traveled 17,000 miles with him.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve sat with him, with me and just an interpreter &#8212; each of us have a simultaneous interpreter.&nbsp; He is deadly earnest about becoming the most powerful military force in the world, as well as the largest &#8212; the most prominent economy in the world by the mid-40s &#8212; the 2040s.&nbsp; It&#8217;s real.<br>&nbsp;<br>I don’t know.&nbsp; We probably have some people who aren’t totally cleared &#8212; I don’t know, but you saw just what we found out about hypersonic &#8212; we &#8212; anyway, as they say in Southern Delaware, &#8220;This boy has got a plan.&#8221;&nbsp; And, you know, we better figure out how we&#8217;re going to keep pace without exacerbating and moving us in a position where we increase the hostilities unnecessarily.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think we also need to take on the rampant disinformation that is making it harder and harder for people to access &#8212; assess the facts, be able to make decisions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In today&#8217;s PDB you all prepared for me, look what Russia is doing already about the 2022 elections and misinformation.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a pure violation of our sovereignty.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now you see what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; More people get their information from the Internet than they do from any other outlet.&nbsp; What&#8217;s &#8212; all the disinformation that&#8217;s having real consequences in terms of people&#8217;s access.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, there&#8217;s so much that you all &#8212; particularly those of you who are new and coming along &#8212; are going to have to be &#8212; keep up with and ahead of in ways that are not even happening now, as good as everything is.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, as we compete for the future of the 21st century with China and other nations, we have to stay on top of the cutting-edge developments of science and technology.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you&#8217;d hold for a second here, I want to point out something.&nbsp; You know, we used to &#8212; we used to be, when I first got here as a U.S. senator, actually three and a half decades ago, we invested more money &#8212; R&amp;D &#8212; money in R&amp;D as a percent of our GDP than any nation in the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re now number eight.&nbsp; China was number nine; they&#8217;re now number two.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look at where we are on things that intelligence communities and others don&#8217;t even think very often about &#8212; about how educated the public is.&nbsp; We&#8217;re coming around right now.&nbsp; This doesn&#8217;t relate to the intelligence community per se, but it does.<br>&nbsp;<br>Think about it.&nbsp; If we were having the debate that was taking place in the United States in the late 1890s and the early 1900s about public education, do you think any of us would say 12 years of free public education was enough to compete in the 21st century?&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; What do you think?&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a shot if we were doing that today.<br>&nbsp;<br>So the fact we have the best-educated public in the world &#8212; well, that&#8217;s our objective &#8212; will matter a great deal.&nbsp; It will matter a great deal.&nbsp; It is as much a part of national defense, in my view, as anything else is.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I think we have to think differently.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t expect you to agree with me.&nbsp; I expect you to at least understand where I&#8217;m coming from because the world is changing so significantly.<br>&nbsp;<br>And it&#8217;s especially important that we work closely with our partners and allies to maintain our technological edge; shore up supply chains; ensure that the rules that govern technologies support democracies, not autocracies.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, at the same time, we have to work in cooperation with nations like China and Russia that are our competitors &#8212; and possibly mortal competitors down the road &#8212; in the context of there&#8217;s &#8212; to meet the existential threats, for example, of climate change.&nbsp; There are certain things that are in our mutual interest.&nbsp; But we can&#8217;t &#8212; we can&#8217;t be lulled into thinking that that&#8217;s enough and that we don&#8217;t really have to keep a watchful eye on what the ultimate objective of the other team is.&nbsp; But there are things where we should be &#8212; where we should be cooperating.<br>&nbsp;<br>This shared danger impacts all of nations.&nbsp; Climate challenges are already accelerating instability in our own country and around the world: extreme weather events that are more common and more deadly; food and water insecurity; sea levels rising, resulting in changing climates and driving greater migration and posing fundamental risk to the most vulnerable of communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If you could hold for just a second again.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in a situation where &#8212; think about this.&nbsp; Think about this: I&#8217;ll never forget the first time I went down in the tank as Vice President, after I got elected.&nbsp; The Defense Department said what the greatest threat facing America: climate change.<br>&nbsp;<br>If, in fact, the seas’ level rises another two and half feet, you&#8217;re going to have millions of people migrating, fighting over arable land.&nbsp; You saw what happened in North Africa.&nbsp; What makes us think this doesn&#8217;t matter?&nbsp; It&#8217;s not your responsibility, but it&#8217;s something you&#8217;re watching because you know what&#8217;s going to happen.<br>&nbsp;<br>People who were Muslim, and the only difference was Black and/or Arab, killing each other by the thousands for arable &#8212; a piece of arable &#8212; arable land in North Central Africa.&nbsp; But what happens &#8212; what happens in Indonesia if the projections are correct that, in the next 10 years, they may have to move their capital because they&#8217;re going to be underwater?<br>&nbsp;<br>It matters.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a strategic question as well as an environmental question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>A dramatically warming Arctic is opening up competition for resources that once were hard to access.&nbsp; I had &#8212; as they say in Southern Delaware &#8212; they talk at you like this, you know what I mean?&nbsp;&#8212; I had a &#8220;Come to Jesus&#8221; meeting, an “altar call” with Mr. Putin about what he thinks is what Russia&#8217;s property is in the Arctic.&nbsp; China looking very closely at that as well, where they are.<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s what I mean about the world changing.&nbsp; What is that going to do to our strategic doctrine in the next 2, 5, 10, 12 years, when you can circumvent the Arctic without icebreakers?<br>&nbsp;<br>So, look, we need your insight, we need your expertise on all these issues.&nbsp; The one thing you all have in common is you all have high IQs.&nbsp; You&#8217;re all smart.&nbsp; You have significant intelligence quotients, and you put it to use to help the elected leaders in this country decide what the best route to go is.<br>&nbsp;<br>So just as you always have been essential as we’ve sought to counter traditional threats, the Intelligence Community is going to be critical to America’s strength as we take on these new challenges and hybrid threats.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, I’ve laid out a broad agenda, and that’s just a fraction of it.&nbsp; But we can’t do any of this without taking care of our best and most important asset: the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know the intelligence community is already one of the best places to work in the federal government.&nbsp; I asked my staff when I found out you came in second just after NASA &#8212; I said, &#8220;Don&#8217;t tell me what the White House is ranked.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; “It will hurt my feelings.”&nbsp; And they assured me, no, you don’t rank them.&nbsp; That was a good thing: “We don’t rank the Oval Office.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>But all kidding aside, it’s about the comradery you have, and most of all, it’s about being able to trust one another &#8212; to trust one another.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My highest priority as President is the safety and security of all Americans, and that includes those who serve in our Intelligence Community.<br>&nbsp;<br>You take on unique risks in these jobs, and we’re taking the cases of anomalous health incidents that are affecting intelligence officers, government officials, and their families very seriously, for example.<br>&nbsp;<br>My administration is coordinating a government-wide effort to respond to these incidents, because this challenge demands &#8212; demands that departments and agencies, including the entire Intelligence Community, work together with urgency.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Talked about changes.&nbsp; What&#8217;s going to happen as we move on and we’re able to develop around the world pathogens that can be transmitted to societies and communities?&nbsp; It may not be a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; It may not be a hypersonic missile.&nbsp; It may not be any of the things we think of.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But think about it.&nbsp; Just think about what&#8217;s happened with one &#8212; I&#8217;m not suggesting it was intended &#8212; a lot more we need to know &#8212; but think what&#8217;s happened: More people have been killed in the United States of America because of COVID than in every single major war we fought combined.&nbsp; Every single one.&nbsp; What&#8217;s next?&nbsp; What is intended?&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of research going on.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to find &#8212; you&#8217;re going to have to increase your ranks with people with significant scientific capacity relative to pathogens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, my point is: Your value is going to increase and increase and increase and increase in terms of security.&nbsp; You know, from the CIA to all the agencies, there&#8217;s a lot that’s going to happen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And to all of you who’ve been affected, we recognize how important it is to make sure that they have the best possible care at a time you&#8217;re figuring out how to deal with what&#8217;s happening, not only to some of those who have been stationed abroad, but their families.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, this is a priority for our entire leadership team.&nbsp; So let me just close by saying how much I value the work you do.&nbsp; That’s why I wanted to come here today.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So much of the work you do is in secret.&nbsp; It means many, many times you don’t get credit &#8212; the credit you deserve &#8212; and the things you prevented from happening, the catastrophes you’ve enabled us to avoid, the judgments you’ve provided us to make our people safer.<br>&nbsp;<br>And America is probably never going to learn about the lives you’ve saved or the disasters that never come to pass because of your diligent, professional intelligence work.&nbsp; But I want you to know I know.&nbsp; For the time being, at least as long as I’m around, I know.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And on behalf of the American people, thank you all for what you do every single day.&nbsp; And we’re grateful &#8212; we’re grateful that you’re there for us.&nbsp; We’re safer because of your dedication, your honesty, your integrity, and your significant intellectual capacity to act in our interest.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re stronger because of your insight.&nbsp; We’re a more noble nation because of your insight.&nbsp; And American lives have been saved repeatedly because of your insight. I know it may sound like hyperbole, but from the bottom of my heart, I thank you.&nbsp; I thank you for all you do and continue to do.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And may God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops and all those patriots serving in harm’s way, because there&#8217;s a lot still there.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>I have to seek permission to leave.&nbsp; I had to check, if you noticed.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Thank you again.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, will you require federal employees to get vaccinated?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Beg your pardon?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you require all federal employees to get vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s under consideration right now.&nbsp; But if you&#8217;re not vaccinated, you&#8217;re not nearly as smart as I thought you were.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned that the CDC’s mask guidance could sow confusion?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have a pandemic because of the unvaccinated, and they&#8217;re sowing enormous confusion.&nbsp; And the more we learn &#8212; the more we learn about this virus and the Delta variation, the more we have to be worried and concerned.&nbsp; And only one thing we know for sure:&nbsp;If those other hundred million people got vaccinated, we’d be in a very different world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, get vaccinated.&nbsp; If you haven’t, you’re not nearly as smart as I said you were.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 27, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/27/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-27-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 20:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:51 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, I have a couple of notes for you at the top. Today, the Department of Health and Human Services, through the Health Resources and Services Administration, awarded $121 million in American Rescue Plan funding to support the work of trusted community-based&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:51 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, I have a couple of notes for you at the top.<br><br>Today, the Department of Health and Human Services, through the Health Resources and Services Administration, awarded $121 million in American Rescue Plan funding to support the work of trusted community-based efforts to increase vaccinations in underserved communities.<br><br>This is the second round of funding for community-based groups.&nbsp; Back in June, HHS awarded $125 million to similar groups for these efforts.<br><br>And these groups will undertake efforts such as mobilizing community outreach workers to educate and assist individuals in accessing and receiving COVID-19 vaccinations, organize pop-up or mobile vaccine locations, and assist in making vaccine appointments or arranging transportation and childcare assistance for vaccine appointments.<br><br>One grantee in Jacksonville, Florida &#8212; one of the states where there, as you know, has been the highest transmission rates &#8212; one of the highest transmission rates &#8212; will use the funding to establish a sustainable community-based workforce and infrastructure to maximize COVID-19 vaccine uptake, minimize disparities, and advance health equities in vulnerable populations.<br><br>Another grantee in Oklahoma will reach rural communities, including Hispanic community members, and will recruit and train community health workers.<br><br>I also wanted to give you a small preview of the President&#8217;s visit to ODNI this afternoon.&nbsp; As we announced earlier &#8212; last week, I guess it was &#8212; he will visit the Office of the Director of National Intelligence later this afternoon to meet with leaders of the Intelligence Community and to thank all of our intelligence professionals for their service to our nation.<br><br>After the meeting &#8212; after meeting with Director of National Intelligence Avril Haines, the President will tour the National Counterterrorism Center Operations Center with NCTC Director Christy Abizaid to see firsthand how we remain ever vigilant in fighting threats to our country.<br><br>He&#8217;s particularly proud of Director Haines and Director Abizaid, who are both the first Senate-confirmed women to hold these positions.<br><br>He will then address the intelligence community workforce to express his admiration and appreciation for their service.&nbsp; In his remarks, he will highlight the integral role our public servants play in shaping national security decision-making and protecting the American people.&nbsp; He will also underscore the importance of intelligence collection and analysis that is free from political interference or pressure.<br><br>And I think many of you have been on these trips with him.&nbsp; He&#8217;s visited a number of national security agencies, and it&#8217;s part of his effort to support the workforce.<br><br>Another item for you: The Justice Department has successfully blocked a merger between two of the three largest insurance brokers in the world &#8212; I know this had been reported on &#8212; Aon and Willis Tower Watson.<br><br>These companies provide insurance brokerage services to thousands of American businesses and charge billions a year for their services.<br><br>The merger would have raised prices for a wide swath of American businesses that need to use a broker to obtain insurance and benefit packages for their employers &#8212; employees, sorry.<br><br>Those higher insurance costs would ultimately have led Americans to pay more for all kinds of products and services, such as banking services, hospital care, cars, and trucks.&nbsp;<br><br>And the proposed merger, as the Justice Department explained in its complaint, was a clear and presumptive violation of the antitrust laws under established law.<br><br>So, these actions, which I&#8217;m &#8212; the reason I&#8217;m lifting them up &#8212; are very much in line with the Presi- &#8212; what the President was talking about when he called for more robust enforcement of the antitrust laws in his executive order to promote competition.<br><br>Last piece, I think, here &#8212; second to last piece, but hopefully useful: Tomorrow, the President will travel to Lehigh Valley, in Pennsylvania, where he will be emphasizing the importance of American manufacturing, buying products made in America, and supporting good-paying jobs for American workers during a trip to the Lehigh Valley Operations facility for Mack Trucks.&nbsp; The President will take a tour of the Mack Trucks facility and meet with local union members.&nbsp; More than 85 percent of the 2,500 employees at the Mack Trucks location are UAW members.<br><br>And a little bit about Mack Trucks, as you&#8217;re preparing for tomorrow: The company has been making vehicles for the military since at least World War One.&nbsp; There are more than 1,500 Mack Trucks in the federal fleets used by both military and civilian agencies.<br><br>He&#8217;ll also receive a briefing on the Mack Trucks electrical refuse truck.&nbsp; The company is currently piloting their electric dump trucks in New York City and North Carolina.&nbsp; And this is all a part of his effort to lift up and talk about his &#8220;Buy American&#8221; agenda as well as the infrastructure package.<br><br>Finally, I just wanted to note that, after additional engagement with a bipartisan group yesterday, we&#8217;re enthusiastic about getting the bipartisan infrastructure plan across the finish line and confident we&#8217;ll be there soon.<br><br>We were encouraged this morning by positive comments by Senator Romney.&nbsp; Our team remains hard at work, as do a number of the supporters on the Hill.<br><br>With that, go ahead, Alex.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I have a few questions on the CDC&#8217;s revised masking guidance &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that some vaccinated Americans should wear masks indoors where there&#8217;s risk of high transmission or currently high transmission.&nbsp; That covers, according to the CDC, about 63 percent of the country right now, which has significant or high transmission.&nbsp; So how will the White House get Americans to start wearing masks when they&#8217;ve gone for more than two months without them?&nbsp; Will we see President speak more about this?&nbsp; I mean, how exactly do you plan to push this publicly?<br><br>And then, along those same lines, on July 4th, the President gave his, sort of, &#8220;independence from the virus&#8221; speech.&nbsp; He declared, quote, &#8220;We are closer than ever to declaring our independence from a deadly virus&#8221; and, quote, &#8220;we&#8217;ve gained the upper hand on the virus.&#8221;&nbsp; Was that declaring premature victory?&nbsp; And are you at all concerned that those statements will make it tougher for you guys to implement this revised guidance now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, I know this is slightly awkward timing, but &#8212; and I know there&#8217;s a lot of reporting out there about the CDC guidance.&nbsp; It is not only appropriate for them to make the decisions, it&#8217;s also appropriate for them to officially announce their own guidance.<br><br>I will say, though, that how we view this, as you asked about, Alex &#8212; implementation of their guidelines that they&#8217;ll outline on a call with all of you later this afternoon &#8212; that we are still in the midst of a once-in-a-generation pandemic battling an ever-evolving virus.&nbsp;<br><br>We have said since the beginning of June that the Delta variant &#8212; a rising variant that had increasing &#8212; was clear from the beginning had great &#8212; a great deal of transmissibility &#8212; was a threat to people who were unvaccinated.&nbsp; We did more than a hundred interviews with officials conveying exactly that.&nbsp;<br><br>And the reality is: We are dealing with a much different strain of this virus than we were even earlier in the spring, back in May, when the masking guidance was done &#8212; provided by the CDC at that time.<br><br>That is their job.&nbsp; Their job is to look at evolving information, evolving data, an evolving historic pandemic, and provide guidance to the American public.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what they will do and what they will provide specific details on later this afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With respect to the President&#8217;s comments, though, do you, in retrospect, regret those comments?&nbsp; Do you think that that was wise at the time, considering, you know, they could make it tougher for Americans to take this seriously?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that, in the President&#8217;s remarks, he also made clear &#8212; and I&#8217;m quoting him &#8212; that today, &#8220;while the virus hasn&#8217;t been vanquished,” we &#8212; you know, he made clear that it was not over; that those who were unvaccinated were still at risk. &nbsp;<br><br>He made clear that you were protected from serious illness, disea- &#8212; or hospitalization if you were vaccinated.&nbsp; That remains the case.&nbsp; And he encouraged people who are not vaccinated to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>But, again, the role of the federal government and our public health officials is to continue to look at evolving data, evolving threats of a historic virus, provide that public health guidance to the American people to protect more people and save more lives.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what they&#8217;re doing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One quick one on infrastructure.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President met with Senator Kyrsten Sinema.&nbsp; Can you tell us anything about how that meeting went?&nbsp; And does he have other meetings planned with any of the primary negotiators or Democratic leadership on the bill as it gets to the &#8212; potentially, the finish line?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would expect &#8212; yes, the President saw Senator Sinema this morning.&nbsp; They are very much aligned on the path forward.&nbsp; Both feel optimistic about the path forward.&nbsp;<br><br>And clearly, both understand, having lived through many iterations of legislating and negotiating before, that it is always at the tail end when you have, you know, some of the trickiest discussions.&nbsp;<br><br>So &#8212; but they, again, remain quite positive about the forward momentum and the path we see the infrastructure package on at this point in time.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have any additional meetings to preview for you, but I will tell you that the President is somebody who just picks up the phone when somebody tells him it&#8217;s going to be constructive.&nbsp; That certainly, I think, will continue to happen as we work to get this across the finish line.<br><br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When the President travels, as in Lehigh County, will you be looking at the rate of infection there?&nbsp; And will that cause us to see any change in the President’s own masking posture or that of people in the entourage there?<br><br>And what should Americans &#8212; who should they look to for specific guidance about making these decisions, day to day?&nbsp; Do they need to be looking at a CDC website for the positivity rate in their community?&nbsp; Do they need to be looking to the White House for that guidance?&nbsp; What is your prescription for how Americans should adjust with these mask guidelines?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; First, we will, of course, be abiding by every aspect of the CDC guidelines on masking that they will provide this afternoon.&nbsp; And that does mean, as you conveyed, that we will be looking at the rates in different areas where the President may visit, and also the rates as they &#8212; if they move in Washington, D.C., and we will apply guidance accordingly.&nbsp;<br><br>That means we will be prepared to wear masks again if required, if the guidance is leading to that, as would the President.&nbsp; And that will continue to be the case.&nbsp;<br><br>And as it relates to the American public &#8212; I mean, our hope is certainly that elected officials, leaders, civic leaders, public health experts around the country will also look at the CDC guidance and they will be constructive partners and voices in sharing with their communities what steps they could take.<br><br>The CDC is going to have the map and the guidance to provide to the public on how this guidance applies to them, and that would be the most accurate place to seek information.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the “summer of freedom,” as the President described it, is that still operative now, given the change in the Delta variant?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first &#8212; I have this little handy chart; I suspected that we might talk a little bit about COVID today, understandably.&nbsp; And what I would note is that what has not changed is the fact that people are &#8212; who are vaccinated have a huge deal of protection from serious illness, from hospitalization, and from death.&nbsp; And I know Shannon &#8212; actually, I see her in the back there &#8212; asked a good question yesterday about the data, so I wanted to give you a little bit of a better understanding of how this data process works.&nbsp;<br><br>So the data that Dr. Walensky, the CDC Director, spoke to back in July was based on data up through the beginning of June &#8212; or the end of May, the beginning of June.&nbsp; That will be updated in August as it relates to individuals who are hospitalized or get sick, who are vaccinated, and those who are unvacc- &#8212; what hospitalizations look like as the percentage breaks down.<br><br>But this is all based on data from either state officials or health agencies &#8212; or the Florida Hospital Association, as it relates to the Florida-specific example here.<br><br>And how the information flows &#8212; to your question earlier yesterday, Shannon &#8212; is it goes from hospitals to states to the CDC.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m using this example to show you &#8212; because this kind of breaks through the reporting of this data &#8212; this is from hospital systems that will go to states.&nbsp;<br><br>And what you can see here: Florida, which is one of the states with the high- &#8212; one of the highest transmiss- &#8212; or one of the highest rates of COVID, I should say &#8212; officials have said that more than 95 percent of those who were hospitalized were not vaccinated.&nbsp; That is information from last week, or just a couple of days ago.<br><br>North Carolina: Unvaccinated make up more than 99 percent of new COVID cases in May and June.&nbsp; That&#8217;s from a few weeks ago, but still updated data.<br><br>Colorado: More than 96 percent of Colorado&#8217;s COVID hospitalizations, deaths in the first half of 2021 were among unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m using these examples because even as the masking guidance is put out later today by the CDC, we are still going to be sending a very clear message to the public that in order to protect yourself or save your life, save the lives of those around you, you need to get vaccinated.&nbsp; Masking is guidance, but &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, can I follow up &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; just on this data point?&nbsp; Because, yeah, I appreciate you looking into this.&nbsp; It seems the problem, from when I talk to doctors, though, is that the Delta variant is evolving in this situation so rapidly that even data from May or June might not be representative of what&#8217;s happening now.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This is from July.&nbsp; A number of these examples are from July.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It was only July 9th, I think, or mid-July &#8212; which I know isn&#8217;t that long ago, though, that the Delta variant became the dominant spread.&nbsp; So, you know, when I talk to hospitals in places like Nevada, Missouri, Kansas City, you know, those doctors are saying they&#8217;re seeing more like 1 in 10, which I know is still not a majority, but it&#8217;s different than some of these numbers.<br><br>You know, the situation in May and June, for the first half of the year when most people weren&#8217;t vaccinated, is much different than it is now.&nbsp; So, are you guys aware of that?&nbsp; Are you talking to people in some of the harder-hit areas about, like, what they&#8217;re seeing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Shannon, one, I think it&#8217;s really important to project data across a spectrum, right?&nbsp; Not from individual hospitals or individual cases.&nbsp; Because what people are really looking at or what we&#8217;re looking at is how it relates to across-state data.<br><br>Florida &#8212; this data is from four days ago.&nbsp; Florida is one of the states that has the highest rate; it accounts for about 20 percent of COVID cases in the country, from the last data I saw.&nbsp; This is from four days ago; 95 percent of those who were hospitalized were not vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s across-Florida data from the Florida Hospital Association.<br><br>Of course, we absolutely look at data, as does the CDC, and we&#8217;re going to continue to evaluate and assess.&nbsp; But because this data goes into what the CDC reports, I thought it would be relevant to all of you to see and understand how we look at the across-the-state data.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The CDC data showed, though, on July 6th, that the Delta variant was the prominent strain: 51.7 percent of cases.&nbsp; So, what took so long between then and now?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Even higher now, as you know.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what led to the change in guidance?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You &#8212; I’m sure you will get on the call with the CDC later this afternoon, and I think that’s a great question to ask them.&nbsp;<br><br>Our guidance is based on the public health experts and what they are advising in terms of steps that should be taken.&nbsp; I think it’s, though, important to note it has always been the case that the guidance has been, if you are not vaccinated, to wear a mask.&nbsp; That has not changed.&nbsp; That has been the case from the beginning.&nbsp; And also, to get vaccinated if you’re not vaccinated.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the President’s message was get vaxxed <em>or</em> masked, and now it’s get vaxxed <em>and</em> masked, in some cases.&nbsp; So does he regret sending the message that it was a binary choice there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Weijia, I think that those comments were back in May.&nbsp; And as I noted at the time, the Delta variant was a &#8212; was by no means a variant &#8212; the variant that it is today.&nbsp; It was not even a &#8212; I can look at the specific data, but it was &#8212; 99 percent of cases were not Delta at the time.&nbsp; That was based on guidance from the CDC.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, they&#8217;re changing their guidance, they&#8217;re changing their advice to the American public &#8212; their public health advice based on evolving data and an evolving, historic &#8212; vari- &#8212; virus.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what they should be doing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what is your message to Americans who are feeling whiplash right now?&nbsp; Why should they trust the same group of health officials who, just two months ago, told them they don&#8217;t have to wear a mask anymore inside?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because our goal is to save their lives, and our responsibility and the responsibility of public health officials is to continue to provide updated guidance, if it warrants, from an evolving virus.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on something related.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve said many times from the podium, as recently as Friday, that it is not the federal government&#8217;s role to mandate vaccines.&nbsp; Can you help us understand what changed between then and yesterday when that&#8217;s exactly what the VA did?&nbsp; And is it a sign of what&#8217;s to come for other agencies?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think the context of the question, which I think is important here, is: Can we mandate vaccines across the country?&nbsp; No, that&#8217;s not a role that the federal government, I think, even has the power to make.<br><br>The federal workforce is part of the workforce of the federal government; that&#8217;s different and very different from the question you just posed, in important context.&nbsp;<br><br>The VA is a huge provider of public health officials and to patients who are some of the men and women who served our country bravely as parts of the military &#8212; as members of the military.&nbsp; And this was a decision that followed, and was aligned with, I should say, the decision by 57 hospitals associations across the country to make sure we were taking &#8212; they were taking every step they could to protect the servicemen and women who seek health services at the VA.<br><br>I will also say, as a big employer &#8212; the federal government &#8212; it is also our responsibility to continue to look at ways that we can protect people and save lives.&nbsp; And so we will continue to look, agencies will continue to look, we will continue to look at what steps we need to take for our workforce.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks Jen.&nbsp; How closely has the President been monitoring the January 6th hearing on the Hill?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s his reaction to some of the testimony from the law enforcement officers today?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say &#8212; I know you didn&#8217;t ask me this question, but I know a number of us have watched the testimony this morning, which has been incredibly compelling, heart wrenching, and, you know, at moments, a reminder of the shameful events of January 6th and of the incredible bravery of the men and women of law enforcement who put themselves in harm&#8217;s way to protect the Capitol, our democracy, and members of Congress from both parties.&nbsp;<br><br>The President has had a range of meetings and briefings and engagements this morning.&nbsp; I know he&#8217;s intending to catch updates and clips, and certainly staff will share with him what they&#8217;ve seen as we&#8217;ve watched the briefings, but he has not been in a position, via his schedule, to watch the hearings this morning.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we anticipate a statement from him at the end of the day after he’s been updated on this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would not anticipate that, no.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one on vaccines before we move on.&nbsp; You know, you just said that the message for unvaccinated Americans has always been to wear a mask.&nbsp; But how concerned is the White House that the message that unvaccinated Americans will hear after this afternoon is that, even if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you now have to wear a mask in some settings, and then just say, “why bother then” on the vaccine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s the good news: We’re all here.&nbsp; You all are all here.&nbsp; You’ve got millions of people and Americans who watch your broadcasts and watch your shows and listen to you to hear what they should know about how to protect themselves and save their lives.&nbsp;<br><br>So our message to the American public is: We are at war.&nbsp; We continue to be at war with a virus and evolving pandemic.&nbsp; Our responsibility here is to always lead with the science and always lead with the advice of health and medical experts.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to provide information to all of you about how to protect yourself and save your lives.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re not saying that wearing a mask is convenient or people feel like it, but we are telling you that that is the way to protect yourself, protect your loved ones, and that&#8217;s why the CDC is issuing this guidance.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow on those two questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; What was &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll come back to you, April.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When was the White House told that this CDC guidance was changing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s been &#8212; it&#8217;s obviously a decision the CDC made.&nbsp; The President was briefed this morning by Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; But beyond that, we&#8217;ve been aware of their discussions with our public health officials.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the CDC is also going to recommend that children in schools all wear a ma- &#8212; that everyone in schools wear a mask regardless of vaccination status.&nbsp; But there are at least eight states that actually prohibit their districts from requiring a mask in schools.&nbsp; So what are parents who have children in those schools, in those states supposed to do?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, look, Kaitlan, I&#8217;m happy not to live in a state where that is the guidance.&nbsp; And this is new guidance that is being issued by the CDC today.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know how it will influence local elected officials in these states, but I certainly hope, for the health and wellbeing of the next generation, that they take a close look at the guidance.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more question.&nbsp; You just said you don&#8217;t think the federal government has the power to mandate vaccinations across the country, but they do have the power to mandate them within the government.&nbsp; So why is everyone who works in the federal government not mandated to get vaccinated?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first, Kaitlan, that we &#8212; you saw the VA announcement yesterday, which was really about public health and about protecting the patients, the men and women who have served our country.&nbsp; But we are going to continue to look at ways to protect our workforce and to save more lives.&nbsp; I just have nothing to preview for you at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we expect more vaccination mandates from federal agencies?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think a range of agencies and leaders will look at what steps they should take to protect their workforce and save lives.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just explicitly, when President Biden was presented with this latest guidance from CDC, what was his reaction?&nbsp; I mean, he welcomed the guidance back in May.&nbsp; What was his reaction this time?&nbsp; How concerned was he when he was told about this latest guidance?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Concerned in what way?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Concerned about, you know, how this will impact the administration&#8217;s ability to perhaps vaccinate those who don&#8217;t &#8212; do not want to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, first, that the President has always said that he is going to be guided by public health experts, by the CDC, and what our doctors are recommending.&nbsp; That has always been the case.&nbsp; And there have been discussions, as you would expect, for months now, from the beginning, about what steps need to be taken, should be taken to protect from an evolving virus.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he did not explicitly talk about, you know, “Let&#8217;s &#8212; maybe the administration should start worrying about, you know, how this impacts your messaging, the work that you&#8217;re doing on the ground”?&nbsp; Did he have anything to say about that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not how he looks at this.&nbsp; He looks at &#8212; as the President of the United States, at a time where we came in with a dangerous distrust in science and government and institutions, he felt &#8212; feels it&#8217;s important to be led by data and scientists, and will be helping &#8212; le- &#8212; helping lead the effort to implement this, of course, in the federal government.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I did have a follow-up to Kelly’s question there.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not just when he&#8217;s traveling, but just when he&#8217;s at the White House, and even for White House staff, is there any decision on whether he or staff will start wearing masks?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will be abiding by public health guidance.&nbsp; And if that is where we fall in the geographical guidance given by the CDC, we will also be following that masking guidance.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, first on crime: As shootings spike in Chicago, the superintendent of police there is blaming courts for releasing attempted murderers on electronic surveillance.&nbsp; Does the President agree with the superintendent, who was just here earlier this month, that ankle bracelets do not cut down on attempted murder?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have to tell you, I have not seen these comments or looked at the full context of them.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to do that after the briefing.&nbsp;<br><br>I think we know &#8212; from seeing, broadly, the rising crime or the rising gun violence across the country, including in cities like Chicago &#8212; that there needs to be greater assistance, greater efforts to make sure guns don&#8217;t get in the hands of criminals who could do harm, and more assistance to local police forces and community policing programs as well.<br><br>The President doesn&#8217;t just use that as rhetoric; he delivers it with action.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know he&#8217;s in discussions &#8212; or in discussions about reforming the police, generally.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got cops now saying that the courts are too soft.&nbsp; Some progressives, including Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, are saying the courts are too strict.&nbsp; So, what does the President think?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President &#8212; I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s a secret that the President disagrees at times with Congresswoman &#8212; the congresswoman about some aspects of policing.&nbsp;<br><br>He believes we need to reform our prison system to keep our community safe while addressing mass incarceration and by diverting nonviolent drug offenders and taking other steps that will improve rehabilitation and reduce recimit [sic] &#8211;recidivism.&nbsp;<br><br>If you &#8212; but he also believes, let&#8217;s be clear, if you commit a violent crime and are found guilty and pose a threat to society, you should serve that time.&nbsp; And when you get out, you should have the support you need to successfully reenter society.&nbsp; That&#8217;s his view.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the CDC guidance, why did the President say, “If you&#8217;ve been fully vaccinated, you no longer need to wear a mask.&nbsp; Let me repeat: If you are fully vaccinated, you no longer need to wear a mask” if it was possible that that was going to turn out not to be true?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, I think we&#8217;re all dealing with an evolving virus where there&#8217;s no playbook and no historic precedent.&nbsp; And what the American people should feel confident in is that we are going to continue to be guided by science, look at public health data in order to provide new guidance, if it&#8217;s needed, to save lives, to protect the American people.<br><br>When he made those comments back in May, we were dealing with a very different strain of the virus than we were &#8212; than we are today.&nbsp; And Delta is more transmissible.&nbsp; It&#8217;s spreading much more quickly.&nbsp; It was nearly non-existent in the United States back in May.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so my last one would be: You guys have been saying this is a pandemic of the “unvaccinated.”&nbsp; If that is coming from the CDC, is the President satisfied with the leadership at the CDC right now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President is satisfied with the fact that they are continuing to look at public health data and give &#8212; provide public health guidance to the American public about how they can protect their lives and the lives of loved ones around them.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if it’s a pandemic of the unvaccinated still, then why do vaccinated people need to put the masks back on?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, first of all, I would say again &#8212; just to go back to this chart, which I will handily point to again: If you are vaccinated &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Overwhelmingly, the unvaccinated.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; if you are vaccinated, your li- &#8212; it can save your life.&nbsp; And I think the clear data shows that this pandemic is killing, is hospitalizing, is making people very sick who are not vaccinated.&nbsp; That co- &#8212; still continues to be the case, regardless of what the mask guidance looks like.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if the vaccines work, which this sign says that they do, then why do people who had the vaccine need to now wear masks &#8212; the same as people who have not had it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because the public health leaders in our administration have made the determination, based on data, that that is a way to make sure they&#8217;re protected, their loved ones are protected.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s an extra step, given the transmissibility of the virus, that people &#8212; that they&#8217;re advising people to take.<br><br>Go ahead, Steve.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last year, when we went through this as a national discussion &#8212; talk about social distancing and shutdowns.&nbsp; Is this White House eyeing anything other than mask guidance?&nbsp; I mean, this week, you said you wouldn&#8217;t lift the travel restrictions.&nbsp; Is anything else coming?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we&#8217;re always going to be guided by the public health guidance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how the travel restrictions decision was made.&nbsp; But we are not &#8212; this is not guidance about businesses shutting down or communities shutting down.&nbsp; This is guidance to individuals about how they can protect themselves.<br><br>We&#8217;ve seen some communities &#8212; L.A. County, for example &#8212; where they have applied versions of mask guidance.&nbsp; It has not shut businesses down.&nbsp; It is meant to protect people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; That is the goal and the objective.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you about expedited removals &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; down at the border?&nbsp; As you know, there are advocates for immigrants who say that what this administration is now doing is taking away due process rights by empowering asylum officers to make decisions in the immediate moment for expedited removal.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your response to that criticism?&nbsp;<br><br>And on the other side of that coin, is it this administration&#8217;s view that most of the people who are claiming credible fear on the border are not entitled to asylum?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, no, that is certainly not our claim.&nbsp; We are &#8212; of course, people who are applying for asylum, who will go through the process, and if their case and their &#8212; may &#8212; warrants, they will be granted asylum.&nbsp; What this is, is that &#8212; I should say, those families process for expedited removal who claim fear will have the opportunity to present their cases before an immigration judge and request asylum or other forms of relief or protection from removal.&nbsp; So even &#8212; even those who are being processed.&nbsp;<br><br>What &#8212; the processing of migrants for expedited removal is a traditionally employed, lawful mean to secure our border, and it is a step toward our broader aim of having a safe and orderly immigration system.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say, at the same time, we continue to work to build a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system.&nbsp; We recently expanded the Central American Minors Program and made 6,000 H-2B visas available to Central Americans.<br><br>But we also want to be crystal clear: Attempting to cross into the United States between ports of entry or circumventing inspection of ports of entry is dangerous.&nbsp; It carries long-term conse- &#8212; immigration consequences.&nbsp;<br><br>But, no, we will still, of course &#8212; individuals who are applying for asylum, who warrant asylum, will be treated accordingly.<br><br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, does the President&#8217;s economic team see any ramifications to this masking policy?&nbsp; Are they concerned at all that it could affect consumer spending or any of the economic growth projections?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I will say, I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re quite at that point.&nbsp; The guidance, of course, is not, as you know, being released until later this afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>I will also say that as we&#8217;ve looked at, kind of, the economic impact of the Delta variant, one of the things we&#8217;ve looked at is that we have &#8212; one, we have programs in place that are meant to be implemented over the course of time to ensure that Americans are getting assistance, getting additional funding into their pockets as needed, which was a lesson learned from the past about ensuring that there wasn&#8217;t an abrupt halt to economic assistance as we&#8217;re going through a historic pandemic, still at war with it, and as we&#8217;re still going through an economic recovery.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s no significant signs at this point of the Delta variant’s impact in that sense.&nbsp; And we&#8217;d expect that much of the economic impact will be felt in communities with lower vaccination rates.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t expect to turn back the clock to what it was in March of 2020 or even six months ago.&nbsp;<br><br>But in terms of longer-term analysis, I don&#8217;t &#8212; we&#8217;re not at that point yet.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on the infrastructure talks &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the President obviously met with Senator Sinema, and he’s making calls on this.&nbsp; Does he see the end of the week as a more or less deadline to get a bipartisan deal on this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to be setting new deadlines today, but what I will tell you is that we were quite encouraged by the conversations overnight and into this morning.&nbsp; We see momentum.&nbsp; It&#8217;s moving in a positive direction.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard that from Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; That certainly is a good sign &#8212; and it&#8217;s only Tuesday.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the federal eviction moratorium is scheduled to expire at the end of the week, and millions of renters are still behind on payments.&nbsp; I know the administration has taken other steps to aid with assistance, but is there any discussion about an extension of that moratorium, especially as we&#8217;re seeing the Delta variant, you know, rear its head?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me just give you &#8212; I know you follow this closely, but for others, just as a reminder: On day one of the administration, as part of the American Rescue Plan rollout, the President did call on Congress to extend the eviction moratorium through September 30th of 2021.&nbsp; The final plan, of course, did not include that proposed moratorium extension, and so the CDC extended the moratorium administratively in January, March, and most recently in June for a final month.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s in place, as you noted, until <s>January 31st</s> [July 31st].<br><br>I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this point in time or &#8212; but certainly, we will be watching this closely, ongoing discussions about how we can continue to help renters.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just on another subject related to January 6th.&nbsp; Yesterday, the White House said that it would nominate Matthew Graves to be U.S. Attorney for D.C., and if confirmed, he would oversee the prosecutions of hundreds of people who were arrested for what happened on January 6th at the Capitol.&nbsp; Did the President or anybody else in the administration discuss those cases with Graves before his nomination?&nbsp; Did they seek any particular position on those cases, such as being aggressive and charging and prosecuting them?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more on this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check and see if there&#8217;s more we can convey about the personnel process.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on Peter&#8217;s point: Does President Biden have confidence right now in Director Walensky’s leadership?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And is a reason why Dr. Fauci briefed President Biden on the new CDC guidance and not Dr. Walensky &#8212; or Director Walensky?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think Dr. Fauci is likely in town, but also has provided briefings to the President on a regular basis, as has Dr. Walensky, throughout the course of the pandemic.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on a different topic: What is the White House doing to specifically win over support from Democrats on the nomination of David Chipman to lead the ATF?&nbsp; Senator Durbin just told us this morning that Democrats don&#8217;t have the votes, and Senator Tester also signaled this morning that the nomination could even be pulled.&nbsp; So does &#8212; is the White House still pushing through on that nomination?&nbsp; And what is the White House doing to whip up votes?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I’d first remind people, as you well know, but for others, that not only is he a veteran of the ATF, but he&#8217;s somebody who has been a supporter of smart gun reform measures that could save lives of people across the country.&nbsp; And we &#8212; the President felt quite confident in the &#8212; his qualifications and his ability to lead the agency at a time where it hasn&#8217;t been led for many years.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of our specific legislative strategy, I&#8217;d really have to talk to the team and see where things stand with that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick follow-up: Senate appropriators just announced a deal on a supplemental on Capitol Police security funding.&nbsp; It does include about a billion dollars for the Special Immigrant Visa program.&nbsp; Does the White House support that deal between Leahy and Shelby?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly have supported and advocated for additional funding for the Special Immigrant Visa program &#8212; something that is a huge priority to the President.&nbsp; I&#8217;d also reiterate, since you gave me the opportunity, that our first flight of Afghan SIV applicants will be coming into the United States this week, which is a very exciting step forward and will be the first of many.<br><br>In terms of the amount of funding, I would have to check with our legislative team on that as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, April.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Jen, a couple of questions.&nbsp; On COVID: Are we at a point where we are saying that there&#8217;s just no absolutes when it comes to what&#8217;s happening in this moment?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not at that point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because we&#8217;re possibly beginning to wear masks again in the building &#8212; in buildings, kids could possibly be wearing masks in schools, and those who are vaccinated are getting breakthrough COVID cases.&nbsp; So you&#8217;re saying &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think &#8212; here&#8217;s what we all have responsibility to do: is to provide the guidance and clear information that is being presented by public health officials to the American public &#8212; not to project confusion, but to alleviate the confusion.&nbsp; And it is &#8212; also, it&#8217;s incumbent upon the public health officials to continue to look at and evaluate and make recommendations based on data to save people&#8217;s lives and protect people from getting the virus, getting &#8212; being hospitalized or, of course, dying.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And a question on Johnson &amp; Johnson and on the testimony today.&nbsp;<br><br>Johnson &amp; Johnson is in the news again.&nbsp; This time, the National Council of Negro Women &#8212; who the President just had at his table &#8212; is suing Johnson &amp; Johnson because they targeted Black women, starting in the ‘90s, with talcum powder that is said to cause ovarian cancer.&nbsp; Is this administration concerned with the credibility, the integrity of Johnson &amp; Johnson, a company that is administering some of these vaccines in COVID?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, April, first, it&#8217;s ongoing litigation, as you noted, so of course I can&#8217;t speak to that.&nbsp; But I do think it&#8217;s important to note that the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine, which is entirely separate from baby powder, was approved by the gold standard, the FDA, which requires a rigorous look at the data and safety guardrails.&nbsp;<br><br>The FDA approved the distribution and the use of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine.&nbsp; And again, it&#8217;s entirely separate from the baby powder, talcum powder litigation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it’s still that same company, the brand.&nbsp; And people will associate &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But the FDA is a U.S. government entity and, again, the gold standard, and has a rigorous review process, so people should remain confident in the vir- &#8212; in the vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And lastly, on the January 6th Select Committee: Last week, President Biden said he “has faith in the American people to ultimately get to the right place.”&nbsp; And what is that “right place,” particularly when you hear testimony today from some of these police officers who &#8212; some are minority &#8212; some of the Black officers said Black officers fought a “different battle.”&nbsp; One officer said he was called the N-word &#8212; N-I-G-G-E-R &#8212; after answering questions of the rioters &#8212; the insurrectionists &#8212; as to who he voted for when he said he voted for Joe Biden.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, April, as I said a little bit earlier, I mean, today&#8217;s testimony &#8212; for anybody who watched it &#8212; it was a searing reminder of the shameful events of January 6th.&nbsp; And certainly that testimony, I think, will stick with people for some time to come.&nbsp;<br><br>And what the President meant is that he is confident in the American people to fight for democracy; to fight for voting rights; to fight for, you know, moving forward from the events that were a dark day in our democracy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he supports &#8212; strongly supports the actions by Speaker Pelosi and the efforts to get to the bottom of what happened on January 6th so that we can prevent it from ever happening again.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, we&#8217;ve got to wrap up guys, sorry.&nbsp; You got an event.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; Have a good day.&nbsp;<br><br>1:27 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
