<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 19:34:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Strengthening the Nation&#8217;s Forests, Communities, and Local&#160;Economies</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/22/executive-order-on-strengthening-the-nations-forests-communities-and-local-economies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 19:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows: Section&#160;1.&#160;&#160;Policy.&#160;&#160;Strengthening&#160;America&#8217;s forests, which are home to cherished expanses of mature and old-growth forests on Federal lands, is critical to the health, prosperity, and resilience of our communities &#8212; particularly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section&nbsp;1.&nbsp;&nbsp;Policy.&nbsp;&nbsp;Strengthening&nbsp;America&#8217;s forests, which are home to cherished expanses of mature and old-growth forests on Federal lands, is critical to the health, prosperity, and resilience of our communities &#8212; particularly in light of the threat of catastrophic wildfires.&nbsp;&nbsp;Forests provide clean air and&nbsp;water, sustain the plant and animal life fundamental to combating the global climate and biodiversity crises, and hold special importance to Tribal Nations.&nbsp;&nbsp;We go to these special places to hike, camp, hunt, fish, and engage in recreation that revitalizes our souls and connects us to history and nature.&nbsp;&nbsp;Many local economies thrive because of these outdoor and forest management activities, including in the sustainable forest product sector.</p>



<p>Globally, forests represent some of the most biodiverse parts of our planet and play an irreplaceable role in reaching net-zero greenhouse gas emissions.&nbsp;Terrestrial carbon sinks absorb around 30 percent of the carbon dioxide emitted by human activities each year.&nbsp;&nbsp;Here at home, America&#8217;s forests absorb more than 10 percent of annual United States economy-wide greenhouse gas emissions.&nbsp;&nbsp;Conserving old-growth and mature forests on Federal lands while supporting and advancing climate-smart forestry and sustainable forest products is critical to protecting these and other ecosystem services provided by those forests.</p>



<p>Despite their importance, the world&#8217;s forests are quickly disappearing; only a small fraction of the world&#8217;s mature and old-growth forests remains.&nbsp;&nbsp;Here at home, the primary threats to forests, including mature and old-growth forests, include climate impacts, catastrophic wildfires, insect infestation, and disease.&nbsp;&nbsp;We can and must take action to conserve, restore, reforest, and manage our magnificent forests here at home and, working closely with international partners, throughout the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is the policy of my Administration, in consultation with State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, as well as the private sector, nonprofit organizations, labor unions, and the scientific community, to pursue science-based, sustainable forest and land management; conserve America&#8217;s mature and old-growth forests on Federal lands; invest in forest health and restoration; support<a> </a>indigenous traditional ecological knowledge and cultural and subsistencepractices; honor Tribal treaty rights; and deploy climate-smart forestry practices and other nature-based solutions to improve the resilience of our lands, waters, wildlife, and communities in the face of increasing disturbances and chronic stress arising from climate impacts.  It is also the policy of my Administration, as outlined in <em>Conserving and Restoring America the Beautifu</em>l, to support collaborative, locally led conservation solutions.</p>



<p>The Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (IIJA) I signed into law provides generational investments in ecosystem restoration and wildfire risk reduction.  As we use this funding, we will seek opportunities, consistent with the IIJA, to conserve our mature and old-growth forests on Federal lands and restore the health and vibrancy of our Nation&#8217;s forests by reducing the threat of catastrophic wildfires through ecological treatments that create resilient forest conditions using active, science-based forest management and prescribed fires; by incorporating indigenous traditional ecological knowledge; and by scaling up and optimizing climate-smart reforestation.  My Administration also is committed to doing its part to combat deforestation around the world and to working with our international partners toward sustainable management of the world&#8217;s lands, waters, and ocean.</p>



<p>Sec. 2.  Restoring and Conserving the Nation&#8217;s Forests, Including Mature and Old-Growth Forests.  My Administration will manage forests on Federal lands, which include many mature and old-growth forests, to promote their continued health and resilience; retain and enhance carbon storage; conserve biodiversity; mitigate the risk of wildfires; enhance climate resilience; enable subsistence and cultural uses; provide outdoor recreational opportunities; and promote sustainable local economic development.  Science—based reforestation is one of the greatest opportunities both globally and in the United States for the land sector to contribute to climate and biodiversity goals.  To further conserve mature and old-growth forests and foster long-term United States forest health through climate-smart reforestation for the benefit of Americans today and for generations to come, the following actions shall be taken, in consultation with State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments and the public, and to the extent consistent with applicable law: </p>



<p>(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretaries) &#8212; the Federal Government&#8217;s primary land managers &#8212; shall continue to jointly pursue wildfire mitigation strategies, which are already driving important actions to confront a pressing threat to mature and old-growth forests on Federal lands:&nbsp;&nbsp;catastrophic wildfires driven by decades of fire exclusion and climate change.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretary of the Interior, with respect to public lands managed by the Bureau of Land Management, and the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System lands, shall, within 1 year of the date of this order, define, identify, and complete an inventory of&nbsp;old-growth and mature forests on Federal lands, accounting for regional and ecological variations, as appropriate, and shall make such inventory publicly available.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;Following completion of the inventory, the Secretaries shall:</p>



<p>(i)    coordinate conservation and wildfire risk reduction activities, including consideration of climate-smart stewardship of mature and old-growth forests, with other executive departments and agencies (agencies), States, Tribal Nations, and any private landowners who volunteer to participate;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;analyze the threats to mature and old-growth forests on Federal lands, including from wildfires and climate change; and</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp;&nbsp;develop policies, with robust opportunity for public comment, to institutionalize climate-smart management and conservation strategies that address threats to mature and old-growth forests on Federal lands.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretaries, in coordination with the heads of other agencies as appropriate, shall within 1 year of the date of this order:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;develop a Federal goal that charges agencies to meet agency-specific reforestation targets by 2030,&nbsp;including an assessment of reforestation opportunities on Federal lands and through existing Federal programs and partnerships;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;develop, in&nbsp;collaboration with Federal, State, Tribal, and private-sector partners,&nbsp;a climate-informed plan (building on existing efforts) to&nbsp;increase Federal cone and seed collection and to ensure seed and seedling nursery capacity is sufficient to meet anticipated reforestation demand;&nbsp;and</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp;&nbsp;develop, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, with State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, and with the private sector, nonprofit organizations, labor unions, and the scientific community, recommendations for community-led local and regional economic development opportunities to create and sustain jobs in the sustainable forest product sector, including innovative materials, and in outdoor recreation, while supporting healthy, sustainably managed forests in timber communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;3.&nbsp;&nbsp;Stopping International Deforestation.&nbsp;&nbsp;As described in the&nbsp;<em>Plan to Conserve Global Forests:&nbsp;&nbsp;Critical Carbon Sinks</em>, my Administration has committed to deliver, by 2030, on collective global goals to end natural forest loss and to restore at least an additional 200 million hectares of forests and other ecosystems, while showcasing new economic models that reflect the services provided by critical ecosystems around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;The plan recognizes that conserving and restoring global forest and peatland ecosystems, particularly in the Amazon, Congo Basin, and Southeast Asia, can provide significant global greenhouse gas emissions mitigation, both by preventing the emissions caused by deforestation and by increasing the amount of carbon dioxide captured from the atmosphere and stored in soils and forest biomass.&nbsp;&nbsp;My&nbsp;Administration is also committed to combating illegal logging and stopping trade in illegally sourced wood products pursuant to the Lacey Act, as amended, 16 U.S.C. 3371&nbsp;<em>et seq.</em>, and to addressing the related importation of commodities sourced from recently deforested land.&nbsp;&nbsp;To further advance these commitments, conserve these critical ecosystems, and address drivers of global deforestation &#8212; including illegal forest clearing to produce agricultural commodities &#8212; the following actions shall be taken:</p>



<p>(a)  within 1 year of the date of this order, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security (through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection), the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the United States Trade Representative, and the Special Presidential Envoy for Climate, shall submit a report to the President evaluating options, including recommendations for proposed legislation, for a whole-of-government approach to combating international deforestation that includes:</p>



<p>(i)   an analysis of the feasibility of limiting or removing specific commodities grown on lands deforested either illegally or after December 31, 2020, from agricultural supply chains; and</p>



<p>(ii)  an analysis of the potential for public-private partnerships with major agricultural commodity buyers, traders, financial institutions, and other actors to voluntarily reduce or eliminate the purchase of such commodities and incentivize sourcing of sustainably produced agricultural commodities. </p>



<p>(b)  within 1 year of the date of this order, the Secretary of State, in coordination with other appropriate agencies, shall submit a report to the President on how agencies that engage in international programming, assistance, finance, investment, trade, and trade promotion, can, consistent with applicable law, accomplish the following:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;incorporate the assessment of risk of deforestation and other land conversion into guidance on foreign assistance and&nbsp;investmentprogramming related to infrastructure development, agriculture, settlements, land use planning or zoning, and energy siting and generation;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;address deforestation and land conversion risk in new relevant trade agreements and seek to address such risks, where possible, in the implementation of existing trade agreements;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp;&nbsp;identify and engage in international processes and fora, as appropriate, to&nbsp;pursue approaches to combat deforestation and enhance sustainable land use opportunities in preparing climate, development, and finance strategies;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;engage other major commodity-importing and commodity-producing countries to advance common interests in addressing commodity-driven deforestation; and</p>



<p>(v)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;assess options to direct foreign assistance and other agency programs and tools, as appropriate, to help threatened forest communities transition to an economically sustainable future, with special attention to the participation of and the critical role played by indigenous peoples and local communities and landholders in protecting and restoring forests and in reducing deforestation and forest degradation.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;4.&nbsp;&nbsp;Deploying Nature-Based Solutions to Tackle Climate Change and Enhance Resilience.&nbsp;&nbsp;Just as forest conservation, restoration, and adaptation&nbsp;generate broad benefits related to climate change and other areas, other nature-based solutions can&nbsp;advance&nbsp;multiple benefits.&nbsp;&nbsp;These solutions include actions that protect coasts and critical marine ecosystems, reduce flooding, moderate extreme heat, replenish groundwater sources, capture and store carbon dioxide, conserve biodiversity, and improve the productivity of agricultural and forest lands to produce food and fiber.&nbsp;&nbsp;To ensure that agencies pursue nature-based solutions, to the extent consistent with applicable law and supported by science, the following actions shall be taken:</p>



<p>(a)  The Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and the Assistant to the President and National Climate Advisor shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense (through the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works), the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce (through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration), the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Homeland Security (through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency), the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, and the heads of other agencies as appropriate, submit a report to the National Climate Task Force to identify key opportunities for greater deployment of nature-based solutions across the Federal Government, including through potential policy, guidance, and program changes. </p>



<p>(b)  The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall issue guidance related to the valuation of ecosystem and environmental services and natural assets in Federal regulatory decision-making, consistent with the efforts to modernize regulatory review required by my Presidential Memorandum of January 20, 2021 (Modernizing Regulatory Review).</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;Implementation of the United States Global Change Research Program shall include an assessment of the condition of nature within the United States in a report carrying out section&nbsp;102 of the Global Change Research Act of 1990, 15 U.S.C. 2932.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;5.&nbsp;&nbsp;General Provisions.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of&nbsp;Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>      April 22, 2022.</p>



<p>    </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Days Of Remembrance Of Victims Of The Holocaust,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/22/a-proclamation-on-days-of-remembrance-of-victims-of-the-holocaust-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 19:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Yom HaShoah, Holocaust Remembrance Day, and throughout this week of remembrance, we reflect on the horrors of the Holocaust when the Nazi regime systematically murdered 6 million Jews and millions of other innocents, including Roma, Sinti, Slavs, persons with disabilities, LGBTQI+ individuals, political dissidents, and many others.&#160; We stand with Jewish people in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On <em>Yom HaShoah</em>, Holocaust Remembrance Day, and throughout this week of remembrance, we reflect on the horrors of the Holocaust when the Nazi regime systematically murdered 6 million Jews and millions of other innocents, including Roma, Sinti, Slavs, persons with disabilities, LGBTQI+ individuals, political dissidents, and many others.&nbsp; We stand with Jewish people in the United States, Israel, and around the world in grieving one of the darkest chapters in history.&nbsp; We honor the memories of the victims. &nbsp;We embrace the survivors. &nbsp;We commit to keeping alive the promise of &#8220;never again.&#8221;</p>



<p>The world must never forget the truth of what happened across Europe during the Holocaust or forget the horrific crimes and suffering the Nazi regime inflicted on millions of innocent people.  Entire families were wiped out.  Communities were shattered.  Survivors were left with agonizing memories and fading tattoos etched into their skin by the Nazis, reducing them to numbers.  It is forever recorded into the history of mankind, and it is the shared responsibility of us all to ensure that the <em>Shoah</em> is never erased from our collective memory &#8212; especially as fewer and fewer survivors remain.  The truth must always be known and shared with future generations in perpetuity.</p>



<p>I have taught my own children and grandchildren about the horrors of the Holocaust, just as my father taught me.  I have taken my family to bear witness to the darkness at the Dachau concentration camp so that they could understand why we must always speak out against antisemitism and hatred in all of its pernicious forms.  The legacy of the Holocaust must always remind us that silence in the face of such bigotry is complicity.</p>



<p>Remembrance is our eternal duty, but remembrance without action risks becoming an empty ritual.  As individuals, we must never be indifferent to human cruelty and human suffering.  As nations, we must stand together across the international community against antisemitism, which is once again rearing its ugly head around the world.  We must combat other forms of hatred and educate new generations about the Holocaust.  We must reject those who try to deny the Holocaust or to distort its history for their own ends.  We recognize that, just as the Holocaust was an act of pure antisemitism, so too Holocaust denial is a form of antisemitism.  We watch with dismay as the term &#8220;Nazi&#8221; is deployed to make flawed historical parallels.  Efforts to minimize, distort, or blur who the Nazis were and the genocide they perpetrated are a form of Holocaust denial and, in addition to insulting both the victims and survivors of the Holocaust, spread antisemitism.</p>



<p>My Administration has stepped up our efforts to counter all the ugly forms antisemitism can take, including Holocaust denial and distortion.  We co-sponsored a United Nations resolution that charged the international community with combating Holocaust denial through education.  We are partnering with the German government to improve Holocaust education and counter Holocaust denial and distortion.  A renowned scholar of the Holocaust and antisemitism, Deborah Lipstadt, was recently confirmed as Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Antisemitism.</p>



<p>In addition to speaking out against the evils of antisemitism, I signed &#8212; and my Administration continues to implement &#8212; legislation that gives us more tools to combat crimes that are based on a victim&#8217;s actual or perceived race, religion, national origin, sexual orientation, gender, gender identity or disability.  We issued the first-ever National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism.  My Administration has implemented increased funding for a program that helps threatened nonprofits &#8212; including houses of worship and other religious affiliated entities &#8212; to improve their safety and security.  On International Holocaust Remembrance Day, I met with Bronia Brandman and the Vice President met with Ruth Cohen &#8212; both Auschwitz survivors &#8212; at the White House so we could bear witness to their stories, combat Holocaust denial and distortion, and give life to the lessons of that most terrible period in human history.</p>



<p>Those like Bronia and Ruth who survived the Holocaust and went on to build new lives inspire our Nation and the world, and they are living testaments to the enduring resilience of the human spirit.  It is the responsibility of all of us to recognize the pain that they carry and to support them by ensuring that the cruelty of the Holocaust is never forgotten.  Today and every day, we stand against antisemitism and all other forms of hate and continue our work to ensure that everyone can live in a world that safeguards the fundamental human dignity of all people.  </p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 24 through May 1, 2022, as a week of observance of the Days of Remembrance of Victims of the Holocaust, and call upon the people of the United States to observe this week and pause to remember victims and survivors of the Holocaust.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-second day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Crime Victims&#8217; Rights Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/22/a-proclamation-on-national-crime-victims-rights-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 19:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Forty years ago, the President&#8217;s Task Force on Victims of Crime was established to help those who had experienced crime and their families &#8212; an important step toward the protection of and support for victims&#8217; rights.&#160; Over the years, crime victims&#8217; rights have evolved.&#160; Dedicated professionals have worked to develop support and services for survivors&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Forty years ago, the President&#8217;s Task Force on Victims of Crime was established to help those who had experienced crime and their families &#8212; an important step toward the protection of and support for victims&#8217; rights.&nbsp; Over the years, crime victims&#8217; rights have evolved.&nbsp; Dedicated professionals have worked to develop support and services for survivors that are more holistic, trauma-informed, and effective at overcoming systemic barriers that certain communities face in prosecuting offenders and obtaining justice.&nbsp; However, more work remains to be done to&nbsp;advance these goals. &nbsp;During National Crime Victims&#8217; Rights Week, our Nation renews our commitment to providing survivors of crime the support they need to heal. &nbsp;We honor the dedicated victim service providers who support crime victims, and we continue to advance this important cause for all people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Delivering true justice requires that we provide all victims with the support they need.  Persistent barriers still prevent many survivors from receiving the services they need and the justice they deserve.  Many crimes &#8212; including violent crimes, such as rape and sexual assault &#8212; often go unreported to law enforcement because, among other concerns, victims fear placing themselves in further danger and negative interactions with the criminal justice system.  My Administration is also working to tackle the epidemic of gun violence, which is a public health and public safety crisis.  In the absence of necessary Congressional action, my Administration is taking action to get illegal guns &#8212; and those who would use them to commit crimes &#8212; off of our streets. </p>



<p>Victims of crime not only face physical and emotional costs, they often suffer a serious economic toll as well, and this is another area in which my Administration is making progress.  The Crime Victims Fund, established through the Victims of Crime Act (VOCA), helps provide critical resources for victim services and victim compensation programs throughout the country.  That is why, last July, I signed the VOCA Fix to Sustain the Crime Victim Fund Act into law to strengthen VOCA and increase the revenues to support survivors of crime and victim services organizations.  My Administration is supporting innovative programs like sexual assault telehealth services and hospital-based victim assistance, enabling providers to quickly reach more survivors and reduce repeated victimization.  I am also proud to have recently signed into law the reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act (VAWA), which funds programs that provide services to survivors of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.  This reauthorization of VAWA also expands the rights of victims of technology-facilitated gender-based violence and also includes historic Tribal provisions to protect Native communities and help them pursue justice. </p>



<p>Strengthening public safety also means addressing the trauma and inequality of victimization experienced by communities of color, Native American communities, the LGBTQI+ community, the Asian American community, and other historically marginalized groups.  People of color suffer higher rates of victimization, and violence is disproportionally concentrated in neighborhoods that have been harmed persistently by racial discrimination, segregation, redlining, and disinvestment.  Breaking the cycle of violence enhances public safety, public health, and equity.  We also know that members of the LGBTQI+ community are more likely to be victims of violent crime.  </p>



<p>My Administration is committed to using all tools at our disposal to ensure every survivor of crime has equal access to the resources and services they need to recover from their ordeals and regain a feeling of safety.  To address a surge in hate crimes and bias-motivated attacks &#8212; and to provide law enforcement with the resources to identify and investigate hate crimes, I signed the COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act into law.  As part of this law, we have funded a new Center for Culturally Responsive Victim Services to help local programs better serve historically marginalized communities.  </p>



<p> In addition to supporting crime victims, we must also hold offenders accountable.  That is why the Departments of Justice and Homeland Security are committed to investigating and enforcing our criminal and civil laws and ensuring that Federal, State, local, territorial, and Tribal law enforcement officers and prosecutors receive the training and resources they need to deliver justice to victims.</p>



<p> It takes enormous courage and extraordinary strength to emerge from life&#8217;s most painful moments.  As a Nation, let us all work together to stop crimes before they happen and to give victims the support they need to restore a sense of trust and safety and to move toward healing and justice.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 24 through April 30, 2022, National Crime Victims&#8217; Rights Week.  I call upon all Americans to observe this week by participating in events that raise awareness of victims&#8217; rights and services and by volunteering to serve victims in their time of need.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-second day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Appointments to Air Force and Military Academy&#160;Boards</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/22/president-biden-announces-appointments-to-air-force-and-military-academy-boards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles: Jenna Ben-Yehuda, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Air Force Academy Secretary Eric Kenneth Fanning, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Air Force Academy Major General James C. Johnson, USAF (Ret.), Member, Board of Visitors&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Jenna Ben-Yehuda, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Air Force Academy</li><li>Secretary Eric Kenneth Fanning, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Air Force Academy</li><li>Major General James C. Johnson, USAF (Ret.), Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Air Force Academy</li><li>Dr. Laura Junor-Pulzone, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Air Force Academy</li><li>Dr. Hila Levy, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Air Force Academy</li><li>Lieutenant Colonel Wesley Spurlock, USAF, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Air Force Academy</li><li>Lieutenant Colonel Roderick “Rico” Alvendia, USA (Ret.), Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Military Academy</li><li>Susan Christine Irons, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Military Academy</li><li>Dr. Leslie T. Fenwick, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Military Academy</li><li>Secretary Charles Timothy Hagel, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Military Academy</li><li>Juan A. Sabater, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Military Academy</li><li>Lieutenant General Nadja Yudith West, USA (Ret.), Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Military Academy</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>The Board of Visitors to the U.S. Air Force Academy</u></strong></p>



<p>The Board of Visitors to the U.S. Air Force Academy advises the Secretary of Defense and the Deputy Secretary of Defense, through the Secretary of the Air Force, and to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives independent advice and recommendations on the morale, discipline, and social climate, the curriculum, instruction, physical equipment, fiscal affairs, academic methods, and other matters relating to the Academy that the Board decides to consider. The Board consists of six members appointed by the President for terms of 3 years.</p>



<p><strong>Jenna Hoffman Ben-Yehuda as Member</strong></p>



<p>Jenna Hoffman Ben-Yehuda is the President and CEO of the Truman Center for National Policy and Truman National Security Project. A longtime advocate for gender equity in national security, she is the founder of the Women’s Foreign Policy Network, a global community of women in foreign affairs in over 100 countries. She earned multiple Superior and Meritorious Honor Awards during her twelve years at the US Department of State where she served in a range of intelligence and policy roles in the Western Hemisphere, including serving as Senior Military Advisor to US Northern Command, US Southern Command, and US Special Operations Command. A life member of the Council on Foreign Relations and member of the World Economic Forum’s Global Future’s Council on US National Security, she holds graduate degrees from the National Intelligence University, and National Defense University and undergraduate degrees from The George Washington University, where she later taught security studies at the Elliott School of International Affairs. She serves on the advisory boards of the Leadership Council for Women in National Security, the Partnership for Public Service, and GLOBSEC.</p>



<p><strong>Secretary Eric Kenneth Fanning as Member</strong></p>



<p>Eric Fanning is President and Chief Executive Officer of the Aerospace Industries Association (AIA), the leading advocacy organization for the aerospace and defense industry with nearly 350 companies in its membership. Fanning joined AIA after serving as the 22nd Secretary of the Army where he provided leadership and oversight of our nation’s largest military service. He previously served as Chief of Staff to the Secretary of Defense, Acting Secretary of the Air Force and Under Secretary of the Air Force, and Deputy Under Secretary of the Navy/Deputy Chief Management Officer. He is the only person to have held senior appointments in all three military departments and the Office of the Secretary of Defense. During his more than 25 years of distinguished government service, Fanning worked on the staff of the House Armed Services Committee, was Senior Vice President of Strategic Development for Business Executives for National Security, was Deputy Director of the Commission on the Prevention of Weapons of Mass Destruction Proliferation and Terrorism, and was associate director of political affairs at the White House. He holds a bachelor’s degree in history from Dartmouth College.</p>



<p><strong>Major General James C. Johnson as Member</strong></p>



<p>James C. Johnson is a senior executive with extensive leadership experience across operations, logistics, talent management, and human resilience. Following 30 years in the United States Air Force, James joined several nonprofit organizations, including Mission Readiness, the U.S. Global Leadership Coalition and he’s on the Board of Directors for The Flag and General Officer Network. Most recently, he served in the Department of Defense as a Highly Qualified Expert on the Independent Review Commission on Sexual Assault in the Military. As the Chief Executive Officer for Operation Gratitude, James leads a team of professionals and grass-roots volunteers and supporters, with the mission to honor the service of our military and first responders. James holds a Bachelor of Arts degree in Political Science from the University of Puget Sound, a Master of Business Administration degree from Saint Martin’s College, a Master of Arts degree in National Security and Strategic Studies from the U.S. Naval War College, and a Master of Science degree in National Resource Strategy from the Industrial College of the Armed Forces.</p>



<p><strong>Dr. Laura Junor Pulzone as Member</strong></p>



<p>Laura Junor Pulzone currently serves as the Director of the Institute for National Strategic Studies, Research at the National Defense University. As Director of INSS, she oversees three research centers and a publishing unit that provide direct analytic support to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and the Office of the Secretary of Defense. Prior to her arrival at NDU, Dr. Pulzone was confirmed as the Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness. As the Deputy, her responsibilities included all military and civilian personnel policies, the military healthcare system including TRICARE, family support services, the Defense Commissary Agency, the Department of Defense Education Activity, and department policy relating to suicide prevention and sexual assault. Dr. Pulzone previously served as the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Readiness, the Chief of Staff for Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation, and as a deputy team leader for readiness at the Center for Naval Analyses (CNA).</p>



<p><strong>Dr. Hila Levy as Member</strong></p>



<p>Hila Levy is a White House Fellow in the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and in parallel military and civilian careers, has worked in national security, international relations, science, and environmental management on every continent.&nbsp; As a Major serving in the US Air Force Reserve, Levy is an intelligence and foreign area officer, and has led teams at tactical, operational, and joint headquarters-level assignments in the Republic of Korea, Japan, the United Kingdom, Air Force Special Operations Command, and most recently, on the Joint Staff. She is a published scientific researcher, undergraduate educator, translator in six languages, and STEM advocate. In 2020, she advised the federal COVID-19 Joint Acquisition Task Force on viral diagnostics procurement to safeguard public health. Levy received a B.S. as the top graduate of the U.S. Air Force Academy and holds an M.Phil. from the School of Advanced Air and Space Studies, M.S. from Johns Hopkins University, and M.St., M.Sc. with Distinction, and D.Phil. from the University of Oxford, where she was the first Rhodes Scholar from Puerto Rico.</p>



<p><strong>Lieutenant Colonel</strong> <strong>Wesley Spurlock as Member</strong></p>



<p>Wesley Spurlock is an active duty Lieutenant Colonel in the United States Air Force currently assigned to the Department of the Air Force’s innovation arm, AFWERX, in Washington, DC. Prior to his current role, Wes served as a White House Fellow at the International Development Finance Corporation and the Domestic Policy Council. From 2015-2017, he served as the Military Aide to the President of the United States &amp; responsible for the Presidential Emergency Satchel (football). Wes also served as the first commander for the KC-46 Pegasus, and was charged with operationalizing the Air Force’s newest aircraft. He has more than 3,000 flying hours in various Air Force Aircraft and has served multiple overseas deployments, in support of Operations Enduring Freedom, Iraqi Freedom &amp; Unified Protector. Wes received a BS in Civil Engineering from the US Air Force Academy, an MBA from Mississippi State University and a MPA from Harvard’s Kennedy School of Government. He lives in Northern Virginia with his wife Jessica and their daughters Madison &amp; Quinn.</p>



<p><strong><u>The Board of Visitors to the U.S. Military Academy</u></strong></p>



<p>The Board of Visitors to the U.S. Military Academy provides independent advice and recommendations to the President of the United States on matters related to morale, discipline, curriculum, instruction, physical equipment, fiscal affairs, academic methods, and any other matters relating to the Academy that the Board decides to consider. The Board consists of six members appointed by the President for terms of 3 years.</p>



<p><strong>Lieutenant Colonel Roderick Alvendia as Member</strong></p>



<p>Roderick “Rico” Alvendia was born and raised in New Orleans, but he attended Jesuit High School in the Philippines when his Father served as a diplomat. He is a 1994 honor graduate of Loyola University in Political Science and a 1998 graduate of Loyola Law School in New Orleans, where in 2008 he was named the Moot Court Distinguished Alumni of the Year. He is the founding partner of the Alvendia, Kelly &amp; Demarest Law Firm in New Orleans. Lieutenant Colonel Alvendia served honorably for 25 years as an Officer in the U.S. Army JAG Corps and deployed to Baghdad, Iraq in 2004 with the 256th Infantry Brigade. In Baghdad, he led a team of international lawyers who successfully prosecuted enemy combatants who conducted fatal attacks on U.S. soldiers and civilians. Alvendia was awarded the Bronze Star Medal for his service during Combat Operations. Ten years ago, Lieutenant Colonel Alvendia co-founded the Legion of Mars, a Non-profit Veterans Organization, which has assisted thousands of deployed military members and their families throughout Louisiana. He is the proud Father of Noah Alvendia, who is attending the Isidore Newman School in New Orleans.</p>



<p><strong>Secretary Charles Timothy Hagel as Member</strong></p>



<p>Charles “Chuck” Hagel served as the 24th Secretary of Defense from 2013 to 2015. He is the only Vietnam Army veteran and enlisted combat veteran to serve as Secretary of Defense.&nbsp; He represented the state of Nebraska in the U.S. Senate for two terms from 1997 to 2009. Previously, Secretary Hagel was Co-Chairman of the President’s Intelligence Advisory Board, Deputy Administrator of the Veterans Administration, a Distinguished Professor at Georgetown University, Chairman of the Atlantic Council, Chairman of the United States of America Vietnam War Commemoration Advisory Committee, Co-Chairman of the Vietnam Veterans Memorial Fund Corporate Council, President and CEO of the USO, The Private Sector Council, and co-founder of Vanguard Cellular Systems, Inc.&nbsp; He is a graduate of the University of Nebraska at Omaha.</p>



<p><strong>Susan Irons as Member</strong></p>



<p>Susan Irons graduated from the United States Military Academy in 1989 and was commissioned in the Army as a Signal Corps officer. Shortly after commissioning, she deployed to Saudi Arabia and Iraq in support of Desert Shield/Desert Storm. Susan has continued her service to others and works as a County Veterans Service Officer in South Dakota and as a board member on the South Dakota Board of Military Affairs. Additionally, she has served as an advisor for the West Point Association of Graduates Advisory Council for four years. Three of Susan&#8217;s five children are carrying on the Army tradition with a daughter graduating from West Point in 2020 and two that are also currently serving on active duty as enlisted soldiers.</p>



<p><strong>Dr. Leslie T. Fenwick as Member</strong></p>



<p>Leslie T. Fenwick, PhD, is noted for her expertise in leadership and ethics; public policy; and diversity, equity and inclusion (DEI) in the workforce. She is Dean Emerita of the Howard University School of Education and a tenured professor of leadership studies and education policy. A nationally-recognized scholar, Dr. Fenwick is a former Harvard University Visiting Fellow and Visiting Scholar, and Salzburg Global Fellow. Since 2017, Dr. Fenwick has been engaged at the U.S. Military Academy at West Point as a McDonald Conference for Leaders of Character Senior Fellow, the 2019 Corbin Distinguished Lecturer, and the 2017 Black History Month Lecturer. She has delivered hundreds of national and international invited and distinguished lectures on equity, leadership, and ethics to convenings for college/university leaders, elected officials and government agencies, and corporate CEOs and senior leaders. Author of the best-selling book, <em>Jim Crow’s Pink Slip</em> (Harvard Education Press, 2022), Dr. Fenwick earned her PhD at The Ohio State University and her bachelor’s degree at the University of Virginia.</p>



<p><strong>Juan A. Sabater as Member</strong></p>



<p>Juan A. Sabater is Co-President and Partner of Valor Equity Partners, a growth focused private equity firm headquartered in Chicago, Illinois.&nbsp; Juan also is Co-Chairman of the Board of Augeo Affinity Marketing, which he has helped to build with his business partner. In addition to his Valor and Augeo responsibilities, Juan serves on the Board of Directors of several charitable organizations in New York City, Puerto Rico and nationally. He is the Co-President of the Board of The Hewitt School and sits on the Advisory Boards of Columbia University’s School of International and Public Affairs and the Princeton University Arts Museum.&nbsp; He also served as Co-Chair of the University of Chicago Parent and Family Program.&nbsp; Juan holds an A.B. in History from Princeton University. He studied history at the University of Oxford, Mansfield College and holds a J.D. from Stanford Law School. He is formerly an officer in the United States Army Reserve.</p>



<p><strong>Lieutenant General Nadja Yudith West as Member</strong></p>



<p>Nadja West (USMA ’82) is the 44th Army Surgeon General and the former Commanding General of U.S. Army Medical Command. &nbsp;A graduate of The George Washington School of Medicine, West completed residencies in Family Medicine and Dermatology and held various clinical, operational and leadership positions throughout her over 30-year career as a soldier. West serves on several non-profit, public and private boards. She is also a trustee of Mount St. Mary’s University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/22/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Cindy Dyer, Nominee for Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, with rank of Ambassador at Large Michael Gonzales, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Zambia Michael Ratney,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Cindy Dyer, Nominee for Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, with rank of Ambassador at Large</li><li>Michael Gonzales, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Zambia</li><li>Michael Ratney, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia</li><li>Geoffrey Pyatt, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of State for Energy Resources</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Cindy Dyer, Nominee for Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, with rank of Ambassador at Large</u></strong></p>



<p>Cindy Dyer is a human rights expert and lawyer with over 25 years of experience working at the local, national, and international levels to address human rights abuses with a focus on human trafficking, gender-based violence (GBV), and harmful practices. She recently served on the Independent Review Commission on Sexual Assault in the Military, and is currently a Senior Advisor and Highly Qualified Expert (HQE) at the U.S. Department of Defense. For 12 years, she was the Vice President for Human Rights at Vital Voices Global Partnership, an international NGO advancing women’s leadership. Prior to joining Vital Voices, she served in a presidential appointment as the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women within the U.S. Department of Justice. She began her career at the local level, serving as a specialized domestic and sexual violence prosecutor in Dallas, Texas for more than 13 years.</p>



<p>Dyer is the recipient of the Equal Justice Award from Legal Services of North Texas and the Prosecutor of the Year Award from the Greater Dallas Crime Commission. Dyer earned her Bachelor’s degree from Texas A&amp;M and her J.D. from Baylor Law School.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Michael Gonzales, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Zambia</u></strong></p>



<p>Michael C. Gonzales is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor. He currently serves as a Deputy Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of African Affairs in the U.S. Department of State. Prior to this assignment, Gonzales was the Director of Analysis of Africa in the State Department’s Bureau of Intelligence and Research. Overseas, he held leadership positions as the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Kathmandu, Nepal and of the U.S. Embassy in Lilongwe, Malawi; and as the Political and Economic Counselor of the U.S. Embassies in Harare, Zimbabwe and Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. Among other assignments, Gonzales served as Spokesperson and Information Officer at the U.S Embassy in Addis Ababa; Ethiopia Desk Officer in the State Department; and Deputy Public Affairs Officer of the U.S. Embassy in Kampala, Uganda.</p>



<p>Gonzales earned a B.A. Degree from Occidental College in Los Angeles, California and an M.A. Degree from American University’s School of International Service in Washington, D.C. He speaks Spanish and French.</p>



<p><strong><u>Michael Ratney, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia</u></strong></p>



<p>Michael Alan Ratney, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, is the Acting Deputy Director of the U.S. Department of State’s Foreign Service Institute. He recently served as Chargé d’Affaires a.i. at the U.S. Embassy in Jerusalem. Previously, Ratney was the Dean of the School of Language Studies at the Foreign Service Institute. Prior to that, he was on the faculty of the National Defense University. He served as the State Department’s Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary for the Levant and Israel and Palestinian Affairs, and was the U.S. Special Envoy for Syria. Earlier, Ratney was the U.S. Consul General in Jerusalem. He was Deputy Assistant Secretary for International Media in the State Department’s Bureau of Public Affairs. Prior to that, he served as Spokesman for the State Department’s Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs. Other assignments include serving as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Doha, Qatar, as well as tours in Mexico City, Baghdad, Beirut, Casablanca, Bridgetown, and Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>Ratney earned a B.S. from Boston University and an M.A. from the George Washington University. He is the recipient of multiple State Department performance awards, including a Presidential Meritorious Service award. He speaks Arabic and French.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Geoffrey Pyatt, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of State for Energy Resources</u></strong></p>



<p>Geoffrey R. Pyatt, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Career Minister, currently serves as U.S. Ambassador to Greece, a position he has held since 2016. Before that, Pyatt was U.S. Ambassador to Ukraine, and he was Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs. Previously, he served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Mission to the International Atomic Energy Agency and International Organizations in Vienna, Austria. He also served at the U.S. Embassy in New Delhi, India as Deputy Chief of Mission and as Political Counselor. Pyatt served as Economic Officer at the U.S. Consulate General in Hong Kong and as Principal Officer at the U.S. Consulate General in Lahore, Pakistan. Since joining the Foreign Service in 1989, Pyatt has also served as Director for Latin America at the National Security Council, as Special Assistant in the Office of the Deputy Secretary of State, in the Bureau of Inter-American Affairs, and at the U.S. Embassy in New Delhi, India and U.S. Embassy in Tegucigalpa, Honduras.</p>



<p>Pyatt is the recipient of numerous performance awards, including a Presidential Distinguished Honor Award. He earned a B.A. from the University of California at Irvine and an M.A. from Yale University. A native of California, he speaks Spanish.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Five New Nominees to Serve as U.S.&#160;Attorneys</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/22/president-biden-announces-five-new-nominees-to-serve-as-u-s-attorneys/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 18:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is announcing five new nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys across the country, as wel as three new nominees to serve as U.S. Marshals. These are officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law as top federal law enforcement officials. These individuals were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is announcing five new nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys across the country, as wel as three new nominees to serve as U.S. Marshals. These are officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law as top federal law enforcement officials.</p>



<p>These individuals were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the law, their professionalism, their experience and credentials in this field, their dedication to pursuing equal justice for all, and their commitment to the independence of the Department of Justice.</p>



<p>The President has proposed a budget that would significantly increase funding for law enforcement as part of a comprehensive approach to tackling the rising crime rate this administration inherited last year.</p>



<p>The President has also launched a comprehensive effort to take on the uptick in gun crime that has been taking place since 2020—putting more cops on the beat, supporting community prevention programs, and cracking down on illegal gun trafficking. Confirming U.S. Attorneys as the chief federal law enforcement officers in their district is important for these efforts.</p>



<p>The President has now announced 48 nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys, and 5 nominees to serve as U.S. Marshals.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong>U.S. Attorney Nominees</strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Rachelle L. Crowe: United States Attorney Nominee for the Southern District of Illinois</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Rachelle L. Crowe has served as the State Senator for Illinois’s 56th District since 2019. From 2006 to 2018, she served as an Assistant State’s Attorney in the Madison County State’s Attorney’s Office in the Violent Crimes, General Felony and Juvenile Abuse units. She was previously an associate at three law firms: Carmody MacDonald P.C. from 2004 to 2006, Riezman Berger from 2002 to 2004, and Hoagland, Fitzgerald, Smith &amp; Praintis from 2000 to 2002. Ms. Crowe received her J.D. from Saint Louis University School of Law in 2000 and her B.A. from the University of Missouri in St. Louis in 1996.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>Joshua D. Hurwit: United States Attorney Nominee for the District of Idaho</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Joshua D. Hurwit has served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Idaho since 2012. Mr. Hurwit was previously an associate at three law firms: Covington &amp; Burling LLP from 2011 to 2012, Kirkland &amp; Ellis LLP from 2008 to 2011, and Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton &amp; Garrison LLP from 2006 to 2007. Mr. Hurwit served as a law clerk for Judge Naomi Reice Buchwald on the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York from 2007 to 2008. Mr. Hurwit received his J.D. from Harvard Law School in 2006 and his B.A. from Stanford University in 2002.</p>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong><u>Gerard M. Karam: United States Attorney Nominee for the Middle District of Pennsylvania</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Gerard M. Karam is a partner at the law firm of Mazzoni Karam Petorak and Valvano, where he has practiced since 1995. His practice focuses on complex civil and criminal litigation. From 1997 to 2001, he served as a member of the Criminal Justice Act Panel for the United States District Court for the Middle District of Pennsylvania. Mr. Karam served as the Chief Public Defender of Lackawanna County, Pennsylvania from 1993 to 2003 and as an Assistant Public Defender in the same office from 1991 to 1993. From 1987 to 1995, Mr. Karam was a sole practitioner. Mr. Karam received his J.D. from Loyola University School of Law in 1987 and his B.S. from Saint Joseph’s University in 1984.</p>



<ol type="1" start="4"><li><strong><u>Jacqueline C. Romero: United States Attorney Nominee for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Jacqueline C. Romero has served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania since 2006. Ms. Romero served as a Senior Counsel to the United States Mint from 2000 to 2006. She previously served as a Trial Attorney in the Commercial Litigation Branch of the United States Department of Justice from 1998 to 2000. She was an associate at Lowenstein Sandler LLP from 1996 to 1998. Ms. Romero received her J.D. from Rutgers Law School in 1996 and her B.A. from the College of New Jersey in 1993.</p>



<ol type="1" start="5"><li><strong><u>Phillip A. Talbert: United States Attorney Nominee for the Eastern District of California</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Phillip A. Talbert has served as the Attorney General-appointed United States Attorney for the Eastern District of California since December 2021, a position he also held from 2016 to 2017. He joined the United States Attorney’s Office in 2002 as an Assistant United States Attorney. From 1996 to 2002, Mr. Talbert served as an Assistant Counsel and Associate Counsel for the United States Department of Justice Office of Professional Responsibility.&nbsp;From 1993 to 1996, he was an associate at Stoel, Rives, Boley, Jones &amp; Grey.&nbsp;From 1990 to 1993, Mr. Talbert served as a Trial Attorney in the Criminal Division of the United States Department of Justice.&nbsp;From 1989 to 1990, Mr. Talbert served as a law clerk for Judge David R. Thompson on the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. Talbert received his J.D. from the UCLA School of Law in 1989, his M.Ec. with honors from the University of Sydney in 1987, and his A.B., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from Harvard University in 1984.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>U.S. Marshal Nominees</strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Michael M. Contrades: United States Marshal Nominee for the District of Hawai</u></strong>‘<strong>i</strong></li></ol>



<p>Michael M. Contrades has served as a Field Representative for the Office of Congressman Kaiali‘i Kahele on the island of Kaua‘i since 2021. Mr. Contrades is also a Capital Improvement Project Coordinator for the County of Kaua‘i and served as a Legislative Liason for the County of Kaua‘i in 2020. Mr. Contrades previously served in the County of Kaua‘i Police Department from 1994 to 2019. He held numerous leadership positions while at the department, including Acting Chief of Police from 2018 to 2019, Deputy Chief of Police from 2011 to 2018, and Captain from 2010 to 2011. Mr. Contrades received his B.S. from Bethel University College of Public Service in 2014.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>David C. Davis: United States Marshal Nominee for the Southern District of Illinois</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>David C. Davis has served as a Task Force Officer for the Illinois State Police Department since 2017. From 1994 to 2016, Mr. Davis worked for the United States Marshals Service, where he served as Supervisory Deputy United States Marshal from 2014 to 2016, Criminal Investigator from 2005 to 2014, Witness Security Inspector from 2003 to 2004, and Deputy United States Marshal from 1994 to 2004. Mr. Davis received his M.A. from Webster University in 2018 and his B.A. from University of Missouri at St. Louis in 1985.</p>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong><u>Enix Smith III: United States Marshal Nominee for the Eastern District of Louisiana</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Enix Smith III served in the Office of Congressman Cedric L. Richmond from 2011 to 2021. He served as Chief of Staff and Deputy Chief of Staff from 2015 to 2021, Law Enforcement Coordinator from 2011 to 2021, and District Director in 2011. Mr. Smith previously worked as a Quality Control Supervisor for Quadel Consulting Corporation from 2006 to 2010 and as a Field Supervisor for Eagle Environment from 2005 to 2006. He was the Program Site Administrator for the Louisiana Community Developers, Inc. from 2002 to 2005 and the Assistant Director for New Orleans Community Enhancement, Inc. from 2002 to 2005. Mr. Smith was previously a teacher for New Orleans Public Schools from 1998 to 2005. Mr. Smith received his B.A. from Xavier University in 1998.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Senior Administration Travel to Hawaii, Fiji, Papua New Guinea, and Solomon&#160;Islands</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/22/readout-of-senior-administration-travel-to-hawaii-fiji-papua-new-guinea-and-solomon-islands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 15:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 22, a high-level U.S. delegation – led by National Security Council Indo-Pacific Coordinator Kurt Campbell, Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink, Deputy Commander INDOPACOM&#160;Lieutenant General&#160;Stephen Sklenka , and USAID Acting Senior Deputy Assistant Administrator for Asia Craig Hart – visited Honiara, Solomon Islands. The delegation met for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On April 22, a high-level U.S. delegation – led by National Security Council Indo-Pacific Coordinator Kurt Campbell, Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink, Deputy Commander INDOPACOM&nbsp;Lieutenant General&nbsp;Stephen Sklenka , and USAID Acting Senior Deputy Assistant Administrator for Asia Craig Hart – visited Honiara, Solomon Islands. The delegation met for ninety minutes with Prime Minister&nbsp;Manasseh&nbsp;Sogavare, along with two dozen members of his cabinet and senior staff. While there, the delegation also met with prominent religious leaders on the island and with key members of the political opposition.</p>



<p>This visit to&nbsp;Solomon Islands was the final leg of the delegation’s trip across the Pacific. It followed stops in Hawaii, where the delegation met with senior officials from Australia,&nbsp;Japan,&nbsp;and New Zealand; Fiji, where they met with Prime Minister&nbsp;Frank&nbsp;Bainimarama, as well as&nbsp;leadership of the Pacific Island Forum, and held the&nbsp;U.S.-Fiji Strategic Dialogue; and Papua New Guinea, where they met with Prime Minister James Marape and senior defense officials to discuss ways to enhance security ties. Across these engagements, the United States reiterated that it will seek to further deepen our enduring ties with&nbsp;the Pacific Islands&nbsp;and take tangible&nbsp;steps to advance a free, open, and resilient Indo-Pacific. The United States will do so by fulfilling and strengthening its commitments in the region, working to advance regional unity, coordinating with allies and partners on meeting twenty-first century challenges, and protecting the sovereignty of Pacific Island states.</p>



<p>In the meeting with Solomon Islands’ Prime Minister Sogavare, the delegation reiterated the key priorities animating the trip and also outlined specific steps&nbsp;the United States&nbsp;would take to advance the welfare of the people of&nbsp;Solomon Islands. The United States will expedite the opening of an embassy in&nbsp;Solomon Islands; advance cooperation on unexploded ordinance; launch a program on maritime domain awareness; dispatch the Mercy hospital ship to address public health; advance a dialogue on the return of the Peace Corps; deliver additional vaccines;&nbsp;and advance initiatives on&nbsp;climate, health,&nbsp;and people-to-people ties.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States respects the right of nations to make sovereign decisions in the best interests of their people. The two sides engaged in substantial discussion around the recently&nbsp;signed&nbsp;security agreement between&nbsp;Solomon Islands and the People’s Republic of China (PRC). Solomon Islands representatives indicated that the agreement had solely domestic applications, but the&nbsp;U.S. delegation noted&nbsp;there are potential regional security implications of the accord, including for the United States and its allies and partners. The U.S. delegation outlined clear areas of concern with respect to the purpose, scope, and transparency of the agreement.</p>



<p>If steps are taken to establish a de facto permanent military presence, power-projection capabilities, or a military installation, the delegation noted that the United States would then have significant concerns and respond accordingly. In response to these enumerated concerns, Prime Minister Sogavare reiterated his specific assurances that there would be no military base, no long-term presence, and no power projection capability, as he has said publicly. The United States emphasized that it will follow developments closely in consultation with regional partners.</p>



<p>At this critical juncture, the United States and Solomon Islands agreed to launch a high-level strategic dialogue, co-chaired on the U.S. side by the White House and the Department of State. Its purpose will be to enhance communication, address mutual concerns, and drive practical progress. In particular, both sides agreed to discuss in greater detail security issues of mutual concern, economic and social development, public health, and finance and debt. Each side committed to take the necessary steps in the intervening period to prepare for a successful engagement.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Signs Executive Order to Strengthen America&#8217;s Forests, Boost Wildfire Resilience, and Combat Global&#160;Deforestation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/22/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-to-strengthen-americas-forests-boost-wildfire-resilience-and-combat-global-deforestation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New actions will protect against wildfire threats, support local economies, and reduce climate pollution Today, on Earth Day, President Biden will sign an Executive Order to expand his Administration’s historic and bold efforts to tackle the climate crisis, make our nation more resilient to extreme weather, and strengthen local economies. The President will sign the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>New actions will protect against wildfire threats, support local economies, and reduce climate pollution</em></p>



<p>Today, on Earth Day, President Biden will sign an Executive Order to expand his Administration’s historic and bold efforts to tackle the climate crisis, make our nation more resilient to extreme weather, and strengthen local economies. The President will sign the Executive Order in Seattle, Washington—rounding out a trip across the West focused on lowering costs for families and protecting communities from intensifying climate impacts. Wildfires and extreme weather events are growing in frequency and ferocity, engulfing communities in the West and across the country and costing lives, homes, and money. Because President Biden knows the cost of inaction is too great, he is taking bold executive action and reaffirming his calls on Congress to address the climate crisis. &nbsp;</p>



<p>America’s forests are a key climate solution, absorbing carbon dioxide equivalent to more than 10% of U.S. annual greenhouse gas emissions. Federal lands are home to many of the nation’s mature and old-growth forests, which serve as critical carbon sinks, cherished landscapes, and unique habitats. However, these magnificent ecosystems are threatened by the climate impacts that are already here, with intensifying wildfires demanding urgent action to protect our forests and the economies that depend on them. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides historic wildfire resilience funding and calls for prioritizing the restoration of old-growth forests.</p>



<p>Building on this directive and the Administration’s commitment to climate-smart forest stewardship, today’s Executive Order will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Safeguard mature and old-growth forests on federal lands</strong>, as part of a science-based approach to reduce wildfire risk.</li><li><strong>Strengthen reforestation partnerships across the country</strong> to support local economies and ensure we retain forest ecosystems and sustainable supplies of forest products for years to come.</li><li><strong>Combat global deforestation</strong> to deliver on key COP26 commitments.</li><li><strong>Enlist nature to address the climate crisis</strong> with comprehensive efforts to deploy nature-based solutions that reduce emissions and build resilience.</li></ul>



<p>Across these efforts, the Administration will leverage historic investments from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and the FY 2022 budget, and work in partnership with states, Tribal Nations, communities, industry, NGOs, labor, scientists, and private landowners, to strengthen our forests while creating good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>Today’s Executive Order will advance the Biden-Harris Administration’s climate goals and economic agenda by:</p>



<p><strong><u>Reducing Wildfire Risk</u></strong></p>



<p>Under President Biden’s leadership, the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s (USDA) Forest Service has developed a <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/01/18/secretary-vilsack-announces-new-10-year-strategy-confront-wildfire">10-year strategy</a> to reduce wildfire risk through science-based fuels and forest health treatments, with a goal of treating an additional 50 million acres across federal and non-federal lands. The Department of the Interior (DOI) has also developed a <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-releases-five-year-monitoring-maintenance-and-treatment-plan">5-year plan</a> for monitoring, maintenance, and treatment efforts focused on fire-prone Interior and Tribal lands.</p>



<p>As a critical down payment, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides $8 billion to fund forest and land management activities, and the FY 2022 Omnibus provides $5.7 billion for wildland fire management and related risk mitigation and research. USDA and DOI are mobilizing $5 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law for hazardous fuels reduction and other mitigation programs, such as a $1 billion Community Wildfire Defense Grant program and $600 million for firefighter pay—providing about 1,500 additional firefighters and supporting the President’s commitment that no federal firefighter will make less than $15 an hour. Already, USDA has <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/news/releases/biden-administration-announces-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-wildfire-mitigation">announced</a> $131 million this year for wildfire risk reduction treatments in high-risk landscapes in Washington, Oregon, California, Idaho, Montana, Colorado, New Mexico, and Arizona.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law directs DOI and USDA to specifically prioritize the restoration of old-growth forests, taking into consideration their contributions to landscape fire adaptation. However, there is currently no inventory that identifies the location and condition of mature and old-growth stands.</p>



<p><strong><em>To strengthen America’s forests and advance a holistic, science-based approach to wildfire resilience and forest restoration, this Executive Order advances action on: &nbsp;</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Data Collection and Analysis:</strong> DOI and USDA will conduct the first-ever inventory of mature and old-growth forests on federal lands. This will be completed and made publicly available in a year and will establish consistent definitions, accounting for regional and ecological variation. The agencies will then analyze threats facing these forests, including from wildfires and other climate impacts.</li><li><strong>Climate-Smart Stewardship:</strong> After completing the inventory, DOI and USDA will develop new policies, with robust opportunity for public comment, to institutionalize climate-smart management and conservation strategies that address the threats facing mature and old-growth forests on federal lands.</li><li><strong>Enhanced Coordination: </strong>DOI and USDA will partner with other federal agencies, states, Tribal Nations, and any interested private landowners to better coordinate conservation and wildfire risk reduction efforts—leveraging investments from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and other sources.</li></ul>



<p>Going forward, the Administration will work with Congress to secure additional resources, by requesting $6.1 billion for wildfire risk reduction in the President’s FY 2023 Budget and continuing to pursue historic climate resilience investments in additional legislation.</p>



<p><strong><u>Strengthening Forests for Thriving Local Economies</u></strong></p>



<p>America’s forests provide millions of jobs and underpin local economies, particularly in rural communities. The Biden-Harris Administration is mobilizing historic resources to help these forests and communities thrive. For example, the Administration’s Building a Better America Rural Infrastructure Tour is <a href="https://www.usda.gov/sites/default/files/documents/usda-rural-fact-sheet.pdf">highlighting</a> wide-ranging support for healthy forest economies, including: planning assistance to boost outdoor recreation economies; support for Tribes, local governments, and conservation non-profits to establish community forests that create jobs; and grants to expand markets for innovative wood products and wood energy that support sustainable forest management.</p>



<p>Through the FY 2022 Omnibus, the Administration is also investing $162 million in cooperative forestry programs across State, municipal, and privately-owned forest landscapes. Additionally, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law significantly expands reforestation projects on National Forest land—enough to plant an estimated 1.2 billion trees and sequester 75 million metric tons of carbon, all while supporting thousands of jobs.</p>



<p><strong><em>The Executive Order will build on these efforts by advancing:</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Economic Opportunities in Outdoor Recreation and Sustainable Forest Products: </strong>The Departments of Agriculture, Commerce, and the Interior will work with state, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, as well as the private sector, nonprofit organizations, labor unions, and the scientific community, to advance forest-related economic opportunities at the local and regional levels. These community-led opportunities will create and sustain jobs in outdoor recreation and in sustainable wood, paper, and other forest products, while supporting healthy, sustainably managed forests in timber communities.<br><br></li><li><strong>Reforestation Partnerships: </strong>The Administration will develop agency-specific 2030 targets for reforestation, including the use of partnerships to advance these goals beyond federal lands to enable our future forests to be more resilient to climate change and wildfire, while also supporting healthy forest economies for years to come.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Seed and Nursery Capacity:</strong><a> </a>USDA and DOI will address a longstanding seed shortfall by developing a plan, in partnership with states, Tribes, and the private sector, to boost federal cone and seed collection and seedling nursery capacity. These actions will support tree-planting efforts by a range of public and private partners. Expanding seed and nursery capacity is especially important for timberlands in the West that have been devastated by wildfire and need to be re-planted.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Combatting Global Deforestation</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden has committed to help deliver on global goals to end natural forest loss by 2030, while restoring at least an additional 200 million hectares of forests and other ecosystems. At the COP26 international climate conference, President Biden announced the “<a href="https://www.state.gov/plan-to-conserve-global-forests-critical-carbon-sinks/">Plan to Conserve Global Forests: Critical Carbon Sinks</a>”—harnessing U.S. diplomatic, policy, and financing tools, in partnership with other countries, Indigenous and local forest communities, the private sector, and civil society, and with a focus on three critical areas of global importance: the Amazon, Congo, and Southeast Asian forests.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>To further advance these efforts and achieve the President’s international commitments, this Executive Order directs the Department of State, in coordination with other agencies, to prepare reports to the President on whole-of-government approaches to stopping global deforestation and restoring lands, including:</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Combat Commodity-Driven Deforestation:</strong> A major driver of global deforestation is forest clearing to produce agricultural commodities like beef, soy, and palm oil. To combat those practices, the Department of State will lead development of a report on whole-of-government approaches to reduce or eliminate U.S. purchases of agricultural commodities grown on illegally or recently deforested lands, including through public-private partnerships to incentivize sustainable sourcing. These efforts will not only protect forests and human rights abroad, but also provide a level playing field for responsible agricultural producers at home.</li><li><strong>Support Sustainable Forest Management Around the World:</strong> The Department of State will coordinate with other agencies to assess the broader use of foreign assistance, trade tools, finance, and international partnerships to combat deforestation and support sustainable forest management around the world, with special attention to the critical role played by Indigenous peoples and local communities and landholders in conserving and restoring forests.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Enlisting Nature in the Fight Against Climate Change</u></strong></p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has led the way on enhancing nature’s ability to support the health, wellbeing, and economic security of all Americans. President Biden launched the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-celebrates-expansion-of-locally-led-conservation-efforts-in-first-year-of-america-the-beautiful-initiative/">America the Beautiful initiative</a> to support his goal of conserving at least 30 percent of U.S. lands and waters by 2030. Interagency Working Groups reporting to the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/climate/">National Climate Task Force</a> are exploring nature-based solutions to address extreme heat, drought, wildfire, flood, and coastal threats. The Administration is also recognizing the value of and elevating <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2021/11/15/white-house-commits-to-elevating-indigenous-knowledge-in-federal-policy-decisions/">Indigenous Traditional Ecological Knowledge</a> across federal scientific and policy processes. The President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides—as part of over $50 billion in historic resilience investments—funding for nature-based solutions, including $2.3 billion for the Forest Service and Interior to advance ecosystem restoration and resilience.</p>



<p>To facilitate use of these and other resources, today the National Climate Task Force’s<a href="https://www.noaa.gov/coastal-resilience-interagency-working-group"> Coastal Resilience Interagency Working Group</a>, co-led by the White House Council on Environmental Quality and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, is releasing a <strong><a href="https://www.noaa.gov/sites/default/files/2022-04/Nature-based-Solutions-Compendium.pdf">Compendium of Federal Nature-Based Solutions for Coastal Communities, States, Tribes, and Territories</a></strong>—streamlining access to more than 100 information resources and 48 federal programs that can support nature-based solutions in coastal areas.  </p>



<p><strong><em>To further amplify the power of nature, including its ability to absorb climate pollution and increase resilience in all communities, today’s Executive Order calls for the following:<br></em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Report on Nature-Based Solutions:</strong> As reaffirmed this year by the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2022/02/28/statements-from-the-white-house-office-on-science-and-technology-policy-ostp-on-the-intergovernmental-panel-on-climate-changes-working-group-ii-report/">Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change</a>, nature-based solutions will play a key role in achieving net-zero emissions and building resilience to climate impacts. Building on ongoing efforts, the White House Council on Environmental Quality, Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), and Office of Domestic Climate Policy will work with agencies to develop a report to the National Climate Task Force on key opportunities for greater deployment of nature-based solutions—everything from restoring marshes, to planting shade trees, to promoting drought-resistant crops.</li><li><strong>Guidance on Valuing Nature: </strong>The Office of Management and Budget will issue valuation guidance to help agencies better account for services provided by ecosystems and the environment (such as pollinators supporting our crops, or forests cleaning our air and water). In support, OSTP and the Department of Commerce will continue leading an interagency initiative to improve and update baseline information on the economic value of our existing natural assets and new nature-based solutions.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>First U.S. National Nature Assessment:</strong> The United States lacks comprehensive knowledge of the state of our nation’s lands, waters, and wildlife and the specific benefits that they provide. To create this comprehensive picture, the 13-agency U.S. Global Change Research Program will develop the first-ever assessment of the condition of nature within the United States. The assessment will also allow us to look ahead at how nature might change in the future and identify opportunities for investments in nature to help achieve our climate, health, environmental justice, and economic goals.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris During a Tour of the William J. Rutter&#160;Center</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-during-a-tour-of-the-william-j-rutter-center/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 02:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51598</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UCSF Mission Bay Medical CenterSan Francisco, California THE VICE PRESIDENT: But I&#8217;m so looking forward to our conversations. But you all just have to know, we applaud and thank you. We are so grateful for what you all do. And you know, we were just talking about it &#8212; it takes a lot to do&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>UCSF Mission Bay Medical Center<br><em>San Francisco, California</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT: But I&#8217;m so looking forward to our conversations. But you all just have to know, we applaud and thank you. We are so grateful for what you all do. And you know, we were just talking about it &#8212; it takes a lot to do the work that that you all do, and it can be quite painful because you see so much pain and you care so deeply.<br><br>And in spite of all of that, you all are about empowerment, about recognizing &#8212; not giving but recognizing the dignity and fighting for the rights.<br><br>And it&#8217;s extraordinary the gift that you have and that you give. And so, I wanted to come here today &#8212; and with the Administrator &#8212; so we could talk with you, we can visit with you so we can talk about you as we travel around the country.<br><br>Because, you know, we were talking earlier about it. When we&#8217;re fighting for the ability of women and their families and their community to receive all that they are entitled to receive, it&#8217;s important that we also let them know that they are not alone. And that&#8217;s part of telling the stories.<br><br>It is also about letting them know and see what the solution looks like so that they don&#8217;t have to ever have an experience of wondering whether it is even possible that they would be treated with dignity and receive what is necessary for them to have a joyful and healthy experience and be seen in the full totality of who they are.<br><br>So, by being here today and lifting up and sharing what you all are doing here, we&#8217;re going to be talking with women you all will never meet, will probably never even know your names or mine, but who will benefit from what you all are doing here on the ground. So, I just want to thank you all so very much.<br><br>And with that, why don’t we begin our conversation.<br><br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Democratic National Committee&#160;Fundraiser</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-democratic-national-committee-fundraiser-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Private ResidenceSeattle, Washington 6:29 P.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; First of all, every time I’m here, I don&#8217;t want to go home, Jay.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; My Lord.&#160; Look, first of all, Mary, Spencer, and Brad and Kathy, thank you.&#160; Thank you for hosting me.&#160; And almost every one of you has &#8212; or part of the reason&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Private Residence<br>Seattle, Washington</p>



<p>6:29 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; First of all, every time I’m here, I don&#8217;t want to go home, Jay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; My Lord.&nbsp; Look, first of all, Mary, Spencer, and Brad and Kathy, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for hosting me.&nbsp; And almost every one of you has &#8212; or part of the reason why I&#8217;m standing here in the first place as the President of the United States &#8212; you&#8217;ve all been an enormous help.</p>



<p>And the thing I want to mention is that, in all the help you give me, not one of you have ever called and asked for a favor.&nbsp; I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; Not one of you have ever called and said, “Now you’re President.&nbsp; Can I get boom, boom, boom?”&nbsp; Not one.</p>



<p>And the way you do it with such honor, integrity.&nbsp; And so many of the philanthropies that some of you run &#8212; always doing this good, decent work for people.</p>



<p>You know, when I ran, I was &#8212; I won’t say “criticized” &#8212; people thought I wasn&#8217;t &#8212; my rationale for running was not one that would carry much weight in terms of the body politic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I said I was running for three reasons.&nbsp; One, to restore the soul of the country and to restore a sense of decency and honor to the &#8212; to the United States of America in terms of the presidency.&nbsp; Because the president and the White House was looked at by many people around the world as what America is about.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not; it&#8217;s much bigger &#8212; bigger &#8212; bigger than that.</p>



<p>But &#8212; and the second thing I said was that I wanted to rebuild the economy &#8212; the backbone of the economy, which I believe to be the middle class.&nbsp; Because if the middle class does well, the poor have a way up and the wealthy still do very well.&nbsp; Everybody does better when everybody is in on the deal.</p>



<p>And the third thing was &#8212; that’s turning &#8212; that I was roundly and justifiably criticized for was saying I want to unite the country.&nbsp; Because no democracy can be sustained without the informed consent of the American people.&nbsp; We’ve got to bring them together.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a tough thing.</p>



<p>And so, one of the things that I found is that I’m reminded every day why elections matter.&nbsp; And I just cite two generic examples of why I say that.&nbsp; Number one &#8212; and the press has heard me say this, so I apologize to the press for my repeating this, but I believe it &#8212; is that, Gov, I think, in the year 2020 and beyond, we&#8217;re in the battle between democracies and autocracies.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve had long discussions and over many, many hours &#8212; I mean, literally, over &#8212; I think it&#8217;s now up to 70-some hours with Xi Jinping.&nbsp; We traveled 17,000 miles.&nbsp; And he doesn’t have a democratic &#8212; with a small “d” &#8212; bone in his body.&nbsp; He’s a very smart and calculating guy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he&#8217;s just very straightforward with me.&nbsp; He doesn&#8217;t think that democracies can be sustained in the 21st century, in the second quarter of the century, because things are moving so rapidly, so incredibly fast that only &#8212; he doesn&#8217;t say “autocracy” &#8212; only autocracies are able to handle it.&nbsp; Because democracies require consensus, and it takes too much time, too much effort to get it together.&nbsp; And by that time, the event, the circumstance has gone beyond your ability to fix it.</p>



<p>And we see that &#8212; I &#8212; we talked about it.&nbsp; We mentioned democracies.&nbsp; One of the things that I did, I put together a worldwide effort, through a Zoom conference, with 142 heads of state on gathering up the democracies of the world to discuss where we go from here.&nbsp; And this was now two and a half months ago.</p>



<p>And as Freedom House will tell you, we have fewer democracies today than we did 15 years ago.&nbsp; Democracies are actually receding, not expanding.&nbsp; Just look around the world.&nbsp; Things are changing.</p>



<p>And so, when I got elected, one of the things I thought was critic- &#8212; critically important was that we stopped treating our allies and friends &#8212; my first discussion, Xi Jinping called me the night I was elected and the day after my &#8212;&nbsp; election &#8212; the next day after my election in 20- &#8212; whatever date it was.&nbsp; I can’t remember now.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, he called me to congratulate me.&nbsp; We ended up spending almost three hours on the telephone.&nbsp; And he &#8212; and it just amazed the Chinese experts who were on the phone with me, the things that he said.&nbsp; He remembered everything I had said to him.&nbsp; He said, “I remember you &#8212; asking you.”&nbsp; I said, “I know.”&nbsp; He said, “You shouldn&#8217;t be criticizing another country in terms of your &#8212; our human rights and our policy towards individuals.”</p>



<p>And I said, “You know, the United States is the most unique the country in the world not because we were born that way, but because we&#8217;re the only country ever organized based on an idea.”</p>



<p>I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; An idea.&nbsp; We’re not based on ethnicity, race, religion, geography.&nbsp; It’s an idea. And what was the idea?&nbsp; “We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all women and men are created equal, endowed by their Creator with certain inalienable rights.”&nbsp; You know it.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve never met it, but we never walked away from it.&nbsp; We’ve never walked away from, except for a very brief period of time in the last administration.</p>



<p>And so, I said, “For me not to be critical of your abuse of human rights would be like you deciding you didn&#8217;t think that China was any longer the center of the earth.&nbsp; You would be abandoning exactly what your country thinks it is and thought it was.”&nbsp; And I said, “So, I&#8217;m not going to stop being critical.”</p>



<p>My generic point was larger, though.&nbsp; If you &#8212; I said I was going to &#8212; he said, “What are you going to do?”&nbsp; And I said, “What I&#8217;m going to do is reestablish our alliances.”&nbsp; And by my implication, he said, “That&#8217;s &#8212; that’s because you&#8217;re trying to hurt China.”</p>



<p>I said, “No.&nbsp; It&#8217;s because we have to bring together the alliances we had before that have been treated like &#8212; our alliances, four years earlier, had been treated like…” &#8212; how can I say it?&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; Not well.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I was going to say something I shouldn’t say (inaudible).</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, think about it.&nbsp; And so, what I did was, I immediately convened a meeting and &#8212; of the G7.&nbsp; And it was in London.&nbsp; I mean, excuse me, in suburban &#8212; it was down in the (inaudible) in England.</p>



<p>And everybody showed up.&nbsp; And the first thing I said, when I walked in, I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And I will not, with the press here, say &#8212; went &#8212; two heads of state said the same thing: “For how long?&nbsp; For how long?”</p>



<p>And I also indicated to Xi Jinping that I was going to pull together the Quad: Australia, India, Japan, and the United States.&nbsp; He said, “You&#8217;re just doing that to affect us.”</p>



<p>I said, “No, it&#8217;s because we&#8217;re trying to put together those folks who have an opportunity to work together in the Indo-Pacific.”</p>



<p>The point being that one of the things that the autocrats fear the most &#8212; and India has its own problems; all those countries have their own problems &#8212; is the notion that somehow we can work together in concert and &#8212; contrary to what are essentially dictatorships, which a lot of countries have become &#8212; particularly, not only China, but Russia and many other countries &#8212; the Philippines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the point I&#8217;m making is that I spend a lot of time and put together, I think, a pretty good foreign policy team &#8212; with our Secretary of Defense, Secretary of State, National Security Advisor, et cetera &#8212; and reached out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what happened was: Putin thought, when we got elected, that we’d &#8212; he’d easily be able to break up NATO.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what part of his objective was from the very beginning.&nbsp; And I know I&#8217;ve been saying that for eight years, but it was part of his objective.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the irony of all ironies to this &#8212; and you know from being the Ambassador to Switzerland &#8212; what happened was: He got exactly what he didn&#8217;t want.&nbsp; He was looking for the further Finlandization of Europe.&nbsp; Instead, he got Finland and the President of &#8212; the President of Finland calling, wanting to see me, wanting to join NATO, and Sweden wanting to join NATO.&nbsp; His action is generating exactly the opposite of what he intended.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not suggesting that that makes things all that easier.&nbsp; But the point is that we have a circumstance where the Ukrainian people are incredibly brave; they’re incredibly resolved &#8212; not just the military that was trained, but the American &#8212; but the people in the streets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he is making &#8212; they&#8217;re making a lie of Putin’s theory that somehow because they&#8217;re Slavic in background and spoke &#8212; many spoke Russian that somehow there would be a welcoming party.&nbsp; The exact opposite has happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reason I bother to raise this is that it raises the issue of whether or not &#8212; what our foreign policy will be from this point on.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s occupied, Jay more of my time than I ever anticipated it would be.</p>



<p>And that, coupled with COVID, has had a phenomenal negative impact on things that relate to, basically, inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The &#8212; when you find ourselves in a situation where in &#8212; because of COVID, there&#8217;s a factory in &#8212; the factory in Vietnam or in Taiwan closes down &#8212; that was the reason why one third of all the inflation last year was the price of automobiles.&nbsp; They couldn&#8217;t get &#8212; they couldn&#8217;t get the computer chips to be able to build the automobiles.</p>



<p>We’re now in a situation where because of Russia being such a major oil producer and because Ukraine and Russia were the wheat and corn breadbaskets of the world, we see everything from the price of eggs to the price of gasoline go up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I come from a family &#8212; not a joke &#8212; where when the price of a gallon of gasoline went up, it was a conversation at our kitchen table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And a lot of people, notwithstanding the fact that we&#8217;ve created more jobs in the first 14 months than any President in the history.&nbsp; We have provided 400- &#8212; 5- &#8212; we created 420,000 manufacturing jobs that people thought were dead in America.&nbsp; We made &#8212; brought the employment &#8212; employment rate down to 3.6 percent from over 6 percent.&nbsp; Notwithstanding all that &#8212; and wages going up &#8212; people are concerned, uncertain, and angry.&nbsp; They&#8217;re angry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They don&#8217;t know quite what to do because, again, when gasoline goes over $4 a gallon, it&#8217;s a big deal in an awful lot of households &#8212; the vast majority of households.&nbsp; When the cost of a dozen eggs goes up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, so the two things we&#8217;ve worked on as hard as we could is dealing with the supply chains so that we&#8217;re able to &#8212; we&#8217;re able &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a law that&#8217;s been on the books since the ‘30s and it’s the “Buy America” law.&nbsp; It’s not a violation of any international group.&nbsp; As President United States these days, I get to spend and decide where we spend about $6- to $700 billion of your money.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, under the law, we&#8217;re able to insist that I can only buy &#8212; I can insist that we buy American and that the vehicles that I&#8217;m &#8212; the &#8212; whatever I&#8217;m purchasing is up to 100 percent made in America &#8212; all the &#8212; all the parts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, Buy American was viewed to be 51 percent.&nbsp; That was enough.&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s 51 percent of American product.&nbsp; It&#8217;s now 75.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my generic point is this: We have not invested in ourselves in America &#8212; the government has not invested in America either in our education and in our &#8212; in our technology.&nbsp; We used to provide &#8212; and now you all are doing it &#8212; but we used to provide from the government &#8212; 2 percent of our GDP was invested in research and development.&nbsp; It’s less than 1 percent now.&nbsp; Less than 1 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We used to be in a situation where we had the best infrastructure in the world &#8212; our ports, airports &#8212; or just go down the road &#8212; high- &#8212; the whole deal.&nbsp; We now rank 13th in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We used to be in a situation where &#8212; if you think about it, why were we the most powerful nation in the world, beginning &#8212; in the beginning of the 21st century &#8212; the 20th century?&nbsp; Because the only nation in the world that had universal education from K through 12.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other people &#8212; they had great education systems for the elite in &#8212; throughout Europe and great universities and great, great what we would call “high school.”&nbsp; But it wasn&#8217;t universal.&nbsp; The rest of the world has caught up with us and what have we done?&nbsp; Does anybody think if, today, we said, “We&#8217;re going to have a national education system,” that we&#8217;d say 12 years is enough?&nbsp; Anybody think 12 years is enough in the 21st century &#8212; in the second quarter of the 21st century?&nbsp; What are we doing?&nbsp; We&#8217;re resisting what we know to be the case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If in fact &#8212; all the studies have shown from the great universities of the last 10 years, if you have mandatory schooling &#8212; or schooling available for pre-K &#8212; three-, four-, and five-year-olds &#8212; you increase by over 56 percent that the child, no matter what the background they come from, is going to be able to get through 12 years of school &#8212; 12 years of schooling and go beyond.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, you all know the studies because you’re &#8212; the philanthropies you run, you&#8217;ve been involved in helping.&nbsp; You all know that, for example, a child coming from a broken home &#8212; with a mom or a dad or &#8212; where there&#8217;s a drug problem or there&#8217;s just pure poverty &#8212; that child, by the time they go to kindergarten, will have heard 1 million fewer words spoken than a child from an average middle-class home.&nbsp; Not different words, just spoken.&nbsp; Just spoken.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re in a situation where we find now, if in fact you have a circumstance where there is three- and four- and five-year-olds in school &#8212; school, not daycare &#8212; school, where they’re learning to read, write, add, and subtract, they increase exponentially their ability to learn.&nbsp; And they don&#8217;t show up &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t matter what their background they come from.&nbsp; It doesn’t matter what the background they come from.</p>



<p>Many of you know better than I &#8212; my son-in-law, who has his doctorate in neuroscience and is a reconstructive plastic surgeon in Philadelphia, talks about it.&nbsp; The brain has been rapidly advancing during that period of time.&nbsp; And it continues to grow after age 20.&nbsp; But what do we do?</p>



<p>So, for very little money, I spoke to the Fortune 500 companies, I spoke to the &#8212; actually the &#8212; when I &#8212; in Washington, we had &#8212; finally were able to gather up a larger number of people, and I spoke to the national Chamber of Commerce.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I pointed out that, when I was Vice President, President Obama asked me to deal with the Recovery Act, which was several billion dollars, and to get it working.</p>



<p>And I said one things I did was I went with the Secretary of Commerce and others to speak to a 300 &#8212; I think it was 340-some or 350 &#8212; I don&#8217;t remember the number &#8212; of the CEOs in the Fortune 500 companies.&nbsp; And I asked what they most needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It will not surprise you what the answer was: a better-educated workforce.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; The notable exceptions in this room: You all don&#8217;t pay for the better-educated workforce you have.</p>



<p>When I got elected in 1973, the DuPont &#8212; “the state of DuPont,” as I used to kid &#8212; DuPont was the eighth-largest corporation in the world, and they educated their newly hired people for the jobs they had.&nbsp; They took the time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That doesn’t happen now.&nbsp; So, I raised the question.&nbsp; I said, “Why…” &#8212; this was the national Chamber &#8212; “why are you opposed to preschool being…”&nbsp; And they all said, “I never thought of it.&nbsp; We’re not.&nbsp; We’re not.”</p>



<p>There are so many things we can do without raising taxes on &#8212; and, by the way, all of the stuff &#8212; we&#8217;ve had expensive programs: the Recovery Act, plus the infrastructure bill.&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; We’ve actually reduced the federal debt by $350 billion in 2021.&nbsp; And it’s projected now to be reduced by $1.3 trillion with all the growth we&#8217;re talking about.&nbsp; That’s a fact.</p>



<p>Whether we do the $1.3 trillion, we&#8217;ll see at the end of the year.&nbsp; The largest number ever in American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But my generic point is &#8212; it’s not some &#8212; what I&#8217;m trying to say is, there&#8217;s so many things we can do that don&#8217;t punish anybody and get so much done.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; I think you should be able to make a million, a billion dollars.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Whatever you can make.&nbsp; But you&#8217;re the prime example of what I&#8217;m about to say because you do it.&nbsp; Everybody has to pay a piece of &#8212; a fair share.&nbsp; The idea &#8212; the idea that we have a system now where it&#8217;s so disproportionately unbalanced &#8212; without &#8212; it won&#8217;t hurt anybody.&nbsp; No big deal &#8212; to pay for what we need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, healthcare.&nbsp; You know, I know some of you have &#8212; I hope you have interest in some of the major drug companies in the country.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; The insulin &#8212; how many people have Stage 1 diabetes?&nbsp; Thousands of people, two hundred thousand kids in America.&nbsp; The average cost on a monthly basis: $641; as high as $1,000, as low in some places as $95.</p>



<p>But here&#8217;s the deal: It cost 10 bucks to develop, at the time, that insulin vial.&nbsp; Ten dollars.&nbsp; I think we should see to it that &#8212; that unless there&#8217;s new research and development put into it to change the formulas that you can&#8217;t charge more than $35.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Imagine being the parent of a kid with Type 1 diabetes, knowing, if they go into insulin shock, what the danger is, sitting there knowing you don’t have the insurance or the wherewithal to pay for it.&nbsp; Not only is your kid in trouble &#8212; you&#8217;re stripped of your dignity.&nbsp; Everything is taken from you.</p>



<p>But what&#8217;s the big fight?&nbsp; I can&#8217;t get a single Republican to say, “That&#8217;s a good idea.”&nbsp; Everybody points out what I have is I have one Democrat that says “no.”&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s true.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; Forty-eight of the fifty Democrats in the Senate vote with me 95 percent of the time, or over 90 percent of the time.</p>



<p>But the second point I want to make: This is not your father&#8217;s Republican Party.  This is a different deal.  Not a joke.  Not a joke.  And it&#8217;s not just Trump, it&#8217;s the MAGA crowd.  It’s all about things that have nothing to do with traditional, conservative doctrine. </p>



<p>I respect conservatives.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing conservative about deciding you&#8217;re going to throw Disney out of its present posture because &#8212; Mickey Mouse?&nbsp; In fact, do you think we should be not be able to say, you know, “gay”?</p>



<p>I mean, what’s going on here?&nbsp; What the hell is going on?&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just &#8212; so, I don&#8217;t believe it’s who the vast majority of American people are.</p>



<p>Another point I want to make is &#8212; and I&#8217;ll stop, I apologize, so we can get to questions &#8212; when I got elected and when I was running, I said that I was going to see to it that if I were President, my administration looked like America.</p>



<p>I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; Looked like America.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what I&#8217;ve done.&nbsp; Of all the thousand appointees I&#8217;ve had that didn’t require Senate confirmation &#8212; well over a thousand &#8212; and all those requiring confirmation, there are more women than men, by a slight margin.&nbsp; It’s not much.&nbsp; But equally as &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s no distinction in terms of qualification.&nbsp; Pick the best person.</p>



<p>I’ve appointed more Circuit Court judges to the federal Circuit Court that were Black than every other president in American history combined.&nbsp; Not because &#8212; not because to make a point, other than the point that &#8212; to let every little Black girl out there know that she could do anything any little white girl can do, given the chance.</p>



<p>You saw how Judge Brown Jackson was treated.&nbsp; The questions they asked her were humiliating.&nbsp; Humiliating.&nbsp; And now we had an event in the White House when she &#8212; on the lawn &#8212; when she was &#8212; was confirmed.&nbsp; And she had a great line she used.&nbsp; She said &#8212; she said it best.&nbsp; She said, “From segregation to the Supreme Court in one generation.&nbsp; I thank my parents.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>You should see, when I go into African American communities, or especially young African American women, they look and they see.&nbsp; Think of all of the young girls of middle-class backgrounds (inaudible) who look up there and see the women who are heading up major Cabinet positions, from the Vice President on down.</p>



<p>So, you know, I &#8212; I think that when &#8212; you&#8217;re more united and stronger than ever when we focus on what we have in common.&nbsp; And I know that sounds, you know, sort of prosaic.&nbsp; I mean &#8212; and I&#8217;ve been doing this a long time.&nbsp; I got involved in public life because of the Civil Rights Movement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not making this &#8212; this is not a, you know, painted rosy picture.&nbsp; But we are unique in the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the only democracy that is as &#8212; as ethnically, politi- &#8212; excuse me &#8212; ethnically, racially so divided.&nbsp; So &#8212; and if we don&#8217;t bring it together, what in the hell are we going to do?&nbsp; What are we going to do?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So again, I&#8217;m not on a crusade; it’s just about fairness. It&#8217;s about giving people a shot.&nbsp; And like I said, you know, I think that the clear contrast with our Republican colleagues &#8212; and I&#8217;m going to have to start pointing this out.&nbsp; Everybody thinks &#8212; they always talk about the Democratic Party divided because there are two senators who occasionally don’t vote with me.</p>



<p>Well, the bad news is, when you have a 50/50 Senate, you have 51 presidents.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It becomes a problem.&nbsp; And &#8212; and the use of the filibuster, which I think is so far out of whack, can hold up anything.&nbsp; You need 60 votes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m going on too long, but (inaudible) questions.</p>



<p>But here&#8217;s the deal: One of the reasons that I&#8217;m here is we have to keep the Uni- &#8212; we have to keep the United States Senate.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t afford to lose it.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t afford to lose the House.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; what I&#8217;m concerned about is that I have been so focused on whatever the immediate emergency is, we haven&#8217;t sold the American people what we’ve actually done &#8212; what we’ve actually gotten done.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve gotten a hell of a lot done.&nbsp; A hell of a lot done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, this is what I&#8217;m here for: to ask you for your help, when it comes to this off-year election, to help keep the Democratic (inaudible) Senate and the Democratic House so that we can, in fact &#8212;</p>



<p>The la- &#8212; the act- &#8212; actual very last point I’ll make: There are a number of Republicans who are not the MAGA group &#8212; that are not.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; They&#8217;re scared to death.&nbsp;&nbsp;They know &#8212; and I know you know this, Jay, that we could privately name them off the top of our heads &#8212; there are a significant number who if they were to vote where they had voted in the past, if they vote their heart, they’d get a primary and they’ll lose a primary.&nbsp; They would lose a primary.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t talk about courage, but it talks about reality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we got to make &#8212; we got to provide room by providing more Democratic votes that allow people to say &#8212;</p>



<p>You know, I remember, early on, learning a lesson from a senior senator when I got there.&nbsp; He said, “It&#8217;s one thing to cast your vote that you feel strongly about on a losing cause. It&#8217;s another thing if you vote with the side that what you care about wins.&nbsp; It ain&#8217;t worth it if you can&#8217;t win.&nbsp; You just get the downside and no upside.”</p>



<p>That’s reality.&nbsp; That’s how, I think &#8212; how human nature functions.&nbsp; And so, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m going to change human nature, but I think the more we are &#8212; go around the country, talking about what we&#8217;ve done, talking about what we can do, talk about the impact of the &#8212; everything from the &#8212; what we&#8217;ve done in terms of healthcare, what we&#8217;ve done in terms of the whole notion of how we&#8217;re going to deal with education, the way in which we&#8217;re going to deal with the notion of the infrastructure bill that’s going to fundamentally change &#8212;</p>



<p>Your state is going to get hundreds of millions of dollars to do good things.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And &#8212; but I know you know, Jay.&nbsp; It really is.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about tens of millions of dollars.&nbsp; I was just at your airport &#8212; I mean, I was just in Portland at their airport.&nbsp; We’re talking about that whole airport facility getting close to a billion dollars.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to be able to do the same thing here so we can once again invest in our country and our people so we can stay competitive.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m outcompeting myself here because I&#8217;m taking up too much of your time before we get to questions.&nbsp; So, thank you very much for listening.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m prepared to take questions at the appropriate moment.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>6:58 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
