<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 20:27:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement on Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for&#160;Prosperity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/statement-on-indo-pacific-economic-framework-for-prosperity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 19:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53888</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, the United States, Australia, Brunei Darussalam, India, Indonesia, Japan, Republic of Korea, Malaysia, New Zealand, Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam of the Indo-Pacific region, acknowledge the richness and the diversity of our vibrant regional economy. We share a commitment to a free, open, fair, inclusive, interconnected, resilient, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region that has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">We, the United States, Australia, Brunei Darussalam, India, Indonesia, Japan, Republic of Korea, Malaysia, New Zealand, Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam of the Indo-Pacific region, acknowledge the richness and the diversity of our vibrant regional economy. We share a commitment to a free, open, fair, inclusive, interconnected, resilient, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region that has the potential to achieve sustainable and inclusive economic growth. We acknowledge our economic policy interests in the region are intertwined, and deepening economic engagement among partners is crucial for continued growth, peace, and prosperity.<br>&nbsp;<br>We recognize the COVID-19 pandemic has underscored the imperative of working closely together to ensure that economic recovery and advancement are grounded in resilience, sustainability, and inclusivity.&nbsp; The pandemic has also emphasized the importance of strengthening economic competitiveness and cooperation and securing critical supply chains, while stimulating job growth and improving economic opportunities, including for our workers, women, medium- and small-enterprises, and our societies’ most vulnerable groups.<br>&nbsp;<br>In the long term, economic competitiveness will be largely defined by our ability to harness technology, promote innovation, participate in the digital economy, justly transition energy systems and achieve energy security, and tackle the climate crisis in a manner that produces equitable, inclusive growth and improves socio-economic welfare. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In order to prepare our economies for the future, we are launching the process to establish the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity.<br>&nbsp;<br>This framework is intended to advance resilience, sustainability, inclusiveness, economic growth, fairness, and competitiveness for our economies.&nbsp; Through this initiative, we aim to contribute to cooperation, stability, prosperity, development, and peace within the region.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We invite participation from additional Indo-Pacific partners that share our goals, interests, and ambitions for the region.&nbsp; We are committed to collaborating with our framework partners in a manner that acknowledges the importance of technical assistance and capacity building, allows us to maintain a flexible approach, and delivers tangible benefits for our peoples.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, we launch collective discussions toward future negotiations on the following pillars.&nbsp; Framework partners will be engaging in such discussions on various ways to strengthen economic cooperation to achieve these goals, and we invite other interested Indo-Pacific partners to join us.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Trade:</strong> We seek to build high-standard, inclusive, free, and fair trade commitments and develop new and creative approaches in trade and technology policy that advance a broad set of objectives that fuels economic activity and investment, promotes sustainable and inclusive economic growth, and benefits workers and consumers.&nbsp; Our efforts include, but are not limited to, cooperation in the digital economy.&nbsp;<br><strong>&nbsp;<br>Supply Chains: </strong>We are committed to improving transparency, diversity, security, and sustainability in our supply chains to make them more resilient and well-integrated. &nbsp;We seek to coordinate crisis response measures; expand cooperation to better prepare for and mitigate the effects of disruptions to better ensure business continuity; improve logistical efficiency and support; and ensure access to key raw and processed materials, semiconductors, critical minerals, and clean energy technology.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Clean Energy, Decarbonization, and Infrastructure: </strong>In line with our Paris Agreement goals and efforts to support the livelihood of our peoples and workers, we plan to accelerate the development and deployment of clean energy technologies to decarbonize our economies and build resilience to climate impacts.&nbsp; This involves deepening cooperation on technologies, on mobilizing finance, including concessional finance, and on seeking ways to improve competitiveness and enhance connectivity by supporting the development of sustainable and durable infrastructure and by providing technical assistance.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Tax and Anti-Corruption: </strong>We are committed to promoting fair competition by enacting and enforcing effective and robust tax, anti-money laundering, and anti-bribery regimes in line with existing multilateral obligations, standards, and agreements to curb tax evasion and corruption in the Indo-Pacific region. This involves sharing expertise and seeking ways to support capacity building necessary to advance accountable and transparent systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>We are continuing to identify additional areas of cooperation based on consultations among partners to further our shared interests, with a view to advancing regional economic connectivity and integration. &nbsp;We look forward to jointly creating conducive environments to boost flows of commerce, trade, and investments amongst our economies, and to enhancing standards and access to opportunities for our workers, companies, and peoples in our combined markets.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Fumio Kishida of Japan in Joint Press&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/23/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-fumio-kishida-of-japan-in-joint-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 17:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Akasaka PalaceTokyo, Japan 2:16 P.M. JST PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&#160; &#160;(As interpreted.)&#160; Well, thank you.&#160; We are immensely pleased with President Biden’s first visit to Japan as the President of the United States. The United States is Japan’s only ally who shares the universal values of freedom, democracy, human rights, and rule of law. It goes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Akasaka Palace<br>Tokyo, Japan</p>



<p>2:16 P.M. JST<br><br>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&nbsp; &nbsp;(As interpreted.)&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; We are immensely pleased with President Biden’s first visit to Japan as the President of the United States.<br><br>The United States is Japan’s only ally who shares the universal values of freedom, democracy, human rights, and rule of law.<br><br>It goes without saying that Japan-U.S. alliance is the linchpin of Japan&#8217;s diplomatic and security policy.&nbsp; The Japan-U.S. summit this time, in this context, was more important than ever in respect of two points.<br><br>For one, we are currently faced with a crisis that shakes the foundation of international order, which is Russia&#8217;s aggression against Ukraine.&nbsp; To defend a resolutely free and open international order based on the rule of law, unity amongst allies and likeminded countries are required utmost now than any other.<br><br>Another thing is that the challenge of ensuring peace and prosperity of the Indo-Pacific region is the most important strategic issue for the international community, and Japan and the United States are thought to take on leadership role.&nbsp;<br><br>In this sense, we highly value the visit by President Biden to Japan, as it powerfully demonstrates United States&#8217; enhanced engagement in this part of the region.<br><br>Also, together with President Biden, we will later make tomorrow&#8217;s Quad Summit a sure success.<br><br>Based on this common awareness, today, frank and useful discussion took place on matters of international community.<br><br>First, on Russia’s egregious aggression, unilateral attempt to change the status quo by force is totally unacceptable.&nbsp; Regardless of location, we reaffirm to respond resolutely together with the international community, including G7.<br><br>Also, confirmation was made to support fully the government and people of Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>We also discussed the impact the Ukraine situation could give on the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;<br><br>For China, we concurred to monitor closely recent activities of Chinese navy and joint military exercise of China and Russia, and strongly oppose the attempt to change the status quo by force.<br><br>In East China Sea and South China Sea, the Japan and the United States will closely cooperate on responding to China-related issue, including human rights.<br><br>Also, we affirmed that our two countries’ basic position on Taiwan remains to be unchanged; and underscored the importance of peace and stability of Taiwan Straits, which is an indispensable element for peace and prosperity of the international community; and called for peaceful resolution of Cross-Strait issue.<br><br>On DPRK, sharing the serious concern over nuclear and missile issues, including the launch of ICBM-class ballistic missiles.&nbsp; Japan and the United States and Japan-U.S.-ROK to cooperate to even more closely was affirmed.<br><br>Toward immediate resolution of abduction issue, I reiterated my request for full understanding and cooperation.&nbsp; President Biden extended his strong support.&nbsp; After this, President Biden will be meeting with family members of the abductees.&nbsp;<br><br>At a time when regional security environment is becoming more severe, with President Biden we affirmed the need to quickly reinforce the deterrence and response capability of Japan-U.S. alliances.&nbsp; I stated my determination to fundamentally reinforce Japan&#8217;s defense capabilities and secure a substantial increase of its defense budget needed to effect it.&nbsp; President Biden strongly supported my determination.<br><br>We also concurred to expand and deepen security and defense cooperation between Japan and the United States.&nbsp; Further, President Biden reiterated his commitment to Japan&#8217;s defense.&nbsp; And to make sure that extended deterrence will remain unwavering, we concurred to keeping close touch, including on the ministerial level, between our two countries.<br><br>In addition, to alleviate the impact on local communities of Okinawa and others, we also concurred to steadfastly implement U.S. forces in Japan realignment, including construction in Henoko of replacement facilities Futenma Air Station.&nbsp;<br><br>And because situation around the nuclear weapons are getting severe, we also concurred at once realistic and effective efforts on nuclear disarmament and non-proliferation, and work toward a world without nuclear weapons.<br><br>Engagement in the Indo-Pacific by the United States, and especially in the economic order, is becoming ever more important.&nbsp; Japan welcomes the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework &#8212; IPEF &#8212; by President Biden, and will participate and cooperate in this initiative.&nbsp; Having said so, Japan hopes to see the United States return to the TPP from a strategic perspective.&nbsp;<br><br>Also, in order to expand and deepen Japan-U.S. economic cooperation, we agreed to hold the ministerial-level Japan-U.S. Economic Policy Consultative Committee, the so-called economic 2+2, coming July.<br><br>Further, we concurred on cooperation in economic security, including the development of advanced semiconductors and specific cooperation regarding space.<br><br>With Russia&#8217;s aggression of Ukraine severely damaging the situation over energy and food, we confirmed that we shall respond through coordination with the G7 and likeminded nations, as well as with international organizations.&nbsp; Through such cooperation, Japan and the United States hopes to engage in initiatives to realize a sustainable and inclusive social economic environment.<br><br>Regarding the new form of capitalism, which I am proposing, President Biden reconfirmed his strong support.&nbsp; By cooperating with President Biden, who is promoting policies that focus on the middle class, we hope to create a major global trend of common economic policies among major countries.<br><br>We also exchanged views on global health, cancer research, climate change, production and promotion of human rights and democracy, and other global challenges, and agreed that our two countries should lead efforts of the international community in such areas.<br><br>Further, I expressed the necessity to reform and strengthen the United Nations, including the Security Council, which bears an important responsibility for the peace and security of the international community, and gained President Biden&#8217;s support.<br><br>The President stated that the United States will support Japan becoming a permanent member of a reformed Security Council.&nbsp;<br><br>&#8220;The Pacific Ocean does not separate Japan and the United States.&nbsp; Rather, it unites us.”&nbsp; Those are the words delivered by President Kennedy to Prime Minister Ikeda, which resonate with amplified weight in today&#8217;s context.</p>



<p>I conveyed the importance of human resources development and people-to-people exchange towards a free and open Indo-Pacific, and President Biden concurred.</p>



<p>Japan will hold the presidency of the G7 next year.&nbsp; As the world faces an unprecedented challenge caused by Russia&#8217;s aggression of Ukraine and the heightened risk of use of weapons of mass destruction, at next year&#8217;s G7 Summit I hope we can demonstrate the will of the G7 to resolutely reject aggression by force, threat by nuclear weapons, and attempts to overturn the international order with a strength that will make a mark in history.</p>



<p>As the Prime Minister of Japan, the only country to have ever suffered atomic bombings, I believe there is no other venue as fitting as Hiroshima to demonstrate our commitment to peace.&nbsp;<br><br>I hope that we can vow to the world that mankind will never cause the catastrophe brought about by nuclear weapons, that President Biden and other leaders of the G7 will together confirm in front of the Peace Memorial on solidarity to defend peace, global order, and values.</p>



<p>I explained such plans to the President.&nbsp; And we reaffirmed that next year&#8217;s G7 Summit will be held in Hiroshima and that we shall work together for its success.</p>



<p>Today, as an outcome of our meeting, we decided to issue a joint statement.&nbsp; This statement is the joint strategy of Japan and the United States as we keep in mind the current situation in Ukraine and the strategic importance of the Indo-Pacific and aim to uphold and develop a free and open international order.</p>



<p>Under the current situation of international affairs, which may be described as the end of the post-Cold War era, the true value of the Japan-U.S. alliance is being tested more stringently than ever before.</p>



<p>In order to realize a free and open Indo-Pacific and to establish a free and open rules-based international order, Japan and the United States will engage in utmost efforts with irreversible resolve.&nbsp; I look forward to furthering our partnership with President Biden.<br>Thank you, Joe.&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p>I now would like to give the floor to President Biden of the United States of America.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Thank you very much, Prime Minister, for that warm welcome you’ve given me here in Japan.<br><br>In recent years, the alliance between Japan and the United States has grown stronger, deeper, and more capable as we work together to take on the challenges &#8212; just as important as the opportunities &#8212; of a rapidly changing world.<br><br>A great example of this: We viewed Japan’s lunar rover just coming out here &#8212; over out here &#8212; before &#8212; after lunch.  A symbol of how our space cooperation is taking off, looking toward the moon and to Mars.<br><br>And I’m excited &#8212; I’m excited at the work we will do together on the Gateway Station around the moon, and I look forward to the first Japanese astronaut joining us on the mission to the lunar surface under the Artemis program.<br><br>And tomorrow, we’re going to meet with the fel- &#8212; our fellow Quad partners, Australia and India, for our fourth Leaders&#8217; Summit, and our second time meeting together in person.<br><br>The Quad is showing the world that cooperation among democracies can get big things done, and I am grateful for your leadership.<br><br>And thank you for bringing us all together again to keep driving our progress as we advance a positive vision for the future of the Indo-Pacific region.<br><br>Today, we made several commitments to further increase our bilateral cooperation and to work together to ensure a free and open Indo-Pacific that creates opportunity and prosperity for all the people in the region.<br><br>Through our comprehensive and reliance &#8212; excuse me &#8212; and Resilience Partnership, which we announced last year, we’re in a situation now that we’ve invested our cooperation to spur innovation while delivering concrete progress for our people:<br><br>Promoting a secure 5G network and improving Internet connectivity for our partners in the region.<br><br>Improving critical infrastructure and strengthening supply chain resilience, particularly on semiconductors, batteries, and critical minerals.<br><br>Responding to COVID-19 and building a greater health security and stronger health system is also part of the future, and helping the world prepare for the next pandemic with our new CDC regional office right here in Japan.<br><br>Cooperating on clean energy and decarbonization to tackle the climate crisis.<br><br>And after this, the United States and Japan, together with 11 other nations, will be launching the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.<br><br>This framework is a commitment to working with our close friends and partners in the region on challenges that matter most to ensuring economic competitiveness in the 21st century &#8212; by improving security and trust in the digital economy, protecting workers, strengthening supply chains, and tackling corruption that robs nations of their ability to serve their citizens.<br><br>You know, the two lis- &#8212; the two largest democracies &#8212; the two largest economic &#8212; economies in the democratic world, the United States and Japan, are demonstrating the strength of democracies in action.<br><br>Our cooperation has been particularly vital in organizing the global response to hold Putin accountable for his brutal war in Ukraine and his attack on the norms and principles that are the foundation of our international order.<br><br>Mr. Prime Minister, you’ve been outstanding; you’ve been an outstanding partner throughout this crisis.  And our unity in the G7 to impose economic costs on Russia and support the people of Ukraine is sending a strong message about our willingness to defend a rule-based international order. <br><br>And I’m looking forward to continuing our discussions at the upcoming G7 Summit in Germany and returning to Japan next year, in 2023, for the G7 Summit.  And I welcome the Prime Minister’s announcement that the G7 Summit will take place in his hometown of Hiroshima. <br><br>Today, we also discussed ways to continue to strengthen our security cooperation.<br><br>The United States remains fully committed to Japan’s defense, and we welcome &#8212; we welcome the opportunity to work more closely together in an increasingly challenging security environment.<br><br>I applaud Prime Minister Kishida’s determination to strengthen Japanese defense capabilities as well.<br><br>A strong Japan and a strong U.S.-Japan alliance is a force for good in the region.  I support the peace and stability that’s going to continue and, we hope, increase across the Taiwan Straits; promote freedom of navigation in the East and South China Seas; and to deter the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.<br><br>So, thank you again, Mr. Prime Minister, for your partnership and your friendship.<br><br>The alliance between our two countries is stronger than it’s ever been and it’s as important as it has ever been.<br><br>I’m looking forward to exploring even more ways that our relationship will help move us toward a future that benefits all people.<br><br>So, thank you very much, Mr. <s>President</s> [Prime Minister].  And I really, truly, appreciate your hospitality. <br><br>MODERATOR:  (As interpreted.)  Thank you very much.  We will now accept questions from the press.  First, Japanese journalists, to be followed by U.S. journalists.  That will be the order of the questions. <br><br>Those of you who have questions, please raise your hand.  For Japanese journalists, I will appoint the journalist, and U.S. journalists will be appointed by President Biden. <br><br>Please come to the closest microphone, identify yourself and your affiliation, and please be brief and clear in your questions. <br><br>Due to infection prevention, please keep your facial masks when you deliver your question. <br><br>Now, Japanese journalists, are there any questions?  The front row, Yamamoto-san?<br><br>Q    (As interpreted.)  TV Asahi.  My name is Yamamoto.  Prime Minister, President Biden, thank you very much. <br><br>First, to Prime Minister: With the Russian aggression of Ukraine, Prime Minister, you&#8217;ve been saying that security of Europe and security of the Indo-Pacific are inseparable.  In today&#8217;s meeting, did you talk about response to China?  How did you analyze the current status of the Cross-Straits relations?  Did the Japanese side or U.S. side explain how U.S. would respond in times of contingency?  What was the request from the U.S. side regarding Japanese response to a contingency in Cross-Straits situation?  Did you explain the defense budget increase or enemy base strike capability?  What did you explain in that context, Prime Minister?<br><br>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:  (As interpreted.)  Well, thank you for your question.  First of all, at today&#8217;s summit meeting, as regard Taiwan Strait issue that you asked, we confirmed that basic stances of two countries on Taiwan remains to be unchanged, and underscored the importance of peace and stability of Taiwan Strait, which is an indispensable element for security and prosperity of international community, and called upon peaceful resolution of Cross-Strait issues.<br><br>In the region, security-related environment is getting severer.  Unilateral attempt to change the status quo by force, like Russia&#8217;s aggression against Ukraine this time, should never be tolerated in Indo-Pacific.  Above all, in East Asia, it’s indispensable to further strengthen Japan-U.S. alliance.<br><br>Based on this shared awareness, I have said that &#8212; fundamentally reinforce Japan&#8217;s defense capability.  And I stated my determination to fundamentally reinforce Japan&#8217;s defense capabilities and secure substantial increase of its defense budget needed to effect it.  And President Biden strongly supported my determination.<br><br>And also from myself, I have said that includes what is called “enemy base strike capability.”  All the options will be there, not to exclude any one of them.  And this is what I said to President in Indo-Pacific region, as well as to ensure the peace and prosperity of the international community, the basis is the cornerstone of which is Japan-U.S. alliance.  And toward the further strengthening of the alliance, we would like to remain in close coordination between Japan and the United States.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  I have a question for Prime Minister Kishida as well.  But, Mr. President, I wanted to ask you about the economy.  During your trip here to Asia, you&#8217;ve promoted the investments by Samsung and Hyundai.  But back home in the United States, Americans are dealing with record-high inflation.  The Fed has raised interest rates to try to address those issues.  And there are also just enormously high gas prices.<br><br>Given the cross-currents of the economy right now &#8212; the war in Ukraine, the China lockdowns that we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; should Americans be prepared for a recession?  In your view, is a recession in the United States inevitable?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  No.<br><br>Q    Why not?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Look, you&#8217;re talking about the significant progress we&#8217;ve made in making sure we don&#8217;t have supply chain backups &#8212; about the 8,000 jobs that Hyundai is going to be bringing to Georgia; 3,000 jobs to Texas from Samsung, $17 billion investment; Toyota, 1,700 jobs in North Carolina on battery technology; the situation where we &#8212; at &#8212; we&#8217;ve created over 8 million new jobs, where unemployment is down to 3.6 percent, and so on and so forth &#8212; as if they&#8217;re a problem.  Imagine where we’d be with Putin&#8217;s tax and the war in Ukraine had we not made that enormous progress.<br><br>Our GDP is going to grow faster than China&#8217;s for the first time in 40 years.  Now, does that mean we don&#8217;t have problems?  We do.  We have problems that the rest of the world has, but less consequential than the rest of the world has because of our internal growth and strength.<br><br>Here&#8217;s the situation.  And when it comes to the gas prices, we&#8217;re going through an incredible transition that is taking place that, God willing, when it&#8217;s over, we&#8217;ll be stronger and the world will be stronger and less reliant on fossil fuels when this is over.<br><br>You see what Europe is doing relative to the importation of Russian gas.  You see what &#8212; anyway, I won&#8217;t go through it all, but &#8212;<br><br>And what I&#8217;ve been able to do to keep it from getting even worse &#8212; and it&#8217;s bad.  The price of gas at the pump is something that I told you &#8212; you heard me say before &#8212; it would be a matter of great discussion at my kitchen table when I was a kid growing up.  It&#8217;s affecting a lot of families.<br><br>But we have released over two hundred and, I think, fifty-seven thousand &#8212; million barrels of oil, I should say.  Us and the rest of the world we convinced to get involved.  It&#8217;s helped, but it&#8217;s not been enough.<br><br>We also find ourselves in a situation where we have food shortages &#8212; food shortages because of Ukraine.  There are over &#8212; there are literally millions of bushels of oil &#8212; I mean, excuse me, of grain being held up in Ukraine that would fundamentally impact positively on the market in terms of bringing down food prices across the board.<br><br>So we&#8217;re finding ourselves in a position where we&#8217;re working very hard with American farmers and American manufacturing- &#8212; and American agricultural products to provide more fertilizer and a whole range of things.<br><br>This is going to be a haul.  This is going to take some time.  But in the meantime, it seems to me the best thing I can do &#8212; in addition to try to get the Middle Eastern countries, including OPEC, to raise their production of oil and move along that route &#8212; is to see to it that we continue to grow our economy, create jobs.<br><br>And the other thing is: There&#8217;s a second wave &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t want to talk about it &#8212; not necessarily you; people don&#8217;t want to talk about it right now.  And I won&#8217;t take up the time.  But there&#8217;s a second wave to impact on inflation, in terms of people&#8217;s daily cost. <br><br>If you&#8217;re able to have childcare at 17 percent of &#8212; 7 percent of your income, if you&#8217;re able to be in a position where we were able to provide for a tax cut for middle-class people and working-class people, et cetera &#8212; all those things would be very helpful.  <br><br>And we &#8212; but when we have a 50-50 Senate, it means we have 50 presidents.  And I&#8217;m having a little trouble getting some of these things passed.  But we&#8217;re not going to give up.  We&#8217;re going to keep pushing.<br><br>Q    Can I just follow you on one point?  Secretary Yellen said recently that some of the tariffs on Chinese imports impose more harm on consumers and businesses, and aren&#8217;t very strategic.  Do you share that view?  And are you considering taking down some of those tariffs?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  I&#8217;m talking with the Secretary when we get home.  I am considering it.  We did not impose any of those tariffs.  They were imposed by the last administration, and they&#8217;re under consideration.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Prime Minister Kishida, if I may, sir: We&#8217;re going to be hearing more about this Indo-Pacific Economic Forum today.&nbsp; What message do you hope that it sends to China in the global market?&nbsp; And do you see this as a potential precursor to some type of trade pact, given the &#8212; the political situation in the United States dealing with TPP?<br><br>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&nbsp;&nbsp;(As interpreted.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, thank you for the IPEF &#8212; your question.&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, United States in the Indo-Pacific region is making economic interest known and highly interested, and the very posture shown by the United States is something we highly value in Japan.<br><br>Regarding the TPP, we are truly hoping for return of the United States.&nbsp; But even with the TPP, it&#8217;s important that we proceed with discussions on IPEF.&nbsp; And that attitude of the United States is wholeheartedly welcomed by the Japanese government, and we would like to support the U.S. initiative.</p>



<p>China right now in the Indo-Pacific region is demonstrating significant economic presence.&nbsp; That&#8217;s true, but look into the substance of their presence.&nbsp; Are they abiding by international rules?&nbsp; What about development finance?&nbsp; Are they carrying about sustainable initiatives?&nbsp; They have to do that because they are a major power.&nbsp; They have significant responsibility.&nbsp; Even in the economic field, they have to live up to that responsibility.<br><br>So Japan will cooperate with the United States &#8212; and, vis-à-vis China, persuade them to live up to their responsibilities to abide by international rules.&nbsp; And we think that such attitude is very important.<br><br>Thank you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; So, once again, we will receive question from a Japanese reporter.&nbsp; Please raise your hand.<br><br>Asahi (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Ikejiri from Asahi Newspaper.&nbsp; Prime Minister Kishida, President Biden, nice to meet you.&nbsp; I have a question once again about IPEF.</p>



<p>It is said that IPEF is different from the framework of TPP, and some other members are saying that there is less merit there, benefit.&nbsp; Would the IPEF will be effective a framework?&nbsp; Or in order to ensure the effectiveness for IPEF, what is the role that Japan will be playing, Prime Minister Kishida?</p>



<p>And also, there was expectations expressed for United States to come back to TPP.&nbsp; What was the response you received?<br><br>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; First of all, on IPEF, under the leadership of President Biden, shortly after this press conference, there will be official launch of IPEF.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the plan.&nbsp; Such ceremony is slated to take place.</p>



<p>I said this before, but this is a demonstration of the positive commitment of the United States to the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; Japan welcomes such steps, and we are in full support.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m going to join President Biden to participate in the inauguration ceremony.</p>



<p>And through IPEF, it&#8217;s important to realize sustainable and inclusive economic growth in the Indo-Pacific.<br><br>In your question, you asked about the concern of some countries who may think that there is very little merit or advantage to them, but we&#8217;re going to discuss various matters, not only with the United States, but regional partners, including the ASEAN countries, in order to jointly deliver concrete results.</p>



<p>So this is a venue to engage in positive discussion for cooperation.&nbsp; And through such initiatives, we want to deliver concrete and specific results.&nbsp; And that will serve as specific and actual advantage or merit for those countries.</p>



<p>You asked the question on TPP.&nbsp; From the strategic perspective of U.S. engagement in the international order of the Indo-Pacific, we want United States to be engaged from the economic perspective as well, so our position remains unchanged.&nbsp; We think it&#8217;s desirable for the United States to return to the TPP.<br><br>So, Japan hopes to see Japa- &#8212; to see U.S. come back to the TPP.&nbsp; And during the meeting, I directly communicated our hopes as such to the President.<br><br>I will not make any further detailed comments since it pertains to diplomatic exchanges.<br>Finally, I invite questions from the U.S. press.<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Nancy Cordes, with NBC &#8212; CBS.&nbsp; Hey, Nance.<br><br>(Reporter approaches microphone.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Dangerous.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tight quarters.<br><br>Thank you so much.&nbsp; I have a question for the Prime Minister, but first to you, Mr. President: We&#8217;re already dealing with one global pandemic, and you said yesterday that monkeypox is something that everyone should be concerned about.&nbsp; There are a few confirmed cases in the U.S., and some countries are imposing 21-day quarantines for people who are infected or even, in some cases, just exposed.&nbsp; Should Americans expect something similar?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; No, I don&#8217;t think so.&nbsp; Look, we&#8217;ve had this monkeypox in the larger numbers in the past, number one.&nbsp;<br><br>Number two, we have vaccines to care for it &#8212; to take care of it.&nbsp;<br><br>Number three, there is &#8212; thus far, there doesn&#8217;t seem to be a need for any kind of extra &#8212; extra efforts beyond what&#8217;s going on.&nbsp; And so, I just don&#8217;t think it rises to the level of the kind of concern that existed with COVID-19 or &#8212; and the smallpox vaccine works for it.&nbsp; So &#8212; but I think people should be careful.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think that the U.S. has enough smallpox vaccine stockpiled?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I think we do have enough to deal with the likelihood of the problem.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, Mr. Prime Minister, can you tell us how Japan would respond if China were to invade or tried to take over Taiwan?&nbsp; And how do you hope that the U.S. would respond if that were to happen?<br><br>And, Mr. President, if you could tell us how the U.S. is prepared to respond, we would appreciate it.&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; On Taiwan: In the summit meeting, it was brought up in our discussions &#8212; the situation in the Taiwan Straits.&nbsp;<br><br>The fundamental position of Japan and the United States was reaffirmed; there is no change.&nbsp; And we asserted the importance of peace and stability of the Taiwan Straits, which is fundamental to international order, and peaceful resolution of the Straits issue should be pursued.&nbsp; We reconfirmed that position.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, in Asia, we are against any unilateral attempt to change status quo by force in Asia, all the more so because of such position regarding the situation in Ukraine.&nbsp; We think that unilateral attempt to change status quo is impermissible.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re cooperating with the international cooperation and we decided to participate in the strong sanctions, and we are providing humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;<br><br>And in Asia as well, peace and stability must be upheld and defended.&nbsp; And in order to defend peace and stability in Asia, we will drastically upgrade and strengthen our defense capability, and United States is the only ally for Japan.&nbsp; And Japan-U.S. alliance is thus very, very important.&nbsp; We have to strengthen this alliance to defend peace and stability of the region.&nbsp; That&#8217;s our belief.&nbsp;<br><br>And in so doing, extended deterrence and response by the United States must be reliable.&nbsp; We have full confidence in response by the United States, including extended deterrence.&nbsp; And strengthening of Japan-U.S. alliance is very important.&nbsp;<br><br>And we truly hope that as many members of the general public will have even deeper confidence on this alliance so that that in turn will lead to regional peace and stability.&nbsp; And I look forward to cooperating with President Biden to that end.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Our policy toward Taiwan has not &#8212; Taiwan &#8212; has not changed at all.&nbsp; We remain committed to supporting the peace and stability across the Taiwan Straits and ensuring that there is no unilateral change to the status quo.&nbsp;<br><br>I would add that one of the reasons why it&#8217;s so important that Putin pay a dear price for his barbarism in Ukraine: The idea that on your station today and every other station in America they’re showing bombings of every school &#8212; no &#8212; no military purpose &#8212; schools, hospitals, daycare centers, all the things, museums &#8212; blowing up all the museums.&nbsp; I believe what Putin is attempting to do is eliminate the identity of Ukraine &#8212; the identity.&nbsp; He can&#8217;t occupy it, but he can try to destroy its identity.&nbsp;<br><br>And the reason I bother to mention that is: He has to pay and Russia has to pay a long-term price for that, in terms of the sanctions that have been imposed.&nbsp;<br><br>And the reason I bother to say this &#8212; it’s not just about Ukraine: If, in fact, after all he&#8217;s done there&#8217;s a rapprochement met between China &#8212; I mean, excuse me, between the Ukrainians and &#8212; and Russia, and these sanctions are not continued to be sustained in many ways, then what signal does that send to China about the cost of attempting &#8212; attempting to take Taiwan by force?&nbsp; They&#8217;re already flirting with danger right now by flying so close and all the maneuvers they’ve undertaken.&nbsp;<br><br>But the United States is committed.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made a commitment.&nbsp; We support the One China policy.&nbsp; We support all &#8212; all that we&#8217;ve done in the past, but that does not mean &#8212; it does not mean that China has the ability &#8212; has the &#8212; excuse me, the jurisdiction to go in and use force to take over Taiwan.&nbsp;<br><br>So we stand firmly with Japan and with other nations that &#8212; not to let that happen.&nbsp; And my expectation is it will not happen; it will not be attempted.&nbsp;<br><br>And my expectation is &#8212; a lot of it depends upon just how strongly the world makes clear that that kind of action is going to result in long-term disapprobation by the rest of the community.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Very quickly: You didn&#8217;t want to get involved in the Ukraine conflict militarily for obvious reasons.&nbsp; Are you willing to get involved militarily to defend Taiwan, if it comes to that?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You are?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; That&#8217;s the commitment we made.&nbsp; That’s the commitment we made.&nbsp; We are not &#8212;<br><br>Look, here&#8217;s the situation: We agree with the One China policy; we’ve signed on to it and all the attendant agreements made from there.&nbsp; But the idea that &#8212; that it can be taken by force &#8212; just taken by force &#8212; is just not a &#8212; is just not appropriate.&nbsp; It will dislocate the entire region and be another action similar to what happened in &#8212; in Ukraine.&nbsp; And so, it&#8217;s a burden that is even stronger.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you very much.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; This will be the end of the joint press conference by Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden.&nbsp; Thank you very much for your cooperation.&nbsp;<br><br>2:58 P.M. JST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Holds Justice40 Week of Action to Highlight Historic Investments in Overburdened and Underserved&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-holds-justice40-week-of-action-to-highlight-historic-investments-in-overburdened-and-underserved-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[White House announces that over $29 billion in funding opportunities have already incorporated Justice40 considerations President Biden’s Executive Order on Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad laid the foundation for the most ambitious environmental justice agenda ever undertaken by an Administration—committing to center communities overburdened by pollution, on the frontlines of climate impacts,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>White House announces that over $29 billion in funding opportunities have already incorporated Justice40 considerations</em></p>



<p>President Biden’s Executive Order on <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/executive-order-on-tackling-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad/">Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad</a> laid the foundation for the most ambitious environmental justice agenda ever undertaken by an Administration—committing to center communities overburdened by pollution, on the frontlines of climate impacts, and marginalized by decades of underinvestment.</p>



<p>As part of this historic commitment to environmental justice, President Biden created the&nbsp;Justice40 Initiative&nbsp;to ensure that federal agencies deliver 40 percent of the overall benefits of climate, clean energy, affordable and sustainable housing, clean water, and other investments to disadvantaged communities. In total, hundreds of federal programs, representing billions of dollars in annual investment—including programs that were funded or created in the President’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/16/the-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-advances-environmental-justice/">Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</a>—are being &nbsp;utilized to maximize benefits to disadvantaged communities through the Justice40 Initiative.</p>



<p>At the start of 2022, the Biden-Harris Administration marked <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/26/fact-sheet-a-year-advancing-environmental-justice/">a year of progress</a> on advancing environmental justice. Today, the Administration is launching a Justice40 Week of Action to highlight additional steps that are delivering real benefits to communities across the country. The Administration is kicking off the week with announcements including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Clean School Buses:</strong> The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) <a href="https://www.epa.gov/cleanschoolbus">announced $500 million in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding</a> to begin replacing the nation’s fleet of school buses with clean, American-made, zero-emission buses, while prioritizing applications from school districts serving disadvantaged communities.</li><li><strong>Snapshot of Justice40 Funding Rollouts To-Date: </strong>The White House Office of Management and Budget released a snapshot of over $29 billion in new funding opportunity notifications and announcements that the Biden-Harris Administration has already rolled out to deliver on the Justice40 Initiative—with much more on the way. To put that figure in context, the President’s FY23 budget request for climate and environmental justice&nbsp;discretionaryfunding totals about $45 billion.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Progress on Key Recommendations:</strong> The White House Council on Environmental Quality (CEQ) released a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2022/05/23/biden-harris-administration-outlines-historic-progress-on-environmental-justice-in-report-submitted-to-congress-2/">report submitted to Congress</a>, outlining steps the Biden-Harris Administration has taken to implement recommendations from the first-ever White House Environmental Justice Advisory Council (WHEJAC), including regarding the Justice40 Initiative.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Outreach and Listening Sessions:</strong> The White House launched a Justice40 stakeholder engagement series to provide updates on how leaders at the agency, state, and community level are using the mandate of the President’s Justice40 Initiative to deliver benefits to disadvantaged communities, and for Administration officials to hear community input on opportunities to maximize these benefits.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Environmental Justice Website:</strong> The White House launched a new website, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/environmentaljustice">WhiteHouse.gov/EnvironmentalJustice</a><strong> </strong>to provide a public platform and centralized location for the Administration’s environmental justice priorities, including the Justice40 Initiative.</li></ul>



<p>These actions will be followed throughout the week by additional announcements from across the Biden-Harris Administration. Although there is much more work to do, this Administration has made historic strides to realize the vision of the Justice40 Initiative, including:</p>



<p><strong><u>Delivering Historic and Long Overdue Investments in Disadvantaged Communities</u></strong><br><br>President Biden and Vice President Harris secured $5 billion in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law for a key environmental justice priority—clean school buses to protect our kids and neighborhoods from dirty diesel exhaust. Last week, Vice President Harris joined EPA Administrator Regan to <a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/biden-harris-administration-makes-500-million-available-clean-school-buses-through-epa">announce</a> that $500 million is now available for school districts and other eligible school bus operators and contractors to begin replacing the nation’s fleet of school buses with clean, American-made, low and zero-emission buses. New, clean school buses will produce cleaner air for students, bus drivers, school staff working near the bus loading areas, and the communities that the buses drive through each day. This investment, like other climate and clean energy-related Bipartisan Infrastructure Law investments, are included in the President’s Justice40 Initiative and will prioritize applications that will replace buses serving high-need local education agencies, Tribal schools, and rural areas.</p>



<p>Over the last year, the Biden-Harris Administration has already made available tens-of-billions of dollars in funding opportunity notifications and announcements to deliver on the Justice40 Initiative. A new compilation from the White House Office of Management and Budget provides a snapshot of at least $29 billion of these opportunities. This initial wave of funding includes announcements on:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Remediating and Reducing Legacy Pollution.</strong> Using funding from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, the EPA announced $1.3 billion for various grants that will remediate and reduce pollution, such as cleaning up <a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/biden-administration-announces-254-million-tackle-polluted-brownfield-sites">brownfield</a> and <a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-announces-plans-use-first-1b-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-funds-clear-out">Superfund</a> sites, and reducing <a href="https://www.grants.gov/web/grants/view-opportunity.html?oppId=338182">lead in drinking water</a>, to benefit disadvantaged communities. The Department of the Interior (DOI) also announced $725 million for reclaiming <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-administration-announces-nearly-725-million-create-good-paying-union-jobs">abandoned mine lands</a>. Funds will help communities eliminate dangerous environmental hazards and pollution caused by past coal mining, while creating good-paying jobs and providing opportunities to revitalize coal communities. Additionally, DOI announced the availability of $775 million in initial grants to states for <a href="https://www.doi.gov/sites/doi.gov/files/state-initial-grant-guidance-4-11-22.pdf">plugging orphaned oil and gas wells</a> to clean up these environmental and safety hazards, create good-paying union jobs, catalyze economic growth and revitalization in disadvantaged communities, and shut down sources of harmful methane emissions. DOI is also taking action to clean up orphaned wells on federal lands, giving priority to wells in proximity to disadvantaged communities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Improving Water Quality. </strong>&nbsp;The EPA announced more than $9.6 billion through EPA’s <a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-announces-additional-19-billion-state-revolving-loan-funds-water-infrastructure">State Revolving Funds</a> to accelerate progress on water infrastructure projects. This funding helps states, Tribes, and territories upgrade water infrastructure to provide safe drinking water and protect vital water resources.&nbsp; EPA is continuing to work with states, Tribes, and territories to ensure that disadvantaged communities fully benefit from these historic investments. EPA Administrator Regan <a href="https://www.epa.gov/system/files/documents/2021-12/governors-bil-letter-final-508.pdf">sent a letter</a> to Governors in December 2021encouraging&nbsp; them to target the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funds toward disadvantaged communities and those most impacted by urgent water challenges.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Reducing Transportation Emissions and Improving the Nation’s Transportation Infrastructure.</strong> The Department of Transportation (DOT) announced $1.47 billion to states, local government authorities, and Tribes, including $1.1 billion for the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2022-03-04/pdf/2022-04621.pdf">Bus and Bus Facilities and Low or No Emission grant programs</a>. In order to access this funding, applicants are required to describe specific environmental justice activities that have been incorporated in the application and, provide evidence of strategies used in the planning process to seek out and consider the needs of those historically disadvantaged and underserved by existing transportation systems. DOT also announced over $6 billion for surface transportation projects with significant national or regional impact. The Department seeks to fund projects that benefit low-income communities, disadvantaged communities, communities underserved by affordable transportation, or overburdened communities.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Department of Energy (DOE) announced over $3 billion for <a href="https://www.energy.gov/sites/default/files/2022-03/wpn-bil-22-2.pdf">Weatherization Assistance Program</a> formula grants from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that will reduce energy costs for low-income households by increasing the energy efficiency of their homes, while ensuring health and safety and creating jobs. DOE also announced over $3 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law for competitive solicitations in areas including advanced battery manufacturing and clean energy R&amp;D. These solicitations support achievement of the Administration’s Justice40 Initiative goals in a variety of ways, including ensuring development of environmental justice analyses, requiring applicants to describe how the technology being developed has the potential to advance equity and energy justice and revitalize the economies of coal, oil and gas, and power plant communities, or defining success metrics that include the advancement of environmental justice and economic revitalization initiatives.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Building Community Resilience and Advancing Nature-Based Solutions.</strong> The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/09/fact-sheet-biden-administration-announces-nearly-5-billion-in-resilience-funding-to-help-communities-prepare-for-extreme-weather-and-climate-related-disasters/">announced</a> $1.2 billion for states, local governments, territories and Tribes, under the Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities (BRIC) program and Flood Mitigation Assistance, to help communities build resilience to natural disasters thanks to the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The Biden-Harris Administration implemented a number of changes to enhance funding opportunities for Tribes and disadvantaged communities, including by changing program selection criteria and providing a larger allocation for Tribes. Additionally, the Department of Agriculture announced $1 billion in <a href="https://www.usda.gov/climate-solutions/climate-smart-commodities">Partnerships for Climate-Smart Commodities</a> to support the production and marketing of climate-smart commodities through a set of pilot projects. Projects funded through this funding opportunity will build markets and invest in America’s climate-smart farmers, ranchers, and forest owners to strengthen U.S. rural and agricultural communities, including through the meaningful inclusion of small and underserved producers and early adopters.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Providing Healthy and Affordable Housing. </strong>The Department of Housing and Urban Development announced $759.7 million for grants to supportsustainable and affordable housing in disadvantaged, Tribal, and low-socioeconomic communities, including $365 million to identify, remediate, and protect the most vulnerable and disadvantaged from the harmful effects of lead-based paints in homes.</li></ul>



<p>In response to the Administration’s Justice40 efforts, philanthropic, labor and nonprofit organizations have also committed new resources to assist communities in Justice40 implementation—including the <a href="https://www.justice40accelerator.org/">Justice40 Accelerator</a>, a partnership between Elevate, Groundswell, The Hummingbird Firm, Partnership for Southern Equity and the Solutions Project that are working together to ensure the tools and resources are in place for frontline organizations to be prepared to access the benefits of the Justice40 Initiative.</p>



<p><strong><u>Renewing a Focus on Environmental Justice Across the Federal Government</u></strong></p>



<p>Today, the White House Council on Environmental Quality (CEQ) released a report submitted to Congress that outlines how the Biden-Harris Administration has addressed recommendations from the first-ever White House Environmental Justice Advisory Council (WHEJAC). The report fulfills a statutory obligation under the Federal Advisory Committee Act to provide a report to Congress within one year of receiving recommendations from a Federal Advisory Committee. The report is a formal response to recommendations the WHEJAC provided on the Justice40 Initiative, the Climate and Economic Justice Screening Tool, and revisions on Executive Order 12898 Executive Order 12898 on&nbsp;<em>Federal Actions&nbsp;To&nbsp;Address Environmental Justice in Minority Populations and Low-Income Populations</em>.</p>



<p>The report submitted by CEQ to Congress contains detailed status updates from fifteen agencies to the WHEJAC’s recommendations on the Justice40 Initiative. In keeping with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to improving transparency in government, the report illustrates how Federal agencies are advancing and implementing the President’s commitment to environmental justice right now. The report also summarizes actions that agencies are taking—informed by nearly 200 recommendations from the WHEJAC—to ensure that the benefits of key programs are reaching the communities that need them most.</p>



<p><strong><u>Elevating the Voices of Environmental Justice Communities &nbsp;<br></u></strong></p>



<p>The White House announced the launch of a Justice40 stakeholder engagement series that will bring Administration officials into communities to both listen to the concerns of stakeholders and identify ways to magnify the impact of Justice40 covered programs. This stakeholder engagement began with a public Justice40 update briefing with senior Administration officials highlighting leaders at the agency, state and community level who are using the mandate of the President’s Justice40 Initiative to deliver benefits to disadvantaged communities.<br><br>The White House also announced the launch of a new website, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/environmentaljustice">WhiteHouse.gov/EnvironmentalJustice</a>, which provides a public platform and centralized location for information about the Administration’s environmental justice priorities and initiatives, such as the Justice40 Initiative and the White House Environmental Justice Interagency Council, as well as news and updates on environmental justice across the whole-of-government.</p>



<p>This week also marks the closure of the extended public comment period for the beta version of the <a href="https://screeningtool.geoplatform.gov/en">Climate and Economic Justice Screening Tool</a>. This geospatial mapping tool will provide important information for the <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/d/2021-02177/p-163">Justice40 Initiative</a> by helping agencies to identify disadvantaged communities that are marginalized, underserved, and overburdened by pollution. The tool was released in a beta version in order to receive feedback from the public, Tribal Nations, and Federal agencies.&nbsp; After hearing from environmental justice leaders, community-based organizations and allied groups, and members of the public from across the country, CEQ <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2022/04/21/ceq-extends-public-comment-period-on-beta-version-of-the-climate-and-economic-justice-screening-tool/">extended</a> the public comment period until May 25, 2022. An updated version of the screening tool, along with an updated technical support document, will be released after the feedback from the public comment period, Tribal consultations, and meetings with Federal agencies has been reviewed. The screening tool will be continually updated as new data and research become available.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Indo-Pacific Economic Framework For Prosperity Launch&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/23/remarks-by-president-biden-at-indo-pacific-economic-framework-for-prosperity-launch-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Izumi Garden GalleryTokyo, Japan 4:42 P.M. JST PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Thank you all for joining today for the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity. Prime Minister Kishida, thank you for your leadership and partnership as we prepared for this announcement. We’re launching today with countries from across the Indo-Pacific &#8212; Australia, Brunei, India &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Izumi Garden Gallery<br>Tokyo, Japan</p>



<p>4:42 P.M. JST<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Thank you all for joining today for the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity.</p>



<p>Prime Minister Kishida, thank you for your leadership and partnership as we prepared for this announcement.</p>



<p>We’re launching today with countries from across the Indo-Pacific &#8212; Australia, Brunei, India &#8212; and, by the way, Mr. Prime Minister, thank you for being here as well &#8212; Prime Minister of India &#8212; the Republic of Korea, Malaysia, and New Zealand, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam.</p>



<p>And we’re here today for one simple purpose: The future of the 21st century economy is going to be largely written in the Indo-Pacific &#8212; in our region.</p>



<p>The Indo-Pacific covers half the population of the world and more than 60 percent of the global GDP.&nbsp; And the nations represented here today, and those who will join this framework in the future, are signing up to work toward an economic vision that will deliver for all peoples &#8212; all our peoples: the vision for an Indo-Pacific that is free and open, connected and prosperous, and secure as well as resilient, where our economic &#8212; where economic growth is sustainable and is inclusive.</p>



<p>We’re writing the new rules for the 21st century economy that are going to help all of our countries’ economies grow faster and fairer.</p>



<p>We’ll do that by taking on some of the most acute challenges that drag down growth and by maximizing the potential of our strongest growth engines.</p>



<p>Let’s start with new rules governing trade in digital goods and services so companies don’t have to hand over the proprietary technology to do business in a country.</p>



<p>Let’s create a first-of-its-kind supply chain commitments to eliminate bottlenecks in critical supply chains and develop early warning systems so we can identify problems before they occur.</p>



<p>And let’s &#8212; let’s pursue other first-of-its-kind commitments to clean energy and decarbonization.</p>



<p>The climate crisis is an existential threat that is costing us trillions in economic damage, but there’s also incredible potential and opportunity to solve problems and create good jobs by transitioning to a clean energy economies.<br><br>Let&#8217;s choke off the loopholes that get at the corruption that steals our public resources.&nbsp;<br>It’s &#8212; it’s estimated that corruption saps between 2 to 5 percent of global GDP.&nbsp; It exacerbates inequality.&nbsp; It hollows out a country’s ability to deliver for its citizens.&nbsp;<br>And tax and trade belongs in the same framework, because if companies aren’t paying their fair share, it’s harder for governments to pay for Trade Adjustment Assistance or to fund education or health services, or a range of public investments &#8212; that make it so hard for families, it feels like they can&#8217;t raise their children and give them a better life.</p>



<p>That’s ultimately my economic policy and &#8212; and foreign and domestic &#8212; what our foreign and domestic policy is about.&nbsp; And that’s what this framework is about as well.</p>



<p>So, starting today with 13 economies &#8212; economies that represent diverse sets of perspectives as we work on pursuing our common goals.</p>



<p>That’s critical because a key to our success will be the framework’s emphasis on high standards and inclusivity.&nbsp; This framework should drive a race to the top among the nations in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>



<p>And I want to be clear that the framework will be open to others who wish to join in the future if they sign up and meet the goals and work to achieve those goals.</p>



<p>I’m glad to have seen so many of you in person this &#8212; the past two weeks.&nbsp; At the U.S.-ASEAN Summit, I saw many of you in Washington, and during my travels to Asia.&nbsp; And I’m eager to hear from each of you today.</p>



<p>I thank you for taking the time to be part of this framework launch.</p>



<p>And let me close by saying the United States is deeply invested in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; We’re committed for the long haul, ready to champion our vision for a positive future for the region together with friends and partners, including the nations in this room and on the screen.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;It’s a priority in our agenda, and we’re going to keep working to make progress with all of you every day so that we can deliver real, concrete benefits for all our people.</p>



<p>That’s how I believe we will win the competition of the 21st century together.</p>



<p>So thank all of you again for joining today.&nbsp; And I’ll invite Prime Minister Kishida to say a few words now.<br><br>Mr. Prime Minister.<br><br>(Event participants give remarks.)<br><br>SECRETARY BLINKEN:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Secretary.&nbsp; Mr. President, the floor is yours for closing remarks.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I’ll be brief.&nbsp; First of all, let me say thank you for everyone for joining today.&nbsp; And thank you very much for hosting us, Mr. Prime Minister.<br><br>The &#8212; we launched this new framework.&nbsp; I appreciate hearing from all of you and for your contributions.&nbsp; And it’s clear there will be a lot of hard work ahead of us to forge consensus on each of the framework pillars.<br><br>But in our discussions today, it’s clear that we all recognize the fundamental direction we need to move in.&nbsp; We share the same goal of ensuring a free and open Indo-Pacific that will deliver greater prosperity and greater opportunity for all of our children.<br><br>So let’s all take all the tasks that we have together, work together coming out of this launch, and to speed our progress toward that goal and work rapidly to develop the first commitments.<br><br>So thank you again, Prime Minster Kishida, for your strong leadership in this launch and for welcoming us here in Tokyo.<br><br>I’m looking forward to continuing to work with all of you and to strengthen the economic cooperation to deliver inclusive growth and shared prosperity.<br><br>You’re all probably tired of seeing me all this time &#8212; after all this time, in the last couple of months, but thank you again.&nbsp; I really appreciate the work you’re all doing.&nbsp; And we can &#8212; I think we can make some real progress.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>5:27 P.M. JST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Fumio Kishida of Japan During Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/23/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-fumio-kishida-of-japan-during-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Akasaka PalaceTokyo, Japan 11:30 A.M. JST&#160;PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&#160; (As interpreted.)&#160; President Joe Biden, I am absolutely delighted to be able to welcome you to Tokyo for the first time as the U.S. President.&#160;Your visit to Japan this time demonstrates that whatever the situation may be, the United States will continue to strengthen its engagement in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Akasaka Palace<br>Tokyo, Japan</p>



<p>11:30 A.M. JST<br>&nbsp;<br>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; President Joe Biden, I am absolutely delighted to be able to welcome you to Tokyo for the first time as the U.S. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>Your visit to Japan this time demonstrates that whatever the situation may be, the United States will continue to strengthen its engagement in the Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp; And I sincerely welcome your presence here with us today in Japan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Russia’s aggression against Ukraine undermines the foundation of global order, and we can in no way allow whatsoever such attempts to change the status quo by force wherever it may be in the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>That is exactly why, during this time, it is when Japan and the United States &#8212; two nations that share fundamental values &#8212; should strongly lead the international community to realize a free and open Indo-Pacific based on the rule of law.<br>&nbsp;<br>And in doing so, I very much look forward to having a very productive meeting between you, President of the United States, and Japan during your visit here in Tokyo.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, Mr. Prime Minister, thank you for the welcome. &nbsp;I&#8217;m delighted that you’re welcoming me.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s been &#8212; it&#8217;s been a good relationship we had thus far.&nbsp; It&#8217;s great to be with you again and to continue our discussions on how Japan and the United States can harness our alliance as a positive force not only in the region, but in the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>The U.S.-Japanese alliance has long been the cornerstone of peace and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific, and the United States remains fully committed to Japanese dis- &#8212; to Japan&#8217;s defense.&nbsp; And we will face the challenges of today and the future together.<br>&nbsp;<br>Later today, we’ll launch a new Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, the purpose of which is to increase our cooperation with other nations in the region and to deliver concrete benefits for the people of the Indo-Pacific region.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Japan is also a key &#8212; key global leader, working with our G7 partners to hold Putin accountable for his war in Ukraine and to stand up for our shared democratic values.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank you, Mr. Prime Minister, for your strong leadership and your support of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; It was welcomed more than you will know.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, again, Fumio, thank you for welcoming me to Japan and my team and, of course, for hosting the Quad Summit tomorrow.&nbsp; Two great democracies in the Indo-Pacific are &#8212; are always looking for ways to do more together to bring us closer.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m looking forward to taking &#8212; and talking to you more about these issues and the matters of the days ahead, but well beyond that time.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You&#8217;re a good friend.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>11:37 A.M. JST&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On-the-Record Press Call on the Launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic&#160;Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/23/on-the-record-press-call-on-the-launch-of-the-indo-pacific-economic-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 07:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[7:09 P.M. JST MR. PATEL:&#160; Good evening, everybody.&#160; Thanks so much for joining.&#160; This call will be on the record and embargoed until 4:15 Japan Standard Time tomorrow, May 23rd.&#160; Joining us for this briefing, we have National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, and U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai. We, of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>7:09 P.M. JST</p>



<p>MR. PATEL:&nbsp; Good evening, everybody.&nbsp; Thanks so much for joining.&nbsp; This call will be on the record and embargoed until 4:15 Japan Standard Time tomorrow, May 23rd.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Joining us for this briefing, we have National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, and U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai.</p>



<p>We, of course, will have some time for questions at the end, but I will turn it over to Jake to kick us off.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And thanks, everybody, for joining this evening.&nbsp; And thanks to my colleagues and partners, Secretary Raimondo and Ambassador Tai.</p>



<p>I wanted to just start with some broad comments about the thrust and purpose of IPEF, and then – and then turn it over to the Secretary and the Ambassador to dive into some more detail on the key substantive elements of the framework.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, or IPEF, is part of President Biden&#8217;s commitment to putting American families and workers at the center of our economic and foreign policy, while strengthening our ties with allies and partners for the purpose of increasing shared prosperity and for the purpose of defining the coming decades for technological innovation in the global economy &#8212; especially in the most vital region for the coming decades, the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>The President will launch IPEF in Tokyo, Japan, on Monday.&nbsp; And joining him for that launch will be the initial IPEF partner countries.&nbsp; They are as follows: Australia, Brunei, India, Indonesia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Malaysia, New Zealand, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam.&nbsp; Alongside the United States, that&#8217;s 13 countries launching this &#8212; a baker&#8217;s dozen.</p>



<p>But, of course, as we&#8217;ve also indicated from the start, this is an open platform.&nbsp; So there are other countries that could conceivably join us as we move forward.</p>



<p>Together, this very diverse set of economies represent around 40 percent of global GDP.&nbsp; And the fact that we have such a range and a significant number of partner countries in on the ground floor for the launch reflects the far-reaching ambition of the framework and also indicates that there&#8217;s deep interest across the region in it.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve got major economies, emerging economies, economies with which we have free trade agreements, and others for which this will be the United States’ first economic negotiation.</p>



<p>And that diversity of members is consistent with both the vision of IPEF and consonant with the fact that the four-pillar structure that we&#8217;ve built has flexibility and creativity designed into it so that we can, in fact, accommodate this diverse range of countries.</p>



<p>One more thing, just to say on the membership: We believe that we&#8217;re heading into this launch with a really significant amount of momentum, really, especially coming out of the U.S.-ASEAN Summit that the President hosted just a few days ago.&nbsp; It was at that summit that he had the opportunity to really share his vision for this framework with key leaders in ASEAN.&nbsp; And we are proud that seven ASEAN countries have joined with many of our other close partners in the region as part of IPEF.</p>



<p>IPEF is a 21st century economic arrangement designed to tackle 21st century economic challenges, ranging from setting the rules of the road for the digital economy, to ensuring secure and resilient supply chains, to helping make the kinds of major investments necessary in clean energy infrastructure and the clean energy transition, to raising standards for transparency, fair taxation, and anti-corruption.</p>



<p>We believe that expanding U.S. economic leadership in the Indo-Pacific through vehicles like IPEF is good for America &#8212; American workers and businesses as well as for the people in the region. &nbsp;</p>



<p>With 60 percent of the world&#8217;s population, the Indo-Pacific is projected to be the largest contributor to global growth over the next 30 years.&nbsp; And trade with the Indo-Pacific supports more than 3 million American jobs, as well as being the source of nearly $900 billion in foreign direct investment in the United States &#8212; (inaudible) global economic growth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the United States, for our part, is an Indo-Pacific economic power.&nbsp; Foreign direct investment in the region from the United States totaled more than $969 billion in 2020 and has nearly doubled in the last decade.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the United States is the primary exporter of services to the region, which in turn not only fuels regional growth and prosperity and greater security, but it also supports American jobs at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That being said, we and our partners in the region agree that much in the coming decades will depend on how well governments harness innovation, especially the transformations underway in clean energy and the digital and technology sectors, while at the same time fortifying our economies from a range of threats from fragile supply chains, to corruption, to tax havens.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact is that past models did not address these challenges &#8212; or did not address them fully and take them head on &#8212; leaving our workers, businesses, and consumers more vulnerable.&nbsp; So we believe that we need a new model that we can move on quickly to, in fact, take these challenges head on, and that&#8217;s what IPEF will do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve spent months engaging with major partners in the region.&nbsp; And the broad participation is a reflection of that investment of time and effort and energy, as well as with organized labor, the business community, bipartisan members of Congress and other key stakeholders to chart the way forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just a couple of more points before I turned to my colleagues &#8212; in terms of diving into the four pillars of IPEF.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One, the fact that this is not a traditional free trade agreement is a feature of IPEF not a bug.&nbsp; There are free trade traditionalists who have raised questions about it.&nbsp; Our fundamental view is that the new landscape and the new challenges we face need a new approach, and we will shape the substance of this effort together with our partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second is that IPEF should be seen both as a coherent whole; it is a vision of the modern economy and the way to get &#8212; it’s a way to tackle the challenges and seize the opportunities of that economy.&nbsp; But it also &#8212; it should also be seen as an opportunity to drive initiatives, in part.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, for example, if we can rapidly develop an early warning system for critical supply chains, we will not wait until all of IPEF is complete to roll that out and move forward on it.&nbsp; So different elements of this could end up moving at different speeds, even as all of the pieces will end up fitting into a larger integrated framework.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally &#8212; and I think this is really critical &#8212; this is a foundational element of our overall strategy towards the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; We believe that IPEF brings shape and coherence to the economic pillar of our Indo-Pacific strategy.&nbsp; We think it sets us up for success in helping to shape the future of the region in a way that produces a region that is free, open, connected, resilient, and secure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We all know that economics is a critical part of succeeding with any strategy in the Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp; And we see IPEF as a vital platform for our engagement and a chance, alongside all of the other ways in which we have elevated our engagement in the Indo-Pacific, to put our stamp on this critical region for decades to come, and to ensure that American leadership delivers good outcomes for our people and for all the people in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with those opening framing comments, let me turn it over to Secretary Raimondo.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Thank you, Jake.&nbsp; And thank you, everybody, for joining us on the call this evening.&nbsp; So I will add on with a few more points to what Jake said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I&#8217;ll begin by saying just how excited we are for the launch tomorrow of this Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.&nbsp; As Jake said, it consists of 13 countries, which account for 40 percent of global GDP.&nbsp; And on top of that, it includes some of the world&#8217;s fastest-growing, most dynamic economies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is &#8212; it is, by any account, the most significant international economic engagement that the United States has ever had in this region.&nbsp; And the launch of it tomorrow, here in Tokyo, marks an important turning point in restoring U.S. economic leadership in the region and presenting Indo-Pacific countries an alternative to China&#8217;s approach to these critical issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since I&#8217;ve been Commerce Secretary, I have heard over and over again from the U.S. business community that they will benefit from &#8212; they and their employees will benefit from the U.S. restoring and re-exerting economic leadership in the region &#8212; an increasingly important region to U.S. businesses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there is also a strong demand signal coming from the region.&nbsp; We hear over and over again in the Indo-Pacific region that there is a desire for U.S. economic leadership and for the U.S. to have a proactive economic vision and economic agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Jake said, this framework is intentionally designed not to be a “same old, same old” traditional trade agreement.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s designed as a more innovative and flexible approach, designed to reflect the fact that our economies have changed.&nbsp; The most pressing issues that we need to tackle with our allies have changed, and we need a new approach going forward if we&#8217;re going to meet the needs of our citizens.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, by focusing on economic priorities that affect all of our economies, this framework is designed to reflect the shared realities we face, which is climate change; the opportunity and challenges presented by moving, meeting the need of climate change and the opportunity of clean tech jobs; supply chain disruptions; and the need for a better-coordinated, high-tech manufacturing economy.</p>



<p>As Jake said, there are four pillars in the framework.&nbsp; The Department of Commerce will be leading three of the four pillars, which is: the supply chain resiliency pillar, clean energy and decarbonization pillar, and tax and anti-corruption.</p>



<p>Just very quickly on each one.&nbsp; On supply chains, I think we all have seen how &#8212; the cost of supply chains that aren&#8217;t resilient.&nbsp; And COVID exposes incredible economic costs of insufficient supply chain resilience.</p>



<p>We saw &#8212; frankly, we continue to say all the ways that bottlenecks and lack of transparency in the Indo-Pacific cause ripple effects throughout the United States economy, hurting workers and driving inflation.&nbsp; And, you know, we&#8217;ve learned that “just in time” leaves much to be desired.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say if we had had this Indo-Pacific Economic Framework and the agreement therein in place before COVID, I think we could have experienced much less disruption.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, during COVID, we saw semiconductor packaging operations in Malaysia be closed on account of COVID outbreaks.&nbsp; The result of that was thousands of workers were put out of work in Michigan auto-manufacturing plants.&nbsp; And if we had had more transparency, more communication, more data-sharing, and an early alert system, that may not have happened.&nbsp; And the workers who were furloughed in a Michigan plant would not have experienced that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in IPEF, we are seeking to develop a first-of-its-kind supply chain agreement that better anticipates, predicts, and, importantly, prevents disruptions in supply chains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the clean energy and infrastructure pillar, we all know jobs of the future are going to be in clean tech manufacturing and innovation, and so we want to work with partners in this agreement to view clean energy as a driver of job creation and economic growth.&nbsp; And to support this pillar, we will be signing agreements to pursue concrete, high-ambition commitments such as renewable energy targets, carbon removal purchasing commitments, energy efficiency standards, and new measures to combat methane emissions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, the third pillar Commerce is leading on is the tax and anti-corruption.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to be working to ensure everybody plays by the same set of rules, because corruption is a huge drag on everyone&#8217;s economy.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to be seeking commitments to enact and enforce effective tax, anti-money laundering, anti-bribery schemes in line with our values.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I guess I&#8217;ll just close by saying: This is an exciting time.&nbsp; I want to thank all of our partner countries for working with us.&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking forward &#8212; tomorrow is the beginning; I&#8217;m anxious to begin and get to work and discuss the next steps ahead as we negotiate the specific terms and develop the details of this framework and, you know, establishing a new approach to regional economic engagement.</p>



<p>This has never been done before, in terms of the ambition and inclusivity across a broad range of regional partners.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m confident that there&#8217;ll be benefits for U.S. businesses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would say, especially as businesses are beginning to increasingly look for alternatives to China, the countries in the Indo-Pacific Framework will be more reliable partners for U.S. businesses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re excited to get going and develop a framework that will be durable and beneficial for American businesses and workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I will turn it over to my partner in this endeavor, Ambassador Katherine Tai.</p>



<p>AMBASSADOR TAI:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Gina.&nbsp; I will spend some time to talk about the trade pillar.&nbsp; From day one of his administration, President Biden has been clear that we have to rethink what trade policy can be in the 21st century and that it must benefit more people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For decades, trade policy was often reduced to a zero-sum game that left many of our workers behind.&nbsp; And that is why we are designing trade policies that aim to deliver real economic prosperity and advance our global priorities, like combating climate change, protecting labor rights, and building resilient supply chains.&nbsp; These issues are not mutually exclusive; we can and must do both.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the last several months, USTR, the NSC, and the Department of Commerce have worked with our trading partners, members of Congress, and a diverse range of stakeholders on the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework that the President will launch tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At its core, the Economic Framework will link major economies and emerging ones to tackle 21st century challenges and promote fair and resilient trade for years to come.&nbsp; At the same time, it will be designed to adapt to address barriers and obstacles that may arise in the future as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You heard Gina describe three of the pillars.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll walk through the details of the trade pillar that USTR will lead in order to create a more connected and resilient economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will work with our IPEF partners on a wide range of trade issues, including the digital economy and emerging technology, labor commitments, the environment, trade facilitation, transparency and good regulatory practices, and corporate accountability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The digital economy in particular best represents an area where we need to work with our IPEF partners, given the prominent role it plays in today&#8217;s global marketplace and how it affects our workers, our consumers, and our businesses.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we will address issues in the digital economy that will help build connectivity and trust between key markets, including standards on cross-border data flows and data localizations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will also work with our partners to address other digital concerns such as online privacy, discriminatory and unethical use of artificial intelligence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Collectively, the trade pillar will unlock enormous economic value, including for small- and medium-sized businesses that historically have not benefited from trade agreements as much as their large counterparts have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also intend to pursue an accelerated implementation of the World Trade Organization&#8217;s Trade Facilitation Agreement, which will also address and improve the movement of goods across borders.&nbsp; We will see commitments with IPEF partners that facilitate agricultural trade through science-based decision making and the adoption of sound, transparent regulatory practices.&nbsp; This will help our farmers, our ranchers, and our fishers gain certainty for getting their products to the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While these provisions will help promote inclusive economic prosperity, we also want this framework be part of our broader strategy to make trade a race to the top.&nbsp; And that is why the IPEF will pursue an agenda for setting strong labor and environmental standards and corporate accountability provisions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In raising regional standards, we can set an example for the rest of the world to follow, which in turn helps all of our workers and communities.&nbsp; Our aim is for the IPEF to address the challenges in the 21st century global economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow begins the next chapter of our collaboration with our key partners in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I look forward to convening our partners in the months ahead in a range of forms.&nbsp; We will continue to work with stakeholders, as we have done for the last several months, to ensure a diverse range of interests and concerns are represented.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will work with members of Congress in both parties.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, of course, we will make frequent trips to the Indo-Pacific to engage leaders in this region and continue our discussions to create a fairer, more resilient economy for families, workers, and business in the United States and here in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is truly a team effort.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m grateful to Jake Sullivan and Secretary Raimondo for their work in bringing this framework to life.&nbsp; We believe it will deliver on the President&#8217;s vision of trade policy that promotes widespread economic growth and advances our shared global priorities.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m excited to continue to keep all of you updated on our progress as we move forward.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. PATEL:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; We will move into taking some folks’ questions.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call is on the record, but it is embargoed until 4:15 Japan Standard Time tomorrow, May 23th.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So with that, why don&#8217;t we start with Nancy Cook at Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing the call.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp; Just an overview question.&nbsp; You know, you talked a lot in the call about the commitments that you&#8217;re going to seek for these &#8212; for countries to join this agreement.&nbsp; Are there any requirements?&nbsp; Like, are you requiring participants to do anything?&nbsp; Or is it really, like, suggestions and recommendations and commitments that you&#8217;re seeking?</p>



<p>Really, I&#8217;m asking: Are there binding things or non-binding things?</p>



<p>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; So, this is Secretary Raimondo.&nbsp; I would say there will certainly be &#8212; like any other agreement, it will be a negotiation at which will &#8212; which will, you know, begin post-launch.&nbsp; So after tomorrow, we&#8217;ll spend the next &#8212; you know, the weeks ahead, scoping out each pillar.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, yes, there will be firm commitments.&nbsp; There will be signed agreements.&nbsp; And like any agreement, you know, we plan to have high-standard commitments that will be enforceable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, also, like any agreement, I would say the greatest enforcement is that if you don&#8217;t hold up your end of the bargain, you don&#8217;t receive the benefits.&nbsp; And so there will be incentives to go ahead and live up to the commitments that will be part of the agreement.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up, Secretary Raimondo: But tomorrow &#8212; like, what you&#8217;re unveiling tomorrow, there are not commitments in place at this point.&nbsp; There are not, like, binding things.&nbsp; Those are going to be negotiated moving forward.&nbsp; Is that right?</p>



<p>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp; Yes, exactly.&nbsp; Tomorrow is the beginning.&nbsp; Tomorrow &#8212; tomorrow is the starting gate.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s incredible that we have, you know, a dozen countries signed up to this.&nbsp; But, yes, tomorrow we begin the negotiations.&nbsp; And we will, in the weeks and months ahead, define precisely the de- &#8212; exactly what’s in each pillar and what each country will be committing to and signing up for.</p>



<p>MR. PATEL:&nbsp; Great, thanks so much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next, let&#8217;s go to Peter Baker with the New York Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thanks for doing the call, especially for doing it on the record.&nbsp; Could you just outline for us a little bit more about what was wrong with the TPP negotiated by the Obama-Biden administration, that we&#8217;re not getting back into it and that you&#8217;re trying to distinguish this from?&nbsp; In other words, what&#8217;s the big difference?</p>



<p>And what is the incentive for countries in the region that want market access and tariff reductions but don&#8217;t seem to be getting it as part of this agreement?</p>



<p>AMBASSADOR TAI:&nbsp; Hi, Peter.&nbsp; This is Katherine Tai.&nbsp; So let me take your question first and see if the others want to join in after.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With respect to TPP, I think that the biggest problem with it was that we did not have the support at home to get it through.&nbsp; If you look back at the years 2015 and 2016, and despite Herculean efforts, it could not be gotten through Congress.&nbsp; And then, in 2017, it was President Trump who took the United States out of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that there&#8217;s a very, very strong lesson there: that TPP, as it was envisioned, ultimately was something that was quite fragile and that the United States was not able to deliver on.&nbsp; And that informs very much our thinking about bringing the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, as it&#8217;s designed here, to the region &#8212; which is that trade is an important component of this, but not the only component.&nbsp; So that we are bringing in more robust and comprehensive approach to our partners in this region.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>There has been a lot of swirl about the fact that there is not tariff liberalization incorporated into the scope of what we are engaging on here.&nbsp; And I think that also goes to the fact that the kinds of trade agreements, the traditional ones that we&#8217;ve done before, are very much a part of the practice that has brought us to where we are, both in terms of the fragility of where that trajectory has taken us.</p>



<p>But also, if you look at the world economy today, I just am &#8212; have arrived in Tokyo from the APEC meetings in Bangkok.&nbsp; And of all of the counterparts that I had the chance to speak with in depth, each one of them reiterated for me that their priorities in their economic policymaking, including in trade, are to promote an economic recovery that advances resilience, sustainability, and inclusion for their economies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they&#8217;re looking for engagement, especially from us, around a vision for trade and economic engagement that will reinforce those priorities, given where we are in the global economy and a couple of very, very turbulent years that we&#8217;re all still working to recover from.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just to be clear then, the thing that made it &#8212; TPP &#8212; no good was it wasn&#8217;t able to be delivered, you couldn&#8217;t get it through Congress.&nbsp; Are these agreements that will come out of this process agreements that will go to Congress at some point?<br><br>AMBASSADOR TAI:&nbsp; Peter, on that, let me say this: I think that the robust stakeholder engagement that you are hearing all of us talk about &#8212; stakeholders throughout our economy, expanding the table for engagement with our stakeholders, engaging with our traditional stakeholders &#8212; we can&#8217;t &#8212; they have to be part of the solution and part of our engagement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But bringing to the table and ensuring that other stakeholders, like our workers, like our environmental organizations, the ones who are the smartest about climate and the policy solutions that we need, that they have premier seats at the table and that they will be influencing and shaping the policies that we create.<br><br>Our trading partners, our members of Congress &#8212; along the way, this engagement is designed for maximum supportability and durability because, ultimately, we know that this engagement is something that we need to stick for our partners and for our stakeholders at home in this region.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right, I&#8217;m confused.&nbsp; Does Congress vote on these agreements or not?<br><br>AMBASSADOR TAI:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see where these negotiations take us, and let&#8217;s see where the discussions go.&nbsp; But along the way, we have to keep &#8212; regardless, we have to keep Congress close, and Congress needs to be a part of shaping what we do with our partners here.</p>



<p><br>MR. PATEL:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s try to limit our follow-ups so we can get through as many of our colleagues as we can.&nbsp;<br><br>Next, let&#8217;s go to Asma Khalid from NPR.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thank you guys for doing this.&nbsp; I had two quick questions.&nbsp; And one, I know, Jake, you touched on, actually, earlier a bit about Taiwan.&nbsp; But if I could just get clarity here on the record about why Taiwan was not a part of this initial grouping of countries or self-governed democracies &#8212; whatever you want to call Taiwan &#8212; given its role in supply chains.<br><br>And then the follow-up question is something that I also wanted to get clarity on &#8212; I believe Nancy touched on &#8212; around the incentives for countries to join.&nbsp; Can you articulate at all what those incentives are?&nbsp; Or have they not been, I guess, decided upon yet since negotiations haven&#8217;t begun with various countries?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll make a couple of comments but then invite both Secretary Raimondo and Ambassador Tai, particularly on the second question.&nbsp; And Ambassador Tai should speak to the first one as well because she just met with her counterpart.&nbsp;<br><br>But I would just say that we intend to pursue a deeper bilateral engagement with Taiwan on trade and economic matters in the coming days and weeks.&nbsp; And we think that that track can help strengthen both of our economies while we&#8217;re also pursuing IPEF with the countries that we listed.&nbsp; And we think it puts us in the best position for us to be able to enhance our economic partnership with Taiwan and also to carry IPEF forward with this diverse range of countries.<br><br>Just briefly on what the U.S. has to bring to the table: I’d just start by saying that, you know, the premise of the question is that without market access, you know, countries wouldn&#8217;t be really interested.&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve got an incredible range of countries who&#8217;ve signed up to this, including some with whom we haven&#8217;t had meaningful economic negotiations before.<br><br>So why is that?&nbsp; One reason is because having the opportunity to work closely with the United States on rules and standards; on greater clarity and transparency and coordination on supply chains; on innovation, as it applies to the digital economy and the decarbonization; on technical expertise; on anti-corruption matters and taxation; on investment in infrastructure and in growing businesses, both foreign direct investment in the U.S. where we have a huge market to offer people for that and the enormous investment we&#8217;re making in the region &#8212; the United States is going to be a partner of choice on all of the elements of this framework, even setting aside the question of traditional tariff liberalization.<br><br>And so we think we bring a huge amount to the table.&nbsp; And we think that proposition has been validated by the fact that we&#8217;ve gotten such an overwhelming and broad-scale response from, you know, the Indian subcontinent, to Down Under, to Southeast Asia, to Northeast Asia.<br><br>And let me stop there and see if Katherine or Gina has anything they want to add.</p>



<p><br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; No, I think that&#8217;s exactly right.&nbsp; You know, I would just offer additionally, having spent time in the region, the demand to have the United States increasingly present economically is so strong, which is why, as Jake said, you know, a dozen countries have decided to join us tomorrow for the launch.<br><br>You know, so, broadly, there is a strong desire to have U.S.&nbsp; businesses, the United States government engaged in the region.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, if you&#8217;re asking for kind of a list of specific issues, you know, it’s everything from trade facilitation &#8212; which, by the way, you know, we talk about there are non-tariff barriers, which often can be, you know, more expensive than tariffs, which &#8212; so, one, you know, we&#8217;ll have trade facilitation, as Katherine mentioned earlier; we&#8217;ll work together on technology standards to promote interoperable Internet and other kinds of standards.<br><br>I mean, the Commerce Department sets standards in technology.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re &#8212; if you don&#8217;t set standards in a way that allows your company to participate, you&#8217;re out of &#8212; out of business, you know?&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a binary.&nbsp;<br><br>Decarbonization of key industries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Capital.&nbsp; You know, we expect that for the infrastructure pillar, there will be sources of public and private capital flowing from the United States into the region; you know, into infrastructure projects in countries in the region.<br><br>So, anyway, the list is long.&nbsp; But I think that there will be, you know, a very concrete benefit to countries in the region.&nbsp;<br><br>By the way, just today, you know, you see reporting that Apple is looking to boost production outside of China.&nbsp; And many companies &#8212; many U.S. companies are looking to diversify away from China.&nbsp; Well, countries &#8212; Vietnam, Malaysia, Indonesia &#8212; that are actually signed up and in the Indo-Pacific Framework will obviously have an advantage to get that business from American companies, because they will have signed up to be the high-standard agreement that we plan to sign pursuant to the IPEF.<br><br>So I think once we get underway, the concrete benefits are going to become pretty clear.</p>



<p>AMBASSADOR TAI:&nbsp; This is Katherine Tai.&nbsp; Let me just very, very quickly &#8212; on the Taiwan question, I did just meet Minister John Deng in Bangkok.&nbsp; And we had a great conversation.&nbsp; It was a really, really encouraging and really dynamic meeting that we had.<br><br>And coming out of the conversation we had &#8212; I think this was just two days ago &#8212; both Minister Deng and I have committed that our teams would be in touch and that we&#8217;d be in touch in the next couple of weeks.&nbsp; So please stay tuned for that.<br><br>In terms of the tariff question &#8212; again, the tariff liberalization, let me just put an additional point, add on to what &#8212; all of the great examples that Gina has just provided, which is: You know, in our trade policies, our trade experiences and trade relationships, we have so many examples of situations where there are no tariffs between us and another country.&nbsp; And yet, you know, we have farmers who can&#8217;t get, for example, a single potato across the border and into the other market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I just want to reinforce Secretary Raimondo’s point that, in terms of economic value, we&#8217;re looking at connectivity and we&#8217;re offering a program relating to connectivity for our stakeholders.&nbsp; And that goes beyond tariffs.<br><br>In fact, average bound tariff MFN for the United States right now is 2.4 percent.&nbsp; It&#8217;s very low.&nbsp; In terms of where the value is that is left to be unlocked in the global economy right now, it is in the areas where we are engaging through this framework.</p>



<p><br>MR. PATEL:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; I think we have time for one last question before our speakers have to head to another commitment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why don&#8217;t we go next to Trevor Hunnicutt with Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for taking the question.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a quick one.&nbsp; Jake said that this is an open architecture arrangement.&nbsp; Does that mean that it&#8217;s open to all countries in the region, regardless of how they perform on indices of economic freedom and democracy?&nbsp; And what role do you see China potentially playing in this in the future?<br><br></p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So I think one of the things we will do on a going-forward basis with addi- &#8212; in terms of additional members is work with the other countries that are now in &#8212; with the founding partners, so to speak &#8212; to determine both the process and criteria by which to add additional members.<br><br>And it won&#8217;t just be if you raise your hand, you&#8217;re automatically in.&nbsp; But we also want to maintain a proposition of inclusivity and diversity of economies.<br><br>So the short answer is that we will not dictate, just as the United States, who comes in going forward, but we&#8217;ll have to work that with our partners.&nbsp; And that will be part of those initial discussions that Secretary Raimondo referred to.&nbsp; But that will immediately follow from the launch event tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>Oh, and on China, just broadly speaking, those &#8212; the &#8212; what I just said would apply to that case.</p>



<p><br>MR. PATEL:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; As a reminder to everybody, this call was on the record, but it is under embargo until tomorrow at 4:15 Japan Standard Time.&nbsp; Again, until 4:15 tomorrow, May 23rd, Japan Standard Time.<br><br>Thanks so much, everyone, for joining and a special thanks to our speakers.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll all be in touch again over the course of this trip.</p>



<p> 7:49 P.M. JST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: In Asia, President&#160;Biden and a Dozen Indo-Pacific Partners Launch the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for&#160;Prosperity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/fact-sheet-in-asia-president-biden-and-a-dozen-indo-pacific-partners-launch-the-indo-pacific-economic-framework-for-prosperity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 07:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[IPEF will strengthen our ties in this critical region to define the coming decades for technological innovation and the global economy Framework will create a stronger, fairer, more resilient economy for families, workers, and businesses in the United States and in the Indo-Pacific region Today in Tokyo, Japan, President Biden launched the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>IPEF will strengthen our ties in this critical region to define the coming decades for technological innovation and the global economy</em><br> <br><em>Framework will create a stronger, fairer, more resilient economy for families, workers, and businesses in the United States and in the Indo-Pacific region</em></p>



<p>Today in Tokyo, Japan, President Biden launched the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity (IPEF) with a dozen initial partners: Australia, Brunei, India, Indonesia, Japan, Republic of Korea, Malaysia, New Zealand, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam. Together, we represent 40% of world GDP. &nbsp;<br><br>The United States is an Indo-Pacific economic power, and expanding U.S. economic leadership in the region is good for American workers and businesses — as well as for the people of the region. IPEF will enable the United States and our allies to decide on rules of the road that ensure American workers, small businesses, and ranchers can compete in the Indo-Pacific. As the President has said, tackling inflation is a top economic priority, and this framework will help lower costs by making our supply chains more resilient in the long term, protecting us against costly disruptions that lead to higher prices for consumers.<br><br>U.S. foreign direct investment in the region totaled more than $969 billion in 2020 and has nearly doubled in the last decade, and we are the leading exporter of services to the region, helping fuel regional growth. Trade with the Indo-Pacific supports more than three million American jobs and is the source of nearly $900 billion in foreign direct investment in the United States. With 60 percent of the world’s population, the Indo‑Pacific is projected to be the largest contributor to global growth over the next 30 years. &nbsp;<br><br>The United States and our partners in the region believe that much of our success in the coming decades will depend on how well governments harness innovation — especially the transformations afoot in the clean energy, digital, and technology sectors — while fortifying our economies against a range of threats, from fragile supply chains to corruption to tax havens. The past models of economic engagement did not address these challenges, leaving our workers, businesses, and consumers vulnerable. The framework will focus on four key pillars to establish high-standard commitments that will deepen our economic engagement in the region:</p>



<ul><li>Connected Economy: On trade, we will engage comprehensively with our partners on a wide range of issues. We will pursue high-standard rules of the road in the digital economy, including standards on cross-border data flows and data localization. We will work with our partners to seize opportunities and address concerns in the digital economy, in order to ensure small and medium sized enterprises can benefit from the region’s rapidly growing e-commerce sector, while addressing issues is such as online privacy and discriminatory and unethical use of Artificial Intelligence. We will also seek strong labor and environment standards and corporate accountability provisions that promote a race to the top for workers through trade. </li><li>Resilient Economy: We will seek first-of-their-kind supply chain commitments that better anticipate and prevent disruptions in supply chains to create a more resilient economy and guard against price spikes that increase costs for American families. We intend to do this by establishing an early warning system, mapping critical mineral supply chains, improving traceability in key sectors, and coordinating on diversification efforts.</li><li>Clean Economy: We will seek first-of-their-kind commitments on clean energy, decarbonization, and infrastructure that promote good-paying jobs. We will pursue concrete, high-ambition targets that will accelerate efforts to tackle the climate crisis, including in the areas of renewable energy, carbon removal, energy efficiency standards, and new measures to combat methane emissions. </li><li>Fair Economy: We will seek commitments to enact and enforce effective tax, anti-money laundering, and anti-bribery regimes that are in line with our existing multilateral obligations to promote a fair economy. These will include provisions on the exchange of tax information, criminalization of bribery in accordance with UN standards, and effective implementation of beneficial ownership recommendations to strengthen our efforts to crack down on corruption.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Japan-U.S. Joint Leaders’ Statement: Strengthening the Free and Open International&#160;Order </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/japan-u-s-joint-leaders-statement-strengthening-the-free-and-open-international-order/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Japan and the United States affirm a partnership that is stronger and deeper than at any time in its history. Guided by our shared values; anchored by our common commitment to democracy and the rule of law; inspired by the innovation and technological dynamism of our economies; and rooted in the deep people-to-people ties&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Japan and the United States affirm a partnership that is stronger and deeper than at any time in its history. Guided by our shared values; anchored by our common commitment to democracy and the rule of law; inspired by the innovation and technological dynamism of our economies; and rooted in the deep people-to-people ties between our countries, the Japan-U.S relationship is the cornerstone of a free and open Indo-Pacific region.<br>&nbsp;<br>It is in this spirit that Prime Minister&nbsp;of Japan KISHIDA Fumio welcomed Joseph R. Biden, Jr to Japan in his first visit as President of the United States. President Biden commended Prime Minister Kishida’s global leadership, including in&nbsp;the Japan-Australia-India-U.S.&nbsp;(Quad)&nbsp;Summit meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>As global partners, Japan and the United States affirm that the rules- based international order is indivisible; threats to international law and the free and fair economic order anywhere constitute a challenge to our values and interests everywhere. Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden shared the view that the greatest immediate challenge to this order is Russia’s brutal, unprovoked, and unjustified aggression against Ukraine.&nbsp;The two leaders&nbsp;condemned Russia&#8217;s actions, and called for Russia to be held accountable for its atrocities. They reaffirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp;The Prime Minister and the President underscored the importance of the international community’s unity, and expressed solidarity with the Ukrainian people in responding to Russia’s aggression through sanctions, including financial sanctions, export controls, and other steps, taken with like-minded countries to impose long-lasting economic costs on Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>The two leaders shared the view that the United&nbsp;Nations&nbsp;(U.N.) forms the foundation of the rules-based international order, grounded in shared principles and universal values articulated in the U.N. Charter, including respect for human rights. Both commended the unprecedented global unity demonstrated by U.N. Member States in condemning Russia’s aggression against Ukraine and suspending it from the U.N. Human Rights Council. Recognizing that the U.N. Security Council (UNSC) has primary responsibility for&nbsp;the&nbsp;maintenance&nbsp;of&nbsp;international peace and security on behalf of the Member States, the two leaders expressed deep concern about Russia’s irresponsible behavior as a Permanent Member and its abuse of the veto, particularly Russia’s attempt to shield itself from accountability for its aggression against another Member State. The two leaders expressed a determination to strengthen the United Nations and to encourage all Member States to recommit to the vision and values enshrined in the U.N. Charter. Both expressed the need to strengthen and modernize the multilateral system to better enable it to meet&nbsp;the challenges of the 21st century.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden reiterated support for Japan’s permanent membership on a reformed Security Council, and for other countries who are important champions of multilateral cooperation and aspire to permanent seats. The two leaders also stressed the importance of strengthening coordination among democracies and like-minded partners to effectively address the challenges they face.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Advancing a “Free and Open Indo-Pacific”<br></u></strong><br>Notwithstanding the ongoing crisis in Europe, the two leaders reaffirmed that the Indo-Pacific is a region of vital importance to global peace, security, and prosperity &#8211; and one that faces mounting strategic challenges to the rules-based international order. From this standpoint, Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden committed to action to advance their shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific region. Prime Minister Kishida welcomed&nbsp;the U.S.&nbsp;“Indo-Pacific Strategy.” President Biden emphasized unwavering U.S.&nbsp;commitment to the region, and underscored that his strategy will be matched with resources and steady implementation. The two leaders welcomed the increasingly vibrant, multilayered, and interconnected architecture in the region that supports our common vision; they affirmed the importance of ASEAN unity and centrality, and highlighted the important work of the Quad, AUKUS, and other multilateral fora. They also underscored the importance of cooperation with like-minded partners in other regions, such as Europe and Canada.&nbsp;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Regional Issues: Responding to an Increasingly Challenging Regional Security Environment<br></span><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden called on China to stand with the international community and unequivocally condemn Russia’s actions in Ukraine. They discussed continuing actions by China that are inconsistent with the international rules-based order, including coercion by economic and other means. Noting China&#8217;s ongoing increase in its nuclear capabilities, the two leaders requested China to contribute to arrangements that reduce nuclear risks, increase transparency, and advance nuclear disarmament. They also concurred to work together to strengthen deterrence to maintain peace and stability in the region. The two leaders strongly opposed any unilateral attempts to change the status quo in the East China Sea, and reiterated their strong opposition to China’s&nbsp;unlawful maritime claims, militarization of reclaimed features, and coercive activities in the South China Sea; they emphasized&nbsp;their firm commitment to the rule of law, including the freedom of navigation and overflight,&nbsp;consistent with the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea&nbsp;(UNCLOS). Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden stated that their basic positions on Taiwan remain unchanged, and reiterated the importance of peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait as an indispensable element in security and prosperity in the international community. They encouraged the peaceful resolution of cross-Strait issues. Both leaders voiced concern over the recent PRC-Solomon Islands security agreement, which was concluded in a non-transparent manner without addressing regional voices of concern. Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden also shared serious and ongoing concerns&nbsp;regarding&nbsp;developments in Hong Kong and human rights issues in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region. They underscored the importance of candid communication&nbsp;with China, including at the leader level, and&nbsp;expressed the intent to work with China&nbsp;where possible on areas of common interest.&nbsp;Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden welcomed the inauguration of the new government of the Republic of Korea (ROK), and stressed the critical importance of close ties and cooperation among Japan,&nbsp;the United States, and&nbsp;the ROK, including&nbsp;security ties. The two leaders condemned North Korea&#8217;s advancing&nbsp;nuclear and missile development activities, including its recent ICBM launches. They reaffirmed their commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula in accordance with UNSC resolutions,&nbsp;and urged&nbsp;North Korea to&nbsp;abide by&nbsp;its obligations under these resolutions. The two leaders reaffirmed U.S. commitment to&nbsp;the&nbsp;immediate resolution of the abductions&nbsp;issue. Both leaders expressed support for a calibrated diplomatic approach to North Korea, and called for its engagement in serious and sustained dialogue.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden condemned the coup in Myanmar and the Myanmar military’s brutal attacks on civilians, and committed to continue taking action to press for the immediate cessation of violence, the release of all those who are wrongfully detained, unfettered countrywide humanitarian access, and a swift return to democracy.<br><br>The two leaders&nbsp;expressed&nbsp;concern about the increasing activities of Russian military forces around Japan, and committed to remain attentive to cooperation between China and Russia in military affairs.<br></p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">The Japan-U.S. Alliance: Strengthening Deterrence and Response Capabilities</span></p>



<p>The&nbsp;two&nbsp;leaders renewed their commitment to strengthening the deterrence and response capabilities of the Alliance. Prime Minister Kishida&nbsp;expressed&nbsp;his&nbsp;resolve&nbsp;to&nbsp;examine all options necessary for national defense, including capabilities to counter missile threats. Prime Minister Kishida stated his determination to fundamentally&nbsp;reinforce&nbsp;Japan’s&nbsp;defense capabilities&nbsp;and secure substantial increase of its defense budget needed to effect it. President Biden strongly supported Prime Minister Kishida’s determination.<br><br>President Biden&nbsp;reiterated&nbsp;the U.S. commitment to&nbsp;the defense of&nbsp;Japan under the&nbsp;Treaty&nbsp;of Mutual Cooperation and Security,&nbsp;backed by the full range of capabilities, including&nbsp;nuclear; the leaders reaffirmed their intent to ensure full bilateral coordination through the Alliance Coordination Mechanism throughout every phase of a developing situation. The two leaders affirmed the critical importance of ensuring that U.S. extended deterrence remains credible and resilient. They reiterated the significance of enhancing bilateral discussions on extended deterrence, including through the Security Consultative Committee (SCC) and the Extended Deterrence Dialogue. The President reaffirmed&nbsp;that Article V of the&nbsp;Treaty&nbsp;applies to the Senkaku&nbsp;Islands, and the two leaders reiterated their opposition to any unilateral action that seeks to undermine Japan’s longstanding administration of the Senkaku Islands.&nbsp;The two leaders decided to accelerate cooperation in the cyber and space domains as well as in the field of emerging technologies. They shared the view that cyber security and information security form the foundation of close alliance cooperation, and will remain a continuous focus of our collaboration. The two leaders expressed their determination to continually modernize the Alliance, evolve bilateral roles and missions, and strengthen joint capabilities including by aligning strategies and prioritizing goals together.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden affirmed their intent to deepen cooperation on joint training and capacity building&nbsp;in third countries, including through cooperation by the&nbsp;Japan and U.S.&nbsp;Coast Guards; the two leaders welcomed the signing of annexes to the Memorandum of Cooperation between the U.S. Coast Guard and the Japan Coast Guard.<br><br>The two leaders confirmed the steady implementation of the realignment of U.S. forces in Japan, including the construction of the Futenma Replacement Facility at Henoko as the only solution that avoids the continued use of MCAS Futenma,&nbsp;development of the Field Carrier Landing Practice Facility at Mageshima, and the relocation of U.S. Marine Corps units from Okinawa to Guam.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Achieving More Resilient, Sustainable and Inclusive Economic Growth</span></p>



<p>The two leaders discussed opportunities to further secure our shared prosperity. They exchanged perspectives on the importance of bold economic policies, including Prime Minister Kishida’s “new form of capitalism” and President Biden’s plan to build from the bottom up and the middle out, that promote technological advances while recognizing that the benefits of such progress must accrue to all communities, reduce inequality, and strengthen the middle-class in both nations. The two leaders also expressed their determination that Japan and the United States play an active role in addressing the challenges most salient for the global community &#8211; whether the emergence of new technologies, the impact of climate change, or&nbsp;transnational threats such as infectious disease.<br><br>The two leaders confirmed that Japan and the United States will collaborate in protecting and promoting critical technologies, including through the use of export controls, supporting their respective competitive advantages and ensuring&nbsp;supply chain resilience. They concurred on establishing a joint task force to explore the development of next generation semiconductors, based on “the Basic Principles on Semiconductor Cooperation” adopted in the Japan-U.S. Commercial and Industrial Partnership (JUCIP). President Biden noted the Japanese Diet’s approval of the Economic Security Promotion Bill, with its focus on supply chain resilience, essential infrastructure protection, technology development and the protection of patent applications. The two leaders concurred in exploring further cooperation to strengthen economic security.<br><br>The two leaders applauded the work to date under the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/fact-sheet-the-u-s-japan-competitiveness-and-resilience-core-partnership/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Competitiveness and Resilience (CoRe) Partnership </a>announced last year, and expressed their intention to hold the Japan-U.S. Economic Policy Consultative Committee (the Economic &#8220;2+2&#8221;) at the Ministerial level in July 2022.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida expressed his support for President Biden’s Indo-Pacific Economic Framework (IPEF), and the two leaders welcomed the launch of discussions among IPEF partners toward future negotiations.<br><br>The two leaders recognized&nbsp;the importance of a multilateral trading system based on free and fair economic rules, and&nbsp;confirmed that they will work closely together, through&nbsp;international frameworks such as&nbsp;the G7, G20, WTO, and OECD, to&nbsp;address non-market policies and practices as well as economic coercion, that are incompatible with the&nbsp;multilateral trading system. They also welcomed the recent progress made on bilateral and multilateral trade issues as well as in advancing close cooperation in such areas as digital trade and combatting forced labor. Both leaders reaffirmed the moral and economic imperative of ending the use of forced labor and concurred in working together, recognizing the importance of enhancing predictability and fostering an enabling environment for businesses that respect human rights in their supply chains.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden reaffirmed the importance of implementing the&nbsp;“G20 Principles&nbsp;for&nbsp;Quality Infrastructure Investment” and confirmed that they will further promote efforts to meet global infrastructure needs, in cooperation with the G7 and regional partners. They reiterated the importance of promoting debt sustainability and transparency under the G20 Common Framework. The two leaders also stressed the importance of fair and open lending practices. They reiterated the importance of internationally recognized rules and standards for major creditor countries.<br><br>The two leaders welcomed recent efforts by the international community to secure stable energy and food supplies, which are threatened by the impact of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine. Prime Minister Kishida emphasized the significant role U.S. Liquid Natural Gas plays in alleviating global supply constraints and welcomed investment by U.S. industry to increase oil and natural gas production. The two leaders also welcomed the establishment of Japan-U.S. Clean Energy and Energy Security Initiative (CEESI) to achieve both energy security and net-zero emissions. They confirmed their commitment to work bilaterally and multilaterally on energy and food security, and to cooperate with international organizations such as the International Energy Agency to promote clean energy and mitigate the impact of the disruption in energy supplies, especially on developing countries. Building on the G7 countries’ commitment to reduce dependence on Russian energy, the two leaders shared their intention to explore an initiative to provide Asian partners with support for strengthening their energy security<em>.</em><br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden welcomed Japan’s commitment to take all available measures to double demand for bioethanol, including for sustainable aviation fuel and on-road fuel, by 2030 to reduce dependence on imported petroleum.<br><br>They also shared the need to strengthen resilient and diverse supply chains of critical minerals and to elevate environmental, social, and governance standards in the sector.<br><br>The two leaders celebrated the deep tradition of space cooperation between Japan and the United States. They announced progress in collaboration on the Artemis program, including reaffirming our shared intention to include a Japanese astronaut on Gateway and on human and robotic lunar surface missions. Both leaders committed to conclude negotiations on the Framework Agreement and the Implementing Arrangement for Gateway cooperation in 2022.<br></p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Global Challenges: Realizing Human Security in a New Era</span></p>



<p>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden confirmed that they will continue cooperating to overcome&nbsp;the&nbsp;COVID-19&nbsp;crisis and strengthen health security to prevent, prepare&nbsp;for, and respond to future pandemics, including through frameworks such as the&nbsp;Quad,&nbsp;the COVID-19&nbsp;Global Action Plan, and the G20 Finance and Health fora.&nbsp;The two leaders&nbsp;confirmed&nbsp;support through COVAX, as well as for “last&nbsp;one&nbsp;mile support” programs to increase equitable access to vaccines,&nbsp;while working together on therapeutics, testing, and strengthening health systems. They also confirmed the need to strengthen the global health architecture, including&nbsp;by reforming&nbsp;the WHO, establishing a new pandemic preparedness and global health security fund at the World Bank, strengthening coordination arrangements between finance and health authorities,&nbsp;with a view to achieving universal health coverage.<br><br>The two leaders welcomed further progress in&nbsp;Japan-U.S.&nbsp;joint research on cancer cures and treatment, and welcomed the renewal of the Memoranda of Understanding enabling this cooperation. President Biden highlighted the role of the National Cancer Center of Japan in promoting international collaborations under the Cancer Moonshot program since 2017, and underscored that U.S. commitment to growing that initiative.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden recognized the existential threat of the climate crisis, and committed to making the 2020s the decisive decade for climate action. They affirmed their intent to meet today’s energy demands while working toward long-term energy security by implementing ambitious 2030 nationally determined contributions under the Paris Agreement and 2050 net zero emission goals. In service of these goals, the two leaders affirmed their intent to enhance cooperation under the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/u-s-japan-climate-partnership-fact-sheet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Japan US Climate Partnership</a>.<br><br>The two leaders recognized the importance of nuclear energy as a critical and reliable source of carbon-free electricity and process heat. To this end, they committed to greater nuclear energy collaboration and to accelerating the development and global deployment of advanced and small modular reactors by jointly using export promotion and capacity building tools. The two leaders also concurred to work together to create more resilient nuclear supply chains, including uranium fuel, for both existing and new reactors.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden reaffirmed their intent to work together toward a world without nuclear weapons. In particular, they affirmed their commitment to strengthen the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons as the cornerstone of the international nuclear non-proliferation and disarmament regime. Prime Minister Kishida noted the importance of advancing realistic measures on nuclear disarmament, while addressing&nbsp;security challenges, and President Biden agreed. The two leaders&nbsp;welcomed recent progress in cooperation on nuclear security, including the removal of&nbsp;all highly enriched uranium (HEU) fuel from the University of Tokyo research reactor “Yayoi” and other Japanese research reactors to the United States, furthering&nbsp;their mutual goal of&nbsp;minimizing worldwide&nbsp;stocks of HEU.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden, recognizing that the pandemic has made promoting gender equity more important than ever, concurred that ensuring that all people, regardless of gender identity, can achieve their full potential is both a moral and strategic imperative, critical to every aspect of society and the economy. The two leaders also emphasized the importance of preventing and addressing gender-based violence, including conflict-related sexual violence.<br></p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">People-to-People Exchange: Creating Diverse and Inclusive Networks that Support a “Free and Open Indo-Pacific”</span></p>



<p>The two leaders underscored the importance of mutual exchange and collaboration, to foster the next generation of leaders that will advance a “free and open Indo-Pacific.” They concurred to resume and boost various exchanges, including&nbsp;through study abroad programs;&nbsp;the JET Programme; the Kakehashi Project and the Tomodachi Initiative;&nbsp;and fellowships and collaborative projects among researchers and practitioners such as the Mansfield Fellowship&nbsp;Program and those of the Japan Foundation. Prime Minister Kishida expressed his intention to boost exchanges among professionals and practitioners in areas such as advanced technologies, climate change and disaster management and implement Kakehashi with an emphasis on Okinawa, Hiroshima and Nagasaki. The two leaders also paid tribute to the history, contributions and cultural heritage of Japanese Americans and concurred to engage next generation Japanese American leaders in the future Japan-U.S. cooperation. The two leaders also reaffirmed the role of the U.S.-Japan Conference on Cultural and Educational Interchange in people-to-people exchange.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Toward&nbsp;Building a Future-Oriented Japan-U.S.&nbsp;Relationship</u></strong><br>As the two largest democratic economies, Japan and the United States have a unique obligation to support democratic values, norms, and principles, and to advance a vision for the future in which peace, prosperity, and freedom are ensured. Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden together embraced this responsibility. They affirmed the importance of building a coalition of likeminded partners to advance this shared vision, noting that Japan will chair the G7 and the United States will host APEC in 2023.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: U.S.- Japan Climate&#160;Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/u-s-japan-climate-partnership-fact-sheet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recognizing that the path to energy security runs through clean energy, the United States and Japan intend to build on their cooperation to increase climate ambition, including through decarbonization and clean energy, and continue to lead on their respective domestic climate efforts and on accelerating international climate action. The two sides intend to reinforce bilateral&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Recognizing that the path to energy security runs through clean energy, the United States and Japan intend to build on their cooperation to increase climate ambition, including through decarbonization and clean energy, and continue to lead on their respective domestic climate efforts and on accelerating international climate action. The two sides intend to reinforce bilateral cooperation in the priority areas below to achieve their 2050 net zero goals and their aligned 2030 nationally determined contributions (NDCs) under the Paris Agreement, alongside promoting a global trajectory consistent with keeping global temperature increase to 1.5 degrees Celsius within reach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The two sides intend to further cooperate and accelerate respective action by:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Exchanging views regarding respective domestic planning for, and implementation of, policies to achieve their respective 2030 NDCs under the Paris Agreement and 2050 net zero emission goals;</li><li>&nbsp;Working to, in line with their respective climate finance pledges, continue contributing to fully delivering on the goal of developed countries to jointly mobilize $100 billion in climate finance as soon as possible, in line with the Climate Finance Delivery Plan, including enhancing action on the ten principles for collective actions identified therein;</li><li>Advancing efforts to make financial flows consistent with the global achievement of net zero greenhouse gas emissions no later than 2050, with deep emission reductions in the 2020s and climate-resilient development;</li><li>Working to ensure there is no new direct government support for unabated international coal-fired power generation and to rapidly scale-up technologies and policies that further accelerate the transition away from unabated coal capacity to an overwhelmingly decarbonized power system in the 2030s, consistent with our 2030 NDCs and net zero commitments, while ensuring stable energy supply;</li><li>Advancing rapid decarbonization of on-road transport, including by working to achieve a significant market share for zero-emission vehicles in the light duty sector by 2030, by reducing emissions from medium and heavy-duty vehicles and by promoting innovation for various technologies;</li><li>Enhancing cooperation bilaterally and through multilateral fora to address climate-related financial risks and opportunities, including by promoting consistent and comparable mandatory disclosure of climate-related information that is decision-useful for investors;</li><li>Continuing to enhance efforts and cooperation in innovation and advanced technology deployment, including in such areas as renewable energy, energy storage (such as batteries and long-duration energy storage technologies), smart grids, building electrification, energy efficiency, clean hydrogen, clean ammonia, carbon capture utilization and storage/carbon recycling, industrial decarbonization, and advanced nuclear power, including small modular reactors;&nbsp;and advancing collaboration under the U.S.-Japan Clean Energy and Energy Security Initiative (CEESI), including several new bilateral task forces for accelerating offshore wind, geothermal energy technologies and nuclear power;&nbsp;</li><li>Collaborating in the First Movers Coalition (FMC), where the United States welcomes Japan as a government partner and steering board member, and recognizing that Japan’s participation in the First Movers Coalition, a flagship initiative launched at COP26 to drive demand for green innovation across hard-to-abate sectors, will help elevate the role of Japanese companies in these efforts, align public investment and demand with green innovation in FMC sectors, and provide supportive policies to help scale up supply to meet FMC demand signals;</li><li>Collaborating to accelerate the deployment of heat pumps in our respective domestic markets and globally to displace fuel burned in buildings and advance energy security and climate goals through electrification of space and water heating in buildings, for example through support for manufacturing, training, and promotion;</li><li>Advancing collaboration to accelerate subnational action including under the Global Subnational Zero Carbon Promotion Initiative by continuing the Zero Carbon City International Forum, sharing best practices and considering opportunities for collaborative actions in third countries;</li><li>Coordinating closely on our diplomatic efforts toward all major economies’ taking bold actions in the 2020s to keep a 1.5 degree Celsius limit on warming within reach, including through the Major Economies Forum and the G20;&nbsp;</li><li>Enhancing collaboration on the implementation of Article 6 of the Paris Agreement, including through capacity building activities on high integrity carbon markets by sharing best practices and lessons learned;</li><li>Pursuing opportunities to cooperate on&nbsp;fully utilizing existing nuclear power, and to advance innovative nuclear power technologies, including&nbsp;strengthening industrial partnerships and deepening successful capacity building cooperation in third countries under the Foundational Infrastructure for the Responsible Use of Small Modular Reactor Technology (FIRST) program;</li><li>Enhancing cooperation to address methane emissions globally, recognizing the importance of the Global Methane Pledge and rapid global action to address methane; and by implementing domestic methane emission reduction based on respective national plans, and encouraging those countries that do not have such plans to develop them, and to pursue opportunities to provide financial and technical assistance to assist third countries to meet their methane reduction targets; and the U.S., as one of the largest producers and Japan, as one of the largest consumers, intend to take action to reduce methane emissions from production and consumption. Japan intends to share knowledge and information on technology to reduce methane emission through a Quad roundtable event focused on the oil and gas sector;</li><li>Working to accelerate deployment of offshore wind installations, both at home and in third countries, and seeking partnerships to scale financing, improve policy conditions, and undertake relevant technical work, recognizing the U.S. goal to deploy 30 gigawatts (GW) of offshore wind by 2030, and Japan’s goal to deploy 10 GW of offshore wind by 2030;</li><li>Securing resilient and diverse supply chains of critical minerals to support energy security and the clean energy transition;</li><li>Collaborating on greening government initiatives with the aim of using the procurement power of our respective national governments to achieve ambitious goals, including procuring carbon-free electricity, acquiring zero-emission light-duty vehicles, constructing net-zero emission buildings, and upgrading lighting to high-efficiency lighting, contributing to net-zero emissions by 2050 through greening overall national government operations;</li><li>Building on established deep cooperation on the decarbonization of the&nbsp;shipping sector&nbsp;to promote&nbsp;the demonstration, deployment, and adoption of low- and zero- emission lifecycle fuels and technologies for shipping, recognizing that decarbonizing the shipping sector is essential to transitioning to a clean energy economy; advancing ocean-based climate actions such as green shipping corridors and supply for zero-emission shipping;</li><li>Cooperating to accelerate the transition to decarbonized and lower-methane economies in third countries, particularly in the Indo-Pacific, including through:&nbsp;<br><br>The Japan-U.S. Clean Energy Partnership (JUCEP), which advances the deployment of renewable energy and decarbonization technologies in the Indo-Pacific through partnerships with the private sector, and; The Japan-U.S. Mekong Power Partnership, or JUMPP, which supports the Mekong’s energy security while encouraging greater regional power trade, renewable energy integration, and power market development.&nbsp; &nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  The U.S.-Japan Competitiveness and Resilience (CoRe)&#160;Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/fact-sheet-the-u-s-japan-competitiveness-and-resilience-core-partnership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States and Japan, as the world’s two largest democratic economies, resolve to promote prosperity and to strengthen the rules-based economic order in the Indo-Pacific region and the world.&#160; Together, the two countries recognize the progress made under the U.S.-Japan Competitiveness and Resilience (CoRe) Partnership announced in April 2021 and commit to broaden and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States and Japan, as the world’s two largest democratic economies, resolve to promote prosperity and to strengthen the rules-based economic order in the Indo-Pacific region and the world.&nbsp; Together, the two countries recognize the progress made under the U.S.-Japan Competitiveness and Resilience (CoRe) Partnership announced in April 2021 and commit to broaden and deepen bilateral economic cooperation including through the Economic Policy Consultative Committee announced in January 2022.&nbsp;<br><br><strong><u>Competitiveness&nbsp;and Innovation</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Digital Economy</strong>:<ul><li>The United States and Japan launched the Global Digital Connectivity Partnership in May 2021 to further promote secure connectivity and a vibrant global digital economy.</li><li>The United States and Japan promoted an open, free, global, interoperable, reliable, and secure Internet at the 12th U.S.-Japan Policy Cooperation Dialogue on the Internet Economy, and endorsed the Declaration for the Future of the Internet.</li><li>The United States and Japan continued to promote sustainable smart cities, including through the Integrated Urban Services Program Launch Workshop in August 2021 and the APEC conference in September 2021.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Open Radio Access Networks (Open RAN)</strong><strong>:&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan strengthened collaboration on 5G supplier diversification and Open RAN, both bilaterally and through the Quad.</li><li>The United States and Japan supported industry-led efforts to promote a diverse and competitive telecommunications marketplace with trusted suppliers through the launch of the Prague Proposals on Telecommunications Supplier Diversity.&nbsp;</li><li>The United States, in collaboration with Japan, will launch in 2022 an Open RAN training academy in Southeast Asia to improve access to skilled workers needed to deploy Open RAN, drive workforce development, and promote supplier diversity.</li><li>Japan funded&nbsp;an R&amp;D lab in Texas to help telecommunications companies to evaluate and verify interoperability of 5G mobile base stations compliant with Open RAN.</li><li>U.S. and Japanese officials and private sector representatives engaged Latin American officials through visits, workshops and seminars to advance secure 5G networks and open and interoperable technologies, including Open RAN.</li><li>Japan held the Beyond 5G International Conference with high-level U.S. representation and aligned visions for the development and deployment of next generation network technologies. &nbsp;Our countries&nbsp;intend to fund new&nbsp;joint research and development projects on 5G and Beyond 5G,&nbsp;including those using Open RAN (including v-RAN) technologies, in addition to projects funded under the&nbsp;Japan-U.S. Network Opportunity&nbsp;(JUNO) program.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Cybersecurity/Critical Infrastructure Resilience</strong><strong>:&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan concurred on the urgent need to take a collective approach to enhancing cybersecurity in an increasingly digital world with sophisticated cyber threats.</li><li>The United States and Japan, together with the EU, will organize the flagship Industrial Control Systems Cybersecurity Week to provide training in the Indo-Pacific Region.</li><li>The United States plans to provide cybersecurity training resources for the ASEAN-Japan Cybersecurity Capacity Building Centre funded and supported by Japan.</li><li>The United States and Japan commit to improving the defense of our nations’ critical infrastructure by sharing threat information.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Collaboration in the Indo-Pacific</strong>: &nbsp;<ul><li>The United States and Japan, together with Australia, are partnering with the Federated States of Micronesia (FSM), Kiribati, and Nauru to improve internet connectivity through a new undersea telecommunications cable.</li><li>The United States and Japan, together with Australia, will promote designing certification frameworks for quality infrastructure projects under the Blue Dot Network with support of the OECD, and in alignment with the G20 Principles for Quality Infrastructure Investment and the G20 Operational Guidelines for Sustainable Financing.</li><li>The United States and Japan will cooperate on supporting quality infrastructure development in emerging markets and encouraging the U.S. and Japanese private sectors to support infrastructure projects that advance global goals in such key areas as climate, digital economy and sustainable development including through the Memorandum of Cooperation between U.S. Trade and Development Agency and Japan Bank for International Cooperation.</li><li>The United States and Japan, along with Australia and New Zealand, are collaborating on the Papua New Guinea Electrification Partnership (PEP), which supports PNG’s ambitious goal of increasing the electrification rate from 13 percent to 70 percent by 2030.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Science and Technology Cooperation:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan held the 16th Japan-U.S. Joint Working-Level Committee (JWLC) Meeting on Science and Technology Cooperation in June 2021 to discuss the full range of science and technology cooperation between our countries, such as quantum technologies, artificial intelligence (AI), biotechnology, and climate change technology.&nbsp;</li><li>The United States and Japan&nbsp;signed the Project Arrangement on quantum information science, which will promote research and development on quantum communication, computing, sensors, and materials.</li><li>The United States and Japan intend to conduct joint research and development projects of critical and emerging technologies for respective economic security interests, foreseeing the potential future acquisition and utilization of such technologies, not only between the two countries but also together with other like-minded countries.</li><li>The United States and Japan acknowledged the progress of collaboration on Privacy Enhancing Technologies and welcomed the planned workshop towards future implementation of the technology.</li><li>The United States and Japan seek to accelerate innovation and startup collaboration to enhance competitiveness, possibly through Japan’s concept to establish a “Startup Campus.”<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Civil Space Cooperation</strong><strong>:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan intend to complete the negotiation on the Framework Agreement in 2022 and conclude it in 2023, which will expand bilateral cooperation for decades to come across a wide variety of space exploration, scientific, and research activities.</li><li>The United States and Japan announced that they are committed to a Japanese astronaut opportunity on the Gateway, a human outpost in the lunar vicinity, as part of expanding Artemis collaboration.</li><li>The United States and Japan also announced continued progress on our Artemis collaboration for human and robotic lunar surface missions, including a shared ambition to see a future Japanese astronaut on the lunar surface.&nbsp;</li><li>To advance the return to the lunar surface, the United States and Japan are working to sign an Implementing Arrangement for Gateway cooperation in 2022.</li><li>Japan provided the United States with an asteroid sample collected by Hayabusa2 in November 2021 and the United States intends to provide Japan with a sample from the asteroid Bennu in 2023, as part of ongoing collaboration on a variety of space science missions.</li><li>The United States and Japan are cooperating to use Earth observation data to improve our capability to predict how our climate is changing.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Cooperation for Creating International Standards:&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan intend to further enhance cooperation in the international standardization organizations through cooperation frameworks such as the new International Standards Cooperation Network.</li><li>The United States and Japan strengthened collaboration on international technical standards development, both bilaterally and through the Quad Critical and Emerging Technology Working Group. The United States and Japan&nbsp;have collaborated in the United Nations fora to&nbsp;develop international guidelines and technical requirements&nbsp;for safe and secured&nbsp;advanced autonomous driving technology. The United States and Japan have collaborated to develop international safety standards for electric and hydrogen fuel cell vehicle technologies.</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Enhanced Cooperation on Export Controls:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan discussed a joint effort to enhance U.S.-Japan cooperation on more effective and agile export controls on critical technologies, including microelectronics and cyber surveillance systems, to address the misuse of critical technologies by malicious actors and inappropriate transfers of emerging technologies through research activities<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Supply Chain Resilience</strong><strong>:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan are working together to advance&nbsp;resilient supply chains for critical commodities in order&nbsp;to minimize supply disruption and inflation concerns, a threat to middle-class prosperity.</li><li>The two countries intend to cooperate with like-minded partners in areas such as:</li></ul></li><li>Semiconductor manufacturing capacity, diversification, next-generation semiconductor research and development, and responding to supply shortages.</li><li>Information sharing and collaboration on advanced battery supply chains; and</li><li>Cooperation to build stable and resilient supply chains for critical minerals, including midstream materials processing.<ul><li>The United States and Japan reaffirmed the importance of respecting human rights in supply chains and reinvigorated our cooperation to enhance predictability and foster an enabling environment for businesses to actively engage in efforts to respect human rights, including through the Economic Policy Consultative Committee.</li><li>The United States and Japan are committed to diversifying and strengthening the resilience of supply chains in the Indo-Pacific region, including through promoting trade facilitation and streamlined customs procedures.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>COVID-19 Response, Global Health, and Health Security</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>COVID-19 Response</strong><strong>:</strong><ul><li>Japan has committed to playing a leadership role under the U.S.-launched COVID-19 Global Action Plan under line of effort 1, “Get Shots in Arms” and to contributing to line of effort 6, “Strengthen Global Health Architecture.” The United States has provided more than $19 billion&nbsp;globally in&nbsp;COVID-19 funding for life-saving health and humanitarian assistance, with $580 million announced in December 2021 to support the work of multilateral partners to help fight the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; Japan has been providing approximately $5 billion in comprehensive support globally since the COVID-19 outbreak, with the recent pledge of up to $500 million that was made as the largest contribution at the COVAX AMC Summit in April 2022.</li><li>Bilaterally and in partnership with COVAX, the United States has shared more than 540 million doses of safe and effective COVID-19 vaccine with more than 115 countries and economies.&nbsp;</li><li>Japan has delivered approximately 44 million doses of COVID-19 vaccine donations to 32 countries and regions bilaterally or through the COVAX Facility and more than $160 million of &#8220;Last One Mile Support&#8221; to 77 countries and regions.</li><li>In April 2021, the United States co-hosted with Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, the launch of the Investment Opportunity for the COVAX AMC to ensure the world’s poorest countries will get access to COVID-19 vaccines, regardless of their ability to pay. &nbsp;Building upon the initial progress by the United States, Japan hosted the COVAX AMC Summit in June 2021, which resulted in securing $9.6 billion in funding commitments excessing the AMC’s commitment goal.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Global Health Architecture including Global Health Security:</strong><ul><li>At the Global Pandemic Preparedness Summit, the United States pledged $150 million over three years, subject to Congressional appropriations, while Japan recently pledged $300 million to the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations through 2026.</li><li>The United States and Japan acknowledge the importance to further strengthen the global health architecture with a view to achieving universal health coverage (UHC), and to enhance prevention, preparedness and response, including through the pandemic preparedness and global health security fund at the World Bank, supporting the work of the G20 Joint Finance-Health Task Force, and ongoing negotiation on a WHO international instrument.&nbsp;</li><li>The United States and Japan committed to further strengthen the IHR (2005), including through implementation, compliance, and targeted amendments.</li><li>The United States and Japan reaffirmed commitments to support the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Malaria, and Tuberculosis.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Scientific Cooperation</strong><strong>:</strong><ul><li>The United States&nbsp;and Japan co-funded&nbsp;joint research projects&nbsp;on the “COVID-19 Research in Non-Medical Sciences,”&nbsp;on “Digital Science for post-COVID-19 Society,” and through the U.S.-Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program, including projects on “Countermeasures for COVID-19 in Medical Research.”</li><li>The United States and Japan supported an industry-led Healthcare Innovation Roundtable to enhance industry support for a pharmaceutical innovation ecosystem.</li><li>Under the Quad Vaccine Partnership, the United States and Japan have tirelessly promoted Quad science and technology cooperation, including on clinical trials, genomic surveillance, and pandemic preparedness joint exercise and the Quad Vaccine Confidence event, contributing to building back better health security.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Cancer:&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>The U.S. National Cancer Institute and the Japanese National Cancer Center extended a Memorandum of Cooperation on research collaboration, and signed a Memorandum of Understanding on cooperation in cancer research in May 2022.</li><li>Japan launched a moonshot research and development program on cancer to foster bilateral U.S.-Japan cancer research through Japan’s Cancer Moonshot program. The United States intends to foster research collaboration through the U.S. research programs including the United States Cancer Moonshot.&nbsp;</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Universal Health Coverage:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan committed, as members of the Group of Friends of UHC to take global leadership on promoting UHC towards the UN High-Level Meeting on UHC to be held in 2023 as well as the target year of achieving the SDGs (2030).</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Climate Change, Clean Energy, and Green Growth</u></strong><strong><u> and Recovery</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Global Subnational Zero Carbon Promotion Initiative:&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>During COP 26, Japan&nbsp;and&nbsp;the United States&nbsp;launched&nbsp;the Global Subnational Zero Carbon Promotion Initiative and subsequently co-hosted the Zero Carbon City International Forum to share subnational commitments, policies, and actions to mitigate climate change and adapt its impacts.&nbsp;<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Sustainable and Climate-Smart Agriculture:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan have been working together to identify opportunities on sustainable and climate-smart agriculture and intend to conduct research collaborations to mitigate methane emissions generated from rice paddies and livestock from 2022.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Clean Energy&nbsp;Cooperation:</strong><ul><li>The Japan-U.S.-Mekong Power Partnership (JUMPP) is providing technical assistance and capacity building to support energy security through regional power trade and renewable integration in the Mekong region.&nbsp;</li><li>Japan and&nbsp;the United States launched the Japan-U.S. Clean Energy Partnership (JUCEP)&nbsp;in April 2021&nbsp;to&nbsp;support&nbsp;countries in the Indo-Pacific&nbsp;and around the world to accelerate the transition to clean, affordable, and secure energy sources.&nbsp; In cooperation with the Government of Indonesia, Japan and the United States utilized financial, technical and business matchmaking tools to increase interest in renewables investment, and to conduct clean energy capacity building activities, including for Small Modular Reactor nuclear energy.</li><li>Japan&nbsp;and&nbsp;United States&nbsp;established&nbsp;the Clean Energy and Energy Security Initiative (CEESI) to&nbsp;strengthen energy security through stable and sufficient energy supply, including LNG, and accelerate innovation and marketization of clean energy technologies&nbsp;including renewable energy, hydrogen and fuel ammonia, CCUS/Carbon Recycling and nuclear power. CEESI will work toward achieving&nbsp;both global energy security and 2050 net zero&nbsp;goals.&nbsp;</li><li>The United States and Japan held the Carbon Neutral Port (CNP) Workshop, and concurred to further strengthen the collaboration and identified the ports of Los Angeles and Yokohama and Kobe as pilot cases.</li><li>The United States and Japan pursue opportunities to cooperate on fully utilizing existing nuclear power, to include collaboration on extending reactor life and ensuring security of fuel supply.</li><li>The United States and Japan committed to cooperate on advanced nuclear power technologies such as small modular reactors and fast reactors, including supporting their global deployment with capacity building and financial tools, and cooperating to develop resilient supply chains.</li><li>Japan will join the U.S.-led First Movers Coalition as a strategic government partner to accelerate the maturation and deployment of breakthrough clean technologies in hard-to-abate sectors.</li><li>The United States and Japan will strengthen cooperation on methane reductions across the fossil energy, agricultural, and waste sectors to support implementation of the Global Methane Pledge. &nbsp;This includes supporting methane emissions reductions in third countries.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Transparency for Investors on Climate Risks:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan will continue to collaborate to address climate-related financial risks and facilitate investors’ ability to evaluate climate-aligned opportunities. This includes by working in international forums to promote best practices on disclosure of climate-related information.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong>Expanding and Renewing our Partnership<br></strong>The United States and Japan committed to strengthen further our vibrant people-to-people ties by expanding collaboration and participation in research projects and international exchange programs. Our exchange programs will continue to distribute the benefits of the CoRe Partnership inclusively and equitably, to empower women in our societies.&nbsp; Exchange programs have engaged civil society, and the public and private sectors to encourage women’s role in the business sector, government, and STEM fields.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
