<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:40:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  President&#160;Biden to Galvanize Global Action to Strengthen Energy-Security and Tackle the Climate Crisis through the Major Economies Forum on Energy and&#160;Climate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-galvanize-global-action-to-strengthen-energy-security-and-tackle-the-climate-crisis-through-the-major-economies-forum-on-energy-and-climate/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden today will reconvene leaders of the Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate (MEF) to galvanize actions that will strengthen energy security, enhance the resilience of global food security, and tackle the climate crisis. &#160;These actions are all the more urgent following Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, which has disrupted energy markets, strained&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden today will reconvene leaders of the Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate (MEF) to galvanize actions that will strengthen energy security, enhance the resilience of global food security, and tackle the climate crisis. &nbsp;These actions are all the more urgent following Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, which has disrupted energy markets, strained economies with rising prices, and threatened vulnerable countries with severe food shortages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At today’s meeting, President Biden’s third MEF convening since taking office, world leaders will raise ambitions and followed the United States leadership, joining new efforts and initiatives aimed at tackling the climate crisis while advancing energy-security and food-security, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Global Methane Pledge Energy Pathway</strong>: Tackling methane leaks from the oil and gas sector by capturing wasted gas and bringing it to market — bolstering our energy-security and climate goals;</li><li><strong>Collective 2030 Zero-Emissions Vehicle Goal and Green Shipping Challenge: </strong>Putting more zero-emission vehicles on the road and decarbonizing ocean-based shipping — reducing emissions in the transport sector while breaking our dependence on volatile oil markets and prices;</li><li><strong>Clean Energy Technologies Demonstration Challenge:</strong> Speeding the commercialization of new technologies — enabling us to break dependence on other unabated, volatile fossil fuels and advance the clean energy transition; and</li><li><strong>Efforts to Enhance Food Security:</strong> Increasing fertilizer efficiency and alternatives — reducing agriculture emissions while bolstering global food security.</li></ul>



<p>The major economies that compose the MEF together account for roughly 80 percent of global GDP and global greenhouse gas emissions.&nbsp; Leader-level MEF meetings convened by President Biden in April and September 2021 contributed to the progress achieved at the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Glasgow (COP 26), where new commitments and initiatives brought the world much closer to keeping a 1.5-degree Celsius limit on warming within reach.</p>



<p>The MEF meeting will continue President Biden’s consistent engagement with leaders since Glasgow to further accelerate climate action, including at the recent meeting of the Quad, the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit, the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity, and this month’s Summit of the Americas.</p>



<p>Citing a recent round of international scientific assessments urgently underscoring the narrowing window for decisive action, President Biden will urge leaders to step up their climate efforts and to achieve further progress at COP 27 this November in Sharm el-Sheikh, Egypt.&nbsp; He will emphasize that the market disruptions triggered by the Ukraine crisis underscore the urgency of accelerating the clean energy transition — to alleviate both climate and energy security risks — and enhancing the resilience of the global food system.</p>



<p>To this end, several countries are expected to announce new 2030 emission targets as part of their nationally determined contributions (NDCs) under the Paris Agreement, with many intending to strengthen their existing 2030 NDC targets before COP 27.&nbsp; Leaders will also join collective efforts launched by President Biden across the energy, transportation and agriculture sectors, as described below.</p>



<p>The President will underscore that as we come together to reduce emissions, we must also continue to drive progress on adaptation.&nbsp; To this end, President Biden and Egyptian President Abdel Fattah El-Sisi will announce that the United States and Egypt will partner on an Adaptation in Africa event, focusing on tangible steps to improve people’s lives and build climate resilience.</p>



<p><strong><u>GLOBAL METHANE PLEDGE ENERGY PATHWAY:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Increasing Energy Security and Reducing Near-Term Warming by Capturing Flared, Vented, and Leaked Methane in the Oil and Gas Sector</em></strong></p>



<p>Every year, the world flares, vents, or leaks an amount of natural gas equivalent to over one-third of Russia’s annual gas production.&nbsp; At the same time, the International Energy Agency (IEA) estimates that nearly half of the oil and gas sector’s methane emissions can be captured and utilized at no net cost. &nbsp;Methane emissions account for more than half of net warming to date, and rapidly reducing them is the most effective strategy to avoid near-term warming.&nbsp; Stronger action in the oil and gas sector is the fastest and most cost-effective way to cut global methane emissions, with the potential to avoid nearly 0.1-degree C of warming by mid-century—equivalent to eliminating the greenhouse gas emissions of the entire road transport sector.&nbsp; These steps have the dual benefit of increasing global gas supplies from existing production, simply by capturing gas that is otherwise wasted and bringing it to market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the September 2021 MEF meeting, the United States and the European Union invited other countries to join them at COP 26 in launching the Global Methane Pledge (GMP) to reduce global anthropogenic methane emissions at least 30 percent below 2020 levels by 2030. &nbsp;And today, building on the success of the GMP, the United States and the European Union invited countries to join the new GMP Energy Pathway, to advance global climate progress.&nbsp; The GMP Energy Pathway aims to encourage all nations to capture the maximum potential of cost-effective methane mitigation in the oil and gas sector, and to eliminate routine flaring as soon as possible, and no later than 2030.&nbsp; Participating countries commit to support these efforts by providing new technical and financial resources and/or by enhancing domestic project and policy action.&nbsp; The initiative will bring together some of the most significant global gas producers and consumers in the world.&nbsp; To support the GMP Energy Pathway, the United States will provide $3.5 million in technical assistance through the Global Methane Initiative, and intends to support a transfer of at least $1.5 million remaining in the Pilot Auction Facility to the World Bank Global Gas Flaring Reduction Partnership.</p>



<p>Domestically, the U.S. is continuing its progress in reducing oil and gas methane emissions across the value chain, supporting American gas companies in cutting emissions and saving consumer costs.&nbsp; Building upon the new source performance standards and emissions guidelines proposed in November 2021, the Environmental Protection Agency will issue a supplemental proposed rule for public comment in 2022 to reduce methane and other air emissions from new and existing oil and gas facilities.&nbsp; The Department of Interior is evaluating new regulations to reduce the wasteful flaring and venting of gas produced on public lands.&nbsp; The Department of Transportation is developing a comprehensive set of safety-related regulations that aim to reduce methane emissions from gas pipeline systems that stretch from production-related gathering lines, through trunk line transmission pipelines, and into local distribution pipelines.&nbsp; In addition, new funding provided under the Bipartisan Infrastructure law is enabling the Department of Transportation to spend $1 billion on replacing unsafe and leaking gas distribution pipelines.</p>



<p><strong><u>CLEAN ENERGY TECHNOLOGIES DEMONSTRATION CHALLENGE: </u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Raising $90 Billion for High-Priority Demonstration Projects This Decade</em></strong><strong><em></em></strong></p>



<p>Achieving net-zero emissions by 2050 requires developing and scaling innovative clean technologies not yet commercially available.&nbsp; The IEA’s <em>Net Zero by 2050</em> roadmap identifies at least $90 billion in public investments needed by 2026 for large-scale clean energy technology demonstration projects around the world to be completed this decade. &nbsp;Investing in the first several commercial-scale demonstrations of transformative technologies during this decade will enable their large-scale deployment to achieve global net-zero emissions by midcentury in every sector of the economy, including heavy industry and long-distance transport.&nbsp; Targeted technologies could include, for example, clean hydrogen, carbon dioxide removal, grid-scale energy storage, industrial decarbonization and carbon capture, advanced nuclear, advanced clean fuels, and next-generation offshore wind.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the MEF meeting, the President will challenge other countries to join the United States in supporting a collective goal to reach the $90 billion in public investment recommended by the IEA.&nbsp; These public investments will leverage additional private investments and advance innovative technologies already in demand by the world’s largest companies through the First Movers Coalition launched by the United States and the World Economic Forum.&nbsp; The President will invite interested countries to come prepared to announce specific investment levels at the Global Clean Energy Action Forum that the United States is hosting this September in Pittsburgh, along with preliminary action plans identifying how they will deploy these technologies to promote an inclusive and equitable transition.</p>



<p>Under the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law signed by President Biden, the United States is devoting $21.5 billion to high-priority clean technology demonstration projects.&nbsp; And just last week the President invoked the Defense Production Act to boost manufacturing of electrolyzers that will be used to produce clean hydrogen and the Department of Energy recently issued a loan guarantee to construct one of the world’s largest clean hydrogen storage facilities.</p>



<p><strong><u>COLLECTIVE 2030 ZERO-EMISSION VEHICLE GOAL:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Reducing Emissions and Dependence on Volatile Oil Markets by Accelerating Zero-Emissions Vehicle Deployment</em></strong></p>



<p>Achieving net zero will require a profound transformation of other sectors, including transportation.&nbsp; To keep a 1.5 C limit within reach, the global market share of zero-emission vehicles (ZEVs) must reach at least 50 percent of new light-duty vehicle sales by 2030.&nbsp; In some advanced economies, transportation is the single-largest emitting sector and vehicle purchases are causing rapid emissions growth in many developing economies.</p>



<p>Accelerating the deployment of ZEVs will also have the additional benefit of reduced oil dependence — enhancing energy security and insulating economies from price volatility driven by geopolitical and other supply disruptions.&nbsp; Accelerated ZEV deployment will also improve public health by reducing emissions of conventional pollutants.</p>



<p>With the support of automakers, labor, and states, President Biden earlier this year set a goal of ZEVs – including battery electric, fuel cell electric, and plug-in hybrid vehicles – achieving 50 percent of all new light-duty U.S. vehicle sales in 2030.&nbsp; At the MEF, the President will invite participants to join the United States in a collective goal of 50 percent ZEVs by 2030.&nbsp; By accelerating action in key markets, this collective goal will help speed a fully global transformation of the automotive sector.&nbsp; Other countries are invited to join the ZEV deployment goal on the road to COP 27.</p>



<p>To advance this goal in the United States, the Environmental Protection Agency and Department of Transportation have, working closely together, finalized stronger vehicle standards through 2026 and are now considering ambitious standards to at least 2030.&nbsp; The Biden Administration is also implementing the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to deploy $7.5 billion in funding for a national network of electric vehicle chargers and more than $7 billion to build a strong domestic battery supply chain and create high-quality jobs.</p>



<p><strong><u>GREEN SHIPPING CHALLENGE:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Catalyzing Action This Decade to Decarbonize Ocean-Based Shipping</em></strong></p>



<p>Emissions from the shipping sector are significant, rising, and on a trajectory incompatible with the goals of the Paris Agreement.&nbsp; If shipping were a “country,” it would be the world’s eighth-largest emitter.&nbsp; At COP 26, many countries, recognizing the urgency of reducing emissions from the shipping sector, joined the Declaration on Zero Emission Shipping by 2050 and the Clydebank Declaration supporting the establishment of green shipping corridors.&nbsp; The United States will also announce that it is co-leading the Zero-Emission Shipping research Mission in Mission Innovation together with Norway and Denmark. &nbsp;Further efforts on shipping decarbonization followed at the recent Our Ocean Conference co-hosted by the United States and Palau.</p>



<p>To build on these efforts, the United States and Norway will announce the launch of a Green Shipping Challenge for COP 27.&nbsp; This initiative encourages governments, ports, maritime carriers, cargo owners, and others in the shipping value chain to come forward with concrete steps that will help put the international shipping sector on a credible pathway this decade toward full decarbonization no later than 2050.&nbsp; These could include, for example, steps to produce zero-emission fuels; develop zero-emission bunkering and recharging capabilities; deploy low- or zero-emission vessels; and create, or provide financial and technical support for green shipping corridors.&nbsp; President Biden will invite leaders to express their support for the Green Shipping Challenge and to announce specific actions under the initiative at COP 27.</p>



<p><strong><u>GLOBAL FERTILIZER CHALLENGE:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Strengthening Food Security and Reducing Agriculture Emissions by Advancing Fertilizer Efficiency and Alternatives</em></strong><strong><em>&nbsp;</em></strong><strong><em></em></strong></p>



<p>Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine has shocked the global food system, showing just how vulnerable it is to disruption.&nbsp; Wheat and fertilizer prices have increased more than 40 percent in some regions, exacerbating food insecurity concerns globally.&nbsp; Even before the invasion, food and fertilizer prices were rising as a result of the combined effects of the COVID-19 pandemic, climate-related impacts, armed conflicts, and low supply-chain resilience. &nbsp;Climate-driven food security shocks will continue to cause food scarcity and suffering if steps are not taken to increase food system resilience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Inability to access fertilizer hampers agricultural productivity in many low-income countries, while in most major economies, more than 50 percent of fertilizers do not reach the intended crop.&nbsp; A 10 percent reduction in global fertilizer loss and waste would free up more than the total amount of mineral fertilizer used by all African countries. &nbsp;In addition, nitrogen fertilizer production consumes up to 4 percent of global natural gas supply; increasing fertilizer efficiency in the short term and transitioning to more affordable alternatives in the medium term will reduce natural gas dependence.&nbsp; Steps to increase the adoption of innovative, alternative, and efficient fertilizer and cropping practices will alleviate pressure on fertilizer and natural gas supplies, increase fertilizer availability, lower nitrous oxide emissions, and reduce food insecurity globally. &nbsp;</p>



<p>In recent months, as part of a continuing effort to add resilience to the agriculture and food supply chains, the United States has established a $500 million program to support innovative and sustainable U.S. fertilizer production and has strengthened support to farmers for the use of precision agriculture and other techniques to improve fertilizer use efficiency.</p>



<p>To spur broader efforts, President Biden will invite countries to join the United States in launching the Global Fertilizer Challenge with the goal of raising $100 million in new funding by COP 27.  The Global Fertilizer Challenge will support innovative research, demonstrations, and training to help countries with high fertilizer usage and loss adopt efficient nutrient management and alternative fertilizers and cropping systems.  It will be implemented in partnership with the Agriculture Innovation Mission for Climate, which now has over 200 government and non-government partners.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Delivering Progress on the Biden-&#8288;Harris Lead Pipe and Paint Action&#160;Plan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-delivering-progress-on-the-biden-harris-lead-pipe-and-paint-action-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Six months since the President and Vice President unveiled the Biden-Harris Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan, the Administration has taken swift action and made quick progress. The Biden-Harris Administration has announced more than $4 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funds and annual appropriations that can we used to begin replacing all of America’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Six months since the President and Vice President unveiled the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/16/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-lead-pipe-and-paint-action-plan/">Biden-Harris Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan</a>, the Administration has taken swift action and made quick progress. The Biden-Harris Administration has announced more than $4 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funds and annual appropriations that can we used to begin replacing all of America’s lead pipes while mobilizing additional resources and tools to get rid of lead, ensure Americans can drink clean water, and live in healthy homes.</p>



<p>Today, to continue momentum implementing the action plan, Vice President Harris, Human and Urban Development Secretary Fudge, and Environmental Protection Agency Administrator Michael Regan are in Pittsburgh to provide an update on the Administration’s commitment to addressing lead pipes and paint, including through announcing $500 million for states and local government to reduce lead exposure and build healthier homes. States and localities can begin applying for the awards, which will target disadvantaged communities in line with the President’s Justice40 Initiative.</p>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris believe no child, no family, and no American should drink water with lead or be exposed to lead paint in their homes. That’s why they made replacing lead pipes a centerpiece of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and why Vice President Harris visited AFL-CIO to release the action plan that helps ensure federal, state, and local resources are moving quickly. Together, their leadership, vision, and actions are removing lead from water and homes, creating good-paying jobs, and supporting the low-income and communities of color disproportionately impacted.</p>



<p><em>Outlined below is how the Administration is making critical progress on the Biden-Harris Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan:</em></p>



<p><strong><u>Tackling Lead Pipes and Paint with Historic Investments</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Today, the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) is making $500 million available for states and local governments to protect children and families from lead-based paint and other home health hazards, targeting the awards to disadvantaged communities, in line with the Justice40 Initiative, by including rating points based on the percentage of the area the grant will target that are disadvantaged communities. <br></li><li>In March, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) issued a memorandum to guide collaborative implementation with state, local, and Tribal partners water infrastructure funding through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, including $2.9 billion for lead service line replacement in 2022. EPA’s memo provided technical guidance to states on the disadvantaged community definitions and EPA oversight of the state programs. Working collaboratively, EPA and state SRF programs continue to make progress towards Justice40.<br></li><li>In May, EPA announced that it is making available $ 728billion in new federal grant funding for the Drinking Water State Revolving Fund (DWSRF). This funding can be used for loans that help drinking water systems install treatment for contaminants, improve distribution systems by removing lead service lines and improve system resiliency to natural disasters such as floods.<br></li><li>In May, EPA issued a new funding memorandum to guide the distribution of $154 million in FY22 Tribal water infrastructure funding from the BIL to support access to safe drinking water and wastewater management in Tribal communities, including projects to replace lead pipes.<br> </li><li>In February, EPA announced $20 million in available grant funding to assist communities and schools with removing sources of lead in drinking water. This grant funding, and additional funding through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will help make rapid progress on the goal of addressing lead and removing lead pipes across the country.<br></li><li>In April, the Village of Elberta, Michigan received $3.4 million in grant and low-interest loans from USDA, leveraging an additional $2 million in state assistance, to improve their water system and remediate lead. Approximately, 79 percent of the service laterals in the water distribution system are known or suspected to contain lead.  USDA has an additional $23.8 million in projects containing lead remediation that are nearing approval and other applications in development.<br></li><li>In March, USDA provided a $350,000 award to the City of Linwood, Kansas for their Water System Improvements Project.  Leveraging $499,586 in HUD’s Community Development and Block Grant funds and $150,000 in applicant contribution, this project will enable the City of Linwood to replace approximately 75 cast iron service lines that may contain lead joints and to make other necessary improvements to the distribution system. <br></li><li>In March, EPA issued a Request for Applications for approximately $100 million in federal funding through the Environmental Finance Center (EFC) Grant Program. A major priority for this program is to provide technical support to disadvantaged communities across the country. Selected technical assistance providers will help communities develop and submit project proposals, including State Revolving Fund (SRF) applications for Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding to reduce lead in drinking water.<br></li><li>Schools and child care facilities are also accessing funds for projects to replace lead lines and remediate lead plumbing, pipes, and paint. In March, the Anson Madison Water District in Maine received a $6 million low-interest loan and $3.5 million grant to mitigate lead exposure for 3,700 residents, including at two area high schools and other educational institutions. In January 2022, USDA’s Rural Development obligated $9.5 million to Columbus County, North Carolina, for the construction and cost overrun of a new replacement school facility housing Pre-K through 8th grade. This new facility replaces two school facilities ranging from 60-94 years old with asbestos in almost all flooring and lead paint throughout – ensuring the new facility meets all code requirements. <br></li><li>In January, the Department of the Treasury adopted the final rule for the $350 billion State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds, which provides for an expanded set of eligible lead remediation uses, including replacement of faucets and fixtures in schools and daycares, and confirms recipients’ ability to use funds for the replacement of lead services lines. The final rule took effect on April 1, 2022. Already, recipients of the State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds, authorized by the American Rescue Plan, are investing more $60 million in lead remediation projects. Some examples of this include:<ul><li>The City of Toledo, OH plans to replace all private lead service lines in the city (approximately 3,000 lines) at no cost to homeowners. Additionally, the City will replace many public lead service lines co-located with private lines.</li><li>The City of Buffalo, NY has budgeted $10 million for an expansion of the City’s ROLL program so that at least an additional 1,000 homes can have their lead water service lines replaced. The City has already successfully replaced the lines in 500 homes and this expanded capacity will more than double its impact.</li><li>The City of Pittsburgh, PA has budgeted $17.5 million to partner with the Pittsburgh Water and Sewer Authority to complete projects to remediate lead in drinking water.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong>Making It Easier to Access Funding</strong></p>



<ul><li>In line with the Office of Management and Budget’s commitment to make existing sources of federal funding for lead pipes accessible to the public, in March, the President Biden’s FY23 Budget request included a summary of all the sources funding for lead pipes across the federal government.<br></li><li>In May, EPA and partners across the federal government announced a renewed Tribal Infrastructure Task Force to improve federal government coordination efforts to deliver water infrastructure and financial assistance to American Indian Tribes and Alaska Native Villages.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Removing Lead in Federally-Assisted Housing</strong></p>



<ul><li>HUD’s Office of Public and Indian Housing will soon issue a FY22 notice of funding opportunity (NOFO) for its Lead-Based Paint Capital Fund grant program that will support control of lead-based paint hazards in public housing.<br></li><li>HUD’s Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes is developing a plan for removing lead service lines from HUD-assisted housing when a public water system is replacing a water main (in the street) but is not removing the service lines at the same time.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Remediating Lead in Schools and Child Care Centers</strong></p>



<ul><li>The Department of Health and Human Service’s (HHS) Administration for Children and Families (ACF) and EPA are collaboratively developing a series of three training webinars on lead testing and remediation in drinking water throughout child care and early childhood facilities using the 3-Ts (Training, Testing, Taking Action). The webinars will provide presentations from HHS and EPA, alongside interactive tools, and case studies.&nbsp;<br></li><li>HUD’s Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes continues to partner with 289&nbsp;state, tribal, and local governments on their implementing on 349 grants that use its funds to make homes of low-income children and their families lead-safe and healthy.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Closing Gaps in Childhood Lead Testing</strong></p>



<ul><li>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) is working with Pediatric Environmental Health Specialty Units (PEHSU) to raise awareness and serve as a place for lead referrals and screening. The PEHSUs are a group of environmental health specialists who provide medical information and advice on environmental conditions that influence reproductive and children’s health. PEHSUs are academically based, typically at university medical centers.<br></li><li>CDC and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) are also planning a state-to-state learning webinar to showcase the efforts of two to three states that have undertaken efforts to increase blood lead screening rates. CDC and CMS will identify examples and a platform to share approaches, best practices, and lessons learned, and encourage coordination across state agencies, to consider implementation of levers to increase blood lead screening rates.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Developing New Regulations to Protect Communities from Lead in Drinking Water</strong><br></p>



<ul><li>EPA is advancing the regulatory process to develop a new proposed rule, the Lead and Copper Rule Improvements. EPA intends to propose requirements that, along with other actions, would result in the replacement of all lead service lines as quickly as is feasible. EPA also intends to consider opportunities to strengthen tap sampling requirements and explore options to reduce the complexity and confusion associated with the action level and trigger level, with a focus on reducing health risks in more communities. The goal of these potential lead service line replacement regulatory improvements—coupled with non-regulatory actions—is to more equitably protect public health.<br></li><li>EPA announced on May 4, 2022 it is seeking input from stakeholder groups on the forthcoming Lead and Copper Rule Improvements proposal. EPA is inviting small businesses, governments, and not-for-profit organizations to participate as Small Entity Representatives for a Small Business Advocacy Review Panel. EPA accepted nominations for the panel until May 18, 2022.<br></li><li>At the same time, EPA is implementing the Lead and Copper Rule Revisions (LCRR) to help ensure that lead service line inventories are developed by public water systems by 2024.<br></li><li>To further protect children from lead, EPA is working to revise the 2021 Dust Lead Clearance Levels and the related 2019 Dust Lead Hazard Standards final rules. These rules provide important provisions to protect children from exposure to lead dust on floors and windowsills. The hazard standards are used to identify a dust-lead hazard and the clearance levels are used to demonstrate adequate clean-up after abatement activities. These apply to pre-1978 homes and child-care facilities. The courts sent the previous Administration’s 2019 rule back to EPA to redo to ensure the levels are protective. EPA currently plans to propose revisions to these rules in FY 2023.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 3613 and S.&#160;4160</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/16/bill-signed-h-r-3613-and-s-4160/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 22:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 3613, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 202 Trumbull Street in Saint Clair, Michigan, as the Corporal Jeffrey Robert Standfest Post Office Building; Thank you to Representatives McClain, Bergman, Huizenga, Meijer, Moolenaar, Upton, Walberg, Andy Levin, Stevens, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 3613, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 202 Trumbull Street in Saint Clair, Michigan, as the Corporal Jeffrey Robert Standfest Post Office Building;</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives McClain, Bergman, Huizenga, Meijer, Moolenaar, Upton, Walberg, Andy Levin, Stevens, and Dingell for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 4160, the &#8220;Supreme Court Police Parity Act of 2022,&#8221; which authorizes the Marshal of the Supreme Court and Supreme Court Police to protect immediate family members of the Chief Justice, any Associate Justice, or any officer of the Supreme Court.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Cornyn and Coons for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Announcing the Launch of the White&#160;House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and&#160;Abuse</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/16/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-announcing-the-launch-of-the-white-house-task-force-to-address-online-harassment-and-abuse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 21:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Eisenhower Executive Office Building 1:52 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Please have a seat.  Hi, everyone.  Well, let me start by saying it is so good to be with our Attorney General, Merrick Garland; our Surgeon General, Vivek Murthy; and on Gender Policy Council &#8212; where she? &#8212; Dr. Jennifer Klein; and all the members of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></p>



<p>1:52 P.M. EDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Please have a seat.  Hi, everyone.  Well, let me start by saying it is so good to be with our Attorney General, Merrick Garland; our Surgeon General, Vivek Murthy; and on Gender Policy Council &#8212; where she? &#8212; Dr. Jennifer Klein; and all the members of the task force.  Thank you all for the work you do, for the extraordinary work that you do.<br> <br>Sloane, thank you for your courage.  It takes a lot to put yourself out there as a public figure, period, but then to speak out about something so many people, regardless of gender, are experiencing.  So thank you for your leadership.  Thank you.<br> <br>And to all the other survivors who are here today: You motivate us.  You inspire us.  And you are the voice of so many people who are in this room because of the voice that you express around these issues.  And so I thank you for that and your strength and your sense of purpose.<br> <br>And in particular, I also want to acknowledge Matthew and Francesca. <br> <br>So I know it is not easy to talk about what you&#8217;ve experienced.  And as all of you know, most of my career, I spent it as a prosecutor.  And the majority of that time, I was focused on crimes affecting women and children, crimes that involved sexual abuse.  And &#8212; and in many of the cases, in particular when they were going to trial, and we were prepared to go to trial, I’d sit down for extensive periods of time to talk with the survivors about their case and talk with them about what it would be like when they were going to walk out of my office and walk down the hall and walk into a courtroom.<br> <br>And for some, as you all know, it was impossible to imagine what it would mean to speak publicly about what they&#8217;d been through, when, you know, most don&#8217;t want to even speak about it in private.<br> <br>But every time, I have to tell you, I was inspired by their bravery for so many reasons, both because of the courage it takes to tell a story that is a story that is informed by some of the most horrible experiences but also informed by such pain.  But I was also inspired because, again, the courage that it takes to be that voice.<br> <br>You know, when I would prosecute a case, and the prosecutors here know that, it was &#8212; the &#8212; I would stand in front of the jury, and I would say, “Kamala Harris for the people.”  And the charging document would not be the name of the victim or survivor versus the defendant, it was the “The People versus.”<br> <br>Because, you see, in our form of justice, we have rightly said that individual should not be made to fight alone.  A harm against her, against him, against them is a harm against all of us as a society. <br> <br>And so, it is with that spirit that we are doing the work we are doing today to convene and to inaugurate this task force, understanding this affects all of us if it affects any one of us. <br> <br>And we therefore, all of us, have a responsibility to stand together to support those who have gone through this, but to also recognize they shouldn’t have to be alone fighting on this issue. <br> <br>So that&#8217;s the spirit with which we convene today and the spirit with which we are doing this work. <br> <br>And I will tell you, as Attorney General, many of you know, when I was in California, I prosecuted the first case in the country of an operator of a cyber exploitation website. <br> <br>And I&#8217;ll never forget &#8212; you know, my office was mostly in Sacramento, and we were dealing with a case &#8212; if you know California &#8212; in another part of the state.  And I flew down to meet with the person who was actually handling the case, to go o- &#8212; went through the files to see: Where were we?  What was going on?  What were we going to do about this case?<br> <br>Because it was, in many ways, a case of first impression &#8212; although it wasn&#8217;t when we thought about the pathology of what was at play.  When we thought about the &#8212; you know, we call it the “MO” &#8212; modus operandi.  Right?  When we talked about and thought about how it was being done, what was motivating it, and how it was making that victim and that survivor feel. <br> <br>So, yes, it was the first in the nation, but we&#8217;d seen that kind of stuff before.  The point was that we needed to update and upgrade ourselves as law enforcement and as the criminal justice system, as a justice system, to recognize where it is now occurring and update our approach to deal with it in all places where it exists in a way that causes harm and pain and injury. <br> <br>And so, that website in particular, it &#8212; what it did is it let people upload sexually explicit photographs of their former partners &#8212; the photographs that were taken and shared with consent in a consensual relationship.  But, of course, what ended up happening is that one of those partners usually in that relationship had &#8212; had a grudge or an issue or a motivation to embarrass or to harm, and would allow the photograph to be posted with the explicit intent &#8212; certainly with the implicit effect &#8212; of trying to embarrass and degrade and hurt and cause pain and attract judgment to that individual. <br><br>Well, in that case, I’m happy to report that the person who ran that website went to prison, because I do believe that there should be consequence for behaviors that harm other human beings.<br><br>But this kind of justice is still so rare, because many of our laws have not caught up with the advances in technology.  So, as a United States senator, I introduced legislation to make these acts a federal crime.<br> <br>And thanks to the recent &#8212; and our President, Joe Biden &#8212; and the recent reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act, for the first time, cyber exploitation victims can sue their abusers in federal civil court.<br> <br>And this is progress, yet we still have so much more work to do to protect people from online harassment and abuse, which is why the work of this task force is so important.<br> <br>Context.  Well, the Internet is an essential part of life in the 21st century.  Can’t get around it.  Can’t get around without it.  And for far too many people &#8212; and Sloane told her story &#8212; the Internet is a place of fear.<br> <br>One in three women under the age of 35 report being sexually harassed online.  Over half of the LGBTQ+ people in our country are survivors of severe harassment.<br> <br>Nearly one in four Asian Americans report being called an offensive name, usually motivated by racism &#8212; being called an offensive name online.  And Black people who have been harassed online in our country are three times more likely to be targeted, again, because of their race.<br> <br>No one should have to endure abuse just because they are attempting to participate in society.<br> <br>Of course, the impact of this abuse extends beyond the ability to use Internet &#8212; the Internet system and the power of the Internet &#8212; without fear.  It’s beyond that.  In many cases, cyberstalking have serious mental health consequences for its victims, sometimes leading to self-harm, sometimes leading to suicide.<br><br>And we continue to see how some acts of mass violence &#8212; the most recent included &#8212; have followed expressions of online hate and abuse.<br> <br>The white supremacist who murdered 10 Black people in Buffalo, New York, was first radicalized, by all accounts, online.<br> <br>And after the massacre of 19 children &#8212; 19 babies &#8212; and 2 teachers in Uvalde, it was revealed that the shooter had threatened to kidnap, rape, and kill teenage girls on Instagram.  One of the girls he harassed described the abuse, I quote, as “just how online is.”  Think about that.  Hate has become so common on the Internet that, as a society, it&#8217;s kind of becoming normalized, and for users, some might say unavoidable. <br> <br>Recent events have also made it clear that we face new threats.  Earlier this week, I met with a group of legal experts about how overturning Roe v. Wade will impact the right to privacy. <br> <br>Now, just think about this: In states where abortion is criminalized, an abuser could purchase a woman&#8217;s location history through a data broker.  This is a realistic scenario.  If that history shows that she sought an abortion out of state, he could then turn it over to law enforcement in a jurisdiction that has deemed that a crime.  This is a horrifying possibility for that woman. <br> <br>So let us be clear: No one should be afraid that an abuser will use their private personal data &#8212; or that a person&#8217;s private personal data will be used against them.  And all people deserve to use the Internet free from fear.<br> <br>This task force, then, will tackle a threat that has been far too real for far too many people for far too long.  And the recommendations of this group and the extens- &#8212; extended group of experts and those who have been advocates in this space for so long &#8212; the collective work &#8212; will help modernize the federal government&#8217;s response to violence against women and people of all genders.  It will lead to more evidence-informed policies and interventions.  And it will support more federal funding to address online harassment and abuse, including grants to train law enforcement and prosecutors. <br> <br>It is incumbent on all of us &#8212; government, local law enforcement, and the tech sector &#8212; to respond to the task at hand with a sense of urgency. <br> <br>So I thank you all for your tireless fight and for your advocacy, for your strength to prevent these harms from happening in the first place and to hold perpetrators accountable.  And the President and I look forward to hearing all of your recommendations. <br> <br>Thank you all so very much.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END                 2:04 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: S.&#160;3580</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/16/bill-signed-s-3580/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 20:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law: S. 3580, the &#8220;Ocean Shipping Reform Act of 2022,&#8221; which authorizes appropriations for the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) for fiscal years 2022 through 2025; establishes additional requirements and prohibited conduct for ocean carriers; requires the FMC to issue rules related to certain fee assessments, prohibited&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>S. 3580, the &#8220;Ocean Shipping Reform Act of 2022,&#8221; which authorizes appropriations for the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) for fiscal years 2022 through 2025; establishes additional requirements and prohibited conduct for ocean carriers; requires the FMC to issue rules related to certain fee assessments, prohibited practices, and establishment of a shipping registry; and authorizes the FMC under certain circumstances to issue an emergency order requiring common carriers to share information directly with shippers and rail and motor carriers.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Amy Klobuchar, John Thune, Maria Cantwell, and Roger Wicker and Representatives Peter DeFazio, Sam Graves, John Garamendi, and Dusty Johnson for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Healthcare Cybersecurity Executive Forum Hosted by National Cyber Director Chris&#160;Inglis</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/16/readout-of-healthcare-cybersecurity-executive-forum-hosted-by-national-cyber-director-chris-inglis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 20:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis hosted Deputy Secretary of Health and Human Services Andrea Palm, senior U.S. government cybersecurity officials, and CEOs and other senior executives representing entities on the Health Sector Coordinating Council Cybersecurity Working Group Executive Committee for a cyber threat briefing and roundtable discussion about cybersecurity in the healthcare and public&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis hosted Deputy Secretary of Health and Human Services Andrea Palm, senior U.S. government cybersecurity officials, and CEOs and other senior executives representing entities on the Health Sector Coordinating Council Cybersecurity Working Group Executive Committee for a cyber threat briefing and roundtable discussion about cybersecurity in the healthcare and public health sector. Participants discussed the five-year anniversary of the Health Care Industry Cybersecurity Task Force’s “Report on Improving Cybersecurity in the Health Care Industry,” including the progress that has been made since the report came out and areas where additional focus is needed. Deputy Secretary Palm provided an update on HHS’s work to finalize a sector incident response plan, and Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency Deputy Director Nitin Natarajan shared resources CISA has available to help manage cybersecurity risk in critical infrastructure sectors, including healthcare. Healthcare CEOs and senior executives relayed their experiences protecting their systems, products, and patients; the investments they’ve made to combat growing cyber threats; and the challenges they’ve faced in dealing with vulnerabilities in the cyber ecosystem. All of the participants agreed on the importance of additional collaboration, including through exercises, to help improve cybersecurity in the sector.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joe&#160;Biden will Host Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate Leaders&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/16/president-joe-biden-will-host-major-economies-forum-on-energy-and-climate-leaders-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 19:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55665</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden will host a virtual leader-level meeting of the Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate (MEF) on June 17, 2022, at 8:30 a.m. Eastern Time. This will be President Biden’s third leader-level convening of the MEF since taking office. This meeting of the MEF is a continuation of the President’s efforts to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joe Biden will host a virtual leader-level meeting of the Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate (MEF) on June 17, 2022, at 8:30 a.m. Eastern Time. This will be President Biden’s third leader-level convening of the MEF since taking office.</p>



<p>This meeting of the MEF is a continuation of the President’s efforts to use all levers to tackle the global climate crisis, urgently address rising costs around the world exacerbated by Russia’s war on Ukraine, and put the U.S. and allies on a path to long-term energy and food security.&nbsp;&nbsp;In urging countries to enhance climate ambition, he invited fellow leaders to join the United States in a set of concrete, collective initiatives that will accelerate global action on climate as well as our energy security and food security efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The MEF includes countries representing 80 percent of global GDP, population, and greenhouse gas emissions.  Other leaders critical to the global effort to tackle the climate crisis have also been invited to participate.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Montana Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/16/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-montana-disaster-declaration-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 18:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Montana and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe storm and flooding beginning on June 10, 2022, and continuing. Federal funding is available to State, tribal, eligible local governments&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Montana and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe storm and flooding beginning on June 10, 2022, and continuing.<br> <br>Federal funding is available to State, tribal, eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storm and flooding in the counties of Carbon, Park, and Stillwater.<br> <br>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.<br> <br>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Maona N. Ngwira as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.  <br> <br>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the State and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.<br> <br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a>FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Bipartisan Senate Passage of the PACT&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/16/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-bipartisan-senate-passage-of-the-pact-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 18:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of the Unity Agenda that I laid out in my State of the Union address, I called on Congress to make sure that veterans and their families and caregivers impacted by toxic exposures finally get the benefits and comprehensive health care they earned and deserve. Today, the United States Senate answered that call&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As part of the Unity Agenda that I laid out in my State of the Union address, I called on Congress to make sure that veterans and their families and caregivers impacted by toxic exposures finally get the benefits and comprehensive health care they earned and deserve. Today, the United States Senate answered that call by overwhelmingly passing the bipartisan<em>&nbsp;Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson Honoring Our PACT Act of&nbsp;</em>2022­—the largest single bill in American history to address our service members’ exposure to burn pits and other toxic substances.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This bill will provide expanded access to health care and disability benefits for veterans harmed by certain toxic exposures, whether in the jungles of Vietnam or the mountains of Afghanistan. It will also let the Department of Veterans Affairs move more quickly and comprehensively in the future to determine if illnesses are related to military service, and it will offer critical support to survivors who were harmed by exposures, including from water contamination at Camp LeJeune. Importantly, the bill includes the tools and resources to ensure that the VA can effectively implement it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Above all, this legislation makes good on our sacred obligation to care for veterans, their families, caregivers, and survivors. I want to thank Chair Tester and Ranking Member Moran for their remarkable work to pass the PACT Act, and I urge the House to swiftly pass this bill so I can sign it into law right away.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in a Press Call on Improving Maternal Health&#160;Outcomes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/16/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-a-press-call-on-improving-maternal-health-outcomes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 16:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:11 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Gene Sperling.&#160; Thank you, and for your extraordinary longstanding service to our country, including the work that you have been doing to ensure the &#8212; the speedy and effective and meaningful implementation of the ARP.&#160; So, thank you for that. I do believe our nation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Via Teleconference</em></p>



<p>10:11 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Gene Sperling.&nbsp; Thank you, and for your extraordinary longstanding service to our country, including the work that you have been doing to ensure the &#8212; the speedy and effective and meaningful implementation of the ARP.&nbsp; So, thank you for that.</p>



<p>I do believe our nation is facing a maternal mortality crisis, given the extent of the work that we as an administration have been doing with our partners.&nbsp; And &#8212; and it is evidenced by the fact that women in our nation are dying from pregnancy-related causes at a higher rate than any other developed nation &#8212; dying before, during, and after childbirth.</p>



<p>Black women are three times more likely to be affected by this and to die from childbirth-related causes.&nbsp; Native women, twice as likely.&nbsp; Rural women, one and a half times likely.</p>



<p>So, our administration has taken historic action to elevate this issue and protect the women of our nation.&nbsp;It&#8217;s that simple.</p>



<p>Last year, we hosted the first-ever White House Maternal Health Day of Action.&nbsp; And this year, I was pleased to bring together members of our Cabinet to focus on the issue of maternal health, which followed, as Gene mentioned, a Call to Action to states to extend Medicaid coverage for postpartum women from 2 months &#8212; from a mere 2 months &#8212; to 12 months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And notably, the ARP gives &#8212; and gives the states the authority to do this.&nbsp; So, again, the connection between this initiative and the details of the ARP and its implementation have made all the difference.&nbsp; And it matters because, of course, Medicaid covers approximately 40 percent of all births nationwide, and one third of pregnancy-related deaths occur between one and a half months and one year postpartum.</p>



<p>Throughout my career, as Gene has said, I do believe that one of the greatest priorities for us in public policy must be the health, safety, and wellbeing of women, including maternal health.&nbsp; And so, today, we are proud to announce that the Centers for Medicaid and Medicaid Service &#8212; and Medicare Services will expand coverage and approve the expansion of coverage in the states of Maine, Minnesota, in&nbsp;<s>New York</s>&nbsp;[New Mexico], and in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>What this means is that 235,000 women will now have access to 12 months of critical postpartum coverage across 14 states and D.C.&nbsp; This means that 12 months of pelvic exams, vaccinations, postpartum depression screening, and regular checkups will be available to those women.</p>



<p>And I think I said New Mexico and I cer- &#8212; I &#8212; New York &#8212; and I certainly meant New Mexico &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; so I&#8217;ll go back to that.&nbsp;<br><br>But what it also means is that the states now, under the leadership of extraordinary leaders &#8212; like Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham, under the leadership of Lieutenant Governor Peggy Flanagan &#8212; can take the step forward and do what we know the women of America need and deserve, which is to have assistance and to have some recognition about what the realities of this are and what their needs are.<br>This is only the beginning.&nbsp; Our administration will continue to fight until every state has expanded Medicaid coverage.&nbsp; And to be clear, this is about prioritizing the right all women in our nation should have to full reproductive healthcare.</p>



<p>That is what this is about.&nbsp; It is about understanding how all women in our nation, regardless of their income, regardless of where they live, should have access to full reproductive healthcare.</p>



<p>So, together, of course, we are going to continue to work with our partners at the state level, at the local level, our community-based and nonprofit folks to ensure that every woman, every mother has the healthcare she needs to thrive.</p>



<p>And with that, I&#8217;ll turn it back over to the team.&nbsp; And &#8212; and thank you all.<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 10:15 A.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
