<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 20:49:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Senior Administration Officials Travel to&#160;Tunisia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-senior-administration-officials-travel-to-tunisia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 20:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27311</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Principal Deputy National Security Advisor Jon Finer, joined by Acting Assistant Secretary of State for Near Eastern Affairs Joey Hood, traveled to Tunis and met today with President Kais Saied of Tunisia. During the visit, he delivered a message from President Biden reaffirming his personal support, and that of the Biden-Harris Administration, for the Tunisian&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Principal Deputy National Security Advisor Jon Finer, joined by Acting Assistant Secretary of State for Near Eastern Affairs Joey Hood, traveled to Tunis and met today with President Kais Saied of Tunisia. During the visit, he delivered a message from President Biden reaffirming his personal support, and that of the Biden-Harris Administration, for the Tunisian people and urging a swift return to the path of Tunisia’s parliamentary democracy. Principal Deputy National Security Advisor Finer discussed with President Saied the urgent need to appoint a prime minister designate who would form a capable government able to address the immediate economic and health crises facing Tunisia. Empowering a new government to stabilize the economy will also create space for an inclusive dialogue about proposed constitutional and electoral reforms in response to the widely expressed demands of many Tunisians for improved living standards as well as honest, effective, and transparent governance. Principal Deputy National Security Advisor Finer also met with civil society leaders and conveyed U.S. support for civil society’s active participation in building a democratic and prosperous future for all Tunisians.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Montana Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-montana-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 18:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Montana and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by straight-line winds on June 10, 2021. Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Montana and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by straight-line winds on June 10, 2021.<br><br>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the straight-line winds in the counties of Dawson, Garfield, McCone, Richland, and Roosevelt.<br><br>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.<br><br>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Jon K. Huss as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp;<br><br>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.<br><br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Eviction&#160;Moratorium</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-eviction-moratorium/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 17:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout the pandemic, preventing evictions and keeping people in their homes has been a proven way of slowing the spread of COVID-19. The Administration believes that CDC’s new moratorium is a proper use of its lawful authority to protect the public health. We are pleased that the district court left the moratorium in place, though&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Throughout the pandemic, preventing evictions and keeping people in their homes has been a proven way of slowing the spread of COVID-19.</p>



<p>The Administration believes that CDC’s new moratorium is a proper use of its lawful authority to protect the public health. We are pleased that the district court left the moratorium in place, though we are aware that further proceedings in this case are likely.</p>



<p>The President continues to call on State and local elected officials and judges to issue local eviction moratoriums and move aggressively to distribute the $46.5 billion in emergency rental assistance funds that are available through the bipartisan COVID relief act that Congress passed in December 2020, and through the President’s American Rescue Plan that was enacted in March 2021. And, the President calls on landlords to seek out rental assistance and not evict tenants from their homes, and echoes Attorney General Garland’s calls for state and local courts to implement policies to discourage eviction filings until landlords and tenants have sought emergency rental assistance funds.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How President&#160;Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda Helps Rural&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-how-president-bidens-build-back-better-agenda-helps-rural-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27235</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards a more sustainable, resilient, equitable, and prosperous future.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda includes President Biden’s American Families Plan and key elements of the American Jobs Plan that were not included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure and Investments Act. In Washington, this proposal is known as “reconciliation.” But the bottom line is a plan that will <strong><u>create jobs</u></strong>, <strong><u>cut taxes</u></strong>, and <strong><u>lower costs for working families</u></strong>—all paid for by making the tax code fairer and making the wealthiest and large corporations pay their fair share.<br><br><strong>LOWER COSTS<br><em>Lower Prescription Drug Costs.</em></strong> Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, and nearly <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/press-release/poll-nearly-1-in-4-americans-taking-prescription-drugs-say-its-difficult-to-afford-medicines-including-larger-shares-with-low-incomes/">1 in 4 Americans</a> struggle to afford prescription drugs. President Biden’s plan will lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Child Care Costs.</em></strong> Rural children are <a href="https://earlylearningnation.com/2018/05/the-challenges-of-rural-pre-k/">less likely to be enrolled in pre-K programs</a> than urban and suburban children, and a third of rural children enter kindergarten without having attended pre-K. President Biden’s plan lowers child care costs and makes universal preschool a reality, providing parents access to high-quality programs in the setting of their choice. The Build Back Better Agenda would also institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, to help improve the health of new mothers and reduce wage loss.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Health Care Costs.</em></strong> More than <a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2019/04/health-insurance-rural-america.html">12 percent of people living in completely rural counties</a> lacked health insurance before President Biden took office, coverage under the Affordable Care Act (even with the ACA’s premium subsidies) was too expensive for many families, and almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicaid/issue-brief/the-coverage-gap-uninsured-poor-adults-in-states-that-do-not-expand-medicaid/">2.2 million people </a>were locked out of coverage because their state refused to expand Medicaid. President Biden’s plan lowers health care costs for those buying coverage through the ACA by extending the American Rescue Plan’s cost savings, providing premium relief that is lowering health insurance costs by an average of $50 per person per month for more than 9 million people.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Higher Education Costs. </em></strong>Education beyond high school is increasingly important to succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century economy, even as it has become unaffordable for too many families. The Build Back Better Agenda would provide two years of free community college—boosting the earnings of low-wage high school graduates by nearly $6,000 per year. President Biden’s plan also increases the maximum Pell Grant award by almost $1,500, and invests billions in subsidized tuition for low- and middle-income students at Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and minority-serving institutions.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Housing Costs</em>. </strong><a href="https://www.urban.org/sites/default/files/publication/99045/rental_housing_for_a_21st_century_rural_america.pdf">One in four rural renters</a> pay over half their income in rent. The Plan’s investments help lower housing costs and increase the supply of affordable housing through tax credits and government financing, including constructing and rehabilitating more than one million sustainable rental housing units and more than 500,000 homes working families can afford. It will also make investments to preserve existing public housing as well as remove lead-based paint from housing units.<br><br><strong>CUT TAXES<br><em>Tax Cuts for Families with Children. </em></strong><a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/webdocs/publications/90556/eib-200.pdf#:~:text=The%20rural%20poverty%20rate%20was%2016.4%20percent%20in,2017%20but%20remained%20highest%20among%20racial%2Fethnic%20minority%20groups.">16.4 percent of rural people</a> fall below the poverty line, struggling to pay expenses like food, rent, health care and transportation for their families. President Biden’s plan will extend the Child Tax Credit expansion in the American Rescue Plan, lowering taxes for middle class families by providing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ARP-Fact-Sheet-AAPI-Communities.pdf">the families of more than 66 million</a> kids and an estimated <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/expanding-child-tax-credit-and-earned-income-tax-credit-would-benefit-more">10.4 million rural residents </a>across the U.S. a major tax cut – benefitting 45 percent of children from rural areas.<br><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Workers Without Children.</em></strong> The President’s agenda permanently extends the American Rescue Plan’s increase to the Earned-Income Tax Credit from $543 to $1,502. This will benefit roughly 17 million low-wage workers, including cashiers, cooks, delivery drivers, food preparation workers, and child care providers.<br><br><strong>CREATE JOBS<br><em>Locally-Led Economic Development. </em></strong>Many rural economies continue to struggle with long-term job loss and economic transition. The President’s plan will create a new Rural Partnership Program to empower rural regions, including Tribal Nations and territories, with resources to attract, access, and leverage federal, private, and philanthropic resources; lead strategic and effective development projects; and create results that matter to communities.<br><br><strong><em>Workforce Training.</em></strong> The U.S. has chronically underinvested in workforce development, and millions of jobs have been going unfilled in growing sectors such as construction and health care. Through high-quality career and technical education pathways and Registered Apprenticeships, President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will invest in training programs that will prepare millions of American workers for high-quality jobs in growing sectors.<br><br><strong><em>Clean Energy Jobs. </em></strong>When President Biden thinks about climate change, he thinks jobs. To position the U.S. to tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice, the President’s plan would create good-paying, union jobs, establish an energy efficiency and clean energy standard, expand and extend clean energy and electric vehicle tax credits, and enlist a new Civilian Climate Corps. As part of the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act, the Build Back Better Agenda would also restore American manufacturing with R&amp;D investments—including critical investments to compete on clean energy.<br><br><strong><em>Investments in Teachers and Schools. </em></strong>Even before the pandemic, our schools faced an estimated teacher shortage of 100,000, undermining the education of our children and students of color in particular. <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/education/tackling-teacher-and-principal-shortages-in-rural-areas.aspx">Rural teachers</a> have an average starting salary that is more than $7,000 less than their suburban counterparts. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will upgrade school infrastructure, address teacher shortages and improve teacher preparation, expand free school meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year and help families purchase food during the summer.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Read about the President’s full Build Back Better Agenda here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/">https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/</a><br></em><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda Will Deliver Historic Investments in American Families and&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-president-bidens-build-back-better-agenda-will-deliver-historic-investments-in-american-families-and-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:14:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards a more sustainable, resilient, equitable, and prosperous future.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda includes President Biden’s American Families Plan and key elements of the American Jobs Plan that were not included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal. In Washington, this proposal is known as “reconciliation.” But the bottom line is a plan that will <strong><u>create jobs</u>, <u>cut taxes</u>, and <u>lower costs for working families</u></strong>—all paid for by making the tax code fairer and making the wealthiest and large corporations pay their fair share.<br><br><strong><u><strong>LOWER COSTS</strong></u></strong><br><strong><em>Lower Child Care Costs. </em></strong>For 57 percent of children under six, there are no good choices for child care where they live. Only 44 percent of four-year-olds are served by public preschool programs. Nearly four in five private sector workers have no access to paid family leave. The President’s plan would ensure that no middle-class family pays more than 7 percent of their income for high-quality child care up to age 5—and that working families most in need won’t pay anything—saving the average family $14,800 per year. President Biden will also make universal preschool a reality, partnering with states to offer every parent access to high-quality preschool for 3- and 4- year-olds in the setting of their choice. Fully implementing this investment is projected to benefit five million families and save the average American family $13,000 per year. And the Build Back Better Agenda would institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, to help improve the health of new mothers and reduce wage loss.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Higher Education Costs. </em></strong>Education beyond high school is increasingly important to succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century economy, even as it has become unaffordable for too many families. The Build Back Better Agenda would provide two years of free community college—boosting the earnings of low-wage high school graduates by nearly $6,000 per year. President Biden’s plan will also increase the maximum Pell Grant award by almost $1,500, and invest billions in subsidized tuition for low- and middle-income students at Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and minority-serving institutions. The plan also invests in evidence-based strategies to strengthen completion and retention rates at institutions that serve high numbers of low-income students, particularly community colleges.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Prescription Drug Costs.</em></strong> Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, and nearly <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/press-release/poll-nearly-1-in-4-americans-taking-prescription-drugs-say-its-difficult-to-afford-medicines-including-larger-shares-with-low-incomes/">1 in 4 Americans</a> struggle to afford prescription drugs. President Biden’s plan will lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Health Care Costs.</em></strong> The Build Back Better Agenda would reduce health insurance premiums, saving 9 million people an average of $50 per person per month, and add dental, vision, and hearing coverage to Medicare. By closing the Medicaid gap for low-income Americans, the President’s plan would help 4 million uninsured people gain coverage. President Biden’s agenda would also expand home care for older and disabled Americans, while improving the jobs and the pay of the home care workers who care for them.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Housing Costs. </em></strong>Driven by the largest shortfall of new housing units in 50 years, rents and housing prices continue to increase—with some 10.5 million renters paying more than half their incomes in rent. The Build Back Better Agenda will use tax credits and government financing to bolster affordable and resilient housing, supporting the construction or rehabilitation of more than two million homes.<br><br><strong><u><span style="text-decoration: underline">CUT TAXES</span></u></strong><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Families with Children.</em></strong> One third of all adults with children struggle to pay their usual expenses. The American Rescue Plan increased the Child Tax Credit from $2,000 per child to $3,000 per child for children over six and $3,600 for children under six. The Build Back Better Agenda will extend the Child Tax Credit expansion in the American Rescue Plan, providing 39 million households and nearly 90 percent of American children a major tax cut and cutting child poverty nearly in half.<br><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Workers Without Children.</em></strong> The President’s agenda permanently extends the American Rescue Plan’s increase to the Earned-Income Tax Credit from $543 to $1,502. This will benefit roughly 17 million low-wage workers, including cashiers, cooks, delivery drivers, food preparation workers, and child care providers.<br><br><strong><u>CREATE JOBS</u></strong><br><strong><em>Workforce Training.</em></strong> The U.S. has chronically underinvested in workforce development, and millions of jobs have been going unfilled in growing sectors such as construction and health care. Through high-quality career and technical education pathways and Registered Apprenticeships, President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will invest in training programs that will prepare millions of American workers for high-quality jobs in growing sectors.<br><br><strong><em>Clean Energy Jobs. </em></strong>When President Biden thinks about climate change, he thinks jobs. To position the U.S. to tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice, the President’s plan would create good-paying, union jobs, establish an energy efficiency and clean energy standard, expand and extend clean energy and electric vehicle tax credits, and enlist a new Civilian Climate Corps.<br><br><strong><em>Investments in Teachers and Schools. </em></strong>Even before the pandemic, our schools faced an estimated teacher shortage of 100,000, undermining the education of our children and students of color in particular. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will address teacher shortages and improve teacher preparation, including through teacher residencies and Grow Your Own programs that produce better outcomes and develop more teachers of color. It would expand free school meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year and help families purchase food during the summer. And the President’s plan also invests in upgrading school infrastructure, so that we have cutting-edge, energy-efficient, resilient school buildings with technology and labs that will prepare students for the jobs of the future.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How President&#160;Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda Helps Black&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-how-president-bidens-build-back-better-agenda-helps-black-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27237</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards a more sustainable, resilient, equitable, and prosperous future.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda includes President Biden’s American Families Plan and key elements of the American Jobs Plan that were not included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure and Investments Act. In Washington, this proposal is known as “reconciliation.” But the bottom line is a plan that will <strong><u>create jobs</u></strong>, <strong><u>cut taxes</u></strong>, and <strong><u>lower costs for working families</u></strong>—all paid for by making the tax code fairer and making the wealthiest and large corporations pay their fair share.<br><br><strong>LOWER COSTS</strong><br><strong><em>Lower Prescription Drug Costs.</em></strong> Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, contributing to the fact that <a href="https://www.nashp.org/states-curb-racial-inequities-in-rx-drug-affordability-with-targeted-legislation/">Black individuals use 10 to 40 percent fewer medications</a> than their White counterparts for the same illnesses. President Biden’s plan will lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Child Care Costs.</em></strong> Only<a href="https://usafacts.org/articles/how-many-children-attend-preschool-us/"> 62.6 percent of all three- and four-year-old Black</a> children are enrolled in preschool or kindergarten programs. President Biden’s plan lowers child care costs and makes universal preschool a reality for all three and four year-olds, providing parents access to high-quality programs in the setting of their choice. The Build Back Better Agenda would also institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, which will help improve Black maternal health outcomes and reduce wage losses that cause persistent earning and wealth gaps for Black women.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Health Care Costs.</em></strong> Almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/uninsured/issue-brief/key-facts-about-the-uninsured-population/">3.9 million Black people</a> were uninsured in 2019 before President Biden took office, coverage under the Affordable Care Act (even with the ACA’s premium subsidies) was too expensive for many families, and almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/taking-a-closer-look-at-characteristics-of-people-in-the-coverage-gap/">1.3 million people of color</a> were locked out of coverage because their state refused to expand Medicaid. President Biden’s plan lowers health care costs for those buying coverage through the ACA by extending the American Rescue Plan’s cost savings, which helps <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/private/pdf/265581/aspe-uninsured-trends-aapi-ib.pdf">360,000 Black people </a>save an average of $50 per person per month, and allowing 328,000 uninsured Black people to gain coverage. The plan also adds  dental, vision, and hearing coverage for the more than <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/state-indicator/medicare-beneficiaries-by-raceethnicity/?dataView=1&amp;currentTimeframe=0&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">5.8 million Black people on Medicare</a> and closes the Medicaid gap for low-income Americans.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Higher Education Costs. </em></strong>Education beyond high school is increasingly important to succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century economy, even as it has become unaffordable for too many families. The Build Back Better Agenda would provide two years of free community college—boosting the earnings of low-wage high school graduates by nearly $6,000 per year. President Biden’s plan also increases the maximum Pell Grant award by almost $1,500, and invests billions in subsidized tuition for low- and middle-income students at Historically Black Colleges and Universities and minority-serving institutions. The plan also invests in evidence-based strategies to strengthen completion and retention rates at institutions that serve high numbers of low-income students, particularly community colleges.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Housing Costs</em>.</strong><a href="https://www.enterprisecommunity.org/blog/12/20/black-renters-entered-pandemic-facing-significant-housing-challenges#:~:text=Our%20analysis%20of%20the%202019,housing%20(see%20figure%201).&amp;text=Indeed%2C%20nearly%20a%20quarter%20of,and%20had%20extremely%20low%20incomes.">30 percent of Black renters</a> pay over half their income in rent. The Plan’s investments help lower housing costs and increase the supply of affordable housing through tax credits and government financing, including constructing and rehabilitating more than one million sustainable rental housing units and more than 500,000 homes working families can afford. It will also make investments to preserve existing public housing as well as remove lead-based paint from housing units.<br><br><strong>CUT TAXES</strong><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Families with Children.</em></strong><a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/601acf15866c634924d12963/1612369686861/Poverty-Reduction-Analysis-Biden-Economic-Relief-CPSP-2021.pdf"> 22.1 percent of Black people </a>fall below the poverty line, struggling to pay expenses like food, rent, health care and transportation for their families. President Biden’s plan will extend the Child Tax Credit expansion in the American Rescue Plan, lowering taxes for middle class families by providing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ARP-Fact-Sheet-AAPI-Communities.pdf">the families of more than 66 million</a> kids and nearly <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/601acf15866c634924d12963/1612369686861/Poverty-Reduction-Analysis-Biden-Economic-Relief-CPSP-2021.pdf">3 million Black people</a> in the U.S. a major tax cut –  cutting the Black poverty rate by 34.3 percent.  This is especially critical for the <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/women/news/2021/03/29/497658/breadwinning-mothers-critical-familys-economic-security/">85% of Black women</a> who are either sole or co-breadwinners for their families.<br><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Workers Without Children.</em></strong> The President’s agenda permanently extends the American Rescue Plan’s increase to the Earned-Income Tax Credit from $543 to $1,502. This will benefit roughly 17 million low-wage workers, including cashiers, cooks, delivery drivers, food preparation workers, and child care providers.<br><br><strong>CREATE JOBS</strong><br><strong><em>Workforce Training.</em></strong> The U.S. has chronically underinvested in workforce development, and millions of jobs have been going unfilled in growing sectors such as construction and health care. Through high-quality career and technical education pathways and Registered Apprenticeships, President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will invest in training programs that will prepare millions of American workers for high-quality jobs in growing sectors.<br><br><strong><em>Clean Energy Jobs. </em></strong>When President Biden thinks about climate change, he thinks jobs. To position the U.S. to tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice, the President’s plan would create good-paying, union jobs, establish an energy efficiency and clean energy standard, expand and extend clean energy and electric vehicle tax credits, and enlist a new Civilian Climate Corps. As part of the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act, the Build Back Better Agenda would also restore American manufacturing with R&amp;D investments—including critical investments to compete on clean energy.<br><br><strong><em>Investments in Teachers and Schools. </em></strong>Even before the pandemic, our schools faced an estimated teacher shortage of 100,000, undermining the education of our children and disproportionately impacting students. Only about <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/clr">7 percent of our nation’s public school teachers are Black</a>, even though Black students make up <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/cge">15 percent of public school students</a>. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/fact-sheet-how-the-biden-harris-administration-is-advancing-educational-equity/">advance educational equity</a> by upgrading school infrastructure, addressing teacher shortages and improving teacher preparation, increasing the diversity of the teacher pipeline, and expanding free school meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year and helping families purchase food during the summer.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><em>Read about the President’s full Build Back Better Agenda here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/<br></a></em><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How President&#160;Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda Helps Latino&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-how-president-bidens-build-back-better-agenda-helps-latino-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards a more sustainable, resilient, equitable, and prosperous future.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda includes President Biden’s American Families Plan and key elements of the American Jobs Plan that were not included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure and Investments Act. In Washington, this proposal is known as “reconciliation.” But the bottom line is a plan that will <strong><u>create jobs</u></strong>, <strong><u>cut taxes</u></strong>, and <strong><u>lower costs for working families</u></strong>—all paid for by making the tax code fairer and making the wealthiest and large corporations pay their fair share. President Biden and Vice President Harris have also repeatedly expressed their strong support for including immigration reform in upcoming reconciliation legislation to enable Dreamers, TPS recipients, farmworkers and essential workers to gain long-awaited pathways to citizenship. <br><br><strong>LOWER COSTS</strong><br><strong><em>Lower Prescription Drug Costs.</em></strong> Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, contributing to the fact that <a href="https://www.nashp.org/states-curb-racial-inequities-in-rx-drug-affordability-with-targeted-legislation/">Latino individuals use 10 to 40 percent fewer medications</a> than their White counterparts for the same illnesses. President Biden’s plan will lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Child Care Costs.</em></strong> Only <a href="https://usafacts.org/articles/how-many-children-attend-preschool-us/">59.4 percent of all three- and four-year-old Hispanic children</a> are enrolled in preschool or kindergarten programs. President Biden’s plan lowers child care costs and makes universal preschool a reality, providing parents access to high-quality programs in the setting of their choice. The Build Back Better Agenda would also institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, to help improve the health of new mothers and reduce wage loss.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Health Care Costs.</em></strong> Almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/uninsured/issue-brief/key-facts-about-the-uninsured-population/">10.9 million Hispanic people</a> were uninsured in 2019 before President Biden took office, coverage under the Affordable Care Act (even with the ACA’s premium subsidies) was too expensive for many families, and almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/taking-a-closer-look-at-characteristics-of-people-in-the-coverage-gap/">1.3 million people of color</a> were locked out of coverage because their state refused to expand Medicaid. President Biden’s plan lowers health care costs for those buying coverage through the ACA by extending the American Rescue Plan’s cost savings, which helps <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/private/pdf/265581/aspe-uninsured-trends-aapi-ib.pdf">730,000 Latino people </a>save an average of $50 per person per month, and allowing 580,000 uninsured Latinos to gain coverage. The plan also adds  dental, vision, and hearing coverage for the more than <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/state-indicator/medicare-beneficiaries-by-raceethnicity/?dataView=1&amp;currentTimeframe=0&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">5 million Hispanic people on Medicare</a> and closes the Medicaid gap for low-income Americans.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Higher Education Costs. </em></strong>Education beyond high school is increasingly important to succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century economy, even as it has become unaffordable for too many families. The Build Back Better Agenda would provide two years of free community college—boosting the earnings of low-wage high school graduates by nearly $6,000 per year. President Biden’s plan also increases the maximum Pell Grant award by almost $1,500, and invests billions in subsidized tuition for low- and middle-income students at minority-serving institutions. The plan also invests in evidence-based strategies to strengthen completion and retention rates at institutions that serve high numbers of low-income students, particularly community colleges.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Housing Costs</em>.</strong> More than <a href="https://curs.unc.edu/2019/11/26/calling-it-home-latino-rental-housing-affordability/">55% of Latino renters</a> pay over 30% of their income in rent. The Plan’s investments help lower housing costs and increase the supply of affordable housing through tax credits and government financing, including constructing and rehabilitating more than one million sustainable rental housing units and more than 500,000 homes working families can afford. It will also make investments to preserve existing public housing as well as remove lead-based paint from housing units.<br><br><strong>CUT TAXES</strong><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Families with Children.</em></strong><a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/601acf15866c634924d12963/1612369686861/Poverty-Reduction-Analysis-Biden-Economic-Relief-CPSP-2021.pdf"> 21.2 percent of Hispanic people </a>fall below the poverty line, struggling to pay expenses like food, rent, health care and transportation for their families. President Biden’s plan will extend the Child Tax Credit expansion in the American Rescue Plan, lowering taxes for middle class families by providing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ARP-Fact-Sheet-AAPI-Communities.pdf">the families of more than 66 million</a> kids and nearly <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/601acf15866c634924d12963/1612369686861/Poverty-Reduction-Analysis-Biden-Economic-Relief-CPSP-2021.pdf">4.5 million Hispanic people</a> in the U.S. a major tax cut –  cutting the Hispanic poverty rate by 39 percent. This is especially critical for the <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/women/news/2021/03/29/497658/breadwinning-mothers-critical-familys-economic-security/">61% of Hispanic</a> women who are either sole or co-breadwinners for their families.<br><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Workers Without Children.</em></strong> The President’s agenda permanently extends the American Rescue Plan’s increase to the Earned-Income Tax Credit from $543 to $1,502. This will benefit roughly 17 million low-wage workers, including cashiers, cooks, delivery drivers, food preparation workers, and child care providers.<br><br><strong>CREATE JOBS</strong><br><strong><em>Workforce Training.</em></strong> The U.S. has chronically underinvested in workforce development, and millions of jobs have been going unfilled in growing sectors such as construction and health care. Through high-quality career and technical education pathways and Registered Apprenticeships, President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will invest in training programs that will prepare millions of American workers for high-quality jobs in growing sectors.<br><br><strong><em>Clean Energy Jobs. </em></strong>When President Biden thinks about climate change, he thinks jobs. To position the U.S. to tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice, the President’s plan would create good-paying, union jobs, establish an energy efficiency and clean energy standard, expand and extend clean energy and electric vehicle tax credits, and enlist a new Civilian Climate Corps. As part of the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act, the Build Back Better Agenda would also restore American manufacturing with R&amp;D investments—including critical investments to compete on clean energy.<br><br><strong><em>Investments in Teachers and Schools. </em></strong>Even before the pandemic, our schools faced an estimated teacher shortage of 100,000, undermining the education of our children and students of color in particular. Only <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/clr">9 percent of our nation’s public school teachers are Hispanic</a>, even though Hispanic students make up <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/cge">27 percent of all public elementary and secondary students</a>. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/fact-sheet-how-the-biden-harris-administration-is-advancing-educational-equity/">advance educational equity</a> by upgrading school infrastructure, addressing teacher shortages and improving teacher preparation, increasing the diversity of the teacher pipeline, and expanding free school meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year and helping families purchase food during the summer.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Read about the President’s full Build Back Better Agenda here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/">https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/</a><br></em><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How President&#160;Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda Helps Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-how-president-bidens-build-back-better-agenda-helps-asian-american-native-hawaiian-and-pacific-islander-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27223</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards a more sustainable, resilient, equitable, and prosperous future.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda includes President Biden’s American Families Plan and key elements of the American Jobs Plan that were not included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure and Investments Act. In Washington, this proposal is known as “reconciliation.” But the bottom line is a plan that will <strong><u>create jobs</u></strong>, <strong><u>cut taxes</u></strong>, and <strong><u>lower costs for working families</u></strong>—all paid for by making the tax code fairer and making the wealthiest and large corporations pay their fair share. President Biden and Vice President Harris have also repeatedly expressed their strong support for including immigration reform in upcoming reconciliation legislation to enable Dreamers, TPS recipients, farmworkers and essential workers to gain long-awaited pathways to citizenship.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>LOWER COSTS</strong><br><strong><em>Lower Prescription Drug Costs.</em></strong> Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, and nearly <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/press-release/poll-nearly-1-in-4-americans-taking-prescription-drugs-say-its-difficult-to-afford-medicines-including-larger-shares-with-low-incomes/">1 in 4 Americans</a> struggle to afford prescription drugs. President Biden’s plan will lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Child Care Costs.</em></strong> Only <a href="https://usafacts.org/articles/how-many-children-attend-preschool-us/">57.9 percent of all three- and four-year-old Asian American</a> children are enrolled in preschool or kindergarten programs and half of <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/women/reports/2021/03/04/496703/economic-status-asian-american-pacific-islander-women/">Asian American women</a> live in areas where the supply of child care is too low to meet demand. President Biden’s plan lowers child care costs and makes universal preschool a reality, providing parents access to high-quality programs in the setting of their choice. The Build Back Better Agenda would also institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, to help improve the health of new mothers and reduce wage loss.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Health Care Costs.</em></strong> More than <a href="https://www.kff.org/uninsured/issue-brief/key-facts-about-the-uninsured-population/">1.5 million AA and NHPIs</a> were uninsured in 2019 before President Biden took office, coverage under the Affordable Care Act (even with the ACA’s premium subsidies) was too expensive for many families, and almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/taking-a-closer-look-at-characteristics-of-people-in-the-coverage-gap/">1.3 million people of color</a> were locked out of coverage because their state refused to expand Medicaid. President Biden’s plan lowers health care costs for those buying coverage through the ACA by extending the American Rescue Plan’s cost savings, which helps <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/private/pdf/265581/aspe-uninsured-trends-aapi-ib.pdf">197,000 uninsured AAPI people</a> save an average of $50 per person per month, and allowing more than 150,000 uninsured AAPI people to gain coverage. The plan also adds dental, vision, and hearing coverage for the more than <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/state-indicator/medicare-beneficiaries-by-raceethnicity/?dataView=1&amp;currentTimeframe=0&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">2.3 million AAPIs on Medicare</a> and closes the Medicaid gap for low-income Americans.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Higher Education Costs. </em></strong>Education beyond high school is increasingly important to succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century economy, even as it has become unaffordable for too many families. The Build Back Better Agenda would provide two years of free community college—boosting the earnings of low-wage high school graduates by nearly $6,000 per year. President Biden’s plan also increases the maximum Pell Grant award by almost $1,500, and invests billions in subsidized tuition for low- and middle-income students at minority-serving institutions. The plan also invests in evidence-based strategies to strengthen completion and retention rates at institutions that serve high numbers of low-income students, particularly community colleges.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Housing Costs</em></strong><strong>.</strong><a href="https://nlihc.org/resource/new-research-highlights-housing-experiences-asian-americans-and-pacific-islanders#:~:text=AAPI%20renters%20are%20severely%20cost,renters%20are%20severely%20cost%2Dburdened.&amp;text=Bangladeshi%2C%20Vietnamese%2C%20and%20Pakistani%20renters,%2C%20and%2034%25%2C%20respectively">26 percent of Asian American renters and 27 percent of Native Hawaiians and Pacific Islander renters</a> pay over half their income in rent. The Plan’s investments help lower housing costs and increases the supply of affordable housing through tax credits and government financing, including constructing and rehabilitating more than one million sustainable rental housing units and more than 500,000 homes working families can afford. It will also make investments to preserve existing public housing as well as remove lead-based paint from housing units.<br><br><strong>CUT TAXES</strong><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Families with Children. </em></strong><a href="https://www.kff.org/infographic/health-and-health-care-for-asian-americans-native-hawaiians-and-other-pacific-islanders-nhopis-in-the-united-states/">9 percent of Asian American families and 16 percent of Native Hawaiian and other Pacific Islander families</a> fall below the poverty line, struggling to pay expenses like food, rent, health care and transportation for their families. President Biden’s plan will extend the Child Tax Credit expansion in the American Rescue Plan, lowering taxes for middle class families by providing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ARP-Fact-Sheet-AAPI-Communities.pdf">the families of more than 66 million</a> kids and nearly <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/601acf15866c634924d12963/1612369686861/Poverty-Reduction-Analysis-Biden-Economic-Relief-CPSP-2021.pdf">600,000 AAPI people</a> in the U.S. a major tax cut –&nbsp; cutting the AAPI poverty rate by 21.7 percent.<br><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Workers Without Children.</em></strong> The President’s agenda permanently extends the American Rescue Plan’s increase to the Earned-Income Tax Credit from $543 to $1,502. This will benefit roughly 17 million low-wage workers, including cashiers, cooks, delivery drivers, food preparation workers, and child care providers.<br><br><strong>CREATE JOBS</strong><br><strong><em>Workforce Training.</em></strong> The U.S. has chronically underinvested in workforce development, and millions of jobs have been going unfilled in growing sectors such as construction and health care. Through high-quality career and technical education pathways and Registered Apprenticeships, President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will invest in training programs that will prepare millions of American workers for high-quality jobs in growing sectors.<br><br><strong><em>Clean Energy Jobs. </em></strong>When President Biden thinks about climate change, he thinks jobs. To position the U.S. to tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice, the President’s plan would create good-paying, union jobs, establish an energy efficiency and clean energy standard, expand and extend clean energy and electric vehicle tax credits, and enlist a new Civilian Climate Corps. As part of the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act, the Build Back Better Agenda would also restore American manufacturing with R&amp;D investments—including critical investments to compete on clean energy.<br><br><strong><em>Investments in Teachers and Schools. </em></strong>Even before the pandemic, our schools faced an estimated teacher shortage of 100,000, undermining the education of our children and students of color in particular. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will upgrade school infrastructure, address teacher shortages and improve teacher preparation, expand free school meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year and help families purchase food during the summer.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Employer Support Of The Guard And Reserve Week,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/08/13/a-proclamation-on-national-employer-support-of-the-guard-and-reserve-week-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 13:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since our founding, courageous men and women&#160;have vowed to serve and defend our country, protect our&#160;citizens, and uphold the principles of our Constitution.&#160; The&#160;citizen Soldiers and Airmen of the National Guard, and the&#160;Soldiers, Sailors, Airmen, Marines, and Coast Guardsmen of&#160;the Reserve, proudly carry on this tradition today.&#160; During National Employer Support of the Guard and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since our founding, courageous men and women&nbsp;have vowed to serve and defend our country, protect our&nbsp;citizens, and uphold the principles of our Constitution.&nbsp; The&nbsp;citizen Soldiers and Airmen of the National Guard, and the&nbsp;Soldiers, Sailors, Airmen, Marines, and Coast Guardsmen of&nbsp;the Reserve, proudly carry on this tradition today.&nbsp; During National Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve Week, we&nbsp;thank and celebrate the civilian employers whose support of&nbsp;our&nbsp;National Guard and Reserve members helps to sustain our&nbsp;all‑volunteer force and our national spirit of service.</p>



<p>National Guard and Reserve members are essential to the safety and security of our Nation, ready to serve at home or abroad at any moment&#8217;s notice.&nbsp; From working on the frontlines of the COVID-19 pandemic, to responding to storm damage and raging wildfires, to&nbsp;deploying overseas, supporting peacekeeping missions abroad, and conducting multilateral exercises with allies and partner nations, National Guard and Reserve members put their lives on hold &#8212; away from both their families and their civilian workplaces &#8212; to stand as a shield or a support whenever our country is in need.&nbsp; When they complete their mission, National Guard and Reserve members return to their civilian careers and fulfill their obligation of monthly weekend drills and annual trainings &#8212; always ensuring they are ready to answer the next call to serve.</p>



<p>We owe a profound gratitude to our National Guard and Reserve members, as well as their civilian employers.&nbsp; In&nbsp;supporting their talented employees&#8217; service to our Nation, employers of National Guard and Reserve members directly contribute to our military readiness and our national security.&nbsp; As our Guard and Reserve members navigate the challenges that accompany their service, many civilian employers go&nbsp;above and beyond to support our service members and their families. &nbsp;National Guard and Reserve members should not have to&nbsp;worry about their civilian employment while they are serving on a mission, and many employers are stepping up with generous pay and leave policies, extension of benefits like health care for family members, and flexibility and support for Guard and Reserve spouses to help fulfill our sacred obligation as a&nbsp;Nation to always take care of those who serve in uniform.</p>



<p>My Administration understands the national security imperative behind improving the well-being of our service members and their families as they balance the pressures of their civilian careers with the demands of military service. &nbsp;Through the First Lady&#8217;s work with Joining Forces, we are committed to supporting military and veteran families, caregivers, and survivors through economic and entrepreneurship opportunities, support for military child education, and health and well-being resources. &nbsp;Ensuring continuing economic opportunities for military and veteran families through meaningful employment is essential, and we are&nbsp;grateful for all&nbsp;of the employers who understand the value in&nbsp;hiring and retaining National Guard and Reserve members and their spouses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden family is a National Guard family, and we are forever grateful and in awe of those who, like our son Beau, understand that duty and service to others is what makes us who&nbsp;we are as Americans. &nbsp;We understand some of the unique challenges that National Guard and Reserve members and their families face &#8212; challenges that are made smaller because of&nbsp;the&nbsp;incredible, patriotic support of their employers. &nbsp;I&nbsp;encourage all Americans to join me in recognizing and thanking employers of our National Guard and Reserve members for their vast contributions to our economy, our communities, and the success of our Nation and our Armed Forces.&nbsp; I also encourage National Guard and Reserve members to recognize their employers who have gone above and beyond in supporting them with the Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve (ESGR), the Department of Defense program that promotes cooperation and understanding between civilian employers and their National Guard and Reserve employees.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim August 15 through August 21, 2021, as National Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve Week.&nbsp; I&nbsp;call&nbsp;upon the people of the United States, State and local officials, private organizations, and all military commanders to&nbsp;honor employers of National Guard and Reserve members with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirteenth day of August, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Appoints Members to U.S. AbilityOne&#160;Commission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/president-biden-appoints-members-to-u-s-abilityone-commission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced that he has appointed the following individuals to the U.S. AbilityOne Commission, which administers the AbilityOne Program, one of the nation’s largest sources of employment for people who are blind or have significant disabilities: Bryan Bashin, Appointee for Commissioner Christina Brandt, Appointee for Commissioner Gabriel M. Cazares, Appointee for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced that he has appointed the following individuals to the U.S. AbilityOne Commission, which administers the AbilityOne Program, one of the nation’s largest sources of employment for people who are blind or have significant disabilities:</p>



<ul><li>Bryan Bashin, Appointee for Commissioner</li><li>Christina Brandt, Appointee for Commissioner</li><li>Gabriel M. Cazares, Appointee for Commissioner</li><li>Chai Rachel Feldblum, Appointee for Commissioner</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong>Bryan Bashin, Commissioner</strong><br>Bryan Bashin is CEO of the Lighthouse for the Blind and Visually-Impaired in San Francisco, a 119-year-old nonprofit devoted to the comprehensive training and employment of blind people.  For 30 years his organization has employed blind workers through the National Industries for the Blind, one of the central non-profits in the AbilityOne program. Over the last 11 years, Bashin has overseen significant expansions of direct blind employment in the AbilityOne space, but most importantly in competitive, integrated workplaces. Bashin previously worked as an Assistant Regional Commissioner for the Department of Education’s Rehabilitation Services Administration (RSA) where he supervised $400 million in federal disability spending in Arizona, Nevada, California, Hawaii, and Pacific territories. From 1998 until 2004, Bashin was Executive Director of the Sacramento Society for the Blind, where he led a strong expansion of blindness services, including competitive employment programs. Bashin has also been an expert witness in cases involving employment of people with disabilities. A former science journalist, Bashin is well acquainted with industrial and technical processes and skill needs of employers. Bashin is currently a Board member of VisionServe Alliance, a membership association of more than 100 U.S. blindness agencies. <br><br><strong>Christina Brandt, Commissioner</strong><br>Christina Brandt is the CEO of an innovative nonprofit, an AbilityOne producer with over four decades of quality service to the government customer. She transformed AtWork! from a sheltered workshop paying subminimum wages to a nationally recognized best-practice provider of customized and integrated community employment for people with intellectual and developmental disabilities. As a subject matter expert, Christina has delivered training and technical assistance in multiple states, including significant work in Oregon implementing the settlement of <em>Lane vs. Brown</em>. Throughout her 46-year career she has advanced equity and inclusion for people with disabilities and was instrumental in securing Washington State’s Employment First legislation.<br><br><strong>Gabe Cazares, Commissioner</strong><br>Gabe Cazares currently serves as the Director of Mayor Sylvester Turner’s Office for People with Disabilities in the City of Houston, Texas. In this capacity, Gabe oversees the accessible and timely delivery of city services, programs, and activities for over 215,000 Houstonians with disabilities. Prior to his appointment, he served as the Manager of Government Affairs at the National Federation of the Blind in Baltimore, Maryland. There he managed the organization&#8217;s education, technology, immigrants&#8217; rights, LGBTQ, and blind entrepreneur small business policy portfolio. Gabe holds a Bachelor of Arts in Political Science with a Spanish minor from Texas State University. He and his partner, Derin Dacey, live in Houston with their 4-year-old rescue dog, Sam.<br><br><strong>Chai Feldblum, Commissioner</strong><br>Chai Feldblum is a national expert in disability law and employment. She led the drafting and negotiating of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 and the ADA Amendments Act of 2008. As a law professor at Georgetown University Law Center, she and her students represented non-profit organizations, including disability rights organizations, in advocating for legislation and administrative regulations to support social justice goals. Chai served as a Commissioner of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission during the Obama-Biden Administration, where she spearheaded the issuance of regulations under Section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973. Those regulations established a goal of 12% representation in the federal workforce of people with all disabilities and a 2% representation of people with significant disabilities. The latter group includes people with the type of disabilities hired under the AbilityOne program. Chai is a lesbian and has a psychiatric disability of anxiety disorder.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
