<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:57:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Release: Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/press-release-nominations-sent-to-the-senate-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Stephanie Dawkins Davis, of Michigan, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Sixth Circuit, vice Helene N. White, retiring. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Stephanie Dawkins Davis, of Michigan, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Sixth Circuit, vice Helene N. White, retiring.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Additional Advisors for Supreme Court&#160;Process</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/president-biden-announces-additional-advisors-for-supreme-court-process/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As President Biden considers a range of deeply qualified potential nominees for the Supreme Court and seeks the advice of lawmakers in both parties as well as legal experts across the country, he is adding three new advisors for the nomination and confirmation process. These advisors bring decades of experience to the table and will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As President Biden considers a range of deeply qualified potential nominees for the Supreme Court and seeks the advice of lawmakers in both parties as well as legal experts across the country, he is adding three new advisors for the nomination and confirmation process.</p>



<p>These advisors bring decades of experience to the table and will join the White House team working with the President on the selection of the nation’s first Black woman to the Supreme Court, reporting to White House Counsel Dana Remus as the President continues to review candidates.</p>



<p>The White House officials currently advising the President on his selection are the Vice President, White House Chief of Staff Ron Klain, Remus, Director of Legislative Affairs Louisa Terrell, White House Senior Advisor Cedric Richmond, Deputy Director of Legislative Affairs Reema Dodin, Senior Counsel to the President Paige Herwig, Counsel to the Vice President Josh Hsu.</p>



<p><strong>Doug Jones, Nomination Advisor for Legislative Affairs</strong></p>



<p><strong>Doug Jones&nbsp;</strong>is a former United States Senator from the State of Alabama. He will advise President Biden on navigating the Senate confirmation process.&nbsp; The first Democratic Senator from Alabama in a quarter century, Jones passed dozens of bipartisan bills into law and started a bipartisan tradition of reading Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.’s “Letter from a Birmingham Jail” in the Senate chamber.&nbsp; Jones was previously the U.S. Attorney for the Northern District of Alabama, where he prosecuted and won the conviction of two Ku Klux Klan members for the 1963 Birmingham church bombing that killed four African-American girls.&nbsp; A native of Fairfield, Alabama, Jones is a graduate of the University of Alabama and Samford University.</p>



<p><strong>Minyon Moore, Nomination Advisor for Engagement</strong></p>



<p><strong>Minyon Moore</strong>&nbsp;is a top public affairs strategist and organizer tapped by President Biden to mobilize a nationwide engagement effort focused on confirmation. &nbsp;Moore currently leads Dewey Square Group’s State and Local Affairs and Multicultural Strategies practices, where she helps clients build coalitions and engage on public policy goals.&nbsp; Moore previously served as President Clinton’s Director of White House Political Affairs and Director the White House Office of Public Liaison, as well as Chief Operating Officer of the Democratic National Committee. &nbsp;Moore coauthored <em>For Colored Girls Who Have Considered Politics</em>&nbsp;in 2018. &nbsp;A Chicago native, she attended the University of Illinois at Chicago and graduated from the Boston University Digital Filmmaking Program (DC).</p>



<p><strong>Ben LaBolt, Nomination Advisor for Communications</strong></p>



<p><strong>Ben LaBolt</strong> is a leading communications strategist joining the White House to advise President Biden on communications and messaging around the confirmation process.  LaBolt is a partner at Bully Pulpit Interactive who served as an advisor to the Biden-Harris Transition. He was previously the national press secretary for President Obama’s re-election campaign and a White House Assistant Press Secretary.  LaBolt has two decades of experience advising for national, state, and local elected officials and campaigns, and served as the White House spokesman on the team to confirm Justice Sonia Sotomayor and Justice Elena Kagan.  A native of LaGrange, Illinois, LaBolt is a graduate of Middlebury College.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at an Event to Reignite the Cancer&#160;Moonshot</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/02/remarks-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-an-event-to-reignite-the-cancer-moonshot/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 22:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room, The White House  1:49 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE FIRST LADY:&#160; Hi &#8212; well, hello.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you.&#160; (Laughs.)&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Please be seated. Gosh, so many friends here.&#160; It&#8217;s so nice to see all of you.&#160; And you&#8217;re getting me so emotional before I have to speak&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room, The White House </p>



<p>1:49 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Hi &#8212; well, hello.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Please be seated.</p>



<p>Gosh, so many friends here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s so nice to see all of you.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re getting me so emotional before I have to speak about cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, anyway, welcome to the White House.</p>



<p>And, you know, certain words have the power to make time stop: Malignant.&nbsp; Aggressive.&nbsp; Terminal.&nbsp; Cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Like a spell, they still the air around us.&nbsp; Frozen in place, we feel the world we knew slipping away.&nbsp; In the span of a breath, a thousand questions fill our minds.&nbsp; &#8220;What can I do?&nbsp; How do I tell people?&nbsp; Why did this happen?&#8221;</p>



<p>And when the hands of the clock begin to move once again, we are not the person we once were, but someone changed: a mother imagining all of the things she might not be there to teach her daughters, a husband wondering how he will juggle chemotherapy appointments with work and childcare, a son trying to be strong for the parents who could outlive him.</p>



<p>It’s not just patients; cancer changes everyone it touches.&nbsp; And in some ways, it touches us all.</p>



<p>For Joe and me, it has stolen our joy.&nbsp; It left us broken in our grief.&nbsp; But through that pain, we found purpose, strengthening our fortitude for this fight to end cancer as we know it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Almost 30 years ago, four of my friends were diagnosed with breast cancer in one year.&nbsp; And one of my dear friends, Winnie, lost her battle.&nbsp; Winnie inspired me to take up the cause of prevention and education.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And since then, I’ve seen the darkness of this disease: financial devastation, confusion over care, and far too many families mourning loved ones.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yet, I’ve also seen hope.</p>



<p>In just this last year, I met a woman whose life was saved by determined nurses who just wouldn’t let her skip her screening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I met a doctor who was inspired to become a cancer researcher because she survived her own diagnosis as a child.</p>



<p>I’ve seen people come together from rival companies or opposite political parties, sharing knowledge and finding common cause, united by the chance to save lives.</p>



<p>A cancer diagnosis today may still leave us feeling hopeless, but we are not hopeless and we are not helpless.</p>



<p>We are living in a golden age of research and discovery.&nbsp; We can end this terror, and all of us have a role to play.</p>



<p>Because this isn’t just about hoping that one person will decipher the answers alone; it’s about listening to patients and survivors and their families, and easing the burden they face.</p>



<p>It’s about the individual choices we can make to stop this disease before it’s too late: to get screenings, to be vigilant with our health.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s about federal and state governments, the business community, and non-profit organizations all helping to make those screenings more available and accessible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s about bringing the brightest minds and the fiercest hearts to the table to learn and to collaborate and to discover together.</p>



<p>Yes, cancer has the power to rewrite our lives.&nbsp; But we have the power too &#8212; more than we even know.&nbsp; We can stop it in its tracks.&nbsp; We can comfort and discover and dream our way past its paralysis.&nbsp; We can come together and rewrite the story that cancer tells.</p>



<p>Now, as your First Lady, I’m deeply proud to be a partner in the commitments we’re making to the Cancer Moonshot today.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re ensuring that all of our government is ready to get to work.&nbsp; We’re going to break down the walls that hold research back.&nbsp; We’re going to bring the best of our nation together &#8212; patients, survivors, caregivers, researchers, doctors, and advocates &#8212; all of you &#8212; so that we can get this done.</p>



<p>And I want you to know that I’ll be there working right beside you.</p>



<p>So, I’m so honored to welcome all of you here to the White House today to take this next step.</p>



<p>Together, we will give Americans a reason to hope.&nbsp; We will use this power of this White House to make your life better.&nbsp; And we will build a future where the word &#8220;cancer&#8221; forever loses its power.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, it’s my pleasure to welcome out next speaker.</p>



<p>Vice President Harris knows the heartache of cancer, but she also knows how much hope can be found in our scientific community.&nbsp; She knows it because she saw it firsthand in her brilliant mother who dedicated her life to researching breast cancer.</p>



<p>Kamala, you honor your mom’s memory every single day, but I believe she’s especially proud of you today.</p>



<p>Please welcome the Vice President of the United States, Kamala Harris.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 1:57 P.M. EST</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td class="has-text-align-left" data-align="left"></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Makes Fourteenth Judicial Nominations&#160;Announcement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/president-biden-makes-fourteenth-judicial-nominations-announcement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 20:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing a judicial nominee, who is extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. This choice continues to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing a judicial nominee, who is extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. This choice continues to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>Stephanie Dawkins Davis is the President’s nominee to the Sixth Circuit of the U.S. Court of Appeals.&nbsp; Judge Davis would be the first Black woman to serve on the Sixth Circuit from Michigan and only the second Black woman to serve on the Sixth Circuit.</p>



<p>This is President Biden’s fourteenth announcement of nominees for federal judicial positions, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 84.</p>



<p>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies.</p>



<p>CIRCUIT COURT<br><strong><u>Stephanie Dawkins Davis: Nominee for the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge Stephanie Dawkins Davis has served as a federal judge on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Michigan since December 2019. Judge Davis previously served as a Magistrate Judge for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Michigan from 2016 to 2019. From 1997 to 2016, Judge Davis served in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Michigan as Executive Assistant United States Attorney from 2010 to 2015 and as an Assistant United States Attorney from 1997 to 2010. During her tenure, she also served as Deputy Chief of the Controlled Substances Unit from 2007 to 2010. Judge Davis began her career as an associate at Dickinson, Wright PLLC in Detroit, Michigan, from 1992 to 1997. Judge Davis received her J.D. from Washington University School of Law in 1992 and her B.S. from Wichita State University in 1989.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on President&#160;Biden’s Plans to Reignite the Cancer&#160;Moonshot</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/02/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-president-bidens-plans-to-reignite-the-cancer-moonshot/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 17:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Via Teleconference 6:32 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MR. MUNOZ:&#160; Hey, everybody.&#160; Thank you for joining tonight’s call on how the President plans to reignite the Cancer Moonshot to end cancer as we know it.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; As a reminder, this call will be attributable to “senior administration officials” and be embargoed until tomorrow a.m. &#8212; at 5:00&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"> Via Teleconference</p>



<p>6:32 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Hey, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for joining tonight’s call on how the President plans to reignite the Cancer Moonshot to end cancer as we know it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As a reminder, this call will be attributable to “senior administration officials” and be embargoed until tomorrow a.m. &#8212; at 5:00 a.m.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Joining us on tonight’s call is [senior administration official].&nbsp; Also joining us is [senior administration official].&nbsp; We have some remarks at the top from both of them, and we’ll have time for questions at the end.&nbsp; And we ask that you keep questions relevant to the Cancer Moonshot.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with that, I will turn it to [senior administration official].<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Welcome, everybody.&nbsp; I’m [redacted].&nbsp; I’m joined by [senior administration official, who [redacted].&nbsp; [Redacted] and will have lots to say, and we’ll both speak back and forth on the effort.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, today, we’re going to preview this announcement that the President will be making tomorrow.&nbsp; You’ve got the factsheet.&nbsp; And just to confirm, we’ll be speaking on background, and the news is under embargo until 5:00 a.m. Eastern tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;So, just to set the stage, you will all recall that as Vice President, in 2016, Joe Biden led the Cancer Moonshot with the mission of accelerating the rate of progress against cancer.&nbsp;&nbsp;And the cancer community and the patient community and medical researchers responded with tremendous energy and ingenuity.&nbsp;&nbsp;And there’s been a lot of progress that has come since then.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;And because of that and because of the amazing possibilities ahead, tomorrow, in remarks here at the White House, President Biden is going to reignite the Cancer Moonshot.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;So, [senior administration official]?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;&nbsp;Yeah, I’ll give a little bit of a preview of what the event will look like.&nbsp;&nbsp;It will take place in the East Room of the White House.&nbsp;&nbsp;The First Lady and the Vice President will also give remarks.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we will lay out, as [senior administration official] said, the President’s plan, this administration’s plan around the Cancer Moonshot.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In attendance in the room will be about 100 members of the cancer community, from patients and survivors, their caregivers and families, advocacy organizations, research organizations and individual researchers, and those from the healthcare community, representatives from industry, members of Congress, members of the Cabinet, and beyond.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we’ll have a big event, really setting the stage for this announcement.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, why is the President reigniting the Cancer Moonshot?&nbsp; Well, because a lot has changed that makes it possible to set really ambitious goals right now.<br><br>The Cancer Moonshot was launched five years ago, and lots has happened.&nbsp; In addition, I have to say that the scientific advances that we saw from the COVID-19 pandemic, from the response to it, also points to things that are possible today.<br><br>So, for all those reasons, the President is going to set some very ambitious goals: Number one, to reduce the death rate from cancer by at least 50 percent over the next 25 years &#8212; I’ll put that in context in a moment of what that means &#8212; and to really substantially improve the experience of people and their families living and surviving with cancer.&nbsp; And by doing these things and more &#8212; two, as the President likes to say and will say: to end cancer as we know it today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now, the President and the First Lady are also going to announce, very importantly, a call to action on cancer screening to jumpstart progress on screenings that were missed as a result of the pandemic, and help ensure that everybody equitably benefits from the tools that we already have to prevent and detect and diagnose cancer, which are extremely valuable and we need to get everybody to be able to take full advantage of those.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, let me &#8212; let me review, just very briefly, how we got here, what’s come before.&nbsp; And then I will turn it a little bit, after [senior administration official] leaves (inaudible), to what exactly we mean by “end cancer as we know it.”<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So &#8212; but let’s go back.&nbsp; You know, 50 years ago, the National Cancer Institu- &#8212; the National Cancer Act was passed.&nbsp; And, you know, for the first 25 years or so, you really didn’t see much change in the death rate from cancer &#8212; this age-adjusted death rate that gets measured.&nbsp; It was pretty flat for a long time.&nbsp; And then we began to see a decrease.<br><br>And over the last 20 or so years, the age-adjusted death rate from cancer has fallen by about 25 percent.&nbsp; And that is really remarkable.&nbsp; It had been flat, and now it fell by 25 percent, which means many more people are surviving cancer, living longer after being diagnosed with cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>And it wasn’t one thing; it was progress on multiple fronts.&nbsp; It includes:</p>



<ul><li>Treatments that target specific mutations; it used to be all the cancer drugs were just cellular poisons.&nbsp; But, specifically, targeted mutation drugs became developed about 20 or so years ago.</li><li>Therapies that use our immune system to detect and kill cancer cells; this was a new idea that really came into full force within the last 10 years or so.</li><li>Cancer vaccines, like the HPV vaccine, that go to the heart of protecting you against those cancers &#8212; at least seven of them &#8212; that are caused by a specific virus.</li><li>And then, new tools, like low-dose CT scans and more refined uses of&nbsp;colonoscopies, and pretty impressive progress against tobacco use through public health campaigns.</li></ul>



<p>All these things together led to this decrease and led to the point that we see even more on the horizon, and the President is prepared to set pretty exciting and ambitious goals.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And we want to kind of place tomorrow’s announcement in what the administration has already done.&nbsp; This is not the first time that the administration has policies or budgets were focused on cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>In the last year, the Biden-Harris Administration has maintained our commitment to ending cancer as we know it.&nbsp; For example, in the President’s first budget, he sustained strong funding for biomedical and health research with increased funding for the National Institutes of Health and the National Cancer Institute, and full funding for the 21st Century Cures Act, including the funding for cancer research at the NCI, named the Beau Biden Cancer Moonshot Initiative.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President also proposed a bold, new vision for biomedical and health research in the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health, or ARPA-H. &nbsp;Its goal is to improve the U.S. government’s capabilities to speed research that can improve human health, to improve our ability to prevent, detect, and treat a range of diseases including cancer, Alzheimer’s disease, and other.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;President Biden committed to a bilateral effort in the spring of last year with the United Kingdom to take on the challenges of cancer together.&nbsp;&nbsp;This has already resulted in a November 2021 U.S.-UK Cancer Scientific Meeting of leadership, patient advocates, and oncology research experts which produced recommendations for how the two nations can work together in partnership to make even more urgent progress on cancer.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;First Lady Jill Biden’s advocacy for cancer education and prevention began decades ago, in 1993, when four of her friends were diagnosed with breast cancer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Following that year, she launched the Biden Breast Health Initiative to educate Delaware high school girls about the importance of cancer prevention.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;As First Lady, she continues her work emphasizing early detection efforts and the patient, family, and caregiver experience with cancer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;She will also stress the importance of cancer screenings, especially those delayed or put off due to the COVID-19 pandemic, and will urge government partners, the business community, and non-profit sectors to help make screenings more accessible and available to all.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;So we just really wanted to reiterate the Biden-Harris administration has prioritized this from the beginning, in addition to prioritizing strengthening healthcare for the American people in a number of other ways, by lowering healthcare costs and expanding coverage.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;&nbsp;So, let me turn to what the President is going to lay out as goals and to what they mean.<br><br>So, President Biden tomorrow is going to set national goals for the Cancer Moonshot, as I said, by working together over the next 25 years to cut today’s age-adjusted death rate from cancer by at least 50 percent from where we are today, and to improve the experience of people and their families living with and surviving cancer.&nbsp;&nbsp;And again, taken together with these and other actions, it would drive us to ending cancer as we know it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, how do we know cancer?&nbsp;&nbsp;To explain what we mean by that, we have to ask, &#8220;How do we know cancer today?&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, I&#8217;m going to give you seven ways we know cancer today that we think we can make really substantial progress in changing pretty dramatically.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Number one, you know, we know cancer is a disease where we have too few effective ways to prevent it.&nbsp;&nbsp;There are some: Don&#8217;t smoke, for example.&nbsp;&nbsp;But we don&#8217;t have lots of effective ways right now to prevent cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Number two, this is a disease where we just usually diagnose it too late.&nbsp;&nbsp;Early diagnosis is so important.&nbsp;&nbsp;But way too often, we diagnose it too late.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Number three, it&#8217;s a disease where we know too little about why treatments work well for some patients and fail to work for other patients.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Number four, we still have too many cancer types for which we still lack good strategies for developing treatments.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Number five, we still have stark inequities in diagnosis, access to treatments and clinical trials, and inequities in patient outcomes based on race, on region, on resources.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Number six, a disease where we leave most patients and families to have to navigate the disease and its aftermath on their own.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And number seven, we know cancer today is a disease where we just don&#8217;t learn from most patients&#8217; experiences.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; These are seven concrete ways in which we know cancer today.&nbsp; And every one of them, there is a lot to do to change.&nbsp; Some of them are about science; there&#8217;s new scientific opportunities that are possible.&nbsp; Some of them are about policy.&nbsp; And some of them are just about being absolutely determined to work some of these problems until they get solved.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, let me elaborate on some of these seven ways which we cancer.&nbsp; I said we have few effective ways to prevent it.&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s everything from expanding screening for inherited cancer risk, figuring out who&#8217;s inherited a cancer gene.&nbsp; We do that in some cases, but it&#8217;s not really broadly done.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But at a scientific end, we can also take lessons from the mRNA vaccines that were developed against the COVID-19 &#8212; the virus that causes COVID-19 &#8212; by asking, &#8220;Can we make mRNA vaccines that teach your immune system to recognize the distinctive mutations that occur in cancer cells?&#8221;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of thinking right now that things like that could cause your body to be able to recognize and attack those early cancer cells before there&#8217;s even any tumor to see and could decrease the overall incidence.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We diagnose too late.&nbsp; What can you do about that?&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s a lot of &#8212; a lot of work going on right now about ideas like maybe an annual blood test to detect dozens of cancers simultaneously based on free-floating DNA in the blood.&nbsp; You know, ideas like that will take a lot of work.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to have to be clinically tested to prove that they really save lives and they&#8217;re going to have to be affordable enough to roll out to the American people.&nbsp; But there is real, concrete work to do that could lead to prevention, that can lead to early diagnosis,<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, stark inequities.&nbsp; We really have to target prevention and early detection to those who need it most and those who just can&#8217;t take advantage of it usually, for lots of reasons.&nbsp; There are all sorts of reasons that people can&#8217;t, say, participate in clinical trials if it means having to go to a major academic medical center.&nbsp; But, well, you even learned from the pandemic that clinical trials can happen out in community hospitals, and telehealth and local sample collection can make a big difference.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there are people who can&#8217;t take advantage of diagnosis and treatment because just the out-of-pocket costs can be a real barrier &#8212; just transportation, time off from work, childcare.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So taking on those inequities which affect &#8212; you know, which are associated with higher mortality rates in different populations &#8212; in the Black population for certain cancers, in rural populations for certain cancers.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, I said where we know too little about why they work in some patients and not others &#8212; there are ways now to figure out, if we really apply our tools, which treatments work for which patients, but we&#8217;ve got to collect that data and we&#8217;ve got to share those data.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Strategies for developing treatments against some kinds of cancers &#8212; the President is very committed to his proposal of an ARPA-H agency at the NIH to take on bold, transformative projects for hard problems like this.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mentioned patients and their families having to navigate cancer on their own.&nbsp; We need to consider navigation services &#8212; equitable navigation services, navigation services that meet the needs of patients &#8212; as really part of cancer care.&nbsp; They&#8217;re very important.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then last of all, failing to learn from most patients&#8217; experiences.&nbsp; I got to say &#8212; and I know this personally and the President knows it even better: Most patients want their experiences to be of value to future patients.&nbsp; Most &#8212; not every one of them &#8212; but most of them want to share that information, and we got to make sure patients have the right and the ability to contribute their information and data to help others if they choose to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I could go into details on that, and we will in the coming weeks, and we&#8217;re going to gather the community together to flesh this out far better than the ideas we&#8217;ve already put down.&nbsp; But we are convinced that under each of these seven headings, there is a lot that can be done.&nbsp; And by reigniting the Moonshot, it&#8217;s going to bring people together &#8212; patients, advocates, researchers, physicians, companies, and many, many others &#8212; to really make sure that we make each of these things no longer the barriers that they are today.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, [senior administration official], let&#8217;s talk about some of the actions that will take place.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; So, [senior administration official] just laid out some of the promise and opportunity in these areas that we&#8217;re defining under ending cancer as we know it.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re really talking about, from the administration side, is mobilizing the entire government behind this effort as a presidential priority.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Under the Biden-Harris administration, the Cancer Moonshot specifically will reestablish White House leadership with a focused White House Cancer Moonshot Coordinator in the Office of the President.&nbsp; This will demonstrate the President and First Lady&#8217;s personal commitment to making progress and to really leverage this whole-of-government approach and national response that the challenge of cancer demands.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We will form a Cancer Cabinet, which will be convened by the White House, bringing together departments and agencies across government to deliver &#8212; to address cancer on multiple fronts.&nbsp; This includes, for example, the Departments of Health and Human Services, Veterans Affairs, Defense, Energy, the Department of Agriculture, EPA, and many others, including the Office of the Vice President, Office of the First Lady, and Office of Science and Technology Policy, and Domestic Policy Council here at the White House.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President and First Lady will issue a call to action on cancer screening and early detection.&nbsp; As [senior administration official] touched on, we need to get back on track after more than nine and a half million missed cancer screenings in the United States as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With regular recommended screenings, we can often catch cancer when there may be even more effective treatment options or prevent it from developing by removing precancerous tissue.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To help ensure equitable access to screening and prevention, we will promote at-home screening where it&#8217;s possible, especially with tools for colon cancer and HPV, with mobile screening and communities without easy access to a clinic, through the community health networks that have been so important and have built and strengthened during the COVID-19 pandemic, and other ways to really bring screening and early detection to people where they are.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also as a part of this screening call to action, NCI will organize &#8212; the National Cancer Institute, NCI &#8212; will organize the collective efforts of their cancer centers and other networks, such as their Community Oncology Research Network, to offer new access points to compensate for these millions of delayed cancer screening and with a focus on reaching the individuals most at risk.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Federal agencies will develop a focused program &#8212; as [senior administration official] said, the promise in studying multi-cancer detection tests, and really understanding the promise for patients and in extending life there.&nbsp; We’ll develop a focused program to expeditiously study and evaluate multi-cancer detection tests, like we&#8217;ve done for COVID-19 diagnostics.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Department of Health and Human Services will accelerate efforts to nearly eliminate cervical cancer through cervical cancer screening and HPV vaccinations &#8212; again, with a particular focus on reaching those communities outside of the reach currently and most at risk.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s Cancer Panel, tomorrow, will release a report entitled “Closing Gaps in Cancer Screening,” laying out recommendations focused on connecting people, community, and systems to increase equity and access.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s on the call to action on cancer screening and early detection.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Additionally, among the specific commitments from this administration on the Cancer Moonshot, we will host a White House Cancer Moonshot Summit, bringing together agency leadership; patient organizations; biopharmaceutical companies; the research, public health, and healthcare communities; and others to highlight innovation and progress and new commitments towards ending cancer as we know it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We will build on an already existing White House Coun- &#8212; White House Cancer Roundtable Series that we&#8217;ve hosted over the last six months.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll expand the topics to the seven pillars that [senior administration official] outlined for us, and include additional communities and perspectives to make sure that this mission and this agenda is being built by those most impacted by this disease and with the most experience and knowledge to help us identify priorities.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, the President will call for an all-hands-on-deck approach, calling on the private sector, foundations, academic institutions, healthcare providers, and all Americans to take on the mission of reducing the deadly impact of cancer and improving patient experiences in the diagnosis, treatment, and survival of cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As I said, progress will be informed by people directly experiencing this disease &#8212; cancer patients, caregivers, and families &#8212; and contributed by all parts of the oncology community and beyond.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tomorrow, we&#8217;ll be launching a website where people can engage and interact with the Cancer Moonshot.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; So, I will wrap up so we can take questions.&nbsp; But let me just say: You&#8217;ve heard what the President is going to lay out tomorrow.&nbsp; You know that for the President and the First Lady, it&#8217;s very personal.&nbsp; Both will speak tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s also personal for the Vice President.&nbsp; The Vice President&#8217;s mother, as I&#8217;m sure many of you know, was a breast cancer researcher.&nbsp; She taught at public universities, worked at a national laboratory, published research papers, and collaborated with NIH and scientists around the world.&nbsp; And in 2008, after a lifetime of researching cancer, she was diagnosed with colon cancer and died of the disease the following year.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I could say it&#8217;s personal for me and it&#8217;s personal for [senior administration official] and, I don&#8217;t know, even on a call with 65 journalists, I&#8217;m going to say I bet it&#8217;s personal for the majority of you too &#8212; that all of us come to this less in our official jobs than as people whose lives have been touched by cancer.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s why the administration is lifting up cancer with such a bold goal.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we&#8217;re happy to take your questions now.&nbsp; And then I know we&#8217;re only to be able to take a handful of questions, but if you have specific questions after the President&#8217;s remarks tomorrow or want to request an interview, we&#8217;re happy to do that.&nbsp; But the way to do it would be to email us at Press@OSTP.EOP.Gov.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be glad to talk more about it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, with that, let&#8217;s turn back to the White House Communications staff to figure out how we&#8217;re going to take questions.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for doing this call.&nbsp; I have a couple of questions.&nbsp; First, when President Obama announced the Cancer Moonshot in 2016, his goal was to make a decade&#8217;s worth of advancements in five years.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering: Has that goal been achieved, and do you think the new goal is more ambitious?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then secondly, on money, Congress authorized $1.8 billion over seven years in 2016 and about $400 million is left.&nbsp; So, is there any new money over and above that behind this Cancer Moonshot?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much for those questions.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, look, I think the Cancer Moonshot that was launched in 2016 was tremendously successful.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen all sorts of new possibilities be created &#8212; those kinds of research advances.&nbsp; I would say it&#8217;s fair to say that we saw a decade&#8217;s worth of research advances occur in those past five years.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s precisely because of that that I think we can talk about setting goals like actually decreasing death rates from cancer over the next 25 years.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s clear now that all sorts of possibilities, like I was talking about &#8212; vaccines &#8212; prophylactic preventative vaccines against cancer &#8212; not something we could have thought of five years ago.&nbsp; And now, you can sit down and write out a plan for how you’d do it and how you might do a clinical trial to observe that you are really preventing.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not easy, but you can do that today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can &#8212; five years ago, it was not plausible to think about doing these annual blood tests that might screen for cancer.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of work that&#8217;s become possible; now we actually have to do it.&nbsp; We got to reduce this to practice and get it out there.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think the same is true for many of these other areas where we&#8217;ve gotten a really clear understanding of the need to share data and ways to do it that are effective.&nbsp; I think the issues around equity are really clear and urgent right now.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I think that did its work.&nbsp; And it would not have been possible, not have been plausible to have set out these kinds of goals of decreasing the death rate by 50 percent and taking on these specific categories before, and it is possible now.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, yeah.&nbsp; And I am very confident that there will be robust funding going forward because, I got to say, in these times of disagreements, there&#8217;s certainly one thing on which we all agree on across party, across everything, which is the effect of cancer on their lives.&nbsp; I know of nothing that unites us more and that is more bipartisan.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Sheryl, thank you so much for that really great question.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s try Josh one more time.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], the questions that Josh had are if there are any new funding commitments to be announced, and what the start date for the 50 percent reduction over 25 years is.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not going to have a funding commitment tomorrow.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to announce what the plan is, because it&#8217;s pretty important to bring together the Cancer Cabinet, bring together the community.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve laid out a set of ideas.&nbsp; I want to make sure that we have got everybody at the table contributing those ideas and a plan.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But so, that&#8217;s the answer there.&nbsp; But again, I am very confident there&#8217;s robust support for it.&nbsp; But I’m also very certain that we want to start this by listening and expanding the circle for ideas on these important seven pillars and more.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when does that start?&nbsp; It starts about now.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know &#8212; you know, I guess this year, let&#8217;s say, for the 25; we’ll start with 2022 and measure 25 years from now.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s probably precise enough.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t &#8212; it won&#8217;t get down to the day, but they measure this in years.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see where we are at the end of this year, and that&#8217;s a target for us to really decrease from.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I believe that&#8217;s possible.&nbsp; We cut it by 25 percent &#8212; research and patient-driven solutions and medicine cut it by 25 percent.&nbsp; I think this will make a huge difference if we can achieve this.&nbsp; And it is going to be a shared bipartisan effort over time.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And one thing to add, [senior administration official]: Setting the goal 25 years out doesn&#8217;t mean that we can&#8217;t start measuring our progress soon.&nbsp; So, taking the death rate by cancer down 50 percent in 25 years is going to take work now, and we&#8217;re going to start to see the results in that year-over-year decrease that we have to keep at the level it is now and even accelerate it.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s not pushing the measurement out; it&#8217;s just setting a really ambitious goal in the future that we can work really hard now towards making progress on.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a really &#8212; it&#8217;s a really great point.&nbsp; The curve is not going to be a cliff in the 24th year.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s be really clear: It&#8217;s going to be steady decline over this period &#8212; targeting that.&nbsp;<br><br>So, you know, we&#8217;re all going to be looking at that accountably and saying, &#8220;Are we making the quantitative progress to land there?&#8221;&nbsp; So, even though Josh has had trouble connecting, you know, verbally, I appreciate the question being delivered in absentia.&nbsp; So, thank you, Josh, for the great question.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks, Kevin.&nbsp; And thank you, [senior administration officials], for doing the call.&nbsp; So, President Obama and Vice President Biden &#8212; in 2015, they both used the word “cure” and the phrase “cure cancer” when they rolled out the original Cancer Moonshot.&nbsp; And then-candidate Biden, I think, was criticized for doing the same in 2019 and 2020.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve heard either of you use that word or that phrase in this call.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering whether it&#8217;s fair to read into that as kind of a &#8212; you know, taking a more measured approach using existing interventions and technologies as opposed to making pledges, promises about really remarkable scientific progress that we all hope for but is hard to guarantee.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, no, I wouldn&#8217;t read that into it, because I think the words “cure cancer” needs to be understood in the following way: When they talked then about curing cancer, they recognized that the way we decreased the death rate in cancer is we have to start curing cancers for some patients.&nbsp; We have immunotherapies right now that it&#8217;s fair to say are cures; we do not have a recurrence in 5 years, in 10 years.&nbsp; You know, you never want to use the word “cure,” but those are cures.&nbsp;<br><br>We are going to bite off piece by piece &#8212; I don&#8217;t think they said, “We&#8217;re going to cure all cancer all at once.”&nbsp; But you cure cancer by curing them one at a time, a patient at the time, a hundred patients at a time.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think the idea of &#8212; and we&#8217;re not using the words “cure cancer” because it could be misunderstood by some people as just “get a cure for cancer.”&nbsp; But, Lev, as you know, there&#8217;s 200 types of cancer we need to get therapies for and therapies that extend life long enough to turn into cures for.&nbsp; But we’ve focused on this very measurable thing of decreasing that death rate 50 percent.&nbsp;<br><br>But, no, I would not think that he&#8217;s walking back the words; I think we&#8217;re speaking with a precision.&nbsp; But along that way, the 50 percent is going to be a lot of cures along the way.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, anyway, that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s it.&nbsp; No walking back, but using words carefully and precisely so that we can hold ourselves accountable.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And I think, as you heard [senior administration official] detail how we got to where we are, some of the big things &#8212; some of the big advancements that delivered a change in the death rate by cancer weren&#8217;t on the treatment side; they were on the prevention side, on the early detection side.&nbsp; So, by opening up the frame and talking about “ending cancer as we know it,” it gives us the leverage and the place to really make progress in those areas.&nbsp;<br><br>Because I know having a treatment for cancer &#8212; I was dia- &#8212; if I was diagnosed with cancer, I&#8217;d want to know there was a treatment.&nbsp; But even better is not ending up being diagnosed with that cancer in the first place.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; If we end up with vaccines that can help prevent cancers from ever occurring in the first place &#8212; I guess [senior administration official] is right, that&#8217;s not curing anything, but, boy, it would have a huge impact.&nbsp; So, I think we&#8217;re just trying to use words carefully because we want to be open to the whole portfolio of approaches.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s a great question, Lev.&nbsp; I appreciate your clarifying that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; You had mentioned ARPA-H and I think had said “in NIH.”&nbsp; Is that decided that that&#8217;s where that agency would be &#8212; inside the NIH instead of its own independent agency?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, when the President first described ARPA-H in the spring as part of &#8212; well, I mean, he’s described it in speeches.&nbsp; But in the speeches and in the budget, he has requested that and proposed that to be a new kind of division within the NIH &#8212; something independent and autonomous, something that has different authorities and different cultures and things like that, but connected to and part of the broader NIH community there.&nbsp;<br><br>So, yes, that&#8217;s how the President has proposed it for sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks.&nbsp; Thank you, Rachel, for the question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], for the new goals you just announced, do you expect the Cancer Cabinet &#8212; to charge it with the agenda?&nbsp; Or will NCI continue to provide central leadership for these efforts &#8212; for the Moonshot &#8212; as the institute has been since 2016?&nbsp; And if so, are there efforts in the works to request funds to support these goals?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, the answer is both.&nbsp; Some of these things, squarely are in the remit of the NCI, but there’ll be other things.&nbsp; Some of the things that need to be done, other agencies have a critical role in.&nbsp; If we&#8217;re going to be deploying &#8212; oh, let&#8217;s say, vaccines that can prevent cervical cancer, and head and neck cancer, these HPV vaccines, that&#8217;s going to be other agencies that will be playing that &#8212; the CDC, for example.&nbsp;<br><br>Some of these questions about, “How do we make sure everybody has access to clinical trials and they can be reimbursed for their out-of-pocket costs and other things?”&nbsp; That might involve CMS.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think NCI could not be more central.&nbsp; But the idea that this is just limited to cancer research, rather than all of the agencies &#8212; and not just the agencies in HHS.&nbsp; I think VA, DOD, DOE all have contributions to make.&nbsp;<br><br>So, there will obviously be huge work at NCI, but we&#8217;re pulling together a Cancer Cabinet to make sure that we get the benefit of all the levers that might be pulled.<br><br>[Senior administration official], do you want to?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s important to emphasize that [senior administration official] had just added VA and DOD.&nbsp; And not only do they have important research programs and research goals, but they also run health systems.&nbsp; And so, they&#8217;re very much a part of the work here, as they were in 2016.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I mean, the VA has health information systems that we&#8217;ve learned tremendous amounts from.&nbsp; There are medical records from which you can learn a tremendous amount.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll just note, I saw a study on multiple sclerosis.&nbsp; It just underscores that we can learn a lot in a lot of places, and we want no stone unturned in this effort.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, Matt, for the question.&nbsp; Really good question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys, thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; Can you guys go into a little more detail about how you see the First Lady&#8217;s role?&nbsp; Obviously, for the vaccine efforts, she&#8217;s traveled around the country.&nbsp; Do you see her doing that, sort of, same kind of work?&nbsp; And will she be, sort of, the face of a piece of this initiative?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, the First Lady has &#8212; is very much a part of this.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a part of the event tomorrow.&nbsp; And as you mentioned, she has been out there with public health messages since the start of the administration.&nbsp; She has spent some time in the last year doing work specifically on cancer, especially around cancer screening and early detection.&nbsp; And we expect &#8212; not only in that area, but we expect her to have some leadership role there with more to come. &nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I think she is excited and committed to this, and brings a tremendous amount to it.&nbsp;<br><br>So, Nikki, thank you for that question.&nbsp;<br><br>And I know we&#8217;ve run out of time for questions, but I&#8217;m really grateful for everybody who&#8217;s here tonight.&nbsp; I&#8217;m excited about it.&nbsp; And we will be able to follow up with you at Press@OSTP.EOP.Gov after the President&#8217;s speech, because, you know, this embargo lifts at 5:00; the President will speak tomorrow.&nbsp; And afterwards, I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;ll be lots of great opportunities for follow up.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you for coming.&nbsp; Thank you for caring about this.&nbsp;<br><br>7:12 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration’s Commitment to Global&#160;Health</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-commitment-to-global-health/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 13:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46373</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States Government is proud to be the largest donor for global health. As we work to end the COVID-19 pandemic, we remain committed to strengthening health systems and institutions; advancing global health security; combatting HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis; advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights, and maternal, neonatal, and child health; closing gaps&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States Government is proud to be the largest donor for global health. As we work to end the COVID-19 pandemic, we remain committed to strengthening health systems and institutions; advancing global health security; combatting HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis; advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights, and maternal, neonatal, and child health; closing gaps in nutrition and non-communicable diseases; and accelerating efforts towards universal health coverage and the Sustainable Development Agenda. In Fiscal Year (FY) 2021, the United States appropriated over $9 billion in global health programs, in addition to almost $16 billion in emergency supplemental funding for COVID-19.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We continue to lead the global community toward a safer, more equitable future. Over the last year, the Biden-Harris Administration has renewed the U.S. leadership in global health, and taken decisive steps to advance global health priorities, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting and strengthening the WHO.</strong> Among his first acts in office one year ago, President Biden declared the United States would reengage with the World Health Organization (WHO), highlighting our nation’s commitment to advancing multilateral cooperation in a time of international health crisis. Last week, the United States once again demonstrated that commitment, by leading a successful decision at the WHO Executive Board meeting to strengthen the International Health Regulations (2005). This strengthening will enhance the world’s ability to prevent, detect, and rapidly respond to infectious disease outbreaks in the future. Beyond COVID-19, the United States is collaborating with global partners through WHO on a wide range of global health challenges such as childhood immunization, nutrition, polio eradication, strengthening the global health workforce to achieve universal health coverage, and tackling the threat that climate change poses to health. These and other issues remain critical priorities, especially in the wake of COVID-19, and demonstrate the importance of strong, equitable health systems that serve those most at risk.<br></li><li><strong>Leading the global COVID-19 response. </strong>Under President Biden’s leadership, the United States has committed to donate 1.2 billion doses of safe and effective vaccine to the world, more than any other nation. To date, we have shipped over 400 million of those vaccines to 112 countries around the world, all for free, with no strings attached or promises extracted. We were the first nation to purchase doses solely for the purpose of donation, with the historic purchase of 1 billion doses of Pfizer vaccine. We were the first nation to step out of the queue for Moderna vaccines, allowing the African Union quicker access to tens of millions of doses. We were the first to broker access to doses for individuals in humanitarian crises. And now, we are leading the push to turn vaccines into vaccinations, with the creation of the Global Vaccine Initiative. To date, the United States is providing nearly $16 billion for life-saving health, economic, and humanitarian COVID-19 assistance to our partners to fight this virus and its impacts. These funds are delivering shots in arms, lifesaving supplies to hospitals, and support that reaches the most vulnerable communities.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights. </strong>One of President Biden’s first actions was issuing a Presidential Memorandum on Protecting Women’s Health at Home and Abroad, which revoked the expanded Mexico City Policy and directed agencies to resume funding to the United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) in support of its essential work to prevent maternal deaths, expand access to voluntary family planning, and prevent and respond to gender-based violence around the world. The Administration continues to advance sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR) for all in the face of continued threats. The White House Gender Policy Council released the first-ever <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/National-Strategy-on-Gender-Equity-and-Equality.pdf">National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality</a>, which emphasizes the core role of advancing SRHR to achieve gender equality. As the largest bilateral donor to family planning, the United States also leads globally by advancing SRHR in multilateral fora and with bilateral partners. As we address the indirect impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic on health systems and vulnerable populations, the United States has supported increased access to SRHR services, particularly in emergency contexts.<br></li><li><strong>Continued global leadership on addressing HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis.</strong> Last week, the U.S. President&#8217;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) celebrated its nineteen-year anniversary. Since its inception and with bilateral support, the U.S. Government has invested $100 billion to transform the global AIDS response. PEPFAR has saved more than 21 million lives, prevented millions of HIV infections, and helped countries build a strong foundation to prevent, detect, and respond to other health threats, including COVID-19. Across 55 countries, PEPFAR invests over $1 billion annually in local health systems strengthening to respond to HIV. At the end of FY21, PEPFAR supported 63.4 million people with HIV testing services, and 18.96 million people with antiretroviral treatment. With $250 million in funding through the American Rescue Plan Act, PEPFAR has continued to advance HIV gains and supported the global COVID-19 response. The U.S. President’s Malaria Initiative invested $770 million in 2020 to forge forward in the fight against malaria, despite the COVID-19 pandemic, reaching almost 60 million people with malaria medicine and protecting more than 7.5 million pregnant women with preventive treatment for malaria. Through the most recent five-year U.S. Government Global TB Strategy, U.S. government investments led to the treatment of 15.7 million people with TB, starting 438,000 individuals with drug resistant TB on second-line drug therapy, and accomplished a treatment success rate of almost 90 percent.<br></li><li><strong>Building health security capacities.</strong> The United States continues to work with partners across the globe, including 19 intensive support partner countries, to provide assistance to better prevent, detect, and respond to infectious disease threats and to meet the target of the multilateral Global Health Security Agenda. The need for these capacities has never been more clear, and robust interagency efforts helped address numerous outbreaks including Ebola, Anthrax, Influenza, Rabies, Polio, Cholera, and more. The U.S. Government’s global health security programs also pivoted to support critical COVID-19 response activities.<br></li><li><strong>Sustaining commitments in maternal and child health. </strong>The United States’ sustained commitment, financial investment, and adaptability has ensured that critical health services continue reaching women, children, and families. In 2020, the United States helped more than 92 million women and children access essential—and often lifesaving—care. The U.S. Government’s investments towards polio eradication have also helped ensure over 400 million children are vaccinated against polio each year; last year was a significant milestone as Africa was declared wild polio free.</li></ul>



<p>In the coming year, the Administration will take the following steps to continue to advance global health priorities:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Continue supporting and strengthening the World Health Organization</strong>. The United States looks forward to rejoining the WHO Executive Board in May 2022, and will launch a Strategic Dialogue with WHO to ensure our mutual priorities are fully aligned. The United States will continue to work closely with WHO and partners around the world, to ensure that the prevention of sexual exploitation and abuse, and support for victims and survivors, remain priority issues.<br></li><li><strong>Accelerate global COVID-19 response efforts. </strong>The U.S. Government will continue to roll out the Initiative for Global Vaccine Access (Global VAX) to accelerate global efforts to get COVID-19 shots into arms and enhance international coordination. This whole of government effort will bolster cold chain supply and logistics, service delivery, vaccine confidence and demand, human resources, data and analytics, local planning, and vaccine safety and effectiveness. The United States has committed more than $1.6 billion in funding to help get shots into arms around the world.<br></li><li><strong>Advance health security and pandemic preparedness. </strong>The United States will continue to advance health security and pandemic preparedness abroad, including through strengthening WHO, working with partners towards targeted IHR amendments and a new pandemic instrument, building country capacities towards the Global Health Security Agenda target, strengthening sustained financing including establishing a new financial intermediary fund at the World Bank, building back better biosafety and biosecurity norms and mitigating biotechnological risks, innovating our science and technological capabilities to shorten the cycle for development of safe, effect, and affordable vaccines, therapeutics, and diagnostics, and more.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Continue investments to strengthen health systems.</strong> The United States will continue to advance the newly launched <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/global-health/health-systems-innovation/health-systems/Vision-HSS-2030">Vision for Health System Strengthening</a> and will work to align global partners toward shared commitments for the health workforce. The United States has committed to supporting and protecting health workers, and affirmed support for WHO’s Gender Equal Health and Care Workforce Initiative, which aim to address gender inequities and inequalities health workers face globally. The United States will continue to invest resources and provide assistance to strengthen countries’ disease surveillance and laboratory detection capacities, continue to lead efforts to eradicate polio, and also strengthen immunization systems and vaccine delivery to ensure a world where people live healthier, safer lives.<br></li><li><strong>Continue championing and expanding sexual and reproductive health and rights. </strong>In addition to maintaining strong financial support, the United States will continue to collaborate with allies and partners through multilateral, bilateral and civil society partnerships to expand progress and leadership to advance sexual and reproductive health and rights. Federal agencies are developing SRHR implementation plans and the National Security Council will continue to elevate and expand SRHR as a core component of our global health policy.<br></li><li><strong>Continue the fight against HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis.</strong> This year, President Biden will host the Global Fund’s Seventh Replenishment Conference, advancing global efforts to address HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis, alongside the U.S. government’s programs.&nbsp; PEPFAR is saving lives and curbing new HIV infections while supporting the health systems infrastructure in countries that continue to serve as a backbone of the COVID-19 response. PEPFAR’s assets can be further leveraged to support the COVID-19 response, while protecting and expanding HIV services and serving the most vulnerable populations around the world. PMI is reshaping its fight against malaria, focusing on reaching the unreached, further building community health systems, and increasing the impact of community health workers as part of its new “<a href="https://www.pmi.gov/home/pmis-strategy/">End Malaria Faster</a>” Strategy. Current investments are building countries’ capacities to respond to both tuberculosis and COVID-19 with support for bi-directional testing approaches for both diseases, joint contact investigations and community screenings, stigma reduction and community empowerment, and expanding infection prevention and control measures—providing vital platforms to address both diseases and respond to future airborne pandemics.<br></li><li><strong>Continue demonstrating strong global leadership on nutrition.</strong> At the 2021 Tokyo Nutrition for Growth Summit, the United States announced a financial commitment of up to $11 billion over three years to combat global malnutrition. The United States also launched the <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/global-health/health-areas/nutrition/usgplan">Global Nutrition Coordination Plan</a>, which will guide the collaborative work of seven U.S. government agencies engaged in scaling up proven approaches to better nutrition.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: President&#160;Biden Reignites Cancer Moonshot to End Cancer as We Know&#160;It</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/fact-sheet-president-biden-reignites-cancer-moonshot-to-end-cancer-as-we-know-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46329</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration Sets Goal of Reducing Cancer Death Rate by at least 50 Percent Over the Next 25 Years, and Improving the Experience of Living with and Surviving Cancer As Vice President, in 2016, Joe Biden launched the Cancer Moonshot with the mission to accelerate the rate of progress against cancer. The cancer and patient&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration Sets Goal of Reducing Cancer Death Rate by at least 50 Percent Over the Next 25 Years, and Improving the Experience of Living with and Surviving Cancer</em></p>



<p>As Vice President, in 2016, Joe Biden launched the Cancer Moonshot with the mission to accelerate the rate of progress against cancer. The cancer and patient community and medical researchers responded with tremendous energy and ingenuity.</p>



<p>Today, President Biden is <strong>reigniting the Cancer Moonshot with renewed White House leadership of this effort</strong>. Because of recent progress in cancer therapeutics, diagnostics, and patient-driven care, as well as the scientific advances and public health lessons of the COVID-19 pandemic, it’s now possible to set ambitious goals: to <strong>reduce the death rate from cancer by at least 50 percent over the next 25 years, </strong>and <strong>improve the experience of people and their families living with and surviving cancer</strong>—&nbsp;and, by doing this and more<strong>, end cancer as we know it today.<br></strong><br>The President and First Lady Jill Biden are also announcing a <strong>call to action on cancer screening </strong>to jumpstart progress on screenings that were missed as a result of the pandemic, and help ensure that everyone in the United States equitably benefits from the tools we have to prevent, detect, and diagnose cancer.<br><br><strong>Building on a Quarter Century of Bipartisan Support, Public Health Progress, and Scientific Advances</strong><br>Over the first 20 years of this century, the age-adjusted death rate from cancer has fallen by about 25 percent, which means more people are surviving cancer and living longer after being diagnosed with cancer. That was enabled by progress on multiple fronts.</p>



<ul><li>Science brought us <strong>treatments that target specific mutations</strong> in many types of cancer –for example, in certain types of lung cancer, leukemia, and skin cancers.</li><li>It has also provided therapies that use our immune system to detect and kill cancer cells and these <strong>immunotherapies</strong> are making a big difference in certain skin cancers, blood cancers, and others.</li><li>We also have <strong>cancer vaccines</strong> – like the HPV vaccine –which prevents the cause of up to seven kinds of cancer.&nbsp;</li><li>We developed <strong>tools, like low-dose CT scans and refined use of colonoscopies</strong>, which help us detect lung cancer and colorectal cancers early when there are better treatment options.</li><li>Starting in the early 1990s, we also made progress against tobacco use through targeted public health education campaigns as well as <strong>new, more effective approaches to smoking cessation</strong>. We have seen a 50 percent decrease in adult long-term cigarette smoking and a 68 percent drop in smoking rates among youth.</li></ul>



<p>Five years ago, with the bipartisan passage and enactment of the <strong>21st Century Cures Act, Congress invested $1.8 billion</strong>, providing seven years of new funding for cancer research in many areas including studies on cancer disparities, new clinical trial networks to drive drug discovery, and innovative projects examining childhood cancer. The law streamlined cancer-related decision-making at the FDA through the formation of an Oncology Center of Excellence, so that effective treatments can be approved faster and patients can have more direct access to information about the regulatory process.</p>



<p>First Lady Jill Biden’s advocacy for cancer education and prevention began in 1993, when four of her friends were diagnosed with breast cancer. Following that year, she launched the Biden Breast Health Initiative to educate Delaware high school girls about the importance of cancer prevention.&nbsp; As First Lady she continues her work emphasizing early detection efforts and the patient, family and caregiver experience with cancer. &nbsp; She will also stress the importance of cancer screenings, especially those delayed or put off due to the COVID-19 pandemic, and will urge government partners, the business community, and non-profit sectors to help make screenings more accessible and available to all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the White House, then-Vice President Biden brought together a task force and challenged the public and private sectors to join together in making progress. Companies, patient groups, universities, and foundations worked together to forge new partnerships and launch new programs.</p>



<p><strong>The Biden-Harris Administration Has Maintained This Commitment</strong><br>In the President’s first budget, he sustained strong funding for biomedical and health research with <strong>increased funding for the NIH </strong>and <strong>NCI, </strong>and full funding for the<strong> 21st Century Cures Act </strong>and the<strong> Beau Biden Cancer Moonshot Initiative</strong> at the NCI<strong>.<br></strong><br>President Biden proposed a bold new vision for biomedical and health research in the <strong>Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health (ARPA-H).</strong> The goal of this entity is to improve the U.S. government’s capabilities to speed research that can improve human health — to improve our ability to prevent, detect, and treat a range of diseases including cancer, infectious diseases, Alzheimer’s disease, and many others. ARPA-H funding has already been included in appropriation and authorization bills pending in Congress.</p>



<p>President Biden committed to<strong> a bilateral effort with the United Kingdom </strong>to take on the challenges of cancer together. This has already resulted in a November 2021 US-UK Cancer Scientific Meeting of leadership, patient advocates, and oncology research experts which produced recommendations for how the two nations can work in partnership to make even more urgent progress on cancer.</p>



<p><strong>The Biden-Harris Administration has also prioritized strengthening health care for the American people</strong> by lowering health care costs and expanding coverage. The President’s health care agenda is the biggest expansion of affordable health care in a decade, and includes cutting prescription drug costs by letting Medicare negotiate prices; strengthening the Affordable Care Act and reducing premiums for 9 million Americans; improving Medicare benefits by capping out-of-pocket costs on drugs, including cancer drugs, purchased at a pharmacy; and covering millions of uninsured Americans in states that have failed to expand Medicaid.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>New Goals for the Cancer Moonshot</strong><br>Based on the progress made and the possibility before us, President Biden today set new national goals for the Cancer Moonshot:</p>



<ul><li>Working together over the next 25 years, <strong>we will cut today’s age-adjusted death rate from cancer by at least 50 percent.</strong></li><li>We will <strong>improve the experience of people and their families living with and surviving cancer.</strong></li></ul>



<p>Taken together, these actions will drive us toward <strong>ending cancer as we know it today.</strong></p>



<p>There’s so much that can be done.</p>



<ul><li><strong>To diagnose cancer sooner</strong> — Today, we know cancer as a disease we often diagnose too late. We must increase access to existing ways to screen for cancer, and support patients through the process of diagnosis. We can also greatly expand the cancers we can screen for. Five years ago, detecting many cancers at once through blood tests was a dream. Now new technologies and rigorous clinical trials could put this within our reach. Detecting and diagnosing cancers earlier means there may be more effective treatment options. <br></li><li><strong>To prevent cancer</strong> — Today, we know cancer as a disease we have few good ways to prevent. But now, scientists are asking if mRNA technology, used in the safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines to teach your body to fight off the virus, could be used to stop cancer cells when they first appear. And we know we can address environmental exposures to cancer, including by cleaning up polluted sites and delivering clean water to American homes, for example, through the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/16/the-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-advances-environmental-justice/">Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</a>.<br></li><li><strong>To address inequities </strong>— Today, we know cancer as a disease for which there are stark inequities in access to cancer screening, diagnostics and treatment across race, gender, region, and resources. We can ensure that every community in America – rural, urban, Tribal, and everywhere else – has access to cutting-edge cancer diagnostics, therapeutics, and clinical trials.<br></li><li><strong>To target the right treatments to the right patients</strong> — Today, we know cancer as a disease for which we understand too little about why treatments work for some patients, but not for others. We are learning more about how to use information about genetics, immune responses, and other factors to tell which combinations of treatments are likely to work best in an individual patient.<br></li><li><strong>To speed progress against the most deadly and rare cancers, including childhood cancers</strong> — Today, we know cancer as a disease for which we lack good strategies for developing treatments against many of the more than 200 distinct types. We can invest in a robust pipeline for new treatments, and the COVID-19 pandemic response has demonstrated we can accelerate clinical trials without compromising safety and effectiveness. <br></li><li><strong>To support patients, caregivers, and survivors</strong> — Today, we know cancer as a disease in which we do not do enough to help people and families navigate cancer and its aftermath. We can help people overcome the medical, financial, and emotional burdens that cancer brings by providing support to navigate cancer diagnosis, treatment, and survivorship.<br></li><li><strong>To learn from all patients </strong>— Today, we know cancer as a disease in which we don’t learn from the experiences of most patients. We can turn our cancer care system into a learning system. When asked, most people with cancer are glad to make their data available for research to help future patients, if it can be done easily while respecting their privacy. Additionally, the diverse personal experiences of patients and their families make their input essential in developing approaches to end cancer as we know it.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Mobilizing the Entire Government</strong><br>Under the Biden-Harris Administration, the Cancer Moonshot will specifically:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Re-establish White House Leadership</strong>, with a White House Cancer Moonshot coordinator in the Executive Office of the President, to demonstrate the President and First Lady’s personal commitment to making progress and to leverage the whole-of-government approach and national response that the challenge of cancer demands.<br></li><li><strong>Form a Cancer Cabinet</strong>, which will be convened by the White House, bringing together departments and agencies across government to address cancer on multiple fronts. These include the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), Department of Defense (DOD), Department of Energy (DOE), Department of Agriculture (USDA), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), National Institutes of Health (NIH), National Cancer Institute (NCI), Food and Drug Administration (FDA), Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), Domestic Policy Council (DPC), Gender Policy Council (GPC), Office of the First Lady (OFL), Office of the Vice President (OVP), Office of Management and Budget (OMB), Office of Legislative Affairs (OLA), Office of Public Engagement (OPE), along with additional members, as needed, to help establish and make progress on Cancer Moonshot goals. <br></li><li><strong>Issue a Call to Action on Cancer Screening and Early Detection</strong>:<ul><li>To deliver the message of urgency and increased access to <strong>get back on track after more than 9.5 million missed cancer screenings in the United States as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic</strong>. With regular recommended screenings, we can often catch cancer when there may be more effective treatment options or even prevent it from developing by removing pre-cancerous tissue.</li><li>To help ensure equitable access to screening and prevention through <strong>at-home screening</strong> (especially for colon cancer and HPV, the virus that causes cervical, head, neck and other cancers), <strong>mobile screening</strong> in communities without easy access to a clinic, through the <strong>community health networks</strong> we have built and strengthened during the COVID-19 pandemic, and other ways to reduce barriers to cancer screening.</li><li>NCI will organize the collective efforts of the NCI cancer centers, and other networks such as the NCI Community Oncology Research Network (NCORP), to <strong>offer new access points to compensate for millions of delayed cancer screenings </strong>due to the pandemic, with a focus on reaching those individuals most at risk.</li><li>Federal agencies, led by the NCI, will develop a focused program to expeditiously<strong> study and evaluate multicancer detection tests</strong>, like we did for COVID-19 diagnostics, which could help detect cancers when there may be more effective treatment options.</li><li>The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) commits to<strong> accelerating efforts to nearly eliminate cervical cancer through screening and HPV vaccination</strong>, with a particular focus on reaching people who are most at risk.</li><li>The <strong>President’s Cancer panel this week released a report <a>“</a></strong><a href="https://prescancerpanel.cancer.gov/report/cancerscreening"><strong>Closing Gaps in Cancer Screening</strong></a><strong>”</strong> laying out recommendations focused on connecting people, communities, and systems to increase equity and access.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Host a White House Cancer Moonshot Summit</strong>, bringing together agency leadership, patient organizations, biopharmaceutical companies, the research, public health, and healthcare communities and more to highlight innovation, progress, and new commitments toward ending cancer as we know it. <br></li><li><strong>Build on a White House Cancer Roundtable Conversation Series</strong> hosted over the last six months, with experts, including people living with cancer, caregivers, and survivors. These discussions focused on cancer prevention, early detection, clinical trial design and access, patient support and navigation, childhood cancer, learning from all patients and issues relating to equity in access and outcomes. Going forward, this will include discussions on additional topics and the knowledge gained will continue to inform this whole-of-government approach on cancer.<br></li><li><strong>Require an All-Hands-On-Deck Approach. President Biden calls on the private sector, foundations, academic institutions, healthcare providers, and all Americans</strong> to take on the mission of reducing the deadly impact of cancer and improving patient experiences in the diagnosis, treatment, and survival of cancer. Progress will be informed by people living with cancer, caregivers, and families and contributed by all parts of the oncology community and beyond. We invite all Americans to share perspectives and ideas, and organizations, companies, and institutions to share actions they plan to take as part of this mission at <a><strong>whitehouse.gov/cancermoonshot</strong></a>.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of&#160;Turkey</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/01/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-ibrahim-kalin-spokesperson-and-chief-advisor-to-the-president-of-turkey-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 02:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Dr. Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of Turkey. They underscored their shared commitment to both ongoing diplomacy and joint efforts to deter further Russian aggression against Ukraine. They also discussed regional issues, including efforts by Turkey and Armenia to normalize relations. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Dr. Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of Turkey. They underscored their shared commitment to both ongoing diplomacy and joint efforts to deter further Russian aggression against Ukraine. They also discussed regional issues, including efforts by Turkey and Armenia to normalize relations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden and First Lady Jill&#160;Biden on Lunar New&#160;Year</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/01/statement-by-president-joe-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-on-lunar-new-year/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 01:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We send our warmest greetings to everyone celebrating the Lunar New Year. Across our country and around the world, families and friends are gathering together in person and in spirit to celebrate the possibility and hope of new beginnings. As we enter this Year of the Tiger — representing strength and courage — let us&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We send our warmest greetings to everyone celebrating the Lunar New Year.</p>



<p>Across our country and around the world, families and friends are gathering together in person and in spirit to celebrate the possibility and hope of new beginnings.</p>



<p>As we enter this Year of the Tiger — representing strength and courage — let us continue doing the work of our time to beat this pandemic, rebuild our economy, and protect our very democracy, which includes standing up to the hate that continues to target Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders.</p>



<p>Every person — no matter their race, background, religion, or language – is created equal and deserves to be treated equally throughout their lives. That is the very idea of America and the heart of our Administration.</p>



<p>Each day, all of our communities are enriched by the diversity and talents of the people of this nation — from frontline workers and military families to business leaders and community activists to artists, entertainers, writers, and public servants.</p>



<p>Together, you show what it means to be the hope and light for better days ahead. From our family to yours, we wish you peace, prosperity, health, and a happy Lunar New Year.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 1,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/01/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-1-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:27 P.M. EST MS. PSAKI:&#160; All right. &#160;Kristen, welcome back. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Thank you, Jen.&#160; I appreciate it. MS. PSAKI:&#160; Okay.&#160; We missed you. A couple of items for you all at the top.&#160; I know there was some good questions yesterday about the status of the infrastructure law implementation,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:27 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right. &nbsp;Kristen, welcome back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I appreciate it.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We missed you.</p>



<p>A couple of items for you all at the top.&nbsp; I know there was some good questions yesterday about the status of the infrastructure law implementation, so I just wanted to bring you a few updates that are hopefully helpful to all of you.</p>



<p>In the 79 days since the bill &#8212; the law was signed, our team has hit the ground running to get money out the door, engage partners, and provide comprehensive resources to help municipalities unlock funding opportunities so no community is left behind.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To date, over $80 billion has already been allocated and is headed out to states, territories, and local governments.&nbsp; That includes over $50 billion to states for highways and roads; $14 billion for 500 Army Corps projects; over $5 billion for &#8212; to states for bridges; over $7 billion to states for water infrastructure; $3 billion to repair and rebuild over 3,000 airports; $1 billion to support Superfund cleanup to 49 sites; and $239 million in Port Infrastructure Development Grants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is just the beginning, and we&#8217;ll do our best to provide you all updates in here on the status of these funds being allocated.&nbsp; State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments will receive over 90 percent of funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to rebuild their communities.</p>



<p>We mentioned yesterday &#8212; or I talked a little bit yesterday about this large guidebook we had put out to provide guidance and information to communities to apply for the part of this that will be through competitive awards.</p>



<p>As we did with the American Rescue Plan, we also know that local leaders have the best sense of where the communities need funding.&nbsp; And the formula funds in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law include flexibility to deal with unique local and state challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we&#8217;ve also said many times, with flexibility comes great responsibility to use funds wisely.&nbsp; So, to ensure accountability and transparency, Mitch Landrieu and the infrastructure team convened a meeting with inspector general &#8212; inspectors generals &#8212; general from all agencies with funding from the infrastructure law to discuss oversight and transparency.&nbsp; He called for each state to appoint an infrastructure implementation lead, and we are committed to showing transparency on how money is allocated and spent.</p>



<p>Also, one other update for all of you at the top. &nbsp;As you know, the President is headed to New York City on Thursday, and I wanted to give you a quick preview of his trip.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He will be joined on the trip by Attorney General Garland to talk about the steps the administration has taken so far to reduce cri- &#8212; gun crime, and how we can be a strong partner for New York City and other cities grappling with increased gun violence over the past two years.</p>



<p>The President and the Attorney General will join with law enforcement officials alongside elected leaders, including Mayor Adams, Governor Hochul, at the New York Police Department headquarters to discuss the work that federal, state, and local law enforcement officials are doing to quickly take guns and repeat shooters off of our streets.</p>



<p>Afterward, President Biden, Attorney General Garland, Mayor Adams, Governor Hochul, and other elected leaders will visit with community violence intervention leader &#8212; leaders in Queens to talk about the community-led work to interrupt gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President outlined a comprehensive plan last year to tackle gun crime that includes giving cities historic funding through the American Rescue Plan to put more cops on the beat and support community violence intervention programs, as well as initiatives like afterschool programming, creating economic opportunities, and reducing recidivism to address the root causes of gun crime.</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s budget also doubles federal support for community policing, with $300 million more for cities plus another $200 million for community violence interventions &#8212; a total of a half a billion dollars for these strategies that are proven to reduce gun crime.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to continue to urge Congress to act on that.</p>



<p>Finally, the Department of Justice continues to step up their efforts to combat violent crime and gun trafficking, including through five strike forces launched last year in New York City and other regions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the Department of Justice reported just last week, those efforts have resulted in thousands of guns and violent criminals being taken off the streets over the past year.&nbsp; But they will, of course, have more to say on Thursday.</p>



<p>Why don’t you kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; It’s been a busy news day so I have a few.&nbsp; Off the top, Senator Manchin just said Build Back Better is &#8220;dead.&#8221;&nbsp; Was the White House aware that he felt this way?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the path forward for some of those Democratic priorities?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, as a policy, we&#8217;re not going to get into private conversations we have with Senator Manchin or any other senators about this piece of legislation or our efforts moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I will note and where there is strong support moving forward across the Democratic Caucus is on taking steps to lower costs for childcare, for healthcare, for eldercare; on making sure that Medicare can negotiate the cost of prescription drugs; and ensuring the tax system is fair.&nbsp; Whatever you call that, there is strong support for that, strong passion for that, a lot of advocacy for that, and there are a lot of members having continued conversations about it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then Russian President Vladimir Putin just said today that the U.S. is ignoring its top security demands but that Moscow is still open for more talks.&nbsp; Is the U.S. open to more talks?&nbsp; If not, what is the step forward with respect to Russia?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely we are.&nbsp; The door to diplomacy remains open.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t know what decision President Putin will make.&nbsp; While we&#8217;ve seen the buildup of troops on the border, Secretary &#8212; our Secretary of State, Tony Blinken, just spoke this morning with Foreign Minister Lavrov, and he reiterated our commitments and openness to a diplomatic path forward.</p>



<p>Let me give you a little bit more of a readout of that.&nbsp; And I can give you more of an update of some of the other conversations we&#8217;ve been having with a range of counterparts as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Secretary Blinken &#8212; I know the State Department did a bit of a background call on this, but let me give you some highlights: The Secretary emphasized the U.S. willingness, bilaterally and together with Allies and partners, to continue a substantive exchange with Russia on mutual security concerns, which we intend to do in full coordination with our partners and Allies.  He reiterated the United States commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, as well as the right of all countries to determine their own foreign policy and alliances. </p>



<p>He also urged immediate Russian de-escalation and the withdrawal of troops and equipment from Ukraine’s borders, and was clear that further invasion of Ukraine would be met with swift and severe consequences and urged Russia to pursue a diplomatic path.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, also met with his German counterpart today as part of our regular consultations with our Allies and partners.&nbsp; But certainly, the door to diplomacy remains open.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve said many times, de-escalation will, of course, make that diplomatic path easier moving forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more on HHS.&nbsp; Last week, there was a GAO report warning that HHS may not be prepared for a future pandemic and that it had fallen short in a number of ways in this pandemic.&nbsp; There have also been reports about White House officials being frustrated with Secretary Becerra’s leadership.&nbsp; So does the President still have confidence in Secretary Becerra?&nbsp; And has he talked to him about any changes he might want to see at HHS or about his leadership of the department?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you know how we feel about anonymous sources around here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They weren’t all anonymous.&nbsp; There were some experts that are publicly criticizing the way HHS has &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; From &#8212; from within the government, I&#8217;m referring to.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would just reiterate that the President remains confident in the role of Secretary Becerra.&nbsp; He is somebody who is an important partner.&nbsp; He has been leading a range of efforts from the Department of Homeland Security &#8212; I mean &#8212; Homeland Security &#8212; the &#8212; from the Department of Health and Human Services.&nbsp; And we have strong partnerships from the very top down with HHS.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re less focused on &#8212; not at all focused, I should say, on palace intrigue, as much as we are on vaccinating more Americans, fighting the Omicron surge, expanding testing capacity, and getting more therapeutics out to the American people.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s how we believe we and the leadership of the Cabinet will be judged.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of follow-ups here.&nbsp; On Ukraine, we&#8217;ve seen some of the major European allies talking directly with Putin.&nbsp; Emmanuel Macron has spoken with him twice.&nbsp; The Italian Prime Minister has spoken with him.&nbsp; Boris Johnson is now traveling to Ukraine.&nbsp; Why not have the President have a &#8212; you know, take more direct involvement like some of these other allies are?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President remains certainly open to that if there&#8217;s a determination that that is the appropriate and most constructive step moving forward.&nbsp; We also have a very active and engaged Secretary of State, who has had a number of conversations with his counterpart, including this morning, and that&#8217;s the channel that those conversations are happening through at this point &#8212; as well as at many other levels, I should say.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the question about Senator Manchin: He also said that no one has reached out to him.&nbsp; He hasn&#8217;t been having talks about trying to do this “in chunks,” as the President has suggested may be the path forward.&nbsp; Why not?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to outline from here conversations that we are having with a range of senators and a range of senators are having with each other, but I can assure you we&#8217;ve been in touch with and hav- &#8212; with every member of the Democratic Caucus.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just some housekeeping on the Supreme Court pick.&nbsp; The Times is reporting that Doug Jones will be the sherpa on the Hill.&nbsp; Can you confirm that and talk about that decision?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to confirm yet at this point about what the team will look like that we bring in, as has been done historically, to help sherpa through our nominee whenever that person is selected.</p>



<p>I can reiterate that we intend to have that team in place before the President makes a selection, and that team will be more than one person.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Kristen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; And thank you for the welcome back.&nbsp; Following up on the Supreme Court decision, a number of Republicans, as you know and as you&#8217;ve been asked about, have spoken out about the President&#8217;s pledge to pick a Black woman for the High Court.&nbsp; How do you respond specifically to Ted Cruz who, overnight, called it &#8220;offensive&#8221; &#8212; offensive to Black women that he would make that pledge?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here’s what I would say first: Just over a year ago, the previous <a></a>president also promised to select a woman for the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Not only were there no complaints about choosing a nominee from a specific demographic &#8212; from the same corners &#8212; but there was widespread praise of now-Justice Barrett on those grounds with Republican lawmakers widely highlighting that they thought this was positive for women in America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, take Senator Cruz himself: He had no objection to Donald Trump promising he’d nominate a woman in 2020.&nbsp; I repeat: No objection at all.&nbsp; In fact, he praised her on these grounds during &#8212; praised her on these grounds &#8212; the nominee.&nbsp; During her confirmation hearing, Senator Cruz said, quote, “I think you&#8217;re an amazing role model for little girls.&nbsp; What advice would you give little girls?”</p>



<p>When President Reagan honored his campaign pledge to place the first woman on the Court, he said it symbolizes the unique American opportunity.&nbsp; There is no outcry around that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s view is that after 230 years of the Supreme Court being in existence, the fact that not a single Black woman has served on the Supreme Court is a failure in the process, not a failure &#8212; or a lack of qualified Black women to serve as Supreme Court justices.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And broadly speaking, we just heard from the President on how he is viewing this pick.&nbsp; He says he is taking the “advise and consent” role very seriously &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; of the Senate.&nbsp; If he thought &#8212; and I know you&#8217;ve been getting questions around this, but just to kind of put a finer point on it: If he thought that a nominee could get more Republican support, how would that weigh on his decision?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I talked with him about this exact question this morning because I know a lot of you are asking about it.&nbsp; And what he reiterated to me is that his focus is on picking the person who is eminently qualified, who is ready to serve and prepared to serve in a lifetime appointment to the Supreme Court, not in navigating the legislative process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just yesterday &#8212; on different a topic, HBCUs: A number of them have gotten more bomb threats today.&nbsp; You ca- &#8212; yesterday said that the bomb threats were disturbing.&nbsp; Can you update us on what, if any, more information the White House, the President has about these potential threats?&nbsp; And is there a concern that it is, in fact, linked to Black History Month?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t have an assessment at this point.&nbsp; We are continuing to evaluate.&nbsp; Our homeland security advisor here in the White House, Liz Sherwood-Randall, is providing regular updates to senior staff, to the President as well.&nbsp; And he certainly is aware of the latest instance of bomb threats not just yesterday, but also those this morning.</p>



<p>And let me just reiterate that we condemn these disturbing threats, and our thoughts are with the students, faculty, and staff of these storied institutions.</p>



<p>We have been long supporters and have made historic investments in HBCUs and deeply value the significant role they continue to play in advancing opportunity for Black students across America.&nbsp; But, right now, we don&#8217;t have any assessment or new assessment right now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any chance that the President &#8212; or are there any discussions about the President visiting one of these HBCUs to reaffirm the commitment that the White House has to the protection of the students (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has certainly visited HBCUs in the past, Kristen.&nbsp; Obviously, right now, our focus is on ensuring we are working in close coordination with our law enforcement authorities and ensuring that the leaders of these institutions and the students know that we are watching closely and that we are standing with them as they face these threats.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t have any trip to predict at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can I follow on that, please?&nbsp; Just one &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go to you next, April.&nbsp; Let me just finish Kristen’s &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more, really quickly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tomorrow is the one-year anniversary of the Family Reunification Task Force.&nbsp; As you know, Secretary Mayorkas has told NBC News that the White House is 100 percent supportive of permanent legal status for families separated at the border.&nbsp; Is that a true statement?&nbsp; Is that a (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We stand by Secretary Mayorkas.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go &#8212; April, go ahead.&nbsp; And then, I’ll come back to you.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, Jen, back on the HBCU bomb threats.&nbsp; There is a historic issue when it comes to bomb threats in the Black community.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with that said, you have people like Lee Merritt calling it &#8220;terrorism.&#8221;&nbsp; And he&#8217;s asking for the DOJ, Homeland Security, and U.S. Attorney&#8217;s Office to investigate &#8212; to form a task force, particularly specifically on these issues.&nbsp; Is there talk around the White House for this to happen?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what I can tell you, April, is that we take these threats incredibly seriously; that, again, our homeland security advisor is in close touch with law enforcement authorities at a federal and local level.&nbsp; And we are assessing what we think the origin, the reasoning, the motivation behind it is.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have an assessment of that quite yet.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of that process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we absolutely are behind these HBCUs.&nbsp; We are &#8212; want to make very clear that we take these threats seriously and we deeply value their contributions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it&#8217;s important for law enforcement authorities and others to make an assessment before we make any determinations about next steps.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the White House see the irony in this moment with these continued bomb threats of HBCUs, particularly as much of the power structure up and down Pennsylvania Avenue are graduates of HBCUs, starting with the Vice President, Howard University; Cedric Richmond, Morehouse; Joyce Beatty, the head of the CBC, Central State; the House Whip, James Clyburn, South Carolina State.&nbsp; So, is there irony in this moment?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m not sure I would say &#8212; call it “irony,” April.&nbsp; But I would say that it is &#8212; it is scary.&nbsp; It is horrifying.&nbsp; It is terrible that these students, these faculty, these institutions are feeling under threat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, again, we don’t know more details at this point in time, and I don’t want to get ahead of law enforcement authorities.&nbsp; But certainly, given the history you referenced, you know, this is something we’re very mindful of and that is why we’re so focuses on providing regular updates and seeing what our law enforcement team assess.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, on the policing executive orders: Reverend Al Sharpton says that there is now a move to break apart the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act for standalone pieces that could possibly go up for a vote and, one way or another, pass or fail.&nbsp; And they’re doing that because the executive orders don’t have as much teeth as a law.&nbsp; What do you say to this effort to break apart the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act and make each portion a standalone bill?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what I can&#8217;t assess from here, April, is whether there’d be support for getting that across the finish line and signed into law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, the President very much wanted to sign the George Fle- &#8212; Floyd Justice in Policing Act into law, and we did not take executive actions becau- &#8212; at the time, because we wanted to leave room and space for that process to proceed in a bipartisan manner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I’d really point you to leadership and committee chairs in Congress to see what is possible on that front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly, we agree, a law is more permanent than executive orders.&nbsp; That is absolutely true.&nbsp; But we have not even finalized, nor do I have a preview of exactly when it would be, a police reform executive order.&nbsp; So, I would also encourage people to wait to assess what that looks like.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Weijia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Back to the Supreme Court.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know the President said he wanted to seek the advice of the Senate, in addition to consent.&nbsp; Is there anything you can share about his conversation with Senators Durbin and Grassley, and whether he shared his list of potential candidates with them?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think they were still meeting when I came out here, or I had not spoken with him yet if it was breaking, so I have not gotten a rundown from him quite yet.</p>



<p>I think he wanted to have an open and engaging conversation with them.&nbsp; In terms of what specific information he shared, I think it was more of him looking to listen to them and hear what they had to say about &#8212; there are a range of names, a range of candidates out there.&nbsp; But also look to them for their advice and their counsel.</p>



<p>As we have noted before, Senator Durbin has been through seven confirmation hearings for Supreme Court justices.&nbsp; Senator Grassley is certainly a veteran of these committee processes.&nbsp; The President takes his role seriously and, as he said today and as your referenced, takes the role of consent of the Senate seriously.&nbsp; But I don’t think we’re going to read out too many specifics other than to say he was looking forward to having an engaging conversation.</p>



<p>Q &nbsp;&nbsp; And since Justice Breyer announced his retirement, has the President spoken personally with any of the candidates who he might be considering?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re not going to give a process update or assessment from here, just as a policy.&nbsp; But I can tell you that what we’re focused on now is &#8212; obviously, the President is continuing to consult with leadership in Congress, as is evidenced &#8212; as was evidenced by this morning.&nbsp; He’ll do more of that this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is obviously an ongoing process as we look to name and nominate a Supreme Court justice before the end of this month.&nbsp; As is, you know, related to Mary’s earlier question, we’ll also be announcing soon a team that we will be bringing in from the outside.&nbsp; So, there are a number of steps that are happening at the same time.&nbsp; But we’re not going to be going into specifics of confirming the internal processes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you mentioned just a bit ago that he is looking for &#8212; to someone who will obviously serve for a lifetime.&nbsp; Will age be a factor as he considers who to nominate so whoever it is can have a longer imprint on the Court?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m just not going to get into more specifics of what he’s looking for.&nbsp; I mean, I think the President outlined, when he spoke earlier, that he’s looking for somebody who is qualified &#8212; who is eminently qualified, who is prepared to serve in this role.</p>



<p>There is a range of candidates he’s been reviewing bios of for some time now.&nbsp; But beyond that, I’ll let him speak to more specifics.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And then one more question on Russia: How soon could the U.S. move troops to the eastern flank?&nbsp; And just to clarify: When the President said “it will happen in the near term,” did he mean troops that are already stationed in Europe?&nbsp; Or would some of those troops be the ones based here at home?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we’ve said previously that there’s NATO troops, of course; there’s 8,500 of them that we’ve committed to the NATO &#8212; the NATO effort.&nbsp; That would be a decision made by the Alliance.&nbsp; Some of those troops are in the United States; some are in Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of any additional troops.&nbsp; Obviously, there are troops currently that are stationed in Eastern European countries.&nbsp; Some of those troops, of course, are not &#8212; many of them are not under the NATO Alliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A couple quick ones on the Supreme Court first.&nbsp; Last week, I know you said you&#8217;d look for an answer on whether you thought the Vice President could break a tie on a Supreme Court vote.&nbsp; Have you guys come to a determination on that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, the Vice President has been the tiebreaking vote for a number of judicial appointments &#8212; or nominees in the past.&nbsp; But our intention is, of course, to get broad support for an eminently qualified nominee.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the Oval, the President evoked the Ninth Amendment as he was talking about the qualifications he&#8217;s looking for for a judicial nominee.&nbsp; In the past and in committee hearings, he&#8217;s certainly brought that amendment up in the context of abortion rights.&nbsp; Is it a fair reading that that is what he was specifically saying that he was looking for from a candidate here?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to give any more detail on any qualifications he’s looking for at this point in time.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll have more conversations about that in the days ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there was a kind of long New Yorker story over the weekend in which a former NSC aide, Andrea Flores, made two claims.&nbsp; One was that Susan Rice and Ron Klain had opposed expanding asylum access for political reasons, and that the White House, partially because of that, wasn&#8217;t doing contingency planning for the lifting of Title 42 whenever we get to that point in the pandemic and hadn’t, kind of, built out capacity to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I was wondering if you could kind of respond to, I think, those two points that would suggest that immigration policy has shifted within the White House from the campaign.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what I can tell you is that &#8212; I did not work with Andrea Flores, so I don&#8217;t know her well, nor can I speak to her role here &#8212; but that our policy as an administration has been entirely consistent with what the President committed to on the campaign.&nbsp; And his effort has been to build a fair, humane, and lawful immigration system and bring it into the 21st century.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hence, he obviously proposed an immigration bill on his first day in office.&nbsp; And beyond that, he has taken steps to protect DACA recipients, ended the Muslim ban and the Public Charge Rule, put together the Family Reunification Task Force, restarted the Central American Minors Program that the previous administration ended, extended or newly desig- &#8212; newly designated Temporary Protected Status for a number of countries, and worked with DHS to give clear guidance for internal enforcement.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s also true that we&#8217;re still in the midst of a pandemic.&nbsp; And that is not something, of course, as we&#8217;ve talked about here a bit in the past, that everybody anticipated still being at, at this point in time.&nbsp; The CDC is obviously the determinant of having Title 42 in place, and that still is in place because of the pandemic that we&#8217;re in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I would also note that we have &#8212; and I think this was noted, I believe, in the story &#8212; but that we have also been very clear about our view on the MPP program and very clear on our view about the inhumanity of the prior administration and how they handled immigration and that we had every intention of implementing a different approach.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one last one.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a bit of a controversy this week on the other side of the pond.&nbsp; Prime Minister Johnson and the actions of him and his staff &#8212; a report came out this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m wondering: Is the President aware of what&#8217;s going on?&nbsp; Is he at all worried that that political controversy is impacting, you know, the U.S. and UK’s ability to, sort of, press President Putin on the Ukraine situation?&nbsp; And, you know, has he ever been &#8220;ambushed by a cake&#8221;?&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; How &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Has the President ever been ambushed by a cake?&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Not that I’m aware of.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But just what his reaction is, sort of, to this controversy that&#8217;s been blowing up.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, I have not spoken with him specifically about the reports in the UK.&nbsp; But what I can tell you is that he is confident in the important partnership we have with the United Kingdom, the role they play as an important partner in making clear to Russia the unacceptable nature of the buildup of troops and their bellicose rhetoric as it relates to Ukraine.&nbsp; And that certainly has not changed, despite cakes in anyone&#8217;s faces.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Starting quickly just with Ukraine.&nbsp; You guys keep holding up this, kind of, diplomatic path for Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; But as he noted today, you&#8217;ve already rejected both of his, kind of, central demands.&nbsp; So, what exactly is this a diplomatic path to if you&#8217;ve already rejected what he&#8217;s asked for?&nbsp; And can you kind of sympathize with the fact that he may be feeling like he&#8217;s strung along and wants to pursue things on another battlefield?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As in invading a sovereign country?&nbsp; Which would be the alternative, right?&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re saying?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perhaps.&nbsp; Perhaps.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s our view: We don&#8217;t know what President Putin is going to do.&nbsp; And it is our responsibility to &#8212; and it&#8217;s an imperative to keep the door to diplomacy open.&nbsp; That does not mean that we are going to not stand by our own values, which includes the &#8212; our belief that &#8212; and the belief of NATO countries &#8212; that it should be up to NATO members to determine who is able to join NATO and that the door to that should be open.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So if that is one of their claims, we have reiterated the same thing privately that we have reiterated publicly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In our view, do we have sympathy?&nbsp; I mean, this is &#8212; you know, Secretary Blinken has used some of these analogies in the past, but when the fox is screaming from the top of the henhouse that he&#8217;s scared of the chickens, which is essentially what they&#8217;re doing, that fear isn&#8217;t reported as a statement of fact.&nbsp; And as you watch President Putin screaming about the fear of Ukraine and the Ukrainians, that should not be reported as a statement of fact.</p>



<p>We know who the fox is in this case.&nbsp; We have seen the buildup of troops at the border.&nbsp; We have seen them move troops to Belarus, on another border.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And our role in the United States is to work with other countries around the world to keep that bor- &#8212; door to diplomacy open, because certainly all of our preference is to de-escalate and to prevent an invasion from happening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that is up to President Putin to make that decision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you think a possible endgame here could be just mutual de-escalation and then live to talk &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; De-escalation in what regard?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; about the issues another day?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8220;Mutual de-escalation&#8221; &#8212; tell me more what you mean by that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, it&#8217;s up &#8212; I suppose it&#8217;s up to you to define.&nbsp; But I mean, you guys have asked for him to move troops back from the border.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But here&#8217;s what I&#8217;m getting at: We are defin- &#8212; it&#8217;s a mistake, I would say, to define things by the terms that President Putin is defining things.&nbsp; This is a country and a leader who has, you know, used chemical weapons, who has invaded multiple countries in the past several years, who has taken aggressive steps on the global stage on many occasions.</p>



<p>So, when we talk about mutual de-escalation, Russia has 100,000 troops on the border; they are the aggressor.&nbsp; We are working with NATO countries to make sure they feel secure in this moment.&nbsp; NATO is a defensive alliance.&nbsp; It is not the same thing.&nbsp; And I think we need to be careful about comparing them as the same thing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And just to switch gears to Supreme Court.&nbsp; You guys, obviously, have got this big nomination that you&#8217;re working on, but there&#8217;s also huge existential questions hanging over the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Does the President plan to decide what he&#8217;s going to do on Supreme Court reform before he makes this nomination?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He is reviewing the Supreme Court Commission report.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a prediction of when he will conclude his analysis of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I just asked because the report includes suggestions about things like changing the number of people on the Court, and you would think he would want to know who &#8212; if he’s going to increase the size of the court, who he&#8217;s going to put on first.&nbsp; Right?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think, Trevor, his focus right now is on going through a process that takes it &#8212; that values the seriousness of the role he has as president, that cons- &#8212; where he consults, as you saw today, with Democrats and Republicans to select and nominate an eminently qualified Black woman to serve on the Court.&nbsp; That&#8217;s his focus right now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, there have been some ethical questions about Supreme Court Justice Clarence Thomas.&nbsp; His wife is &#8212; has a number of political affiliations with groups that file amicus briefs before the Court, have other business before the Court.&nbsp; It&#8217;s his choice whether or not to recuse himself from those cases; he hasn&#8217;t.&nbsp; Does the President feel that there is an ethical issue there that he&#8217;d like to see dealt with?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not had a discussion about that with the President or our counsel&#8217;s office.&nbsp; I will see if there&#8217;s any comment we have from here, or it might be a Department of Justice comment.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll get back to you.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Jen.&nbsp; How’s it going?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Good.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Center for American Progress put out a memo today focusing on specific priorities for a more narrow Build Back Better bill, but not listed is the extended Child Tax Credit.&nbsp; Could the White House (inaudible) support a revised bill that didn&#8217;t include the extended Child Tax Credit?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to make a prediction or negotiate from here.&nbsp; Obviously, the President proposed an extension of the Child Tax Credit, as you know, because it helped cut the &#8212; child poverty by 40 percent last year.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something he would absolutely like to be extended.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is a question here as to what 50 members of the Democratic caucus will support.&nbsp; And they support, as we were talking about a little bit earlier, some big fundamental goals, which is important: lowering cost of childcare, healthcare; negotiating prescription drugs.&nbsp; That&#8217;s important.&nbsp; But I can&#8217;t predict for you here what all 50 of them will support.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Last week, the Surgeon General also was asked on MSNBC about Joe Rogan&#8217;s vaccine comments on Spotify.&nbsp; And he said that tech companies have an “important role to play” in stopping misinformation because he &#8212; they are the “predominant places” where misinformation spreads.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spotify is putting out advisory warnings on episodes that have to do with COVID-19.&nbsp; Does the White House and the administration think this is a satisfactory step?&nbsp; Or do you &#8212; do you think that companies like Spotify should go further than just, you know, putting a label on there to say, “Hey, go do your own &#8212; you know, check this out.&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s more research you can look at &#8212; you know, scientific research regarding COVID”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, last July, I &#8212; you probably know, but the Surgeon General also took the unprecedented step to issue an advisory on the risk of misinformation and public health, which is a very significant step.&nbsp; And amid that, he talked about the role social media platforms have.</p>



<p>So our hope is that all major tech platforms &#8212; and all major news sources, for that matter &#8212; be responsible and be vigilant to ensure the American people have access to accurate information on something as significant as COVID-19.&nbsp; And that certainly includes Spotifly [sic].&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this disclaimer &#8212; it&#8217;s a positive step.&nbsp; But we want every platform to continue doing more to call out misinform- &#8212; mis- and disinformation while also uplifting accurate information.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, look at the facts, right?&nbsp; You are 16 times more likely to be hospitalized if you&#8217;re unvaccinated and 68 times more likely to die than someone who is boosted if you&#8217;re unvaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s pretty significant.&nbsp; And we think that is something that unquestionably should be the basis of how people are communicating about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, ultimately, you know, our view is it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a good step, it&#8217;s a positive step, but there&#8217;s more that can be done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I have another tech question for you &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; which is: There have been some recent reports that the White House is planning to issue a series of executive actions on cryptocurrencies in the next few weeks.&nbsp; Can you give a timeline on when those are coming and what actually might be in those executive actions?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to check with our NEC team on that and see if that&#8217;s something that is coming down the road.&nbsp; But I will check and see if there&#8217;s anything to predict for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Brian.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks a lot, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wanted to first follow up on something you said about the Supreme Court process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said that President Biden has been looking at bios for some time now.&nbsp; How long has that been that he&#8217;s been looking at bios of potential candidates?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Since last year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that was something that started in the transition process?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, since last year, not during the transition process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what prompted that for him to start looking at bios last year?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He takes his role incredibly seriously.&nbsp; And we certainly know and he committed, of course, to the American people he would nominate a Black woman &#8212; a qualified Black woman to serve on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; And so he&#8217;s just been reviewing a range of bios.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Justice Breyer notified him on the 27th of January.&nbsp; Did he get advance notice before that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into any more details.&nbsp; If Justice Breyer wants to get into details about our communications, he can certainly do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I have a question on Russia as well.&nbsp; This is &#8212; the jailed Russian dissident, Aleksey Navalny &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; in an interview with Time Magazine, said that the</p>



<p>U.S. is repeatedly falling into Putin&#8217;s traps &#8212; that Putin makes escalations, like he&#8217;s doing now, and then seeks concessions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to quote Navalny here, where he says, with Putin, the U.S. is acting “like a frightened schoolboy who’s been bullied by an upperclassman.”&nbsp; What&#8217;s President Biden&#8217;s reaction to this?&nbsp; Is he &#8212; is the U.S. reacting like a “frightened schoolboy”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, that we have great respect for Aleksey Navalny and the role he&#8217;s played in speaking out and being vocal, even under duress himself.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s to be hugely admired.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think the President&#8217;s actions, the administration&#8217;s actions that have been broadly supported in a bipartisan manner speak for themselves, whether it&#8217;s our engagement and leadership on the global stage, having more than 200 engagements, leading an effort to have a unified front and making clear about the severity of economic consequences there will be should Russia decide to invade, or whether it is making clear that we are going to continue to stand up for what is a global value, which is the fact that no country should be able to invade another country and take their territory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll let others define that.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s a “frightened schoolboy.”</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So when the President talks about economic actions that &#8212; and economic consequences for Russia if it does invade, why not enact some of those sanctions now?&nbsp; Why not enact those economic consequences now?&nbsp; Why wait for an invasion?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have enacted some sanctions.&nbsp; But I would say that we think it&#8217;s an important point of leverage in the discussions.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; To clarify something you said earlier about the BBB talks &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you know, to the extent that you&#8217;re going to tell</p>



<p>us about them: You said that &#8212; you know, rest assured the President &#8212; you said, “We&#8217;ve been in touch with every member of the Democratic Caucus.”&nbsp; “We&#8217;ve been in touch…”</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We in the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that’s the leg affairs team, mainly, and the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The leg affairs team and senior members of the White House.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just not going to detail more specifics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you can&#8217;t say if the President has been involved personally in any of the conversations with (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has talked to a range of senators.&nbsp; He always does.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On the Ukraine-Russia stuff, any plans in the works for another conversation between the President and President Zelenskyy?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has talked to him a couple of times in the last few weeks, and we&#8217;ve been in regular contact.&nbsp; We also are in very close contact from Jake Sullivan’s level and Secretary Blinken’s level.&nbsp; So, certainly, it&#8217;s possible.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been in regular touch, but I don&#8217;t have any call to predict at this point.&nbsp; He just talked to him a couple days ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And one other question.&nbsp; Today, obviously, is the start of Black History Month.&nbsp; The President issued a couple of tweets about that.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wonder what the administration &#8212; the President’s response is to what has been happening in Texas and other states where a number of books have been banned by school districts.&nbsp; These are, generally, books that have focused on slavery, on Jim Crow, on civil rights, even on the Obamas.&nbsp; Does the White House have a position on the books that are being banned by these local school boards?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not discussed this with the President, but I can tell you that, as an administration, we believe in the freedom of speech and expression.&nbsp; And certainly, we have never been advocates of preventing people from understanding and reading history.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the President plan to do more to recognize &#8212; commemorate Black History Month this month?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Let me see if we can get you some more details.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of questions for you.&nbsp; Back to the Supreme Court.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How will the debate over abortion shake the President&#8217;s selection process?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President is going to select an eminently qualified Black woman to serve on the Court, someone &#8212; and he&#8217;s going to do that through consulting with a range of members of Congress, through outside experts, and obviously through engagement with them directly.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m going to give you more specifics from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But that person &#8212; will that person have to be pro-abortion?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think somebody asked a similar question.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to outline litmus tests from here today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Following up on that, the President has said in the past he does not believe that life begins at conception.&nbsp; When does he believe it begins?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know the President&#8217;s position.&nbsp; He believes in a woman&#8217;s right to choose.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But that’s not the question I asked.&nbsp; I said &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And he&#8217;s spoken &#8212; he&#8217;s spoken to this in the past.&nbsp; And I know you ask this every time you come in here, which is your &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; your absolute right, but I don&#8217;t think I have anything new to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I &#8212; that’s not &#8212; that’s not &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; reveal for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The question is: When does he believe life &#8212;&nbsp;and essential to the debate over the question of a baby&#8217;s viability, pro-life Americans &#8212; don’t you agree? &#8212; should know where the President stands on his thinking on this.&nbsp; It’s a fundamental question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President believes in a woman&#8217;s right to choose.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But his &#8212; when does he believe life begins?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to move on unless you have another question.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, let&#8217;s do another question.&nbsp; One more question &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; unrelated to that.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up on the question for &#8212; on the expanded Child Tax Credit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You have said time and again that this has taken lots of kids and families out of poverty.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A tremendous success there.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But with that now gone &#8212; it looks like it&#8217;s gone, dead &#8212; inflation creeping up, high gas prices, high food prices, how quickly are those same kids and families going to go back into poverty, do you fear?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, how it’s implemented &#8212; first, the President is going to continue to fight for the Child Tax Credit.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something he very much believes in.&nbsp; I just can&#8217;t predict what a package will look like and what there will be support from 50 senators on.</p>



<p>What I can tell you is that as individuals who are eligible file their taxes, they will get the other half of the Child Tax Credit benefit from last year.&nbsp; That is not a forever solution, but that is something that many can look ahead to.</p>



<p>The other part of the Build &#8212; the President’s Build Back Better Agenda that&#8217;s important, as you&#8217;re talking about rising costs for people: You know, we have &#8212; we have a proposal &#8212; the President has a proposal, many Democrats across the board support it, which is &#8212; that will lower costs for Americans across the country and all the issues you talked about, things that really weigh on people&#8217;s family budgets, whether it&#8217;s healthcare, which is a huge &#8212; has a huge impact on people&#8217;s budgets; childcare, which is contributing to preventing 2 million women from rejoining the workforce.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the Build Back Better plan, and that&#8217;s something that we know will help lower costs for families.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, does the President have a message for those struggling families who are very worried right now not seeing that extra $500 or $1,000 a month or whatever that are saying, “I can&#8217;t afford the groceries.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t afford the gas.&nbsp; This is getting very stressful”?&nbsp; A message from the President to those families.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President would say, &#8220;I am here to fight for you, and I &#8212; that&#8217;s why I&#8217;m going to continue to fight to pass legislation that will lower your costs.&#8221;&nbsp; And that is a top priority for him.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I want to go back to what you said in the beginning about the money that&#8217;s going to be flowing down to states and that there&#8217;s going to be an appointment of &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Infrastructure?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Infrastructure.&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp; An infrastructure lead.&nbsp; Can you tell me more about who is &#8212; who&#8217;s going to be appointing that person in each state?&nbsp; Because there may be concern over states when you get to, like, Florida, where you have Governor DeSantis saying that the President is trying to implement “woke-ification” policy and saying that there is no racism within some of the (inaudible) that have been in the past.&nbsp; How can there &#8212; when you talk about accountability, how is that process going to go?&nbsp; And what information may be accessible to the public as far as reporting?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have a huge &#8212; several &#8212; 100-page book that we put out yesterday about how people can apply for a range of funding.&nbsp; And I just outlined for you the money to date that has been allocated.&nbsp; And we have taken steps, and we will continue to, to make sure that is as transparent as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, some of these &#8212; the funding in this package &#8212; as I mentioned, 90 percent of it will go to local, Tribal, and territorial governments.&nbsp; So, that really gives the opportunity for a range of leaders to apply for funding.&nbsp; And the book is meant to give them the information and access they need so they don&#8217;t have to hire lobbyists to do that, so that they can do that on their own.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re doing that in part to ensure that equity is at the central &#8212; is central to how we&#8217;re implementing this bill.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My final question is: What do you say to many organizations &#8212; I&#8217;ve talked to several civil rights organizations &#8212; on the process of selecting a Vice President?&nbsp; They feel like some of the desires of the Black community have been put on the backburner.&nbsp; So, when it comes to selecting a Vice President, why is there no need or no push to speed up the process?&nbsp; The President has said he &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean a Supreme Court justice?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Supreme Court justice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, it&#8217;s okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Supreme Court justice.&nbsp; Why is there no need to speed up that process &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Of selecting a nominee?&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s going to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He’s going to name one (inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to name one this month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right &#8212; name one this month.&nbsp; But there has been a little bit of pushback as far as comparing the process &#8212; the timing to Amy Coney Barrett, as opposed to what the President is going to do during this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve heard Chuck Schumer say that, but is the &#8212; does the President feel the same way as far as moving &#8212; how long, how quickly and expeditiously he wants to move this process along?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I just want to make sure I&#8217;m answering the right question.&nbsp; So, you were saying there&#8217;s unhappiness in the civil rights community about the pace?&nbsp; Or are you talking about the Schumer call for the 38 days?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, is the President going on board with that to push &#8212; to push it that fast?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President takes the decision to select an eminently qualified individual to nominate to the Supreme Court very seriously.&nbsp; He wants that to be a thorough process.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s still doing that expeditiously by nominating someone this month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he wants, of course, the Senate to move forward expeditiously, but we&#8217;re not setting artificial deadlines beyond that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead in the back.&nbsp; Okay, we actually have two more, so let me get to them quickly.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I have a couple of questions on two different topics.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One is Russia and then immigration.&nbsp; On Russia, I know the President has &#8212; spoke with the Amir of Qatar regarding the role of that country exporting natural gas to the European Union.&nbsp; But is the U.S. considering increasing its role as a natural gas exporter to the European Union to serve as an alternative to Russian gas?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are having a conversation with not just countries but also suppliers about how to help meet any shortage of natural gas that could come about if &#8212; if there&#8217;s an invasion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also on Russia: Since Ukraine is not a NATO member, according to the North Atlantic Treaty, NATO cannot really respond militarily to Russia in Ukrainian territory.&nbsp; But are U.S. unilateral military actions on the table to support Kyiv?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean sending U.S. troops to Ukraine?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, no.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on the other topic that I wanted to ask real quick: This administration is now sending Venezuelan migrants arrested at the U.S.-Mexico border to Colombia under Title 42.&nbsp; What agreement has been reached with the Colombian government?&nbsp; Is it similar to the MPP with Mexico?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what we tried to do from the beginning is ensure that, for Venezuelans who are coming &#8212; who were coming from a third country, right? &#8212; that they were able, at some point, to return to that country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in this case, pursuant to Title 42, we began repatriating Venezuelan nationals who had attempted to unlawfully enter the United States to Colombia, where they had previously resided.&nbsp; So, it was, you know, a place where they had been living before.</p>



<p>Flights to Colombia with Venezuelan nationals who have legal status are expected to take place on a regular basis and will be operated by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.&nbsp; Of course, that requires agreement with the government.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When did that started?&nbsp; And how temporary is that supposed to be &#8212; this program?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s just starting now.&nbsp; And I can &#8212; I&#8217;m sure I can get you a timeline of when it actually started to commence.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there a deadline until when this will be implemented?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe we&#8217;ve set a deadline, but I can &#8212; I can get that information for you as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; One on the Supreme Court and two on COVID, if you&#8217;ll indulge me.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, on the Supreme Court: Does President Biden have plans to talk to Senator McConnell &#8212; McConnell at all today or this week?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I expect he will have many more consultations with Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything yet for you at this point, but hopefully we&#8217;ll have more in the next 24 hours.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then two quick ones on the pandemic.&nbsp; First of all, I was wondering if you&#8217;d be able to provide an update on the free mask program that the White House was doing?&nbsp; I&#8217;m just curious if there&#8217;s an update on the how many of the &#8212; of the hundreds of millions of masks have been distributed already.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, is there a way for Americans to know, you know, if there are masks in their area, if they&#8217;ve been delivered to the area pharmacies &#8212; just, you know, sort of, when &#8212; when they know that they can go find them in their area?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, we just announced this last week, but we&#8217;ve already cranked up our shipments.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve shipped 100 million N95 maks [sic] &#8212; masks so far, which is incredible progress.&nbsp; They&#8217;re available at thousands of locations around the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The initial wave of health centers or for people who are looking to see if they&#8217;re available near them is available on the Health Resources and Services Administration&#8217;s website.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the program, we &#8212; we&#8217;re working to expand it to make it available across all health centers over the coming weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then lastly, one from our colleague who couldn&#8217;t be here.&nbsp; At NewsNation, they reported hearing from people who signed up to receive the free COVID tests through the website &#8212; the government website, but they had issues where either the tests were shipped to the wrong address or they never received a confirmation email.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what should people do in that case?&nbsp; Is there a way for them to rectify that?&nbsp; Does the White House have, like, a response team in case somebody never gets a test that they ordered or anything like that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s a &#8220;Help&#8221; component on the website.&nbsp; Hopefully, it should be easy for people.&nbsp; There&#8217;s also a phone number &#8212; I&#8217;m sure we can get that to you after the briefing &#8212; as well that people could call should they have any concerns.</p>



<p>I will note that we confirmed last week that 60 million tests have been &#8212; had been ordered as of then.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an updated number.&nbsp; Tens of millions of tests have gone out the door and reached the right &#8212; right doors.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s the vast, vast, vast majority.</p>



<p>That is earlier than we were scheduled and were planning to get those tests out the doors.</p>



<p>But we can &#8212; we can get you the phone number and you can publicize that in your publication.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you make sure we all get a list of what&#8217;s going on for Black History Month?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>3:13 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
