<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 02:02:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, March 16,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/16/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-march-16-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 02:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:09 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; A couple of items for all of you at the top.&#160; Today marks one year since eight people &#8212; six of them women of Asian descent &#8212; were tragically killed by a gunman who attacked three Asian-run businesses. In the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:09 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; A couple of items for all of you at the top.&nbsp; Today marks one year since eight people &#8212; six of them women of Asian descent &#8212; were tragically killed by a gunman who attacked three Asian-run businesses.</p>



<p>In the aftermath of that horrific attack, the President and Vice President traveled to Atlanta to meet with leaders of the Asian American community and hear about pain &#8212; the pain and fear that too many Asian Americans have felt since the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Today, Erika Mori- &#8212; Moritsugu, Deputy Assistant to the President and AAPI Senior Liaison, is in Atlanta representing the White House as the community mourns the victims of this awful tragedy.</p>



<p>Ambassador Katherine Tai, our U.S. Trade Representative and Co-Chair of the White House Initiative on Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders, also spoke at a vigil in Michigan to stand against Asian Ameri- &#8212; anti-Asian hate past and present.</p>



<p>On this somber day, our administration remains fully committed to reducing the gun violence that terrorizes &#8212; terrorizes our communities and to advancing safety, inclusion, and belonging for all Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders.</p>



<p>I wanted to make a note on gas prices.&nbsp; Right now, oil prices are $94 per barrel.&nbsp; When oil was at this level one month ago, the average cost of a gallon of gasoline was $3.49.&nbsp; And yet now, the average cost of gas is $4.32.</p>



<p>When it comes to oil and gas prices, many accept that gas prices rise quickly but fall slowly &#8212; the so-called “rockets-and-feathers” phenomenon.</p>



<p>But President Biden rejects that.&nbsp; Americans deserve relief, and fast, as oil prices fall.</p>



<p>Retail gasoline prices are updated at least daily, and if gas retailers’ costs are going down, they need to immediately pass those savings onto consumers.</p>



<p>So, I will reiterate what the President said to oil and gas companies last week: The invasion of Ukraine and the volatility of the oil market is no excuse for excessive price increases, profit padding, or any effort to exploit American consumers.  No one should capitalize on Putin’s aggression by taking advantage of American families.</p>



<p>And this chart, which you see here, shows both the price of crude oil, and you see where it is as it relates to the price of gasoline.&nbsp; And as you&#8217;ve seen it gone down &#8212; go down, the price of gasoline obviously has not gone down.&nbsp; So that is the explanation of that particular chart.</p>



<p>I also just wanted to note, before we get to questions, that in some good news, we saw history made yesterday with the strong bipartisan confirmation of Shalanda Young, the first Black woman to serve as Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</p>



<p>For the past year, she has served as a key advisor to the President, a member of the economic team.&nbsp; She has led the development of the President’s budget and helped effectively implement his agenda and vision across the entire federal government.</p>



<p>She’s not just making history, she’s exceptionally qualified and has vast budget experience from her years leading staff on the House Appropriations Committee.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re thrilled to have her as our confirmed director.</p>



<p>Finally &#8212; I know you all just heard the President give remarks on this, but for clarity&#8217;s sake and to make sure everybody fully understands the totality of assistance, what the President announced today was an additional $800 million in security assistance to Ukraine, bringing the total U.S. security assistance committed to Ukraine to $1 billion in just the past week and more than $2 billion since the start of the Biden administration and, more specifically, since last March.</p>



<p>There is additional security assistance in the omnibus the President signed into law yesterday, but we&#8217;re also working with the Ukrainians and others on delivery mechanisms of that.&nbsp; So, what he outlined today is the additional $800 billion from that.</p>



<p>And this assistance, as you heard him say, it will take the form of direct transfers of equipment from the Department of Defense to the Ukrainian military to help them defend their country against Russians’ unpro- &#8212; Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.&nbsp; It also includes U.S.-produced short-range air defense systems the Ukrainians have been using to great effect &#8212; systems they are trained on.</p>



<p>We have also identified and are helping the Ukrainians acquire additional longer-range systems, on which their forces, again, are already trained, as well as additional munitions for these systems.&nbsp; And we will continue to work with Allies and partners to transfer equipment to Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At least 30 countries to date have provided security assistance to Ukraine since the invasion began.&nbsp; And in 2022, the Department of State authorized third-party transfers of defensive equipment from more than 14 countries, a number that continues to grow as Allies and partners increase support to Ukraine.</p>



<p>Chris, why don’t you kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; First off, I just wanted to note this is your 200th briefing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, wow.&nbsp; Time flies when you&#8217;re having fun.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we will celebrate with a lot of questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, 200 &#8212; let&#8217;s do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To start us off, the White House has said the Russian actions in Ukraine are under close scrutiny for potential war crimes, but today President Biden directly labeled Putin a, quote, &#8220;war criminal.&#8221;&nbsp; Has something changed in the administration&#8217;s assessment?&nbsp; What brought this new remark from the President today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the President was &#8212; the President&#8217;s remarks speak for themselves.&nbsp; He was speaking from his heart and speaking from what he&#8217;s seen on television, which is barbaric actions by a brutal dictator, through his invasion of a foreign country.</p>



<p>There is a legal process that continues to &#8212; is underway, continues to be underway at the State Department.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a process that they would have any updates on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, another question on the military assistance.&nbsp; Is the White House, is the administration facilitating the transfer of S-300 anti-air missiles?&nbsp; How is the U.S. facilitating that?&nbsp; How many might be provided to Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me just provide to you &#8212; as I&#8217;ve educated myself a little bit on weapon systems over the past few days, I thought this might be helpful to you.&nbsp; So, S-300s are anti-aircraft systems.&nbsp; We are providing Stingers, who are also anti-aircraft systems.&nbsp; There are a range of anti-aircraft systems that different countries have around the world.</p>



<p>So, as I noted, I know that President Zelenskyy called out specifically S-300s.&nbsp; And while I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics for security reasons, we are continuing to work with our Allies and key partners to surge new assistance, including Soviet- or Russian-origin anti-aircraft systems, which is exactly what that is.</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;re talking about here is how to provide them a range of anti-aircraft systems that will help them do exactly what they&#8217;ve been doing, which is to shoot down planes.&nbsp; And part of what the President announced today was additional Stingers that serve exactly that purpose.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; But given that the S-300 has a much longer range than the Stingers, is that part of the administration&#8217;s plan to find a way to facilitate that specific transfer of weapons?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Without getting into specific systems, there are a range of anti-aircraft systems that do have longer range. We are continuing to consult with our Allies and key partners to surge that assistance, but I&#8217;m not going to get into more specifics.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the last question is: The Federal Reserve raised rates today to help fight &#8212; tame inflation.&nbsp; Is the administration confident that the Fed can beat inflation through rate hikes and not risk a recession?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would note that Chairman Powell spoke to exactly that question today.&nbsp; So, I would point you to his specific comments answering that question, where he did express confidence in the ability to take the steps he announced and avoid that.</p>



<p>I would note that while they &#8212; we respect the independence of the Federal Reserve, as you of course &#8212; as we have said many times &#8212; the President has also said in the past that he recognizes not only their independence, but that it is appropriate and necessary for the Federal Reserve to recalibrace [sic] &#8212; recalibrate their &#8212; that &#8212; their support to maintain stable prices.&nbsp; And obviously, they made an announcement today.</p>



<p>As it relates to &#8212; we, obviously, closely watch here from the administration and closely monitor all risks.&nbsp; And we continue to believe that the United States economy is positioned well to deal with the challenges ahead, even as we continue to monitor.</p>



<p>And, obviously, there are events that impact the economy, including an invasion of a foreign country.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re seeing that impact as well play out in the economic data.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back on this question of labeling Putin a &#8220;war criminal.&#8221;&nbsp; I mean, this war has now been going on for three weeks.&nbsp; So far, the President has declined to use this label.&nbsp; As you note, there is an ongoing, sort of, formal process before you can use this term.&nbsp; So, something must have changed for the President to feel like he can take this additional step today.&nbsp; What?&nbsp; What else is he seeing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President was answering a direct question that was asked and responding to what he has seen on television.</p>



<p>We have all seen barbaric acts, horrific acts by a foreign dictator in a country that is threatening and taking the lives of civilians, impacting hospitals, women who are pregnant, journalists, others.&nbsp; And I think he was answering a direct question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; The administration is making it very clear &#8212; and publicly &#8212; how much assistance the U.S. is providing to Ukraine.&nbsp; Whether we are fighting in this war or not, the U.S. is obviously heavily involved.&nbsp; Putin certainly knows all of this.&nbsp; He knows where this equipment is coming from.&nbsp; Is there any concern that you run the risk that he may view this as the kind of direct U.S. involvement, the direct confrontation that you are trying to avoid?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, all the equipment that we&#8217;re providing, whether it&#8217;s Stingers or Javelins or counter artillery &#8212; counter mortar radar, counter UA- &#8212; UAV tracking radars, anti-armor systems, unmanned aerial systems &#8212; this is all defensive equipment and materials.&nbsp; It is more than we have ever provided to Ukraine in the past.&nbsp; It is a significant amount of assistance that we have expedited the delivery on.&nbsp; And we will continue to do exactly that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as our Department of Defense &#8212; and they can certainly speak to themselves &#8212; for themselves &#8212; they do risk assessments, they assess what the impact will be of the types of assistance they&#8217;re providing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re obviously watching how the types of assistance we have provided have helped the Ukrainians courageously and bravely fight back, and we&#8217;re giving them more of that assistance.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also given them additional types of assistance we had not yet provided to them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, these are all defensive weapons systems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You have noted from the podium that Putin has shown no signs of changing course.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve also noted that there are significant consequences that Putin could still face.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Even with this additional aid that you&#8217;re providing today, it seems there are still other options on the table.&nbsp; So why hold back?&nbsp; Why not use every tool at your disposal now to spare additional lives?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think if you look at the range of tools that we&#8217;ve used to date, we have &#8212; we have implemented more economic sanctions than we have on any other economy in the world.&nbsp; You could compare it, potentially, to Iran or maybe North Korea, but Russia is a much more significant economy, a larger economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I wouldn&#8217;t say that we are holding back in that sense.&nbsp; We do have additional steps we can take, as we&#8217;ve talked about a bit in here before.&nbsp; Obviously, the SWIFT banking system and the implementation of those sanctions happens institution by institution.&nbsp; There are additional individuals that can be sanctioned.&nbsp; We can have new targets.&nbsp; We can deepen the severity of sanctions on existing targets.&nbsp; We can further eject Russia from international economic or- &#8212; the international economic order.&nbsp; We can further dire- &#8212; deny Russia the capacity to mon- &#8212; modernize and diversify its economy, like we have with the export controls and the cutting off of access to a lot of technology.&nbsp; And we can further expose and hold to account the kleptocracy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These are additional actions we have, additional options we have.&nbsp; And we can take them.&nbsp; And that is a decision that we would make through a discussion internally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what are you waiting for?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are &#8212; we have additional escalatory steps that we can take.&nbsp; But I would just note that we have not held back.&nbsp; We have done more economic sanctions and had more &#8212; put in place more financial consequences than we have in any circumstance ever in the world.&nbsp; So I wouldn&#8217;t say that is holding back in any capacity.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, does the White House have any insight or assessment of the negotiations between Ukraine and Russia?&nbsp; President Zelenskyy seemed to indicate there&#8217;d been some progress, but President Putin&#8217;s remarks later did not make the same impression.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We obviously stay in very close touch with the Ukrainians.&nbsp; But what I would note is we haven&#8217;t seen any effort to de-escalate from President Putin and from the Russian military.</p>



<p>So while we will continue to be very supportive, in a range of ways, of diplomatic efforts &#8212; whether that is engaging directly with the Ukrainians, with the Europeans; you saw obviously Jake Sullivan had a call with his counterpart this morning as well &#8212; but we also are providing a range of security assistance and economic assistance to make sure we&#8217;re strengthening Ukraine as they go into these discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it&#8217;s hard to have &#8212; hard to have negotiations that are going to be effective if, you know, one party is continuing to escalate.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Zelenskyy, in his remarks to Congress today, again made his request for a no-fly zone.&nbsp; He no doubt is aware of President Biden&#8217;s position on that.&nbsp; Is there any scenario in which President Biden would change his mind?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that the President watched the speech &#8212; I know some of you asked this, so let me just do this now.&nbsp; He watched the speech from his residence, in his private library.</p>



<p>As you heard him say, he thought that President Zelenskyy was passionate, was powerful.&nbsp; And certainly he &#8212; and he watched the totality of it. &nbsp;</p>



<p>We are in very close touch with the Ukrainians.&nbsp; Nothing that he asked for or said today was a surprise in that sense.&nbsp; And if we were President Zelenskyy, we would be asking for everything possible as well and continuing to ask for it, because he is watching his country and his people be attacked and brutalized by President Putin and the Russian military.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But how President Biden makes decisions is through the prism of our own national security.&nbsp; And as we&#8217;ve said before, a no-fly zone would require implementation, it would require us potentially shooting down Russian planes, NATO shooting down Russian planes.&nbsp; And we are not interested in getting into World War Three.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last &#8212; just lastly, does the White House view Russia as being ready to go back and allow the Iran nuclear deal to come forward?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we can&#8217;t blissfully speak for Russia &#8212;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sanctioned; they especially wouldn’t let me speak for them, I guess, now &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s changed.</p>



<p>But I would say that Russia does not want Iran to acquire a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t either.&nbsp; While we have a range of strong disagreements with them, we can’t speak for their intentions here.&nbsp; Certainly, we believe it&#8217;s in both of our interests for this to move forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Jen, does the President believe that it would be important for President Zelenskyy to be at the NATO summit next week, as long as it is safe for him to do so?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not discussed that exactly with the President.&nbsp; The President is going there to meet with NATO partners and Allies.&nbsp; Obviously, President Zelenskyy is &#8212; his country is in the middle of a war.&nbsp; So I have not talked to him about that specifically.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about Jake Sullivan &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; speaking with his Russian counterpart.&nbsp; The Russian readout said that this happened at the U.S.’s initiative, and the NSC’s readout said that if Russia is serious about diplomacy, then Moscow should stop attacking Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve obviously consistently said from the podium that the door to diplomacy is never closed.&nbsp; Are we seeing, though, a ramp-up in diplomatic efforts with Russia right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, this is the most senior conversation between the U.S. and Russian officials since Secretary Blinken last spoke with Foreign Minister Lavrov.</p>



<p>I would note that we have maintained direct and indirect contact with the Russians, through our embassy and officials there, Ambass- &#8212; including through Ambassador Sullivan, and we also have a military deconfliction channel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we requested this call to clearly lay out our commitment to continuing to impose costs on Russia if they do not stop attacking Ukrainian cities and towns, and to warn them about the consequences and implications of Russia potentially using chemical or biological weapons in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s important to convey those &#8212; those consequences directly, and this was an opportunity to do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one final question on a different topic.&nbsp; The administration has marked the one-year anniversary of the Atlanta spa shootings and spoken about some of the actions that the federal government has tried to take.&nbsp; As you know, this week, an Asian woman in New York, a 67-year-old woman, was hit more than 125 times, was stomped on, was called a racial slur.&nbsp; Obviously, that video is very sickening to watch.&nbsp; Do you know whether the President has seen that video?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just what would the President&#8217;s message be to anyone in the Asian American community who feels like, well, the actions that the government is taking are not enough to stop these attacks and they say that they feel afraid?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that our message to them &#8212; I have not talked to the President about this specific video.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve seen it; a number of us have seen it.&nbsp; And as you said, it is very difficult to watch.</p>



<p>I would say that his message to them would be: Our work is not done; that we want to stand by your side and continue to stand up for you, to protect you, to call out this type of discrimination and horrific actions, as &#8212; and including in the example you gave.</p>



<p>And that what he has done is tried to elevate this type of anti-Asian hate in this country so that people are aware of it, so that communities across the country can continue in that fight as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the work clearly is not done, and we need to be steadfast in it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, David.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a couple of questions on today&#8217;s events.&nbsp; So, first, in the conversation that Jake Sullivan had with his Russian counterpart, he issued a very specific warning about chemical and bio.&nbsp; There was no mention in the readout of nuclear, which is obviously a concern for battlefield weapons.&nbsp; Was that a deliberate omission?&nbsp; Has that conversation taken place in a different channel?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to go back to them and see if there&#8217;s more we want to read out from the conversation.&nbsp; I think what the most important component here to take away, I hope, is that we wanted to have a direct conversation about what the consequences would be of further escalatory action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t have more to read out at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then on your answer, just before, about your concerns about the MiG planes &#8212; we went through a little bit of this yesterday &#8212; I think you just said that you didn&#8217;t want to have NATO pilots bringing down Russian planes.&nbsp; But under the administration&#8217;s policy of moving out this long-range anti-aircraft, it&#8217;s okay to have NATO equipment bringing down Russian planes, as long as it&#8217;s launched by a Ukrainian?&nbsp; Am I understanding the policy right?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; you&#8217;ve heard us talk a fair amount about the Poland &#8212; the planes from Poland.&nbsp; And again, Poland is a sovereign country so they can make decisions on their own.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we have done is done an assessment of our role and the U.S. role, and what our view would be of NATO, of this &#8212; of these planes taking off from NATO airspace.&nbsp; Again, I would note that the equipment that we&#8217;ve provided is defensive, as you know, not offensive.&nbsp; And we see that as being a difference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also looking at &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because the planes can be used for an offensive purpose and the antimissile systems &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; cannot?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.</p>



<p>Also &#8212; also, I would note that what our Department of Defense officials also assessed is what&#8217;s most effective.&nbsp; And while the Ukrainians still have squadrons of planes to utilize, as I think any military official could confirm for you, the types of assistance that we are providing today, including Stingers and other assistance that we&#8217;re amping up support for, is exactly what we feel is effective in fighting this war.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Today, in Putin’s speech, he implied that there&#8217;s going to be even greater crackdowns on civil liberties inside of Russia.&nbsp; Is there anything that you all believe that you can do, in terms of sanctions or supporting the opposition there, that you all are not already taking?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we look at all of the actions that President Putin does, and we assess what responses we may have.</p>



<p>I have nothing to predict at this point in time, but obviously, as he has taken actions, we have taken actions in response.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, specifically on the case of Aleksey Navalny, he &#8212; prosecutors there just said that they want to sentence him for a 13-year prison sentence.&nbsp; Does the White House have a response to that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;ve spoken a number of times in the past about the courage of Aleksey Navalny, about the role he&#8217;s played in being an outspoken advocate for freedoms in a country that has been void of them.&nbsp; And I would echo those &#8212; that response now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about what President Biden specifically hopes to accomplish in his trip next week &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; beyond shoring up NATO Allies?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s a big part of it.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a very important part, Ashley &#8212; shoring up NATO Allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I think from the beginning, and even before this conflict began, we have viewed rebuilding alliances in the world as a key component of what the Biden administration and President Biden could specifically do on the global stage following his predecessor’s &#8212; his predecessor’s actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what he&#8217;ll be doing &#8212; he&#8217;s &#8212; while he&#8217;s there: He&#8217;s meeting with our NATO Allies to coordinate our deterrence and defense.&nbsp; So they will obviously talk about where things are on the ground, coordinated responses, assistance we&#8217;re providing.&nbsp;<br><br>NATO, at this point, as you all know, is more united and more determined than we&#8217;ve been in decades.&nbsp; So we certainly would &#8212; would be focused on continuing that unity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He would also &#8212; he’s also going to join European leaders in a separate part of the day to discuss our work to impose economic costs on Russia.  As I noted earlier, there are obviously a range of coordinated steps and costs we&#8217;ve taken.  There&#8217;s more that we could do, we have the capacity and the ability to do, and we want to continue to do as much of that in a coordinated fashion. </p>



<p>We&#8217;re also looking to continue to provide a range of humanitarian support, especially as we&#8217;re seeing a surge of refugees continue to grow across the border, and, you know, discuss a range of ways we can address the challenges stemmed from Putin&#8217;s war in a coordinated fashion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on a slightly lighter note, does the administration have a position on the effort in Congress to make Daylight Savings Time permanent?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have seen those reports.&nbsp; I was trying to think of a joke; I couldn&#8217;t think of one.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a specific &#8212; we are obviously coordinated and work closely with Congress on all legislation they consider, but I don&#8217;t have a specific position from the administration at this point of time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it something &#8212; is the President more of a morning person or afternoon?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Because people are often divided in those ways, so I&#8217;m just curious if you could talk about that.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is true.&nbsp; Now, to de-link it from this specific question, he is more of an evening person.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t know what analysis you&#8217;ll provide, but I&#8217;ll look forward to reading it tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Has President Biden spoken to President Zelenskyy today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not since this morning.&nbsp; If he does and when he does, which I&#8217;m sure he will soon, we will provide that readout to all of you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Got it.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, President Zelenskyy made a distinction between a humanitarian no-fly zone and a blanket no-fly zone.&nbsp; Does the administration view them as being different or the same thing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there have been descriptions of both of those over the past couple of weeks.&nbsp; And sometimes a humanitar- &#8212; and I don&#8217;t want to put words in his mouth, but a humanitarian no-fly zone can be specific geography or a portion of Western &#8212; or parts of Ukraine, whereas a no-fly zone &#8212; sometimes people refer to it as the totality of the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In our view and the view of the military, there&#8217;s not a difference in terms of the implementation and the escalatory impact.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, today, the Vice President spoke with the President of Slovakia, which is one of three countries that can actually provide those S-300s.&nbsp; But the readout does not mention the missile system.&nbsp; So can you tell us whether the Vice President directly asked Slovakia to provide them to Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t get into more specifics, other than to convey that we are having conversations with a range of Allies about providing additional assistance &#8212; anti-aircraft assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, there are a range of &#8212; of systems, including some of the systems that we provided and we are going to be expediting delivery of to Ukraine from the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on the warplanes that Zelenskyy asked for today.&nbsp; I mean, you&#8217;ve made very clear that the U.S. is opposed to doing that right now.&nbsp; I wonder if the U.S. is also discouraging other NATO Allies from providing fighter jets, even if the U.S. would not have to serve as a middleman.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Other countries can make their own sovereign decisions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then one more on the Asian hate crimes, because you mentioned them at the top, too.&nbsp; Do you know if the DOJ has concluded that there is not enough evidence to charge the shooter in Atlanta with a federal hate crime?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t speak to that from here.&nbsp; You&#8217;d have to ask DOJ that question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, more broadly, since the administration adopted new policies that are meant to make it easier to identify these crimes as hate crimes, do you &#8212; can you point to any progress that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;d point you to the Department of Justice, who are implementing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jacqui.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just one more.&nbsp; I know a lot of people have asked about the MiGs, but can you lay out for us why the administration sees MiGs as provocative and Javelins and Stingers as not provocative?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, Javelins and Stingers are defensive weapons.&nbsp; MiGs or planes are offensive weapons, which are a different type of military system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say the other assessment that we&#8217;ve done &#8212; not through here, not through the White House, not through the President &#8212; from &#8212; from the Department of Defense is to assess what is effective and what works in terms of fighting this war on the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that is why we provided an additional $1 billion &#8212; $800 million announced today, but $1 billion this week &#8212; of assistance, utilizing a number of the high-level military systems &#8212; Stingers, Javelins, counter-artillery, counter-mortar radar, anti-armor systems &#8212;&nbsp;that we know have been effective and we know the Ukrainians are trained on.</p>



<p>Third, Ukraine&#8217;s Air Force already has several squadrons of mission-capable aircraft, and giving them more would not significantly change their effectiveness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally &#8212; I touched on this in the beginning, offensive versus defensive &#8212; but we also do risk assessments from the Department of Defense about what would be escalatory and what &#8212; and that is obviously what we would like to avoid.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, John Kirby has said that success for the U.S. mission in Ukraine is a free, independent, sovereign Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also heard that the official mission is to prevent escalation beyond Ukraine.&nbsp; Which is it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Both are true.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If we&#8217;re not specific about what exactly the desired outcome is, how do we expect to be able to be successful?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Why could &#8212; why could both not be true: a sovereign Ukraine and preventing them from expanding beyond?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, moving on to the nuclear deal, General McKenzie told the Armed Services Committee that, from everything that he can see, the IRGC is a terrorist organization.&nbsp; Is the White House willing to de-list the IRGC from the Foreign Terrorist Organization list in order to get a deal with Iran?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re still in the negotiations, so I&#8217;m not going to speculate or outline from here what the final details look like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And these are likely the group responsible for firing missiles at U.S. facilities in Iraq.&nbsp; So as long as Americans aren&#8217;t killed, are there &#8212; are there are no consequences for something like that, all in an effort to get a nuclear deal?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, you&#8217;re speculating on something that is not even finalized.&nbsp; The deal is not finalized.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would note &#8212; and I would just go back to why we&#8217;re negotiating this deal.&nbsp; And right now, we&#8217;re negotiating this deal because nu- &#8212; Iran&#8217;s nuclear gains are threatening U.S. interests.&nbsp; There&#8217;s urgency to taking steps to contain that, which is why we&#8217;ve been engaged so closely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that is all the result of President Trump pulling out of the deal, and Iran moving closer to having the capacity and acquiring a nuclear weapon and speeding up their breakout time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we are here thanks to the actions of the last president and the last administration.&nbsp; And it is in our interest, it is in the global interest to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Kristen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; How quickly can Ukraine expect to receive the list of military aid that President Biden laid out today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have expedited, as you &#8212; as you would &#8212; as we&#8217;ve noted from here, about 300 million dollars&#8217; worth of military and security assistance over the last couple of weeks.&nbsp; We continue to have channels to deliver military assistance.&nbsp; And so, we would continue to work to deliver it quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There have been military deliveries even in the last few days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, it has been rolling and you&#8217;re confident it will continue to be including these new elements that he laid out today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We continue to have channels to do exactly that, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>And the President said, going back now to the long-range air defense systems, that he was working with Allies to acquire them.&nbsp; Can you tell us where they are and what the expectation is in terms of the timeline for getting those systems to Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t outline where they are because we&#8217;re going to keep those conversations private.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note that a great deal of what we&#8217;re doing is augmenting the type of effective military assistance that we&#8217;re doing from the United States and working to prioritize equipment that they are trained on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we are discussing with a range of partners.&nbsp; When we say &#8220;Stinger&#8221; or &#8220;Javelins,&#8221; those are brands.&nbsp; There are different kinds of similar assistance or other types of assistance that different allies have around the world.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to go back to the MiGs quickly and just be crystal clear about what you&#8217;re saying.&nbsp; Because when I asked the President about this earlier, he said he&#8217;s not going to comment.&nbsp; He didn&#8217;t say that it&#8217;s not an option.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve spoken to it approximately 167 times.&nbsp; So, maybe he &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s 168.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s a growing &#8212; there&#8217;s a growing number of Republicans and Democrats who are supporting the U.S. striking a deal with Poland to send the MiGs.&nbsp; You have Elise Stefanik earlier today saying Ukraine “needs those MiGs.”&nbsp; You have Scalise saying, “Getting [those] MiGs in immediately is…critical.”&nbsp; There&#8217;s a growing chorus of voices saying that now is the time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Has the President reconsidered his stance at all at this point?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, because our military makes assessments, which &#8212; they put out that assessment last week and I would just echo that one part of the assessment is based on what equipment is effective in fighting this war.&nbsp; Anti-armor and air-defense systems, they are effectively defending the country.&nbsp; That is what we have provided additional assistance on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, they have several squa- &#8212; squadrons of mission-capable aircraft &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But they don’t think that’s enough, Jen.&nbsp; You heard President Zelenskyy &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; that are not being &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; very clearly say &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; Kristen, that are not &#8212; Kristen, that are not &#8212; Kristen, that are not being utilized.&nbsp; This is the assessment by our Defense Department.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, they&#8217;re also assessing that the transfer to Ukraine may be mistaken as escalatory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is how our Defense Department is assessing.&nbsp; They’re assessing also that it would not significantly change the effectiveness of the Ukrainian Air Force.&nbsp; And these are the types of risk ass- &#8212; risk assessments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We certainly understand.&nbsp; We share the passion, the anger, the horror at what we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; And that is why we are &#8212; we significantly increased the types of military assistance, the types of equipment that we know is effective and our Defense Department has determined is effective in fighting this war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Zelenskyy ended his speech today by saying, “Being the leader of the world means to be the leader of peace.” Is President Biden satisfied that he&#8217;s meeting this leadership moment, given that we&#8217;re now three weeks into this war?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that President Zelenskyy also thanked the President for the role he&#8217;s played.&nbsp; And without President Biden, there would not be 30 countries around the world providing security and military assistance, NATO would not be as aligned as it is, we would not be unified in our implementation of the most crippling sanctions we&#8217;ve ever implemented against a foreign country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will continue to stand by President Zelenskyy’s side, the side of the Ukrainians and the brave and courageous Ukrainian people, and continue to build on the efforts that have been underway to date.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more very quickly.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the wake of the Second Gentleman testing positive, has President Biden been tested today and has the Vice President been tested?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The &#8212; I can check on the Vice President. The President has not been.&nbsp; He was tested on Sunday.&nbsp; He was not a close contact, so we have not changed our testing mechanism.</p>



<p>Let me check on the Vice President.&nbsp; I know they put out some information last night.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll see if there&#8217;s an update.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Can you confirm that Switchblade drones were part of the package?&nbsp; And if so, do you consider that still defensive?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have more details beyond what was in our factsheet to confirm from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And is the U.S. monitoring the hostage situation in Chernobyl?&nbsp; And did that come up in the call with Sullivan today?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are definitely closely monitoring that situation.&nbsp; And I can check and see if that was a topic of discussion during their call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also, just lastly here, what does the administration make of the Russian proposal of Ukraine being a demilitarized Austrian-and-Swedish-type model?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As a part of their 15-point discussion?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As part of &#8212; right.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, our focus is on supporting the Ukrainians in their efforts.&nbsp; Obviously, pursuing diplomacy is something we will always support.&nbsp; But as President Putin and the Russian military continues to take escalatory steps on the ground and take military action against civilians and innocent people, we think that is the biggest place where we need to see change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask if you&#8217;re &#8212; if you&#8217;re in a position today to say more about the contours of the President&#8217;s travel next week.&nbsp; What&#8217;s after Brussels, if anything?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more for you at this point in time.&nbsp; We&#8217;re still finalizing the additional &#8212; any additional details.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The fact that the Second Gentleman did test positive, does that raise concerns here about the state of &#8212; the situation of the country with BA.2 or any other variants that might be around?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It does not.&nbsp; Not from our health officials.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, back of the room.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll go to the back in a second.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask just very briefly?&nbsp; Sarah Bloom Raskin &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; withdrew her nomination yesterday.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you could speak to that.&nbsp; And in particular, will you name a new no- &#8212; will the President name a new nominee soon for that post?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He certainly will nominate a new person to serve &#8212; to nominate to that post.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been less than a day, so it may be a little bit more time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are certainly disappointed.&nbsp; Sarah Bloom Raskin remains one of the most highly qualified people to ever be nominated to this position.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s an important role, and he will nominate someone to fill the position.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak to how those final, sort of, days played out on that?&nbsp; Did &#8212; was there an attempt to get bipartisan support, or was Senator Manchin’s statement sort of seen as the decisive one when that came down?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; I would say, as I said from this podium, it &#8212; there was continued efforts to seek bipartisan support and continue to support her candidacy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, sorry, going back to the drones, is your position that the drones were assessed by the Defense Department to not be perceived as escalatory and to not be perceived as offensive weapons?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t have anything more to confirm beyond what was in the factsheet and the specifics in there.&nbsp; But defensive weapons is what we have provided.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go to the back in a second.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The administration &#8212; including you, yesterday &#8212; have raised very dire warnings about what will happen &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; if this COVID money doesn&#8217;t come through.</p>



<p>President Biden held a bill signing yesterday &#8212; a very celebratory bill signing for a piece of legislation that that was stripped out of &#8212; that funding was stripped out of.&nbsp; Why didn&#8217;t the President mention it?&nbsp; And is he willing to expend political capital on this?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, he is.&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; I would say that we have been working around the clock over the last few days, behind the scenes and publicly, to convey very clearly to elected officials across the country and the American people what the impacts will be.&nbsp; So, I would expect you&#8217;ll hear from him more soon about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the meeting that Jake Sullivan &#8212; or the conversation that Jake Sullivan had with the Russian Security Council Secretary, can you say why that particular person was the one that the U.S. reached out to, why he was the one that Jake had a conversation with?&nbsp; Is there anything about his proximity to Putin or anything else that we should know?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s more to detail from here.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of questions on Russia.&nbsp; Obviously, the President calling Vladimir Putin personally a “war criminal” today.&nbsp; Are you going to be detailing whether orders to strike maternity wards, residential buildings, innocent children were coming from the very top?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say there&#8217;s a legal process where all of the data and information gathered will be fed into any international investigations.&nbsp; That&#8217;s led by the State Department.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think I spoke to this a few minutes earlier, where I conveyed the President was directly answering a question and speaking to his own passion in watching the barbaric actions of a brutal dictator invading a foreign country.&nbsp; But there is a legal process that is ongoing.&nbsp; The State Department has oversight over that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then the Chinese ambassador to the U.S. published a &#8212; an op-ed in the Washington Post.&nbsp; He said that threats against Chinese entities and businesses are unacceptable and, quote, “wielding the baton of sanctions at Chinese companies while seeking” Chinese &#8212; “China’s support and cooperation simply won&#8217;t work.”&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you have a response to that.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that our &#8212; I don&#8217;t believe that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve &#8212; that&#8217;s an accurate depiction of what we&#8217;ve been doing.&nbsp; What we&#8217;ve been conveying is that rhetorical support or the clear rhetorical lack of denunciation of what Russia is doing flies in the face of what China stands for, including basic principles of the U.N. Charter, including the basic principle of respect for sovereignty of nations.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s just a statement of fact.</p>



<p>Obviously, our objective and what we&#8217;ll watch closely is &#8212; and I don&#8217;t have an update on it from here &#8212; is, you know, any decision to provide additional support to Russia while they&#8217;re invading a foreign country.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Senator Chuck Grassley has put a hold on nomination of LA Mayor Eric Garcetti for U.S. Ambassadorship to India.&nbsp; Has the President spoken with his friend, senator?&nbsp; Or has the White House reached out to him to lift the hold?&nbsp; Or is the White House considering a new name for India?&nbsp; Is the absence of a U.S. Ambassador to India having an impact on your bilateral relationship?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he can&#8217;t actually prevent a vote from moving forward on the floor.&nbsp; I mean, he can convey his opposition as is the right of any senator.&nbsp; But Mayor Garcetti is out of committee, and we&#8217;re hoping to see a vote on the Senate floor soon.&nbsp; And the President has confidence in Mayor Garcetti and believes he&#8217;ll be an excellent representative in India.</p>



<p>It is critical, of course, that we have confirmed leadership at all of our embassies, including India, and we urge the Senate to confirm him as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And in the middle of this war with Ukraine, how are the world&#8217;s largest and oldest democracies working together to bring peace in the region?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, as you know, we remain in touch through a range of channels from our national security team with leaders in India, and continue to encourage leaders to work closely with us to &#8212; to stand up against President Putin&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The wheat supplies from both Russia and Ukraine have been disrupted and are forecasted to be disrupted quite a bit going forward.&nbsp; Does the U.S. see the danger, as some have been talking about, about a breakdown, actually, of food supplies to large parts of the world, maybe starting with Africa?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This is something we&#8217;re watching very closely.&nbsp; I have a little bit of information on this, so let me see if I can find it.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see.</p>



<p>And we are concerned about how the wheat supply could impact different parts of the world, less the United States and more other parts of the world.&nbsp; There are also impacts we could see in the United States, including fertilizer and the production of fertilizer.&nbsp; Ukraine is a large producer of fertilizer.&nbsp; So, there are steps the Department of Agriculture has announced, and we are taking steps to work to address.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this is something &#8212; to go back to your original question &#8212; we are monitoring closely and we are, of course, continuing to evaluate what types of humanitarian assistance we can provide to address.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just a quick one on another part of the world.&nbsp; Taiwan&#8217;s foreign minister said just this week &#8212; it might have been yesterday &#8212; that the U.S. is about to announce more arms sales to Taiwan.&nbsp; Do you have anything on that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict, confirm, or read out on that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check with our Defense Department.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So, the President has obviously sanctioned a lot of Russian oligarchs.&nbsp; I wonder about some of the laws &#8212; our laws that enable this sort of international kleptocracy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, the President&#8217;s been outspoken about his belief that America&#8217;s tax code should be more fair, that it should be enforced better.&nbsp; And I wonder if the President has thought about or has had conversations with people on the Hill about possible legislation that would change some of these laws, make real estate transactions more transparent, require companies and trust to be registered to people by their actual name, prevent Americans from using offshore banks as tax havens.&nbsp; Any of that under consideration?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A number of those he&#8217;s expressed support for in the past.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check with our economic team and see if any of those are under discussion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But no sense that those talks have picked up in the last few weeks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have an update on it.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to get back to Jake Sullivan&#8217;s call: You noted when you were first talking about it that this was the most senior conversation between the U.S. and Russia since Secretary Blinken&#8217;s last conversation with Lavrov.&nbsp; So, why now?&nbsp; Why today?&nbsp; Has something changed that&#8217;s given the administration any reason to think this could produce some progress &#8212; a call like this?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t put that much optimism in it.&nbsp; I would say that there have been ongoing direct and indirect conversations with the Russians.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not that it stopped at any point.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve &#8212; they&#8217;ve &#8212; those have happened through our Ambassador, and it just felt like the appropriate time for our National Security Advisor to have a discussion and directly convey that there will be additional consequences should things proceed, including if there is a use of chemical weapons.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess, to ask you the inverse then &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; would there be any increasing concerns that prompted that call today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that, you know, diplomatic conversations and talks &#8212; there isn&#8217;t always a magic reason why they happen in a particular moment.&nbsp; And this was &#8212; just felt like the appropriate time for them, for us to engage at that level.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; I have to wrap up in a second here, but go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; You put out a list of all of the military equipment &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; included in that $400 million &#8212; $800 million &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that&#8217;s being provided to Ukraine.&nbsp; Among those items &#8212; let me read them to you: 100 grenade launchers, 5,000 rifles, 1,000 pistols, 400 machine guns, and 400 shotguns.&nbsp; Are you saying those items are not offensive weapons?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They&#8217;re weapons that help the Ukrainian people fight against an invasion by a foreign country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They can be used offensively, can they not?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, they are weapons.&nbsp; What I&#8217;m talking about is weapons that can be used to fight &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The answer is &#8220;yes.&#8221;&nbsp; The answer is &#8220;yes.&#8221;&nbsp; I mean, although you don&#8217;t want to say it, that answer to that question is &#8220;yes.&#8221;&nbsp; And so, obviously, you&#8217;re trying to make this distinction between offensive and defensive weapons &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what we’re talking about &#8212; let me finish.&nbsp; Let me finish.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, let me finish, because I give you my point &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me finish my answer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you make &#8212; no, you weren’t &#8212; no, I was finishing a point, and then you can respond to my point.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; You&#8217;re making this distinction between offensive and defensive weapons.&nbsp; Anybody that looks at that list of weapons that I just mentioned, they would say, clearly, they&#8217;re offensive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If a Ukrainian military officer or someone who is enlisted has one of these weapons, they can take out a Russian military official of some sort with these weapons.&nbsp; They&#8217;re offensive in nature.&nbsp; So, why not provide more offensive weapons like this to the Ukrainian military?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, we are providing a range of rifles, et cetera.&nbsp; There is a difference between a plane and planes and massive military systems &#8212; I think anybody would recognize this &#8212; and what we&#8217;re talking about, which is giving rifles and pistols to many of them farmers and people living in countrysides to defend themselves.&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s a difference that most people recognize.</p>



<p>Thank you, everyone, so much.&nbsp; Have a nice day.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, you promised the back of the room today.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will get to you tomorrow.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I have to wrap up.&nbsp; I apologize.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s going to be another kerfuffle, Jen.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No more kerfuffles!</p>



<p>3:52 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Celebrating the Reauthorization of the Violence Against Women&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/16/remarks-by-president-biden-celebrating-the-reauthorization-of-the-violence-against-women-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 21:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 2:09 P.M. EDT&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Please, thank you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you, thank you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; I should be clapping for all of you.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Zahara, do I have permission to proceed?&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;All right.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Well, first of all, as I was standing there listening, I should say that &#8212; thank all of you,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>2:09 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Please, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I should be clapping for all of you.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Zahara, do I have permission to proceed?<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;All right.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, first of all, as I was standing there listening, I should say that &#8212; thank all of you, everyone in this room.&nbsp; We didn&#8217;t change the law; we set out &#8212; I remember some of you way back when I first wrote this legislation &#8212; to change the culture &#8212; to change the culture.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; For real.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So it&#8217;s great to be with you all.&nbsp; And, Ruth, it’s been an honor to stand with you through these years.&nbsp; And she was a serious victim of violence &#8212; left for dead, basically &#8212; before this law was written.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you make me think of the women who were willing to come and testify before the whole world when I first started those hearings.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t viewed, even among the advocacy groups, as necessarily a particularly positive thing to do.&nbsp; It was &#8212; because &#8212; anyway, you know.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for your courage, for being a hero, sharing your powerful voice, and standing up for thousands of women.&nbsp; And that could be said about most of you in this room.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to thank the members of the Senate and the House, members of my Cabinet for all you&#8217;ve done.&nbsp; The idea that this took five years to reauthorize &#8212; I was out of office those years. &#8212; (laughter and applause) &#8212; and it drove me crazy.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I &#8212; that&#8217;s not why it didn&#8217;t happen, but it drove me crazy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It drove me crazy, the rationale for why we weren&#8217;t &#8212; anyway.&nbsp; I won&#8217;t get into that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I know some of you think maybe I should be out of office for another four years.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the point is, it’s wonderful to see so many brave survivors and dedicated advocates and &#8212; and, truly, old friends &#8212; so many who have worked so hard to modernize the Violence Against Women Act to make it stronger and make sure that it endures.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the reason we’ve been able to do so much, make so much progress in the past 20 years is because of all of you.&nbsp; And I know some of you aren&#8217;t even 28 years old, so it doesn&#8217;t count for you guys.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But all kidding aside, it really does &#8212; again, I keep coming back to you &#8212; you changed the culture, not just the law.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to thank the bipartisan members of Congress who helped get this latest reauthorization done.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Dianne &#8212; Dianne Feinstein, Joni Ernst, Lisa Murkowski.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And in the House &#8212; in the House of Representatives, nobody worked harder than Sheila Jackson Lee, and &#8212; and I thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I learned a long time ago: When Sheila wants something, just say yes.&nbsp; It saves time.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Jerry Nadler, a great friend and a great congressman.&nbsp; And Brian Fitzpatrick &#8212; Brian, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, thank you for coming together and never giving up.&nbsp; You know, the fact is that it really wasn’t so long ago this country didn&#8217;t want to talk about violence against women, let alone as being a national epidemic, something the government had to address.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As a society, we literally looked away.&nbsp; We looked away.&nbsp; In many places, it wasn’t a crime.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t recall &#8212; I don&#8217;t recall how many times I was told in the prelude to writing the legislation that it&#8217;s a &#8220;family affair.&#8221;&nbsp; &#8220;You don&#8217;t understand, Biden.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a family affair.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When I began, along with others, to pursue this legislation to change this &#8212; this issue, we were told that we would literally be responsible for the &#8220;disintegration&#8221; of American families in the major press.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t just the wackos; it was in the mainstream press.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we talked about creating shelters to give survivors a way out because so many don&#8217;t have a way out, and their children &#8212; by the way, the vast majority of children on the street with their mothers are there because she&#8217;s a victim of domestic violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And here&#8217;s what they said, here&#8217;s what they wrote: They said these shelters &#8212; providing shelter was nothing more than &#8220;indoctrination centers&#8221; for women&#8217;s liberation issues.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I can get you the articles.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And calling the police meant having to stand in front of your abuser &#8212; your significant other, your husband, whomever &#8212; and say, &#8220;He did it.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I used to say, when I&#8217;d get heat on this, when I spoke &#8212; I remember making a speech to the Chamber of Commerce, and someone said, &#8220;Well, you&#8217;re going overboard here.&#8221;&nbsp; I said, &#8220;Let me ask you, Jack.&#8221;&nbsp; I said, &#8220;If you had a 320-pound guy who could bench 400 pounds standing in front of you and beat the &#8212; smacked you, are you going to say he did it?&nbsp; Because you know he&#8217;s going to come back.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Looking, few &#8212; there were very few police departments that had trained personnel.&nbsp; I mean very few.&nbsp; I &#8212; I&#8217;m sure there were some, I just can&#8217;t remember any of them.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I really mean it.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as a matter of fact, I can’t &#8212; I don&#8217;t think there were any Special Victims Units in most of the police departments around the country before this legislation was written.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now there&#8217;s programs that are on TV for the last 25, 30 years.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, but I really mean it.&nbsp; It mattered.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I mean about changing the culture.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, and there were too few places you could go for advice or for help.&nbsp; Where would you go?&nbsp; And how many times &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I remember the biggest fights I had were the second time around with universities &#8212; with universities.&nbsp; Where do you show up?&nbsp; Where do you report this?&nbsp; &#8220;Well, we don&#8217;t want to…&#8221;&nbsp; I mean major universities &#8212; not Podunk universities.&nbsp; Major universities.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It took time to change the culture, and you did it.&nbsp; You did it.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There was no national hotline.&nbsp; I remember going &#8212; all kidding aside &#8212; there have been millions of women who&#8217;ve hit that hotline button.&nbsp; You know, all the brave guys I talk to, they say, &#8220;Biden, you&#8217;re overdoing this.&#8221;&nbsp; And I&#8217;d say, &#8220;Tell me &#8212; tell you what: If somebody who was twice your size, beating the living crap out of you and you were in the same apartment with them, how do you go and pick up the phone and call for help?&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Women would hide and say, &#8220;I can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t say where I am.&nbsp; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; Help me.&nbsp; Help me.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we got Microsoft and others in this &#8212; in this fight with us, to help us physically locate so the police could pick up where that call was coming from.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That was the background when I first wrote the Violence Against Women Act in 1990 to provide more protection against domestic violence, stalking, sexual assault; to support survivors and help them find ways out of their abusive situations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They’d say, &#8220;Why didn’t &#8212; why didn’t she leave?&#8221;&nbsp; Well, she didn’t leave.&nbsp; She had no place to go, and she had two kids with her.&nbsp; No money.&nbsp; Nothing.&nbsp; No family to go to.&nbsp; Leave?<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ve been asked, time to time, was there &#8212; the reason, I guess, I got a little overwrought about this legislation early on &#8212; not that I ever get overwrought.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But &#8212; and I &#8212; literally, the most oft-asked questions for the first three years of the act was, &#8220;Well, why are you so passionate about this?&nbsp; Was your mother a victim of domestic violence?&nbsp; Was your sister or your wife?&nbsp; Were they &#8212; were they victims?&#8221;&nbsp; I swear to God.&nbsp; That was the most oft-asked question of me.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;d say, &#8220;No, that&#8217;s not the answer.&#8221;&nbsp; I happened to be raised by a gentle, decent man, who taught all of his children &#8212; and I mean this from the bottom of my heart &#8212; Lisa, you know this; you knew my dad.&nbsp; My dad would say the greatest sin of all that anyone could commit was the abuse of power, and the cardinal sin was for a man to raise his hand to a woman or a child.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s what this law has always been about: the abuse of power.&nbsp; Whether it ends in a rape or just the physical be- &#8212; it&#8217;s about the abuse of power. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I believed, as many of you in this room did, that &#8212; that I believe that too.&nbsp; And the only way we could change the culture was by shining an ugly, bright light on it and speaking its name.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You can make all the speeches you wanted, but until those women had the courage &#8212; and I remember &#8212; I remember in a backroom hold and they said, &#8220;It&#8217;s going to be okay.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be okay.&#8221;&nbsp; Can you imagine being among the first to stand before the whole damn world and millions of people hear you recite how you were abused?<br>&nbsp;<br>It took enormous courage.&nbsp; And at the time, the Majority Leader may remember, we both got criticized for wanting to make it public.&nbsp; &#8220;We don’t want to do that.&nbsp; We don’t want to do that.&#8221;&nbsp; That’s why we held public hearings for this law when there were senators and others who said it was too salacious for this to be public, for people to see.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, we &#8212; but I believed &#8212; and a lot of us did &#8212; that we had to let America know what was going on.&nbsp; Take the blinders off.&nbsp; Make them look at it square in the eye.&nbsp; All the ugly side of it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Because I believed, as all of you did, that Americans are basically decent and honorable people.&nbsp; But they didn’t want to get involved.&nbsp; Didn’t want to get involved.<br>&nbsp;<br>How many times have you been in a crowded airport or in a circumstance where you see a man not physically beating but abusing a woman &#8212; and you just say, &#8220;You know, I don’t want to hear that.&nbsp; I don’t want to &#8212; I don’t know what to do.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, I believe that if they could see the truth as to what was going on, we could begin slowly to make change.&nbsp; And that’s exactly what you all did and that’s what happened.<br>&nbsp;<br>This law broke the dam of congressional resistance and cultural resistance.&nbsp; And it brought this hidden epidemic out of the shadows.&nbsp; You know, its introduction &#8212; it introduced our nation to so many brave survivors who those stories changed the way America saw the issue.&nbsp; I mean, in the literal sense, it&#8217;s hard to believe &#8212; even when I go back and think of when &#8212; how it started and where it was.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As a practical matter, things began to shift &#8212; the legal and social burdens &#8212; away from survivors and onto perpetrators and where they belonged.&nbsp; It made addressing general &#8212; excuse me &#8212; gender violence a shared priority with a determined, coordinated response.&nbsp; It created a hotline, as I said, for millions of women who have used the hotline.&nbsp; And again, I&#8217;ll never forget being told the first time &#8212; I said, &#8220;What did you do?&#8221;&nbsp; She said, &#8220;I got behind the drapes and I held the phone.&nbsp; And I prayed to God &#8212; prayed to God &#8212; don’t let him hear this.&nbsp; Pray God.&nbsp; Pray God.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>It supported shelters and rape crisis centers, housing and legal assistance, creating lifesaving options for women and children all across the country.&nbsp; And it helped train police officers, advocates, prosecutors, judges, court personnel to make the entire justice system fair and more responsive to the needs of survivors.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll never forget, Chris, I went to the family court when I was writing this &#8212; and the family court in my state is like many of yours.&nbsp; And I watched &#8212; because I was told this would happen &#8212; I watched a woman come up to the desk and say, &#8220;I want to report that my husband is beating me up.&#8221;&nbsp; &#8220;Well, why don’t you have a seat over there.&#8221;&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Go back and check your family courts back in the day.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s what happened.&nbsp; &#8220;That’s okay.&nbsp; You go over here.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll get to that.&#8221;&nbsp; &#8220;No, no, I &#8212; I need help now.&nbsp; Now.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, the law has saved lives.&nbsp; It&#8217;s helped women rebuild their lives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The hardest thing to get done was arrest on information.&nbsp; Because what used to happen is a cop may be in the street and see a husband or a boyfriend or a man &#8212; anyone &#8212; smack his wife.&nbsp; And he&#8217;d come over and say, &#8220;Do you want to bring charges?&#8221;&nbsp; What the hell is she going to say? &nbsp;&#8220;Yeah, I want to bring…&#8221;&nbsp; We got the law changed to say the cop can arrest on information.&nbsp; He saw it happen.&nbsp; He saw it happen.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And all of these bad &#8212; these tough guys.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Even in 1994, we knew that there was much more we had to do &#8212; you know, that it was only the beginning.&nbsp; That’s why, because of all of you in this room, every time we’ve reauthorized this law, it&#8217;s been improved.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like we didn’t know we wanted to do these other things in the beginning.&nbsp; It&#8217;s we did as much as we could and keep trying to add to it.&nbsp; You remember.&nbsp; You sat at my desk &#8212; a lot of time with me on this.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Broadening from domestic violence to include stalking and sexual assault in 2000. &nbsp;That was the change made.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Expanding access to services for immigrants and communities of color in 2005. &nbsp;That was a change.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Restoring jurisdiction of Tribal courts &#8212; (applause) &#8212; over non-Native domestic violence offenders who abuse women in Indian Country. &nbsp;We did that in 2013.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Extending protections to everyone, regardless of sexual orientation and gender identity, in 2013.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;m sorry to go on, but you all should &#8212; the country owes you &#8212; all of you.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; The law kept growing stronger.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like we didn’t know in 2005 we should be dealing with the things we dealt with in 2013.&nbsp; It was getting it done.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Each link in the chain that we&#8217;re building made a difference &#8212; makes a difference.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Yesterday, I signed the Bipartisan Government Funding Bill.&nbsp; Thank you very much for that.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And, consequentially, we forged the next link in the chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not only &#8212; not only did we reauthorize the Violence Against Women Act through 2027 &#8212; and I have to wonder why the hell we can’t reauthorize it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s like the Voting Rights Act.&nbsp; I thought we had won when I got Strom Thurmond to vote for it and extend it for 25 years, and then the Court came along.&nbsp; But at any rate, that’s another issue.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>But look, you know, I don&#8217;t &#8212; just think about this.&nbsp; If this affected manhood &#8212; men &#8212; I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;d have a problem, you know, doing it for even longer, making it permanent.&nbsp; But at any rate, that&#8217;s a different thing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, we delivered more help to survivors in rural areas &#8212; we understand &#8212; and in underserved communities for a simple reason: There is no place to go.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, whether it&#8217;s Arizona or whether it&#8217;s Michigan, wherever it is, you&#8217;re in a rural area, you call, you get help, and you do get help, and then they leave.&nbsp; And the next nearest &#8212; and the next nearest town is 20 miles.&nbsp; How long does it take for the cop to get there?<br>&nbsp;<br>Tribal courts will now be able to exercise jurisdiction over non-Native perpetrators of sexual assault, child abuse, sex trafficking, and so much more.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>You have all added new services and resources for folks in most underserved communities &#8212; the LGBTQ community, survivors of those rural communities &#8212; providing more support and legal services, for law enforcement to get training they need to help handle the trauma of &#8212; survivors are experiencing.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, by the way, it&#8217;s not a criticism of the police.&nbsp; We &#8212; for all the mistakes police make and all the things they do wrong &#8212; we expect them to be everything from a counselor to a expert on sexual violence to an expert on all these things.&nbsp; But, you know, these are vast majority people with, you know, degrees that are two-year degrees after school.&nbsp; I mean, they’re the smart, but they &#8212; I mean, we expect them to be psychologists; we expect them to be everything.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we established a new civil rights &#8212; a new civil rights cause of action for those whose intimate images were shared on the public screen.&nbsp; How many times have you heard &#8212; I’ll bet everybody knows somebody somewhere along the line that in an intimate relationship, what happened was the guy takes a revealing picture of his naked friend, or whatever, in a compromising position, and then literally, in a sense, blackmails or mortifies that person &#8212; sends it out, put it online.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re giving survivors real resources against abuse now.&nbsp; Ex-partners and stalkers who seek to humiliate and hurt them.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve created &#8212; you created new programs to help end the backlog of the rape kits.&nbsp; And those rape kits, by the way, I don&#8217;t know &#8212; you ought to go to your major cities, those of you in the House and Senate &#8212; this group probably has &#8212; which I have done.&nbsp; And this backlog is so significant.&nbsp; You could solve literally a significant portion of &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, the only thing I learned that’s worse than &#8212; for a woman &#8212; worse than a woman who is abused or raped and says, “It&#8217;s Charlie who did it,” and no one believes her &#8212; him against her.&nbsp; And when &#8212; you can take a look.&nbsp; If you take a look at those rape kits and you went through them all, you could identify and arrest probably 40, 50 percent of the rapists in America.&nbsp; They&#8217;re all there.&nbsp; Their DNAs are there.&nbsp; It’s all in line.&nbsp; And run it against the whole panoply.&nbsp; Very few rapists rape only once.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, look, that &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a lot that goes unprocessed.&nbsp; And we have to make sure survivors get compensation, and if there have been delays in their cases &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve made improvements in the National Criminal Background Check System to help states investigate and prosecute cases when abuses &#8212; when abusers who are barred from purchasing firearms attempt to do so.&nbsp; That, we’ve done federally.&nbsp; Quite frankly, this held &#8212; that&#8217;s one of the things that held up this bill for much too long.&nbsp; Much too long.<br>&nbsp;<br>Those are just a few of the ways we’ve strengthened &#8212; you, not we &#8212; you’ve strengthened the law.&nbsp; Because I just came on the &#8212; back on the &#8212; on the range again.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I haven’t been &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>But look, it comes on top of the work we&#8217;ve done together over the last years to make progress.&nbsp; We know the pandemic only exacerbated instances of domestic violence and sexual violence.&nbsp; It&#8217;s shot up like a Roman candle.<br>&nbsp;<br>And through the American Rescue Plan, the administration<br>directed $1 billion in supplemental funding for domestic violence and sexual assault services &#8212; (applause) &#8212; because they’re badly needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’ve worked with local public housing authorities to make sure that survivors trapped in a bad situation can find safe new housing options in public housing.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Because they don’t have (inaudible) to go.&nbsp; You.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we also made landmark reforms in military justice to help end the epidemic of sexual violence and harassment in our armed forces &#8212; (applause) &#8212; fundamentally changing how the military investigates, prosecutes sexual assault, domestic violence, and other related crimes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you, Kirsten Gillibrand.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, Jackie Speier.&nbsp; Is Jackie here?&nbsp; Stand up, please.&nbsp; Stand up.&nbsp; You did an incredible job.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Earlier this month, I signed a bar- &#8212; bipartisan bill that ends what we know as forced arbitration.&nbsp; That&#8217;s wonderful, isn’t it?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, no, but I mean the small print to sign a contract, and the small print says you can&#8217;t do anything if your boss, male or female &#8212; if you end up getting abused and if you end up doing something &#8212; you know, you can&#8217;t &#8212; you have to do it internally.&nbsp; No more.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No more.&nbsp; Really.<br>&nbsp;<br>And 80 percent of the people who sign those don&#8217;t even know what&#8217;s in the &#8212; in the contract.<br>&nbsp;<br>The mechanism has prevented too many survivors of abuse and harassment in the workplace from having the choice to get their day in court.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, these are just a few of the steps you&#8217;ve all taken and how much you&#8217;ve improved this legislation.&nbsp; But as everyone in this room knows, this work is not going to stop.&nbsp; It never stops.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, one year since a gunman killed eight people in Atlanta, six of whom were women of Asian descent, these horrific murders are a reminder that we still have work to do to put an end to misogyny and racism and all forms of hate we have.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re never going to get it all done, but we can&#8217;t ever stop trying.&nbsp; As long as there are women in this country and around the world who live in fear of violence, there&#8217;s more we have to do to fulfill this sacred commitment.&nbsp; No one &#8212; no one, regardless of gender or sexual orientation, should experience abuse.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; And if they do, they should have the services and support they need to get through it.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re not going to rest.<br>&nbsp;<br>But in the meantime, all of you should be enormously proud of what you&#8217;ve accomplished.&nbsp; This reauthorization is testament to the power of your voices and your tireless dedication to changing things for the better.<br>&nbsp;<br>And one last thing: Some of you in here helped me work on the International Violence Against Women Act.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m coming back.&nbsp; Seriously.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;ll tell you a very short concluding story.<br>&nbsp;<br>When I was Vice President &#8212; I can&#8217;t remember, probably the seventh year in or thereabouts &#8212; I was in India, and I met &#8212; at the home where Mahatma Gandhi was able to be hidden for a long while.&nbsp; And &#8212; and &#8212; and I met with two of the daughters of India&#8217;s most serious liberators.&nbsp; And, you know, I thought they were going to ask me questions about, you know, U.S.-India relations.&nbsp; They said, “Can you help us write a Violence Against Women Act?”&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Just by some of you speaking out &#8212; Republicans and Democrats &#8212; just by your speaking out about how we abhor those nations that do, in fact, call for &#8212; and go through the list &#8212; it’s changing behaviors.&nbsp; I think we have to even be stronger than that, but that’s another &#8212; that’s another boring speech.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>But, look, let’s keep going.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; May God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>2:34 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s call with National Security Advisor Thanos Dokos of&#160;Greece</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-national-security-advisor-thanos-dokos-of-greece/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 20:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Dr. Thanos Dokos, National Security Advisor of Greece.  Mr. Sullivan underscored the strength of our bilateral cooperation and welcomed ongoing efforts to expand and deepen our diplomatic, economic, and defense partnerships.  Mr. Sullivan and Dr. Dokos discussed Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified aggression against Ukraine, including the ethnic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Dr. Thanos Dokos, National Security Advisor of Greece.  Mr. Sullivan underscored the strength of our bilateral cooperation and welcomed ongoing efforts to expand and deepen our diplomatic, economic, and defense partnerships.  Mr. Sullivan and Dr. Dokos discussed Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified aggression against Ukraine, including the ethnic Greek community based in Mariupol.  They reiterated their commitment to international efforts to hold Moscow to account for its actions and to ensure Ukraine has the ability to defend itself.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Assistance the United&#160;States is Providing to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/16/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-assistance-the-united-states-is-providing-to-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 20:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 1:01 P.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; I want to begin by thanking President Zelenskyy for his passionate message this morning.&#160; I listened to it in the private residence, and he was convincing.&#160; And &#8212; significant speech. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; He speaks for a people who have shown remarkable courage&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>1:01 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; I want to begin by thanking President Zelenskyy for his passionate message this morning.&nbsp; I listened to it in the private residence, and he was convincing.&nbsp; And &#8212; significant speech.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He speaks for a people who have shown remarkable courage and strength in the face of brutal aggression &#8212; courage and strength that has inspired not only Ukrainians but the entire world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Putin is inflicting appalling &#8212; appalling devastation and horror on Ukraine &#8212; bombing apartment buildings, maternity wards, hospitals.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, it’s &#8212; it’s God awful.&nbsp; I was speaking about this with the &#8212; our &#8212; our Commander, behind me here &#8212; General Milley.&nbsp; I mean, it just is amazing.</p>



<p>Yesterday, we saw reports that Russian forces were holding hundreds of doctors and patients hostage in the largest hospital in Mariupol.&nbsp; These are atrocities.&nbsp; They’re an outrage to the world.&nbsp; And the world is united in our support for Ukraine and our determination to make Putin pay a very heavy price.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; America is leading this effort, together with our Allies and partners, providing enormous levels of security and humanitarian assistance that we’re adding to today and we’re going to continue to do more in the days and weeks ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are crippling Putin’s economy with punishing sanctions that’s going to only grow more painful over time with the entire NATO and EU behind us, and many other countries.</p>



<p>What’s at stake here are the principles that the United States and the united nations across the world stand for.&nbsp; It’s about freedom.&nbsp; It’s about the right of people to determine their own future.&nbsp; It’s about making sure Ukraine never &#8212; will never be a victory for Putin, no matter what advances he makes on the battlefield.</p>



<p>The American people are answering President Zelenskyy’s call for more help, more weapons for Ukraine to defend itself, more tools to fight Russian aggression.&nbsp; And that’s what we’re doing.</p>



<p><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In fact, we started our assistance to Ukraine before this war began, as they started to do exercises along the Ukrainian border &#8212; the Russians &#8212; starting in March of last year.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We took the threat of Putin invading very seriously, and we acted on it.&nbsp; We sent Ukraine more security assistance last year &#8212; $650 million in weapons, including anti-air and anti-armor equipment before the invasion &#8212; more than we had ever provided before.&nbsp; So when the invasion began, they already had in their hands the kinds of weapons they needed to counter Russian advances.</p>



<p>And once the war started, we immediately rushed $350 million in additional aid to further address their needs: hundreds of anti-air systems, thousands of anti-tank weapons, transport helicopters, armed patrol boats, and other high-mobility vehicles, radar systems that help track incoming artillery and unmanned drones, secure communications equipment and tactical gear, satellite imagery and &#8212; and analysis capacity.&nbsp; And it’s clearly helped Ukraine inflict dramatic losses on Russian forces.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Saturday, my administration authorized another $200 million to keep a steady flow of weapons and ammunition moving to Ukraine.&nbsp; Now I’m once again using my presidential authority to activate &#8212; to activate additional security assistance to continue to help Ukraine fend off Russia’s assault &#8212; an additional $800 million in assistance.&nbsp;&nbsp;That brings the total of new U.S. security assistance to Ukraine to $1 billion just this week.&nbsp; These are the lar- &#8212; these are direct transfers of equipment from our Department of Defense to the Ukrainian military to help them as they fight against this invasion.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I thank the Congress for appropriating these funds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This new package on its own is going to provide unprecedented assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; It includes 800 anti-aircraft systems to make sure the Ukrainian military can continue to &#8212; can continue to stop the planes and helicopters that have been attacking their people and to defend their Ukrainian airspace.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And at the request of President Zelenskyy, we have identified and are helping Ukraine acquire additional longer-range anti-aircraft systems and the munitions for those systems.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our new assistance package also includes 9,000 anti-armor systems.&nbsp; These are portable, high &#8212; high-accurate &#8212; high accurately &#8212; high-accuracy shoulder-mounted missiles that the Ukrainian forces have been using with great effect to destroy invading tanks and armored vehicles.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’ll include 7,000 small arms &#8212; machine guns, shotguns, grenade launchers &#8212; to equip the Ukrainians, including the brave women and men who are defending their cities as civilians, and they’re on the countryside as well.&nbsp; And we’re &#8212; and we &#8212; and as well as the ammunition, artillery, and mortar rounds to go with small arms &#8212; 20 million rounds in total.&nbsp; Twenty million rounds.&nbsp; And this will include drones, which &#8212; which demonstrates our commitment to sending our most cutting-edge systems to Ukraine for its defense.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’re not doing this alone.&nbsp; Our Allies and partners have stepped up to provide significant shipments of security assistance and will continue to help facilitate these deliveries as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States and our Allies and partners are fully committed to surging weapons of assistance to the Ukrainians.&nbsp;&nbsp;And more will be coming as we source additional stocks of equipment that are &#8212; that we’re ready to transfer.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now &#8212; now, I want to be honest with you: This could be a long and difficult battle.&nbsp; But the American people will be steadfast in our support of the people of Ukraine in the face of Putin’s immoral, unethical attacks on civilian populations.&nbsp; We are united in our abhorrence of Putin’s depraved onslaught, and we’re going to continue to have their back as they fight for their freedom, their democracy, their very survival.&nbsp; And we’re going to give Ukraine the arms to fight and defend themselves through all the difficult days ahead.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to continue to mobilize humanitarian relief to support people within Ukraine and those who have been forced to flee Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In just the past few weeks, we’ve provided $300 million in humanitarian assistance to the people in Ukraine and in neighboring countries.&nbsp; Tens of thousands of tons of food, water, medicine, and other basic supplies to support the people in need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our experts on the ground in Poland and Moldova and other neighboring countries are there to make real-time assessments of the rapidly evolving crisis and get urgently needed humanitarian supplies to the people in need when they need it.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will support Ukraine’s economy with direct financial assistance as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And together with our Allies and partners, we will keep up the pressure on Putin’s crumbling economy, isolating him on the global stage.&nbsp; That’s our goal: make Putin pay the price, weaken his position while strengthening the hand of the Ukrainians on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together with our Allies and partners, we&#8217;re going to stay the course.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll do everything we can to push for and end this tragic, unnecessary war.&nbsp; This is a struggle that pits the appetites of an autocrat against humankind’s desire to be free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And let there be no doubt, no uncertainty, no question:&nbsp;America stands with the forces of freedom.&nbsp; We always have and we always will.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank you all.&nbsp; And God bless you.&nbsp; And now I&#8217;m going to walk over and sign this legisla- &#8212; sign this bill to allow the drawdown of those materials.</p>



<p>And may God protect the young Ukrainians who are out there defending their country.</p>



<p>What I&#8217;m signing here is the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961.&nbsp; Translated into plain English: a total of $800 million in defense articles.</p>



<p>(The Delegation of Authority is signed.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what will it take for you to send the Polish MiGs that President Zelenskyy is asking for?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to comment on that right now.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to comment on anything other than what I told you (inaudible).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;1:10 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 552(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/16/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-552c2-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 17:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 552(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United&#160;States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the Secretary of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 552(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section 552(c)(2) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $10&nbsp;million in commodities and services from the inventory and resources of any agency of the United States Government to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet:  Reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act&#160;(VAWA)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/fact-sheet-reauthorization-of-the-violence-against-women-act-vawa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, President Biden signed into law the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022, bipartisan legislation passed by Congress as part of the Omnibus appropriations package. One of the driving forces of President Biden’s career has been fighting back against abuses of power.&#160; That force led him to write and champion the groundbreaking&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, President Biden signed into law the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022, bipartisan legislation passed by Congress as part of the Omnibus appropriations package.</p>



<p>One of the driving forces of President Biden’s career has been fighting back against abuses of power.&nbsp; That force led him to write and champion the groundbreaking Violence Against Women Act (VAWA) as a U.S. Senator, landmark legislation that first passed in 1994.&nbsp; In the nearly three decades since, he has worked with Members of Congress from both parties to pass legislation to renew and strengthen VAWA three times: in 2000, 2005, and 2013. &nbsp;Each time, he worked to expand access to safety and support for all survivors and increase prevention efforts.&nbsp; Preventing and responding to gender-based violence wherever it occurs, and in all of its forms, has remained a cornerstone of the President’s career in public service—from VAWA reauthorization to a national campaign to combat campus sexual assault to reforms to address sexual assault and harassment in the military. &nbsp;</p>



<p>While incidents of domestic violence and sexual assault have declined significantly since VAWA first took effect—and efforts to increase access to services, healing, and justice for survivors have improved with each iteration of VAWA—much work remains.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The 2022 reauthorization of VAWA strengthens this landmark law, including by:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Reauthorizing all current VAWA grant programs until 2027 and, in many cases, increasing authorization levels.&nbsp;</li><li>Expanding special criminal jurisdiction of Tribal courts to cover non-Native perpetrators of sexual assault, child abuse, stalking, sex trafficking, and assaults on tribal law enforcement officers on tribal lands; and supporting the development of a pilot project to enhance access to safety for survivors in Alaska Native villages.</li><li>Increasing services and support for survivors from underserved and marginalized communities—including for LGBTQ+ survivors of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault and stalking; funding survivor-centered, community-based restorative practice services; and increasing support for culturally specific services and services in rural communities.</li><li>Establishing a federal civil cause of action for individuals whose intimate visual images are disclosed without their consent, allowing a victim to recover damages and legal fees; creating a new National Resource Center on Cybercrimes Against Individuals; and supporting State, Tribal, and local government efforts to prevent and prosecute cybercrimes, including cyberstalking and the nonconsensual distribution of intimate images.</li><li>Improving prevention and response to sexual violence, including through increased support for the Rape Prevention and Education Program and Sexual Assault Services Program; expansion of prevention education for students in institutions of higher education; and enactment of the Fairness for Rape Kit Backlog Survivors Act, which requires state victim compensation programs to allow sexual assault survivors to file for compensation without being unfairly penalized due to rape kit backlogs.</li><li>Strengthening the application of evidence-based practices by law enforcement in responding to gender-based violence, including by promoting the use of trauma-informed, victim-centered training and improving homicide reduction initiatives.</li><li>Improving the healthcare system’s response to domestic violence and sexual assault, including through enhanced training for sexual assault forensic examiners.</li><li>Updating the SMART Prevention Program and the CHOOSE Youth Program to reduce dating violence, help children who have been exposed to domestic violence, and engage men in preventing violence.</li><li>Enacting the National Instant Criminal Background Check System (NICS) Denial Notification Act to help state law enforcement investigate and prosecute cases against individuals legally prohibited from purchasing firearms who try to do so.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Over the past year, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken significant steps to prevent and respond to gender-based violence at home and abroad:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Increased funding for domestic violence and sexual assault services.&nbsp; </strong>Directed&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/10/25/hhs-announces-nearly-800-million-american-rescue-plan-funds-support-domestic-violence-sexual-assault-survivors-their-children.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$1 billion in supplemental funding</a>&nbsp;for&nbsp;domestic violence and sexual assault services&nbsp;through the American Rescue Plan (ARP) in response to the pandemic, including&nbsp;<a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/fysb/grant-funding/2021-fvpsa-american-rescue-plan-culturally-specific-program-instruction-guidance" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$49.5 million for culturally-specific community-based organizations</a>&nbsp;that help survivors from historically marginalized communities access the services and support they need. The ARP also provided approximately 70,000 housing choice vouchers to local Public Housing Authorities in order to assist individuals and families, including those who are fleeing, or attempting to flee, from domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, stalking, or human trafficking.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Reformed the military justice system to address sexual assault, harassment, and related crimes. </strong>Signed into law&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/27/statement-by-the-president-on-s-1605-the-national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2022/">National Defense Authorization Act</a>, which included&nbsp;sweeping reforms to the military justice system—the most significant since the Uniform Code of Military Justice was established more than seventy years ago—and implemented the President’s campaign promise to address the scourge of sexual assault in our armed forces.&nbsp;In conjunction with the President’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/01/26/executive-order-on-2022-amendments-to-the-manual-for-courts-martial-united-states/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;on military justice reform, this bipartisan, historic law adopts core recommendations of&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-results-of-the-independent-review-commission-on-military-sexual-assault/">Independent Review Commission on Sexual Assault</a>, as called for by President Biden, and fundamentally shifts how the military prosecutes and investigates sexual assault, domestic violence, sexual harassment, and other serious crimes, and increases prevention initiatives and support for survivors.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Ended forced arbitration for sexual assault and harassment.&nbsp; </strong>Signed into law the&nbsp;Ending Forced Arbitration of Sexual Assault and Sexual Harassment Act&nbsp;of 2021—bipartisan legislation that empowers survivors of sexual assault and harassment by giving them a choice to go to court instead of being forced into arbitration.</li><li><strong>Directed action to protect students from campus sexual assault.&nbsp; </strong>Directed the Department of Education to&nbsp;review Title IX regulations&nbsp;and other agency actions to ensure that all students have an educational environment that is free from discrimination on the basis of sex. &nbsp;The Department is developing a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking currently under review that will address the need for protection for students who experience campus sexual assault while treating all students fairly.</li><li><strong>Increased resources for survivors of crime, including gender-based violence.&nbsp; </strong>Signed into law the&nbsp;Amendments to the Victims of Crime Act&nbsp;(VOCA), which passed Congress with strong bipartisan support and expands the allocation of resources for the Crime Victims Fund. This has already resulted in an increase of hundreds of millions of dollars of non-taxpayer funding for essential and lifesaving services to crime victims around the country, including survivors of gender-based violence.</li><li><strong>Led multinational effort to address online harassment and abuse.&nbsp; </strong>Launched the Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse during the 2022 meeting of the United Nations Commission on the Status of Women, together with the governments of Denmark, Australia, the United Kingdom, and Sweden. This multinational initiative will align countries, international organizations, and civil society to better prioritize, understand, and address the growing scourge of technology-facilitated gender-based violence.</li><li><strong>Prioritized the crisis of Missing or Murdered Indigenous People, including gender-based violence.</strong> &nbsp;Issued an executive order directing the Departments of Justice, Interior, Homeland Security and Health and Human Services to create a strategy to improve public safety and justice for Native Americans and to address the epidemic of missing or murdered Indigenous peoples, which disproportionately affect Native women, girls, and LGBTQI+ individuals; the Department of the Interior established the Missing and Murdered Unit to pursue justice for missing or murdered American Indians and Alaska Natives.</li><li><strong>Strengthened regional leadership on violence against Indigenous women and girls.&nbsp; </strong>Re-launched the United States’ leadership and participation in the&nbsp;Trilateral Working Group on Violence Against Indigenous Women and Girls&nbsp;with the Governments of Mexico and Canada. The White House will host the Fourth Convening of the Trilateral Working Group this summer to improve and reaffirm our respective national and regional commitments to prevent and respond to violence against Indigenous women and girls through increased access to justice and prevention services.</li></ul>



<p>On International Women’s Day in 2021, President Biden signed an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/08/executive-order-on-establishment-of-the-white-house-gender-policy-council/">Executive Order</a> creating the White House Gender Policy Council and calling for the development of the first-ever government-wide National Action Plan to End Gender-Based Violence, as well as an update to the 2016 United States Strategy to Prevent and Respond to Gender-Based Violence Globally. These strategies will provide a roadmap to guide the Biden-Harris Administration’s whole-of-government effort to end gender-based violence—and in so doing, create a society where survivors are supported and all people can live free from abuse.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/16/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 17:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United&#160;States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the Secretary of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&nbsp;1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section 506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $800 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet on U.S. Security Assistance for&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/fact-sheet-on-u-s-security-assistance-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 17:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden today announced an additional $800 million in security assistance to Ukraine, bringing the total U.S. security assistance committed to Ukraine to $1 billion in just the past week, and a total of $2 billion since the start of the Biden Administration. The assistance will take the form of direct transfers of equipment from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden today announced an additional $800 million in security assistance to Ukraine, bringing the total U.S. security assistance committed to Ukraine to $1 billion in just the past week, and a total of $2 billion since the start of the Biden Administration. The assistance will take the form of direct transfers of equipment from the Department of Defense to the Ukrainian military to help them defend their country against Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.<br><br>The new $800 million assistance package includes:</p>



<ul><li>800 Stinger anti-aircraft systems;</li><li>2,000 Javelin, 1,000 light anti-armor weapons, and 6,000 AT-4 anti-armor systems;</li><li>100 Tactical Unmanned Aerial Systems;</li><li>100 grenade launchers, 5,000 rifles, 1,000 pistols, 400 machine guns, and 400 shotguns;</li><li>Over 20 million rounds of small arms ammunition and grenade launcher and mortar rounds;</li><li>25,000 sets of body armor; and</li><li>25,000 helmets.</li></ul>



<p>In addition to the weapons listed above, previous United States assistance committed to Ukraine includes:</p>



<ul><li>Over 600 Stinger anti-aircraft systems;</li><li>Approximately 2,600 Javelin anti-armor systems;</li><li>Five Mi-17 helicopters;</li><li>Three patrol boats;</li><li>Four counter-artillery and counter-unmanned aerial system tracking radars;</li><li>Four counter-mortar radar systems;</li><li>200 grenade launchers and ammunition;</li><li>200 shotguns and 200 machine guns;</li><li>Nearly 40 million rounds of small arms ammunition and over 1 million grenade, mortar, and artillery rounds;</li><li>70 High Mobility Multipurpose Wheeled Vehicles (HMMWVs) and other vehicles;</li><li>Secure communications, electronic warfare detection systems, body armor, helmets, and other tactical gear;</li><li>Military medical equipment to support treatment and combat evacuation;</li><li>Explosive ordnance disposal and demining equipment; and</li><li>Satellite imagery and analysis capability.</li></ul>



<p>In addition to the U.S.-produced short-range air defense systems the Ukrainians have been using to great effect, the United States has also identified and is helping the Ukrainians acquire additional, longer-range systems on which Ukraine’s forces are already trained, as well as additional munitions for those systems.</p>



<p>The United States continues to expedite the authorization and facilitation of additional assistance to Ukraine from our Allies. At least 30 countries have provided security assistance to Ukraine since the Russian invasion began. In 2022, the Department of State authorized third-party transfers of defensive equipment from more than 14 countries, a number that continues to grow as Allies and Partners increase support to Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Nikolay Patrushev, Secretary of the Russian Security&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-nikolay-patrushev-secretary-of-the-russian-security-council-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 14:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with General Nikolay Patrushev, Secretary of the Russian Security Council, to reiterate the United States’ firm and clear opposition to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. Mr. Sullivan clearly laid out the United States’ commitment to continue imposing costs on Russia, to support the defense of Ukraine’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with General Nikolay Patrushev, Secretary of the Russian Security Council, to reiterate the United States’ firm and clear opposition to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. Mr. Sullivan clearly laid out the United States’ commitment to continue imposing costs on Russia, to support the defense of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and to reinforce NATO’s eastern flank, in continued full coordination with our Allies and partners.&nbsp;Mr. Sullivan told General Patrushev that if Russia is serious about diplomacy then Moscow should stop attacking Ukrainian cities and towns. Mr. Sullivan also warned General Patrushev about the consequences and implications of any possible Russian decision to use chemical or biological weapons in Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces Resources for Historically Black Colleges and Universities that Have Recently Experienced Bomb&#160;Threats</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-resources-for-historically-black-colleges-and-universities-that-have-recently-experienced-bomb-threats/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 12:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris To Make Announcement During White House Event March 16th, 2022 In the last three months, more than one-third of our country’s Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) have received bomb threats. While, thankfully, no explosive devices were found on any of these campuses, significant and lasting damage has been done by threatening the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Harris To Make Announcement During White House Event</em> <em>March 16<sup>th</sup>, 2022</em></p>



<p>In the last three months, more than one-third of our country’s Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) have received bomb threats. While, thankfully, no explosive devices were found on any of these campuses, significant and lasting damage has been done by threatening the safety and security of the students, faculty, and staff at these institutions. As a result of these threats, learning has been disrupted, critical resources have been diverted to emergency response, and there has been an increased burden on already overwhelmed campus mental health systems. HBCU students – already experiencing negative impacts from the pandemic such as lingering effects of illness, trauma, and basic needs insecurities – are now experiencing additional stress and anxiety because of these bomb threats that can negatively affect their academic success.</p>



<p>It is important to view these recent and repeated threats through both the lens of the present day as well as our country’s history. HBCUs were founded to educate Black people in an America that refused to accept them as full human beings and prevented them – because of racial discrimination – from attending other colleges. Threats to the education and well-being of Black Americans and HBCUs are an unfortunate part of American history. The bomb threats that we witnessed in January, each week in February – Black History Month, and this month are reminiscent of the attempts during the Civil Rights Era to intimidate and provoke fear in Black Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is taking a whole-of-government approach in responding to these threats and ensuring the safety and well-being of students, staff, and faculty. Immediately following the first reports of the threats, Education Secretary Cardona and Homeland Security Secretary Mayorkas hosted a briefing with more than 40 presidents of HBCUs from across the nation to share information on grant programs, training resources, and other tools available to HBCUs to strengthen campus safety and security. Leaders from the Department of Education (ED) and other federal agencies have visited HBCU campuses. During these visits, federal officials heard firsthand about the need to modernize and update their operations, including campus safety and security, as well as the need for more resources to help bolster mental health services due to increased apprehension across the campus community.</p>



<p>Today, in response to these needs, Vice President Kamala Harris is announcing that HBCUs that have recently experienced a bomb threat resulting in a disruption to the campus learning environment are eligible for grant funds. These grant funds are from the Project School Emergency Response to Violence (Project SERV) program at ED. Project SERV provides short-term, immediate funding for local educational agencies and institutions of higher education that have experienced a violent or traumatic incident to assist in restoring a safe environment conducive to learning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ED will work with the HBCUs that have received recent bomb threats to determine if Project SERV can help get funds to their campuses for immediate needs, such as targeted mental health resources or enhanced security, to restore the learning environment on their campuses. ED is able to provide this funding to HBCUs to ensure students feel safe on their campuses. ED staff will work with each HBCU to help determine their specific immediate needs. Awards typically range from $50,000 to $150,000 per school.</p>



<p>In addition to the short-term funds provided through Project SERV, the Biden-Harris Administration is providing HBCUs a compendium of resources that are available across the federal government – from ED, Department of Health and Human Services, Department of Homeland Security, and Department of Justice – to help with long-term improvements to campus mental health programs, campus safety, and emergency management planning and response. The resource guide offers a centralized source of information on grant programs and technical assistance activities across federal agencies.</p>



<p>These announcements today build off the historic investments and support the Biden-Harris Administration has already delivered to HBCUs – $5.8 billion in total to date, including more than $2.7 billion in American Rescue Plan funding – to ameliorate chronic underfunding and help address critical needs brought on by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Educational opportunity is a fundamental element of the American promise and HBCUs have played an outsized role in securing that opportunity for Black people. As President Biden indicated in Executive Order 14041 – which re-established the White House Initiative on HBCUs – HBCUs have a proud history and legacy of achievement. That legacy continues, with more than 100 HBCUs, located in 19 states, the District of Columbia, and the U.S. Virgin Islands that serve nearly 300,000 students annually. These storied institutions have excelled, in the face of discrimination, and their strength and convictions will not be compromised by these violent bomb threats.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
