<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 01:07:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Joey and Paula&#160;Reed</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-president-bidens-meeting-with-joey-and-paula-reed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 01:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met today with Joey and Paula Reed, the parents of Trevor Reed, who is wrongfully detained in Russia. During their meeting, the President reiterated his commitment to continue to work to secure the release of Trevor, Paul Whelan, and other Americans wrongfully held in Russia and elsewhere, and to provide all possible assistance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met today with Joey and Paula Reed, the parents of Trevor Reed, who is wrongfully detained in Russia. During their meeting, the President reiterated his commitment to continue to work to secure the release of Trevor, Paul Whelan, and other Americans wrongfully held in Russia and elsewhere, and to provide all possible assistance until they and others are free and returned home to their families who are advocating so passionately for their release. This is the President’s second interaction with the Reeds. On March 8, President Biden spoke to the Reeds by phone while he was in Texas.</p>



<p>The President’s national security team will remain in regular contact with the Reeds, the Whelan family, and other families of Americans held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad. We are grateful for their partnership and feedback. We will continue to work to ensure we are communicating and sharing information in a way useful to these families.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Previously, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with the Reed family in a virtual group meeting and then privately in December. He expressed our commitment to bringing Trevor home. We understand the pain felt by all of Trevor’s families and friends enduring the nightmare of his absence, which we are committed to bringing to an end.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress, on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Somalia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-somalia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&#160;U.S.C.&#160;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&#160;a&#160;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&#160;the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C.&nbsp;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&nbsp;a&nbsp;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&nbsp;the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date. &nbsp;In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13536 of April&nbsp;12, 2010, with respect to Somalia is to&nbsp;continue in effect beyond April 12, 2022.</p>



<p>     The situation with respect to Somalia continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.  Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13536 with respect to Somalia.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency With Respect to&#160;Somalia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-somalia-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:09:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 12, 2010, by Executive Order&#160;13536, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the deterioration of the security situation and the persistence of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On April 12, 2010, by Executive Order&nbsp;13536, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the deterioration of the security situation and the persistence of violence in Somalia; acts of piracy and armed robbery at sea off&nbsp;the coast of Somalia, which have been the subject of United&nbsp;Nations Security Council resolutions; and violations of the arms embargo imposed by the United Nations Security Council.</p>



<p>On July 20, 2012, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13620 to take additional steps to deal with the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13536 in view of United&nbsp;Nations Security Council Resolution 2036 of February&nbsp;22, 2012, and Resolution 2002 of July&nbsp;29, 2011, and to address: &nbsp;exports of charcoal from Somalia, which generate significant revenue for al-Shabaab; the misappropriation of Somali public assets; and certain acts of violence committed against civilians in Somalia, all of which contribute to the deterioration of the security situation and the persistence of violence in Somalia.</p>



<p>The situation with respect to Somalia continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on April 12, 2010, and the measures adopted on that date and on July 20, 2012, to deal with that threat, must continue in effect beyond April 12, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1&nbsp;year the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13536.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"><br>                                JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">&nbsp;<br><br>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Communications Director Kate&#160;Bedingfield</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/press-briefing-by-communications-director-kate-bedingfield/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:40&#160;P.M. EDT&#160; MS.&#160;BEDINGFIELD:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good afternoon. MS.&#160;BEDINGFIELD:&#160; Thanks for having me back.&#160; So I have a little bit I’d like to do at the top here and then &#8212; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Do we get to vote on who we’d prefer?&#160; (Laughter.) MS.&#160;BEDINGFIELD:&#160; I’m not going to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:40&nbsp;P.M. EDT&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Thanks for having me back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I have a little bit I’d like to do at the top here and then &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do we get to vote on who we’d prefer?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I’m not going to take that personally.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I thought that’s what you were saying.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Thank you so much for &#8212; thank you so much for that.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>So I have a little bit at the top, and then I’m, of course, happy to take your questions.</p>



<p>So, as the President remains focused on lowering costs for American families, we have a number of announcements today that will help households save money on utility bills.</p>



<p>First, the Department of Energy announced over $3 billion from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is now available through the Weatherization Assistance Program for states and territories to retrofit households, make homes more energy efficient, and save families money.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President’s Infrastructure Law increased this program’s resources ten-fold, which means more homeowners will be able to improve insulation, upgrade lighting and appliances, and electrify heating and cooling systems &#8212; all of which save families hundreds of dollars per year while making homes more resilient to climate change and extreme temperatures.</p>



<p>Second, the Department of Energy is proposing new energy-saving standards for household appliances and equipment as part of a roadmap to complete 100 actions this year that would save families more than $100 annually on their utility bills.&nbsp; And that’s actually a very conservative estimate &#8212; $100 annually on their utility bills.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To give one example of the impacts, U.S. households buy over 7 million room air conditioners ever year, and today we’re proposing a new efficiency standard that would save consumers up to $275 over the life of the product.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Energy also announced new codes that will make federal buildings more energy efficient, reduce operating costs, and ensure we are good stewards of taxpayer dollars.</p>



<p>Together, these efforts can save more than $15 billion in net costs, reduce greenhouse gas emissions, and advance environmental justice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From implementing his Infrastructure Law to updating important standards, these actions show the President following through on his mission to lower costs for working families and help them save money each month on their energy bills.</p>



<p>And then secondly, I’d like to say: Yesterday, the full Senate took its first vote on the nomination of Lisa Cook &#8212; an important step forward toward confirming her and our other qualified nominees for the Federal Reserve.</p>



<p>We need to confirm Dr. Cook, along with the other three qualified nominees &#8212; Jerome Powell for Chair, Lael Brainard for Vice Chair, and Philip Jefferson for a seat on the Board of Governors &#8212; so that the Federal Reserve can move ahead in its work to help address inflation.</p>



<p>We call on senators on both sides of the aisle to support these nominees because they are eminently qualified to serve.&nbsp; This is important, and we hope the Senate can get it done soon so they can get to work.</p>



<p>So, thank you very much.&nbsp; And with that, AP.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; AP is reporting plans by the administration to end Title 42 by May 23rd.&nbsp; Is the Biden administration prepared to deal with the aftermath of ending Title 42 and the expected influx of migrants?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, first, what I would say is that this is a decision that we have long deferred to CDC.&nbsp; Title 42 is a public health directive; it is not an immigration or migration enforcement measure.&nbsp; So the decision on when to lift Title 42 we defer to the CDC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That being said, of course we are planning for multiple contingencies, and we have every expectation that when the CDC ultimately decides it&#8217;s appropriate to lift Title 42, there will be an influx of people to the border.&nbsp; And so, we are doing a lot of work to plan for that contingency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think you saw yesterday the Department of Homeland Security did a briefing walking through some of the planning that they&#8217;re doing to increase efficiency, to ensure that we have the capacity, to ensure that we are operating in a way that&#8217;s &#8212; that is treating migrants humanely, fairly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So you heard from them yesterday on some of the planning that they&#8217;re doing more broadly &#8212; now, not specifically tied to Title 42 or an ultimate decision to lift it, but just more broadly to the work that they&#8217;re doing to continue to build up our migration system and ensure that we are restoring order at the border.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then secondly, if Putin has bad information, per declassified U.S. intelligence, what does that mean for the war in Ukraine and the prospects for negotiations right now?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I certainly am not a spokesperson for the Kremlin and cannot speak to what is in Vladimir Putin&#8217;s head.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I can say is, of course, we have information that Putin felt misled by the Russian military, which has resulted in persistent tension between Putin and his military leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We believe that Putin is being misinformed by his advisors about how badly the Russian military is performing and how the Russian economy is being crippled by sanctions because his senior advisors are too afraid to tell him the truth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it is increasingly clear that Putin’s war has been a strategic blunder that has left Russia weaker over the long term and increasingly isolated on the world stage.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On that &#8212; I mean, in the lead up to Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine, the administration declassified information like this to sort of lay out what Putin’s intentions were.&nbsp; You seem to be doing that again now by making it clear that he&#8217;s being misled by his advisors.&nbsp; Can you just discuss what&#8217;s the hope and the goal in going public with this now?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, again, I think what this does is paint a picture of what a strategic error Putin and Russia have made here.&nbsp; We saw from the outset that they, for example, made a aggressive push toward Kyiv at the beginning of the invasion.&nbsp; They are now publicly trying to redefine the goals of their invasion to be &#8212; to be different than they were at the outset.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think putting forward this information simply contributes to a sense that this has been a strategic error for them.&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to characterize, you know, what they are thinking.&nbsp; I&#8217;m certainly not going to characterize how they may or may not use this information to make decisions.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not my place.&nbsp; But I do think that making this information public contributes to an understanding that this has been a strategic failure for Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, we will continue to pursue our strategy of imposing severe costs on Russia and trying to strengthen Ukraine on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if Putin is being misinformed like this, then who is really pulling the strings here?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a question that I&#8217;m able to speak to from this podium.&nbsp; I think this is a &#8212; again, I don&#8217;t speak for the Kremlin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I can speak to is what &#8212; the information that we see, which, again, as I say, shows that he has felt misled by the Russian military, and it has resulted in this persistent tension.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just lastly, how does this impact concerns about whether, you know, any deal that may be negotiated with Russia &#8212; between Russia and Ukraine &#8212; can be trusted?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, again, we are not negotiators in that process.&nbsp; We are obviously in close contact with the Ukrainians as they work through this process.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, our role is to do everything we can to strengthen Ukraine on the battlefield, as we&#8217;ve done with the security assistance &#8212; the unprecedented amount of security assistance and weapons that we&#8217;ve flowed to Ukraine and also to strengthen &#8212; strengthen their hand at the negotiating table by continuing to apply incredibly severe costs and sanctions on Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the intelligence, is your &#8212; is your expectation that releasing this information is &#8212; are you hoping that it changes Putin&#8217;s calculus or the military&#8217;s calculus as they approach these things?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; It is &#8212; that is not our intent.&nbsp; Our intent is simply to make the information available so that there is a full understanding of what kind of strategic blunder this has been for Russia and for the Russian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there anything more that you can share just about, you know, whether this is an assessment that you&#8217;re extremely confident in?&nbsp; I know, you know, typically, there&#8217;s a range of views among analysts across the intelligence agencies about how solid information is.&nbsp; Is there anything you can tell us about how solid this is?&nbsp; And what is underlying this that gives you the confidence that this is the right reading?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak more specifically to the intelligence because we obviously do not do anything to compromise sources or methods.&nbsp; I will simply say we have made it public and allow you to draw conclusion from that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So does the U.S. believe that Putin is now fully aware of the misinformation, that he now has a clear picture of Russia&#8217;s military operations and how badly it is performing?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, again, I would just say that we obviously have information, which we have now made public, that he felt misled by the Russian military.&nbsp; We believe he&#8217;s being misinformed by his advisors about how badly the Russian military is performing and how the Russian economy is being crippled by sanctions because, again, his senior advisors are too afraid to tell him the truth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beyond that, I can&#8217;t characterize &#8212; I can&#8217;t characterize any further than that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there any examples that you might be able to offer us &#8212; other than Putin not knowing initially that his military was using and losing conscripts in Ukraine &#8212; that show how Putin was potentially being misinformed by his advisors?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any detail beyond what we&#8217;ve made public already.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just fin- &#8212; one more.</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Of course.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; U.S. officials have obviously been saying since yesterday that the U.S. is not going to be fooled by Russian claims about a withdrawal from Ukraine until you all see it happen on the ground.&nbsp; Does President Zelenskyy share in that skepticism?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; Ask that one more time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You all have been saying that you&#8217;re not going to be fooled by Russia&#8217;s assessment or promises that it is going to start withdrawing and start pulling back on military attacks in Ukraine.</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Wondering if President Zelenskyy &#8212; since he spoke with President Biden &#8212; does he share in that assessment?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Well, I won&#8217;t &#8212; I won&#8217;t characterize President Zelenskyy’s thinking, but I will say that we continue to see evidence today of Russia attacking, advancing &#8212; attacking in places where they had previously said they would not.&nbsp; So I think that is self-evident.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And obviously we continue to do everything we can to flow assistance, security assistance to the &#8212; to the Ukrainians.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Kate.&nbsp; Back to Title 42 for a minute.&nbsp; Back in the spring of last year, there was a very large surge of families &#8212; record surge of children at the &#8212; migrant children at the border that overwhelmed Border Patrol stations.&nbsp; It took a long time to get them moved into HHS &#8212; into sort of temporary shelters and then, ultimately, to HHS.&nbsp;<br><br>Since then, there hasn&#8217;t been a major overhaul of the immigration system.&nbsp; Legislation that the President proposed is completely stalled in Congress.&nbsp; You know, there have been some sort of tweaks and &#8212; and changes around the edges, but there hasn&#8217;t been a wholesale kind of rethinking or change of the asylum system at the border.&nbsp; The MPP program that Donald Trump put into place is back in place by a court order, but it&#8217;s also at a very low level.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what is there in place now if there is another surge in the next month or two when this is lifted?&nbsp; What is there in place that gives the administration confidence that &#8212; that some different result will happen than happened a year ago?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I think if you look back to the spring &#8212; to the time period you’re referencing &#8212; there was an effort to move those unaccompanied minors as quickly as possible out of Border Patrol custody and into facilities that were more suited for children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we were able to dramatically reduce those numbers &#8212; they were in the thousands &#8212; over the course of a couple of months through the work of DHS and others &#8212; and HHS, I should say.&nbsp; We were able to dramatically reduce those numbers, move those kids quickly out of Border Patrol &#8212; Border Patrol custody and into the system.</p>



<p>So I think, you know, if you look at what we were able to do last spring, there was &#8212; there was an ability to move those numbers and move those children quickly into a more &#8212; into facilities that were better suited for them.</p>



<p>Writ large, I would, again, point to the things that the President has done to try to rebuild what was &#8212; if you remember when we came into office &#8212; a system that was decimated by the previous administration.</p>



<p>The previous administration spent four years trying to tear apart a lot of the pieces of our immigration system.&nbsp; And so we were, in many ways, building from, you know &#8212; I won&#8217;t say scratch, certainly &#8212; but we were building from a place where a lot of this &#8212; these pieces had been torn down.</p>



<p>So what we focused on and what the President has focused on is working with the Department of Homeland Security to give clear guidance for internal enforcement; extending and newly designating TPS &#8212; Temporary Protected Status &#8212; for a number of countries; restarting the Central American Minors Program that the previous administration ended; putting together the Family Reunification Task Force, which we have made some progress on reunifying some of those families who were torn apart under the previous administration; of course, ending the Muslim ban and the public charge rule; and protecting DACA recipients.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this President has taken numerous important, substantive steps.&nbsp; Of course, there is more work to do.&nbsp; There is absolutely more work to do.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve taken serious strides forward since we took office last year.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then one quick follow-up.&nbsp; You said again the line that the administration has used a lot, which is that the Title 42 isn&#8217;t an immigration policy; it&#8217;s a public health policy.&nbsp; Has the President, has Ron Klain, has anybody else in the senior administration tried to overrule the CDC over &#8212; during the past year in its efforts to lift <s>Title 2</s> [Title 42] prior to now?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Yes, Ed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; On COVID, can you help us understand &#8212; you guys have laid out sort of what happens if the money runs out that you&#8217;re requesting.&nbsp; Can you remind us: What, in the view of the White House, is the most urgent item on that list that runs the risk of not being funded?</p>



<p>And Republicans again today are saying the money for this is there in previously passed legislation.&nbsp; There’s one figure they&#8217;re saying &#8212; is $160 billion is there from the COVID relief bill.&nbsp; What is the White House response to that suggestion?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, firstly, this is funding that&#8217;s going to be used to provide tests.&nbsp; It will fund additional vaccines &#8212; for example, as we were talking about yesterday, should there come a time where a fourth shot is recommended for the broader population.&nbsp; It will &#8212; it will also fund lifesaving treatments and also our ability to additionally provide vaccines around the world, which is another piece of ensuring that the virus is not able to &#8212; to move around the globe.</p>



<p>So, you know, this is critically important funding.&nbsp; The stakes are very real and very high.&nbsp; You have heard the President state this repeatedly &#8212; that this is critical in order for us to continue our progress.</p>



<p>The other thing I would say about this funding is that it will allow us to prepare for the eventuality &#8212; the possibility &#8212; I shouldn&#8217;t say “eventuality” &#8212; the possibility of another variant, another wave.&nbsp; It will give us the funding that we need to be prepared for the future.&nbsp; So it is critically urgent in that way.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m sorry, what was the second part of your question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, the idea that they say the money&#8217;s already there &#8212; that there&#8217;s unused funds from previously passed legislation.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, obviously, we initially proposed this as emergency funding, but we are working with the Congress &#8212; the Congress is working to get this done.&nbsp; The President has been very clear that it should get done.&nbsp; How the &#8212; how the mechanism of finally coming to an agreement on this works out, we&#8217;ll leave that to the Congress.&nbsp; But the President has been very clear that we need this funding and that it&#8217;s urgent.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to follow up on something he said earlier &#8212; that he may have a meeting with the family of Trevor Reed, and they&#8217;re trying to make that happen: Is that happening today or at some point soon?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Don&#8217;t yet know if it&#8217;s happening today, but I spoke to the President about this earlier.&nbsp; You obviously all heard from him.&nbsp; He is very eager to meet with the family, and we&#8217;re working through when that&#8217;s possible.</p>



<p>Kristen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; I want to ask you about the call with President Zelenskyy, but just a couple more on this new information about Putin being left in the dark by his military advisors.&nbsp; Who authorized the release of that intelligence?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not something I can speak to.&nbsp; Obviously, it was declassified and put forward into the public sphere.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say &#8212; did the President sign off on this?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I cannot speak to that, except to say that this is information that we declassified and made public.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; There has been so much discussion about the concerns over whether Putin would use chemical weapons, nuclear weapons, biological weapons.&nbsp; Does this increase the administration&#8217;s concern that Putin might lash out in that way?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, as I say, I&#8217;m not going to characterize what Vladimir Putin is thinking, what the Kremlin is thinking, or how this might impact their calculus.&nbsp; That is not the intent of putting the information forward.&nbsp; What it does is underscore that this has been a strategic blunder for Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I am not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to characterize how, you know, Vladimir Putin might be thinking about this.</p>



<p>I will say that we are prepared for any and all contingencies.&nbsp; As you know, there&#8217;s a lot of work going on to be prepared for contingencies.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve also been very clear that should Russia act in that way, there will be severe consequences.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the call, Kate, the readout that the White House put out says, “The leaders discussed how the United States is working around the clock to fulfill the main security assistance requests by Ukraine.”&nbsp; We don&#8217;t know what specifically the President of Ukraine asked for of President Biden, but publicly, at least, he has called for those Polish MiGs; he&#8217;s called for anti-aircraft.&nbsp; Are &#8212; has the President changed his decision in that space?&nbsp; Is he now potentially more open to providing those Polish MiGs, given that statement?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We have propi- &#8212; excuse me &#8212; we have provided an unprecedented amount of security assistance to Ukraine, including anti-air, anti-tank systems, small ammunitions &#8212; things that our military have assessed are the most impactful weapons on the battlefield in Ukraine.</p>



<p>So, as the President is making a decision about what to send, he takes into account two things.&nbsp; First, the assessment of our military about what is most impactful, what is best able to help the Ukrainian armed forces turn back Russian aggression.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen that the weapons that we have provided have been instrumental in helping them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then secondly &#8212; and then secondly, as he has said many, many times, he is not looking for direct American military conflict with the Russian military.&nbsp; He has been clear that providing the planes makes this &#8212; there are logistical complications to providing the planes.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s not going to make decisions that is going to lead to direct conflict between the United States military and the Russian military.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And yet President Zelenskyy has been clear, including when he addressed NATO: He doesn&#8217;t think it&#8217;s enough.&nbsp; He doesn&#8217;t think that NATO is doing enough.&nbsp; He thinks that there, yes, has been a lot of assistance, but it doesn&#8217;t go far enough for him to achieve the goals.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Again, the scope &#8212; the scope and scale of the assistance &#8212; the security assistance that we have provided to the Ukrainians is unprecedented.&nbsp; We have worked very, very closely with them &#8212; again, as they discussed on the call today.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve worked very closely with them to provide them with the weapons that they need.</p>



<p>And again, the President takes into account those two factors that I was just talking about when making decisions.</p>



<p>But that being said, he &#8212; we have sent $2 billion in security assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; And we continue to supply them those &#8212; those deliveries are happening daily.&nbsp; Every day, they’re &#8212; those weapons are being delivered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we are doing everything &#8212; the President is making every effort to ensure that they are getting what they need.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Very quickly &#8212; any reaction to former President Trump calling on Putin to release information about Hunter Biden?&nbsp; Are you concerned about that?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So what I would say about that is: What kind of American, let alone an ex-president, thinks that this is the right time to enter into a scheme with Vladimir Putin and brag about his connections to Vladimir Putin?&nbsp; There is only one, and it&#8217;s Donald Trump.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; Earlier today, Germany said it is willing to act as a security guarantor for Ukraine as part of the peace negotiations between Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; Is the U.S. willing to become a guarantor of Ukraine’s security or considering that option?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So we are in constant discussion with Ukrainians about ways that we can help ensure that they are sovereign and secure.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s nothing specific about a security guarantee that I can speak to at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any more information on the $500 million in budgetary aid for Ukraine that was mentioned as part of the readout between the President&#8217;s call with President Zelenskyy?&nbsp; Did President Zelenskyy specifically ask for this to help pay for salaries and other government functions?&nbsp; And is it coming out of the $13.6 billion in Ukraine-related funding in the omnibus or is it separate from that?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So it is financial assistance the Ukrainian government can use to bolster its economy and pay for budgetary expenses, such as paying salaries and maintaining government services.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t yet have additional detail on where the money is coming from.&nbsp; That is being worked through.&nbsp; But it is a commitment that the President made today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, what is the administration&#8217;s current view of whether the U.S. Embassy in Moscow should remain open?&nbsp; And how is the administration going about evaluating whether or not to keep the embassy open?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any additional news to make on that at this moment.&nbsp; Obviously, we will come back to you if there&#8217;s development on that front, but there&#8217;s nothing new that I can announce from this podium at this moment.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; On the economy, the yield curve for the 10-year Treasury note has inverted.&nbsp; Historically, this is viewed as a sign that investors are pessimistic about the long-term view of the economy and they expect a recession is nearing.&nbsp; So can you tell us what the White House believes is the prospects for a recession nearing and how concerned you might be about it?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, you know, as Chairman Powell said after the last Fed meeting, “All signs are that this is a strong economy” and “the probability of a recession within the next year is not particularly elevated.&nbsp; Our team looks at a broad range of indicators to understand the health of the economy now and going forward.&nbsp; This is one, but there are many, many others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the other important indicators to include, as we&#8217;re assessing where the economy stands, are things that, frankly, because of the President&#8217;s economic plan, you know, we&#8217;re able to confront from a position of strength.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s, for example, the fastest economic growth in nearly 40 years, a record 7.4 million jobs created, the fastest decrease in unemployment on record to 3.8 percent, and the first major economy to return to pre-pandemic levels.</p>



<p>So while historically this has been one indicator, it is far from the only one.&nbsp; And many of the other fundamentals that we look at to assess where we are economically are incredibly strong and getting stronger.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the meeting later today between President Biden and moderate and progressive House Democrats: What should we see as a sign of this meeting?&nbsp; Are we &#8212; should we expect that there&#8217;s going to be some kind of consensus around a plan on the domestic side that is going to be ready to ship over to the Senate?&nbsp; Or can you tell us more about what they&#8217;re going to discuss on the executive action front?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So this is part of his continued engagement with the Hill.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been meeting with a number of different caucuses over the course of the last month &#8212; he and the &#8212; and our senior team here at the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are obviously constantly in close contact with the Hill.&nbsp; I would not &#8212; I would not view this as a decision-making meeting; this is a discussion of our shared priorities.&nbsp; I would not anticipate a deliverable coming out of it.&nbsp; This is, again, a continued discussion of our strategic priorities as we try to move forward on our agenda.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just really quickly on India.&nbsp; Daleep Singh is there for the next couple of days meeting with officials.&nbsp; Is the U.S. frustrated with India&#8217;s response to the &#8212; to Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine?&nbsp; And what kind of message is Daleep and his team going to be delivering to the Indian government on that front?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, as you note, Daleep will be in New Delhi to continue our ongoing consultations with the government of India and advance a range of issues in the U.S.-India economic relationship and strategic partnership.&nbsp; He will meet with the government of India to deepen cooperation; to promote inclusive economic growth and prosperity, and a free and open Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He will consult closely with counterparts on the consequences of Russia&#8217;s unjustified war against Ukraine and mitigating its impact on the global economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He will also discuss the priorities of the Biden administration, including the promotion of high-quality infrastructure through Build Back Better World and the development of an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Kate.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Hi.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know this was asked yesterday, but in the last 24 hours, has this White House learned anything about why there is that gap in call logs on January 6th from the Trump White House that was given over to the Select Committee?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We have not &#8212; my answer has not changed from 24 hours ago, which is that I would refer you to the Archives on that.&nbsp; But certainly, where we can cooperate, where we are needed to cooperate to fill in that gap, we will.&nbsp; But I would refer you to the Archives on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then regarding the $500 million to Ukraine,</p>



<p>what is the current explanation of why the President hasn&#8217;t sent over a nominee to the Senate to be the U.S. Ambassador to Ukraine right now?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the current thinking on that?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That&#8217;s an excellent question, and I&#8217;ll have to circle back with you on it.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; On the pandemic: The President got his second booster shot today, but more than half of American &#8212; adult Americans have not gotten their first booster shot, even as public health, you know, officials warn about a fall increase of BA.2 variant.&nbsp; I wonder: Is the White House concerned about that?&nbsp; Like what is the White House doing to sort of help close that gap?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the message to Americans?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, our message to Americans, first and foremost, is to get vaccinated and get boosted.&nbsp; It is the best way to protect yourself from the virus and to protect against the spread of the virus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would say about &#8212; what I would say about the BA.2&nbsp; is that &#8212; you know, it is certainly more transmissible than the original Omicron strain, but there&#8217;s no evidence that it&#8217;s more severe than Omicron.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our vaccines continue to work well against BA.2, particularly, again, with the high level of protection provided by boosters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we continue to both encourage people to get boosted, but I would also point to all the work that we&#8217;ve done to make boosters available, to make vaccines available.&nbsp; There are 90,000 free locations nationwide where you can get &#8212; where you can get vaccinated and boosted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, lastly, I would revisit something we were talking about earlier, which is that we need Congress to pass the 22 and a half billion in emergency COVID funding immediately so that we can maintain our tools to protect people and to be fully prepared for the possibility of any new variants.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; One more on that last part.&nbsp; Has the President or the White House reached out specifically to any of these legislators who have lobbed criticism that, you know, you haven’t used the money that&#8217;s already been allocated for pandemic &#8212; the fight against the pandemic?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any specific engagements to read out, but obviously we continue to work closely with the Hill.&nbsp; The President has stated very clearly that there&#8217;s an urgent need for this money and wants to see it &#8212; he wants to see it done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well how, after printing trillions of dollars &#8212; taxpayers might want to know &#8212; is there not enough money to continue fighting the pandemic?&nbsp; Trillions of dollars and now &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We have &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you&#8217;re out of it?&nbsp; Is all of the accounting done &#8212; every single dollar?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, we have the resources that we need in this current moment.&nbsp; What we need is this funding to be able to plan for the future; to prepare for, as I say, the possibility of a new variant, the possibility of a new wave.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t want to be caught flat-footed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We currently have, for example, all of the vaccine supply that we need to vaccinate and boost every American.&nbsp; But what we need to have this money for is to prepare to be ready for the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we &#8212; as we know, the &#8212; you know, the virus can be unpredictable, and we need to be prepared.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s an urgent need to do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; But can you see why taxpayers would be skeptical?&nbsp; I mean, trillions of dollars and, all of a sudden, you need billions more.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I think taxpayers want to be prepared for the virus, and they want to make sure that we have the resources that we need to keep them safe.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what this administration is focused on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And separately, why (inaudible) &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Jacqui.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; Sorry.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; hide protections in (inaudible) &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jacqui, yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President, Kate, has called &#8212; the President has called Putin a “war criminal.”&nbsp; He said that he believes he will &#8220;meet the legal definition&#8221; of a war criminal.&nbsp; And the U.S. has vowed to pursue all accountability measures, including prosecution.&nbsp; Sentencing for war crimes is long-term imprisonment.&nbsp; So how does all of that not equate to calling for regime change?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; The President has been incredibly clear about this.&nbsp; He is not advocating for a policy of regime change.&nbsp; He &#8212; what he said a couple of days ago was a statement of personal moral outrage, but we do not have a formal policy of regime change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we are doing is continuing to impose unprecedented costs on Russia.&nbsp; We are ensuring that the Russian &#8212; that Russia is paying for this choice.&nbsp; You know, Putin himself has said that the cost, the impact of the sanctions has been significant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we are continuing to focus on our strategy of making sure that we are providing security assistance to Ukraine and imposing significant costs on Russia for these choices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So when he said that he believes Putin will &#8220;meet the legal definition&#8221; of war criminal, was he not saying that he believes he will be convicted of that crime?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; He was not, in fact.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then does the President and the national security team here believe that Ukraine can win and push Russia out of its borders?&nbsp; And if so, has the U.S. adjusted its strategy at all in helping Ukraine since they started to win?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I would argue that, from the outset, that we&#8217;ve done everything in our power &#8212; a tremendous, tremendous amount &#8212; to provide Ukraine with what it needs, to provide it with the resources to turn back Russian aggression.&nbsp; That has been the focus of our strategy.&nbsp; Again, a two-pronged strategy to impose costs and provide the &#8212; both the security assistance and the humanitarian assistance to support Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any reason why no one from this administration has just plainly said, “We think Ukraine can win this war”?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We &#8212; I think in our actions and in the support that we&#8217;ve provided, we&#8217;ve been very clear that we&#8217;re doing everything we can to stand with Ukraine and ensure that they are able to push back against Russian aggression.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more on the southern border.&nbsp; Has DHS requested National Guard troops to be sent to the border?&nbsp; Is that something the administration is considering?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; As far as I know, that is not currently under consideration, but I&#8217;m happy to check in on it and come back to you.</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; First, Senator Susan Collins came out in support of Judge Jackson&#8217;s confirmation to the Supreme Court today.&nbsp; Do you have a reaction to the, kind of, confirmation that you&#8217;ll have a bipartisan vote there?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then also, you know, in her statement, she said that the process is broken and it should go back to kind of being based on qualifications, experience, and not ideology.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m curious what you think about that.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; The President is incredibly grateful to Senator Collins for her thorough and fair consideration and her support.&nbsp; The two of them spoke earlier in this process, and he appreciated her thoughts and her insight.</p>



<p>Obviously, her support speaks to the qualification of Judge Jackson to sit on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; She &#8212; Judge Jackson has been working hard to earn support and, you know, as you well know, responded to Republicans’ requests for in-person meetings by promising to sit down with any senator who wanted.&nbsp; And she has engaged very directly.&nbsp; She answered over 20 hours of questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, she has earned the support of some of the most respected retired conservative judges in the country, and the Fraternal Order of Police, and so many others in law enforcement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So she is an incredibly quality nominee for the Supreme Court.&nbsp; And the President is very grateful for Senator Collins’ measured, reasonable, thorough, and fair consideration, and, ultimately, support for her.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did he make of the other part of the statement or the White House make of the other part of the statement that the process as a whole is broken?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I think what we&#8217;re seeing in immediate &#8212; in the immediate case is that the process is moving forward.&nbsp; She&#8217;s receiving fair consideration.&nbsp; I think she was &#8212; the President was incredibly proud of the way she handled herself during the hearings and thought she very effectively spoke to her judicial philosophy and handled incoming criticism.</p>



<p>So, I won&#8217;t speak to the &#8212; whether the process writ large is broken, as we are focused narrowly in this moment on the process in front of us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would say the process in front of us is working.&nbsp; And I think, again, you know, Senator Collins’ support today &#8212; that the President was very grateful for it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Back to the intel release.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if this is partially just an effort to embarrass Vladimir Putin &#8212; to, sort of, publicly shame him or something.&nbsp; It comes across as &#8212; you know, you say that you can&#8217;t speak for the Kremlin, but then you&#8217;re saying he feels misled by his advisors.&nbsp; It seems like there might be something going on here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; Our aim &#8212; again, our aim is to show that this has been a strategic blunder for Russia, that there is &#8212; ultimately, this is going to leave them weaker; it is not going to leave them stronger.&nbsp; And I think making this information public simply contributes to the picture that, strategically, they are having to reorganize, to refit.&nbsp; And that shows that, again, this was a terrible decision for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And at the end of the day, as we&#8217;ve long said &#8212; as we&#8217;ve said from the outset, as we said even before they invaded &#8212; we said that this would be a strategic mistake for them.&nbsp; And I think that that has borne out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And going back to the COVID funding &#8212; I think it was your answer to Ed &#8212; I&#8217;m trying to read between the lines just a little bit.&nbsp; But you had said, &#8220;Previously, we asked for $22 billion as emergency funding that wouldn&#8217;t need any offsets.&nbsp; Now we would like Congress to get us this money.&#8221;&nbsp; Are you saying that you&#8217;re willing to accept offsets?&nbsp; That &#8212; and also, are you willing to accept less than the $22 billion?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, what I would say is we have been very clear that we need this money now.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re hopeful that Congress is nearing a solution.&nbsp; And, you know, again, the President called for this initial 22 and a half billion as emergency funding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But at the end of the day, we need the money.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important.&nbsp; It&#8217;s critical for our preparedness for the next &#8212; you know, the next phase of COVID and being prepared so that we&#8217;re not caught flat-footed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So ultimately, we are &#8212; we are hopeful that Congress is nearing a solution on this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we should take that as you&#8217;re willing to accept the offsets.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; You should &#8212; no.&nbsp; You should take it as what I said, which is that we&#8217;re hopeful that Congress is reaching a solution on this and Congress will determine, ultimately, where we net out on this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much, Kate.&nbsp; Going back to her question: Who the White House believe is winning this war?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I think that &#8212; the White House believes that Ukraine has been &#8212; has fought valiantly, has been incredibly brave and resolved in the face of atro- &#8212; of atrocious, brutal invasion from Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think what you&#8217;ve seen in the actions from this White House is that we have provided weapons, we have provided assistance, we have been there every step of the way and will continue to be.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve put enormous, enormous economic pressure on Russia in order to &#8212; in order to hopefully drive this conflict to a solution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, I think &#8212; again, I don&#8217;t know that I have to say it &#8212; I think that our actions show and the support that we provided shows that &#8212; that we believe that Ukraine has been incredibly, incredibly brave, incredibly strong, and we&#8217;re going to continue to support them as they move forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kate &#8212; did you &#8212; do you want another one?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, do you mind?&nbsp; Because President Zelenskyy just tweeted also that President Biden and him talk about a new package of sanctions.&nbsp; Could &#8212; do you have anything more specific on that?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have anything that I can preview in this moment.&nbsp; But certainly, we are continuing to look at options to &#8212; to expand and deepen our sanctions.&nbsp; And I anticipate that we would probably have more for you on that in the coming days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; Two quick ones, hopefully.&nbsp; Could you give us any steer on the additional capabilities bit of that readout in &#8212; from the Zelenskyy call?&nbsp; Is there &#8212; is there a shift in thinking, perhaps, that Ukraine needs a different category of weapons &#8212; not just enough to hold the Russians back, but actually to push them back and out?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So &#8212; so an example of one of the &#8212; one of those additional capabilities &#8212; something that we talked about a little bit last week while we were in Europe &#8212; you know, shore &#8212; ship-to-shore capability, anti-ship capability &#8212; that&#8217;s just one example.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, beyond that, I&#8217;m not going to go into further detail on what&#8217;s being discussed, except to say that we&#8217;re doing everything we can to ensure that Ukraine has what it needs on the battlefield.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And the other one is: Today, Boris Johnson said &#8212; very black and white &#8212; he said sanctions &#8212; Western sanctions, not just British or G7 sanctions &#8212; should stay in place until the Russian troops are all gone.&nbsp; That was a lot more black-and-white than anything that&#8217;s come out of the White House.&nbsp; Did you &#8212; does the White House share that kind of maximalist goal with sanctions?&nbsp; Are they going to stay there until the last Russian troops are gone?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not something that I&#8217;m going to be able to pre-state in this moment.&nbsp; I will let &#8212; I will let Boris Johnson and the UK government speak for themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; There have been some reports recently that some Democratic senators on the Hill have expressed concerns about Eric Garcetti&#8217;s nomination to be Ambassador to India.&nbsp; Does the White House still have confidence in him and its ability to get him confirmed?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We do.&nbsp; We do have &#8212; the President has confidence in Mayor Garcetti.&nbsp; He believes he will be an excellent representative in India.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would remind you that his nomination advanced unanimously with bipartisan support in committee, and we&#8217;re continuing to engage with senators and working to earn bipartisan support for his nomination and believe he should receive a vote in the Senate expeditiously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And earlier this month, President Zelenskyy signed a decree to combine Ukraine&#8217;s national TV channels into one platform, saying he wants to create a unified information policy.&nbsp; Ukraine also announced it was banning 11 political parties with ties to Russia.&nbsp; Is the White House concerned at all about these moves by the Ukrainians?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So this is the first that I&#8217;m hearing of it.&nbsp; I will look into it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to talk to our national security team and get back to you.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kate &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Yeah, Karen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; excuse me, Kate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oops.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; High praise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Red hair.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You had mentioned that the administration encourages boosters.&nbsp; You talked about the work you&#8217;ve done on that.&nbsp; But given that COVID cases are down and that the pace of boosters has been sluggish, will there be an actual public campaign by the President or the administration &#8212; more of an outward effort &#8212; to get people to get their boosters?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I think we&#8217;ll &#8212; we will continue to do the work we&#8217;ve been doing.&nbsp; And today, we launched a new website, COVID.gov, which gives people what they need to track transmission in their community, to find a test-to-treat location &#8212; so, an opportunity, a location where you can go; you can get a test; and if you&#8217;re positive, you can get an antiviral.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this website is part of our effort &#8212; our continued and ongoing effort to make sure that people have what they need to deal with COVID as we move into potentially the next phase of this &#8212; of this disease.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, from the outset, we have said and continue to believe &#8212; because the science shows &#8212; that getting vaccinated, getting boosted is the best thing that you can do in order to protect yourself from the virus.&nbsp; So, that has been a big piece of our public messaging.&nbsp; That’s been a big piece of our message to the country.&nbsp; And it will continue to be.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President today described this new moment where he said COVID “no longer controls our lives.”&nbsp; How critical is it that Americans get boosted to stay in this new moment right now?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s important.&nbsp; And our message has consistently been that it is important to &#8212; it&#8217;s important to get boosted.&nbsp; The science shows it is the best way to prevent the spread of the virus and to &#8212; and to protect you and your loved ones and your family and your friends from getting sick.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, our message will always be: It is important to go out and get boosted.&nbsp; We have &#8212; we are doing everything in our power, we have done everything in our power to make sure that boosters are free and available to everybody in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Regarding the President&#8217;s budget proposal, which was released earlier this week, Senator Manchin is already saying that he can&#8217;t support this so-called &#8220;Billionaires Tax,&#8221; because it would tax unrealized gains on certain assets.&nbsp; I wanted to hear your response to that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m also wondering if he sticks with that &#8212; you know, if it &#8212; given his opposition, does that mean this &#8212; his proposal is DOA?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, what I would say is that the President&#8217;s budget is a classic Joe Biden budget.&nbsp; It is focused on security, it is focused on our &#8212; on security in our communities, security abroad.&nbsp; And it was designed in order to help ensure that we have the money in reserve to pay for and bring down the deficit, even after Congress sends us &#8212; whatever they ultimately send us on the proposals that he very much wants to see passed to lower prescription drug costs, to lower the cost of childcare, to tackle the climate crisis.&nbsp; So the key priorities in this budget are those and ensuring that the wealthiest pay their fair share.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, I think Senator Manchin and President Biden share a belief that the rich should pay their fair share.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ll allow the process of negotiation to work itself out.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not &#8212; I&#8217;m obviously not going to negotiate from the podium, but I do think that Senator Manchin and President Biden share that fundamental belief that the rich should pay their fair share &#8212; the wealthiest, I should say, should pay their fair share.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;ll continue to work with him and to work with Congress to move these forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Twenty-one states have filed a lawsuit against the government because of the mask mandates on transportation.&nbsp; I wonder if the White House is prepared through the CDC to issue some new guidance to lift these mask mandates.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any news to make on this at this moment.&nbsp; I will say these are conversations that are underway.&nbsp; And certainly, when we have news to make on this, we&#8217;ll come back to you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; When I asked Jake Sullivan the question of why no one in the administration had said definitively whether or not the White House thinks that Ukraine can win this war, he referred me to the Pentagon.&nbsp; And moments ago, when the same question was asked to you, you said, you know, &#8220;I don&#8217;t know I ha- &#8212; I don&#8217;t know I have to say it.&#8221;&nbsp; But the President has said, &#8220;I don&#8217;t care what Putin thinks.&#8221;&nbsp; So why isn&#8217;t the administration being more definitive on this question?&nbsp; Is it for fear that this might provoke Moscow?&nbsp; Is it that you don&#8217;t have a clear definition of what victory might look like over there?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I think what is important here, as I said in my previous answer &#8212; I think what&#8217;s important here is our actions.&nbsp; I think we have &#8212; we have provided the security assistance.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve provided the weapons to Ukraine.&nbsp; We continue to support Ukraine.&nbsp; We continue to do everything in our power to ensure that they have what they need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think if there&#8217;s &#8212; I don&#8217;t think there should be any question about whether this White House and this President is doing everything in his power to support Ukraine in the face of Russian aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But towards what end?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; I have two questions, one on Iran and one on electric vehicle.&nbsp; So on Iran, today, Secretary Blinken announced new sanctions against Iran over the ballistic missile activities.&nbsp; Will this endanger the nuclear talks?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Sorry, the second part of the &#8212; I’m sorry, the second part?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, will this endanger the nuclear &#8212; the nuclear talk?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; No, not at all.&nbsp; In fact, these sanctions are not connected to the Iran deal.&nbsp; They demonstrate, in fact, what we have always said, which is that we will continue to hold Iran accountable for its missile proliferation and support to proxy networks, as we work diplomatically to place strict limits on its nuclear program.</p>



<p>So that will be true whether we are back in the nuclear deal or not.&nbsp; And the sanctions that we&#8217;re applying today will remain in place whether or not we&#8217;re back in the nuclear deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as you know, it is our firm view that getting out of the deal was a disaster. &nbsp;And second, that these other problems &#8212; missiles and proxies &#8212; are better addressed without Iran at the nuclear breakout threshold.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, ultimately, we are able to hold Iran accountable on issues like the missile program, while continuing to work toward a potential deal to limit their nuclear program.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second question, on the electric vehicles. So, yesterday, you announced investment in electric vehicles.&nbsp; And this week, actually a Chinese company called SEMCORP, which is Shanghai Energy New Materials Technology, just announced a new electric vehicle battery investment in Ohio which will create around 1,200 jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know pushing cutting-edge technology and preserving supply chain is Biden administration’s priority.&nbsp; But would you also worry about national security aspects and future supply chain concern over a Chinese investment on those items?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, as you say, a significant economic priority &#8212; a significant plank of the Biden economic agenda is bringing our supply chains to America, making more in America, manufacturing in America.&nbsp; The President has been very focused on taking steps to ensure that we&#8217;re doing that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re seeing investment.&nbsp; You know, you&#8217;ll all remember the investment that Intel announced a couple of months ago.&nbsp; You know, these are investments that are happening in part because President Biden is creating an environment where companies feel like they will get the support and they will therefore bring their jobs here.</p>



<p>On the national security question, I would only say, of course, we would always review and undertake all of the necessary steps.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything beyond that to say.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>3:26 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-naftali-bennett-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 22:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of Israel to express his deepest condolences following the horrific terrorist attacks that have killed 11 people in three Israeli cities. The President emphasized that the United States stands firmly and resolutely with Israel in the face of this terrorist threat and all threats&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of Israel to express his deepest condolences following the horrific terrorist attacks that have killed 11 people in three Israeli cities. The President emphasized that the United States stands firmly and resolutely with Israel in the face of this terrorist threat and all threats to the state of Israel. The leaders discussed the importance of regional partnerships, as exemplified by the Abraham Accords and the Negev Summit, in promoting security and improving the lives of people across the Middle East. The President offered all appropriate assistance to our Israeli allies as they confront threats to their citizens.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-60/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 20:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Candace A. Bond, of Missouri, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Trinidad and Tobago. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Timmy T. Davis, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Candace A. Bond, of Missouri, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Trinidad and Tobago.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Timmy T. Davis, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the State of Qatar.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Michael J. Lombardo, of California, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2022, vice Maria Rosario Jackson, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Michael J. Lombardo, of California, to be a Member of the National Council on the Arts for a term expiring September 3, 2028.&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Nasser H. Paydar, of Indiana, to be Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, Department of Education, vice Robert L. King.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Puneet Talwar, of the District of Columbia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Morocco.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Status of the Country’s Fight Against&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/30/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-status-of-the-countrys-fight-against-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 19:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 1:40 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Today, I’d like to update you all on where we stand on COVID-19.&#160; Because of the strategy we executed over the past year on vaccinations, testing, treatments, and more, we’re now in a new moment in this pandemic. It does not mean&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>1:40 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Today, I’d like to update you all on where we stand on COVID-19.&nbsp;<br><br>Because of the strategy we executed over the past year on vaccinations, testing, treatments, and more, we’re now in a new moment in this pandemic.<br><br>It does not mean that COVID-19 is over; it means that COVID-19 no longer controls our lives.&nbsp; That’s what it means.&nbsp;<br><br>Cases are ticking up as we thought they might.&nbsp; But now, thanks to the foundation we’ve laid, America has the tools to protect people &#8212; all the people.<br><br>And, you know, as we’ve done from day one, my administration is making it easier than ever for Americans to access these tools.<br><br>Today, I&#8217;m announcing the launch of COVID.gov &#8212; COVID.gov &#8212; a one &#8212; (clears throat) &#8212; excuse me, a one-stop shop where anyone in America can find what they need to navigate the virus: free vaccines and boosters, free at-home tests, high-quality masks.&nbsp; And for the latest information about the level of COVID-19 spread in your community, you can get that immediately.<br><br>Now, you’ll also be able to find our new test-to-treat locations, which I announced in my State of the Union Address.&nbsp; These are pharmacies and other places in your neighborhood where you can get tested.&nbsp; And if you&#8217;re positive, you can get lifesaving treatments all in one stop.<br><br>We’ve already stood up 2,000 test-to-streat [sic] sites &#8212; test-and-treat sites across the country.<br><br>We’re also nearly at &#8212; we have nearly 200 sites just to serve military families and veterans communities as well.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve done &#8212; what we’ve done throughout the pandemic, we’ve ensured there are &#8212; these locations are at the hardest-hit, hardest-to-reach communities as well.<br><br>The bottom line: No longer will Americans have to scour the Internet to find vaccines, treatments, tests, or masks.&nbsp; It’s all there.&nbsp; And just go visit COVID.gov &#8212; COVID.gov.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And let me remind you: When I took office about 14 months ago, the pandemic was raging, the economy was reeling, and the deficit was soaring.&nbsp; Most schools were closed.&nbsp; We didn’t have enough vaccines.&nbsp; The unemployment claims were sky high.&nbsp;<br><br>And then we got to work, and we delivered: enough vaccines for every American months ahead of schedule, effective treatments, at-home tests that are free and accessible.<br><br>Over 99 percent of our schools are open again.&nbsp; Businesses are open again.&nbsp; And because of how we responded, we created more jobs last year than ever before &#8212; 6.7 million jobs.<br><br>And by the way, we did it while cutting the deficit &#8212; the largest one-year deficit reduction in American history.&nbsp; Say that again: The largest one-year deficit reduction in American history.&nbsp;<br><br>But none of that happened by accident.&nbsp; We were able to do it because we coordinated across the government, partnered with state and local leaders, governors on both sides of the aisle, and the private sector to leverage every resource we had to fight against this virus.<br><br>We left no stone unturned.&nbsp; And we were able to do it because Congress worked with us and provided us the necessary funding.<br><br>But now, just as we’ve reached the critical turning point in this fight, Congress has to provide the funding America needs to continue to fight COVID-19.<br><br>We’re alr- &#8212; we’re already seeing the consequences of congressional inaction.&nbsp; The monoclonal antibod- &#8212; take monoclonal antibodies, for example.&nbsp; They’ve helped save lives.&nbsp; This isn’t partisan; it’s medicine.<br><br>But Congress hasn’t provided enough money to keep purchasing these monoclonal bo- &#8212; antibodies.&nbsp; We’ve had to cancel planned orders and cut the supply we’re sending to the states.&nbsp; Without more funding, we’ll start to run out of them by the end of May &#8212; the end of May.<br><br>We’ve also had to scale back our plan to purchase more preventive therapies for Americans who are immunocompromised &#8212; critical tools to protect the most vulnerable among us.&nbsp; Without more funding, we risk running out of the supply by this fall.<br><br>The same is true of testing.&nbsp; It took months to ramp up our testing capacity.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Omicron &#8212; we saw how vital &#8212; and with Omicron, we saw how vital it was&nbsp;<s>and</s>&nbsp;[that] we have enough tests on hand to weather the surge.&nbsp;&nbsp;But without funding, we’re not going to be able to sustain the testing capacity beyond the month of June.&nbsp; And if we fail to invest, we leave ourselves vulnerable if another wave of the virus hits.<br><br>Look, on vaccines &#8212; a most important tool in this fight &#8212; we’re also running a risk.<br><br>Yesterday, the Food and Drug Administration &#8212; the FDA &#8212; and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention –- the CDC &#8212; authorized a fourth shot for those 50 years and older.<br><br>We know boosters are critical to providing an additional level of protection.&nbsp; That’s why I plan to get my second booster today right here after I’m done speaking.<br><br>If you haven’t gotten your first booster, please don’t wait.&nbsp; Do it today.<br><br>Those who are 50 and older, as well as those who are immunocompromised, can now get it &#8212; get even more protection than they have from the initial first doses.&nbsp; We have enough supply to give booster shots to those newly eligible individuals.<br><br>But if Congress fails to act, we won’t have the supply we need this fall to ensure that shots are available, free, easily accessible for all Americans.<br><br>Even worse, if we need a different vaccine for the future to combat a new variant, we’re not going to have enough money to purchase it.&nbsp; We cannot allow that to happen.</p>



<p>Congress, we need to secure additional supply now.&nbsp; Now.&nbsp; We can’t wait until we find ourselves in the midst of another surge to act.&nbsp; It’ll be too late.<br><br>And we also need this &#8212; this funding to continue our efforts to vaccinate the world &#8212; commitments we made.&nbsp; It’s critical to our ability to protect against new variants.&nbsp; There’s no wall that you can build high enough to keep out a virus.<br><br>Congress needs to act now, please.<br><br>Let me close with this: I’ve worked so hard to get our lives &#8212; we’ve worked so hard to &#8212; we, all of us, have worked so hard to get our lives back.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We’re summoning every ounce of American resilience; pulled every lever of our government; called upon the goodness, decency, and patriotism of the American people; and, together, we turned an unthinkable pain into an extraordinary progress and purpose.&nbsp; Americans are back to living their lives again.&nbsp; We can’t surrender that now.&nbsp;<br><br>Congress, please act.&nbsp; You have to act immediately.&nbsp; The consequences of inaction are severe.&nbsp; They’ll only grow with time, but it doesn’t have to be that way.</p>



<p>We’ve proven what we can do when we work together.&nbsp; So, I urge Democrats and Republicans to get this done with urgency.<br><br>Let’s stand united.&nbsp; Let’s continue to pull together.&nbsp; Let’s get this done.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; And God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.<br><br>And now I’m going to get my second booster shot.<br>(The President moves to a chair to receive the booster shot.)<br><br>I’m not sure why I’m doing it on stage.&nbsp; Just to prove I&#8217;m getting it, I guess.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what is the danger of Putin being left in the dark by his military advisors?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m reluctant to comment on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you comment on the declassified intelligence that he doesn&#8217;t trust his military leadership, since it is declassified?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I can&#8217;t.<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, is the U.S. willing to provide security guarantees to Ukraine as part of peace talks?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m feeling great.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the U.S. willing to provide security guarantees to Ukraine as part of peace talks with Russia?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, are you going to extend Title 42?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have a decision on that soon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, the difference between rich and poor countries on vaccination, will it impact your &#8212; the fight against COVID here?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry &#8212;<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The difference between &#8212; the gap &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Somebody asked about the vaccines, which is relevant.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For kids under five, is there &#8212; are there enough funds to provide them vaccines for free?<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>(The President receives the booster shot.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How does it feel, Mr. President?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Wonderful.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>No, I have to admit to you, I&#8217;ve always thought that it discourages people getting a vaccination when they watch people get a needle in their arm.&nbsp; So I apologize if I discouraged them.&nbsp; It didn&#8217;t hurt a bit, and I was able to roll my sleeve up.<br><br>And thank you all so very much.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you meet with Trevor Reed&#8217;s parents?&nbsp; Will you meet with Trevor Reed&#8217;s parents, Mr. President, while they&#8217;re here in Washington?&nbsp; They say that you promised them a meeting.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to see if I can get to see them.&nbsp; They&#8217;re good &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re good people.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t &#8212; we&#8217;re trying to work that out.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>1:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Transgender Day Of Visibility,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/30/a-proclamation-on-transgender-day-of-visibility-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 19:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA A PROCLAMATION To everyone celebrating Transgender Day of Visibility, I&#160;want you to know that your President sees you.&#160; The First Lady, the Vice President, the Second Gentleman, and my entire Administration see you for who you are &#8212; made in the image of God and deserving&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">A PROCLAMATION</p>



<p>To everyone celebrating Transgender Day of Visibility, I&nbsp;want you to know that your President sees you.&nbsp; The First Lady, the Vice President, the Second Gentleman, and my entire Administration see you for who you are &#8212; made in the image of God and deserving of dignity, respect, and support. &nbsp;On this day and every day, we recognize the resilience, strength, and joy of&nbsp;transgender, nonbinary, and gender nonconforming people.&nbsp; We celebrate the activism and determination that have fueled the fight for transgender equality.&nbsp; We acknowledge the adversity and discrimination that the transgender community continues to face across our Nation and around the world.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Visibility matters, and so many transgender, nonbinary, and gender nonconforming Americans are thriving.&nbsp; Like never before, they are sharing their stories in books and magazines; breaking glass ceilings of representation on television and movie screens; enlisting &#8212; once again &#8212; to serve proudly and openly in our military; getting elected and making policy at every level of government; and running businesses, curing diseases, and serving our communities in countless other ways.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Despite this progress, transgender Americans continue to face discrimination, harassment, and barriers to opportunity. &nbsp;Transgender women and girls &#8212; especially transgender women and girls of color &#8212; continue to face epidemic levels of violence, and 2021 marked the deadliest year on record for transgender Americans. &nbsp;Each of these lives lost was precious. &nbsp;Each of them deserved freedom, justice, and joy. &nbsp;We must honor their lives with action by advancing equity and civil rights for all transgender people.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the past year, hundreds of anti-transgender bills in States were proposed across America, most of them targeting transgender kids. &nbsp;The onslaught has continued this year. &nbsp;These&nbsp;bills are wrong. &nbsp;Efforts to criminalize supportive medical care for transgender kids, to ban transgender children from playing sports, and to outlaw discussing LGBTQI+ people in&nbsp;schools undermine their humanity and corrode our Nation&#8217;s values.&nbsp; Studies have shown that these political attacks are damaging to the mental health and well-being of transgender youth, putting children and their families at greater risk of&nbsp;bullying and discrimination.</p>



<p>     My entire Administration is committed to ensuring that transgender people enjoy the freedom and equality that are promised to everyone in America.  That is why I signed an Executive Order Preventing and Combating Discrimination on the Basis of Gender Identity or Sexual Orientation.  We are expanding Federal non-discrimination protections; promoting strategies to address violence against the transgender community and advance gender equity and equality; and disseminating new resources to enhance inclusion, opportunity, and safety for transgender people.  Additionally, Americans will soon be able to select more inclusive gender markers on their passports.  I continue to call on the Congress to swiftly pass the bipartisan Equality Act, which will ensure that LGBTQI+ individuals and families cannot be denied housing, employment, education, credit, and more because of who they are or who they love.  We will continue to work to help transgender people around the world live free from discrimination and violence.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this Transgender Day of Visibility, we honor transgender people who are fighting for freedom, equality, dignity, and respect.&nbsp; We also celebrate the parents, teachers, coaches, doctors, and other allies who affirm the identities of their transgender children and help these young people reach their potential.&nbsp; Transgender people are some of the bravest Americans I know, and our Nation and the world are stronger, more vibrant, and more prosperous because of them. &nbsp;To transgender Americans of all ages, I want you to know that you are so brave. &nbsp;You belong. &nbsp;I have your back.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim March 31, 2022, as Transgender Day of Visibility. &nbsp;I call upon all Americans to join us in lifting up the lives and voices of transgender people throughout our Nation and to work toward eliminating discrimination against all transgender, gender nonconforming, and nonbinary people &#8212; and&nbsp;all people.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirtieth day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on César Chávez Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/30/a-proclamation-on-cesar-chavez-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 19:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50108</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA A PROCLAMATION Today we celebrate the life and legacy of César Estrada Chávez, a champion for social justice and advocate for hardworking people who build and sustain our Nation.  Born into poverty and raised by migrant workers, Chávez courageously dedicated his life to improving conditions for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">A PROCLAMATION</p>



<p>Today we celebrate the life and legacy of César Estrada Chávez, a champion for social justice and advocate for hardworking people who build and sustain our Nation.  Born into poverty and raised by migrant workers, Chávez courageously dedicated his life to improving conditions for workers across the country.  Chávez witnessed firsthand the inequities of an economy that only served those at the top and left millions of hardworking Americans behind.  Today, as we continue to build an economy from the bottom up and the middle out and that rewards work and not just wealth, we stand on the shoulders of César Chávez and carry forward his fight to advance the rights and dignity of working people and fulfill the promise of America for all Americans.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When César Chávez founded the United Farm Workers of America alongside Dolores Huerta, he drew national attention to&nbsp;the many agricultural workers who experience inhumane working conditions and unlivable wages. &nbsp;Through strikes, marches, and boycotts, he inspired millions of people across the country to fight for safe and healthy workplaces, better wages, improved workplace protections from sickness and disability, and other core rights and protections.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the process, Chávez inspired generations of people across all backgrounds, ages, and industries to organize, bargain, and expand opportunity for workers and their families. &nbsp;His devotion to &#8220;La Causa&#8221; brought hope to workers and Latinos across the Nation &#8212; and his fight for justice, equality, and dignity gave workers and Latinos everywhere a voice. &nbsp;Today, we&nbsp;must summon the same courage and moral clarity to carry his legacy forward so that everyone has a fair shot at the American dream.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That is why my Administration continues to urge the Congress to pass the Protecting the Right to Organize Act and the Farm Workforce Modernization Act &#8212; so farmworkers can bargain collectively, obtain legal status, and have better working conditions.&nbsp; It is why I fought hard to pass the American Rescue Plan early in my Administration to ensure Latino workers, families, and small businesses had the protections and financial support they needed to pay rent and put food on their table. &nbsp;It is why I appointed Marty Walsh, a former union leader, to lead the Department of Labor &#8212; because he understands how union workers hold this country together. &nbsp;It&nbsp;is&nbsp;why my Administration created an historic Task Force on&nbsp;Worker Organizing and Empowerment &#8212; because I believe in empowering workers to organize and providing those that put food on our table an earned pathway to citizenship.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As our Nation celebrates César Chávez&#8217;s 95th birthday, let&nbsp;us keep the lessons he taught in our minds and the values he&nbsp;lived by in our hearts:&nbsp; the power of workers to bargain for a&nbsp;better deal, strength in the face of extraordinary adversity, and the conviction to fight for what we believe in.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When I became President, I proudly placed a bust of César Chávez in the Oval Office &#8212; a constant reminder of the enduring values he embodied, the vision of freedom he fought for, and his commitment to social justice and equal dignity that we must uphold each and every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>     NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 31, 2022, as César Chávez Day.  I call upon all Americans to observe this day as a day of service and learning, with appropriate service, community, and education programs to honor César Chávez&#8217;s enduring legacy. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this</p>



<p>thirtieth day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at Greater Washington Inclusive Growth&#160;Announcement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/30/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-greater-washington-inclusive-growth-announcement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:14 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning, everyone.&#160; Good morning.&#160; You know, it&#8217;s so wonderful &#8212; we all love homecomings, don&#8217;t we?&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And this is a homecoming for me to be on this stage at Cramton Auditorium at Howard University. Dr. Frederick, I want to thank you for always warmly welcoming us to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:14 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s so wonderful &#8212; we all love homecomings, don&#8217;t we?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And this is a homecoming for me to be on this stage at Cramton Auditorium at Howard University.<br><br>Dr. Frederick, I want to thank you for always warmly welcoming us to this incredible place.&nbsp; In this very auditorium, I have memories of so many moments in my life, including the day that I was here in the back of the room for freshman orientation.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And in many ways, including my family, this is where it all started.<br><br>So, thank you, all, very much.&nbsp; It&#8217;s wonderful to be here with you all today.<br><br>Ellis Carr, thank you for that introduction and for your extraordinary leadership.&nbsp; We had some time, all of us, backstage to talk about the work that you all are doing, and I cannot thank you enough.<br><br>And Wayne Frederick, I want to just thank you again for all that you do to lead this venerable institution.&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s so much about Howard University and all of our universities, our colleges, our community colleges that really do highlight what this is about, what this topic is about &#8212; which is creating a place and an environment where the talent of our nation can be nurtured and supported and encouraged.<br><br>That really is the essence of what we&#8217;re doing today, and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re talking about today.<br><br>And this, of course, is an institution that since its founding, has worked to advance &#8212; as we are doing, all of us, today &#8212; inclusion, growth, and equity in our country.<br><br>Today, we are, of course, joined by the Secretary of Commerce, Gina Raimondo &#8212; thank you for your work, Madam Secretary; and the Administrator of our Small Business Administration, Isabel Guzman.&nbsp; And thank you.&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;ve known Isabel&#8217;s work &#8212; I&#8217;m going to say the Administrator&#8217;s work since her work in California, and you have a longstanding track record of supporting and encouraging community strength and growth.&nbsp; And so, I thank you for that.<br><br>And we are, of course, honored to be joined as well by a number of extraordinary leaders from the Greater Washington Partnership &#8212; leaders who have dedicated themselves to advancing economic development and economic opportunity for all our communities.<br><br>So, thank you all for your leadership and for being here today.<br><br>I believe America is a nation that is driven by the ambition and aspirations of her people.&nbsp; And our economy, to a great extent, therefore is driven by the ambition and aspiration of our small businesses.<br><br>Small-business owners work morning and night to transform an idea into a reality.&nbsp; And that energy, of course, drives our entire nation forward.&nbsp; It creates jobs.&nbsp; It drives innovation.&nbsp; It accelerates economic growth.<br><br>And in America today, too many small businesses and too many entrepreneurs are also being left behind.<br><br>So, to start and grow a business, as we all know, entrepreneurs with these incredible ideas, with ambition and aspiration &#8212; well, to actually put it into effect, they need capital.&nbsp; Capital to buy inventory, to rent a storefront, to pay their employees.&nbsp; They need financial services to help run the daily operations of their business and to invest in the future.<br><br>But far too many entrepreneurs are unable to access this essential support.<br><br>Consider: Black entrepreneurs are three times more likely to report that they did not apply for credit for fear of being turned away by a bank.<br><br>Black and Latino entrepreneurs are rejected at a much higher rate when applying for small-business loans from traditional financial institutions, even when they have credit profiles similar to other applicants.<br><br>People who live in rural areas, including many Native Americans, often lack access to traditional banking services of any kind.<br><br>And many Asian American business owners, in particular immigrant business owners, face language barriers that limit their opportunity and ability to access capital and banking services.&nbsp;<br><br>And let us acknowledge that when we think of the importance, the relevance, and the strength of traditional banks, we must also acknowledge that they’ve not always necessarily seen the vision of small-business owners who are women, small-business owners of color, rural small-business owners, and small-business owners who serve low-income communities.<br><br>Community lenders, on the other hand, were created to see that vision.&nbsp; Community lenders, known as CDFIs and MDIs, predominantly serve overlooked and underserved communities.<br><br>The people who run these institutions &#8212; and here’s where the magic lies &#8212; the people, Senator, who run these institutions &#8212; because we’ve worked together; Senator Cardin is right here in the front row &#8212; often live and work in those communities.<br><br>I’m going to repeat that: The people who run these institutions often live and work in those very communities.&nbsp; They know the people they are lending too.&nbsp; They understand their needs and their challenges and their strengths.&nbsp; And so, when they make a loan, they personally feel the positive impact of that loan.&nbsp; They feel it firsthand because they’re there. And so, community lenders can often see the potential that others might overlook.<br><br>Last year, for example &#8212; and I’ve been traveling the country meeting with our incredible small-business owners, but I’ll share with you one story because it is also in the place where I was born: Oakland, California. &nbsp;<br><br>But, last year, I met with a small-business owner.&nbsp; Her name is Reign, and she owns a catering company in Oakland, California.&nbsp; And when she started out &#8212; she was telling me about how she needed a van.&nbsp; And so, she went to a traditional bank and filled out an application for a loan, and she was rejected.<br><br>And she told me about a word that she heard then that I have heard many small-business owners tell me they were presented with as something that was supposed to describe themselves that they had never heard before.&nbsp; That word is “unbankable.”&nbsp; I’ve heard so many small-business owners tell me they were told, as though this is their identity, that they were “unbankable.”<br><br>So, Reign, not being deterred by a word &#8212; (laughter) &#8211;went to a community lender.&nbsp; And that lender, of course, saw her vision to build a catering company that made fresh, local, and sustainable food, cooked with love and served with care.&nbsp; And they, of course, gave Reign that loan to buy that van.<br><br>And, today, Reign runs one of the most successful catering businesses in Oakland.&nbsp; She has catered for clients from the mayor to the Golden State Warriors &#8212; yes &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; from Google to Stanford University.<br><br>So, Reign&#8217;s story is just one of so many.<br><br>Since I took office, I have consulted with some of the most active community lenders in our nation.&nbsp; And I have seen the tremendous difference that these lenders are making in communities across our country.<br><br>Latino communities in urban neighborhoods &#8212; like Columbia Heights, right here in Washington, D.C. &#8212; and rural communities across the country &#8212; like those in Oregon, like Native communities in South Dakota, and Black communities in the Mississippi Delta.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, I’m heading to Mississippi on Friday to be with Bill Bynum.<br><br>Expanding our nation&#8217;s investment in community lenders has been a priority of mine and ours for years.&nbsp; In fact, when I was Senator, together my colleague, the great senator from Maryland, and so many others &#8212; we helped secure $12 billion for community lenders as part of a COVID-19 relief bill.<br><br>And now, with extraordinary partners such as the Secretary of the Treasury, Janet Yellen; Secretary Raimondo; Administrator Guzman, our administration is working to broaden the reach of community lenders.<br><br>And that brings me to one of the reasons that I’m here today, which is to share with you the development of all of this work.<br><br>In 2011, the Small Business Administration launched the Community Advantage pilot loan program.&nbsp; It was a pilot.&nbsp; Through this program, the SBA partially guarantees loans made by community lenders.<br><br>It allows community lenders to make more investments in underserved communities and to make entrepreneurs loans that others might have deemed too risky &#8212; entrepreneurs like Reign.<br><br>Since its founding, the Community Advantage program has helped launch businesses, create jobs, and drive innovation across our nation.&nbsp;<br><br>Originally, the program was scheduled to expire this fall.&nbsp; But today, I am proud to announce that we are extending the Community Advantage program until 2024.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we are expanding it so we will expand the number of lenders in the program and increase the amount of money that they can lend.&nbsp; So, this, of course, means that more small businesses will be able to benefit from the program.<br><br>And, of course, our work collectively is not going to stop there.&nbsp; Since the President and I took office, we have held roundtables, listening sessions, and one-on-one consultations with business owners and community leaners [sic] &#8212; leaders.&nbsp;<br><br>I was saying to the folks who are in the front row here that, you know, the experience that I&#8217;ve had, I know we all have, is, our small-business owners &#8212; they&#8217;re not only leaders in business: They are civic leaders.&nbsp; They are community leaders.&nbsp; They are the ones who sponsor the local softball league.&nbsp; They are the ones who mentor and hire people from the community.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the role models.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>So, when we talk about extending and expanding this program, all of that we have in mind.<br><br>And to better understand, then, how programs like these can serve our best communities, in terms of the best and the brightest, this is the work that we are doing.<br><br>And today, informed by all of those conversations, we are announcing a number of improvements also &#8212; because we heard from folks when we had these meetings &#8212; so, a number of improvements to the Community Advantage program.<br><br>So, for example, we are simplifying program requirements so lenders can devote more of their resources to serving their borrowers and spend less time on the paperwork.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get rid of some of that bureaucracy.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There&#8217;s the lender section.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And we are updating program rules to allow those people who are borrowing to restructure their debt if they fall behind on payments.<br><br>You know, during the pandemic, community lenders demonstrated again and again how much good they do in their communities.&nbsp; So these reforms are intended to make it easier for more lenders to connect with more small businesses who need to borrow or make a loan.&nbsp; And this, of course, will unleash economic opportunity in communities around our country.<br><br>So, the bottom line is this: When small-business owners have the support they need, they create jobs.&nbsp; When small-business owners have the support they need, they drive innovation and inspire innovation.&nbsp; And they grow, as a result of all of that, our entire economy.<br><br>When we talk about how we are doing as a nation and the strength of our nation; and we look to, as a measure of that, the strength of our economy, then we must ask: How are our small businesses doing, and are we doing enough for them?<br><br>Because after all, the answer to all of that will lead us to also understanding: When they do well, it benefits us all.<br><br>And so, let us continue to all work together to address the inequities that stand in the way of the ambition and the aspirations of our communities.<br><br>Let us continue in the mission of encouraging the ambition and the aspiration.&nbsp; And that brings me, of course, before I conclude my comments, to the mission of the Greater Washington Partnership.<br><br>The $4.7 billion investment announced today, over $600 million of which will go to community lenders, is a major step forward not only for the Capital region and the people of this region, but, by example, the role modeling you are doing will benefit people around the country.<br><br>It is truly a model.&nbsp; And it is a model that can and should be replicated around our nation.<br><br>Our collective goal is to create an economy in which every person, wherever they live, has the opportunity to succeed and to thrive.<br><br>Thank you all very much.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 11:30 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
