<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 23:26:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-chancellor-olaf-scholz-of-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 23:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. welcomed Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany to the White House.&#160;President Biden reaffirmed his commitment to further strengthening U.S.-German relations and working with the new Chancellor to deepen the transatlantic partnership.&#160;The leaders discussed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders, reaffirmed their support&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. welcomed Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany to the White House.&nbsp;President Biden reaffirmed his commitment to further strengthening U.S.-German relations and working with the new Chancellor to deepen the transatlantic partnership.&nbsp;The leaders discussed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders, reaffirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and reiterated their commitment to preventing Russia from using energy as a weapon.&nbsp;The leaders also discussed Germany’s G7 Presidency, including taking stronger joint action to end the COVID-19 pandemic, building back better health security, tackling the climate crisis, and supporting an inclusive global economic recovery.&nbsp;The leaders committed to cooperate closely on challenges posed by China and to continue promoting stability and prosperity in the Western Balkans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 7,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/07/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-7-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:55 P.M. EST&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; I know we have a time limit because of the press avail with the Germans, so we will get to as many people as possible.&#160; I just have a couple of items for you at the top. Today, the White&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:55 P.M. EST<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; I know we have a time limit because of the press avail with the Germans, so we will get to as many people as possible.&nbsp; I just have a couple of items for you at the top.</p>



<p>Today, the White House Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment, led by Vice President Harris as Chair and Labor Secr- &#8212; and as well as Chair &#8212; as Chair and Labor Secretary &#8212; as well as Chair, and Labor Secretary Walsh as Vice-Chair –&nbsp;released publicly the report it delivered to President Biden&nbsp;that&nbsp;includes nearly 70 recommendations to promote worker organizing and collective bargaining.</p>



<p>The recommendations include ways to increase private-sector workers’ access to information about their existing right to join or organize a union &#8212; a hugely important issue for the President.</p>



<p>The President accepted the recommendations, and as a follow-up, the task force will submit a second report to the President in six months, which will describe progress in implementation and contain additional proposals for further action.</p>



<p>I also wanted to note that, today, the Secretary &#8212; Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack will be announcing that the Partnerships for Climate-Smart connection &#8212; Commodities program, in which the Department of Agriculture will invest $1 billion in partnerships to support America’s climate-smart farmers, ranchers, and forest landowners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So these funds will go to projects that promote farming, ranching, and forestry practices that either remove carbon from the atmosphere or cut greenhouse gas emissions.&nbsp; And the investment is the latest Biden administration initiative aimed at combatting climate change with a goal to cut the farm sector’s greenhouse gas emissions in half by 2030 and put the United States on a path to net-zero emissions by 2050.</p>



<p>Finally, I wanted to note: I have a Team USA water bottle out here today and a Team USA pin out here today.&nbsp; As you all know, we made a decision &#8212; the United States &#8212; not to send a diplomatic or official delegation to Beijing given the PRC’s ongoing genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang and other human rights abuses.&nbsp; And that was a clear statement and a clear policy made by our government.</p>



<p>But at the same time, we wanted to note Team USA has our full support.&nbsp; We’re behind them; we’re watching from home.&nbsp; And we want to thank them and their families for everything they have sacrificed over the course of time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lots of athletes to watch. &nbsp;I’ll just give a plug, because I’m an Olympics-obsessed person: Nathan Chen, we’re going to watch him; Chloe Kim; Mikaela Shiffrin, you’ve got lots of more chances.</p>



<p>Anyway, we’ll be rooting for our U.S. athletes even as we made a very important statement about our concerns about Beijing’s and the Chinese human rights abuses.</p>



<p>With that, let’s go ahead.&nbsp; Colleen, kick us off.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, regarding Dr. Lander, I wondered if he should have been reprimanded more strongly, given the President&#8217;s pledge on his first day in office to, you know, fire anybody who mistreated their employees.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me just give you an overview of what we have done to date.&nbsp; And I know there may be more questions on this, of course, which we welcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has been crystal clear with all of us about his high expectations of how he and his staff should be creating a respectful work environment.</p>



<p>And one of the steps we took early on in the administration was to institute a Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy across the Executive Office of the President &#8212; something that was done early on.</p>



<p>It was because of this policy and this process that when these &#8212; when the complaint was filed, a full and thorough investigation was conducted pursuant to that policy.</p>



<p>In addition, following the conclusion of the thorough investigation into these actions, senior White House officials conveyed directly to Dr. Lander that his behavior was inappropriate and the corrective actions that were needed, which were &#8212; which the White House will monitor for compliance moving forward.</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note that Dr. Lander also sent a message to his staff outlining some of the steps he&#8217;s intending to take to build a respectful work environment.&nbsp; And certainly, we would encourage those.&nbsp; And again, the team &#8212; the senior team will be watching for compliance to these steps.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It looks like he’s had a history of, you know, possible mistreatment of his employees over a long period of time.&nbsp; How can you be sure that this reprimand will stick?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just reiterate, again, that &#8212; well, let me start with the first part of your question.</p>



<p>Each nominee undergoes a thorough vetting process as a part of their nomination and confirmation process.&nbsp; And, of course, we look carefully to ensure each candidate&#8217;s suitability for the role they&#8217;re chosen for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. Lander’s record was thoroughly examined as a part of his confirmation, and he received bipartisan support, including final confirmation with a voice vote.</p>



<p>But again, once we were made aware of the complaint, we launched a thorough investigation, and compliance with the recommendations is &#8212; will be &#8212; will be required in this regard.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On Ukraine, Zelenskyy’s office said yesterday that a diplomatic solution seems much more likely than war, and then we saw Jake Sullivan say yesterday that an invasion could come at any day.&nbsp; Can you help us square the difference here and why there still seems to be such a dark assessment &#8212; a stark difference in assessing the threat?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what our National Security Advisor also conveyed during some interviews with a range of your networks yesterday was that we&#8217;re pursuing a two-track approach, which includes deterrence and diplomacy, but that we are ready either way for whatever decision President Putin might make.&nbsp; And we don&#8217;t have a new assessment of his decision and where he stands on it.</p>



<p>We also need to be prepared.&nbsp; Being prepared is exactly what we can do from the U.S. government, in coordination and in partnership with our NATO Allies, our partners in Eastern Europe, and of course, the Ukrainians.&nbsp; And that is what we&#8217;re focused on.&nbsp; So, we don&#8217;t actually see it as a conflict.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Kyiv wrong, then, on this?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In terms of the preparations?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A diplomatic solution being more likely than war.&nbsp; It seems hard to square that with Sullivan saying that an invasion could come at any day.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we would certainly prefer a diplomatic solution.&nbsp; I think that’s everybody’s preference and everybody’s hope.</p>



<p>But again, this is up to &#8212; remains up to President Putin to make a decision about which path he is going to take.&nbsp; We don’t have an assessment of that, so what our focus is on is preparing for a range of contingencies, including in coordination with the Ukrainians, making sure they have the supplies they need, the humanitarian assistance they need, the security assistance they need.&nbsp; And we’re doing that &#8212; we’re doing that consistently, even while we are closely watching the buildup of troops on the border.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To switch topics if I may, Delta’s CEO is asking for the administration’s help in creating this no-fly list for unruly passengers.&nbsp; Is that something the administration supports?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not had a chance to talk to our team about that.&nbsp; I can see if there’s any opinion on that from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And, quickly, a housekeeping thing: Do you have a sense of when the President will start meeting with SCOTUS candidates?&nbsp; And if any of these meetings happen in Delaware, where the President &#8212; where there are not visitor logs, does the White House pledge to disclose that those meetings took place?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, at this point, I don’t have any more details about the process to outline for you.&nbsp; As you know, what the President has been focused on over the course of the last several days is reviewing and consulting with internal team members on a group of qualified nominees.&nbsp; He also has been engaging, as you all know, with Democrats and Republicans and consulting closely to &#8212; as a part of the “advice and consent,” &#8220;consent&#8221; part of his &#8212; the role of picking a nominee to move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>After last week’s meeting with Chairman Durbin and Ranking Member Grassley, the President and Vice President and their senior teams, including White House Counsel Dana Remus, have also spoken to the range of additional members of Congress and outside legal experts, and that engagement will continue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There, is of course, a vetting process that takes place.&nbsp; We have not outlined that in detail from here.&nbsp; And, of course, we will venture to be as transparent as possible, even as we are working to protect the process as the President is making his decision.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; With the meeting today between the President and the German Chancellor, does the President view Germany as a reliable partner on this issue?&nbsp; When it comes to troop movements or sending weapons to Ukraine or talking publicly about sanctions, they&#8217;ve been much less aggressive than other NATO Allies.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;d also note that Germany is the second-largest donor to Ukraine and Europe.&nbsp; The President has also noted, as we have noted, that different countries make different contributions.&nbsp; I think that the Chancellor also did an interview with the Washington Post this morning where he spoke to that in more detail.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have a close, abiding, important relationship with the Germans.&nbsp; That includes having forces stationed in Germany, which has a huge strategic value to the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So today is an opportunity for the President to build on the relationship with the Chancellor, to continue to build on the long and abiding relationship with the Germans.&nbsp; And we are united in our view of the actions &#8212; the potential actions of Russian leaders and united in our efforts to hold them accountable.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s your understanding about where the Chancellor stands right now when it comes to including Nord Stream 2 in potential sanctions if Russia invades.&nbsp; They’ve really danced around that issue and haven&#8217;t given a clear answer about whether they would, in fact, be willing to put that pipeline on hold.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know you all will have the opportunity to, I&#8217;m sure, ask him this question himself.&nbsp; And I, of course, don&#8217;t speak for him.&nbsp; But what I can reiterate here is that we said we’d work with Germany to ensure that Nord Stream 2 does not move forward should Russia invade, and that remains the position &#8212; agreed position.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Emmanuel Macron is meeting with President Putin today, and Chancellor Scholz will be meeting with him in the coming weeks.&nbsp; So, has President Biden asked either of them to deliver a message to Putin when they meet with him?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s important to remember that there are a range of different diplomatic talks happening at the same time through different formats.&nbsp; Some are leader to leader; some are through NATO; some are through the OSCE.&nbsp; And this is reflective of that &#8212; these conversations that are happening.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, the President spoke with President Macron yesterday.&nbsp; And, of course, that close discussion and coordination with a range of leaders is part of how we&#8217;re approaching this.<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is multilayered diplomacy at work here.&nbsp; So &#8212; and we are also directly in touch with the Russians ourselves.&nbsp; So, I wouldn&#8217;t &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t look at it through that prism.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You guys are &#8212; said in a background call that part of the discussion with Germany today was about continuing to prepare this robust sanctions package, but we&#8217;ve been talking about sanctions for months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So if Germany is as aligned with its Allies as they &#8212; you all are conveying, why isn&#8217;t this sanctions package already complete?&nbsp; Why isn&#8217;t that done already, in terms of figuring out what it looks like?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our internal sanctions package?&nbsp; Or what sanctions package?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because you&#8217;ve said consistently that the sanctions that you&#8217;re preparing are in close consultation with Allies, including Germany.&nbsp; And that conversation is, you know, obviously happening again today, as we&#8217;re getting warnings that Russia could at any moment take significant action.<br>&nbsp;<br>So the discussion about sanctions has been over the course of several months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why isn&#8217;t it done yet if Germany is as on board with the rest of the NATO Alliance as they&#8217;re projecting to be?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, Jacqui, I mean, as we&#8217;ve said before: One, I think there is alignment that we will work with Germany to ensure that Nord Stream 2 does not move forward, which is obviously a key &#8212; a key point of discussion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note, just &#8212; and reiterate that it&#8217;s not operational at this time, and there&#8217;s no oil flowing through the pipeline.&nbsp; That has been a key point of discussion, and that is agreed to.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also reiterate what we&#8217;ve said in here in the past is that: While we have our own sanctions package prepared, which we&#8217;ve been consulting with and briefing members of Congress on, and others do &#8212; and we&#8217;re united in the effort to put forward an economic sanctions package that has significant consequences, as are our European partners &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s identical.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One point to clarify: You said that that is agreed to on Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; I just want to clarify: The Germans have &#8212; are you saying that the Germans have committed not to bring Nord Stream 2 online if Russia invades?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I&#8217;m not going to get into the private diplomatic conversations, but it &#8212; we have said a number of times that if they invade, it will not move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, I wanted to ask about Dr. Lander again.&nbsp; I know you got a question on this earlier, but does the fact that Dr. Lander has a job, still, cheapen the President&#8217;s promise to fire anyone who treats colleagues with disrespect on the spot?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I would just reiterate that the President takes his commitment to having a respectful work environment incredibly seriously.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s something that he conveys clearly to all of us on a regular basis.&nbsp; That is why we put in place &#8212; in part put in place a safe and respectful workplace policy, which is how &#8212; which is the process through which this thorough investigation proceeded through and the process through which, again, that there was an internal investigation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Dr. Lander &#8212; obviously, his behavior was inappropriate, and corrective actions needed to be taken, and that was clearly conveyed through this process.&nbsp; And he will be held to account for delivering on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, real quick &#8212; one third topic.&nbsp; We got announcements that in Delaware and New Jersey, the governors are going to be ending mask mandates coming up pretty soon.&nbsp; What is the White House view on these kinds of announcements, given that in Virginia, Governor Youngkin faced a lot of pushback from Democrats for making similar changes to the mask policy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, but they weren&#8217;t actually that similar because what happened here in New Jersey and a couple of other states you mentioned is that they pulled back the requirement.&nbsp; They didn&#8217;t make it more difficult for schools, school administrators, and local officials to keep requirements that they made a determination would keep their schools safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect that President Macron and President Biden will have a follow-up conversation so that he can relay any, sort of, impressions that he got from his face-to-face meeting?&nbsp; And would you commit to letting us know if that conversation happens?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly would.&nbsp; On the latter, I would say that, as you know, the President spoke with President Macron just yesterday.&nbsp; Again, there’s multilayers of diplomacy happening at many times.&nbsp; Sometimes those readouts happen at the Secretary of State level or National Security Advisor.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I can assure you we are in close contact with the French; of course, the Germans; and all of our NATO partners and Allies.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the Pentagon, John Kirby has talked about the possibility of additional U.S. forces being moved to Europe.&nbsp; Has the President requested any additional recommendations from Secretary Austin?&nbsp; And is he reviewing any other plans along those lines?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would just say that we are in constant contact, of course, with the Defense Department but also with our NATO partners about what their needs are.&nbsp; So, I don’t have anything to predict for you other than to reiterate what was said last week, which is that we leave the door open to that possibility.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that’s an active possibility at this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It always has been.&nbsp; And I would remind everyone that there are thousands of troops that are on the &#8212; in Eastern European countries as a part of our NATO Alliance, so this is to bolster up the troops that are already there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back on the mask mandate question in New Jersey and other states: The CDC is still recommending universal masking in schools, so &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s correct.&nbsp; And that still remains our recommendation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So are you pleased with and fine with the New Jersey governor&#8217;s decision?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, our advice to every school district is to abide by public health guidelines.&nbsp; It continues to be, at this point, that the CDC is advising that masks can delay, reduce transmission.&nbsp; There are also a number of other mitigation measures that we&#8217;ve put in place, but that continues to be CDC guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s always been up to local school districts to determine how they implement.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does it say, then, that a governor like Phil Murphy, who’s been so closely aligned with the policies of this administration, would get ahead of the medical experts and say, “Never mind what they say; school districts, you decide”?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s always been up to school districts.&nbsp; That&#8217;s always been our point of view and always been our policy from here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And our policy from the federal government is to continue to advise everybody to abide by public health guidelines.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think it signals that perhaps the public believes it&#8217;s time for a change in the federal guidelines &#8212; the CDC’s guidance?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we certainly understand and have seen in polling that the public is tired of COVID.&nbsp; We understand that.&nbsp; So are we.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there has been some good signs recently where there has been a decrease in hospitalizations around the country.&nbsp; And again, we&#8217;re in constant touch about &#8212; about what it looks like moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>But our responsibility, as the federal government, is to rely on the data and the science that is being analyzed by our public health experts.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to rely on that for what recommendations we&#8217;re making.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; A couple things.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve reported that U.S. officials are losing patience with the Chinese in these negotiations about them fulfilling their purchase commitments under the phase one trade deal signed by Donald Trump.&nbsp; What is the perspective from the White House in terms of what can you do? &nbsp;And does the President intend to weigh in on this issue?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s a good question, Andrea.&nbsp; I mean, we &#8212; as you know, they did not abide by their purchase agreements.&nbsp; We know that factually; we&#8217;ve seen that.&nbsp; This is really under the purview of the USTR and our Trade Representative, Katherine Tai.&nbsp; We remain in close touch with her about that, but I&#8217;d really point you to them for any updates on the process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, this situation on the Canadian bor- &#8212; or in Ottawa, the truckers protest: There does seem to be evidence that these truckers are getting support from conservative forces or right-wing forces in the U.S.&nbsp; Are you investigating that at all?&nbsp; Is there any, kind of, you know, involvement of U.S. authorities in looking at those money flows going to these truckers?&nbsp; And are you concerned about it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say a couple of things. &nbsp;This doesn&#8217;t answer your question, but I just want to get this out there too on this particular topic, and then I&#8217;ll come around &#8212; I promise.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have been engaged since the outset &#8212; well, some of it hopefully answers your question, I should say &#8212; of the protests.&nbsp; There have been zero impacts to CBP operations, which is a question people have understandably been asking us.&nbsp; Some &#8212; some shipments were rerouted by our law enforcement partners to other points of entry due to road closures.&nbsp; Some shippers have had to reroute.&nbsp; But CBP has been in communication throughout to ensure shipments can be cleared and onto the normal routes.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of an assessment of any other engagement from here, we have &#8212; we don&#8217;t really have any update on that or any investigation to read out at this point in time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, you know, the Federal &#8212; the Federal Reserve nominees have run into a little bit of criticism from Republicans, in particular Sarah Raskin.&nbsp; Are you concerned that you&#8217;re &#8212; I mean, especially given the absence of Senator Luján, are you concerned that you might not get all those nominees through and that you may have to withdraw Sarah Raskin?&nbsp; There’s just been another dust &#8212; dustup overnight?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; She is one of the most, if not the most, qualified person to ever be nominated to this position.&nbsp; She just gave extensive answers at a hearing last week, and she would be someone the President would be proud to have in that role, as independent as it may be.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, no, that is not an assessment or a prediction we&#8217;re making.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, two questions for you.&nbsp; One, the Secretary-General of NATO has recently talked about the possibility of a more permanent military presence in Europe in response to Russia.&nbsp; Where does the Biden administration stand on that issue?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had a permanent military presence in Europe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You mean in addition?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, a longer &#8212; a longer-term, more permanent presence in Europe.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve always had one.&nbsp; But you mean a plussed-up one?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would really point &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the language that was used was “longer term.”<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, but we&#8217;ve always had one, so it&#8217;s been very long term to date.&nbsp; But I would say: If &#8212; if he is asking &#8212; and I have not seen his comments about increased, plussed-up presence in some of the places from U.S. troops that we&#8217;ve had &#8212; I would really point to the Department of Defense.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, we would &#8212; we would be in touch with our NATO Allies and partners about that.&nbsp; But that is really related to the aggression at the border that we&#8217;re seeing in Ukraine, but there&#8217;s been tens of thousands of troops in Europe for some time now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on the topic of masking in schools, if you could just clarify &#8212; I know you’ve talked about this a little bit already: Do you think that at some point in the future, even if that point isn&#8217;t now, it would be appropriate for there to be updated federal guidelines just to avoid confusion?&nbsp; I think the administration has been clear that on other issues, there are sort of messaging issues that could have been a little bit more clear coming from the administration.&nbsp; So on this issue, do you think that that might be appropriate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the guidance is very clear, which is that we recommend masking in schools.&nbsp; That is the recommendation from the CDC.&nbsp; It is also true that at some point, when the science and the data warrants, of course our hope is that that&#8217;s no longer the recommendation.&nbsp; And they are continually assessing that.&nbsp; But the guidance is very clear.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is also true that it has always been up to local school districts to make determinations about how to implement these policies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just to follow on that, you had said that you guys are in “constant contact” with the CDC about what it looks like to move forward.&nbsp; Can we expect the President to provide some sort of roadmap for how states can transition out of a state of emergency &#8212; kind of akin to what he did with the winter strategy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re in constant discussion internally about the moment we&#8217;re in, as it relates to COVID.&nbsp; And, of course, as the President said, I think during his press conference just two weeks ago &#8212; a week and a half ago &#8212; you know, we certainly don&#8217;t see this moment now as the new normal, right?&nbsp; And we &#8212; but we want to get to a point where we are not &#8212; where COVID is not disrupting our daily lives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;m sure you will hear more from the President about that, but that&#8217;s &#8212; we&#8217;re constantly discussing that internally.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask one more just for our colleague?&nbsp; The Education Department announced Friday it was going to withdraw its appeal for a $100,000 student loan forgiveness court decision.&nbsp; I’m wondering if you could shed any light on why the Biden administration reversed its decision to appeal the case and if there&#8217;s any plans to fight other bankruptcy cases.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would really point you to the Department of Education and the Department of Justice, potentially. &nbsp;But I will check and see if there&#8217;s anything more we can offer on that from here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I got one more on masks.&nbsp; I just &#8212; I was wondering if I could just ask it this way &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the President’s wife is an educator.&nbsp; He just heard from governors across the country last week, many of whom were saying, “This is enough.&nbsp; It’s time for a new normal.”&nbsp; Where is he on this after taking all of these inputs?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President is not a private citizen; he is President of the United States, right?&nbsp; So his &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you’re his spokesperson, so I’m asking you &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, but I guess I&#8217;m saying it&#8217;s different than asking kind of a person on the street.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; I mean, I&#8217;m just &#8212; you know, it is different because he is the President; he needs to project the &#8212; what the data and the science is telling us.&nbsp; And the data and science &#8212; where we get that guidance from is the CDC and our health and medical experts.&nbsp; Their guidance remains &#8212; continues to be that, in schools, people should mask up.&nbsp; So that is what we are continuing to convey and recommend.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, can you tell us any more about where he will be going on Thursday?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not quite yet, but hopefully &#8212; maybe by the end of the day.&nbsp; We hope to have some more details very soon.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Going back to Dr. Lander, &#8220;the investigation found credible evidence of multiple women having complained to other staff about negative interactions with him,&#8221; with a pattern of abusive and disrespectful behavior.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Again, the President, at the outset of this administration said, “I will fire you on the spot.&nbsp; On the spot.&nbsp; No ifs, ands, or buts.”&nbsp; So why is he not being fired?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Matt, let me first say that no one is suggesting that this behavior is acceptable &#8212; quite the opposite.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that since he&#8217;s &#8212; he made the comment he did &#8212; which I think was one of the first few days in office, if I remember correctly &#8212; we put in place this &#8220;Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy&#8221; to ensure there was a mechanism &#8212; right?&nbsp; &#8212; to conduct investigations, as was conducted in this case, that can be thorough, that result in some actions and some steps.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s exactly what happened here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, this is not acceptable behavior.&nbsp; Dr. Lander is expected to comply.&nbsp; And he will be monitored for compliance, because having a safe workplace environment is imperative to the President, the Vice President, the First Lady, the Second Gentleman &#8212; all of us who work here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But are there ways in which he&#8217;s being held to account if he&#8217;s not being fired?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, as I outlined a little bit earlier, but let me reiterate a little bit: In addition to a full and thorough investigation, he was &#8212; it was conveyed through meetings with senior White House officials directly that his behavior was inappropriate, corrective action was needed, and we will monitor for compliance to that &#8212; to those actions that were required.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Again, I think you may have also seen, or it was reported, that he also sent a note to his staff conveying his commitment to abiding by that.&nbsp; And we certainly hope that that is the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it doesn&#8217;t sound like a zero-tolerance policy if that&#8217;s the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our objective and the President&#8217;s objective is to prevent this behavior from ever happening again.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the Supreme Court.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just &#8212; I wanted to ask about the President&#8217;s efforts to engage with Republicans &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and whether that&#8217;s the best use of his time, considering what he has said about the public not wanting him to be the “President Senator.”<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is true.&nbsp; And I think he has &#8212; he has not been the “President Senator” over the course of the last period of time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s also true that he takes his role as President and going through the process of selecting and nominating an eminently qualified nominee very seriously.&nbsp; And in his experience as the former Chairman of the Judiciary Community [sic] &#8212; Committee, that includes consultation with key members of the Senate, and that is an important part of the process in this case.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think what he was referring to in those comments was hours and hours and hours of endless closed-door meetings as it related to negotiating through the course of the fall.&nbsp; But this is a opening to a lifetime appointment &#8212; an opening on the Supreme Court, which is a lifetime appointment &#8212; something the President takes very seriously.&nbsp; And consulting with Republicans and Democrats is an important part of that process, in his view.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Nord Stream 2, you have &#8212; you’ve made clear the administration&#8217;s position.&nbsp; I did want to understand, though: Is the administration ready to take some type of action without Germany to stop Nord Stream 2?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand your question.&nbsp; I just am not in a position to detail further, other than to convey that it will not move forward if Russia invades.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Dr. Lander, if I may.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about what some of the specific corrective changes that were ordered &#8212; what some of those were?&nbsp; And also, has the President spoken with Dr. Lander since the investigation was completed?&nbsp; And does he worry about this overshadowing Moonshot?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the President&#8217;s hope &#8212; all of our hope &#8212; is certainly that Dr. Lander will abide by &#8212; making changes, that he will be held to account to &#8212; to comply fully with the steps that needed to be taken.<br>&nbsp;<br>I can see if there&#8217;s more specific details.&nbsp; I certainly understand why you&#8217;re asking.&nbsp; But overall, it&#8217;s ensuring that he is creating a work environment that people feel safe, they feel supported, and that is respectful.&nbsp; And that is the overarching policy that needs to be implemented moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>You saw him send a note to staff last week, and now it is whether he is implementing those policies moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have they spoken?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any conversations between them to read out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Just following up on a question asked earlier about the &#8212; what you said isn&#8217;t a split between Ukraine&#8217;s messaging and your guys&#8217; messaging &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the risk of an invasion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Can you walk us through the communication strategy &#8212; like what you&#8217;re trying to highlight, given the risk of invasion, and why you&#8217;re trying to highlight it more strongly than Ukraine?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Do you see it as &#8212; you know, sounding the alarm more vocally, is there an advantage that you see in sort of preventing Putin from taking any further steps here?&nbsp; Have we &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; And I can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t speak for the communication strategy of the Ukrainians; only they can speak to that.&nbsp; But I can tell you that what we have been trying to do &#8212; we obviously have a range of information &#8212; a broad range of information that we have been able to gather here and also through partnership with our allies across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our objective, as we talked about a little bit on Friday, is to deny Russia the opportunity to use some of the tactics, sometimes some of the lies that they have done in the past to justify an invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; That&#8217;s straight out of their playbook.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have seen tactics they have used in the past, where a few years ago, Russia&#8217;s Defense Ministry falsely accused the United States of running a clandestine biological weapons lab in the country of Georgia, enabling them &#8212; their efforts to destabilize the Georgian government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They used to fabricate stories in Syria about how attacks on international aid convoys were undertaken by rebels or terrorists.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve &#8212; so we have undertaken an effort to, in some cases, declassify information; in other cases, describe in as great of detail as we can without putting at risk sources and methods what we&#8217;re seeing, what information we&#8217;re evaluating so that they are &#8212; it is &#8212; it makes it more difficult for them to lay a predicate for invading Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So that is why we&#8217;re doing it.&nbsp; I&#8217;d also note that a number of your news organizations of course have reporters near there who are seeing the troop buildup.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So there is justification and validation from even that, but also from our partners around the world as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Senator Manchin expressed confidence over the weekend that reforms of the Electoral Count Act will pass.&nbsp; Would the President be supportive of signing reforms to the Electoral Count Act if it were to pass?&nbsp; Or would he require that there be elements of the bill &#8212; voting rights bill included in order to do so?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would really point you to Senator Klobuchar, who is really one of the point people leading this effort.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, we have said many times that the Electoral Count Act, while we support the effort, is not a replacement for voting rights legislation for a range of reasons.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know there&#8217;s a lot of discussions on the Hill about what that may look like or want a final package.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t outline that from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And China used a young Uyghur athlete to carry the Olympic Torch during the Opening Ceremony of the Games in Beijing.&nbsp; What did the administration make of that, given the ongoing genocide against Uyghurs in Xinjiang?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know that our U.N. Ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, spoke to this yesterday.&nbsp; So let me reiterate what I thought were some very powerful comments &#8212; if I&#8217;m remembering &#8212; I know someone spoke to it, but I believe it was her &#8212; that we can&#8217;t allow this to be a distraction from, exactly as you said, the human rights abuses, the genocide that we’re seeing in parts of China.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That is why we did not send a diplomatic delegation, even as we’re cheering for our U.S. athletes.&nbsp; Diplomacy is complicated, as we know, but we can&#8217;t allow it to be a distraction from what we know is happening to many people in China.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to reiterate, on Inauguration Day, President Biden said he would fire anyone that treated another colleague with disrespect, talked down to someone &#8212; and they would &#8212; he would fire them &#8220;on the spot&#8221; &#8212; “No, ifs, ands, or buts.”&nbsp; So what is the White House’s message to people that work in this building and throughout the federal government that took the President at his word and don’t understand why Dr. Lander has not been fired?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our message &#8212; and thank you for your question &#8212; is that the President has crystal-clear expectations with all of us about how we are to treat our colleagues, treat people who work for us, and that is what he expects for people across the building.<br>&nbsp;<br>It is because of those comments that he made early on, in part, that we put in place a Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy that was the mechanism for which this thorough investigation went forward.&nbsp; And it also &#8212; it is based on that that their investigation &#8212; from that came the meeting that Dr. Lander had with senior White House officials where it was made clear what steps he was required to take and that we will be complying and watching for compliance with those steps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And our objective is, of course, to prevent any of this behavior from happening again in the future.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the overarching objective.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But those weren’t comments; those were a promise.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he &#8212; we put in place a policy to ensure there is a mechanism for investigating and a mechanism for preventing this type of behavior from repeating itself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he promised to fire people that did this, and he hasn’t fired the individual the White House found violated what he said.&nbsp; (Inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand.&nbsp; And, again, let me just reiterate: Nothing about his behavior is acceptable to anyone here &#8212; at all.&nbsp; Quite the opposite.&nbsp; Let me be clear about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there is now a process in place, that was not in place at the time, to evaluate and determine what the next step &#8212; the steps should be taken in the event that any behavior like this occurs to prevent it from happening in the future.&nbsp; That is exactly what happened in this case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, fellow federal employees shouldn&#8217;t expect that people will be fired if they treat colleagues with disrespect?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I think I&#8217;ve outlined very clearly what the process was.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re just saying it’s legal &#8212; that it’s legal what you’re doing.&nbsp; Correct?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions for you.&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp; Two questions &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s more than &#8212; it&#8217;s more than that.&nbsp; I think it’s clear that we are putting in place &#8212; we had put in place a process &#8212; an internal process &#8212; to ensure that there was a thorough investigation, that the &#8212; that it was evaluated, that steps were taken for this individual, Dr. Lander, to meet with senior officials to make clear that there were requirements that would be put in place and he was expected to comply with them to prevent this behavior from ever happening again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; First, on Senator Manchin, on Build Back Better: He reiterated again his view that that structure is done.&nbsp; And he said he wants regular order for any pieces of that (inaudible); that means potentially weeks &#8212; hearings, all of that.&nbsp; Is the President on board with that idea of hearings, markups?&nbsp; And if not, what&#8217;s his plan for elements of Build Back Better to move forward?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak for Senator Manchin; I know you’re not asking me to, but what there is broad agreement on and support for is taking steps to lower costs for the American people, whether it&#8217;s Medicare or whether it’s the ability to negotiate the price of prescription drugs &#8212; something broadly supported; whether it&#8217;s lowering the cost of childcare, eldercare; making sure that the tax system is more fair.</p>



<p>In terms of the mechanisms and the legislative process, I just don&#8217;t have any more predictions for you in terms of how it will proceed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on jobs, a positive report on Friday, by and large.&nbsp; However, Black unemployment is still twice the rate of white unemployment.&nbsp; What is the White House doing?&nbsp; What does the White House think needs to be done to deal with that, especially for Black men?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, just as a reminder, that there is still &#8212; as much as the President oversaw the largest creation of jobs &#8212; job creation ever in one year in American history, it means there&#8217;s more work to be done, because there are still a lot of work that needs to be done to level the playing field, to ensure that small businesses have the assistance they need, including Black-owned small businesses; that we are doing everything we can to ensure there is opportunity for a range of parts of the economic world.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A few on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Congressman Clyburn says that the President will need bipartisan support for his Supreme Court pick, citing Senator Luján’s stroke and hospitalization.&nbsp; Is it the White House&#8217;s position that Republican votes would be helpful in the Senate, or do you view them as necessary?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve, I think, conveyed from here that we haven&#8217;t set a deadline for when a vote should be.&nbsp; We have said we want it to happen as expeditiously as possible.&nbsp; We have also said, and I&#8217;ll reiterate, that because the President has every intention of nominating an eminently qualified Black woman to serve on the Supreme Court, that this is a person who should warrant bipartisan support.&nbsp; And that is certainly what we hope for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaking of the timeline, the President has said that he intends to make that announcement by the end of the month.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has that timeline shifted in any way?&nbsp; Might he make this announcement before President’s Day weekend?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; February is February, so I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you in terms of when in February, quite, at this point, it will be.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And one more question, if you don’t mind.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As far as where and when he could meet with the potential nominees &#8212; he&#8217;s going to Camp David this weekend.&nbsp; Is the President going to meet with potential Supreme Court justices at Camp David this weekend?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything for you on the process of how the President will interview nominee &#8212; potential candidates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Does the White House have a reaction to the death of the Navy SEAL candidate who died after completing what&#8217;s known as “Hell Week”?&nbsp; And has the President spoken to his family, or does he have plans to?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have &#8212; not &#8212; not yet, Karen.&nbsp; I will &#8212; we will check and see where that is at this point.&nbsp; Obviously, there&#8217;ll be an investigation here.&nbsp; I&#8217;d point you to the Department of Defense for any specifics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a starting point here, obviously, our heart goes out to the family members, the community, the friends, and we look &#8212; we will look for more details to come out of an investigation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And would there be any thought given to reexamining that training as part of that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I would really point you to the Department of Defense, and the President would certainly look to his Defense Department and leadership to make any recommendations in that regard.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; First, on the Olympics: Does the White House agree with Speaker Nancy Pelosi that American athletes shouldn&#8217;t speak out against Beijing for their own safety?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know we saw those comments, obviously.&nbsp; I think they were last week, if I remember correctly.&nbsp; The President&#8217;s view is that, first, we support our athletes 100 percent.&nbsp; (Holds up Team USA water bottle).&nbsp; Yay.&nbsp; All athletes have the right to freely express themselves, and that is the case in Beijing at the Olympics; it is the case anywhere.&nbsp; They will make those choices as individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s the responsibility of China to live up to its own obligations to maintain a safe environment for all athletes at these games.&nbsp; The world will be watching.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we leave it up to individuals.&nbsp; We certainly support the right to peaceful protest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the First Lady&#8217;s comments this morning about &#8212; she said &#8212; she conceded that free tuition for community college is dead; it’s out of Build Back Better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m wondering, kind of, what was the thought about having her give that message.&nbsp; Is the White House trying to restart negotiations on Build Back Better?&nbsp; Was there some sort of underlying intent to have the First Lady come out and say that this morning?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think it was speaking from her heart about her view that free community college would benefit kids, young people, level the playing field across the country.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something the President agrees with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think you all have seen many, many iterations of the Build Back Better legislation &#8212; or options &#8212; in recent months.&nbsp; It hasn&#8217;t been in there in a while, so I think it was speaking &#8212; she was speaking from her heart about how beneficial she thinks that funding and that support would be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, April.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, two topics.&nbsp; One, recently, a Black man was killed in Minnesota over a no-knock warrant.&nbsp; Has the White House taken note of this?&nbsp; And does this bring a fresh &#8212; a renewed call for this executive order &#8212; this police reform executive order, as well as the standalone pieces that are potentials on police reform on Capitol Hill?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely. &nbsp;And it should.&nbsp; Let me reiterate, because I asked a little bit about this, this morning, as well. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, one, let me first say that we mourn the tragic death of Amir Locke, and our thoughts and prayers are with his family.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is committed to ensuring fair, impartial, and effective policing in keeping our communities safe.&nbsp; These goals go hand-in-hand, in our &#8212; in his view, with what we can achieve by building trust between the police and communities they serve.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, back in September, Attorney General Garland issued a new policy impoving [sic] &#8212; imposing restrictions on the use of no-knock warrants, chokeholds, and carotid restraints by federal agents.&nbsp; Obviously, that&#8217;s for federal agents, so that&#8217;s limited &#8212; not to local. &nbsp;But &#8212; you know, I know you follow this closely but for others.<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden &#8212; the reason he has been such a strong supporter &#8212; one of the reasons &#8212; of the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act is that it would further restrict the use of no-knock warrants across the country, incentivizing funding &#8212; by using funding as an incentive.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have been engaging with, as you know, civil rights groups, a number of law enforcement groups.&nbsp; All agree on the need to reform the use of no-knock warrants.&nbsp; That is &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of agreement on that to keep both citizens and law enforcement officers safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President is examining the possibility of extending those restrictions to other federal agencies through actions &#8212; executive actions that he would have the power to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think you all saw Susan Rice convey last week that we&#8217;re not there yet.&nbsp; We want to make sure we do any action through the administration the right way and it&#8217;s thorough, but certainly, that&#8217;s part of what&#8217;s being looked at.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And on the second topic: There is a serious shroud of secrecy around the nominees of the Supreme Court, understandably.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve got two questions on this.&nbsp; One, what&#8217;s traditional about the process?&nbsp; And then, what is very unique to the process because of the historical nature?&nbsp; If you can tell us. &nbsp;And I&#8217;m sure you can give us something.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, no, no, it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a very thoughtful question.&nbsp; I was just trying to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, it is.&nbsp; Yes, it is.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I walked right into that one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, you did.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I walked right into that one.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I think is unique in this moment is that the President is someone who has served as the Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, as the Vice President when there were a number of nominees &#8212; historic &#8212; many historic &#8212; a number of historic nominees who were nominated and confirmed by the Senate. &nbsp;And he takes the process and the seriousness &#8212; the need for it to be thorough &#8212; he&#8217;s very focused on it.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I don&#8217;t know that that&#8217;s unique.&nbsp; Obviously, every President, I would hope, takes the process seriously.&nbsp; But he also takes, as is &#8212; there was a question earlier about this &#8212; the component about advice part of it very seriously, in terms of consulting with Republicans and Democrats in the process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, what is unique about this moment?&nbsp; You know, that’s a good &#8212; I want to read your article about this to hear what you have to say.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, you &#8212; we’ve got a lot of articles already.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay. &nbsp;Well, your next article about it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, I think it&#8217;s safe to say that there are some criticisms that have been out there, without any names being confirmed, that are unique to &#8212; to having the possibility, the likelihood, the plan for a woman of color being nominated for this position.&nbsp; And the types of language that are used by some to describe who the President might pick as a nominee are unique to that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you just spoke, a moment ago, about advice on &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; his nominees.&nbsp; We know the internal advice, particularly from the Counsel&#8217;s Office, as well as the Vice President. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But externally &#8212; when is the last time the President talked to Anita Hill?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; To Anita Hill?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to check on that for you, April.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is she part of this process?&nbsp; Because we know there are &#8212; we know that he talked, and they had a very real conversation before he, you know, became President-elect.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is she &#8212; I want to know, one: Has he consul- &#8212; when is the last time he consulted with her?&nbsp; And if she is part &#8212; because the names of those who are on the outside are dribbling out &#8212; and is she one of those, and he respects her opinion.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will check with our team who are overseeing the process.&nbsp; And you &#8212; you&#8217;re familiar with who that internal team is.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know we probably have to wrap up soon here.&nbsp; Go ahead, Ed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Two things.&nbsp; On gas prices: So, if President Biden has said, with oil prices, that he released the Strategic Petroleum Reserves and that brought down prices &#8212; actually, on that day, the price of oil actually rose and went down for the Omicron variant as the fears of lockdown.&nbsp; Today, oil prices are $91 &#8212; more than $91 a barrel.&nbsp; Is there any consideration by the administration to reversing any of the policies or regulations or removing some to encourage more drilling in the U.S. for future demand?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me tell you what we are doing.&nbsp; Of course &#8212; we, of course, tapped the Strategic Petroleum Reserve; sometimes they take some time to be digested into the system.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also worked with a number of countries around the world to do something similar.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been engaged with OPEC nation countries about the need for the supply available to meet the demand.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve also called out the record profits made by oil companies, which should not be lost as an issue as consumers are looking at the price that they are paying at &#8212; the prices they are paying.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then I would also note that you should check with oil companies on whether they are tapping into all of the land leases they have available at their disposal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what about the &#8212; what about &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe they are.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about encouraging the investment in drilling in other places in the U.S.?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I think the President&#8217;s view is that we are &#8212; it is a huge advantage to us to be a leader in the clean energy transition.&nbsp; And over the course of years and decades, we&#8217;ve become a clean energy superpower because, ultimately, that&#8217;s such &#8212; not just where the jobs are, it&#8217;s where the strategic advantage will lie in 10, 20, 30 years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note again &#8212; and you can ask the oil companies this &#8212; there is land they&#8217;re not all drilling on.&nbsp; Every lease is not used.&nbsp; I&#8217;d encourage them &#8212; you to ask them that question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the President provided to continue (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, in the middle.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is this time for him to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Can we &#8212; just finish.&nbsp; I think we just &#8212; go ahead, in the middle right there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m asking if it is the time for the President to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Simon, let me just &#8212; let me just &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; (inaudible)?&nbsp; His approval rating continues to sink.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; let me just &#8212; let me just have him ask his question.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the American people (inaudible) sending a different message?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Quickly back to Nord Stream 2.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We know the American position to that; you made that crystal clear.&nbsp; Did the pro- &#8212; did the President know the German position before the talks in the Oval Office began?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I’m sure this will be a part of the discussion.&nbsp; I would bet someone will ask about this when we&#8217;re having a press conference in just a little bit here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what I can just reiterate is that it will not move forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, one on Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And quick question on President Macron’s visit in &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Moscow today and the Minsk agreement.&nbsp; What is the White House’s position on the question of autonomy or more autonomy for the different regions in Ukraine?&nbsp; For instance, the Donbass with a majority Russian population, should they have an increased say in the Ukrainian national politics, including the question of which alliance Ukraine wants to be a member of?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, our position on this has not changed.&nbsp; Obviously, the Minsk agreements is part of the discussion, as has been reported, between President Putin and President Macron.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll wait for those discussions to conclude.&nbsp; And we certainly support any means of diplomatic engagement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>All right, thanks, everyone.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to give us water bottles?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have enough water in here for everybody.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>2:43 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Chancellor Scholz of the Federal Republic of Germany Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/remarks-by-president-biden-and-chancellor-scholz-of-the-federal-republic-of-germany-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 22:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 1:37 P.M. EST PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Welcome, everyone.&#160; I&#8217;m delighted to have the Chancellor here today &#8212; Chancellor Scholz.&#160; We&#8217;ve met before, but this is the first time I&#8217;m able to host you in the White House.&#160; And it’s good to have a chance to get to know you more personally.&#160; And we’re going&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>1:37 P.M. EST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Welcome, everyone.&nbsp; I&#8217;m delighted to have the Chancellor here today &#8212; Chancellor Scholz.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve met before, but this is the first time I&#8217;m able to host you in the White House.&nbsp; And it’s good to have a chance to get to know you more personally.&nbsp; And we’re going to spend some time alone together, I hope.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, to state the obvious, Germany is one of America&#8217;s closest allies.&nbsp; We’re working in lockstep to further deter Russian aggression in Europe and to address the challenges posed by China and to promote stability in the We- &#8212; in the Western Balkans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We then &#8212; we have to take on the pandemic, climate change, and &#8212; among many others issues.&nbsp; So, we have a lot to talk about, Mr. Chancellor &#8212; Chancellor, and &#8212; Olaf.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m looking forward to us working closely together with you and this year during Germany&#8217;s presence at the G7.&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking forward to that as well.&nbsp; So, welcome, welcome, welcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The floor is yours, sir, if you wish to say anything.</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you for having me here.&nbsp; And, really, I appreciate very much that we have the chance to discuss all the topics you raised.&nbsp; They are very important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are closest allies and working intensely together.&nbsp; And this is necessary for doing the steps that we have to do &#8212; for instance, fighting against Russian aggression against Ukraine.</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s an important meeting at a very, very important time. &nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you all.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We’ll get a ch- &#8212; we’ll get a &#8212;</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p> 1:40 P.M. EST </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Situation in and in Relation to&#160;Burma</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-situation-in-and-in-relation-to-burma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 22:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&#160;U.S.C.&#160;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal&#160;Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C.&nbsp;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date. &nbsp;In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the situation in and in relation to Burma declared in Executive Order 14014 of February 10, 2021, is to continue in effect beyond February 10, 2022.</p>



<p>The situation in and in relation to Burma, and in particular the February 1, 2021 coup, in which the military overthrew the democratically elected civilian government of Burma and unjustly arrested and detained government leaders, politicians, human rights defenders, journalists, and religious leaders, thereby rejecting the will of the people of Burma as expressed in elections held in November 2020 and undermining the country&#8217;s democratic transition and rule of law, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States. &nbsp;Therefore, I&nbsp;have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14014 with respect to Burma.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>February 7, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency With Respect to the Situation in and in Relation to&#160;Burma</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/07/continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-situation-in-and-in-relation-to-burma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 21:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 10, 2021, by Executive Order 14014, I declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the situation in and in relation to Burma. The situation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On February 10, 2021, by Executive Order 14014, I declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the situation in and in relation to Burma.</p>



<p>The situation in and in relation to Burma, and in particular the February 1, 2021 coup, in which the military overthrew the democratically elected civilian government of Burma and unjustly arrested and detained government leaders, politicians, human rights defenders, journalists, and religious leaders, thereby rejecting the will of the people of Burma as expressed in elections held in November 2020 and undermining the country&#8217;s democratic transition and rule of law, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States. &nbsp;For this reason, the national emergency declared on February 10, 2021, must continue in effect beyond February 10, 2022. &nbsp;Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14014 with respect to the situation in and in relation to Burma.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>February 7, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawal Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/nominations-and-withdrawal-sent-to-the-senate-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 21:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Alice Hill, of the District of Columbia, to be Deputy Administrator for Resilience, Federal Emergency Management Agency, Department of Homeland Security, vice Daniel J. Kaniewski. &#160; &#160; &#160;Mary Green Swig, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Alice Hill, of the District of Columbia, to be Deputy Administrator for Resilience, Federal Emergency Management Agency, Department of Homeland Security, vice Daniel J. Kaniewski.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Mary Green Swig, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice John A. Lancaster, term expired.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWAL SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Mary Green Swig, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice Stephen D. Krasner, term expired, which was sent to the Senate on February 3, 2022.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Appointees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/president-biden-announces-key-appointees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 21:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles: Elver Ariza-Silva, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board Heather Dowdy, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board Gregory S. Fehribach, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board Mozhdeh Amelia Hamraie, Member, Architectural and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Elver Ariza-Silva, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board</li><li>Heather Dowdy, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board</li><li>Gregory S. Fehribach, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board</li><li>Mozhdeh Amelia Hamraie, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board</li><li>Hannah Raissa Ibañez, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board</li><li>Alexis Ander Kashar, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board</li><li>KR Liu, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board</li><li>Benjamin William Julian Nadolsky, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board</li><li>Madeline Rose Ruvolo, Member, Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board</li><li>Gen. John R. Allen, USMC (Ret.), Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Naval Academy</li><li>Dr. Paul J. Angelo, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Naval Academy</li><li>President Emeritus Robert E. Clark II, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Naval Academy</li><li>Adm. Michelle Janine Howard, USN (Ret.), Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Naval Academy</li><li>Lt. Cmdr. John S. McCain IV, Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Naval Academy</li><li>Lt. Col. Amy McGrath, USMC (Ret.), Member, Board of Visitors to the U.S. Naval Academy</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board</u></strong></p>



<p>The Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Access Board is an independent federal agency that promotes equality for people with disabilities through leadership in accessible design and the development of accessibility guidelines and standards.&nbsp; The Board develops and maintains design criteria for the built environment, transit vehicles, telecommunications equipment, medical diagnostic equipment, and information technology.&nbsp; It also provides technical assistance and training on these requirements and accessible design and continues to enforce accessibility standards that cover federally funded facilities.</p>



<p><strong><u>Elver Ariza-Silva, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Elver Ariza-Silva is active in advocacy efforts for all people with disabilities, with a focus on those who are Latino in the District of Columbia. Originally from the Republic of Colombia, Ariza-Silva is a polio survivor and a professional with more than 20 years combined experience in human and social services and in the food industry. Ariza-Silva has served as a research assistant for a Johns Hopkins University study that focused on preventing child trafficking from Latin America and has held leadership roles in the food industry. Ariza-Silva was appointed by Mayor Vincent C. Gray and Mayor Muriel Bowser to serve as Chairman on the Statewide Independent Living Council. Ariza-Silva served as Vice-chair of the Accessibility Advisory Committee Board of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, advising Metro on ways to improve Metro Rail, Metro Bus, and Metro Access.</p>



<p><strong><u>Heather Dowdy, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>With fifteen years of experience developing and demonstrating accessible technology in mobile, web and artificial intelligence, Heather Dowdy is passionate about connecting the dots across disability, race, tech, and faith. She currently leads Accessibility at Netflix, leveraging technology to connect people with disabilities to their next favorite story. Previously, Dowdy served in several accessibility leadership roles at Microsoft and Motorola Mobility, including being named Chair of the Accessibility Working Group of the Mobile &amp; Wireless Forum. As the oldest daughter of Deaf parents, Dowdy is fluent in American Sign Language (ASL). Dowdy has served as a Board Member of the World Institute on Disability (WID), deaf kids CODE, and Billion Strong. She loves using the design thinking process to create solutions that improve usability for everyone. Dowdy holds a Bachelor of Science degree in Electrical Engineering from the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.</p>



<p><strong><u>Gregory S. Fehribach, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Greg Fehribach is a leader in accessibility and inclusion for people with disabilities. An attorney for over thirty-five years who is affiliated with the Indianapolis law firm Tuohy, Bailey, &amp; Moore, LLP, Fehribach founded The Fehribach Group in 1995, where he provides innovative access solutions to clients nationwide who are seeking to create an accessible environment that is welcoming to all guests. Under Fehribach’s guidance as legal counsel, Indianapolis has often been named a top accessible American city, as demonstrated when it hosted the 2012 Super Bowl, considered the most accessible Super Bowl for people with disabilities to date. Fehribach currently serves as a Trustee of the Health &amp; Hospital Corporation of Marion County (Indianapolis). In 2013, Fehribach’s vision for the full inclusion, equity, and economic independence for people with disabilities led to the development of the innovative Gregory S. Fehribach Center. In 2004 he was appointed by the Governor of the State of Indiana to be a Trustee for Ball State, and he continues to serve as a Distinguished Fellow at the university.</p>



<p><strong><u>Mozhdeh Amelia Hamraie, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Aimi Hamraie (they/them) is a disabled designer and scholar, with expertise in architectural and digital media accessibility. They are the author of <em>Building Access: Universal Design and the Politics of Disability </em>(University of Minnesota Press, 2017), a history of the Universal Design movement and accessibility standards in the United States. Hamraie has also published numerous other articles on the topics of disability access, architecture, and urbanism in academic journals. They are quoted in the New York Times, the Chronicle of Higher Education, National Public Radio, the History Channel, and other news sources. Hamraie works as Associate Professor of Medicine, Health, &amp; Society and American Studies at Vanderbilt University, where they train students in the pre-medicine and pre-health professions in the field of disability studies. Hamraie also directs the Critical Design Lab, a collaborative of disabled designers and researchers located in three countries. The Critical Design Lab was recognized with a United States Artists Fellowship in Media for 2022.</p>



<p><strong><u>Hannah Raissa Ibañez, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Hannah Raissa Ibañez, Esq. currently works as a Senior Staff Attorney on the Tenant Defense Project for Inner City Law Center, a non-profit law firm that provides free legal services to vulnerable residents of Los Angeles. In this role, she provides litigation defense to low-income tenants, working poor families, immigrants, people who are living with HIV/AIDS, people with disabilities, and veterans facing homelessness and eviction. Prior to joining ICLC, she was an Assistant Public Defender for Florida’s Sixth and Twelfth Judicial Districts, serving in both Misdemeanor and Felony Divisions. She served on the board for the Red Tent Women’s Initiative, a Florida non-profit that focuses on providing resources to incarcerated women to assist in their transition back into society. She developed a pro-bono clinic between the Sixth Judicial Circuit Public Defender’s office and her alma mater Stetson Law school to provide support to Public Defenders and their clients, while giving young lawyers the opportunity to consider a career in social rights advocacy. Currently, she volunteers with the Los Angeles chapter of the National Lawyers Guild as a Legal Observer, ensuring that the constitutional rights of peaceful organizers are protected.</p>



<p><strong><u>Alexis Ander Kashar, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Alexis Kashar is a civil rights attorney, business leader, and technologist. She grew up in a multi-generational Deaf family that encouraged her interest in civil rights and accessibility from an early age. She graduated from the University of Texas School of Business and the University of Texas Law school. For over two decades, she was among a small group of Deaf attorneys in the world practicing civil rights and special education law in the private sector, where she fought for a more accessible world. She is also a second-generation entrepreneur in the accessible design and technology space. Kashar’s parents founded Krown Manufacturing where they were pioneers in the world of assistive technology, manufacturing communication kits for homes and hotels around the world. She is currently the President of the Board for the New York School for the Deaf, one of New York&#8217;s oldest institutions and the founder of Rosebyander Jewelry. Kashar currently resides in Westchester, New York.</p>



<p><strong><u>KR Liu, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>KR Liu is a leader in the area of disability inclusion and LGBTQ rights. She has been on the forefront of issues blazing a trail towards inclusive design and marketing for almost 20 years. Diagnosed with severe hearing loss at the age of three, she’s made it her life’s work to be a strong advocate for disabled people. As the Head of Brand Accessibility at Google, Brand Studio she drives innovation of representation for diverse disabled audiences, a segment that historically has been overlooked. Liu has been invited to speak at the White House, the United Nations, Capitol Hill, CES, SXSW to push for a more accessible and inclusive world for all through brand marketing and inclusive design in technology. She successfully lobbied on Capitol Hill with Senator Warren’s team and helped pass legislation called the Over-The-Counter Hearing Aid Act of 2017. She is on several boards such as the Consumer Technology Association Foundation, Deaf Kids Code, and the American Association for People with Disabilities. She is a nationally awarded advocate, with a strong reputation in inclusive design, brand marketing, policy, and inclusion.</p>



<p><strong><u>Benjamin William Julian Nadolsky, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Benjamin Nadolsky of Knoxville, Tennessee is the principal of Nadolsky Consulting Group LLC, a firm specialized in education, accessibility, and disability rights. He is on the Board of Directors for the World Institute on Disability and the Pennhurst Preservation &amp; Memorial Alliance Advisory Board. Additionally, he is a professional student at the University of Pennsylvania, receiving his JD/MBA, a Coelho Law Fellow, and a co-chair for the Yale Disability Alumni Group. Previously, he served as a high school teacher for two years in Nashville, TN. While teaching, he received his M. Ed. from Lipscomb University. In 2018, he received his B.A. in Global Affairs and History from Yale University. There, he served through mayoral appointment on the City of New Haven’s Commission on Disabilities, founded Yale’s only undergraduate organization dedicated to disability rights, Disability Empowerment for Yale, and worked as an Inaugural Kerry Yale College Fellow for U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry. During his college career, Nadolsky also interned with the U.S. Department of Education Office of Educational Technology, the Office of Former U.S. Senator Bob Corker (TN), and the Office of Former Knox County Mayor Tim Burchett (TN).</p>



<p><strong><u>Madeline Rose Ruvolo, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Madeline Ruvolo is a transportation planner on the Accessible Services team at the San Francisco Municipal Transportation Agency. She specializes in the accessibility of active transportation and emerging mobility projects and programs. Previously, Ruvolo worked for the UCLA Institute of Transportation Studies, the Los Angeles Department of Transportation, and the Oakland Department of Transportation. Ruvolo has received many accolades for her work at the intersection of transportation and disability, including the prestigious Dwight David Eisenhower Transportation Fellowship and Myra L. Frank Memorial Graduate Scholarship. She holds a master’s degree in Urban and Regional Planning from the Luskin School of Public Affairs at the University of California, Los Angeles and a Bachelor of Arts in American Studies from Scripps College, where she graduated summa cum laude. Ruvolo is from Silver Spring, Maryland and resides in Oakland, California.</p>



<p><strong><u>The Board of Visitors to the U.S. Naval Academy</u></strong></p>



<p>The Board of Visitors to the U.S. Naval Academy inquires into the state of morale and discipline, the curriculum, instruction, physical equipment, fiscal affairs, academic methods, and other matters relating to the academy which the Board decides to consider. The Board consists of six members appointed by the President, three appointed by the Vice President, four appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, one designated by the Senate Armed Services Committee and one designated by the House Armed Services Committee. The President of the United States receives an annual written report of the Board&#8217;s findings and recommendations.</p>



<p><strong><u>General John R. Allen, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>General John R. Allen, USMC (Ret.) is a retired four-star Marine Corps General who currently serves as the 8th President of the Brookings Institution. General Allen was the first Marine to command a theater of war, serving as Commander of the NATO International Security Assistance Force (ISAF) and U.S. Forces in Afghanistan. Following his retirement in 2013, General Allen served as Special Presidential Envoy to the Global Coalition to Counter ISIL under the Obama administration. A graduate of the Naval Academy class of 1976, where in 2021 he was named a Distinguished Graduate, General Allen’s nearly 38 years in the Marine Corps included two postings at the Naval Academy, first as an instructor in the Political Science Department, and then as the 79th Commandant of Midshipmen – the first Marine to hold this position.</p>



<p><strong><u>Dr. Paul J. Angelo, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Paul J. Angelo, PhD, is a fellow for Latin America Studies at the Council on Foreign Relations, where he researches migration, insecurity, and strategic competition in the Western Hemisphere. A U.S. Navy Reserve foreign area officer, Angelo also serves as the executive officer of a U.S. Naval Forces Southern Command unit based in San Juan, Puerto Rico.&nbsp;He was formerly an International Affairs Fellow at CFR, and in this capacity, he represented the U.S. Department of State as a political officer at the U.S. Embassy in Tegucigalpa, Honduras.&nbsp;His previous service in the Navy includes tours on board a destroyer deployed to the Asia-Pacific region; at the U.S. Embassy in Bogotá, Colombia; in a United Kingdom-based NATO role;&nbsp;and as an instructor at the U.S. Naval Academy.&nbsp;Angelo holds a BS in political science (with honors) from the U.S. Naval Academy, where he was awarded the Harry S. Truman Scholarship; an MPhil in Latin American studies (with distinction) from the University of Oxford, where he studied as a Rhodes Scholar; and a PhD in politics from University College London.</p>



<p><strong><u>President Emeritus Robert E. Clark II, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>President Emeritus Robert Clark served as the 17<sup>th</sup> President of Wesley College before retiring in June 2021 after ensuring the long-term viability of the Wesley College brand with a historic Acquisition Agreement signed with Delaware State University. In recognition of his leadership and service to the College and the community, the Board of Trustees bestowed upon him the title of President Emeritus. Clark is a proud Navy Veteran, and a 1984 graduate of the United States Naval Academy.&nbsp; During his 32 years of service as a Submarine Officer, he served on five nuclear powered fast attack submarines, as well as in some of the most critical and rewarding positions in the Navy, including; 84<sup>th</sup> Commandant of Midshipmen at the United States Naval Academy; Commodore of Submarine Squadron Four; Deputy Executive Assistant, and then Executive Assistant, to two Vice Chiefs of Naval Operations, where he was the only officer in the history of the office to hold both positions concurrently; and Commanding Officer of the nuclear powered submarine USS Connecticut (SSN 22).&nbsp; He and his wife, Ruth Ann, have two sons, both Naval Officers, a daughter-in-law, and a granddaughter.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Admiral Michelle J. Howard, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Admiral Michelle Howard (Ret.) served 35 years in the United States Navy. Howard led Sailors and Marines multiple times in her career as the Commander of a ship, an Expeditionary Strike Group, a Task Force, and a Naval theater. Her last command was from 2016 to 2017 as U.S. Naval Forces Europe and U.S. Naval Forces Africa. She simultaneously led NATO’s Allied Joint Force Command Naples with oversight of missions from the Western Balkans to Iraq. Her operational experiences include: Desert Shield/Desert Storm, a West African Training Cruise, Indonesia Tsunami Relief Efforts, Maritime Security Operations in the North Arabian Gulf, and Counter-piracy efforts in Gulf of Aden/Somalia Basin. She graduated from the United States Naval Academy in 1982 and from the Army’s Command and General Staff College in 1998. Howard was the Shapiro Visiting Professor at the Elliott School of International Affairs, George Washington University from 2018 to 2020. She is on the board of directors for IBM, the Stimson Center, and on an advisory panel to the United States Institute of Peace.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lieutenant Commander John S. McCain IV, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Lt. Cmdr. John “Jack” McCain is a reserve Naval Aviator for Helicopter Sea Combat Squadron 85, and graduate of the United States Naval Academy and Georgetown&#8217;s School of Foreign Service. He has deployed five times in the Pacific, Persian Gulf, and Afghanistan where, as an Afghan Hand, he flew alongside Afghan pilots in the Blackhawk, throughout Kandahar and Helmand. Prior to that he was a leadership instructor at the Naval Academy and a search and rescue pilot in Guam. He is currently working as American Airlines’ Director for State and Local Government Affairs for the Western United States.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lieutenant Colonel Amy McGrath, Member</u></strong></p>



<p>Lt. Col. Amy McGrath, USMC (ret.) is a US Naval Academy graduate who served as a Marine F/A-18 pilot and weapons systems officer with three combat deployments in Iraq and Afghanistan. After her operational flying tours, she served as a Congressional Fellow and in the Pentagon as Marine Corps’ liaison to the State Department and a tour teaching political science at USNA. In 2018 and 2020, she ran U.S. House and Senate races in Kentucky. More recently she founded Honor Bound, Inc. a 501(c)(4) nonpartisan organization committed to leadership development for women with a service background and encouraging those women to run for elected office.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the Community College National Legislative&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-community-college-national-legislative-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Washington, D.C.  Thank you, Chair Cooksey—Jim—and thank you to Dr. Richard Rhodes as well. It has been my privilege to work with ACCT and AACC as Second Lady and now First Lady.  But as a teacher, I want to say on behalf of my colleagues and students, just how grateful we are for your leadership. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Washington, D.C. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Thank you, Chair Cooksey—Jim—and thank you to Dr. Richard Rhodes as well. It has been my privilege to work with ACCT and AACC as Second Lady and now First Lady. <br><br>But as a teacher, I want to say on behalf of my colleagues and students, just how grateful we are for your leadership. <br><br>With us today are some of the hardest working and determined advocates for community colleges. <br><br>But I want to especially acknowledge the students. I know that, with work and family obligations on top of your studies, it probably wasn’t easy to get here today. But you came because you know that showing up matters. Thank you for using your voice on behalf of your community.  <br><br>Some of you may know that I’m an enormous sports fan. I’m a First Lady for all Americans—but when it comes to teams, my heart belongs to the Philadelphia Eagles, 76ers, Phillies, and Flyers alone. <br><br>The competition, the crowds, the rivalries—I love it all. <br><br>But too often, we treat what happens in our nation’s capital like a sports game too—wondering which team will score the most points with voters. <br><br>Legislation becomes a football to keep away from the other side, and Americans get lost in the playbook. <br><br>Governing isn’t a game. There are no teams to root for or against, just people—Americans from all walks of life—who need help and hope. <br><br>There’s no scoreboard—there’s no “us” versus “them.” If someone wins it doesn’t mean someone else has to lose. And most of all, there are no spectators. All of us must do our part because the decisions that are made in the halls of Congress and the rooms of the White House affect us all.<br><br>You know that. It’s why you’re here today. You know what’s at stake. <br><br>One year ago, I told this group that Joe was going to fight for community colleges. And since then, we’ve made some incredible progress. <br><br>The American Rescue Plan put billions into community colleges so they could support their students through financial aid, child care support, and other wraparound services. <br><br>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law passed, creating millions of new jobs—along with potential opportunities to train for in-demand skills. But Joe has also had to make compromises. Congress hasn’t passed the Build Back Better agenda—yet. And free community college is no longer a part of that package. <br><br>We knew this wouldn’t be easy—Joe has always said that. <br><br>Still, like you, I was disappointed. Because—like you—these aren’t just bills or budgets to me. We know what they mean for real people. For our students. <br><br>We’ve seen how entire towns can be transformed when community colleges and private companies work together to train students for jobs that are desperately needed—with skills like manufacturing or modernizing our electrical grid. <br><br>We’ve seen how fragile that grasp on a middle-class life can be—how our students struggle to pay their bills and buy their books. We know that if we can make that path a little easier—with high speed internet, or affordable prescriptions, or more Pell grants—they can actually cross that finish line.  <br><br>We’ve all had that bright, engaged student—someone who has so much passion and potential—fade from our classes because they can’t find a reliable baby sitter. They start missing lectures, they fall behind and just can’t catch up. Or the cost of child care just gets to be too much, and they have to choose between extra shifts at work and pursuing the degree that will help them earn more money. <br><br>But there is no choice when it comes to keeping your kids safe. And one day, that student is just gone. It breaks my heart.  <br><br>So, we know that affordable child care and universal preschool would profoundly change people’s lives. <br><br>Build Back Better isn’t just a piece of legislation. And it’s certainly not a football to pass or pivot.<br><br>It’s about helping community colleges train our workforce for 21st-century skills. <br><br>It’s about supporting students with tutoring, child care, and transportation. <br><br>It’s about pioneering the new climate jobs that will lead us into the future. <br><br>And it’s an investment in our kids, with universal preschool that will lay a foundation to learn and succeed for the rest of their lives. <br><br>No one can tell that story better than you. No one can help us push past the playbook and see the human heart that drives our work better than you. <br><br>Governing does have one thing in common with sports. When you get knocked down, you have to get back up. When you lose, you work harder and you come back for more. <br><br>There are a lot of reasons that I wanted Joe to run for president—but one of the biggest was because I knew that no one would work harder for my students and yours. <br><br>I’ve never believed that more than I do today. <br><br>Joe doesn’t quit. He doesn’t give up. <br><br>He is keeping his promise to rebuild our middle class and he knows that community colleges do just that. He knows that you are our greatest resource and our best investment. He will keep fighting for us.  <br><br>So, thank you for being here. This is how we move forward, step by step. We take the hard-won victories and we keep pushing for the change we need. With work and persistence, we will win the progress our students deserve.<br><br>Joe and I are with you. We will continue to work as hard for your community as you do. We are not giving up.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>White&#160;House Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment&#160;Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/white-house-task-force-on-worker-organizing-and-empowerment-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 14:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment – led by Vice President Harris as Chair and Labor Secretary Walsh as Vice-Chair – released publicly the report it delivered to President Joe Biden that includes nearly 70 recommendations to promote worker organizing and collective bargaining for federal employees, and for workers employed by public and private-sector employers.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment – led by Vice President Harris as Chair and Labor Secretary Walsh as Vice-Chair – <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/White-House-Task-Force-on-Worker-Organizing-and-Empowerment-Report.pdf">released publicly the report it delivered to President Joe Biden</a> that includes nearly 70 recommendations to promote worker organizing and collective bargaining for federal employees, and for workers employed by public and private-sector employers.</p>



<p>Additionally, the recommendations include ways to increase private sector workers’ access to information about their existing right to join and/or organize a union, and the legally-defined process of how to do so.</p>



<p>Read the entire report<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/White-House-Task-Force-on-Worker-Organizing-and-Empowerment-Report.pdf"> here.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call Previewing the German Chancellor&#8217;s&#160;Visit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/07/background-press-call-previewing-the-german-chancellors-visit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[5:09 P.M. EST MODERATOR:  Thank you, everyone, for joining us today on this background press call previewing the German Chancellor’s visit tomorrow.  As a reminder of the ground rules, this briefing will be on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern tomorrow, Monday, February 7th. For your own awareness but not for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>5:09 P.M. EST<br> <br>MODERATOR:  Thank you, everyone, for joining us today on this background press call previewing the German Chancellor’s visit tomorrow. <br> <br>As a reminder of the ground rules, this briefing will be on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern tomorrow, Monday, February 7th.<br> <br>For your own awareness but not for reporting, the senior administration official on today’s call is [senior administration official].<br> <br>[Senior administration official], I’ll turn it over to you for opening remarks, after which we’ll do Q&amp;A.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, [senior administration official], and thanks to everybody for joining.  Delighted to have the opportunity to speak with you tonight about the Chancellor’s visit to Washington tomorrow.<br> <br>President Biden is very much looking forward to welcoming Chancellor Scholz on his first visit to Washington and the White House, and sees it as a good opportunity to affirm the deep and enduring ties between the United States and Germany. <br> <br>Germany is one of our closest and strongest Allies in Europe.  The President and the Chancellor had the opportunity to interact last October in Rome at the G20 Summit.  Scholz, at the time, was serving as Finance Minister and coalition negotiations were going on.  But it was clear that he was the presumptive chancellor, which is why then-Chancellor Merkel brought him along to the meeting of the <s>P3</s> [Quad] countries, so it gave the President an opportunity to have an initial conversation with him as part of the handover from Chancellor Merkel to ensure continuity.</p>



<p>The President had a very early congratulatory call with Chancellor Scholz, and they have since consulted together with other European leaders a few times over the last two months since he became Chancellor.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is looking forward to getting to know Chancellor Scholz personally on this first official visit to Washington as head of state.&nbsp; And I would say that the fact he is coming here almost two months to the day from taking office illustrates the continued importance that the United States places on our bilateral relationship with Germany and the importance of this relationship between these two leaders.<br>&nbsp;<br>The leaders have a very full agenda to discuss tomorrow.&nbsp; We expect them to talk significantly about the situation in Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; They’ll likely discuss their shared concerns about Russia’s military buildup on Ukraine’s border and their shared commitment to both ongoing diplomatic efforts to encourage Russia to de-escalate tensions as well as ongoing efforts to ensure deterrence to further Russian aggression.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Related to that, they will discuss our ongoing efforts to prepare a robust sanctions package that would impose severe costs if Russia further invades Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>Germany, at the start of the year, assumed the presidency of the G7, and so I expect that will be a significant part of their conversation as well, including Germany’s agenda and the way our two countries can work together with fellow G7 members to address global challenges.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Many of the things that comprise Germany’s G7 agenda are priorities for the Biden administration as well, including the importance of continued close cooperation on ending the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing the threat of climate change, and promoting economic prosperity and international security based on our shared democratic values.<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, I expect the leaders will want to discuss their support for the Western Balkans, which is a priority region in Europe for both the United States and for Germany, and how we can continue to promote stability in the region, as well as continue to make progress on the further European integration of the Western Balkans; as well as our collective response to undemocratic moves by China and continued efforts within the transatlantic relationship, including in our bilateral relationship, on how we can work together to address China’s nonmarket economic practices and human rights abuses.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, just closing thought: The United States and Germany have long worked together to address the world’s most important challenges, and we see the meeting tomorrow as an opportunity to ensure the continuity of close relations between the United States and Germany, to give the two leaders an opportunity to get to know one another personally, and an opportunity for them to discuss all of the pressing global challenges that both of our countries are facing today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, let me stop there with opening comments and happy to turn it over to questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this &#8212; and [senior administration official].&nbsp; I wanted to ask about Nord Stream.&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s been a lot of tension over that.&nbsp; The President has opposed that project for a long time.&nbsp; What role do you think Nord Stream will play in this discussion?<br>&nbsp;<br>And if I could just follow up on the sanctions question as well &#8212; or the sanctions issue: Can you say what the German position is now about SWIFT?&nbsp; There&#8217;s been, kind of, a lot of back and forth.&nbsp; But is that a serious option for, you know, imposing costs on Russia?&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much for the questions.&nbsp; In terms of the &#8212; to take your second question first, in terms of the German position on SWIFT, I don&#8217;t want to characterize what their government&#8217;s view is, so I would refer you to them to set out what their position is on the package of sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>But certainly, what I can say is: We have been coordinating very closely with Germany &#8212; including in advance of the Chancellor&#8217;s visit and just more generally over the last number of weeks, as we have with our other European partners &#8212; on a swift and severe package of sanctions that the U.S. and Europe would both impose on Russia in the event of an invasion on Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, lots of conversations with Germany and very much welcome the unity that we have been seeing from our European Allies and partners on their readiness to join with us in imposing swift and severe consequences on Russia if there is further aggression.<br>&nbsp;<br>And on Nord Stream, this, as you alluded to, is a topic that we have had numerous conversations with the German government about &#8212; with the Merkel government, as well as with the Scholz government.&nbsp; I would assume that it is going to be a topic of conversation between the leaders tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>And what I can say is that we have made our position very clear, which is that: If Russia invades Ukraine, one way or another Nord Stream 2 will not move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [Senior administration official], have the Germans assured you that they are in agreement with this position?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, again, I&#8217;m not going to speak on behalf of the Germans, and we&#8217;ll let them for themselves tomorrow, and we&#8217;ll let the Chancellor speak.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, you know, what I &#8212; what I can say is that we&#8217;ve had extensive common- &#8212; conversations with the Germans.&nbsp; We&#8217;re confident that the Germans share our concerns with Russian aggression, that they&#8217;re very involved in our ongoing efforts on both deterrence and diplomacy.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have made our position very clear, as I laid out.&nbsp; And what I can say is that we will continue to work very closely with Germany to ensure the pipeline does not move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thank you so much for doing this call on a Sunday.&nbsp; You know, I mean, the narrative that&#8217;s out there is that Germany has kind of been the outlier, in terms of the NATO nations, in not being particularly specific or aggressive in laying out the costs that they would impose.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I&#8217;m wondering if the White House is satisfied with the new German government&#8217;s, you know, approach so far to laying out costs if Russia were to invade and will the President be encouraging the Chancellor to play more of a leadership role in the, sort of, NATO/Western diplomatic effort to deter a Russian invasion.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks for that question.&nbsp; And certainly recognize that &#8212; that that&#8217;s the narrative that&#8217;s been out there.&nbsp; You know, what I can say from the perspective of the White House is that we have been engaged very closely with our German partners, including the new German administration over the two months since they&#8217;ve taken office.<br>&nbsp;<br>As I said earlier, we&#8217;ve been coordinating with them very closely on the packages of sanctions that we would put into place.&nbsp; We&#8217;re coordinating very closely with them within NATO.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know there&#8217;s been a lot of churn over this question about: Is Germany going to send arms?&nbsp; What sort of role is it playing on the security side?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would point out a number of things:<br>&nbsp;<br>First, Germany, after the United States, is the second-largest donor to Ukraine and to Europe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, Germany has been very supportive of the things that the United States has done militarily.&nbsp; Most recently, as we announced last week, supporting our ability to move a battalion from Germany into Romania to reinforce and ensure our Ally in Romania, our Allies in the eastern flank are feeling a sufficient reassurance and deterrence to Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>And third, as an overarching point, the beauty of having an alliance with 30 NATO Allies is that different Allies step up to take different approaches to different parts of the problem.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So really, across the board, we have continued to work in close cooperation with Germany on the sanctions front.&nbsp; Germany, as I said, has been a significant donor to Ukraine, including doing a lot on the humanitarian assistance side of things, and, finally, has facilitated a lot of what we have been able to do in terms of our own military deployments of an additional number of troops that are heading out to Germany as part of our “assure and deter mission,” as well as enabling us to get a striker squadron of 1,000 service members very quickly to Romania, because they were already based in the theater in Europe, and specifically in Germany.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I really think, across the board, Germany continues to be an important member of the transatlantic Alliance, with all of us working together to address different parts of the same problem.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; I guess I would ask to see if you could expand on that a little bit.&nbsp; And, you know, we&#8217;re seeing more public and more strident pronouncements of the &#8212; of a looming invasion &#8212; some of the stuff in the last day or so.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering: Do you expect that you&#8217;ll share &#8212; the meeting will share intelligence to kind of help Germany see, maybe, closer to the view of the U.S. of the dangers?&nbsp; And do you, kind of, see &#8212; I know that there&#8217;s consensus on some level but not on others, do you &#8212; are you sensing a coalescing a little bit more of the views between the U.S. and the German government?&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, I absolutely think that our countries are unified in terms of awareness of the risk of further Russian aggression to Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have been, for a long time, sharing intelligence with Germany, with the rest of our Allies.&nbsp; We are engaged in very regular conversations &#8212; both by the White House, the State Department, our embassy in Berlin, our other agencies &#8212; on the situation.&nbsp; And I think there is absolutely &#8212; absolute agreement that if there is further Russian aggression that there&#8217;s a number of things that need to be done &#8212; in terms of deployment of additional troops to the eastern flank, and to the imposition of a large package of economic sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Germany has been completely on board with the statements that have come out of the European Council meeting, the European Foreign Affairs Council on this.&nbsp; There was a statement that came out by G7 Foreign Ministers a number of weeks ago, and NATO has spoken to this as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I&#8217;m absolutely confident that Germany shares our concerns over Russian aggression, shares our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re continuing to work closely with them and the EU on what this package of severe economic sanctions would look like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And equally, we are both committed to trying to make diplomacy work.&nbsp; One of the things I should have mentioned in talking about the comparative advantage a few minutes ago is that Germany has also played a very significant diplomatic role through its leadership, along France, in the Normandy Format.&nbsp; And those meetings have continued both at foreign minister level and at national security advisor level by the French and Germans in recent weeks, with more engagement expected in the coming week.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, certainly, across the board on all of these things, I think there is very much unity of purpose and agreement on the need to be able to respond either diplomatically or in terms of sanctions and deterrence, depending on which path Putin chooses.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this call.&nbsp; You said that if Russia invades, you know, one way or another Nord Stream 2 won&#8217;t happen.&nbsp; Are there also conversations underway about how to block Nord Stream from becoming operational if Russia does not invade in the next few months and if, you know, it makes its way through the German regulatory process?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, I&#8217;m not going to engage in hypotheticals.&nbsp; I &#8212; certainly, everybody hopes that that Russia does not invade, and then that’s going to be a question that &#8212; that we&#8217;re going to have to deal with.<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, the one thing that I will point out is that there is not currently any gas flowing through the pipeline.&nbsp; And there won&#8217;t be any gas for months, in part because of the diplomacy that the United States has been able to do on this issue with Germany.<br>&nbsp;<br>The &#8212; Germany&#8217;s Federal Network Agency, as you know, has suspended the certification process of Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; So, the pipeline is not currently operational and no gas is expected to flow through that pipeline anytime soon.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as you noted, there are steps that need to be taken by the German regulatory agency.&nbsp; There&#8217;s also steps that need to be taken by the EU regulatory agency.&nbsp; So, you know, more broadly, our position remains what it has been, which is that we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve always been opposed to Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; The President has made this &#8212; this clear for several years now, which he views as a Russian geopolitical project that undermines the energy security and national security of a significant part of the Euro-Atlantic community.<br>&nbsp;<br>We engaged in significant diplomacy with the Germans last summer, leading to agreement on a joint statement that sets out a number of things that we intend to do to ensure that Russia does not use energy as a weapon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, so I&#8217;ve spoken to what our position is now &#8212; if there is Russian aggression against Ukraine &#8212; in terms of ensuring that one way or another Nord Stream 2 will not move forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If we are in the happy situation where there is not a Russian invasion and we are able to move along the diplomatic path, we will continue to engage in conversations with Germany and our European partners about this issue more broadly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know that you’ve answered several questions on Nord Stream; I was just hoping to try to put a finer point on it as well.&nbsp; Over the summer when Chancellor Scholz’s predecessor visited with President Biden, there was an announcement about an agreement that the U.S. and Germany had reached about the operationality of Nord Stream 2, and I&#8217;m wondering if that agreement still holds up under the new administration and if you could detail exactly what that agreement is.<br>&nbsp;<br>And second, in the statement between the U.S. and the EU a couple of weeks ago, it said that tomorrow would also see a meeting of the U.S.-EU Energy Council.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if you could detail a little bit more about whether that meeting is still taking place and what it is.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, that meeting on the U.S.-EU Energy Council is being chaired by the State Department along with the EU, so I would refer you to the State Department to be able to get more information on that.&nbsp; This is something that had been set up a number of years ago, which provides an opportunity for the United States and the European Union to come together at the level of Secretary of State here in the United States, as well as the Energy Secretary, with their counterparts on the EU side.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, lots to talk about and &#8212; in general terms and with energy issues, with our shared commitment to addressing climate change.&nbsp; And in the current context, I would expect that Ukraine is going to be a significant part of that discussion as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the statement, this was agreed, as you said, between the Biden administration and the Merkel administration.&nbsp; It was published on July 21st.&nbsp; And I just pulled it up on my computer here as we were talking, and the joint statement is actually on the State Department website, so you can take a look at that and read it in full, and it outlines the commitments that our two governments made.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is certainly something that we continue to view as an operative agreement that &#8212; that holds.&nbsp; We are continuing to have conversations about this agreement with the new Scholz administration, and they are continuing to implement the agreement.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s a number of things that are included in here in terms of, you know, commitments that they have made to address energy security issues, to abide by the spirit and letter of the Third Energy Package with respect to Nord Stream 2, you know, including climate change, to setting up a new climate and energy partnership, to German commitments to establish and administer a Green Fund for Europe, as well as the readiness of both of our countries to take a number of steps in response to &#8212; I&#8217;m looking at &#8212; sorry &#8212; “…to ensure the U.S. and the EU remain prepared, including with appropriate tools and mechanisms to respond together to Russian aggression, malign activities, including Russian efforts to use energy as a weapon.&nbsp; Should Russia attempt to use energy as a weapon or commit further aggressive acts against Ukraine, Germany will take action at the national level and press for effective measures at the European level, including sanctions to limit Russian export capabilities…This commitment is designed to ensure that Russia will not misuse any pipeline, including Nord Stream 2, to achieve aggressive political ends by using energy as a weapon.”<br>&nbsp;<br>So, sorry for the lengthy quotation from that.&nbsp; You can see the entire document on the website.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But yes, we very much still see this as an operational agreement.&nbsp; We see it as something that the Scholz administration remains bound by, even though it was negotiated by his predecessor.&nbsp; Scholz, of course, was part of that government as Vice Chancellor.&nbsp; And we continue to discuss with the German government the implementation of the provisions, including in this joint agreement.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; Again, this is all the time &#8212; that is all of the questions we have time for.&nbsp; I appreciate you joining the call.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and is embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern tomorrow morning, Monday, February 7th &#8212; February 7th.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you, and I hope everyone has a wonderful day.<br>&nbsp;<br>5:31 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
