<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 13:59:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Gross Domestic&#160;Product</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-gross-domestic-product/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 13:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The American economy — powered by working families — continues to be resilient in the face of historic challenges. Last quarter, consumer spending, business investment, and residential investment increased at strong rates. The number of Americans on unemployment insurance remains at the lowest level since 1970. Later this morning, I will meet with small business&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The American economy — powered by working families — continues to be resilient in the face of historic challenges. Last quarter, consumer spending, business investment, and residential investment increased at strong rates. The number of Americans on unemployment insurance remains at the lowest level since 1970. Later this morning, I will meet with small business owners who are creating and growing their businesses at a historic rate. While last quarter’s growth estimate was affected by technical factors, the United States confronts the challenges of COVID-19 around the world, Putin’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, and global inflation from a position of strength.</p>



<p>We need to keep making progress — cutting costs for working families, making more in America, and creating good-paying jobs you can raise a middle-class family on. Congressional Republicans, led by Senator Scott, believe the way to fight these global challenges is by raising taxes on middle class families, including half of small business owners. I have a different approach. Congress should send to my desk a bipartisan innovation bill to bolster our supply chains and make more in America. And Congress needs to pass legislation to lower costs and lower the deficit, reducing families’ prescription drug and utility bills and restoring fairness to our tax code — without raising taxes on anyone making less than $400,000 per year. That’s how we grow our economy and strengthen the middle class.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: U.S. Agencies Are Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the&#160;World</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/fact-sheet-u-s-agencies-are-advancing-the-human-rights-of-lgbtqi-persons-around-the-world/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51934</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’re… making equality the centerpiece of our diplomacy around the world.  We believe LGBTQ+ rights are human rights.  In February, I signed a presidential memorandum establishing that it’s the policy of the United States to pursue an end to violence and discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity. – President Joe Biden&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>We’re… making equality the centerpiece of our diplomacy around the world.  We believe LGBTQ+ rights are human rights.  In February, I signed a presidential memorandum establishing that it’s the policy of the United States to pursue an end to violence and discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">– President Joe Biden</p>



<p>Today, the U.S. Government released a first of its kind progress <a href="https://www.state.gov/lgbtqi-human-rights/">report</a> on implementation of President Biden’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/04/memorandum-advancing-the-human-rights-of-lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-queer-and-intersex-persons-around-the-world/">Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World</a>. &nbsp;The progress demonstrates the U.S. commitment to promoting and protecting the human rights of LGBTQI+ people around the world through our diplomacy and foreign assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Federal agencies are:   <br><br><strong>Combating Criminalization of LGBTQI+ Status or Conduct Abroad</strong>:  The Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), together with U.S. embassies and USAID missions, are taking innovative and bold steps to leverage diplomatic engagement and foreign assistance to promote the human rights of LGBTQI+ people, including through elevating concerns about criminalization of LGBTQI+ status or conduct with local officials, in collaboration with like-minded partners.  U.S. embassies and USAID missions also continue to welcome decisions of governments that decriminalize LGBTQI+ status or conduct.  As documented in the report, the scope and breadth of U.S.  engagement in this critical area continues to increase and strengthen.     <br><br><strong>Protecting Vulnerable LGBTQI+ Refugees and Asylum Seekers:</strong>  In December 2021, the Department of State announced a package of new pledges to support LGBTQI+ refugees, including enhanced training for the staff of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees.  The Department of State is also working to increase resettlement for LGBTQI+ persons and members of other vulnerable groups through new and expanded referral programs with NGOs and other organizations to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.  U.S. embassies also continue to support LGBTQI+ refugee needs through highlighting gaps in services and supporting civil society partners.  In February, the Department of Homeland Security issued revised guidance to recognize informal same-sex marriages for the purposes of obtaining refugee or asylee status, even if they are not officially recognized by officials in countries of origin.  The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) is providing resources for LGBTQI+ refugees and their allies, including intensive case management for refugees who are vulnerable to discrimination.<br><br><strong>Ensuring Foreign Assistance Protects Human Rights and Advances Non-discrimination:  </strong>In FY2021, the Department of State increased its support to the Global Equality Fund to $10 million annually.  The Fund now supports programs in over 100 countries in all global regions.  The Department of Health and Human (HHS) Services also supported new initiatives to increase access to health services for LGBTQI+ persons, including a new health and resource center for transgender persons in India.  USAID released new guidance outlining how to integrate the needs of LGBTQI+ persons into <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/External_Draft_-_Integrating_LGBTQI_Considerations_into_RFSs_Programming_Sectors-508.pdf">food security</a> and <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/_External_Draft_Integrating_LGBTQI_Considerations_In_Education_Programming_210601-508.pdf">education</a>-related development programming.  To advance non-discrimination in foreign assistance, the Department of Labor added new terms, definitions, and requirements related to advancing LGBTQI+ human rights in its guidance for its overseas grant solicitations and contracts, and HHS developed a similar equity appendix for the annual update to the Notice of Funding Award Guidance.  The Department of State’s U.S. Fulbright Student and Teacher Programs also updated its applications to include non-binary gender options for the first time.  And the Peace Corps undertook steps to recruit more diverse applicants, including by holding a panel on “Translating Transgender Identity Abroad” to specifically recruit transgender applicants.  To coordinate these efforts and facilitate resource and experience sharing, USAID convenes a thirteen-agency working group to discuss policy, programming, and inclusive data priorities.<br><br><strong>Taking Swift and Meaningful Responses to Human Rights Abuses of LGBTQI+ Persons Abroad:</strong>  The Department of State’s Global Equality Fund provides emergency funding to LGBTQI+ activists through the Dignity for All program to respond to active human rights violations and crises globally.  USAID programs build in flexibility and support for rapid response programming in the countries where they operate.  And across the globe, U.S. diplomats and U.S. development professionals are at the forefront of highlighting LGBTQI+ human rights attacks and abuses.  For example, in Poland, U.S. Embassy Warsaw supported “Words Matter,” a <a href="https://pl.usembassy.gov/wordsmatter_eng/">video</a> featuring members of the Polish LGBTQI+ community reading and reacting to homophobic comments posted in response to the Embassy’s social media campaign for Pride Month.  The &#8220;Words Matter&#8221; video reached over 12 million Poles and was widely covered by both Polish and international media.  In Guatemala, following murders of Guatemalan leaders in the transgender community in June 2021, U.S. Embassy Guatemala City issued a <a href="https://twitter.com/usembassyguate/status/1403573244112867331?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1403573244112867331%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonblade.com%2F2021%2F06%2F17%2Fus-condemns-murder-of-prominent-transgender-activist-in-guatemala%2F">statement</a> condemning the murders and urging full investigations. <br><br><strong>Building International Coalitions:</strong>  At the UN General Assembly’s Third Committee in November, the U.S.-led resolution on democracy and elections included for the first time a call for states to eliminate discrimination in the right to participate in public affairs based on “sexual orientation and gender identity.”  The U.S. Mission to the United Nations led the lobbying campaign to include this important new language.  The U.S. also advanced LGBTQI+ human rights together with like-minded partners in the Organizing for Security and Cooperation in Europe and the Organization of American States, and in the Equal Rights Coalition, which recently released statements with U.S. support focused on<a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/aggression-against-ukraine-and-the-protection-of-lgbti-persons-and-refugees-equal-rights-coalition-statement"> protection of LGBTQI+ persons in Ukraine</a>, and on <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nexus-between-democracy-and-the-human-rights-of-lgbti-people-equal-rights-coalition-statement-december-2021">democracy and LGBTQI+ human rights</a>. <br><br><strong>Rescinding Inconsistent Polices:</strong>  This Administration continues to update polices that are inconsistent with the President’s Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World.  USAID, for example, reinstated a reporting mechanism to track overall foreign assistance which advances LGBTQI+ human rights and inclusive development.  In collaboration with HHS, the Department of State withdrew from the “Geneva Consensus Declaration,” and requested its removal from the UN document system in February 2021.  The Geneva Consensus Declaration opposes abortion and related reproductive health and rights and is widely viewed as undermining LGBTQI+ human rights. <br><br><strong>Advancing Inclusive Democracy</strong>:  During the Summit for Democracy, the U.S.  supported a <a href="https://equalrightscoalition.org/publications/erc-statement-on-the-nexus-between-democracy-and-the-human-rights-of-lgbti-persons/">statement</a> from the Equal Rights Coalition on Democracy and LGBTQI+ rights which affirms that promoting and protecting the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons is essential for democratic renewal.  As part of the Presidential Initiative for Democratic Renewal, the State Department also committed up to $5 million to launch the <a href="https://www.state.gov/statements-of-interest-requests-for-proposals-and-notices-of-funding-opportunity/drl-fy2021-global-lgbtqi-inclusive-democracy-and-empowerment-glide-fund/">Global LGBTQI+ Inclusive Democracy and Empowerment (GLIDE) Fund</a>, a new program under the Global Equality Fund that will facilitate the participation and leadership of LGBTQI+ community members in democratic institutions.  Also, during the Summit for Democracy, USAID committed to launch a new Global Development Alliance to support LGBTQI-led civil society organizations to respond to the COVID-19 crisis, engage in democratic processes, and build networks of allies.  USAID intends to commit $5M USD over five-years to this program involving substantial capacity building opportunities and direct grantmaking to LGBTQI+ and transgender-led organizations around the world.<br><br><strong>Reducing Bias-Motivated Violence:  </strong>Agencies continue to take steps to reduce bias motivated violence and hate crime targeting LGBTQI+ persons.  For example, the Department of Justice, in coordination with the Department of State, has Resident Legal Advisor (RLA) programs in Albania, Croatia, Kosovo, and North Macedonia which advance LGBTQI+ human rights and assist foreign counterparts with managing cases, including of including LGBTQI+ individuals.  Additionally, the RLA program in the Baltics assists investigators, prosecutors, and judges with investigating, prosecuting, and adjudicating hate crimes, including crimes motivated by a victim’s gender identity or sexual orientation.  To strengthen knowledge on patterns of violence, discrimination, and appropriate responses, in September 2021, the Department of State launched a new partnership with the Library of Congress to evaluate existing academic research for linkages between bias, discrimination, and violence, including against LGBTQI+ persons.  The goal is to better understand which criminal justice interventions can prevent escalations in violence.  An inter-agency review committee will review the research findings and provide recommendations for future actions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Comprehensive Proposal to Hold Russian Oligarchs and Elites&#160;Accountable</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/fact-sheet-president-bidens-comprehensive-proposal-to-hold-russian-oligarchs-accountable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, in concert with his supplemental request to Congress to support Ukraine, President Biden will send a proposal for a comprehensive legislative package that will enhance the United States Government’s authority to hold the Russian government and Russian oligarchs accountable for President Putin’s war against Ukraine. The proposals were crafted in close consultation with interagency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, in concert with his supplemental request to Congress to support Ukraine, President Biden will send a proposal for a comprehensive legislative package that will enhance the United States Government’s authority to hold the Russian government and Russian oligarchs accountable for President Putin’s war against Ukraine. The proposals were crafted in close consultation with interagency partners, including the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Justice, the Department of State, and the Department of Commerce. The Biden Administration looks forward to working closely with Members of Congress as a whole to implement this package of proposals.</p>



<p>This package of proposals will establish new authorities for the forfeiture of property linked to Russian kleptocracy, allow the government to use the proceeds to support Ukraine, and further strengthen related law enforcement tools.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Establishing a Streamlined Administrative Authority to Seize and Forfeit Oligarch Assets:</strong> This proposal aims to streamline the process for seizure of oligarch assets, expand the assets subject to seizure, and enable the proceeds to flow to Ukraine. It would:</p>



<ul><li>Create a new, streamlined administrative process involving the Departments of the Treasury and Justice, for the forfeiture of property in the United States that is owned by sanctioned Russian oligarchs and that has a connection to specified unlawful conduct. A forfeiture decision would be reviewable in federal court on an expedited basis.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Create a new criminal offense, making it unlawful for any person to knowingly or intentionally possess proceeds directly obtained from corrupt dealings with the Russian government.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Enabling the Transfer of the Proceeds of Forfeited Kleptocrat Property to Ukraine to Remediate Harms of Russian Aggression.</strong> This proposal would improve the United States’ ability to use forfeited oligarch funds to remediate harms caused to Ukraine by Russian aggression. Under the proposal, the Departments of Justice, Treasury, and State will work together to use forfeited funds related to corruption, sanctions and export control violations, and other specified offenses to remediate harms of Russian aggression toward Ukraine.</p>



<p><strong>Clamping Down on Facilitation of Sanctions Evasion: </strong>This proposal would allow for the forfeiture of property that Russian oligarchs use to facilitate the evasion of sanctions.&nbsp;Under current law, the United States can forfeit the proceeds of sanctions violations, but it cannot forfeit property used to facilitate sanctions violations.&nbsp;This proposal closes that gap.</p>



<p><strong>Modernizing Racketeering to Include Sanctions Evasion: </strong>This proposal would strengthen the United States’ ability to investigate and prosecute sanctions evasion by adding the crime of sanctions evasion to the definition of “racketeering activity” in the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations (RICO) Act. This proposal would give the Department of Justice a powerful forfeiture tool used against racketeering enterprises to dismantle organizations that enable violations of U.S. sanctions.</p>



<p><strong>Expanding the Time Limit to Follow the Money: </strong>This proposal would improve the United States’ ability to pursue money laundering prosecutions (and post-conviction forfeitures) based on foreign offenses by extending the statute of limitations from five years to ten years.&nbsp;Criminal investigations of oligarchs can be complicated because sophisticated criminals use intricate schemes that may cut across multiple jurisdictions. The United States often works with international partners on these cases. Extending the statute of limitations would provide additional time for investigators and prosecutors to hold oligarchs criminally accountable.</p>



<p><strong>Leveraging Foreign Partners’ Ability to Freeze and Seize Oligarch Wealth: </strong>This proposal would improve the United States’ ability to work with international partners to recover assets linked to foreign corruption.&nbsp;This proposal would make several amendments to improve our ability to enforce foreign restraint and forfeiture orders in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The United States has already been working with allies and partners to track down assets all over the world:</strong></p>



<ul><li>In March, the U.S., led by the Department of the Treasury and Department of Justice, launched the Russian Elites, Proxies, and Oligarchs Task Force with international partners to coordinate the freezing and seizing of Russian assets around the world.</li><li>So far, member states in the European Union have reported freezing over $30 billion in assets, including almost $7 billion in boats, helicopters, real estate, and artwork.</li><li>Dozens of yachts have been seized by REPO Task Force member countries. The U.S. Treasury has sanctioned and blocked vessels and aircraft worth over $1 billion, as well as frozen hundreds of millions of dollars of assets belonging to Russian elites in U.S. bank accounts.</li><li>Last week, in the wake of criminal charges, Treasury designated a global sanctions evasion network associated with Konstantin Malofeyev, crack downing on the movement of illicit assets.</li><li><a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/90-million-yacht-sanctioned-russian-oligarch-viktor-vekselberg-seized-spain-request-united">Earlier this month</a>, the Department of Justice announced that Spain seized a 255-foot, $90 million yacht of sanctioned Russian Oligarch Viktor Vekselberg at the request of United States.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Declaration for the Future of the&#160;Internet</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/28/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-declaration-for-the-future-of-the-internet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (April 27, 2022) 4:06&#160;P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&#160; So, this call is going to be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&#160; The contents of this call are embargoed until tomorrow, Thursday, April 28th, 7:00 a.m. Eastern. You all should have gotten the Declaration under embargo in your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(April 27, 2022)</p>



<p>4:06&nbsp;P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; So, this call is going to be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The contents of this call are embargoed until tomorrow, Thursday, April 28th, 7:00 a.m. Eastern.<br><br>You all should have gotten the Declaration under embargo in your inboxes.&nbsp; If you didn&#8217;t, please email me.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a factsheet that is also coming your way soon.<br><br>So, with that, I&#8217;m going to &#8212; and &#8212; sorry, and just for your awareness but not for your reporting, the speakers on this call are [senior administration official] and then [senior administration official].<br><br>So, I&#8217;m going to start with [senior administration official] to kick us off with some remarks.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; And thank you for joining the call.<br><br>It goes without saying that the Internet has enabled extraordinary benefits for the country and also the world, but it has also created new policy challenges, both domestically and internationally.</p>



<p>On the international front &#8212; what we’re talking about today &#8212; we have seen a trend of rising digital authoritarianism, where some states have been acting to repress freedom of expression, to censor independent news sources, to interfere with elections, promote disinformation around the world, and deny their citizens other human rights.</p>



<p>The last two months have provided an extreme example of such behavior in connection with Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.<br><br>Russia has aggressively promoted disinformation at home and abroad, censored Internet news sources, blocked or shut down legitimate sites, and gone so far as to physically attack the Internet infrastructure in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Russia, however, is hardly alone but just one of the leaders in a dangerous new model of Internet policy along with the People’s Republic of China and some of the other most censorial states in the world.</p>



<p>In response to these alarming trends, the United States is launching the Declaration for the Future of the Internet &#8212; otherwise known as the “DFI” &#8212; jointly with more than 50 partners, 50 other states from around the world, including &#8212; on the morning of April 28th, 2022.&nbsp; And U.S. National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan will be hosting the launch with endorsing partners.<br><br>In fact, I think I can say more.&nbsp; We have more than 55 partner countries from around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will note that this effort takes into account and is complementary to existing processes in the United Nations, the G7, the G20, the OECD, WTO, ICANN, the Freedom Online Coalition, and other relevant multilateral and multi-stakeholder fora.&nbsp; We will use this Declaration and the principles to fortify existing institutions.</p>



<p>Now I’m going to turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk more about the Declaration itself.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks to all of you for joining this afternoon.&nbsp; We are tremendously excited about the launch tomorrow of the DFI, which represents, obviously, something a number of us have been working on across the administration, joined by dozens of countries around the world &#8212; as [senior administration official] says, more than 55 at this point &#8212; for quite some time.&nbsp; And just really excited to get it &#8212; get it out there.<br><br>You know, as [moderator] said, and as I hope you all have in your inboxes &#8212; you have the Declaration text itself, so I’m going to keep my summary brief.<br><br>But, basically, the Declaration affirms fundamental principles regarding how countries should comport themselves with respect to the Internet and to the digital ecosystem, the digital economy.&nbsp; It commits governments to promoting an open, free, global, interoperable, reliable, and secure Internet for the world.</p>



<p>This includes defending the Internet &#8212; an Internet that is governed through a multi-stakeholder approach that works with and through existing institutions and processes; an Internet that fosters the protection and promotion of basic human rights online; and an Internet that advances these goals across relevant economic policies and regulatory activities.</p>



<p>I want to point out the significance of the timing of the Declaration.&nbsp; What you’re seeing with the launch of the DFI is democratic governments and other like-minded partners from around the world rising to the challenge at this critical moment in history.<br><br>Over the last year, the U.S. has worked extensively and intensively with partners from all over the world &#8212; with civil society, with industry, with academics, and other stakeholders &#8212; to try to reverse the current trajectory of the Internet, including through the development of this Declaration.</p>



<p>The DFI has not been a “U.S. effort” to which others are joining, but a truly joint effort with America’s allies and partners.&nbsp; The U.S. and partners endorsing this Declaration will work together in the weeks, months, and years ahead to implement these principles and to promote this vision globally, while respecting each other’s regulatory autonomy within our own jurisdictions and in accordance with our respective domestic laws and international legal obligations.<br><br>The Declaration will also remain open after the launch to all partners who are willing to endorse its vision and uphold its principles.&nbsp; And so, we’re excited to have more than 55 countries join tomorrow.&nbsp; We’re also excited to see other counties come on &#8212; come on board as this goes forward.</p>



<p>Efforts like this take work and time, but we believe the DFI will advance a positive vision for digital technologies anchored by democratic values.&nbsp; We look forward to working with governments, the private sector, international organizations, the technical community, academia and civil society, and other relevant stakeholders worldwide to promote, foster, and achieve this shared vision.</p>



<p>[Moderator], let me turn it back over to you for a few questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Could we cue up the directions, please, to ask a question?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Thanks so much for this.&nbsp; Can you maybe address why you aren’t doing this through the U.N. framework at the OEWG, and if this is any kind of indictment of that process?<br><br>And I noticed India and New Zealand are not on the list.&nbsp; Have you asked them?&nbsp; And what is the significance of getting their buy-in?<br><br>And finally, can you talk a little bit about the risks you see of splinternet and whether this is about more disinformation or physical attacks on infrastructure?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to start with those?&nbsp; Well, maybe I’ll start with one point, which &#8212; the good news is New Zealand has, in fact, joined the Declaration slightly (inaudible).&nbsp; And we &#8212; you know, the hope remains that time isn’t fully passed yet for India to join.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve been engaged in &#8212; in very intensive efforts to have all of these &#8212; all of these countries join.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;ve been very &#8212; frankly, as [senior administration official] said, you know, we&#8217;re not at the end of this; the Declaration remains open.&nbsp; And, you know, for some people, it takes time (inaudible) think about it or, frankly, even just see who else has joined.&nbsp; And we remain confident that like-minded countries around the world will &#8212; will sign up.<br><br>[Senior administration official], I don&#8217;t know if you want to address anything else that was in the question.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, I just wanted to echo, [senior administration official], the points you made on membership.&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s been growing by the day, which is terrific, and I think you&#8217;re going to continue to see it grow going forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, in terms of the splinternet issue &#8212; look, I think the reality is that what we&#8217;re seeing as we look out over the world is a, you know, trend by some countries, and particularly some of the authoritarian countries, to try to create a splinternet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I mean, you look at what Russia is doing, some of the steps that China has been taking &#8212; and I think we actually see this as, in many ways, a response to these kind of splinternet tendencies by a number of the authoritarian countries around the world.&nbsp; Because what we&#8217;re really doing is taking a big-tent approach, laying out a broad &#8212; you know, and as I say, you know, more than 55 countries &#8212; broadly-shared vision of the future of the Internet.&nbsp; And we think that kind of galvanizing the world behind a shared vision is a very important part of pushing back on these splinternet tendencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, on a more technical level, I think you&#8217;ll see &#8212; see in the text of the Declaration, you know, one of the principles we are committing to &#8212; all the countries are committing to &#8212; is kind of a reaffirmation of, you know, the multistakeholder approach to governance of the Internet &#8212; the idea that, you know, going back to its creation decades ago, it has been governed by a multi-stakeholder approach.&nbsp; And, you know, we view this as an opportunity to kind of reaffirm a commitment to that at a time when not every country is on board.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; You know, let me double-down on that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not &#8212; we and our allies are not here to splinter the Internet but, frankly, to save it from splintering.&nbsp; You know, there has been a determined effort, as you said, to try and set up the two multiple Internets, each &#8212; each different.&nbsp; And we are &#8212; and our allies &#8212; reaffirming the vision of one Internet for the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Internet was originally a network of networks designed to interconnect everyone, and we think there&#8217;s extraordinary value in that.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re here to try to restore that vision.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next question, please.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, everyone, thank you so much for your time.&nbsp; I want to dig in a little bit on &#8212; you said, you know, in the coming weeks, months, years, they&#8217;re going to be implementing these principles.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if you can &#8212; like, more specifically, what does that mean?</p>



<p>And part of the reason I ask is that I think we can look at how China has approached these questions.&nbsp; It has often been by really kind of pushing products to countries in terms of telecom equipment, undersea cables, like, that provide them sort of &#8212; sort of material support, if they bring their countries online and their infrastructure up to date.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, principles are one thing, but how do you counter &#8212; how do you plan to counter sort of an on-the-ground offensive, that is often about sort of more material, in line with this document you&#8217;re going to put out tomorrow?&nbsp; Thanks so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So I think this is a great question, David, and thanks for it.&nbsp; And I should &#8212; maybe we should have made clear off the &#8212; you know, right off &#8212; right off the top: Obviously, what we&#8217;re doing with the DFI tomorrow is one important part, but only one important part of a kind of comprehensive set of tools and policies we, as the United States, have to promote our vision of the Internet and of global digital connectivity.</p>



<p>You know &#8212; and, for example, you know, our State Department colleague who&#8217;s on &#8212; on with us, you know, works for a new bureau the State Department just set up a couple of weeks ago in order to &#8212; in order to help make the U.S. more effective, both at a diplomatic level but also, as you say, at pushing out, like, tangible, concrete things.</p>



<p>And I think we could give you a whole, you know, separate interview on all the things we are doing to promote Open RAN 5G technologies around the world to help, you know, get the DFC to try to finance trusted telecommunications networks in developing countries around the world, you know, in competition with Huawei and other Chinese providers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, we&#8217;ve been doing a ton &#8212; both through DHS, CISA, also through various other mechanisms, modalities &#8212; to share cybersecurity, you know, operational information; how to have Shields Up posture, to provide that kind of practical assistance, as well.</p>



<p>And then, of course, we&#8217;ve been, through our State and AID colleagues, doing things to sort of tangibly promote the Internet freedom agenda, right?&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been, you know, providing, sort of, material support &#8212; you know, encryption technologies and things like that to NGOs around the world and in repressive societies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then you&#8217;ve seen us, kind of at a policy level &#8212; I think you will see us through the IPEF and the digital provisions of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework and through the work we&#8217;re doing at TTC, kind of at a regulatory level, drive that agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we see here is a way to kind of, as we&#8217;re taking, you know, tangible steps in the assistance space, in the help the NGOs space, in the kind of global regulatory space &#8212; you know, this is a way of really re-energizing, at a principles-driven level, what the vision is that will then help build global support and drive all of these &#8212; drive further all of these kinds of individual, practical workstreams across the different areas of the vision that we&#8217;re pulling together and laying out tomorrow.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; I think we can do the next question, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; I was wondering if you could talk a little bit about, I guess, what&#8217;s changed since December when you all were working on the Alliance for the Future of the Internet and, sort of, what lessons you all have learned and who you’ve talked to since then.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So I’ll be happy to discuss that.&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve been using the time since December to &#8212; essentially in recruitment and working with other countries &#8212; to sort of improve things.&nbsp; And I think that has really paid off.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I think that there&#8217;s now, as I said, more than 55 countries.&nbsp; You know, it takes time to sort of socialize an idea.&nbsp; Sometimes two steps is better than one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think if you look carefully at the &#8212; I shouldn&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t think I want to encourage you to compare it with leaked versions &#8212; but I think that, you know, we talked to a lot of partners.&nbsp; We recognize the importance of civil society and stakeholders in this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, some of the feedback that we got &#8212; as you&#8217;ve probably noticed, most obviously, the name has changed from “alliance” to “declaration.”&nbsp; So that&#8217;s one area which changed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve envisioned things.&nbsp; You know, I think the underlying thinking is similar, but we envisioned this declaration as a useful tool for multiple other fora.&nbsp; And I made it just very clear, I think, that this works in harmony with and is a complement to existing fora.</p>



<p>So, you know, it&#8217;s a reaffirming and an updating of the visions that anchored and powered some of the original Internet freedom work in the &#8212; from &#8212; over the last 20 years or so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, yeah, I think that the delay has actually helped us quite a bit.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; I think we can do our next question, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, folks.&nbsp; I wonder if you might just briefly address what, if any, outreach you may have done on this initiative to Russia and China and what you may have heard back from them, if anything.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to be in a position to get into specific diplomatic conversations with specific countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would say is we&#8217;ve obviously &#8212; in addition to the countries that have joined and that might be joining, you know, if not tomorrow, in the coming weeks &#8212; we have &#8212; I guess I wouldn’t say &#8212; I don’t think this will come as a surprise to any countries, even countries that we always thought were unlikely to join this, but I&#8217;m not going to comment on specific diplomatic discussions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; I think we have time for one more, so let’s do our last question, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, yeah, Ina with Axios.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Two things.&nbsp; One, some have called for something akin to a Geneva Convention governing what types of cyber warfare are and aren’t permissible.&nbsp; I&#8217;m guessing this is largely adjacent to that push, although there&#8217;s a little bit of discussion, I think, about protecting Internet infrastructure.&nbsp; But I want to make sure I have that correct.</p>



<p>And then also, I&#8217;m curious: What role, if any, do the big tech companies play in this?&nbsp; Were they &#8212; were you outreaching to them?&nbsp; Do you see them as not &#8212; this is really about nation states, not companies?&nbsp; So if you could clarify those two.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I’ll take a stab.&nbsp; So, on the first: Yeah, this is not a &#8212; this is not about cyber warfare.&nbsp; I mean, I guess you&#8217;re right to say at the edge &#8212; you know, at the edge, there may be some overlap.&nbsp; We have principles related to cyber ransoms, electoral interference.&nbsp; Some people consider electoral interference to be the edge.&nbsp; So I think it&#8217;s compatible with some of the developing principles in cyber warfare, but it&#8217;s not a cyber warfare treaty or anything &#8212; or agreement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you know what this does have in common is this increasing sense that there needs to be almost constitutional principles for countries that “it shalt and shall not” &#8212; things that should be off limits.&nbsp; And, you know, some people call for that in cyber warfare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here we&#8217;re calling for it &#8212; or we&#8217;re agreeing on it, politically, more directly and in all kinds of areas, whether it&#8217;s unlawful surveillance of your citizens, whether it&#8217;s blocking legitimate news sources, whether it&#8217;s shutting down the Internet, and whether &#8212; or whether it&#8217;s, what I would say, interfering with elections of other countries.</p>



<p>You know, I think there is a need.&nbsp; And this is the first &#8212; I&#8217;ll emphasize that this is the first document to bring all these concepts together and put them in one place in this fashion, be agreed to by so many countries, and then to sort of stand on it &#8212; to stand on its own.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the question &#8212; the related question is whether big tech is involved.&nbsp; I mean, they’re obviously stakeholders in this, and we&#8217;ve consulted, like any other stakeholder or any other member of civil society.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the primary impetus here was to get at this question of state behavior and to meet what we have seen is a very negative trajectory, what we&#8217;ve seen as an effort to fundamentally change the Internet &#8212; the nature of the Internet &#8212; from something that is an instrument of commerce and culture to something that is an instrument of state power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we believe that winning this particular struggle is, frankly, key to &#8212; the key part of the overall struggle between democracies and authoritarian governments.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s the kind of &#8212; that&#8217;s the focus of this effort.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And, [senior administration official], you didn&#8217;t have anything to add, right?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; I think [senior administration official] was &#8212; nothing to add to [senior administration official]’s comments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; So, everyone, thanks for joining us today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The contents of this call are embargoed until tomorrow, Thursday, April 28th, 7:00 a.m. Eastern.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m about to send around the factsheet as well.&nbsp; Again, if you did not get the materials, please email NSC Press or email me.&nbsp; Thanks again, everyone, for joining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:28 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States and 60 Global Partners Launch Declaration for the Future of the&#160;Internet</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/fact-sheet-united-states-and-60-global-partners-launch-declaration-for-the-future-of-the-internet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Internet has been revolutionary. It provides unprecedented opportunities for people&#160;around&#160;the world to connect and to express themselves, and continues to transform the global economy,&#160;enabling&#160;economic opportunities&#160;for&#160;billions of people. Yet it has also created&#160;serious policy challenges. Globally, we&#160;are witnessing a&#160;trend of rising digital authoritarianism&#160;where&#160;some states act to repress freedom of expression, censor independent news sites, interfere&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Internet has been revolutionary. It provides unprecedented opportunities for people&nbsp;around&nbsp;the world to connect and to express themselves, and continues to transform the global economy,&nbsp;enabling&nbsp;economic opportunities&nbsp;for&nbsp;billions of people. Yet it has also created&nbsp;serious policy challenges. Globally, we&nbsp;are witnessing a&nbsp;trend of rising digital authoritarianism&nbsp;where&nbsp;some states act to repress freedom of expression, censor independent news sites, interfere with elections, promote disinformation, and deny their citizens other human rights.&nbsp;At the same time, millions of&nbsp;people still face barriers to access&nbsp;and cybersecurity risks and threats undermine the trust and reliability of networks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Democratic governments and other partners are rising to the challenge.&nbsp;Today, the United States with 60&nbsp;partners from around the globe launched the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Declaration-for-the-Future-for-the-Internet_Launch-Event-Signing-Version_FINAL.pdf">Declaration for the Future of the Internet</a>. Those endorsing the Declaration include&nbsp;Albania, Andorra, Argentina, Australia, Austria, Belgium, Bulgaria, Cabo Verde, Canada, Colombia, Costa Rica, Croatia, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Denmark, Dominican Republic, Estonia,&nbsp;the European Commission,&nbsp;Finland, France, Georgia, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Iceland, Ireland, Israel, Italy, Jamaica, Japan, Kenya, Kosovo, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Maldives, Malta, Marshall Islands, Micronesia,&nbsp;Moldova, Montenegro, Netherlands, New Zealand, Niger, North Macedonia,&nbsp;Palau,&nbsp;Peru, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Senegal, Serbia, Slovakia, Slovenia, Spain, Sweden,&nbsp;Taiwan, Trinidad and Tobago, the United Kingdom, Ukraine,&nbsp;and&nbsp;Uruguay.</p>



<p>This Declaration&nbsp;represents&nbsp;a&nbsp;political commitment among Declaration partners to&nbsp;advance apositive&nbsp;vision for the Internet and digital technologies.&nbsp;It&nbsp;reclaims the promise of the Internet in the face of the global opportunities and challenges presented by the 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century.&nbsp;It also&nbsp;reaffirms and recommits its partners to a single global Internet – one that is truly open and fosters competition, privacy, and respect for human rights.&nbsp;The Declaration’s principles includecommitments to:&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;Protect human rights and fundamental freedoms of all people;&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;Promote a global Internet that advances the free flow of information;&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;Advance inclusive and affordable connectivity so that all people can benefit from the digital economy;&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;Promote trust in the global digital ecosystem, including through protection of privacy; and&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;Protect and strengthen the&nbsp;multistakeholder&nbsp;approach to governance that keeps the Internet running for the benefit of all.</p>



<p>In signing this Declaration, the United States and partners will work together to promote this vision and its principles globally, while respecting each other’s regulatory autonomy within our own jurisdictions and in accordance with our respective domestic laws and international legal obligations.</p>



<p>Over the last year, the United States has worked with partners from all over the world – including civil society, industry, academia, and other stakeholders&nbsp;to reaffirm the vision of an open, free, global, interoperable, reliable, and secure Internet&nbsp;and reverse negative trends in this regard. Under this vision, people everywhere will benefit from an Internet that is&nbsp;unifiedunfragmented; facilitates global communications and commerce; and supports freedom, innovation,&nbsp;education&nbsp;and trust. &nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Small Business Boom Under the Biden-&#8288;Harris&#160;Administration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/fact-sheet-the-small-business-boom-under-the-biden-harris-administration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Through the American Rescue Plan and the equitable implementation of emergency relief programs, President Biden and Vice President Harris fostered the strongest recovery for Main Street on record. In 2021, Americans applied to start 5.4 million new businesses—more than 20 percent higher than any previous year on record. The boom in new business creation has been&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Through the American Rescue Plan and the equitable implementation of emergency relief programs, President Biden and Vice President Harris fostered the strongest recovery for Main Street on record. In 2021, Americans applied to start 5.4 million new businesses—more than 20 percent higher than any previous year on record.</p>



<p>The boom in new business creation has been particularly strong for entrepreneurs of color. In 2021, Hispanic Americans started new businesses at the fastest rate in more than a decade and 23 percent faster than pre-pandemic levels.</p>



<p>And, in the three-quarters of 2021, small businesses with fewer than 50 employees created 1.9 million jobs, the fastest start to small business job growth in any year on record.</p>



<p>This new White House report details the historic recovery for America’s small businesses and demonstrates how the Biden-Harris agenda laid the foundation for this small business boom. By focusing on combatting the pandemic, providing Americans with greater financial security, and delivering more than $450 billion in emergency relief to small businesses, the Biden-Harris Administration has helped create the conditions for unprecedented business and job creation.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris strategy to rescue and revitalize Main Street contrasts sharply with the latest tax plan from Republicans in Congress. The Congressional Republican proposal put forward by Senator Rick Scott to impose a minimum tax on middle-class families would increase taxes on small businesses across the country. In addition to detailing the historic economic progress the Biden-Harris Administration has made to date, the Appendix includes a new state-by-state analysis of the Congressional Republican tax plan. The analysis finds that this tax plan would raise taxes on nearly half of small business owners (6.1 million people), including 82 percent of small business owners making less than $50,000 per year. Under the Congressional Republicans’ plan, the typical small business owner would see their taxes increased by almost $1,200.</p>



<p>President Biden rejects Congressional Republicans’ plan to increase taxes on half of small business owners. His four-pillar economic strategy for small businesses will lower costs and level the playing field for families and small businesses. The plan is focused on:</p>



<p>1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Expanding access to capital,</p>



<p>2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Making historic investments in helping small businesses navigate available resources,</p>



<p>3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Leveraging federal spending to support small businesses, and</p>



<p>4.     Leveling the playing field for small business owners by reforming the tax code.</p>



<p>Read the full report here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/President-Biden-Small-Biz-Boom-full-report-2022.04.28.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/President-Biden-Small-Biz-Boom-full-report-2022.04.28.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the 2022 National and State Teachers of the Year&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/27/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-2022-national-and-state-teachers-of-the-year-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 4:35 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you, Kurt.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you. Secretary &#8212; Secretary Cardona, thank you.&#160; And &#8212; and I want to thank Jill.&#160; Jill is the nation’s first First Lady to work full time as a professor &#8212; as a teacher.&#160; She taught high school and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>4:35 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Kurt.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>Secretary &#8212; Secretary Cardona, thank you.&nbsp; And &#8212; and I want to thank Jill.&nbsp; Jill is the nation’s first First Lady to work full time as a professor &#8212; as a teacher.&nbsp; She taught high school and she teaches at a community college for a long time now.<br><br>We made a deal that &#8212; she was so &#8212; teaching is not what Jill does, it’s who she is, like most of you &#8212; who you are, what you believe.&nbsp; And so when we got elected &#8212; the presidency and as Vice President, as well &#8212; I suggested and she agreed fully that she should continue to teach.&nbsp; And people said, “What?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Well, she teaches 14 credits a semester at community college full time, and she does her job.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, you know, I’m very, very supportive of teachers for a number of reasons &#8212; some of them are personal.&nbsp; But if I didn’t support teachers, I’d be sleeping alone in one of these bedrooms up here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>You know, before I begin the formal comments, one of the things that Jill reminded me of when she spoke &#8212; and I’ll bet all of you can give examples as well &#8212; I &#8212; I had &#8212; I got lucky.&nbsp; I won the &#8212; I won the lottery, in terms of parents; my mother and father were wonderful people.&nbsp; I had one of those moms that everybody wished had been their mom, for real.&nbsp; Everybody hung at my house.</p>



<p>But I also was a bit of a runt, in terms of my size.&nbsp; And I used to ta- &#8212; ta- &#8212; ta- &#8212; talk like this.&nbsp; I stuttered badly.&nbsp; And when you stutter, everyone thinks you have to be either stupid or totally incompetent.</p>



<p>And if you notice, it&#8217;s the only infirmity a child can talk about &#8212; an adult can talk about having had that people &#8212; you didn&#8217;t because you’re teachers &#8212; think they can laugh, think it&#8217;s funny.</p>



<p>If you saw the movie “The King&#8217;s Speech,” you understand.&nbsp; You understand.</p>



<p>We went to see it, Jill and I, and right as the King was standing at the racetrack making the speech, she reached over &#8212; I guess I tightened up somehow; it brought back all &#8212; all the memories.&nbsp;<br><br>And I look back on it now and I wonder, besides I really got lucky with my parents &#8212; my mother would say, “Look at me, Joey.&nbsp; Look at me.&nbsp; You&#8217;re smarter than anybody.&nbsp; You&#8217;re this.&nbsp; You&#8217;re that.&nbsp; So, stop.&nbsp; You can do this.”<br><br>My point is this: that I had teachers &#8212; I can name the ones through grade school, high school, and even college.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t really beat my stuttering, and still occasionally I do, until I was &#8212; took speech and debate class in college just to force myself to be able to stand up.<br><br>When they sent me the copy &#8212; the guy who wrote “The King&#8217;s Speech” found the original speech and made a copy of it and sent it to me &#8212; no, I mean, from the movie.</p>



<p>And he does his speeches exactly like I did, which a nun taught me.&nbsp; If you took a look at my speech, you&#8217;ll see that there&#8217;s all these slash marks in the speech.&nbsp; Because, you know, an awful lot of people who are &#8212; I can&#8217;t sing worth a damn, but the people &#8212; entertainers and singers can sing like a nightingale but can&#8217;t talk, can&#8217;t speak.</p>



<p>And I look back on my life, and I think, beyond my family &#8212; my sister, my brother, my mom, my dad &#8212; the people who made a difference in my life, in a fundamental way, were teachers.</p>



<p>I remember &#8212; I was talking on the way over.&nbsp; This &#8212; my staff is going, “Why aren’t you giving the speech we wrote?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But I remember &#8212; I truly remember &#8212; and we were talking about it on the way over &#8212; what got me involved in politics.&nbsp; I got into politics &#8212; involved in politics because I think the greatest sin that anyone can commit is the abuse of power, whatever that power is &#8212; the power of a teacher, the power of a doctor, the power of a leader.&nbsp; When someone who is relying on you or you cannot &#8212; just the abuse of power.<br><br>And I got involved because my state was the only state in the Union, when Dr. King was murdered, that was occupied by the National Guard for 10 months with drawn bayonets in every corner because we had a very conservative governor who ordered the National Guard and &#8212; because my state has the eighth-largest Black population in America as a percent of population.</p>



<p>And I had a job with the &#8212; one of the oldest law firms in the state.&nbsp; And I quit and became a public defender; that’s what got me involved.</p>



<p>But again, where teachers come in: I was &#8212; I had no intention of running for public office.&nbsp; Everybody thought Biden knew he wanted to be President at the time he was in sixth grade or something.&nbsp; I love these biographies.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal: What I did do &#8212; I wanted to get engaged.&nbsp; And so, we had a very, very conservative Democratic Party in my state.&nbsp; And I thought it was &#8212; I thought it was wrong on civil rights.&nbsp; The more &#8212; the more progressive party was the Republican Party because we were a southern Democratic Party.&nbsp; We&#8217;re a slave state to our great shame, early on.&nbsp; We fought on the side of the North, like Maryland did, and four &#8212; two other states, but we were a border state.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what got me going.&nbsp; And so, I was asked by a group of senior lawyers whether or not I’d join a thing called a “New Democratic Coalition.”&nbsp; And the reason I bother to tell you that was how to reform the party, how to bring it into the &#8212; into the &#8212; you know, the 21st century &#8212; the 20th century, at the time.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and one day after being asked to see if I can help recruit someone to run for the United States Senate against a very popular Republ- &#8212; Democ- &#8212; Republican senator, a group of senator &#8212; a former senator, a former congressman, and two former governors came to me and said, “We want you to run.”&nbsp; And I wasn&#8217;t even old enough.&nbsp; I was 29 years old.</p>



<p>And I thought, “This is crazy.”&nbsp; But I remember going home from that convention, and the first stop I made was to speak to a professor in Dr. Ingersoll, who was one of those professors who was my &#8212; my &#8212; my philosophy professor in political science.&nbsp; And I stopped him, and I told him what was going on.&nbsp; And he looked at me, and I&#8217;ll never forget what he said.&nbsp; He said, “You should do it.”&nbsp; I said, “I can&#8217;t do that.”&nbsp; I never even knew anybody who was in the Senate.</p>



<p>And he looked at me; he said, “Remember what Plato said.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll paraphrase it,” he said.&nbsp; “The penalty good people pay for not being involved in politics is being governed by people worse than themselves.”</p>



<p>But my generic point is this: He gave me the confidence,</p>



<p>as a 29-year-old kid with no money, to run.&nbsp; He gave me the confidence.&nbsp; Just like the nun would tell me, “Joey, Joey, you can do this.”&nbsp; It gave me the confidence.</p>



<p>And I think about it.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to think about, 20 years from now, how did you end up standing on the podium in the White House?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, you didn&#8217;t ever expect that.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I wonder how I got here.&nbsp; I got here because of my parents and my teachers.&nbsp; My teachers.</p>



<p>And so, folks, you know, that idea is exemplified by the National Teacher of the Year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Kurt, you have and I have something in common though.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I was an adjunct professor in law school for years teaching an advanced course in separation of powers.&nbsp; And I taught to get &#8212; to get money when I was at Syracuse Law School.&nbsp; To get through law school, I was a substitute teacher.&nbsp; You should be nicer to them.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)</p>



<p>But that’s not what Kurt and I have in common.&nbsp; What we have in common is we both married women who are smarter than we are.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>This is an assistant dean at Oberlin College, one of the finest colleges in the country.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Kurt teaches history; he taught 25 years.&nbsp; In fact, he teaches in the same town, in the same district he grew up in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, when I left the vice presidency, I had a chance to do a number of things.&nbsp; But I became a professor at the University of Pennsylvania, and &#8212; presidential politics.&nbsp; And I &#8212; it was &#8212; I enjoyed it, but it&#8217;s hard.&nbsp; That&#8217;s another thing people don&#8217;t realize: It&#8217;s hard.&nbsp; How much you prepare.</p>



<p>I had a three-credit course I taught in law school.&nbsp; I would literally, every single &#8212; I didn&#8217;t want to do it during the week because I didn&#8217;t want people to say I’m taking away from my job as a senator, so I did it on Saturdays at Delaware Law School.</p>



<p>I would prepare &#8212; Jill will tell you &#8212; three to four hours every single &#8212; before every class.&nbsp; And it was what &#8212; not only I taught, but &#8212; what I did as Chairman of the Judiciary Committee.&nbsp; I taught about separation of powers.&nbsp; It was what I did my whole life.&nbsp; And it took me all that time.</p>



<p>But the point is: It really mattered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know &#8212; you know, I love what this guy said in his classroom about &#8212; he said his classroom &#8212; he said, “We listen to each other and respect people&#8217;s opinion.”</p>



<p>Well, part of this is all about fundamentally teaching respect.&nbsp; While we might be in the opposite sides of hot topics, we&#8217;re on the same side in terms of having respect for one another.</p>



<p>Well, Kurt, I understand you wanted to go back home to be a teacher because your teachers inspired you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll bet every one of you can name one or two teachers who fundamentally impacted your lives.</p>



<p>Well, you know, I think you&#8217;ve paid it forward many times over, old buddy, and &#8212; transforming the lives of your students in Oberlin, Ohio, helping students see themselves in you.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what happens, I think.&nbsp; And helping all your students not only learn history, but see &#8212; see what they &#8212; that they have a role in shaping history &#8212; I mean in a literal sense. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And to the Delaware Teacher of the Year, where &#8212; where were you, Jahsha?&nbsp; Where’s the Delaware Teacher of the Year?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I got to admit, we&#8217;re the second-smallest state, but I&#8217;m a little prejudiced on behalf of the state of Delaware.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know there are a lot of eighth graders at Brandywine who are feeling confident and more comfortable because of your help.&nbsp; Jill taught at the same school when she was in Delaware, at Brandywine school &#8212; high school.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And even though Teacher Appreciac- &#8212; Appreciation Week officially starts next week, I wanted to get us started earlier.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s an honor for me and the First Lady and Secretary Cardona to recognize the Teachers of the Year from 50 different states.&nbsp; And it really is something we look forward.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I had &#8212; I did a eulogy today for a brilliant woman, the former Secretary of State.&nbsp; And I sat in the front row with two other presidents who were also there to honor her.&nbsp; And I told them what I was doing.&nbsp; And they all talked about how much they enjoyed the years they were here with the Teacher of the Year event.</p>



<p>Over &#8212; over the past two years, though, the entire country has witnessed the extraordinary dedication and resolve of our nation&#8217;s teachers.</p>



<p>Early in the pandemic, teachers and teachers’ aides had to &#8212; had to do &#8212; not just be educators, you had to be tech support, you had to be moral support, you had to be &#8212; you had to be health support.&nbsp; I mean, you had to take care of your own children in addition.</p>



<p>And I watched how hard it was &#8212; how really hard.&nbsp; There was so much heroic work to help kids connect, get connected to schools, and just the socialization that they were missing in so many places for so long.&nbsp; It&#8217;s estimated they&#8217;re five to seven months behind in their education right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The American people saw it.&nbsp; Because guess what?&nbsp; When you&#8217;re taught remotely from home, the moms and dads understood what you were doing.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And that &#8212; no, and they know they realized how damn hard it is.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious.</p>



<p>I think it was &#8212; you know, my mother used to say, “Out of everything bad, something good will happen if you look hard enough for it.”&nbsp; I think that was the upside.&nbsp; The American people became, “Whoa.&nbsp; My goodness.”&nbsp; And they understand what you’ve been saying for years.&nbsp; That you are professionals &#8212; all of you.&nbsp; All of you have a responsibility to make sure you have what you need, and we have a responsibility to make sure we have what you need to educate our children safely so they have a chance &#8212; a chance to achieve their dreams &#8212; dreams they don’t even know they have &#8212; they don’t even know they have.</p>



<p>That’s why I made it a priority to get educators vaccinated and re-open our schools quickly.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We made a historic commitment to our schools &#8212; $130 billion in the Rescue Plan &#8212; $130 billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It helped us go from 50 percent of our schools being closed to 99 percent of schools open and safe &#8212; better heating, air conditioning, and ventilation systems, safer buildings.&nbsp; It isn’t a thriving building until it comes alive, though, with teachers and students.</p>



<p>With the help of the American Rescue Plan, local governments were able to &#8212; as the state officials here can tell you &#8212; in education &#8212; were able to add a record 279,000 new educators in 2021 &#8212; two hundred and sev- &#8212; 50,000 &#8212; another 50,000 jobs &#8212; teaching jobs in the first months of 2022.</p>



<p>In January, compared to the period before the pandemic, schools have increased their number of social workers by 65 percent and counselors by 17 percent.&nbsp; You&#8217;re expected to do everything.&nbsp; You&#8217;re expected to not only teach, you&#8217;re expected to be a guidance counselor yourself, but you&#8217;re also expected to deal with the problems that they have at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You see it.&nbsp; You can see it in their faces when they walk into school and, as Jill said, just by the way they answer the questions &#8212; and questions about how they&#8217;re doing, how they’re feeling.&nbsp; And you need help.&nbsp; You need social workers.&nbsp; You need school psychologists and psychiatrists.&nbsp; You need that kind of help.</p>



<p>And the American Rescue Plan funds are especially important now that we see the impact that this pandemic exacted on our children.&nbsp; As I&#8217;ve said, students have lost months of learning, particularly reading and math.&nbsp; It’s not just academic skills they’ve fallen behind on, teachers are seeing young children struggle to interact in group settings, to manage conflict, to take turns.&nbsp; They’ve got a learning &#8212; a lot of learning to make up.&nbsp; And we’re doing everything we can to help you.&nbsp; I want to know &#8212; I want input from you as well, because we have a lot of teachers we seek their input.</p>



<p>Using funds from the American Rescue Plan, schools are providing and expanding summer learning &#8212; summer learning and tutoring programs to give students the extra time and attention they need to catch up and develop those fundamental math and reading skills.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You all know, if you get far behind in first, second, third, fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh grade, it takes a lot of time to make up.&nbsp; And if you lose your confidence, it even gets harder.</p>



<p>So, I urge more states, counties, and cities and towns to use their American Rescue Plan funding, which is in the billions of dollars, to hire more teachers, more tutors, more critical personnel in our schools.</p>



<p>Now we have an opportunity to make even more game-changing investments for educators, students, and families.</p>



<p>We’re in a competition for leading the 21st century.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; That’s what we&#8217;re &#8212; that&#8217;s where we are right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, parenthetically, if you think about it: What was the reason why we led the world &#8212; beginning around nineteen-five, -six, and -seven, and -eight?&nbsp; Because we became the first nation in the world to have universal education of 1 through 12, for everybody &#8212; no matter what, without cost.</p>



<p>Well, guess what?&nbsp; If we were sitting down today, deciding we were going to set up an education system, raise your hand if any of you think 12 years is enough in the 21st century?&nbsp; Just 12 years.&nbsp; Things are moving too rapidly.&nbsp; They&#8217;re changing exponentially.</p>



<p>And as Jill said, any country that out-educates us is going to outcompete us.&nbsp; It&#8217;s that basic.&nbsp; So, we have to build a 21st century, because the rest of the world isn’t waiting.&nbsp; We have to build for it.</p>



<p>One of the tough images of the pandemic was children sitting in their cars with their mother or dad or older brother or sister in a McDonald&#8217;s parking lot because that’s the only way they could get on Wi-Fi to do their homework.&nbsp; This is the United States of America for God&#8217;s sake.&nbsp; The United States of America.</p>



<p>If we didn’t know it before, we know now: High-speed Internet is essential.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re spending tens of billions to make sure that we have high-speed Internet available to everyone &#8212; rural America, inner-city America, suburban America &#8212; throughout every single school system in America.&nbsp; That’s part of the whole legislation we passed in terms of infrastructure.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s starting now &#8212; it&#8217;s going to create millions of jobs as well.&nbsp; For real.&nbsp; But again, we got to get in the 21st century.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to move.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I &#8212; the budget I proposed supports schools, supports students, and supports you.</p>



<p>The bridge &#8212; to bridge the gap between under-resourced schools and their wealthier counterparts, we&#8217;re proposing a $19 billion increase in Title I schools &#8212; the most historically neglected and underfunded schools in our nation.&nbsp; We got to get &#8212; we got to let them catch up.&nbsp; That investment would more than double the current funding of Title I schools.</p>



<p>And also &#8212; also proposing the largest increase in special education funding in two decades.&nbsp; We made the promise; we&#8217;ve never filled &#8212; fulfilled it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to fulfill it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to add another billion-dollar commitment with the goal of doubling the number of social workers, school counselors, and school nurses in K through 12.</p>



<p>And, by the way, thanks to the American Rescue Plan, we’re making real progress towards that goal.</p>



<p>And to support you, the educators, my budget includes $610 million to increase teacher diversity, effectiveness, and retention.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; This is key.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because all of you know that it takes time to become a teacher &#8212; the teachers you are today.&nbsp; But nearly 1 in 10 teachers leave the profession every year, with the youngest teachers being the most likely ones to leave first.&nbsp; So, we’ve got to invest in ways to keep them in the profession.</p>



<p>This year, my administration helped over 150 public servants, including teachers, get &#8212; 150,000 &#8212; get school forgive &#8212; forgiveness loans for college loans through changes we made in the Public Service Loan Forgiveness Program.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last team kind of messed it up.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve cleared it up.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, but I really mean it.&nbsp; Because if you go &#8212; if you &#8212; anyway, well, I won&#8217;t go into it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just go to that website.&nbsp; To learn how these changes can benefit you, and &#8212; I encourage you to go to StudentAid.gov, and you&#8217;re going to find you can have, in many of your cases, your entire student debt wiped out, because you are teaching and that&#8217;s considered a vital profession.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One more thing.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not enough to give teachers praise.&nbsp; We ought to give you a raise.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; and I have to really listen to you, which I know Senator Cardona has been doing.&nbsp; And we should stand up for you.&nbsp; We should have your back.&nbsp; Teaching is one of the hardest jobs in this country to be able to do it well, and one of the most important.</p>



<p>Today, there are too many politicians trying to score political points, trying to ban books &#8212; even math books.&nbsp; I mean, did you ever think &#8212; even you younger teachers &#8212; did you ever think, when you&#8217;d be teaching, that you&#8217;d be worried about book burnings and banning books, all because it doesn&#8217;t fit somebody&#8217;s political agenda?</p>



<p>American teachers have dedicated their lives to teaching our children and lifting them up.&nbsp; We got to stop making them the target of the culture wars.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where this is going.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me close with this, because I know &#8212; if I know anything about teachers, I know that some of you were probably grading papers on the way here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the way, Jill traveled with me around the world.&nbsp; I&#8217;d say, &#8220;Jill, leave the binder.&nbsp; Leave the bag.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, how many are math teachers?&nbsp; Raise your hand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She envies the hell out of you.&nbsp; She thinks your job is easier.&nbsp; You just have to check if they know the answer.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>She teaches writing.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But she gets off the plane &#8212; am I joking? &#8212; with up to 50, 60 papers she&#8217;s grading on Air Force One.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I mean, I said, &#8220;Jill&#8221; &#8212; she&#8217;s walking down the, you know &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; you think I&#8217;m kidding you?&nbsp; I&#8217;m not kidding with you.&nbsp; I &#8212; this is deadly earnest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; and many of you are trying to figure out how you&#8217;re going to &#8212; if you have class tomorrow, you may not and you may be here for the &#8212; tomorrow.&nbsp; But on Monday, are you ready for your class?&nbsp; Are you prepared?&nbsp; Do you have your lesson plan together?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because you know &#8212; look, these aren&#8217;t &#8212; we always talk about &#8220;these children.&#8221;&nbsp; They&#8217;re not someone else&#8217;s children.&nbsp; They&#8217;re our children.&nbsp; And they are the kite strings that literally lift our national ambitions aloft in a literal sense.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you got to do one thing to make sure the nation succeeded in the next two generations, what would you do?&nbsp; You&#8217;d want &#8212; I would say, literally, have the best-educated public in the world.&nbsp; Have our students gain confidence enough to know what they can do, to reach in.&nbsp; We have an obligation.&nbsp; We have an obligation to help them teach and reach their potential.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve heard me say it many times about our children, but it&#8217;s true: They&#8217;re all our children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the reason you&#8217;re the Teachers of the Year is because you recognize that.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not somebody else&#8217;s children; they&#8217;re like yours when they&#8217;re in the classroom.&nbsp; You represent a profession that helps them gain the confidence &#8212; a confidence they believe they can do anything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, think of your own lives.&nbsp; Think of where you gained the confidence beyond your family, God willing you&#8217;re able to.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you know what else we&#8217;re finding out?&nbsp; We&#8217;re having a big fight about it now, but I&#8217;m going to get it done eventually, or someone will.&nbsp; And that is that we&#8217;ve learned now &#8212; you all know those who &#8212; of you in the teaching profession know that if you come from a broken home or a home that has a single parent &#8212; and there may be a drug problem or something, from a very poor home &#8212; you&#8217;re going to end up hearing a million words &#8212; fewer words spoken by the time you get to first grade than from a kid coming from an average middle-class home.&nbsp; Not different words, just words spoken, because they&#8217;re not engaged in it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, we learned that if, in fact, you have kids go to school at three years old and four years old and five years old, you&#8217;ll increase exponentially &#8212; by 57 percent &#8212; the likelihood that they will make it no matter what their background, all the way through 12 years of school and probably beyond.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for so &#8212; for that and so much more that you do, you believe in these kids.&nbsp; And I know some of them are really difficult.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I get it.&nbsp; But you believe in them.&nbsp; And you know: When they know you believe in them, they believe in you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So thank you for what you do.&nbsp; You are &#8212; if I get to have one profession that&#8217;s the best in the world &#8212; not a joke &#8212; it&#8217;s you who I want to be the best profession in the world, because you affect what this country looks like, what it&#8217;ll act like, what it&#8217;ll be like, its success or failure, more than any other group of Americans, period.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So thank you for what you do.&nbsp; Keep it going.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I promise you, Jill has your back &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and mine.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Thank you very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how did the release just happen, given the invasion and what’s going on?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Say again?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you surprised Trevor Reed was released by Russia, given the invasion?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I did it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I raised it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How though?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It was three months ago.</p>



<p>5:02 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Roundtable with Lesbian Leaders to Celebrate Lesbian Day of&#160;Visibility</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/27/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-lesbian-leaders-to-celebrate-lesbian-day-of-visibility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, in celebration of Lesbian Day of Visibility, the White House hosted a roundtable conversation with trailblazing lesbian and LGBTQI+ senior leaders from the White House and the broader Biden-Harris Administration. The roundtable included lesbian and queer advocates ,community leaders, leaders across the federal government, several of whom are the first out lesbians to hold&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, in celebration of Lesbian Day of Visibility, the White House hosted a roundtable conversation with trailblazing lesbian and LGBTQI+ senior leaders from the White House and the broader Biden-Harris Administration. The roundtable included lesbian and queer advocates ,community leaders, leaders across the federal government, several of whom are the first out lesbians to hold their position, including: Ambassador Chantale Wong, Director of the Asian Development Bank, who is the first out lesbian to be confirmed by the U.S. Senate to an ambassador post; Admiral Rachel Levine, Assistant Secretary for Health, who is a lesbian and the first openly transgender woman to achieve the rank the four-star admiral in any of the country’s uniformed services; White House Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre; and Deputy White House Communications Director Pili Tobar. The roundtable was convened by White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Participants discussed the unique barriers and challenges faced by lesbians and LGBTQI+ women, including barriers to health equity and reproductive justice; the impacts of anti-LGBTQI+ state legislation on the mental health and wellbeing of lesbian and LGBTQI+ girls; the effects of isolation and discrimination on lesbian older adults; and the economic justice and housing issues impacting lesbian women and couples. Participants highlighted that lesbians who are also women and girls of color, transgender women, women with disabilities, and older women face additional intersecting challenges to achieving economic security and full inclusion. Administration officials highlighted the actions the Biden Administration has taken to advance equity and visibility for lesbians and other LGBTQI+ women, and reaffirmed the President’s commitment to full equality for all lesbians and LGBTQI+ women and girls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>External participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Charlotte Clymer, Transgender Activist, Military Veteran, and Board Member, LPAC Action Network</li><li>Desireé Luckey, Director of Policy, Unite for Reproductive and Gender Equity (URGE)</li><li>Dr. Imani Woody, Founder and CEO, Mary’s House for Older Adults</li><li>Joanne N. Smith, President and CEO, Girls for Gender Equity (GGE)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the President’s Travel to the Republic of Korea and&#160;Japan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/27/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-presidents-travel-to-the-republic-of-korea-and-japan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51891</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will visit the Republic of Korea and Japan from May 20-May 24 to further deepen ties between our governments, economies, and people. This trip will advance the Biden-Harris Administration’s rock-solid commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific and to U.S. treaty alliances with the Republic of Korea and Japan. It will build on more&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will visit the Republic of Korea and Japan from May 20-May 24 to further deepen ties between our governments, economies, and people. This trip will advance the Biden-Harris Administration’s rock-solid commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific and to U.S. treaty alliances with the Republic of Korea and Japan. It will build on more than a year of intensive diplomacy with the Indo-Pacific, including the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit on May 12-13 in Washington, D.C. In each country, President Biden will hold bilateral meetings with his counterparts: newly elected President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea and Prime Minister Kishida Fumio of Japan. The leaders will discuss opportunities to deepen our vital security relationships, enhance economic ties, and expand our close cooperation to deliver practical results. In Tokyo, President Biden will also meet with the leaders of the Quad grouping of Australia, Japan, India, and the United States. We look forward to having further details to share about this trip soon.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 27,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/27/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-27-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 22:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51888</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:07 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, I have no toppers today.&#160; Don’t be so disappointed.&#160; And I know we have a hard out for some people to gather, so we will all keep you updated on when that needs to happen.&#160;But, Zeke, why don’t you kick us off?&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:07 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, I have no toppers today.&nbsp; Don’t be so disappointed.&nbsp; And I know we have a hard out for some people to gather, so we will all keep you updated on when that needs to happen.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, Zeke, why don’t you kick us off?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just two quick.&nbsp; The President put out a statement this morning on the prisoner swap for the release of Trevor Reed.&nbsp; And he called it &#8212; said there were some “difficult decisions” that he had to make, involved.&nbsp; Can you just elaborate on what he meant?&nbsp; Is there a concern that this sort of arrangement incentivizes other countries to wrongfully detain Americans?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that it&#8217;s a huge moment today that speaks to President Biden&#8217;s commitment to bring home Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained around the world.&nbsp; And he has been clear since the beginning of this administration that he is committed to doing exactly that: to bringing Americans home.<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;s brought home Americans from Venezuela, from Afghanistan, from Haiti, from Burma, and now, today, from Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Trevor&#8217;s freedom is the result of months and months of hard, careful work across the U.S. government.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now I&#8217;ll get to your question.&nbsp; When he referenced the tough decision in his statement this morning, he was referencing the decision to commute the sentence of Konstantin Yaroshenko.&nbsp; I would emphasize that this individual had already served the majority of his prison sentence for a nonviolent drug crime.&nbsp; And our overriding priority here was the safe return of Trevor Reed, knowing not only had he been held against his will for too long, but that his health condition required urgent treatment.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to be able to not only be reunited &#8212; united &#8212; reunited with his family, but to receive the treatment he needed from the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, again, our objective is to bring all Americans who are detained, who are held, who are away from their families home from overseas.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to be able to preview for you what processes or approaches we&#8217;re going to take for those moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there a concern that now it&#8217;s not just detaining Americans but wrongfully mistreating them allows &#8212; a lot of them get seriously ill &#8212; it gives other countries leverage over the United States in terms of creating another opportunity, such as this, for this sort of prisoner swap?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, unfortunately, Zeke, you know, there are Americans who are held in other places around the world who we are still working to bring home.&nbsp; And that has been the case long before the President and, importantly, our hostage negotiator took the steps to bring Trevor Reed home.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I &#8212; this has been going on for a long time, I guess is my &#8212; is my larger point.&nbsp; And our effort and our objective was to take steps that we needed to take to bring him home, knowing his health conditions and knowing he&#8217;s been held for too long.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a slightly different topic: Russia yesterday effectively cutting out that &#8212; cutting off natural gas to Poland and Bulgaria.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House response to that?&nbsp; And are there additional steps the U.S. government is taking to reassure its European allies that &#8212; maybe not so much now, but certainly when the weather turns later this year &#8212; that they will have the energy supplies they need?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, unfortunately, this is not &#8212; this is the type of step, the type of almost weaponizing energy supplies that we had predicted that Russia could take in this conflict.&nbsp; That is why we, of course, have been in touch with Europe, including over the &#8212; with these countries &#8212; including over the last 24 hours, with leaders in Poland and Bulgaria.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we have been working for some time now, for months, with partners around the world to diversify natural gas supply to Europe to &#8212; in anticipation of and to also address near-term needs and replace volumes that would otherwise come from Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that last month, in advance of this, the President launched a task force with the EU to target additional LNG volumes for Europe, including Poland and Bulgaria.&nbsp; This will help replace, over time, Russian gas to Europe, decreasing Europe&#8217;s dependence on Russia and Putin’s ability to use energy to coerce Europe.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that Poland and Polish leaders have said they have the capacity through the reserves and other imports right now, for the moment.&nbsp; And Bulgaria has said it is also looking at other import actions.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we are working and we have been working to address over the long term.&nbsp; We have been in touch with these leaders over the last 24 hours.&nbsp; And I would also note what they&#8217;ve said about what their capacities are for the current short term.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Has the President been in touch with or does he plan to reach out to Paul Whelan&#8217;s family, Brittney Griner’s family, any of the other families who have loved ones detained in Russia?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have, of course, been in touch with their families over the course of time.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to detail those conversations further.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But Paul Whelan&#8217;s brother, David Whelan, put out a statement today.&nbsp; He said, “If this case required difficult decisions that the President doesn&#8217;t take lightly, how difficult are the decisions he faces to release Paul?”&nbsp; What&#8217;s your response to the Whelan family?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our response is that we are going to continue to do, the President is going to continue to do, our State Department officials and negotiators are going to continue to do everything they can to bring Paul Whelan home.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I could just ask one more follow-up: The President, of course, met with Reed’s family here at the White House.&nbsp; Can you talk about the personal impact that that meeting might have had?&nbsp; Did it &#8212; did he leave that meeting with a sense of urgency &#8212; a renewed sense of urgency to get this done?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say the President has had a sense of urgency about bringing Americans home long before that meeting.&nbsp; Of course, he enjoyed that meeting he had with them.&nbsp; He also spoke with them on the phone when he went and traveled to Texas.&nbsp; And again, I know he was intending to reach out to them this morning as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the economy, we have a GDP print that&#8217;s coming out tomorrow that&#8217;s expected to show fairly marginal growth.&nbsp; There&#8217;s increasing expectations from banks, predictions of &#8212; that we&#8217;re entering a recession.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Your budget plan had a focus on budget deficit reduction, as opposed to fiscal stimulus.&nbsp; Is there any plan to change that as we see the threat of a recession looming?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, as I&#8217;ve said before on the recession question: Obviously, we look closely at economic data.&nbsp; We continue to believe that there are &#8212; there are strong data in the economy, whether it&#8217;s record job growth, whether it is the current unemployment rate.&nbsp; And that is a result of the actions of the President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note on the GDP expectations for tomorrow: As you noted, the market expectations and other analysts out there do expect the growth to be slower in quarter one, which is what the data is being reported out tomorrow, than in quarter &#8212; the fourth quarter of last year.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This largely reflects the str- &#8212; very strong pace of growth in the fourth quarter.&nbsp; When taken together, growth over the two quarters is expected to be at a solid pace if we look at it over time, which is how we look at data.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And looking under the hood, the slowdown relative to quarter four is mainly for technical reasons like the change in inventory.&nbsp; So, last quarter, companies built up their inventories very quickly.&nbsp; And growth in inventories are expected to be slower, though still positive, this quarter.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is something that has been pointed out &#8212; or this trend or these reasoning &#8212; this reasoning, I should say, has been pointed out by a range of outside economists and forecasters, including former NEC Director Jason Furman.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A quick follow-up just on inflation: There&#8217;s been some numbers that have shown that, you know, the monthly interest payment that somebody pays when they take out a mortgage has basically doubled over the past year.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You&#8217;ve talked about what you&#8217;re doing on meat prices.&nbsp; But if you look at the grocery bill, pretty widely there are many categories where we&#8217;re seeing double-digit inflation: flour, coffee, fruit.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Is there any strategy to deal with some of these other areas where we&#8217;re seeing, kind of, broad-based inflation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say the President&#8217;s plan to address inflation or address causes or costs as they&#8217;ve gone up for the American people has many different components.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Obviously, there&#8217;s an important purview that the Federal Reserve has, and they&#8217;ve indicated their plans to recalibrate.&nbsp; We support that &#8212; that effort or steps they intend to take.&nbsp; And obviously, they have purview over and they&#8217;ve predicted that inflation will come down and moderate before the end of the year.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>But how the American people experience inflation is costs, as you noted, whether it&#8217;s at the grocery store or other costs on their pocketbook.&nbsp; And the President has taken a number of steps to address costs, even extending the pause on student loans, which is something he did just a few weeks ago; the steps to fix the “family glitch” in the Affordable Care Act so more people would be eligible for lower-cost healthcare; and continuing conversations that are happening on Capitol Hill right now on his proposals to lower costs on childcare, healthcare, the cost of prescription drugs.&nbsp; These are all areas that impact and will help families as we&#8217;re working to bring costs down.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President told Trevor Reed’s family that he wanted to call them in the middle of the night last night but didn&#8217;t want to jinx the release of their son.&nbsp; Can you tell us more about what&#8217;s been happening behind closed doors for the last, you know, 12 or 24 hours regarding this release?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And, you know, I think what the President was referring to &#8212; you know, and I&#8217;ve fortunately &#8212; because it&#8217;s a part of history and a great day, obviously, when you bring an American home, and the President has, of course, been a part of many of these in a much higher and more important role &#8212; is just &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of sensitivity, as you all know, around the period of time when individuals are in transit &#8212; right? &#8212; when they are being brought to a third country.<br>&nbsp;<br>As we&#8217;ve noted, you know, we are very grateful to Turkey for allowing the exchange to take place in their country.&nbsp; So, basically, over the last 24 hours &#8212; one, as I noted, this &#8212; this had been happening over several months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, Roger Carstens, the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, and his team and many others have been &#8212; had been negotiating and engaging in this.&nbsp;&nbsp;And the exchange took place in Turkey during the early hours of the morning, East Coast time.&nbsp;&nbsp;So I think what the President was referring to was his understanding and knowledge that that would be happening but not wanting to put anyone in a position of putting that at risk, even people who are excited and joyful and looking forward to the news.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, then once they got to Turkey and they were safely on a plane on their way back, we were able to obviously make notifications and phone calls and also put out this statement from the President to make all of you aware.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Were any other conditions agreed to for Trevor Reed&#8217;s release, besides the release of this Russian?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This was the discussion about one issue and one topic, and that was the release of Trevor Reed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But were there any other conditions agreed to besides releasing the Russian in exchange for Trevor Reed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is no other condition.&nbsp; There were no other conditions that I’m aware of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what does the White House read into Russia’s willingness to release Trevor Reed now, in the middle of this invasion of Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think the release of Trevor Reed, him returning home to his family, receiving the healthcare that he has long needed, does not change our approach or view, opposition, or the President&#8217;s intention to put forward a package in the coming days to help continue to support the Ukrainians.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of what they mean or how they assess it, I would leave it to them to speak to that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But does it make anyone here at the White House more optimistic about what could be ahead, or does it have nothing to do with anything &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This is &#8212; was about one issue and topic, and I don&#8217;t think we should read into it further.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we go toward the back?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, we can come to the back in a moment.&nbsp; Go ahead, Weijia.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; To follow up on MaryAlice&#8217;s question, during an interview this morning, Trevor Reed’s parents said they believed that personal meeting with the President was the, quote, “tipping point,” that it made all the difference.&nbsp; Is that true?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, look, I would say anytime that you meet with &#8212; a President meets with or any official from the government meets with the parents or family members of someone who&#8217;s being detained, that impacts them personally.<br>&nbsp;<br>But this had been negotiated &#8212; in negotiations for months.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I spoke with David Whelan today, and he is concerned that Reed’s release now narrows the chances for his brother&#8217;s release, because Russia obviously was &#8212; you know, wanted Yaroshenko’s release for years now, and now that it&#8217;s happened, he worries that that was a major concession that the U.S. no longer has.&nbsp; So what do you say to the Whelan family?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we would say we will continue to advocate for the immediate, unconditional of Paul Whelan at every opportunity.&nbsp; And using wrongful detention as a bargaining chip represents a threat to the safety of everyone traveling, working, and living abroad.&nbsp; We obviously oppose this practice anywhere, and we are going to continue to do everything we can to bring him home.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They are thrilled, obviously, about Trevor Reed&#8217;s release, but they can&#8217;t help but have some questions about why Paul Whelan, who’s been detained in Russia longer than Trevor Reed, is not home.&nbsp; Can you explain that?&nbsp; And did Reed&#8217;s health, as you mentioned, have anything to do with it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Obviously, our objective continues to be to bring Paul Whelan home and any American who is not with their family and is being detained overseas.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m just not going to get into more details because I want to maintain the protection of our process.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on a separate topic: Yesterday, Dr. Jha said that people who are at high risk for developing a severe case of COVID are eligible for Paxlovid.&nbsp; And the Vice President just got her second booster shot.&nbsp; She has no symptoms.&nbsp; Can you help us understand why she&#8217;s taking it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he also said, which you didn&#8217;t include in your summary there, but &#8212; that you should consult with your doctor, and she consulted with her doctor.&nbsp; She has been given Paxlovid.&nbsp; That’s something many Americans may be eligible for; they should also consult with their doctor.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think, overall, we&#8217;re just grateful that this is an approved drug on the market that many people can benefit from, including the Vice President.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead in the back.&nbsp; In the way back.&nbsp; Way back.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Eleven years ago, Japan had a terrible disaster and the U.S. launched a program most people have probably forgotten called Operation Tomodachi.&nbsp; Twenty-five thousand American military and ten thousand volunteers came from Japan to help.&nbsp; And one of those that came was President Biden.&nbsp; I’m wondering if on this upcoming trip he&#8217;ll be coming back to that area for a short visit.<br>&nbsp;<br>And while we&#8217;re waiting for advisement, is it possible to do an interview with you?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh &#8212; okay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You often come with an interview request.&nbsp; I should know ahead of time.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will just note I expect we will have more details on the President&#8217;s travel to Asia &#8212; something he is clearly looking forward to since he&#8217;s spoken about it publicly &#8212; soon, in the coming days.&nbsp; But in advance of that, I&#8217;m just not going to have much more to preview for all of you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead &#8212; go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Yesterday, after the Vice President announced that she tested positive, the usual people on the Internet and elsewhere who don&#8217;t like vaccines, who don&#8217;t think COVID (inaudible), immediately started with the, “Well, she would have been fine even if she hadn&#8217;t gotten the vaccine.”<br>&nbsp;<br>It seems like every time there&#8217;s a high-profile announcement that someone has gotten COVID &#8212; be it a member of Congress, AG Garland, people at the Gridiron dinner &#8212; people take it as proof that vaccines don&#8217;t work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, what about the White House&#8217;s messaging could be better on that, given that 234,000 Americans died?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, first, I would say the truth, is &#8212; which is, I think, why you&#8217;re asking me this question &#8212; is quite the contrary.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, the Vice President is continuing to carry out her duties, as the Vice President of the United States, from home, engaging in meetings, policy discussions &#8212; I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ll see her in some capacity publicly from home as well &#8212; because she is double boosted and she has taken the steps to protect herself, like we have continued to recommend other Americans do.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I would note that while the vaccine &#8212; the reason to take the vaccine is, of course, because it can protect you from severe death &#8212; from death, from severe illness &#8212; “severe death,” that was a little intense how I said that &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; from death or severe illness, and it &#8212; by multitudes of numbers.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, we&#8217;re going to continue &#8212; and if you are eligible for a booster as she was, as the President was, we recommend you get that for a second booster, because it can put you in a position where even if you get COVID, you&#8217;re able to still not &#8212; experience minimal symptoms or no symptoms, like the Vice President has been, and to continue to go about daily life the best you can while you&#8217;re quarantining.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Tam.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yep, thank you.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci said on the PBS NewsHour last night, quote, “This country is out of the pandemic phase of COVID.”&nbsp; What phase are we in right now?&nbsp; And also, if we are out of the pandemic phase, why are emergency measures still in place?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what Dr. Fauci was saying is that we are in a different phase of this pandemic, and that&#8217;s absolutely true.&nbsp; Last month, the President announced a plan for how we can move forward safely while staying on our front foot against COVID.&nbsp; As he pointed out, nationwide, cases are relatively low &#8212; far below the 900,000 cases a day we saw during the Omicron surge.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Even as we&#8217;ve seen upticks, hospitalizations are about &#8212; at about the lowest level since the pandemic, and deaths are declining.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s no question that we are in a moment &#8212; a different moment in our fight against COVID.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we also know COVID isn&#8217;t over and the pandemic isn&#8217;t over.&nbsp; And what Dr. Jha said yesterday also is that &#8212; different doctor, I realize, but I just want to reference him since he was just here &#8212; is that cases are low, driven by the extremely &#8212; while cases are low, cases &#8212; while cases &#8212; while low, cases are still &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve seen an uptick in some places driven by the extremely transmissible BA.2 variant.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We know the risk of potential sur- &#8212; surges, even as a potential new variant or subvariant remains.&nbsp; So, different phase, because we&#8217;re at a much lower level of hospitalizations, of deaths, and even, nationwide, of cases.&nbsp; But we are still seeing people get very sick from COVID and cases of COVID, and we have measures that we should all continue to take to protect ourselves.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a couple of very quick, short other questions.&nbsp; Daleep Singh is reportedly taking a leave of absence.&nbsp; Can you confirm that &#8212; when he&#8217;ll be gone and what that means for the sanctions work that he&#8217;s doing that is very important right now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is very important.&nbsp; He&#8217;s a very important member of the national security team.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any details or any confirmation of his plans.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I would note, and if Daleep were here &#8212; and we’ll invite him &#8212; he would note is that he has an incredible team he works with who helps put together these sanctions package, help &#8212; packages &#8212; helps implementation, helps coordinate diplomatically.&nbsp; And we will &#8212; there are a number of people who will continue to do that work.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when are you sending the funding request for Ukraine funding up to the Hill?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President said last week it will be this week.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s only two days left of this week.&nbsp; As soon as tomorrow, but in the next two days.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Indonesia decided to invite President Zelenskyy to the G20.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you have a reaction to that, but also what it says about progress that the U.S. might be making behind the scenes, hoping to expel Russia from that forum, and if the decision to invite President Zelenskyy has informed and the President can confirm that he&#8217;s going to now attend the summit.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve seen the reports that President Zelenskyy has been invited to the G20.&nbsp; And we certainly welcome that.&nbsp; As you know, President Biden said just last month that Ukraine should be able to participate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we don&#8217;t have further confirmation beyond the news reports, which we certainly think are positive.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>And as he also said last month &#8212; which is, of course, why you&#8217;re asking me &#8212; he doesn&#8217;t think Russia should be invited, but, ultimately, it&#8217;s a decision for the G20.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we don&#8217;t have any new announcements at this point.&nbsp; We will continue to engage.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve reached out, of course, to Indonesia, as you noted, who&#8217;s hosting the summit.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t have any other additional details.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s six months away.&nbsp; Typically, the President does attend, but I don&#8217;t have anything to confirm about a trip six months away at this point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick one on Ukraine.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been questions about why the U.S. hasn&#8217;t suspended steel tariffs on Ukrainian steel coming in.&nbsp; Do you have any information about why we&#8217;ve maintained those tariffs, considering everything with (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Sure.&nbsp;&nbsp;I &#8212; obviously, there are a range of considerations to provide not only direct assistance but economic relief to the Ukrainians under consideration.&nbsp;&nbsp;I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point in time.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ll go to Kristen and then Jacqui, and then I&#8217;ll go to the back.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Jen, thank you so much. &nbsp;Following up on Tam, we actually just reported that the White House is tomorrow &#8212; as soon as tomorrow &#8212; going to request the supplemental, and that will &#8212; it will be through the end of the fiscal year, and that it&#8217;s going to be “massive.”&nbsp;<br><br>Can you help characterize how much money will the administration be asking for?&nbsp;&nbsp;Will we hear from the President on this?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;So, let me try to answer all those questions, and then tell me if I don&#8217;t.&nbsp; I can confirm “as soon as tomorrow” &#8212; only two days left in this week, but it will definitely be this week that we will send up the supplemental.<br><br>In terms of the President&#8217;s schedule, his role, I have nothing to preview at this point in time.&nbsp; As soon as anything is finalized, if he&#8217;s going to speak publicly, we will announce that to all of you or let you all know.<br><br>In terms of the length or the size, I don&#8217;t have a number for you at this point in time.&nbsp; But there is plans for this to be a proposal to go through the fiscal year.&nbsp; And it will include, as our past packages have included, security or military assistance, humanitarian, economic assistance, given those, in our view, will help address a range of the needs the Ukrainians have.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You did answer all of my question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, there is a renewed push on Capitol Hill and behind the scenes here at the White House for some revised version of the Build Back Better plan &#8212; a scaled-back version.<br><br>When was the last time President Biden spoke with Senator Manchin in earnest about what he could sign off on?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re just not going to detail that, per the President&#8217;s request, from here &#8212; any conversations he has with Senator Manchin or other senators &#8212; just to protect those conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fair enough.&nbsp; Can you characterize, though &#8212; are the negotiations happening in earnest?&nbsp; Are there real talks going on about specific things that Senator Manchin, that the White House could agree to?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would &#8212; I would tell you &#8212; and I&#8217;m sure your colleagues on the Hill, now that all these senators are back, can confirm this with a number of them right now, or today &#8212; that there are still a great deal of interest, passion in moving forward with the President&#8217;s plan to lower costs for Americans and a lot of senators who would like to see this move forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Mayorkas is getting a real grilling on Capitol Hill today, particularly about Title 42 and the plans that are in place to deal with it.&nbsp; DHS has acknowledged that a surge would put a substantial strain on resources.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, obviously, DHS announced this six-point, 20-page plan.&nbsp; But given that strain that DHS is anticipating, why should the American people have confidence that you&#8217;ll be able to deal with that surge of migrants if Title 42 is lifted?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say, just as a reminder: It is a health authority, not an immigration plan or an immigration authority, and it&#8217;s not meant to be a replacement of.&nbsp; So the determination about where we stand and to lift it was made by the CDC.<br><br>Just to note the six-point plan that Secretary Mayorkas put out and talked about today, or over the last 24 hours, includes six pillars: surging resources, including personnel, transportation, medical support; enhancing CBP processing efficiency and moving with deliberate speed to mitigate potential overcrowding; administering consequences for unlawful entry; bolstering the capacity of nongovernmental organizations to receive noncitizens; targeting and disrupting the transnational criminal organization and smugglers; and deterring irregular migration.&nbsp;<br><br>So, what he talked about today is exactly what his preparedness plan &#8212; that&#8217;s been in the works and in the planning for months &#8212; would do.&nbsp; And they have talked about the need, potentially, for more resources to make that happen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to be very clear, and some Democrats have said this: Does the plan &#8212; will the plan be in place before Title 42 is lifted?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is exactly what the preparedness and implementation plan is intended to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jacqui.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci said that he&#8217;s not going to the White House Correspondents’ Dinner, citing COVID concerns.&nbsp; Obviously, he&#8217;s the President&#8217;s chief medical advisor.&nbsp; As far as we know, the President is still planning to attend.&nbsp; How should people understand Dr. Fauci’s decision versus the President&#8217;s decision?&nbsp; And is there any concern that the President would be seen as not following the science in some way?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, first, I would note and respect everyone&#8217;s privacy, including Dr. Fauci’s, as much as he&#8217;s very much a public figure.&nbsp; But as you all know, he can speak for himself and his decisions.&nbsp; And every individual will make their own decisions about whether they attend this event, other events, whether they wear a mask at it or not.<br><br>Obviously, the White House Correspondents’ Association is requiring same-day testing.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a decision they have made.&nbsp; The President outlined, as you all know, a 100-page plan in March intended to position us to go back to our more normal routines.&nbsp; But in that, that requires making risk assessments and decisions about what you&#8217;re going to do and what you&#8217;re going to attend and be a part of, as we all do every day.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, the President felt it was very important to be at and speak at the memorial service for a diplomatic icon &#8212; Secretary Madeleine Albright.&nbsp; He made the decision to do that, despite the fact that there were hundreds if not thousands of people there.&nbsp;<br><br>He has made the decision he wants to attend, in a safe way, the White House Correspondents’ Dinner to show his support &#8212; showcase his support for the free press, for the work of all of you, for the work of your colleagues around the world to not only share accurate information about COVID but also report on the war in Ukraine and all of the work that happens every single day.&nbsp;<br><br>That does stand in stark contrast to his predecessor, who not only questioned the legitimacy of the press on a nearly dai&#8211; &#8212; daily basis, but also never attended the dinner, I don&#8217;t believe.<br><br>So, he felt that was important and made a risk assessment to do that in consultation with his doctors and healthcare team.&nbsp;<br><br>I would note that we also take additional precautions and steps.&nbsp; I would expect that he may wear a mask when he&#8217;s not speaking.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll wear a mask when I&#8217;m at the dinner, in all likelihood.&nbsp; And we also took steps, including the fact that he&#8217;s not attending for the eating portion of the dinner and he&#8217;ll be there for the program, which includes a number of speakers, the presentation of scholarships, as you know, and, of course, his speaking and his roasting, where he will be “on the menu,” as he likes to say, when Trevor Noah is speaking.<br><br>So, you know, just like anything, it&#8217;s a risk assessment and a decision he made on a personal basis.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And I want to ask a few questions on Title 42, but real quick, I want to take another stab at a question I tried yesterday.&nbsp; You answered the first part of it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve heard the President say over and over again that he has never spoken to his son about his business dealings.&nbsp; Has he ever spoken to his son&#8217;s business partners about his son&#8217;s business dealings?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, nothing has changed about what I said yesterday.&nbsp; The President does not get involved in the business dealings of his son.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Even through his son&#8217;s business partners?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nothing has changed since what I said yesterday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe you answered that part of my question yesterday though.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s not involved in his son&#8217;s business dealings.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On Title 42, Mayorkas detailed this six-point plan; part of it involves sending healthcare providers from the VA.&nbsp; He was asked about this on the Hill today.&nbsp; He said that it&#8217;s necessary, that this interagency effort is necessary.&nbsp; But is it appropriate to be taking resources away from the VA to help with the surge at the border?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, these dec- &#8212; these decisions and discussions about what resources are possible are made through the interagency process, and clearly, having support and resources for our nation&#8217;s veterans is a top priority to the President.&nbsp; But we also want to take steps we can at the border, even as we anticipate an increase in migrants coming to the border, to keep the American people safe.&nbsp; And this is part of that effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another piece of this plan talked about the law enforcement help.&nbsp; CBP has 23,000 agents working on the southern border right now.&nbsp; We&#8217;re already seeing 7,000 illegal crossings a day; that is expected to surge to 18,000 when Title 42 is lifted.&nbsp; So, how does adding 600 law enforcement officers make a dent in that?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, Jacqui, that one of the reasons that Secretary Mayorkas is participating in the important, you know, democratic process of testifying on the Hill is to answer the questions of exactly how the resources he&#8217;s requesting, and they have identified as needing, to address this potential increase will help address that.&nbsp; So I would point you to his many hours of testimony today and tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then there&#8217;s been reporting that Speaker Pelosi is unhappy with the way that the White House has handled Title 42 and worried that if it comes up for a vote as part of the Ukraine package, that Democrats wouldn&#8217;t have the votes to defeat that.&nbsp; Does the White House share that concern?&nbsp; And what do you make of Pelosi seeming to be kind of shaky on just how close she is with the White House on this decision?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say we&#8217;re incredibly close with Speaker Pelosi, and the President has known her for many, many decades.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have more to spell out or explain what her meaning was or what “defeat it” means or doesn&#8217;t mean.&nbsp;<br><br>There are many strong feelings and points of view on Capitol Hill in the House and in the Senate about Title 42.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t a decision made by the White House.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a decision made to lift it by the CDC.&nbsp; The authority given to &#8212; was given to them by Congress.&nbsp;<br><br>And our effort and our focus is on implementation.&nbsp; And the Department &#8212; the Secretary of Homeland Security is obviously testifying on that.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t have any more to explain about the particular comments.&nbsp; But we obviously work very closely with Speaker Pelosi on a range of issues, including immigration.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But a number of Democrats are, you know, speaking up about their problems with Title 42.&nbsp; I mean, Mark Kelly was briefed by Mayorkas yesterday.&nbsp; He said that he still has remaining questions about how and when resources are going to hit the ground.&nbsp; These are Democrats saying these things.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not wanting, you know, Title 42 to replace an immigration effort, but they&#8217;re saying that there just is not a plan in place to support what&#8217;s going to happen when Title 42 goes away.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what I was trying to note earlier, perhaps not articulately, is that there are a range of members who have strong concerns about it being lifted.&nbsp; Again, not a decision we make &#8212; a decision made by health and science experts.&nbsp; And there are many members who feel very strongly about it actually being &#8212; it lifted and that moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is why Secretary Mayorkas is on the Hill doing, I believe, four hearings, answering extensive questions from a range of members, Democratic and Republican.&nbsp; He put out a six-pillar plan on exactly how he&#8217;s going to implement it.&nbsp; And that has been a plan that&#8217;s been in the works for six months.&nbsp; So, this is part of the democratic process happening, and he&#8217;s happy to be on the Hill answering their questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Peter.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Jen.&nbsp; The bipartisan leadership of the Senate Judiciary Committee, Senators Durbin and Grassley, have expressed concern about the DHS inspector general delaying or diminishing reports on sexual misconduct.&nbsp; This is Trump-era holdover.&nbsp; Is the President going to fire or in some way intervene with Mr. Cuffari, who is the inspector general, and is there any broader sense about what to do about Trump-era inspectors general?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know that there can be changes made.&nbsp; I have not dug into this particular inspector general with the President or the team here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to do that.&nbsp; And I can follow up with you after the briefing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the issue of student debt, I know you&#8217;ve been asked about this before, but Senator Schumer just told reporters on the Hill that the President is getting closer to canceling up to $50,000 in student loan debt for borrowers.&nbsp; He said, &#8220;The President is moving in our direction… We&#8217;re getting closer.”&nbsp; Is that true?&nbsp; When can we expect a decision?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, the President has been considering and looking at options for how to provide more le- &#8212; relief to students across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note, again, that not a single borrower of federal student loans has paid a penny on these loans since he took office.&nbsp; And this has been the longest time of that for any President, probably, in history.&nbsp; You can factcheck me on that. And he&#8217;s continuing to consider a range of options in terms of any additional steps.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow-up on that &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me go to the back.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; A follow-up on the student loan forgiveness.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said that the President is looking at a range of options with regards to canceling some student debt.&nbsp; But is the President looking at any options for those students and parents who saved and sacrificed so that they wouldn&#8217;t have to take out such massive loans?&nbsp; Is he looking at including them in relief retroactively?&nbsp; How would they be made whole if there was<br>some sort of canceling of debt?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean for people who have paid off all of their student loans?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah &#8212; who made sacrifices so that they wouldn&#8217;t have to take out some of those loans.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; What I can tell you at this point is that there&#8217;s legislation he&#8217;d be happy to sign for individuals who have $10,000 in existing student debt.&nbsp; If Congress wanted to send that to him, he&#8217;d be happy to sign it, and he&#8217;s looking at executive actions and authorities.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Then, you know, if the President does move on canceling some of the student debt, isn&#8217;t that just one half of the equation though?&nbsp; I mean, what is he looking at in order to keep some of these public universities from jacking up tuition prices, despite some of the federal subsidies that they&#8217;ve been getting?&nbsp; I mean, what is it to stop some of these schools from just increasing tuition for the next generation of students?&nbsp; Isn&#8217;t that half of the equation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if people would consider it half of the equation.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll let Americans define it.&nbsp; I would point you the Department of Education to talk about their efforts on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one last quick follow-up.&nbsp; Is the President&#8217;s weekly lunch with the Vice President still a priority for him?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Obviously, they&#8217;re not going to be dining in person while she is quarantining at home, but they did speak yesterday and I expect they will speak regularly while she is quarantining.&nbsp; And she is participating in a number of policy meetings here, too.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a follow-up.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, well &#8212; and then I can come to you next.<br>&nbsp;<br>Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; So polite.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any reaction to Boeing claiming that it&#8217;s lost $1.1 billion on the Air Force One contract?&nbsp; And, more important, has the President ordered Boeing to stick with the traditional blue-and-white design instead of the garish red?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This is bringing me back to, like, my first week in this job.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know, we gave you a year.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, I appreciate it.&nbsp; I actually don&#8217;t have any information on the plans for the new Air Force One.&nbsp; I can certainly check and see what we know, and I can get back to you on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Do you know why the Vice President&#8217;s doctor recommended she take Paxlovid?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, well, I think as Dr. Jha said yesterday, there are a range of Americans who may not know they&#8217;re eligible and they should consult with their doctor.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what she did.&nbsp; And one of the chal &#8212; not challenges, but one of our efforts right now is to provide more information publicly and have more people consult with their doctors about whether they&#8217;re eligible.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know if she&#8217;s, like, showing symptoms?&nbsp; Or would her getting, like, severe COVID present, like, a national security risk?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They obviously said yesterday that she did not have any symptoms.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update beyond that.<br>&nbsp;<br>She&#8217;s continuing to work from home, conducting her duties as Vice President, so I don&#8217;t believe we&#8217;re talking about a national security issue in this moment.&nbsp; She can also do secure calls and video conferences from her home because we have that capacity.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if she got severe COVID disease, would that not be a national security risk?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Paxlovid would potentially prevent that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to speak to a hypothetical of the Vice President getting sicker at this point in time, which I think is probably understandable.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can the White House give us any update on Trevor Reed&#8217;s condition after his release or any treatments that he might have received following his release?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you know, obviously we&#8217;re going to respect his privacy, and we spoke to his health conditions because we wanted to emphasize how important it was and the urgency of bringing him home.&nbsp; But we will, of course, leave that to him and his family to speak to and respect his health privacy beyond now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the Vice President, did her role as Vice President have any impact on her receiving this treatment?&nbsp; Did that &#8212; you know, her serving as somebody who is in the line of succession, did that have any impact on her getting Paxlovid?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s important to note Paxlovid is widely available across the country through people consulting with their doctors.&nbsp; So it is not just a treatment that is available to only a small population of the public.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, what our effort is and what our focus is, at this point, is more broadly educating people on how they may be eligible for it.&nbsp; Certainly, we are grateful that this treatment is out there and available so that the Vice President, somebody who&#8217;s incredibly important in the line of succession, can take it.&nbsp; But she did it through consultations with her doctor.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, in the middle.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So, Democrats on the Hill today said they will act soon on efforts to lower the prices of gas and that a federal gas tax holiday is still on the table for them.&nbsp; If they give the &#8212; or if they include a federal gas tax holiday in a bill, would the President support that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has long said that he&#8217;s open to a range of options, including a federal gas tax holiday, and we&#8217;re continuing to consult with members of Congress about a range of options on lowering the price of gas.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, on Poland and Bulgaria: Energy experts see that as sort of a warning from Russia to Germany, other countries in Europe, to pay in rubles.&nbsp; Is there a me- &#8212; and we&#8217;re also hearing that some companies in Europe are paying rubles for energy.&nbsp; Is there a message from the White House to those companies or countries that might cave and pay in rubles for energy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we have a new message to offer today.&nbsp; What I would note is that we have long predicted &#8212; I mean, this is the Russian playbook; part of the Russian playbook is weaponizing energy.&nbsp; So could they do it other places?&nbsp; That certainly is possible.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the reasons why this taskforce was launched, at the President &#8212; that we&#8217;re working with the Europeans on, to ensure that we are diversifying access for LNG and also for oil as well for the Europeans.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, about a month ago, you announced that the U.S. was going to release 1 million barrels a day for six months.&nbsp; Oil prices &#8212; crude oil prices are still over a hundred dollars a barrel today.&nbsp; Gas prices are up.&nbsp; Is it having the intended effect?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve said this is one tool that we can &#8212; we can utilize.&nbsp; And I know that gas prices also did come down from the beginning as a result of these actions, but we&#8217;re continuing to explore additional options.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As we know, the oil markets are a global market, and increasing supply and continuing to work with other countries to increase supply is part of our overall objective here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It went down only 3 cents, and we&#8217;re about 20 cents away from the record.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we&#8217;re going to continue to take steps to reduce the price of gas for the American people.&nbsp; Every option &#8212; a range of options remains on the table, as is evidenced by the earlier question.&nbsp; And we know that increasing supply and ensuring supply meets the demand on the marketplace as part of that effort.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also watch closely for any attempt at price gouging.&nbsp; When oil prices come down, obviously gas prices should come down.&nbsp; And as you know, because we&#8217;ve had a range of charts in here, we watch that closely as well.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something we will continue to call out.<br>&nbsp;<br>I can do like one &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I think we have to gather in a second.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, I think &#8212; okay.&nbsp; Okay, one last one.&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can I just ask quickly: When the supplemental request comes out, either I guess tomorrow or Friday, will there be anything changing any of the COVID-related requests that are previous?&nbsp; Is the only &#8212; are the only new materials going to be related to the Ukraine request, or will there be a new &#8212; a new spate of requests on COVID assistance as well?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, we will request assis- &#8212; COVID funding, and we will reiterate our requests for $22.5 billion for COVID funding, something we feel will help meet the immediate emergency needs we have.&nbsp; And that was a discussion, obviously, that we didn&#8217;t get through but we will continue with Congress in the coming days and weeks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks so much, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>3:47 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
