<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 06:17:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-cyril-ramaphosa-of-south-africa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 06:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. yesterday met with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa on the margins of the G7 Summit. They discussed the U.S.-South Africa bilateral relationship and underscored the need to expand global COVID-19 vaccine supply and to cooperate on climate goals in Africa and on other bilateral and regional issues. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. yesterday met with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa on the margins of the G7 Summit. They discussed the U.S.-South Africa bilateral relationship and underscored the need to expand global COVID-19 vaccine supply and to cooperate on climate goals in Africa and on other bilateral and regional issues.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Suga Yoshihide Suga of Japan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-suga-yoshihide-suga-of-japan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 23:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Suga Yoshihide of Japan at the G7 to discuss shared challenges in the Indo-Pacific and the world, including COVID-19, climate change, North Korea, China, and preserving peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait. President Biden affirmed his support for strengthening our alliance, extending U.S.-Japan cooperation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Suga Yoshihide of Japan at the G7 to discuss shared challenges in the Indo-Pacific and the world, including COVID-19, climate change, North Korea, China, and preserving peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait. President Biden affirmed his support for strengthening our alliance, extending U.S.-Japan cooperation to new areas like the Build Back Better World (B3W) initiative and strengthening our shared ties with other allies and partners. President Biden affirmed his support for the Tokyo Olympic Games moving forward with all public health measures necessary to protect athletes, staff and spectators. President Biden expressed pride in the U.S. athletes who have trained for the Tokyo Games and will be competing in the best traditions of the Olympic spirit.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout: Trilateral Meeting of Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom, President Joe Biden, and Prime Minister Scott Morrison of Australia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/readout-trilateral-meeting-of-prime-minister-boris-johnson-of-the-united-kingdom-president-joe-biden-and-prime-minister-scott-morrison-of-australia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 21:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prime Minster Johnson, President Biden and Prime Minister Morrison met in the margins of the G7 summit in Carbis Bay on 12 June 2021. They discussed a number of issues of mutual concern, including the Indo-Pacific region. They agreed that the strategic context in the Indo-Pacific was changing and that there was a strong rationale&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Prime Minster Johnson, President Biden and Prime Minister Morrison met in the margins of the G7 summit in Carbis Bay on 12 June 2021. They discussed a number of issues of mutual concern, including the Indo-Pacific region. They agreed that the strategic context in the Indo-Pacific was changing and that there was a strong rationale for deepening strategic cooperation between the three governments. They welcomed the forthcoming visits and exercises in the Indo-Pacific by the Carrier Strike Group, led by HMS Queen Elizabeth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-mario-draghi-of-italy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 20:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Draghi of Italy on the margins of the G7 Summit.  President Biden pledged to further deepen our strong bilateral ties, highlighting this year’s 160th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the United States and Italy.  The President and the Prime Minister pledged to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Draghi of Italy on the margins of the G7 Summit.  President Biden pledged to further deepen our strong bilateral ties, highlighting this year’s 160th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the United States and Italy.  The President and the Prime Minister pledged to continue their close cooperation to overcome the pandemic, including through the G7 commitment to donate COVID-19 vaccines globally, and to build back better global health security for the future. He expressed appreciation for Italy’s continued support for Afghan peace and security.   President Biden welcomed Italy’s leadership of the G20 this year and commended its focus on people, planet and prosperity.   The two leaders agreed to work together on global challenges and shared foreign policy priorities, including China, Russia, and Libya.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on President Biden&#8217;s Meetings at the G7 Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/12/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-president-bidens-meetings-at-the-g7-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 20:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 7:00 P.M. BST&#160;MODERATOR:&#160; Good evening, everyone.&#160; Thank you so much for joining us for this background briefing.&#160; This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and embargoed until the conclusion of the call.&#160; We’ll, of course, have time for Q&#38;A at the end. Not for reporting or attribution, but just for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>7:00 P.M. BST<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you so much for joining us for this background briefing.&nbsp; This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and embargoed until the conclusion of the call.&nbsp; We’ll, of course, have time for Q&amp;A at the end.</p>



<p>Not for reporting or attribution, but just for your knowledge, on today&#8217;s call we have joining us [senior administration official].&nbsp; And with that, I&#8217;m going to pass it off to our speaker.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; I thought I&#8217;d just give you an update on what we observed over the last couple of days and heading into the last day tomorrow, after which we’ll release the communiqué.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what is really striking to me is the amount of convergence we&#8217;ve seen, both &#8212; that&#8217;s true both in terms of the direction of convergence and also the speed with which it&#8217;s happening.</p>



<p>Now, I had a chance to look back, and, three years ago, if you look back to the communiqué in 2018, China wasn&#8217;t even explicitly mentioned, even though you could find whole paragraphs devoted to countries like North Korea, Russia.&nbsp; Back then, they couldn&#8217;t reach consensus on anything as it related to China.</p>



<p>And, you know, this year, what is &#8212; what is striking is the very strong and shared foundation for a joint approach.&nbsp; And I don’t want to get ahead of specifics in the communiqué, but I can give you at least some of the areas of convergence, because I think they&#8217;re all profound and really important to highlight.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I’ll give you a few examples: First, working together to respond to China&#8217;s non-market economic practices that are harmful and distorted to the global economy.&nbsp; Being willing to speak out on human rights abuses, including in Xinjiang.&nbsp; And more than just speaking out, taking action, responding to forced labor in supply chains, again, including from Xinjiang.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, this is something we talked about yesterday &#8212; some of us at least &#8212; (inaudible) infrastructure initiative that is high standards, values-driven, transparent, and multilateral.&nbsp; And, you know, today, in fact, there was quite a bit of discussion about coordination on supply chain resilience and coming up with technology standards that are suited for the 21st century so that, as democracies, we’re aligned and we&#8217;re supporting each other.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, you know, I could go on, actually.&nbsp; But if that&#8217;s not a common approach, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t know what is.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just a huge move forward in three years, and, you know, I&#8217;m quite encouraged by what we heard.<br>&nbsp;<br>So let me just stop there and see if there are questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; So, now, everyone, if you&#8217;ve got a question, please use the “raise hand” function on the Zoom interface, and we&#8217;ll try to take some questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let&#8217;s start with Anne Gearan from The Washington Post.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much for doing this.&nbsp; This is, kind of, logistics, but can you let us know when you think we will see the communiqué and in what form?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Anne.&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I can at least give you a ballpark sense.&nbsp; So there are a couple of sessions planned for tomorrow for the leaders in the communiqué, but (inaudible).&nbsp; So I would say sometime around (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, you broke up.&nbsp; Sometime around what time?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; (Inaudible) digital technology is a little bit choppy.&nbsp; I said sometime around midday would be my expectation.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We’re actually probably going to be on a bus or a plane.&nbsp; So we’re, like &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; and (inaudible) it looks like there’s going to be news in it, so we’re trying to figure out how best to do that.&nbsp; And, you know, anything you guys can do to make sure that we have it in real time would be a huge help.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well taken.&nbsp; And will do.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Next we will go to Josh Wingrove at Bloomberg.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; This morning there was a dis- &#8212; or the indications were, earlier today, that there was sort of a discussion between some people who wanted China more explicitly named, including President Biden, and others who were less keen on that, including Chancellor Merkel.&nbsp;Can you give me an update on that? &nbsp;And can you specify: Is &#8212; is the word &#8220;China&#8221; going to be in the communiqué? &nbsp;Because that, too, was uncertain as of a day ago. &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I would say there was unanimity in terms of a willingness to call out human rights abuses and violations of fundamental freedoms that invoke our shared values.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, so this was &#8212; there has been, yesterday, and there certainly was today, a tremendous (inaudible) this together, and what forges the G7 partnership.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s very much about our shared (inaudible).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, there was a willingness to speak out &#8212; not just a willingness; I think there was unanimity in terms of our (inaudible) to speak out and (inaudible) and to be specific (inaudible), and (inaudible) and with a commitment to take action in response to what we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; And, you know, again, that was &#8212; that was a &#8212; that&#8217;s a dramatic change from where we were only three years ago.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sorry &#8212; we&#8217;re perhaps near our Zoom &#8212; the end of our Zoom era, but you did cut out a few times there.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m sorry, Josh.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know &#8212; I don&#8217;t know when I cut out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perhaps I would just suggest: If there was a point you felt particularly strongly about, if it came in the middle, we might not have heard it in full.&nbsp; So, if you wanted to sum up &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay, I&#8217;ll just summarize.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, Josh, is this better now?&nbsp; Can you hear me?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes, sir.&nbsp; I can.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll give it another shot.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, what I was saying was that, again, I heard from everyone that what binds us together as a G7 partnership, more than anything else, are the shared values of democracies.&nbsp; And that, because of that partnership, you know, it&#8217;s our obligation to call out human rights abuses and other &#8212; other violations of fundamental freedoms that calls us into &#8212; that really invoke our shared values.<br>&nbsp;<br>And more than just &#8212; more than just calling out those abuses, which are &#8212; that&#8217;s important &#8212; there was a (inaudible) to take action.&nbsp; And (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s go to Steve Holland with Reuters.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just to be specific about what&#8217;s going to be in the communiqué: You&#8217;re saying it&#8217;s going to cite &#8212; it&#8217;s going to criticize China&#8217;s non-market policies and China&#8217;s human rights treatment in Xinjiang.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don’t want to get ahead of what &#8212; I can&#8217;t get ahead of what&#8217;s in the communiqué because it hasn&#8217;t (inaudible) and leaders have to sign off.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m just trying to reflect the conversation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, I think you mentioned the word &#8220;criticize.&#8221;&nbsp; And certainly there&#8217;s a strong convergence in terms of a willingness to call out human rights abuses.&nbsp; But I would say, with respect to non-market economic practices, my reference there was to work together collaboratively within the G7 to find ways to confront those practices and to offer a better choice and affirmative path.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there was a lot of discussion about what that could mean in terms of (inaudible); in terms of cooperation on technology standards; in terms of things we can work together to bolster our supply chain resilience, ways we could come (inaudible) &#8212; ways we could come (inaudible) to provide support to low-income countries with the resources (inaudible) and through the (inaudible) that we&#8217;ve built.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s a long list of items that were discussed, (inaudible) a positive agenda, while also being clear about what we don&#8217;t tolerate.&nbsp; And all of those actions and that agenda, again, flow from shared values that everyone &#8212; everyone &#8212; held up as the reason (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s go to Franco Ordoñez with NPR.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I wanted to just kind of follow up on that.&nbsp; It sounds like, from the conversations, the &#8212; that the leaders are ready to be more specific about addressing these human rights (inaudible).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But you also mentioned being committed to taking action.&nbsp; I wanted to ask: Will that be &#8212; do you anticipate that will be outlined in the communiqué, not only calling out the human rights, but outlining some of the steps to take action?&nbsp; And if it doesn&#8217;t outline some of those steps, do you feel like that would be falling short in any way?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t, again, (inaudible) communiqué, but (inaudible) communiqué (inaudible) &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; You&#8217;re coming out a little garbled.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; There&#8217;s a commitment here about how our (inaudible) in terms of our actions, and that&#8217;s both being (inaudible) and also what we&#8217;re for.&nbsp; So you’ll see strong elements of both tomorrow.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t get into specifics again, Franco, just because, you know, the doc is not final.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you want to go back &#8212; you already have heard about (inaudible) important (inaudible) actions we’ve taken together.&nbsp; The pandemic response means our contributions &#8212; the unprecedented amount that the G7 has agreed to provide without conditions, without any strings attached, both for this (inaudible).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And (inaudible) to deal with (inaudible).&nbsp; Because that’s the spirit in which the discussion have taken place (inaudible) &#8212; why our model is still the single best way to deliver for our people, but also to meet the biggest challenges and (inaudible), supply chain resilience, (inaudible) competition.&nbsp; And, yes, (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Much of that answer was very unclear and garbled.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if you want to try again, but that came across as about 80 percent choppy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, boy.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, Franco, can you hear me any better?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes, that was a little clearer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay, well, I mean, I started off by saying I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any specifics in the communiqué.&nbsp; You are going to see a very clear commitment on a number of fronts in which &#8212; (phone line drops).<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Our speaker just dropped.&nbsp; Give us one second while we try to get him back on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>[Senior administration official], are you there?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey, it&#8217;s [senior administration official].&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hey there.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; I know [senior administration official] is experiencing some tech issues.&nbsp; So why don&#8217;t I just close this out with a little bit of &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s perfect.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; &#8212; again, sort of &#8212; yeah.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll close it out with an overview of how we&#8217;re seeing today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as [senior administration official] said at the top of the call, I mean, the &#8212; not just today, but the G7 writ large, we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve seen and felt and been encouraged by a growing convergence.&nbsp; And you look at where the G7 was three years ago &#8212; with China not even explicitly mentioned, though entire paragraphs were devoted to North Korea and Russia &#8212; I think it just underlines that the &#8212; where the G7 has come from there, and the fact that we have a strong, common foundation on our approach to issues that matter.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, as [senior administration official] said, in terms of where we are right now, we&#8217;ve reached consensus on a number of points that are reflective of that shared approach.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re working together to respond to non-market economic practices that are objectionable in a global economy; speaking out on human rights abuses; responding to forced labor in supply chains; pursuing an affirmative infrastructure initiative that&#8217;s high standards and transparent; and coordinating on supply chain resilience and technology standards so that democracies are aligned and supporting each other.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, you know, as we close out the day, that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re seeing and that&#8217;s where we are.&nbsp; I appreciate folks bearing through some of the audio difficulties.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be back with one of these very soon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much for joining us again, everyone.&nbsp; Again, this call is on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and embargoed until the call concludes, which will be momentarily.&nbsp; Thank you so much again.</p>



<p>7:15 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with President Emmanuel Macron of France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-emmanuel-macron-of-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Emmanuel Macron on the margins of the G7 Summit. The two leaders reaffirmed their commitment to deepening our bilateral ties and to the Transatlantic alliance. They highlighted their dedication to ending the pandemic, including through participation in the G7 commitment to donate COVID-19 vaccines to countries&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Emmanuel Macron on the margins of the G7 Summit. The two leaders reaffirmed their commitment to deepening our bilateral ties and to the Transatlantic alliance. They highlighted their dedication to ending the pandemic, including through participation in the G7 commitment to donate COVID-19 vaccines to countries in need, and to build back better global health security for the future. They reaffirmed their commitment to reform the international tax system to address some of the inequities created by globalization. President Biden expressed his appreciation for France’s leadership on climate issues through the Paris Agreement, and both leaders underscored their dedication to achieve ambitious outcomes at the COP26 Summit in Glasgow in November. President Biden and President Macron discussed our work to strengthen and modernize NATO, and our close cooperation on counter terrorism cooperation, including in the Sahel, and other shared foreign policy priorities such as China and Russia.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and President Macron of the French Republic Before Bilateral Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-macron-of-the-french-republic-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carbis Bay Hotel &#38; EstateSaint Ives, United Kingdom 3:01 P.M. BST Q    How are you, sir? PRESIDENT MACRON:  How are you?   PRESIDENT BIDEN:  I&#8217;m well.  The sun is shining.  We&#8217;re almost on the beach.  I&#8217;m well.  And I&#8217;m with the President of France; that makes me even feel better.  (Laughs.) AIDE:  We&#8217;re on. PRESIDENT BIDEN:  We&#8217;re on.  Okay.  We&#8217;re on. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Carbis Bay Hotel &amp; Estate<br>Saint Ives, United Kingdom</p>



<p>3:01 P.M. BST<br> <br>Q    How are you, sir?<br> <br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  How are you?  <br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  I&#8217;m well.  The sun is shining.  We&#8217;re almost on the beach.  I&#8217;m well.  And I&#8217;m with the President of France; that makes me even feel better.  (Laughs.)<br> <br>AIDE:  We&#8217;re on.<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  We&#8217;re on.  Okay.  We&#8217;re on.  Did you know that?  (Laughter.)  Well, we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re just having a &#8212; we&#8217;ve had a good couple days so far.  I&#8217;ve had a chance to spend some time with President Macron, get to know him.  And we &#8212; we have some things we&#8217;ve got to talk about a little bit later, but things are going, I think, well.  And we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re, as we say in &#8212; back in the States, &#8220;We&#8217;re on the same page.&#8221;  So, thank you.<br> <br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  Yeah.  Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.  We had a &#8212; I want to thank you for our discussion yesterday and the working sessions we had, indeed. <br> <br>We have to &#8212; to deal with this pandemic and the COVID-19.  We have to face a lot of challenges, a lot of crisis &#8212; climate change.  And for all these issues, what we need is cooperation.  And I think it&#8217;s great to have the U.S. President part of the club and very willing to cooperate.  And I think that what you &#8212; what you demonstrate is that leadership is partnership. And &#8212; and we do appreciate it, and I think we can deliver great things for that.<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  I think we can do a lot, too.  We &#8212; the United States, I&#8217;ve said before &#8212; we&#8217;re back.  The U.S. is back.  We feel very, very strongly about the cohesion of NATO. <br> <br>And I, for one, think that the European Union is an incredibly strong and vibrant entity that has a lot to do with the ability of Western Europe to not only handle its economic issues, but provide the backbone and the support for NATO. <br> <br>And so I &#8212; we&#8217;re very supportive &#8212; very supportive.<br> <br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  Thank you. <br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Thank you. <br> <br>Q Mr. President, have you convinced allies that America is back?<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Ask him.<br> <br>Q    Is America back?<br> <br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  Yeah.  Definitely.<br> <br>Q    Do you believe America is back?<br> <br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  Definitely.<br> <br>3:03 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Roundtable with LGBTQ+ and Gun Violence Prevention Leaders on the Fifth Anniversary of the Pulse Nightclub Mass Shooting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-lgbtq-and-gun-violence-prevention-leaders-on-the-fifth-anniversary-of-the-pulse-nightclub-mass-shooting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and White House Public Engagement Director and Senior Advisor Cedric Richmond hosted a virtual roundtable with LGBTQ+ leaders and&#160;gun violence survivors and advocates to recognize the fifth anniversary of the mass shooting at the Pulse Nightclub in Orlando, Florida. Together, they observed a moment of silence to honor&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and White House Public Engagement Director and Senior Advisor Cedric Richmond hosted a virtual roundtable with LGBTQ+ leaders and&nbsp;gun violence survivors and advocates to recognize the fifth anniversary of the mass shooting at the Pulse Nightclub in Orlando, Florida. Together, they observed a moment of silence to honor the 49 individuals who lost their lives in the Pulse tragedy and the traumatic impact that the mass shooting had on LGBTQ+ and Latino communities across the country.</p>



<p>During the meeting, three courageous LGBTQ+ gun violence survivors discussed the impact that gun violence has had on their lives. Participants shared their perspectives on the ongoing public health crisis of gun violence in America and the burden that this crisis has on LGBTQ+ communities across our nation. They discussed the epidemic levels of violence faced by transgender people, especially transgender women of color, and the impact of firearms in the crisis of anti-transgender homicides. Participants also discussed the intersection of gun safety and the movement to prevent and end suicide among LGBTQ+ youth.</p>



<p>Ambassador Rice and Congressman Richmond expressed gratitude for the participants’ courageous leadership in addressing acts of anti-LGBTQ+ violence, and for their persistent advocacy to tackle the gun violence epidemic. They reiterated President Biden’s commitment to advancing full equality for every LGBTQ+ person and family, including his urging for the Senate to pass the Equality Act to ensure that LGBTQ+ Americans can live free of discrimination and without fear of who they are or whom they love. Finally, they underscored President Biden’s deep commitment to ending the gun violence public health epidemic in America and reiterated his call for the Senate to pass bipartisan legislation to reduce gun violence that has already passed the House.</p>



<p>Participants in yesterday’s roundtable included:</p>



<ul><li>Jason Lindsay, Pride Fund to End Gun Violence</li><li>Elle Moxley, The Marsha P. Johnson Institute</li><li>Destini Philpot, Students Demand Action Baltimore &amp; Good Kids Mad City Baltimore</li><li>Casey Pick, The Trevor Project</li><li>Andrea Pino-Silva, Community Justice Action Fund</li><li>Bamby Salcedo, The TransLatin@ Coalition</li><li>Nadine Smith, Equality Florida</li><li>Beverly Tillery, New York City Anti-Violence Project</li><li>Brandon Wolf, Survivor of the Pulse Nightclub Mass Shooting, and Advocate for LGBTQ+ Equality and Gun Violence Prevention</li><li>Christopher Zoeller, March for Our Lives Florida</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the 5th Anniversary of the Pulse Nightclub Shooting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-5th-anniversary-of-the-pulse-nightclub-shooting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 15:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Five years ago today in Orlando in the middle of Pride Month, our nation suffered the deadliest attack affecting the LGBTQ+ community in American history, and at the time, the deadliest mass shooting by a single gunman. Within minutes, the Pulse nightclub that had long been a place of acceptance and joy turned into a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Five years ago today in Orlando in the middle of Pride Month, our nation suffered the deadliest attack affecting the LGBTQ+ community in American history, and at the time, the deadliest mass shooting by a single gunman.</p>



<p>Within minutes, the Pulse nightclub that had long been a place of acceptance and joy turned into a place of unspeakable pain and loss. Forty-nine people were there celebrating Latin night were murdered, even more injured, and countless others scarred forever – the victims were family members, partners and friends, veterans and students, young, Black, Asian and Latino – our fellow Americans.</p>



<p>A few days later, I traveled with President Obama to pay respects to them and their families, to thank the brave first responders and the community who found strength and compassion in each other, and to pledge that what happened would not be forgotten.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the years, I have stayed in touch with families of the victims and with the survivors who have turned their pain into purpose, and who remind us that we must do more than remember victims of gun violence and all of the survivors, family members, and friends left behind; we must act.</p>



<p>In the coming days, I will sign a bill designating Pulse Nightclub as a national memorial, enshrining in law what has been true since that terrible day five years ago: Pulse Nightclub is hallowed ground.</p>



<p>But there is more we must do to address the public health epidemic of gun violence in all of its forms – mass shootings and daily acts of gun violence that don’t make national headlines.</p>



<p>It is long past time we close the loopholes that allow gun buyers to bypass background checks in this country, and the Senate should start by passing the three House-passed bills which would do exactly that. It is long past time we ban assault weapons and high capacity magazines, establish extreme risk protection orders, also known as “red flag” laws, and eliminate gun manufacturers’ immunity from liability.</p>



<p>We must also acknowledge gun violence’s particular impact on LGBTQ+ communities across our nation. We must drive out hate and inequities that contribute to the epidemic of violence and murder against transgender women – especially transgender women of color. We must create a world in which our LGBTQ+ young people are loved, accepted, and feel safe in living their truth.&nbsp;And the Senate must swiftly pass the Equality Act, legislation that will ensure LGBTQ+ Americans finally have equal protection under law.</p>



<p>In the memory of all of those lost at the Pulse nightclub five years ago, let us continue the work to be a nation at our best – one that recognizes and protects the dignity and safety of every American.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: G7 to Announce Joint Actions to End Public Support for Overseas Unabated Coal Generation by End of 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/fact-sheet-g7-to-announce-joint-actions-to-end-public-support-for-overseas-unabated-coal-generation-by-end-of-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is rallying the world’s democracies to deliver for our people, meet the world’s biggest challenges, and demonstrate our shared values Today, President Biden and fellow G7 Leaders agreed to a set of concrete actions to accelerate the global transition away from coal generation as part of our efforts to combat the climate&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The United States is rallying the world’s democracies to deliver for our people, meet the world’s biggest challenges, and demonstrate our shared values</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden and fellow G7 Leaders agreed to a set of concrete actions to accelerate the global transition away from coal generation as part of our efforts to combat the climate crisis. <br><br><strong><em>Accelerating Decarbonization and Transition from Unabated Coal: </em></strong>Confronting the climate crisis presents a historic opportunity to drive our economic recovery, create millions of good-paying union jobs, and build back better as we invest in a more resilient, prosperous, equitable, and secure future. Recognizing that unabated coal power generation is the single biggest source of greenhouse gas emissions globally, and consistent with President Biden’s domestic leadership, G7 Leaders will commit to an end to new direct government support for unabated international thermal coal power generation by the end of this year. To support key developing countries in their transitions away from unabated coal, Canada, Germany, the UK, and the United States will also include a new collective commitment to provide up to $2 billion to support the work of the Climate Investments Funds focused on accelerating the transition from coal for key developing countries while investing in technology, job training, and infrastructure to enable the transition to a more reliable and prosperous clean energy economy.<br><br>Hard-to-abate heavy industrial sectors like cement and steel will play a key role in this transition. Therefore, Leaders are launching the G7 Industrial Decarbonization Agenda, a first-of-its-kind platform to accelerate innovation, deploy decarbonization technology, and harmonize standards. The Leaders also will emphasize sectoral decarbonization in power, transport, agriculture, and buildings.<br><br><strong><em>Aligning to Confront the Climate Crisis:</em></strong> Additionally, for the first time in history, all G7 Leaders will align their long-term and short-term climate goals in a manner consistent with keeping the 1.5 degrees Celsius global warming threshold within reach. Leaders will also resolve to strengthen adaptation and resilience to protect people from the impacts of climate change and to halt and reverse biodiversity loss, as well as to mobilize finance and leverage innovation to reach these goals.<br><br>To fully address the climate crisis, we also must recognize and focus on the role of conservation. This is why the United States supports the G7 goal of conserving or protecting at least 30 percent of global land and marine areas by 2030 – a commitment grounded in scientific evidence that has shown increasing conservation is critical for maintaining the health and productivity of our ecosystems for generations to come.<br><br>Domestically, President Biden is advancing policies that will achieve carbon-pollution free energy in electricity generation by 2035. These policies will support scale up of technology that captures carbon and then permanently sequesters or utilizes that captured carbon, which includes lowering the cost of carbon capture retrofits for existing power plants — all while ensuring that overburdened communities are protected from increases in cumulative pollution.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
