<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 14:10:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Maritime Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/20/a-proclamation-on-national-maritime-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 14:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53662</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From sea to shining sea, whether in still or raging waters, America has always been a Nation of maritime travel.  Across our 25,000 miles of waterways and over 360 commercial ports, the United States Merchant Marine is integral to our Nation&#8217;s prosperity.  From helping move goods throughout the supply chain to supporting our troops wherever they are&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>From sea to shining sea, whether in still or raging waters, America has always been a Nation of maritime travel.  Across our 25,000 miles of waterways and over 360 commercial ports, the United States Merchant Marine is integral to our Nation&#8217;s prosperity.  From helping move goods throughout the supply chain to supporting our troops wherever they are deployed, the Merchant Marine plays a vital role in the economic security and defense of our country.  On National Maritime Day and every day, we honor the Merchant Marines for their service and sacrifice and acknowledge their crucial role in protecting our Nation&#8217;s security and commerce.</p>



<p>Today, our Merchant Marine remains inextricably linked to our national and economic security and competitiveness.  Merchant mariners&#8217; legacy of perseverance and dedication is carried on by today&#8217;s civilian mariners.  As tyranny and violence again cause the tragic loss of innocent lives and senseless destruction in Europe, our merchant mariners have answered the call of duty by crewing vessels of our United States Ready Reserve, moving vital military cargo to help the Ukrainian people in their defense of freedom.</p>



<p>We also salute the remarkable efforts of our entire maritime industry throughout the COVID-19 pandemic.  They put the well-being of the American people first, risking their lives to ensure that essential cargoes of medical supplies and personal protective equipment were delivered to those in need across our Nation.</p>



<p>As we continue to build a better America, our Merchant Marine plays a pivotal role in securing our coastal and inland waterways so that they are open to trade.  No matter the hardship, mariners provide a smooth passage for America&#8217;s critical domestic goods and serve as stewards of our Nation&#8217;s trading gateways with the rest of the world.  My Administration continues its unwavering support of the United States Merchant Marine, as well as the Jones Act, which protects the integrity of our domestic maritime industry, supports hundreds of thousands of jobs, and contributes over $150 billion in economic benefits.</p>



<p>We also know that the future success of the vital maritime industry depends on its ability to attract the talent of all Americans and reflect the diversity of the Nation it serves.  That is why we are resolved to continue the urgent work of advancing diversity, equity, and inclusion in the ranks of the Merchant Marine and to end sexual assault, sexual harassment, and bullying in the workplace.</p>



<p>Our Nation&#8217;s merchant mariners serve with honor and integrity each and every day.  Today, we recognize their service and sacrifice and recommit ourselves to fulfilling the promises and uplifting the values that they continue to protect.</p>



<p>The Congress, by a joint resolution approved May 20, 1933, has designated May 22 of each year as &#8220;National Maritime Day&#8221; to commemorate the first transoceanic voyage by a steamship in 1819 by the S.S. Savannah.&nbsp; By this resolution, the Congress has authorized and requested the President to issue annually a proclamation calling for its appropriate observance. &nbsp;I also request that all ships sailing under the American flag dress ship on that day.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 22, 2022, as National Maritime Day.  I call upon all Americans to observe this day and to celebrate the United States Merchant Marine and maritime industry with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twentieth day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Armed Forces Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/20/a-proclamation-on-armed-forces-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Armed Forces Day, we share our unending appreciation for the proud patriots who answer the call to serve, taking the sacred oath to defend our Constitution. &#160;The brave members of our Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, Coast Guard, and National Guard and Reserve forces represent the best of our Nation.&#160; Today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Armed Forces Day, we share our unending appreciation for the proud patriots who answer the call to serve, taking the sacred oath to defend our Constitution. &nbsp;The brave members of our Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, Coast Guard, and National Guard and Reserve forces represent the best of our Nation.&nbsp; Today and every day, we honor their immeasurable service on behalf of our grateful Nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>On this special day of tribute, we recognize the sacrifices that our service members and their families make on our behalf, and we recommit to our solemn duty to support them as they protect us.&nbsp; Our Nation has a sacred obligation to properly equip and prepare our troops when we send them in to harm&#8217;s way and to support them &#8212; both while they are serving abroad and when they return home &#8212; as well as their families, caregivers, and survivors.&nbsp; We must meet this obligation.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>My Administration&#8217;s unity agenda focuses on key issues that bring Americans together: &nbsp;supporting our veterans, beating the opioid epidemic, addressing our national mental health crisis, and ending cancer as we know it. &nbsp;Each of these issues impact our military community, and each is essential to meeting our obligation to our troops, their families, caregivers, and survivors.&nbsp; Mental health issues pose a real challenge to our service members and their families, and my Administration will continue to strengthen the tools, resources, and support for our military community so our brave service members, who have answered the call to serve, can thrive.&nbsp; This includes taking bold action to reduce suicide among service members, veterans, and their families.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>The success of our Armed Forces also rests on every member of our military community feeling that their safety and ability to prosper is prioritized as they defend our Nation.&nbsp; That is why my Administration is so focused on addressing the potential adverse consequences related to toxic exposures or exposures to other environmental hazards during deployment or in garrison. &nbsp;</p>



<p><br>Safety for our troops also means addressing the scourge of sexual harassment and sexual assault in our military. &nbsp;We have already taken important steps. &nbsp;In December, I was proud to sign into law historic military justice reforms as part of the 2022 National Defense Authorization Act. &nbsp;The Department of Defense is working to implement these critical changes, alongside recommendations from the Independent Review Commission on Sexual Assault in the Military for prevention, climate and culture, and victim care and support. &nbsp;Much work still lies ahead to deliver the progress that our troops deserve, and this will remain a top priority for my Administration. &nbsp;</p>



<p><br>Our diversity is one of our greatest strengths as a Nation, and we will continue to strive for our Armed Forces to reflect society at every level within its ranks. &nbsp;Ensuring equal opportunity and greater inclusivity will bolster the strength of our military and make sure every American knows they can succeed and thrive as a member of the United States Armed Forces.&nbsp; We&nbsp;are renewing our efforts to address the recruitment, retention, and well-being of women in the military as well as providing a path to service for other under-represented groups.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>As we look around the world today, we are reminded again that freedom comes at great cost.&nbsp; Throughout our history, brave Americans have always stepped forward to defend our liberties &#8212; willing to pay the price to keep our country safe. &nbsp;Our Nation&#8217;s Armed Forces are the best in the world.&nbsp; And we know that it is not only the person who wears our Nation&#8217;s uniform that serves. Their loved ones serve as well.&nbsp; Today, we also honor the families, caregivers, and survivors of our Armed Forces &#8212; all those who sacrifice on our behalf and who give their all to support the service members they stand behind.</p>



<p>On Armed Forces Day, we salute our brave service members, whose dedication and sacrifice ensure that our Nation&#8217;s Armed Forces are unmatched in strength, unity, and resilience.&nbsp; They&nbsp;are the greatest fighting force the world has ever known.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, and Commander in Chief of the Armed Forces of the United States, continuing the precedent of my predecessors in office, do hereby proclaim the third Saturday of each May as Armed Forces Day.</p>



<p><br>I direct the Secretary of Defense, on behalf of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, and the Secretary of Homeland Security on behalf of the Coast Guard, to plan for appropriate observances each year, with the Secretary of Defense responsible for soliciting the participation and cooperation of civil authorities and private citizens.&nbsp; I invite the Governors of the States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and other areas subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to provide for the observance of Armed Forces Day within their respective jurisdictions each year in an appropriate manner designed to increase public understanding and appreciation of the Armed Forces of the United States.&nbsp; I also invite veterans, civic leaders, and other organizations to join in the observance of Armed Forces Day each year.</p>



<p><br>Finally, I call upon all Americans to display the flag of the United States at their homes and businesses on Armed Forces Day, and I urge citizens to learn more about military service by attending and participating in the local observances of the day.</p>



<p><br>Proclamation 10210 of May 14, 2021, is hereby superseded.</p>



<p><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twentieth day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Safe Boating Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/20/a-proclamation-on-national-safe-boating-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 13:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Exploring America&#8217;s magnificent lakes, rivers, ponds, bays, and oceans has long been a favorite pastime for recreational boaters and a memorable way to discover our Nation&#8217;s natural treasures.&#160; As we prepare for warmer weather, and as more Americans take to the water, National Safe Boating Week reminds us of the importance of following responsible and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Exploring America&#8217;s magnificent lakes, rivers, ponds, bays, and oceans has long been a favorite pastime for recreational boaters and a memorable way to discover our Nation&#8217;s natural treasures.&nbsp; As we prepare for warmer weather, and as more Americans take to the water, National Safe Boating Week reminds us of the importance of following responsible and safe boating practices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So many Americans enjoy recreational boating, and most trips are safe.  But many preventable accidents occur each year that result in tragic deaths and injuries.  Observing boating safety precautions is essential for all boaters, whether you are fishing, sailing, kayaking, or motoring.</p>



<p>Safe boating practices start well before the hull breaks the water&#8217;s surface.  Experts agree that taking a State-offered boating safety course is one of the best ways to minimize accidents.  Most boating fatalities involve boats whose operators &#8212; including paddlers in rentals &#8212; did not have proper boating safety education.  I urge all Americans to use the free assistance of the Coast Guard Auxiliary and America&#8217;s Boating Club to ensure that your vessels are safe and that operators have the tools they need to operate them safely.</p>



<p>I also call upon Americans to follow basic boating safety procedures and to always wear a life jacket to protect yourself and your loved ones.  In 2020, three-quarters of boating deaths were drownings, and nearly 7 out of every 8 drowning victims were not wearing a life jacket.  In addition, avoid using alcohol or drugs when operating a boat.  Alcohol continues to be a significant contributing factor in boating deaths, and its effects are compounded by water movement, exposure to the elements, and dynamic operating conditions.  Finally, wearing an engine cut-off switch link will stop the boat&#8217;s engine in the event the operator falls overboard, protecting everyone from vessel and propeller strikes.  By adhering to safe boating practices, Americans will be safer on the water while enjoying the boating season. </p>



<p>This week, we also pay tribute to the United States Coast Guard and the Federal, State, Tribal, and local partners who help save lives and protect us from accidents on the water.  This season, let us recommit to following basic boating safety procedures to prevent boating fatalities, avoid property damage, and help boaters stay safe as they enjoy the beauty of the open water. </p>



<p>In recognition of the importance of safe boating practices, the Congress, by joint resolution approved on June 4, 1958 (36 U.S.C. 131), as amended, has authorized and requested the President to proclaim annually the 7-day period before Memorial Day weekend as &#8220;National Safe Boating Week.&#8221;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, do hereby proclaim May 21 through May 27, 2022, as National Safe Boating Week.  I encourage all Americans who participate in boating activities to observe this occasion by learning more about safe boating practices, and by taking advantage of boating safety education opportunities.  I also encourage the Governors of the States and Territories, and appropriate officials of all units of government, to join me in encouraging boating safety in every community.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twentieth day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden After Touring Samsung Electronics Pyeongtaek&#160;Campus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/20/remarks-by-president-biden-after-touring-samsung-electronics-pyeongtaek-campus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 13:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53652</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Samsung Electronics Pyeongtaek CampusPyeongtaek, Republic of Korea 7:47 P.M. KST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Mr. President, thank you.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you.&#160; You’re very generous.&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; Mr. President, thank you for that introduction.&#160; It’s wonderful to be back in the Republic of Korea. President Yoon, I’m honor- &#8212; I’m honored by the welcome you’ve given&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Samsung Electronics Pyeongtaek Campus<br>Pyeongtaek, Republic of Korea</p>



<p><br>7:47 P.M. KST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You’re very generous.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you for that introduction.&nbsp; It’s wonderful to be back in the Republic of Korea.</p>



<p>President Yoon, I’m honor- &#8212; I’m honored by the welcome you’ve given me to your beautiful country, and congratulations again on your election &#8212; congratulations &#8212; and recent inauguration.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I and my country look forward to a very productive few days together where we can get to know one another better and explore ways to take the alliance between the Republic of Korea and the United States to an even greater heights than it already exists.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Vice Chairman Lee, thank you for welcoming us to this Samsung semiconductor facility.&nbsp; This is an auspicious start for my visit because it’s emblematic of the future of cooperation and innovation that our nations can and must build together.</p>



<p>I’m joined by my Secretary of Commerce &#8212; Secretary Raimondo is here in the front row &#8212; who is working every day to bring us closer to that goal.</p>



<p>I’ve just seen how this plant makes the most advanced semiconductor chips in the world.&nbsp; They’re a wonder of innovation and design, precision and manufacturing.</p>



<p>Semiconductors power our economies and enable our modern lives, from our automobiles to our smartphones to medical diagnostic equipment.</p>



<p>And when it comes to the most advanced chips, like the ones made here at Samsung &#8212; it&#8217;s only one of only three companies in the world that makes these chips.&nbsp; It’s an incredible &#8212; an incredible achievement.</p>



<p>Because these little chips, only a few nanometers thick, are the key to propelling us into the next era of humanity’s technological development: artificial intelligence, quantum technologies, 5G, and so very much more &#8212; things we haven’t even thought of at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This plant also reflects the close bonds in innovation between our countries.&nbsp; Much of the technology and machinery that is used to make these chips was designed and produced in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And by uniting our skills and our technological know-how, it allows the production of chips that are critical to both our countries and are essential &#8212; essential &#8212; sectors of our global economy.</p>



<p>And thanks for the incredible $17 billion investment that Samsung announced last May, soon to the United States &#8212; to have a facility like this one that manufactures the most advanced chips in the world in <s>Tylor</s> [Taylor], Texas.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>This investment will create 3,000 new high-tech jobs in Texas and add &#8212; to add to 20,000 jobs Samsung already supports in the United States of America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I want to thank Samsung for their investment and for continuing to expand the very productive partnership between the Republic of Korea and the United States.</p>



<p>And I &#8212; I know that Samsung will also be working with Stellantis on a joint venture to build a new facility in the United States that will manufacture batteries for electric vehicles.</p>



<p>Inve- &#8212; Investments like these are going to help catapult us forward toward a clean energy future, which we both badly need, advancing our shared economic growth, our energy security, and our climate goals.</p>



<p>I also want to make clear that these are smart business decisions.&nbsp; Samsung investment of &#8212; didn’t invest $17 billion without, as we say in America, running the numbers.</p>



<p>The United States is a top destination for foreign direct investment, like the one Samsung is making, because we have world-class, highly skilled, and highly committed workers.</p>



<p>I urge Samsung and Stellantis and any company investing in the United States to enter into partnerships with our most highly skilled and dedicated and engaged workers you can find anywhere in the world: American union members.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Stellantis knows how much benefit comes from a successful relationship with a union in America.&nbsp; They have a national agreement with my friend Ray Curry and the United Auto Workers.</p>



<p>For every joint venture that manufactures electric vehicle batteries would be made stronger by collective bargaining relationships with America unions.</p>



<p>We also have outstanding, skilled, dedicated union building and construction trades workers ready to build the new Samsung facility in Texas.</p>



<p>So, let’s work together to make this happen and to get that plant built on time and on budget safely and efficiently.&nbsp; Because union labor means high-quality work that delivers the best possible return on investment.</p>



<p>The United States has premier colleges and universities; a culture that fosters innovation and entrepreneurship; a transparent and predictable legal system, where companies know their ideas and their investments will be protected.&nbsp; And my administration is doubling down on all of these strengths.</p>



<p>We’re investing more than $1 trillion to upgrade America’s infrastructure coast to coast over the next decade.</p>



<p>And hopefully soon, with the Bipartisan Innovation Act,</p>



<p>we will deliver historic federal investments in U.S. research and development, including funding for something called the CHIPS Act to revitalize the U.S. semiconductor industry.</p>



<p>Our two nations work together to make the best, most advanced technology in the world.&nbsp; And this factory is proof of that.</p>



<p>And that gives both the Republic of Korea and the United States a competitive edge in the global economy if &#8212; if &#8212; we can keep our supply chains resilient, reliable, and secure.</p>



<p>Over the last few years, we’ve seen just how critical it is.&nbsp; COVID-19 pandemic &#8212; the COVID-19 pandemic exposed the fragility of “just in time” supply chains.&nbsp; A global semiconductor shortage has caused a shortfall in consumer goods, especially automobiles, and it is contributing to higher prices around the world.</p>



<p>And now, Putin’s brutal and unprovoked war on Ukraine</p>



<p>has further spotlighted the need to secure our critical supply chains so that our economy &#8212; our economic and our national security are not dependent on countries that don&#8217;t share our values.</p>



<p>A critical component of how we&#8217;ll do that, in my view, is by working with close partners who do share our values, like the Republic of Korea, to secure more of what we need from our allies and partners and bolster our supply chain resilience.</p>



<p>That’s why our strategy is to build around strengthening our ties and our cooperation across the board.&nbsp; That’s how both our nations can improve our long-term resilience, increase our shared prosperity, and put our people in the best position to come out ahead in the competition for the 21st century.</p>



<p>And that’s why, Mr. President, I came to the Republic <s>in</s> [of] Korea on my first trip to Asia as President of the United States.  So much &#8212; so much of the future of the world is going to be written here in the Indo-Pacific over the next several decades.</p>



<p>We’re standing at an inflection point in history where the decisions we make today will have far-reaching impacts on the world we leave to our children tomorrow.</p>



<p>This vibrant democracy has become a powerhouse of global innovation by investing in educating its people.</p>



<p>And companies like Samsung that are driven by a responsible development of technology and innovation will be critical to shaping the future and the direction our two countries &#8212; the direction we both want to go.</p>



<p>So, this is the moment, in my view, to invest in one another, to deepen our business ties, to bring our people even closer together.</p>



<p>This is something President Yoon and I will be talking about on our visit later this &#8212; after this meeting and in the months ahead.&nbsp; Because the Alliance between the Republic of Korea and the United States of America is a linchpin of peace, stability, and prosperity for the region and the world that we seek.</p>



<p>So, thank you all very much and, President Moon [sic] &#8212; Yoon, thank you for everything you&#8217;ve done so far.  Appreciate it.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  </p>



<p>7:56 P.M. KST</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake&#160;Sullivan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/20/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 09:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Anchorage, Alaska (May 19, 2022) 3:35 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; All right.&#160; Hey, everybody.&#160; Hello, hello.&#160; Well, heading to Asia.&#160; Okay, I have Jake Sullivan, our National Security Advisor.&#160; He’s going to just take a few questions, and then we’ll let him go. MR. SULLIVAN:&#160; Sure. MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; All right.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Anchorage, Alaska</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(May 19, 2022)</p>



<p>3:35 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Hey, everybody.&nbsp; Hello, hello.&nbsp; Well, heading to Asia.&nbsp; Okay, I have Jake Sullivan, our National Security Advisor.&nbsp; He’s going to just take a few questions, and then we’ll let him go.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, do you guys want to jump in, or do you want me to give a little bit of a laydown on where we’re going the next couple days?&nbsp; I can do it either way.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk a little louder though, please.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; I was just saying: Happy to give a little laydown of where we’re going, what we’re doing the next couple days, or happy just to take your questions.&nbsp; Whatever you prefer.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can I try one?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How concerned are you about a possible nuclear missile or nuclear test by the North Koreans while &#8212; while we&#8217;re there?&nbsp; And what &#8212; what would it mean for the visit?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, we&#8217;ve been forthcoming in downgrading and releasing our intelligence and our analysis that there is a genuine possibility, a real risk of some kind of provocation while we&#8217;re in the region, whether in South Korea or in Japan.&nbsp; That could take the form of a nuclear test &#8212; the seventh nuclear test that North Korea has conducted.&nbsp; It could take the form of a missile test.<br><br>There have been a number of missile tests this year and, of course, North Korea has a long history &#8212; going back decades, at this point &#8212; of missile tests, both to advance their capabilities and to cause provocations.</p>



<p>We are prepared for those eventualities.  We are coordinated closely with both the ROK and Japan.  We know what we will do to respond to that.  We have communicated with not just our allies but also with China that this would cause the United States only to increase our fortitude, in terms of defending our allies, and cause adjustments to the way that our military is postured in the region.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, what &#8212; sorry, go ahead.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Just as far as the trip is concerned, I think all it would do what underscore &#8212; it would underscore one of the main messages we are sending on this trip, which is that the United States is here for our allies and partners, we are here to help provide deterrence and defense for the ROK and Japan, we will respond to any threats and any aggression decisively, and our cooperation with these two countries bilaterally and the U.S.-Japan-ROK cooperation trilaterally will only strengthen in the face of any further provocations by North Korea.<br><br>And if something does occur, it will only serve to reinforce and highlight the fact that the United States is going to be engaged in the Indo-Pacific, is going to be a stalwart ally, and is going to stand up to and not shrink from any acts of aggression.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say what the administration is doing to get North Korea to the table for any sort of talks right now?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made no bones about the fact that since the very beginning of this administration, we have reached out to North Korea to say that we are prepared to sit down and talk, without preconditions, to discuss a pathway forward to make progress toward the ultimate goal of the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.&nbsp; And we have proposed to do that on an action-for-action basis &#8212; that we are prepared to take steps if they are prepared to take steps in service to that ultimate goal.<br><br>We&#8217;ve communicated that directly to the North Koreans through multiple channels.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve communicated that to our &#8212; in coordination with our allies and partners.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve also spoken with the PRC about our willingness to do that.<br><br>Thus far, North Korea has not displayed any indication of willingness to engage in meaningful or constructive diplomacy.&nbsp; And as long as they continue to refuse to do so, we’ll continue to stay on the course we&#8217;re on, which is to impose pressure, to coordinate closely with our allies, and to respond to provocations with clarity and decisiveness.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have they indicated anything like a meeting between Kim Jong Un and President Biden as one of the things that they desire for this communication?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve not gotten any indication to that effect.</p>



<p>Q    I just want to go back to the historic stuff that was announced, in terms of NATO this morning.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:  What?<br><br>Q    The historic announcement with NATO this morning.<br><br>So, if Turkey decides that they&#8217;re going to block Finland and Sweden from joining NATO, do you think that an F-16 deal should go through?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t want to answer a hypothetical question, because our view is that we believe that the Turkish concerns about the accession of Sweden and Finland that have been expressed by President Erdoğan and others can be addressed and can be resolved.<br><br>And today, when the President met with President Niinistö and Prime Minister Andersson, the President of Finland and the Prime Minister of Sweden indicated that they&#8217;re both intending to speak directly to President Erdoğan and their teams are going to engage directly with senior Turkish officials.<br><br>We&#8217;re prepared to support that effort in any way, but we think they can work through, and that ultimately Finland and Sweden will be admitted as members of NATO.</p>



<p>Q    Have they been addressed yet, do you know?  Have any of the checklist items that Turkey wants &#8212; have they been addressed yet, to date?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:  Two NATO aspirants have had initial conversations with the Turks.  They will have further very high-level consultations with them over the course of the next days.  And they will work through this between them.<br><br>I don&#8217;t want to speak for the Finns and the Swedes.  This is something that, you know, they feel they want to do as part of their effort to bring Turkey to a place where they support their membership.  President Biden was very clear: We&#8217;re prepared to support that. </p>



<p>Also, I&#8217;ve spoken with my Turkish counterpart, Secretary Blinken has spoken with his Turkish counterpart, and we&#8217;ve indicated if there&#8217;s anything we can do to be supportive, we will do it.<br><br>But fundamentally, this is an issue about concerns that Turkey has raised vis-à-vis Finland and Sweden.&nbsp; This is not a U.S. issue, other than it being a U.S. issue in that we want to see it resolved in a way that brings these two members in the Alliance.&nbsp; And we’re confident that is going to happen.</p>



<p>So, I don’t think we’re going to get to the point where we have to think about the kinds of hypothetical &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the &#8212; about the security guarantees and what that means, that &#8212; in the interim of this accession, what does that mean?&nbsp; How do you guarantee Sweden and Finland’s security?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:  Well, we are going to work very closely with Finland and Sweden to deter any aggression against either of them.  And of course, we would be prepared to work with Finland and Sweden to respond to any aggression that occurred.  And that&#8217;s on the basis of the very deep existing partnership that we already have with these two countries.<br><br>Our militaries are interoperable.  We exercise together.  We train together.  And we would be prepared to work with the Turk- &#8212; with the Finns and Swedes and other NATO Allies to respond to any contingency. </p>



<p>But I’m not going to get into specifics of what that looks like.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll leave that to our respective militaries to work through.&nbsp; Just to say, on both the deterrence and the response side, the United States will be there for Finland and Sweden, if anything were to occur between now and the time that they are fully admitted as members of NATO and have the full Article 5 protection.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just clarify that point?&nbsp; Because, yesterday, you were still saying that Article &#8212; Article 5 does not kick in until they&#8217;re fully members.&nbsp; Can you &#8212;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And I just said, before you started asking your questions before I finished my statement, which is: This is in the period between now and when they are full members of NATO, where Article 5 applies.&nbsp; We are prepared to work with them to deter aggression and to respond.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that is different from the legally binding, in our view, security guarantee provided by Article 5.&nbsp; But as a practical matter, any would-be aggressor should be on notice that the United States will be there for Finland and Sweden in the event that they are attacked.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there any plans for the President to engage directly with President Erdoğan?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Not at the moment, but the President made clear that the United States is prepared to do whatever we&#8217;re asked to do to be supportive in resolving this issues.&nbsp; And if that were requested of him, he would, of course, be happy to do it.</p>



<p>Q    On a slightly different note, CNN reported today that Biden will be meeting with MBS soon.  Can you confirm that and give us any details?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:  I cannot confirm that.  No.<br><br>Q    Can I ask something about South Korea?  Will you &#8212; will the President be addressing the issue of the $7 billion of Iranian funds &#8212; the unfreezing of that funding during his trip in South Korea?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:  You know, on technical and expert levels, we discuss that issue with the South Koreans on a regular basis.  This is bound up in the sanctions imposed on Iran&#8217;s nuclear program.  I don&#8217;t know that it will be on the agenda of the two presidents.<br><br>Q    Can you just clarify the U.S. position on the freezing of those funds, though?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:  Our view is that the sanctions should be enforced, and that as long as Iran continues to advance its nuclear program, we should be working with our allies and partners to ensure that we are maintaining the form of economic pressure on them to sharpen the choice to get them to ultimately to agree to what is a perfectly fair and reasonable deal on the table for them in Vienna.<br><br>Q    Jake &#8212;<br><br>Q    On Ukraine aid.<br><br>Q    Sorry.<br><br>Q    Go ahead, Betsy.<br><br>Q    On Ukraine aid, presuming that the bill passes the Senate today, are there plans for the President to sign it while he&#8217;s abroad? <br><br>And he had said in a statement that there could be &#8212; the funding would run out as soon as today.  Is there any contingency for if there were a gap?  Are there any consequences in any &#8212; even a short gap in funding?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:  So, since we’ve been on the plane, I haven’t actually seen if the final vote has gone through.  Maybe you all have.  Has it &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  It has.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:  It’s passed?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  It’s passed, yeah.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:  So, the President does intend to sign the bill while he&#8217;s on the road so that he can sign it expeditiously.  The modalities of that are being worked right now so that he can get it and sign it.<br><br>There won&#8217;t be a gap for that very reason.  We, today, authorized the 10th Presidential Drawdown &#8212; the remaining $100 million &#8212; on May 19, just as we said we were going to do.<br><br>That money will be converted into capabilities.  Those capabilities will flow in the coming days.  And then the next Presidential Drawdown will be teed up shortly following his signature.  So, we will have the kind of continuity of support that we asked for.  And for that, we are grateful to the bipartisan backing that we&#8217;ve gotten from the Congress, who stepped up and did this in a timely fashion.<br><br>Q    On China &#8212; Jake, can you share your reaction to China saying that this is becoming a “dangerous situation” with the stance towards Taiwan?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:  I&#8217;m sorry?<br><br>Q    China was saying that they gave you a warning about how the situation with Taiwan is becoming a, quote, “dangerous situation” because of the closeness.  Is that accurate?  Are you aware of that report &#8212; that they issued that warning?  They say that they told you it was becoming dangerous.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I did not see the specific phraseology of “dangerous,” but they&#8217;ve offered formulas of that sort for months now.&nbsp; There&#8217;s not, I don&#8217;t think, anything particularly new in that statement.<br><br>Our view, as we&#8217;ve expressed many times, is that we are concerned about peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait and the ratcheting up of tensions.&nbsp; And we believe that China is contributing to the ratcheting up of those tensions through provocative military activities around Taiwan and around the Strait.<br><br>But we&#8217;ve been equally clear that our policy towards Taiwan has not changed.&nbsp; We support the One China policy, the Three Joint Communiqués, the Taiwan Relations Act, the Six Assurances.&nbsp; And we remain committed to supporting peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait and to ensuring that there are no unilateral changes to the status quo.<br><br>So, from &#8212; from our perspective, our position has been clear and consistent.&nbsp; And we believe that it would help if the PRC also dialed down the actions and activities that we think are contributing to tensions there.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Follow-up on China.&nbsp; So, there was a report this morning that China is replenishing its &#8212; or going to replenish its strategic oil reserves with oil from Russia.&nbsp; Does that cross the red lines that you&#8217;ve laid down for them in terms of cooperating with Russia on evading sanctions?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have banned Russian oil to the United States, but we have not imposed sanctions on the sale of Russian oil elsewhere.&nbsp; And, therefore, other countries purchasing Russian oil are not contravening the sanctions that we have laid out.<br><br>Now, of course, the Europeans are contemplating their own Russian oil ban, which we support.&nbsp; But President Biden made clear, when he issued the ban that we did, that we are in a particular position given that we&#8217;re an energy producer and so forth, and Europe is in a different position.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to your knowledge, is that accurate, though, that that &#8212; that that&#8217;s what China is doing with Russia?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, we have seen the statements about it, but we have not yet seen the action taken to that effect.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two more on China, if you’re willing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine: After overreaching initially, clearly the Russians &#8212; seems to be signs that are settling into more of a stalemate over in eastern Ukraine.&nbsp; What &#8212; do you think there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s a danger that time &#8212; people have assumed that Russia is the one suffering economically from the sanctions and so on, and even militarily.&nbsp; But if it says there’s a stalemate militarily, the West is also suffering from the sanctions &#8212; clearly, right? &#8212; it&#8217;s having a lot of spillover.</p>



<p>So is there a fear that time could actually end up being on the Russian side if they just want to settle for a grinding, you know, semi-frozen conflict in eastern Ukraine, just destabilizing Ukraine, and this goes on for months and months and months and months?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; You know, there &#8212; I certainly understand the question.&nbsp; There is something tragic in the logic of time being on the side of a country that is losing young men in large numbers by the day, as Russia is, and suffering &#8212; the people of the country, the economy of the country &#8212; under the weight of these sanctions.<br><br>So it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s hard for me &#8212; I can see a certain cynical kind of element to that logic.&nbsp; My view is: Time is not on their side because of just the sheer cost that is being imposed on them in human terms and in economic terms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, Vladimir Putin bet that Western unity would crack.&nbsp; I think he has been surprised by the clarity and resolve of the response of the free world.<br><br>And one thing that every leader that Joe Biden talks to reinforces is that we&#8217;re prepared for the long haul.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been saying now for weeks and months this could go on for a long time.&nbsp; And our allies and partners understand that very well &#8212; our allies and partners in Europe and the allies we&#8217;re going to see right now &#8212; the Republic of Korea and Japan.&nbsp; And, in fact, the Republic of Korea and Japan have stepped up in really significant ways to support this effort.<br><br>And I expect that he will walk out of those meetings over the next three days with a sense of reaffirmation that we&#8217;re committed to this for as long as it takes.<br><br>So we feel that this significant asset we have, of unity in the face of this aggression, is an asset that&#8217;s durable.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask one more question?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two different things.&nbsp; One, if you could lay down a little bit of tonight &#8212; or I guess, tomorrow &#8212; on the Samsung visit and what we should expect on that engagement.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, separately, President López Obrador, I guess early this morning, made some comments suggesting an answer should be coming very soon on his concerns about exclusion of certain countries.&nbsp; Can you give us an update about where things stand there?&nbsp; Has the President made a decision?&nbsp; Do you &#8212; are you guys ready to put out an invite list?&nbsp; And will you meet his concerns?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We&#8217;re having constructive conversations with President López Obrador.&nbsp; Senator Dodd, our special representative for this summit, spent two hours with him on Zoom yesterday.&nbsp; It was a good exchange of views.&nbsp; Ambassador Salazar will be engaged, even today.&nbsp; I’m not going to get into the details of what are candid and constructive conversations back and forth.&nbsp; And when we have something more to say on this, we&#8217;ll say it.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce today.<br><br>In terms of the event tonight, the President will be met by President Yoon at this Samsung facility, along with leadership of Samsung.<br><br>The facility is actually a very similar model to what Samsung will build in the United States.&nbsp; And that significant multibillion-dollar investment that they will be making in the U.S. will mean good-paying jobs for Americans and, very importantly, it will mean more supply chain resilience, because it will mean that the United States will be manufacturing significant quantities of semiconductors necessary as inputs for a lot of our key industries.<br><br>So the President will get a tour and then have the opportunity to speak to the public and to the press about the investments that Samsung is making in that semiconductor manufacturing facility, other investments Samsung is making as well that will help create American jobs and advance our competitive position.<br><br>And then the final thing that he will reinforce is that this ecosystem of high technology among democracies and free societies is one that needs to be protected against predation by other countries.&nbsp; And so he will have the opportunity also to say: Just as we&#8217;re promoting this kind of investment in advancement, we also need to protect these technologies from intellectual property theft.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, to follow up on that: On export controls on high tech, are you expecting any outcomes with South Korea and Japan on this trip, on export controls on high tech?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to have some very robust discussions on export controls, as well as investment parameters.&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t expect that we&#8217;re going to have specific announcements, because what we&#8217;re looking to do is align our approach around a set of principles and then on a case-by-case basis, as opposed to some new initiative or some new formula.&nbsp; And we actually believe that there has been substantial convergence, which will be on display on this trip, on this issue in both Korea and Japan.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can I follow up on China?&nbsp; You recently &#8212; or, a couple of days ago, you met with Yang Jiechi.&nbsp; I think you mentioned that &#8212;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Spoke by phone, yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, you spoke by phone.&nbsp; Yes, correct.&nbsp; And then you mentioned that you discussed DPRK.&nbsp; I think you hit on Taiwan too, a little bit.&nbsp; Is there anything more that you can share from that meeting?&nbsp; Essentially, what kind of message are you conveying to the Chinese ahead of the President&#8217;s trip to Asia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to say too much because I actually value the opportunity to engage with Yang in a way that allows for the free exchange of perspectives back and forth without it all being played out in the press.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I will say that, you know, I was quite direct with him about our concerns about North Korea&#8217;s nuclear and missile activities and our view that this is not in China&#8217;s interests, it&#8217;s not in America&#8217;s interests, and that China can &#8212; you know, should contemplate taking whatever steps it can to reduce the possibility of a provocative North Korean act.<br><br>And, you know, it was a &#8212; we had a good back-and-forth on that subject.&nbsp; He shared his perspective, which I won&#8217;t characterize.&nbsp; And, yes, we covered Taiwan, and we covered some other issues as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just follow up on another meeting, Jake?&nbsp; Did &#8212; can you confirm reports that you also met with a Pakistani spy agency chief and whether you discussed the issues of counterterrorism in Afghanistan?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Met with him when?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Recently in Washington, D.C.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I did not.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, did you have any communications with him recently?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No, no &#8212; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not being cute.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I met with the head of the ISI a year ago &#8212; the previous head &#8212; on a visit to Washington.&nbsp; But I di- &#8212; I have not met the current ISI chief nor spoken with him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Yang call, just to go back to that, was that partially to set up another call between Biden and Xi?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It was not.&nbsp; Although, I &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if, in the coming weeks, President Biden and President Xi speak again.&nbsp; But this was not specifically laying the groundwork for a call that is contemplated.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How come we haven’t &#8212; how come the administration hasn&#8217;t been talking to its Chinese counterparts very frequently, especially with Ukraine and the invasion?&nbsp; I think it had been two months since you had talked to Yang.&nbsp; Can you say maybe why &#8212; why isn&#8217;t there more communication with the Chinese?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I mean, I&#8217;d have to go back and look at what the rhythm was in terms of National Security Advisor engagement with their kind of rough counterpart, like Yang.&nbsp; But I actually think the cadence is not unusual.</p>



<p>You know, we spent a whole day together in Rome.&nbsp; And then, you know, seven, eight weeks later, we had a good, long conversation yesterday.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll speak again when necessary.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; and Secretary Blinken speaks with the foreign minister, I think, on a fairly similar cadence to what we&#8217;ve seen previously.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re certainly not intending to present any notion that we are slowing or we&#8217;re somehow constraining our high-level diplomatic engagement with China.&nbsp; We have said all along that we think intense competition requires intense diplomacy.&nbsp; And we should stay in close contact.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more on China. &nbsp;Is the U.S. prepared to levy secondary sanctions on China for Chinese companies and banks helping North Korea &#8212; just as prepared to levy secondary sanctions on &#8212; for that as you are for China helping Russia?</p>



<p>And then also on that: Do you feel pretty satisfied that China isn&#8217;t helping Russia and that they have heeded your warnings?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have not seen evidence thus far of China supplying military equipment to Russia for its brutal war in Ukraine, nor have we seen evidence that China has systematically worked to undermine Western sanctions.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s something we continue to track very closely, week by week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to make any threats about secondary sanctions in public.&nbsp; We have had conversations with China in private about our sanctions regime vis-à-vis North Korea.&nbsp; And, you know, the fact is that an overwhelming majority of North Korea&#8217;s economic activity runs through China.&nbsp; And so, in the past, there have been instances where Chinese entities have been part of the sanctions effort.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And beyond that, I don&#8217;t have anything to add.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Yellen said yesterday that some of the Trump-era tariffs imposed on China &#8212; that they&#8217;ve done more harm on businesses and U.S. consumers than good.&nbsp; Is there &#8212; if that&#8217;s really the case, why not lift them?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President has asked his economic team and his foreign policy team to engage in a consistent review of our trade policy towards China.&nbsp; There are discussions now about how best to move forward to deal with the challenges that China poses to our economy and our national security with their non-market economic practices, and how to move beyond the trade approach of the previous administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He will ultimately make a series of decisions on that, following his &#8212; the opportunity to get advice from his team.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to say anything else in public on that because I don&#8217;t want to prejudge what he ultimately decides.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, could you talk about why the decision was made to skip the DMZ on this trip?&nbsp; Is it just too dangerous?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President has been to the DMZ before.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not that it&#8217;s too dangerous, no.&nbsp; In fact, we have &#8212; senior U.S. government officials go there on a regular basis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But one of those U.S. government officials was then-Vice President Joe Biden in 2013.&nbsp; In fact, I was on the trip with him then as his national security advisor.&nbsp; And the head of U.S. Forces Korea &#8212; the Commander of U.S. Forces Korea, Scaparrotti, took us by Black Hawk up to the DMZ.&nbsp; He had the chance to see the whole thing, do the whole thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he felt on this trip, rather than repeat that, he wanted an opportunity actually to see where the rubber hits the road in terms of U.S. and ROK forces sitting side by side or managing the theater. </p>



<p>And so, we will do that at the airbase.  It will give him an opportunity to get briefed on the larger strategic picture in a way that actually will show him more than going and standing at the DMZ.  It&#8217;ll give him a much larger domain awareness for the security threats to the Peninsula and the wider region.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask a non-security aspect of the Quad, Jake?&nbsp; So, in the March meeting, I believe, they announced &#8212; the Quad announced 1 billion doses of vaccines, mostly for Indo-Pacific, Southeast Asia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now it seems like that&#8217;s not going to be met &#8212; that target.&nbsp; I understand that the Indian manufacturer has run into trouble; they haven&#8217;t been given the WHO approval.&nbsp; But also, I think we&#8217;re hearing that experts are saying that it&#8217;s not a question of not enough vaccines, but not enough funding to get them into &#8212; shots in arms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, does the Quad see that reality?&nbsp; And is there &#8212; can we expect a pivot in strategy from the Quad on vaccines?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We are working assiduously to get the necessary approvals because we think there still is the need for supply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in addition, we haven&#8217;t just been standing still waiting for that.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; Over the past several months, all of the Quad partners have worked together to get hundreds of millions of vaccines out into the world, many of them into Southeast Asia, and have put forward initiatives to help fund shots in arms.&nbsp; The United States has been on the leading edge of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the particular effort to get an Indian manufacturer to be able to produce and disseminate these vaccines has been constrained by regulatory efforts, but that has not slowed the four Quad partners from having a very robust COVID response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do think that coming out of this last COVID-19 Summit, where we got $3 billion in new commitments, that the emphasis on testing, treatment, and shots in arms, in addition to actual vaccine supply &#8212; that that is something you will see reflected in the collective efforts of the Quad going forward as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you had any (inaudible) pandemic funding from the U.S., though?&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any global pandemic response funding.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I mean, first of all, we&#8217;ve &#8212; I can&#8217;t give you the exact dollar figure, but it is more than any other country has provided in terms of COVID-19 global funding.&nbsp; And we are continuing to pursue efforts, including major initiatives to get shots in arms, with the funding that has already been allocated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, going back to your earlier point about Samsung and the opportunity to talk about semiconductors and jobs, Hyundai is also expected tomorrow, in Georgia, to announce a big plant.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President going to get a chance to engage on that?</p>



<p>And if I could also &#8212; just a second question on Yoon and on Prime Minister Kishida: This is the first really big opportunity for the President to just spend some time with these two very new leaders.&nbsp; Can you just talk to us a little bit of, you know, what he wants to get out of that and just, you know, sort of finding out who these &#8212; who these two people are and how he can work with them going forward?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah, I mean, you&#8217;ve heard the President say before that &#8212; he refers to this Tip O&#8217;Neill expression that &#8220;All politics is local.&#8221;&nbsp; He says, &#8220;All politics is personal.&nbsp; All foreign policy is personal.&#8221;&nbsp; It&#8217;s fundamentally about these personal relationships with leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, in both cases, he&#8217;s looking for the opportunity to just spend time to get to know these leaders so that they have a feel for one another and that then, when they need to pick up the phone in a crisis or to respond to a major world event, there&#8217;s a baseline of trust, understanding, and almost like a common operating language as they go forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;s already built that, to a certain extent, with Prime Minister Kishida.&nbsp; They did meet in Glasgow last year.&nbsp; They have had the chance to do extended video conversations.&nbsp; He has spoken only briefly on the phone with President Yoon after his election, and he&#8217;s only extremely recently been inaugurated.&nbsp; So this will be an opportunity to build that relationship, you know, from &#8212; from the ground up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Korea, President Yoon will be there today.&nbsp; So not just in the formal bilateral context, but they&#8217;ll go through the Samsung tour together.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll come with the President to Osan Air Base for &#8212; for the briefing event with the U.S. and ROK militaries.&nbsp; And then they will have a very small meeting, in addition to the expanded meeting, to be able to get to know one another.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, with Prime Minister Kishida, not only will they have the opportunity for one-on-one time, but the Prime Minister will host him for a very small dinner as well that will give them the chance to just, you know, talk as humans, as opposed to as world leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes, he will meet with the CEO of Hyundai in Seoul &#8212; that will be before he leaves on Sunday &#8212; and will have the opportunity to say thank you for this significant investment that will occur in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we like to think that, in part, having this trip and having this emphasis on the relationship between the U.S.-ROK and investments in the United States has helped give it momentum and boost to these announcements you&#8217;re now seeing &#8212; seeing come out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, there was some language in the readout of your call with the Saudi Deputy Defense Minister that suggested that you talked about the economic recovery, which is not normally a topic with defense ministers.&nbsp; Just curious how oil was discussed on that call, whether you discussed getting them more and more engaged in helping the economic recovery by getting more barrels of oil out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I actually saw him in person.&nbsp; He was in town &#8212; is still in town for a series of defense dialogues.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s an important advisor across a range of issues, despite his formal title being Deputy Defense Minister.&nbsp; We did talk about economics, we did talk about energy, and I&#8217;ll leave it at that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about IPEF a little bit?&nbsp; Just &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On that, can I just follow up?&nbsp; I know you said you can’t confirm &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We’re going to need to wrap it up, guys.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that the President is going to the Middle East.&nbsp; But is it possible that if he did go to the Middle East, he would meet with MBS?&nbsp; Would he meet with the Crown Prince?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I really don&#8217;t have any announcements or even speculation on travel to the Middle East.&nbsp; And if and when we have any speculation, informed or otherwise, I will speculate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about IPEF real quick?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because this is something that you&#8217;re going to launch, right?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So without any kind of free trade component, I think many are saying, “Yeah, countries will sign on because this is an important relationship with the U.S., but it&#8217;s really not an attractive package to many countries in the region.”&nbsp; Can you respond to &#8212; respond to the criticism?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;ll respond to that.&nbsp; I think you&#8217;re going to see a really impressive display of energy and enthusiasm by a significant number of countries in the Indo-Pacific for the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is going to be a wide-ranging and comprehensive set of countries from across the region, a mix of different kinds of economies.&nbsp; And that diversity and breadth of participation, in our view, actually vindicates the basic theory behind IPEF, which is &#8212; you&#8217;re right &#8212; it is not a traditional free trade agreement.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a good thing.&nbsp; It is a modern negotiation designed to deal with modern challenges.</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re going to cover supply chains, the digital economy, the clean energy transformation, significant investments in infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we think that, at the end of the day, what you&#8217;re going to see is a response to the real-world challenges facing these economies and really meaningful progress on substance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think what&#8217;s interesting when you hear some of the &#8220;Well, we don&#8217;t quite know.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not sure because it doesn&#8217;t look like things have looked before&#8221; &#8212; I say, &#8220;Just you wait.&#8221;&nbsp; Because I think this is going to be the new model of economic arrangement that will set the terms and rules of the road for trade and technology and supply chains for the 21st century.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we&#8217;re planting a stake in the ground that we want to be at the center of that.&nbsp; And we see a lot of countries signing on with us to make that a reality, and it&#8217;s going to give huge thrust and momentum to our economic initiatives in the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>The other thing is that there&#8217;s a certain lagging indicator here.&nbsp; I would say, two months ago, there was a lot of, like,</p>



<p>“Well, is this real?&nbsp; Is it not real?&nbsp; Is it something that&#8217;s meaningful or not meaningful?”&nbsp; Week by week, as we&#8217;ve built out the substance working with these countries, they&#8217;ve not only come on board, but they&#8217;ve gotten increasingly invested in and motivated by the elements of it.</p>



<p>So, we think this event on Monday is going to be a big deal and is going to be a significant milestone in U.S. engagement in the Indo-Pacific. And at the end of the President&#8217;s first term, I think we will look back and say this was a moment where the U.S. engagement in the Indo-Pacific got kicked into a different gear.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) is there any kind of capacity building or trade (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, absolutely.&nbsp; I mean, there&#8217;ll be significant resources around infrastructure, around trade facilitation.&nbsp; There will be the opportunity to set &#8212; to organize regulatory approaches that will make trade significantly easier.&nbsp; And there&#8217;ll be the opportunity for us to set the rules of the digital economy for the 21st century.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a lot in this that people are going to want to be at the table at.&nbsp; And the reason we know people are going to want to be at table &#8212; at it &#8212; is they&#8217;re going to be there.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have a significant roster of countries signing up to this thing and joining us there for &#8212; to be in at the takeoff of this effort.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We’re going to just take two more.&nbsp; Two more, guys.&nbsp; That&#8217;s it.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; There was some intelligence that was declassified yesterday about &#8212; in Mariupol &#8212; what sounded like almost torture of city officials and residents.&nbsp; But a concern &#8212; it sounded like the intelligence was finding that Russian officials were concerned that the treatment could backfire.&nbsp; One, can you confirm that this &#8212; that these reports are correct?&nbsp; And &#8212; and, two, who are these Russian officials, and what is the sort of broader concern that is going on there?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to speak beyond the four corners of the information that was released yesterday, other than to say that we warned, before the conflict began, that we were likely to see brutality and repression by Russia in occupied areas.&nbsp; And we are seeing that in cities and towns across the areas that Russian forces are currently holding.</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re also seeing, increasingly, is the reality of the Ukrainian populace pushing back against this in these areas and the concern in Moscow that, in fact, what they had hoped for at the beginning, which is the Ukrainians would welcome them as liberators or as brothers, is not bearing out in the first instance.&nbsp; And the level of antipathy and animosity will only grow as Russia&#8217;s brutality and repression unfolds in these places.</p>



<p>And we think that&#8217;s a dynamic well worth watching, even as so many &#8212; so much of the attention is focused on the fighting on the frontline in the Donbas.&nbsp; Because what&#8217;s happening in these occupied areas is brave Ukrainian saying, “We don&#8217;t want to live this way.”&nbsp; And we think that that is going to impose its own form of pressure on the long-term Russian effort to occupy these areas.</p>



<p>And this comes back to the question you were asking at the beginning about whether time is on Russia&#8217;s side.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen before that military advances can give way to grinding occupations that bleed a country dry.&nbsp; And this is &#8212; this is not going to be a circumstance where Russia is just going to be able to sit on any territory it takes and have these courageous and brave Ukrainians just say, “Yeah, we&#8217;re fine with that.”&nbsp; They will not be.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Last question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, thank you.&nbsp; Have the North Koreans actually ever responded to any of the overtures from the Biden administration?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I guess all I will say is that we&#8217;ve gotten no indications from them that they are prepared to sit down and talk.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s true from the opening weeks of the administration all the way through to today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know if they&#8217;re still &#8212; if Kim is still in touch with the former President?&nbsp; There has been reporting that says as such.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I do not know that.&nbsp; Thank you, guys.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, can you give us a sense of what’s going to be happening in Anchorage?&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be stopping for an hour and a half.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, just a gas &#8212; gas refuel.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the President get off the plane for any kind of &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t expect him to get off the plane.&nbsp; Yeah, we’re just refueling.&nbsp; That’s it.&nbsp; If there’s more, I’ll share that with you, but I don&#8217;t know of any more than that.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; President Biden knows that parents across the country are worried about finding enough infant formula to feed their babies, which is why he has directed his administration to do everything possible to ensure that there is enough safe infant formula in the country available for families that need it.</p>



<p>Yesterday, we announced two important actions.&nbsp; As you all know, the President invoked the Defense Production Act to ensure that manufacturers have the necessary ingredients to make safe, healthy infant formula here at home.</p>



<p>Just to give some background on how the DPA works, I thought I’d dive in with some specific details here, since we&#8217;ve gotten so much inquiry about this.</p>



<p>The DPA is an authority that empowers the government to require companies to direct their resources to support the national defense.&nbsp; That includes supporting critical infrastructure and public health.</p>



<p>Yesterday, as well, the President gave HHS the authority to order suppliers to direct needed resources to infant formula manufacturers before any other customer who may have ordered that good.&nbsp; So, with this authority, we can direct firms to prioritize and allocate the production of key infant formula inputs as needed.&nbsp; This can and will help increase production and speed up supply chains.</p>



<p>Just an example of how this works: There are a range of things needed to make formula, from oils and fat blends to labels and cans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The company that makes one of those items, like a label, has a lot of customers, one of which happens to be infant formula manufacturers.&nbsp; And they are likely a very small share of the overall market for that good.</p>



<p>By having DPA authority available for infant formula, we make sure formula manufacturers are at the top of the list for that item and can maintain the higher levels of production that the companies put in place in February to address the shortage caused by the Abbott plant being shut down.</p>



<p>Second, the President also announced Operation Fly Formula to speed up the important &#8212; the important &#8212; the import of FDA-approved infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible.</p>



<p>By using DOD-contracted aircraft, we can bypass regular air freightening [sic] &#8212; freighting routes and speed up the importation and distribution of safe infant formula.</p>



<p>This is the same type of action we took to get critical COVID materials, such as testing supplies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These announcements build on previous administration actions that have increased manufacturing production and are getting more safe infant formula onto shelves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sorry, my throat is a little dry.&nbsp; (Clears throat.)&nbsp; I apologize.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Need some water?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Probably.&nbsp; I apologize, guys.</p>



<p>Okay, Aamer, you want to kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On infant formula, does the President agree with criticism from Senator Wyden and others that Abbott fell short of its corporate responsibility with its failure to keep up with sanitation upgrades at its Michigan plant?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, the President&#8217;s &#8212; the President&#8217;s goal right now is to make sure he understands how difficult it is for families to find, in this &#8212; in this particular time, to find baby formula.&nbsp; And so he wants to do everything in his power, use every lever in his power to get that &#8212; to get that situation taken care of and to get us in a better place.</p>



<p>When it comes to Abbott &#8212; look, we have told this story.&nbsp; You guys have heard us say this.&nbsp; The FDA stepped in, and Abbott had &#8212; had a safety issue that the FDA flagged for them, and they volu- &#8212; Abbott voluntarily shut down that facility in Sturgis, in Michigan.</p>



<p>And so that is &#8212; the number one thing that&#8217;s important to us is safety &#8212; safety and health first.</p>



<p>And so, just &#8212; I just want to add to &#8212; so what we announced yesterday just builds on what we&#8217;re trying to do in order to get things back &#8212; to get things going again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there&#8217;s an agreement by the FDA and Abbott Nutrition detailing next steps to reopen Abbott Sturgis plant and make sure we do it in a safe way.&nbsp; FDA guidance is that that will allow major formula manufacturers to safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market; efforts to cut the red tape and provide consumers flexibility on types of formula they can buy; and calling on Federal Trade Commission and State Attorney General &#8212; and State Attorneys General to crack down on price gouging or unfair market practice.</p>



<p>So this is a top priority not just for the President, but clearly for his administration.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re going to continue working overtime, working 24/7.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to be focused on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, I get that the FDA was coming in to do the thing &#8212; it was working on safety.&nbsp; But does the President understand just the outrage that some people have?&nbsp; This is while Abbott was doing stock buybacks and they weren&#8217;t keeping up their plant.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, we understand the outrage, right?&nbsp; We &#8212; we see how mothers and parents are dealing right now in this situation.&nbsp; As a mom, who had to deal with getting formula for my child when she was a little &#8212; a little one and was allergic to certain formula, I know how this feels &#8212; trying to make sure your baby is eating healthy and safely.</p>



<p>You know, clearly, I&#8217;m not dealing with this in this current form and what&#8217;s happening, which is &#8212; which is &#8212; you know, which is something that we&#8217;re trying to deal with.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s the focus.&nbsp; Our focus right now is how do we &#8212; how do we do this safely; how do we make sure that we&#8217;re doing everything in our power, which we have been for the past several months, to get to a place where families are not struggling to feed their child &#8212; their children.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any sense of how many weeks, after you do all of these, before it actually makes a difference for parents?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know &#8212; so, by invoking &#8212; (clears throat) &#8212; excuse me.&nbsp; Wow, I really have a tickle in my throat.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so sorry.</p>



<p>By invoking &#8212; invoking the DPA.&nbsp; So the President, again, knows how important this is for families across the country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he has directed his administration to do everything possible to ensure that there is enough safe infant formula in the country available for families that are in need.</p>



<p>So, you know, again, this is going to cut the red tape and implement W-I-C &#8212; WIC flexibility so that parents can get any formula when they walk into stores.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re building off of: increased supply on the &#8212; market supply is higher than it was before the recall, so we have seen an increase out there before the recall; fighting against bad actors &#8212; as I mentioned before, with FTC &#8212; that may possibly be hoarding and selling product in unacceptable way &#8212; prices.</p>



<p>So work is so far from over, but with every action we take, we are making serious progress and elevating the shortage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But when it comes to &#8212; I know folks were asking about picking up formula from other countries and when that’s going to happen and where that’s going to happen.  You know, we’re working with manufacturers right now to identify existing stockpiles of FDA-approved formula overseas, to arrange pick up by DOD commercial flight.  And we’ll have more details to share, and we’re hoping that happens soon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to take a little bit of water guys, but go ahead, Nancy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Abbott plant &#8212; it shut down in February.&nbsp; Why did it take so long for the White House to act on the DPA?&nbsp; And why couldn’t those actions have been taken months ago?&nbsp; Like, how long is it going to take for results to &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, as I said &#8212; as I just laid out, we&#8217;ve been doing this for months with the &#8212; our &#8212; the administration.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been working on this for several months now.&nbsp; And the DPA was always on the table.&nbsp; We are always examining, trying to figure out the best way to do this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there are other actions, as I just listed, that we have been doing.  This is a &#8212; building on the DPA.  And the &#8212; and the Operation Fly <s>Over</s> [Formula] is just an added addition to the &#8212; to items that we&#8217;ve announced just a couple of days ago.</p>



<p>So, we have not been sitting on this.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been doing everything in our power to move forward as quickly as possible to really respond to what&#8217;s happening currently, right now, with the baby formula. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m just going to take one (inaudible).&nbsp; (Take a drink of water.)&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On gas prices.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, ma’am.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, we saw another record high on gas prices.&nbsp; Do you have any &#8212; anything you can share with us on what the administration can do about that?&nbsp; And is there anything you can share on what the administration is discussing as you help Europe try to block Russian oil but that would lead to even more higher prices and &#8212; or &#8212; for U.S. consumers?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, this is something that’s been also a priority for the President: making sure that we’re lowering cost for the American people.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve announced several steps just in general, as we talk about lowering cost, the past several weeks &#8212; whether it’s the high-speed Internet for tens of millions of Americans or when he went to Illinois recently to give farmers the tools and resources they need to boost production and lower prices and feed the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, the nonpartisan <s>CBC</s> [CBO] found that the deficit fell by $1.5 trillion this year, putting us on track for the fastest deficit reduction in any year on record.&nbsp; And one of the things &#8212; the two items that we did take on recently to address Putin’s price hike at the pump is the &#8212; is rallying our allies and partners around the world and release that 1 million barrels of oil per day from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve for the &#8212; for the next six months, as you&#8217;ve heard us talk about.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s an additional 60 million barrels of oil from over the country&#8217;s reserve.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, we did &#8212; we allowed E15 gasoline, which is homegrown biofuels, to be sold this summer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we have &#8212; we are doing everything in &#8212; that we can as an administration to make sure we address the high prices at the pump, with food, with other things that &#8212; with other items that the American public is feeling.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to continue to do that and make sure that we focus on what can we do for &#8212; from this administration to lower those costs &#8212; price.&nbsp; It is a&nbsp;priority.&nbsp; It is also a priority for this President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) price caps?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to share on any further &#8212; kind of any further items to preview on what we&#8217;re doing next.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the President have any issues with price caps that are being talked about in Europe?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to share on that. </p>



<p>Q    Karine, just &#8212; not to beat a dead horse, but &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you don&#8217;t have anything to share right now, but are there &#8212; are there other tools in the famous toolbox here? Because it’s &#8212; you’ve used up a lot of tools, and there&#8217;s been no noticeable effect for Americans.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, I &#8212; you know, again, what we&#8217;re seeing right now, currently, as we&#8217;re looking at the gas prices &#8212; because, JJ, that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s just the question that she started off asking me &#8212; it&#8217;s because of Putin’s price hike.&nbsp; It’s because of what Putin is doing in Ukraine &#8212; his aggression and his war on Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we saw a jump in prices once that happened &#8212; about 60 to 70 percent.&nbsp; So we are doing &#8212; that&#8217;s why we did the last two things.&nbsp; The E15 was one of the most recent items that we pushed forward to try and help the American public and get the gases &#8212; the gas prices to come down.</p>



<p>So, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview, but the President has, as I laid out, a bunch of steps, has taken this very seriously, and understands the pain of the American public and what they&#8217;re feeling &#8212; American families &#8212; and what they&#8217;re feeling at the <s>price</s> [gas] pump and with high prices in general.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You and other officials have mentioned Putin’s price hike very often lately.&nbsp; Do you believe that this will be an effective message going into the midterms?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in addition to that, I think the President also hits really hard on other cultural issues.&nbsp; Like, I think during the AAPI event, he mentioned &#8212; or he condemned people who filled the shooters with crazy ideas.&nbsp; He also does a lot of the ultra-MAGA kind of sentiment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I guess I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m trying to get a feel of what&#8217;s the messaging that&#8217;s coming out of the White House ahead of the midterms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, let me get back to the &#8212; you&#8217;re talking about the “Great Replacement Theory,” which is a conspiracy theory that&#8217;s incredibly dangerous.&nbsp; And what the President said when he was in Buffalo in particular, when he was visiting with the families of victims and the families who lost their loved ones, he was &#8212; spoke very clearly and said that you have to call this out.&nbsp; It is important to call out the hatred. It’s important to call out this very dangerous theory.&nbsp; And &#8212; and white supremacy is poison.&nbsp; He said this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s important for the leader &#8212; the leader of this country, of our country; the leader of &#8212; one of the leaders of the &#8212; around the globe to make sure that he sa- &#8212; he says that in a very forceful way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, that is what you saw the President do, and that is important &#8212; and critically important &#8212; especially how dangerous that conspiracy theory is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, when we talk about Putin’s price hike, it is a fact.&nbsp; It is a fact that we want to make sure that we&#8217;re communicating very clearly with the American public as what they are seeing at the &#8212; at the pumps and why we&#8217;re in this situation.</p>



<p>So, you know, you asked me about &#8212; about the contrast of what we&#8217;ve been doing with Republicans.&nbsp; I mean, it is true, when you think about what we&#8217;re seeing with, you know, a woman&#8217;s right to choose and to decide what to do with their body, you know, that &#8212; that is something that the President has spoken about and the Republicans are against; when we talk about the leaked document that we saw from SCOTUS; when we talk about, you know, what we&#8217;re trying to do with the middle class and inflation.&nbsp; You know, that is the number one challenge for families, as we&#8217;ve been just discussing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are two potential paths forward.&nbsp; President Biden&#8217;s plan is to tackle inflation and lower costs for families.&nbsp; And congressional Republicans &#8212; MAGA &#8212; plan to raise taxes on middle class.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we have to ask the question: Who has &#8212; who has their back?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the President&#8217;s plans lowers everyday costs, lowers the deficit, and ask large corporations and billionaires to pay &#8212; pay for their fair share.&nbsp; The congressional Republican plan is to increase taxes on middle-class families and let billionaires and large companies off the hook as they raise prices and reap record profit.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So this is important that we are able to say, “This is our plan, and this is what the other side is trying to do.”&nbsp; And we want to make very clear and &#8212; and speak to the American people about those things.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, let me stay on gas prices &#8212; because now we are going into the summer traveling season, when demand usually shoots up.&nbsp; Is there a role for conservation here?&nbsp; And should the American public be thinking about driving less or planning different kinds of vacations to deal with the higher prices?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So it&#8217;s not our place to tell the American public, you know, how they should spend their summers and what they should do.</p>



<p>We are doing everything that we can to make sure that we lower the prices.&nbsp; This is, again, Putin’s price hike &#8212; why we made the announcement on the E15 gasoline, which is going to, you know, have some long-term effects.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll see that down the line.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; so we&#8217;re going to &#8212; again, we&#8217;re going to continue to do what we can, because this is a priority.&nbsp; This is incredibly important to the President.&nbsp; He understands what it means for the &#8212; American families, the American people to &#8212; when they see increased prices and how they&#8217;re &#8212; we’re trying to make sure that we alleviate that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, does the President have any reaction or concern about former President Trump telling Dr. Oz that he should simply declare victory in Pennsylvania before all the ballots are counted?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I ca- &#8212; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t get into politics from here, so I&#8217;m not going to dive into that at all.&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, I mu- &#8211; I understand my role.&nbsp; And I actually have not spoken to the President about that, so I can&#8217;t even speak to the question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he following the (inaudible) counting of these returns since it might be a close race?&nbsp; And, you know, obviously, I assume he&#8217;s for the Democrat, Fetterman, in that race.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah &#8212; well, yeah, absolutely.&nbsp; I spoke to that yesterday &#8212; or I can&#8217;t even remember; I lost my days.&nbsp; But when I was asked about that at the podium.&nbsp; But I &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to dive in into the politics of the midterms or the primary.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, shifting back to formula, Senator Patty Murray says she gives everyone involved in the response to the formula crisis an “F” grade.&nbsp; Does the President share that view?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Murray is also calling on the White House to appoint a formula coordinator going forward.&nbsp; Is that something you would consider?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, the &#8212; the coordinator, I &#8212; you know, we appreciate Senator Patty Murray.&nbsp; We work with her closely on so &#8212; on many issues.&nbsp; I do not have anything on the coordinator.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; you know, I &#8212; look, we understand the frustration of, you know, the American public.&nbsp; We appreciate &#8212; the American public and the members.&nbsp; We appreciate members that have led on solutions to address the shortage.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to continue working closely with them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, this is a priority for the President.&nbsp; He understands how difficult this is for working &#8212; for families who have children and trying to make sure that they are, you know, being fed safely.&nbsp; And that is our priority as well, which is how we got here.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; We have to remember how we got here: FDA, you know, told Abbott facility that there was some safety issues, and they voluntarily shut down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, safety is key here.&nbsp; We want to make sure that we&#8217;re doing this in a safe and healthy way.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I have one more foreign policy question, Karine? Can you give a reaction to the report &#8212; recent report by the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction that decisions by both President Trump and President Biden to pull all U.S. troops out of Afghanistan were the key factors that led to the collapse of the Afghan military, leading to the Taliban takeover?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; When &#8212; when was that reported?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This report came out, like, maybe a week or two weeks ago.&nbsp; And I actually sent the NSC about &#8212; an email about this.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I have not seen the report, so I would need to see it in more detail to respond.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know how we&#8217;ve spoken about the Afghanistan and the operation and how it was just a non-ending war that we spent billions of dollars on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, this is something that the President had talked about &#8212; the strategy there and wanting to make sure that we got our troops out of there.&nbsp; And so, I don&#8217;t have anything more to add without really seeing &#8212; diving into the report.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>4:34 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: In First Stop on Asia Travel, President&#160;Biden Tours Model for Samsung’s New Texas Semiconductor&#160;Facility</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/20/fact-sheet-in-first-stop-on-asia-travel-president-biden-tours-model-for-samsungs-new-texas-semiconductor-facility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53639</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Plant in Texas will Create 3,000 New Good-Paying Jobs; Biden to Call on Congress to Pass Bipartisan Innovation Act to Supercharge New Investments in Innovation Today, President Biden and the President of the Republic of Korea (ROK) Yoon Suk Yeol will tour the Samsung Electronics Pyeongtaek Campus – a model for the new Samsung&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>New Plant in Texas will Create 3,000 New Good-Paying Jobs; Biden to Call on Congress to Pass Bipartisan Innovation Act to Supercharge New Investments in Innovation</em></strong></p>



<p>Today, President Biden and the President of the Republic of Korea (ROK) Yoon Suk Yeol will tour the Samsung Electronics Pyeongtaek Campus – a model for the new Samsung plant being built in Taylor, Texas. The stop will demonstrate how our alliances deliver for the American middle class, investing in manufacturing in the United States, creating good paying jobs and strengthening our supply chains. The United States and the ROK are among each other’s largest trading and investment partners, with more than $62 billion of foreign direct investment by Korean firms in the United States as of 2020 – supporting over 94,000 American and bringing our governments, businesses, and people closer together.   </p>



<p>At the plant, President Biden will also make the case for quickly passing the Bipartisan Innovation Act which will deliver historic federal investments in U.S. research and development, supply chains, and domestic manufacturing – including funding for the CHIPS Act to provide $52 billion to catalyze more private-sector investments and advance American technological leadership. As the President has said, tackling inflation is his top economic priority, and making these investments will help lower costs by making our supply chains more resilient in the long term, protecting us against costly disruptions and higher prices for consumers.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has been working around the clock with Congress, our allies and partners, and the private sector to generate additional semiconductor manufacturing capacity with strong labor protections, address key bottlenecks and lower costs for families, and cement American leadership in the industries of the future. In President Biden’s first year in office, the U.S. economy created a historic 6.6 million new jobs. The economy has added 545,000 manufacturing jobs since President Biden took office – more manufacturing jobs on average per month than any other President in the last 50 years and 2021 seeing the highest increase in U.S. manufacturing jobs in nearly 30 years.</p>



<p>As a result of sustained engagement with Samsung and the Republic of Korea, Samsung is investing $17 billion to build a new semiconductor facility, adding to the 20,000 jobs Samsung already supports in the United States. Under President Biden, semiconductor manufacturing is coming back to America<strong>:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Since the beginning of 2021, the semiconductor industry has announced nearly $80 billion in new investments in the United States through 2025, according to the Semiconductor Industry Association.Thisincludes <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-bringing-semiconductor-manufacturing-back-to-america/">Intel’s $20 billion</a> fab outside Columbus, Ohio; Texas Instruments investing up to $30 billion in Texas; Wolfspeed’s $1 billion expansion in North Carolina; and expansions by Global Foundries and SK Group.</li></ul>



<ul><li>In June, the Commerce Department issued a set of recommendations on how to secure the U.S. semiconductor supply chain. Since that time, Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, and National Economic Council Director Brian Deese have held regular follow-up engagements with industry leaders and diplomatic partners and allies to advance practical solutions to strengthen the global semiconductor supply chain.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The U.S. Department of Defense has used Defense Production Act authorities to strengthen supply chains for key defense-related semiconductors.</li></ul>



<ul><li>In October of last year, President Biden hosted a global summit on supply chains with the heads of state from 14 countries and the European Union on the margins of the G20 in Italy to discuss supply chain disruptions, with a focus on semiconductors. This year, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo and Secretary of State Antony Blinken will hold a follow-on ministerial-level convening of international partners, members of the private sector, and other stakeholders to discuss next steps in securing global supply chain resilience including for semiconductors.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The President also focused on semiconductor supply chain resilience in his bilateral meetings with foreign leaders and directed the Administration to cooperate with Europe on strengthening global supply chains through the U.S.-E.U. Trade and Technology Council (TTC) and through the Quad’s focus on critical technologies. At the TTC last week, the U.S. and EU announced <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/16/fact-sheet-u-s-eu-trade-and-technology-council-establishes-economic-and-technology-policies-initiatives/">an early warning system</a> to better predict and address potential semiconductor supply chain disruptions as well as establish a Transatlantic approach to semiconductor investment aimed at ensuring security of supply and avoiding subsidy races.</li></ul>



<p>President Biden hosted a virtual summit with leading firms that produce chips and those that use chips to identify practical ways to discuss actions they could to address the disruptions resulting from the global chip shortage. By the end of the year, the participants had <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/ford-enters-semiconductor-business-amid-chip-shortage-impact-11637242202">announced new partnerships</a> between semiconductor companies and U.S. automakers to strengthen the resiliency of the automotive chip supply chain.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on the Oklahoma Abortion&#160;Bill</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-oklahoma-abortion-bill/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 01:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President believes that women have the fundamental right to make their own reproductive health choices.&#160;Roe has been the law of the land for almost 50 years, and basic fairness and the stability of our law demand that it not be overturned.&#160; Today’s action by the Oklahoma legislature is the most extreme effort to&#160;undo&#160;these fundamental&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President believes that women have the fundamental right to make their own reproductive health choices.&nbsp;<em>Roe </em>has been the law of the land for almost 50 years, and basic fairness and the stability of our law demand that it not be overturned.&nbsp; Today’s action by the Oklahoma legislature is the most extreme effort to&nbsp;undo&nbsp;these fundamental rights we have seen to date.&nbsp; In addition, it adopts Texas’ absurd plan to allow private citizens to sue their neighbors for&nbsp;providing reproductive health care and helping women to exercise&nbsp;their constitutional rights.</p>



<p>This is part of a growing effort by ultra MAGA officials across the country to roll back the freedoms we should not take for granted in this country.&nbsp; They are starting with reproductive rights, but the American people need to know that other fundamental rights, including the right to contraception and marriage equality, are at risk.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>The President is committed to standing up for these constitutional rights, and for protecting Americans’ fundamental freedoms.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden in&#160;Ecuador</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/19/remarks-by-first-lady-jill-biden-in-ecuador/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 23:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53634</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carondelet PalaceQuito, Ecuador 2:21 P.M. ECT FIRST LADY BIDEN:  Thank you, María de Lourdes, for that very kind introduction. Mr. President, Madam First Lady, María Mercedes, Foreign Minister Holguín, and Ambassador Baki, Ministers of State, and to you, the people of Ecuador: Here, at the center of the world, there is so much to fill&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Carondelet Palace<br>Quito, Ecuador</p>



<p>2:21 P.M. ECT</p>



<p>FIRST LADY BIDEN:  Thank you, María de Lourdes, for that very kind introduction.<br><br>Mr. President, Madam First Lady, María Mercedes, Foreign Minister Holguín, and Ambassador Baki, Ministers of State, and to you, the people of Ecuador:<br><br>Here, at the center of the world, there is so much to fill us with awe: the majestic Andes, the volcanos like fire gods waiting to awaken.  From the Galapagos to the Amazon, the story of our very origins on Earth.  The breathtaking coast and the history that dusts every stone and brick that lines the streets of Quito. <br><br>And no less spectacular is the heart of the Ecuadorian people.  Thank you for your warm hospitality and welcome.<br><br>I am honored to be here in this beautiful capital today.  And on behalf of my husband and the people of the United States: <em>Buenas tardes</em>.  (Applause.) <br><br>Ambassador Fitzpatrick, you and Silvana are doing great work here.  And our U.S. Embassy team represents the United States with excellence every day.  Thank you to both of you.  (Applause.)<br><br>Two hundred years ago next week, you won independence from Spain right here in Quito, at the Battle of Pichincha.</p>



<p>And since then, you’ve built a democracy that is able to withstand the tides of time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, you have a President and a First Lady who serve the people.</p>



<p>President Lasso is carving his place in your history by reaching out to those who have often been ignored or left behind, by listening to those who have faced inequality and discrimination and poverty and finding solutions for their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As he said in his inaugural address, “I have not come to satisfy the hatred of a few, but to satisfy the hunger of many.”&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Thank you, President Lasso, for leading with courage and conviction.<br><br>And, Madam First Lady, today I saw your heart through your work to serve children of Ecuador’s most vulnerable.&nbsp; And may God bless you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Ecuador, the progress you’ve made here is a light to your neighbors.&nbsp; And your illumination can bring a more equitable and sustainable future in this corner of the world.<br><br>But alone, you can only do so much.&nbsp; Any one of us can only do so much.&nbsp; So that’s what I’d like to talk to you about today: how when we work together, we can make our nations and our world stronger.<br><br>A little over a week ago, in a small school on the other side of the world, I sat with Ukrainian mothers, with tears permanently in &#8212; on the edges of their eyes, as if they could barely contain their sadness.<br><br>While they wore brave faces, they grasped their children’s hand or touched their children’s hair, unable to bear to lose the physical connection for even a moment.<br><br>The mothers I met there told me about the violence; the days and days without food, harbored in basements, no sunlight.&nbsp; They never wanted to leave their homes, but what else could they do?</p>



<p>Perhaps you’re wondering why I am telling you about mothers who are almost 7,000 miles away.&nbsp; After all, there are desperate parents all around this world.<br><br>I met them just two days ago in Buffalo, New York, in my own country &#8212; a mother and a father weeping over the daughter whose life was stolen in a hateful gun massacre.&nbsp;<br><br>I met Syrian mothers in Jordan who told me that they couldn’t protect their daughters from the soldiers who came to abuse them.</p>



<p>I met a mother in a Kenyan refugee camp who told me of leaving her child’s lifeless body behind in the sand because she only had the strength to carry one of her two children.<br><br>And I will meet the children of Venezuelan parents later today when your First Lady and I visit students whose families have fled their homes.<br><br>It&#8217;s tempting to believe that other people’s problems are theirs to solve alone.&nbsp; What does a terrified mother in Ukraine matter to someone who is oceans away?&nbsp; What does a hungry child in Ecuador matter to a family in New York?&nbsp; What does inequality in the United States matter to young people right here in Quito?</p>



<p>But they do matter.&nbsp; Injustice and corruption, poverty and pollution, disease and despair &#8212; they aren’t contained by any borders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If we’ve learned anything from the COVID-19 pandemic, from these last few years of sickness and sorrow, it’s how one deadly virus can move through the world, how hunger and violence are woven together, how a war in Europe can ripple through stock markets and supermarkets here, how the loss of trees in your Amazon can take a piece of the future from all of us.&nbsp;<br><br>But we’ve seen something else in the past few years as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;We’ve seen how kindness can spread through something as simple as wearing a mask.&nbsp;&nbsp;We’ve seen calls for injustice [justice] echoing through the streets of cities near and far.&nbsp;&nbsp;We’ve seen countries rise up against tyrants and offer shelter to their neighbors.&nbsp;&nbsp;Unexpected acts of kindness that speak to our very humanity.<br><br>Yes, we are connected, especially in the Americas.&nbsp; If one nation is vulnerable to authorit- &#8212; authoritarianism or a health crisis or poverty, it won’t be long before those same problems reach us all.<br><br>But when nations here in South America embrace democracy, you become the living proof that governments can deliver for the people that they represent, inspiring others to follow your lead.</p>



<p>When parents in every hemisphere don’t have to worry about how they will have to feed their children or hide them from violence, when they can work in their home countries and build their communities, their children can learn and grow and become the leaders and the innovators that we need.<br><br>My husband, Joe, has always said that politics is personal, and that’s why he’s worked so hard to build relationships throughout the world and here in Ecuador.</p>



<p>You know Joe, and I hope that you know that he cares deeply about you.&nbsp; And I do too.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why I’m here today.<br><br>The United States is committed to Ecuador.&nbsp; Together &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.&nbsp; Together, we vaccinated your people, and we’re working &#8212; working on strengthening your healthcare system.&nbsp; Together, we’ve trained and mentored entrepreneurs and small businesses, especially those run by women.<br><br>And together, we’ve worked to preserve Ecuador’s precious environment, help more students go to college.&nbsp; And together, we will defend your government from cyberattacks.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And it’s not just Ecuador.&nbsp; The United States, like you, is investing throughout this region.&nbsp; And, like you, we are committed to building rela- &#8212; lasting relationships.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, I will head to Panama and then Costa Rica &#8212; two other critical democracies.&nbsp; From visiting schools and meeting students, to learning about health systems and how they’re serving patients, I’m going to see things that are making lives better.<br><br>And, in June, Joe and I are excited to invite leaders and their spouses to Los Angeles, California, for the Summit of the Americas.</p>



<p>At the summit, our leaders have an ambitious agenda to come together on things like achieving an equitable and sustainable future, building health and pandemic resilience, and strengthening democratic government [governance].<br><br>But let &#8212; today, let me say this: The United States stands with you, the people of Ecuador &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and everyone who believes in education and health, democracy and justice, and working together to build a stronger world for us all.<br><br>There are moments that transcend words; it is often the language of motherhood: A deep ache that just runs down the slope of her shoulders that says, “My child is in danger, and I don’t know what to do.”&nbsp; Or the shift of a jaw, set in determination &#8212; a small shadow that tells the world, “There is nothing &#8212; nothing &#8212; I wouldn’t do to keep my children safe.”<br><br>Sometimes it’s a sigh that resonates from a place I know well, somewhere hidden inside of all parents, where we keep memories of first steps and the sweet, familiar scent of your child resting in your arms.&nbsp; Or it’s a smile that has seen the hard edges of the world but bends towards hope.</p>



<p>No one needs to translate that strength, that yearning, that love.<br><br>Every terrified mother or father, every hungry child, every hopeful student and hardworking person who dreams of a better world, they’re not just “other people.”&nbsp; The threads of their lives are tied to ours, no matter how far apart we are.<br><br>No one can heal the world’s wounds alone &#8212; not the United States, not Ecuador.&nbsp; But we can be the arms of welcome and the hands of kindness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can stand shoulder-to-shoulder and lift each other when we fall.&nbsp; We can and we will.&nbsp; And we will build a better world together.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Thank you, and may God bless you.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>END                    2:35 P.M. ECT</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden Administration Approves First Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/biden-administration-approves-first-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 22:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Department of Defense (DOD) is sourcing the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)’s request for Operation Fly Formula to transport Nestlé S.A. formula from Zurich, Switzerland to Plainfield, Indiana. DOD is actively working the request to identify commercial aircraft. The Operation Fly Formula shipments will transport the equivalent of up to 1.5 million 8-ounce&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Department of Defense (DOD) is sourcing the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)’s request for Operation Fly Formula to transport Nestlé S.A. formula from Zurich, Switzerland to Plainfield, Indiana. DOD is actively working the request to identify commercial aircraft.</p>



<p>The Operation Fly Formula shipments will transport the equivalent of up to 1.5 million 8-ounce bottles of three formulas—Alfamino® Infant, Alfamino® Junior, and Gerber Good Start® Extensive HA—all of which are hypoallergenic formulas for children with cow’s milk protein allergy. These formulas have been prioritized because they serve a critical medical purpose and are in short supply in the United States because of the Abbott Sturgis plant closure. These shipments will include approximately 246 pallets.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, USDA and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) are authorized to use DOD-contracted commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. In addition, President Biden has directed his Administration to take a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to reopen Abbott Nutrition’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance to allow major formula manufacturers to safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Alfamino.png" alt="" class="wp-image-53631" width="356" height="207" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Alfamino.png 820w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Alfamino.png?resize=615,357 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Alfamino.png?resize=768,446 768w" sizes="(max-width: 356px) 100vw, 356px" /><figcaption>Photo credit: Nestlé S.A.</figcaption></figure></div>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Gerber.png" alt="" class="wp-image-53632" width="128" height="190" /><figcaption>Photo credit: Nestlé S.A.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on FTC Vote to Protect Children’s&#160;Privacy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/statement-from-president-biden-on-ftc-vote-to-protect-childrens-privacy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 20:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the State of the Union I said that it is time to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children and demand tech companies stop collecting personal data on our children.  I want to commend the Federal Trade Commission for unanimously taking a big step in that direction today.    When children and parents access&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In the State of the Union I said that it is time to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children and demand tech companies stop collecting personal data on our children.  I want to commend the Federal Trade Commission for unanimously taking a big step in that direction today.    When children and parents access online educational products, they shouldn’t be forced to accept tracking and surveillance to do so.   The FTC is making it clear that such requirements would violate the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, and that the agency will be cracking down on companies that persist in exploiting our children to make money.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
