<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 15:26:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;4426</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/06/bill-signed-h-r-4426/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 15:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54780</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, June 6, 2022, the President signed into law:  H.R. 4426, the &#8220;Homeland Security for Children Act,&#8221; which requires the Department of Homeland Security to ensure that the needs of children are considered in homeland security planning. Thank you to Representatives Donald Payne Jr. and Bennie G. Thompson for their leadership.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, June 6, 2022, the President signed into law:<br> <br> H.R. 4426, the &#8220;Homeland Security for Children Act,&#8221; which requires the Department of Homeland Security to ensure that the needs of children are considered in homeland security planning.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Donald Payne Jr. and Bennie G. Thompson for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Takes Bold Executive Action to Spur Domestic Clean Energy&#160;Manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/fact-sheet-president-biden-takes-bold-executive-action-to-spur-domestic-clean-energy-manufacturing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 13:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Historic Actions Include Authorizing Defense Production Act to Lower Energy Costs, Strengthen Power Grid, and Create Good-Paying Jobs Today’s clean energy technologies are a critical part of the arsenal we must harness to lower energy costs for families, reduce risks to our power grid, and tackle the urgent crisis of a changing climate. From day&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Historic Actions Include Authorizing Defense Production Act to Lower Energy Costs, Strengthen Power Grid, and Create Good-Paying Jobs</em></p>



<p>Today’s clean energy technologies are a critical part of the arsenal we must harness to lower energy costs for families, reduce risks to our power grid, and tackle the urgent crisis of a changing climate. From day one, President Biden has mobilized investment in these critical technologies. Thanks to his clean energy and climate agenda, last year marked the largest deployment of solar, wind, and batteries in United States history, and our nation is now a magnet for investment in clean energy manufacturing.</p>



<p>Since President Biden took office, the private sector has committed over $100 billion in new private capital to make electric vehicles and batteries in the United States. We have made historic investments in clean hydrogen, nuclear, and other cutting-edge technologies. And companies are investing billions more to grow a new domestic offshore wind industry.</p>



<p>We are also now on track to triple domestic solar manufacturing capacity by 2024. The expansions to domestic solar manufacturing capacity announced since President Biden took office will grow the current base capacity of 7.5 gigawatts by an additional 15 gigawatts. This would total 22.5 gigawatts by the end of his first term – enough to enable more than 3.3 million homes to switch to clean solar energy each year.</p>



<p>While President Biden continues pushing Congress to pass clean energy investments and tax cuts, he is taking bold action to rapidly build on this progress and create a bridge to this American-made clean energy future. Today, President Biden is taking action to:</p>



<ul><li>Authorize use of the Defense Production Act (DPA) to accelerate domestic production of clean energy technologies, including solar panel parts;</li><li>Put the full power of federal procurement to work spurring additional domestic solar manufacturing capacity by directing the development of master supply agreements, including “super preference” status; and</li><li>Create a 24-month bridge as domestic manufacturing rapidly scales up to ensure the reliable supply of components that U.S. solar deployers need to construct clean energy projects and an electric grid for the 21<sup>st</sup> century, while reinforcing the integrity of our trade laws and processes.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Together, these actions will spur domestic manufacturing, construction projects, and good-paying jobs – all while cutting energy costs for families, strengthening our grid, and tackling climate change and environmental injustice. With a stronger clean energy arsenal, the United States can be an even stronger partner to our allies, especially in the face of Putin’s war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>The stakes could not be higher. That is why President Biden also continues to urge Congress to quickly pass tax cuts and additional investments that advance U.S. clean energy manufacturing and deployment. Failing to take these actions would deny consumers access to cost-cutting clean energy options, add risks to our power grid, and stall domestic clean energy construction projects that are critical to tackling the climate crisis. At the same time, President Biden will keep using his executive authority to take bold action to build an American-made clean energy future.</p>



<p><strong><u>INVOKING THE DEFENSE PRODUCTION ACT FOR CLEAN ENERGY</u></strong></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is authorizing the use of the Defense Production Act (DPA) to accelerate domestic production of clean energy technologies – unlocking new powers to meet this moment. Specifically, the President is authorizing the Department of Energy to use the DPA to rapidly expand American manufacturing of five critical clean energy technologies:</p>



<ul><li>Solar panel parts like photovoltaic modules and module components;</li><li>Building insulation;</li><li>Heat pumps, which heat and cool buildings super efficiently;</li><li>Equipment for making and using clean electricity-generated fuels, including electrolyzers, fuel cells, and related platinum group metals; and</li><li>Critical power grid infrastructure like transformers.</li></ul>



<p>In deploying the DPA, the Biden-Harris Administration will strongly encourage the use of strong labor standards, including project labor agreements and community benefits agreements that offer wages at or above the prevailing rate and include local hire provisions. The Administration also will strongly encourage projects with environmental justice outcomes that empower the clean energy transition in low-income communities historically overburdened by legacy pollution.</p>



<p>Following this announcement, the White House and the Department of Energy will convene relevant industry, labor, environmental justice, and other key stakeholders as we maximize the impact of the DPA tools made available by President Biden’s actions and strengthen domestic clean energy manufacturing.</p>



<p><strong><u>BOOSTING MADE-IN-AMERICA CLEAN ENERGY WITH FEDERAL PROCUREMENT</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden is also putting the full power of federal procurement to work spurring additional domestic solar manufacturing capacity. Today, the President directed the development of two innovative tools to accelerate Made-in-America clean energy:</p>



<ul><li>Master Supply Agreements for domestically manufactured solar systems to increase the speed and efficiency with which domestic clean electricity providers can sell their products to the U.S. Government; and</li><li>So-called “Super Preferences” to apply domestic content standards for federal procurement of solar systems, including domestically manufactured solar photovoltaic components, consistent with the Buy American Act.</li></ul>



<p>These federal procurement measures can stimulate demand for up to a gigawatt of domestically produced solar modules in the near term, and up to 10 gigawatts over the next decade from U.S. government demand alone. To further increase the impact of these actions, the Administration will also partner with state and local governments and municipal utilities in these innovative arrangements – increasing the potential market impact over the next decade to as much as over 100 gigawatts. These procurement actions will provide a significant demand anchor for a revitalized domestic solar manufacturing industry.</p>



<p><strong><u>SUPPORT FOR U.S. GRID-STRENGTHENING, CLEAN ENERGY CONSTRUCTION PROJECTS </u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Because of private investor confidence in President Biden’s leadership and our national commitment to a clean energy future, the United States is now on track to triple its solar manufacturing capacity by 2024. The expansions to domestic solar manufacturing capacity announced since the President took office will grow the current 7.5 gigawatts of capacity by an additional 15 gigawatts of capacity, for a total of 22.5 gigawatts by the end of his first term – enough to enable more than 3.3 million homes to switch to clean solar energy every year. To rapidly build on this progress and create a bridge to this American-made clean energy future, we need to boost short-term solar panel supply to support construction projects in the United States right now. This is because grid operators around the country are relying on planned solar projects to come online to ensure there is sufficient power to meet demand, and to ensure we can continue to deploy solar at the rates needed to keep us on track to meet the President’s climate goals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, President Biden is using his powers to create a 24-month bridge for certain solar imports while reinforcing the integrity of our trade laws and processes. Specifically, the President is:</p>



<ul><li>Temporarily facilitating U.S. solar deployers’ ability to source solar modules and cells from Cambodia, Malaysia, Thailand, and Vietnam by providing that those components can be imported free of certain duties for 24 months in order to ensure the U.S. has access to a sufficient supply of solar modules to meet electricity generation needs while domestic manufacturing scales up; and</li><li>Reinforcing his commitment to safeguarding the integrity and independence of all ongoing trade investigations by career officials at the Department of Commerce and recognizing the vital role these processes play in strengthening our economy.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>ADDITIONAL STEPS TO CUT COSTS, SUPPORT GOOD-PAYING JOBS, AND ADVANCE ENVIRONMENTAL JUSTICE</u></strong></p>



<p>Today’s actions build on this Administration’s existing initiatives to grow domestic clean energy innovation and manufacturing and to lower energy costs for Americans, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Permitting More Clean Energy on Public Lands.</strong> As part of the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-permitting-action-plan-to-accelerate-and-deliver-infrastructure-projects-on-time-on-task-and-on-budget/">Biden-Harris Permitting Action Plan</a>, a new five-agency collaboration is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/12/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-races-to-deploy-clean-energy-that-creates-jobs-and-lowers-costs/">expediting reviews of clean energy projects on public lands</a> through the Department of the Interior, helping us race ahead toward permitting at least 25 gigawatts by 2025&nbsp;–&nbsp;enough to power around five million homes. These actions have already <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-outlines-roadmap-continued-renewable-energy-progress-public-lands">increased</a> clean energy permitting activities by 35 percent, including major solar <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-advances-three-solar-projects-california-marking-significant">project approvals</a> and <a href="https://www.blm.gov/press-release/bureau-land-management-utah-issues-first-competitive-solar-leases">leases</a>. We have also launched five new Renewable Energy Coordination Offices and reduced rents and fees by more than 50 percent for solar and wind projects on public lands.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Boosting Community-Based Clean Energy in Cities and Rural Areas. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration is helping 17 local communities remove red tape with the <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-kicks-summer-solar-2021-tool-fast-tracks-solar-power-communities-nationwide">SolarAPP+ online tool</a> to enable same-day approvals for residential solar installation permits, and an additional 400 interested communities are in the pipeline. The National Climate Task Force launched new initiatives on increasing deployment of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-creates-cost-saving-clean-energy-opportunities-to-combat-climate-crisis/">Distributed Energy Resources</a>, including rooftop solar, with a focus on bringing the benefits of these projects to underserved communities. The United States Department of Agriculture provided the largest-ever investment in rural renewable energy last year. In addition, the Department of Energy and the Department of Health and Human Services are partnering to develop and pilot a digital platform that will connect customers who are eligible for the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program with community solar subscriptions, to further reduce customer energy costs. Likewise, the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development is working with municipalities to enable residents of affordable housing to directly benefit from low-cost community solar power without seeing a rent increase or adjustment to their utility allowance.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting a Diverse Solar Workforce with Good-Paying Jobs, including pathways to stable careers with the free and fair choice to join a union.</strong>&nbsp;Solar industry jobs consistently rank among the top fastest-growing in the nation, and many require only a high school education or GED. The Economic Development Administration recently awarded funding to support solar employment training in tribal and coal-impacted communities. In addition, the Department of Energy has issued a Request for Information&nbsp;and hosted six workshops&nbsp;to&nbsp;determine common goals and needs from&nbsp;stakeholders, including industry,&nbsp;unions, and&nbsp;training organizations. DOE will continue to explore these issues, including by providing funding, new collaborations with industry, other federal agencies, and state-based job boards to develop&nbsp;equitable&nbsp;worker-centric training and education programs, work-based learning opportunities, and support services such as career counseling, mentorship, and job readiness programs.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Developing</strong><strong> Clean Energy Domestic Manufacturing for Export and Building Capacity in Allied Nations. </strong>The Export-Import Bank of the United States (EXIM) Make More in America Initiative, approved by the EXIM board in April, will prioritize investments to expand clean energy manufacturing. The U.S. International Development Finance Corporation supports building resilient clean energy manufacturing supply chains in allied nations around the world, reducing global dependence on China.</li><li><strong>Investing in Clean Energy for Resilience in Puerto Rico: </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration joined forces with the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico to advance dozens of solar energy projects that will enable Puerto Rico to meet its target of 100%&nbsp;renewable&nbsp;electricity, while improving power sector resilience and increasing access to more affordable energy and cleaner air.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Health Policy and Advocacy&#160;Groups</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-health-policy-and-advocacy-groups/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 13:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week, the White House Gender Policy Council, the White House Domestic Policy Council, and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with national health policy and advocacy groups on protecting access to health care, including access to abortion.&#160; Participants discussed the health care crisis that the nation will face if&#160;Roe v.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Last week, the White House Gender Policy Council, the White House Domestic Policy Council, and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with national health policy and advocacy groups on protecting access to health care, including access to abortion.&nbsp; Participants discussed the health care crisis that the nation will face if&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade</em>&nbsp;is overturned and underscored that all individuals have a right to make decisions about their health and well-being. &nbsp;They also discussed access to reproductive health care as an issue of health equity and economic security and highlighted the disproportionate impact that restrictions have on underserved communities.&nbsp;Administration officials affirmed the President’s strong commitment to reproductive rights and committed to continued engagement and partnership with these groups.Participants included representatives from:</p>



<ul><li>Center for American Progress </li><li>Community Catalyst </li><li>Families USA </li><li>Protect Our Care </li><li>Young Invincibles</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before Air Force Two&#160;Departure </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-air-force-two-departure-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reno-Tahoe International AirportReno, Nevada Q    Do you have any confidence Congress can get something real done on guns? THE VICE PRESIDENT:  I really hope and pray that they do.  And I have a great deal of confidence in people like Chris Murphy.  And I know that &#8212; that he is sincerely working at this in a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Reno-Tahoe International Airport<br><em>Reno, Nevada</em></em></p>



<p>Q    Do you have any confidence Congress can get something real done on guns?<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  I really hope and pray that they do.  And I have a great deal of confidence in people like Chris Murphy.  And I know that &#8212; that he is sincerely working at this in a bipartisan way, which is really the only way we&#8217;re going to be able to get anything done.<br><br>You know, I temper my optimism with, you know, knowing that when Sandy Hook happened, nothing happened.  But, you know, I &#8212; I do believe that people can learn, and I do believe that people can revisit an issue like this and perhaps have a change of heart and mind.  So, I remain optimistic. <br> <br>So, thank you.<br><br>                                END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the 90th Annual Meeting of the U.S. Conference of&#160;Mayors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-90th-annual-meeting-of-the-u-s-conference-of-mayors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Peppermill ResortReno, Nevada 12:52 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon. Thank you, Mayor Suarez, for your introduction, for your work.  It is good to see you again.  You have been an extraordinary leader not only for your city, but in our country.  So, thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The Peppermill Resort<br><em>Reno, Nevada</em></em></p>



<p>12:52 P.M. PDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon.<br> <br>Thank you, Mayor Suarez, for your introduction, for your work.  It is good to see you again.  You have been an extraordinary leader not only for your city, but in our country.  So, thank you. <br> <br>Mayor Schieve, thank you for hosting us.  It is so good to be back in Reno. <br> <br>And to everyone, it is my honor to be with you this afternoon. <br> <br>You, our mayors &#8212; you are leaders not only for the constituents that elected you, but, I think if weren’t clear before the last couple of years, it is clear to everyone now you are not only local leaders, you are national leaders who show such courage, conviction, and fortitude during some of the most difficult times.<br> <br>And so, I’m here, most of all, to thank you all for what you do, what you have been doing, and what you are committed to do. <br> <br>As many of you probably know, I spent the first 20 years of my career in local government.  And throughout the years, I have partnered with mayors in every public office I’ve held &#8212; from my time as the elected District Attorney of San Francisco, to being Attorney General of California, and a United States Senator, and, now, of course, as Vice President.<br> <br>In fact, since first becoming Vice President a little over a year ago, I have met with &#8212; as I have counted it, roughly &#8212; so far, I’ve met with nearly 60 mayors.<br> <br>All that to say: I know what you all do and I know how important it is.  And I know how personal it is.  As a mayor, your work does not stop at the end of the day when you walk out of City Hall.  Your work is full time. <br> <br>It finds you at the grocery store &#8212; I know &#8212; (laughs) &#8211;when a retiree may come up to you to tell you about that streetlight that’s out on his block.  (Applause.)  I know.  (Laughs.)<br> <br>Your work finds you at your child or your grandchild’s basketball game when the assistant coach wants to know when his neighborhood is getting high-speed Internet.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>Your work finds you at your place of worship when a young mother will ask you how to get guns out of the wrong hands.<br> <br>People look to you to solve problems.  And because you are so present where you work and lead, you often have the experience of people literally searching your eyes to figure out if everything is going to be okay &#8212; even when sometimes you may not be sure.  But you still keep getting up and getting out there and making it work.<br> <br>And that is why President Joe Biden and I are honored to partner with America’s mayors to continue to build our nation.<br> <br>When we took office, as many of you remember, our economy and the pandemic &#8212; well, things weren’t looking good; in fact, in many ways, heading in the wrong direction. <br> <br>But our administration worked with you to get our country back on track.  We worked together to help millions of people who, at the time, were facing eviction to stay in their homes. <br> <br>We worked together to make sure families had enough food to eat.  We worked together to help small businesses stay open or reopen their doors and retain their employees. <br> <br>And because of our work together, since the President and I took office, we have seen record job creation, record declines in unemployment, and a record increase in labor participation.  (Applause.)   <br> <br>Just yesterday, in fact, we learned that the long-term health of our Medicare and Social Security programs is stronger than it was a year ago.  And, of course, the jobs report that came out today proves that we continue to move in the right direction. <br> <br>Last month alone, we added 390,000 jobs, which is tremendous progress &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and happening as we see a shift from recovery to sustainable economic growth. <br> <br>All together, we have created nearly 9 million new jobs since taking office, which is a record-setting pace of job creation.  Unemployment is down to 3.6 percent.  And small business creation is growing at an historic rate &#8212; which means, of course, at a local level, more folks are starting a new business in your community than ever before.<br> <br>The backstory on this is that, within our first month in office, many of you will remember, the President and I asked you all to meet with us and to meet with us in the White House.  It was virtual, but it was a meeting in the White House; you were there.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>And we asked you &#8212; there was a reason for that meeting, and those meetings, because there were many.  We asked you what you needed.  Because, you see, as many of you know, the President and I, as I said &#8212; I did and he also started at local government.  So we know you all are &#8212; are &#8212; you &#8212; you got your finger on the pulse.  You’re right there on the ground.  So we knew you, our mayors, were some of the folks that could be most informative and helpful to us to ensure that we would do the right thing.<br> <br>And through those meetings, you told us exactly what it would take to help your communities get through the pandemic.  The result of that and that work together, that partnership was the American Rescue Plan.  (Applause.)<br> <br>The ARP &#8212; you know I’ve spent time in D.C.; we now got a lot of acronyms &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; so I’m going to say “ARP,” but it’s the American Rescue Plan.  One of the things that we talked about with you and we knew has, in many policy initiatives, been an issue and we needed to deal with it &#8212; the ARP dealt with one of these issues, which is the need to make sure there would be direct funding to cities.  (Applause.)  So we did that. <br> <br>And we did that because we also knew why it is important.  It is important because then you all, at a local level, could put that money to work immediately, which you did.  Because after the ARP passed, you used this money to get people vaccinated.  You used it to support frontline workers, to keep small businesses open, to address crime and keep communities safe, to re-open schools so that children could return to the classroom and parents could return to work. <br> <br>None of this would have happened without your work to craft and implement the ARP.  And so, I’m here to say, for so many reasons, again: Thank you.  Thank you for all you have done to enable the progress that we have made.<br> <br>Together, we are heading in the right direction &#8212; toward steady and stable growth.  But while our economy has recovered faster than anyone thought possible, it is also a fact, as we all are living and know, that supply has struggled to keep up with the demand for new goods and products.<br> <br>We have seen the global supply chain slow down because of the pandemic.  And we have seen the economic impact of Putin’s unprovoked war in Ukraine ripple across the world. <br> <br>Both of these factors have resulted in rising costs.  And people in your cities, in your towns are feeling the pinch and seeing higher prices from the pump &#8212; gas pump to the grocery store.<br> <br>The President and I are doing everything in our power to lower the cost of the things that matter most for American families, and that includes the work that we still, together, must fight to achieve, such as bringing down the cost of childcare.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We believe strongly if we are to have a strong workforce, we must recognize that we must support working parents and their ability to parent.  So we have been fighting to say that for parents making a certain income and less than a certain income, they should not have to pay more than 7 percent of their income in child support.<br> <br>We are fighting for eldercare and affordable eldercare &#8212; bringing down the cost of eldercare.  And we are for fighting to make sure that we lower the cost of prescription drugs like insulin, which we should cap at $35 a month.  (Applause.) <br> <br>We are fighting to lower the cost of gas, including an historic step to blunt the increase in gas prices by releasing 1 million barrels a day from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve. <br> <br>We are already lowering the cost of high-speed Internet.  In fact, just last month, I announced that nearly 40 percent of American households are now eligible to receive a discount of $30 off their Internet bill each month.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And I will note that this happened, getting that in the infrastructure law happened because you all joined our fight to include bipartisan work around having high-speed Internet and affordable broadband in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.  And in so doing, you all helped put real money in the pockets of Americans. <br> <br>As a mayor, you understand how much rising costs impact members of your community because, again, you are deeply connected to the day-to-day lives of your constituents.  You see firsthand how these costs create uncertainty about the future for many people. <br> <br>This uncertainty is made worse by the existential challenges that societies around the world right now are grappling with. <br> <br>As Vice President, I have met with dozens of world leaders and have traveled to many places to sit down and meet with our allies and our partners.  And I can tell you this: There is a sense among all that we currently live in an unsettled world.   <br> <br>We see this most clearly in Ukraine, where the long-established principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity now rest on shaky ground, and we also see it here at home.  We also see it here at home where we are once again forced to defend fundamental principles that we hoped were well established.  Principles like the freedom to vote; the rights of women to make decisions about their own bodies &#8212; (applause); even &#8212; even questioning what constitutes the truth.<br> <br>The American people are grappling with these issues at a time when they also face immediate concerns about safety and security and about attacks on their communities that keep happening again and again. <br> <br>Mayors, you step up when horrific acts of violence shake us to our core, and you see firsthand how the hate that fuels these acts is manifesting itself in our communities.  There’s a through-line from what happened at Tops Market in Buffalo to what happened at those spas and parlors across Atlanta, at Pulse nightclub in Orlando, at the Tree of Life synagogue in Pittsburgh. <br> <br>Our country is facing what might be considered an epidemic of hate where people are being targeted just because of who they are &#8212; because of their race, because of their ethnicity, their gender, their religion, their sexual orientation. <br> <br>This then is a moment that requires all of us &#8212; as leaders, as citizens of a society &#8212; a civil society &#8212; to stand up and say: Enough is enough.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And we must speak truth and be honest as mayors &#8212; because your work does not allow you to be anything but practical.  No.  Well, we must speak honestly about what is happening and agree that the hate we see is &#8212; is not new.  There have always been those who see diversity and inclusion not as the strength we know it to be, but as a weakness. <br> <br>But we also cannot deny that this moment feels different and that data shows us, in the last couple of years, more hate incidents have happened now than at any other point in the last 20 years. <br> <br>Our interconnected world has now meant that bad actors can find each other online.  It has given space for hate to flourish and provided demagogues with a megaphone to inflame these tensions. <br> <br>Let us not allow those who are motivated by hate to separate us or to make us feel fear.  (Applause.)  Let us not allow that. <br> <br>Instead, as we all know, it is a time to renew our commitment to fight for unity; to remind our communities that we all have so much more in common than what separates us; that if we are to maximize our strength as a nation, we must find a way to commit to come together with a principle that includes believing that a harm against any one of us is a harm against all of us and, therefore, that no one should be made to fight alone.<br> <br>To combat hate, we cannot be silent and we must have the courage to speak truth about what fuels these crimes as we work to come together as a society. <br> <br>And so let us speak out.  No 86-year-old should fear for her safety to go to the grocery store.  No nine-year-old should be afraid to go to school.  And no 18-year-old should be able to buy a weapon of war.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, the President &#8212; the President spoke last night, and he said &#8212; and I think many of us know and agree: We need to pass  commonsense gun safety laws &#8212; common sense.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We need to take action.  And we know it is even more clear this day, just after the massacre of those 19 babies in Uvalde, after the killing just two days ago in Tulsa of 4 people, and after the countless lives lost to gun violence every day on streets across America.<br> <br>So, it’s clear that we must renew the assault weapons ban.  We must expand &#8212; (applause) &#8212; background checks.  We must repeal the liability shield that prote- &#8212; protects gun manufacturers.   And we must pass &#8212; (applause) &#8212; red-flag laws to prevent people from possessing firearms if they are a danger to themselves or others.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And finally, the United States Senate must confirm a permanent Director to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobi- &#8212; Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives &#8212; ATF.  (Applause.)  Because it’s been a long time, guys, since there’s been a permanent director there.  And that organization knows best how these steps will protect our communities.<br> <br>So here’s the thing.  The U.S. Conference of Mayors has been a strong advocate on so many of these issues &#8212; on sensible gun laws, by my count, for well over half a century.<br> <br>And so, again, I thank you.  And, in conclusion, I ask you: Please continue to make your voices heard.  Please continue to use your bully pulpit to fight for safer communities, for more economic opportunity, and for all the things that you so uniquely understand and know that our families need to succeed and to thrive.<br> <br>And I know that each of you is up to this challenge, because you are “The Mayor.”  (Laughter and applause.)  You deliver each and every day, and you always get the job done. <br> <br>God bless our mayors.  And God bless America.  Thank you.  <br> <br>                          END                 1:14 P.M. PDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with State Legislative Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/03/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-state-legislative-leaders-on-reproductive-rights-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 21:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, hosted a meeting with state legislative leaders in Kansas, Louisiana, and North Carolina on efforts to defend reproductive health and rights. Legislative leaders discussed the status of ongoing attacks in these states on reproductive rights, as well&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, hosted a meeting with state legislative leaders in Kansas, Louisiana, and North Carolina on efforts to defend reproductive health and rights.</p>



<p>Legislative leaders discussed the status of ongoing attacks in these states on reproductive rights, as well as their efforts to protect access to critical reproductive health care. On August 2, 2022, Kansans will vote on a ballot measure that would strip the right to abortion from the state constitution. The Kansas Supreme Court has twice ruled that the Kansas state constitution guarantees the fundamental right to abortion. Louisiana’s legislature will adjourn in a matter of days, and multiple bills are currently circulating that would undercut women’s rights. In North Carolina, ongoing work is required to protect access to care. &nbsp;White House Senior Officials thanked participants for their leadership and efforts to defend reproductive freedom.</p>



<p>Today’s engagement follows <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/24/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-state-legislative-leaders-on-reproductive-rights/">a meeting senior White House officials held last week</a> with legislators who are advancing&nbsp; legislation to protect reproductive rights.</p>



<p>State legislative leaders from today’s meeting included:</p>



<ul><li>North Carolina House Democratic Leader Robert Reives</li><li>North Carolina Representative Julie Von Haefen</li><li>Kansas Senate Minority Leader Dinah Sykes</li><li>Kansas House Minority Whip Stephanie Clayton</li><li>Kansas Senate Minority Whip Pat Pettey</li><li>Kansas House Minority Caucus Chair Barbara Ballard</li><li>Kansas Senate Agenda Chair Marci Francisco</li><li>Kansas Representative Sydney Carlin</li><li>Kansas Representative Gail Finney</li><li>Kansas Representative Christina Haswood</li><li>Louisiana Representative Mandie Landry</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Sections 1209 and 1236 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015, as&#160;Amended</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/03/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-sections-1209-and-1236-of-the-national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2015-as-amended/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 19:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegation of Authority Under Sections 1209 and 1236 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015, as Amended By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;301 of title 3, United States Code,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegation of Authority Under Sections 1209 and 1236 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015, as Amended</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of Defense the authority and functions vested in the President by sections 1209(l)(3) and 1236(o) of the Carl&nbsp;Levin and Howard P. &#8220;Buck&#8221; McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 (Public Law 113-291, 128 Stat. 3292), as amended, to waive certain limitations on the cost of construction and repair projects in support of the Counter-ISIS campaign in Iraq and Syria, including making any determinations and submitting any congressional notifications required for such waivers.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/03/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:  Nate Fick, Nominee for Ambassador at Large for Cyberspace and Digital Policy Daniel N. Rosenblum, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Kazakhstan Kathleen Ann Kavalec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration: </p>



<ul><li>Nate Fick, Nominee for Ambassador at Large for Cyberspace and Digital Policy</li><li>Daniel N. Rosenblum, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Kazakhstan</li><li>Kathleen Ann Kavalec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Romania</li><li>Richard K. Delmar, Nominee for the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury</li><li>Karla Gilbride, Nominee for General Counsel of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</li><li>Terrence Edwards, Nominee for Inspector General for the National Reconnaissance Office</li><li>Richard E. DiZinno, Nominee for Member of the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board</li><li>Adam Wade White, Nominee for Member of the Tennessee Valley Authority Board of Directors</li><li>William Renick Sr., Nominee for Member of the Tennessee Valley Authority Board of Directors</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Nate Fick, Nominee for Ambassador at Large for Cyberspace and Digital Policy</u></strong></p>



<p>Nate Fick leads Elastic’s information security business globally as Vice President, Security Strategy.&nbsp;Previously, he was CEO of Endgame, a cybersecurity software company, from 2012 through its acquisition by Elastic in 2019.&nbsp;He also led Endgame’s professional services business through its acquisition by Accenture in 2017.&nbsp;Fick spent nearly a decade as an operating partner at Bessemer Venture Partners, where he worked with management teams to build technology businesses.&nbsp;He writes and speaks regularly on leadership, corporate governance, security and technology issues.&nbsp;Fick was named by Fast Company magazine as one of the “100 Most Creative People in Business” and Endgame was selected by Forbes as one of the “100 Best Cloud Companies in the World.”&nbsp;From 2009-2012, Fick was CEO of the Center for a New American Security (CNAS). While at CNAS, he launched the Center’s program on technology and national security, and oversaw work related to NATO readiness, diplomacy in the Indo-Pacific, and support for veterans and military families.&nbsp;Fick served as a Marine Corps infantry and reconnaissance officer, including combat tours in Afghanistan and Iraq.&nbsp;Fick graduated with high honors in Classics from Dartmouth College and holds an MPA from the Harvard Kennedy School and an MBA from the Harvard Business School.&nbsp; He serves as a board member of the Council on Foreign Relations, and on the Military and Veterans Advisory Council at JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Daniel N. Rosenblum, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Kazakhstan</u></strong></p>



<p>Daniel N. Rosenblum, a career member of the Senior Executive Service, has served as U.S. Ambassador to Uzbekistan since 2019.&nbsp;Prior to that, he was a Deputy Assistant Secretary in the State Department’s Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs where he managed U.S. policy and diplomatic relations with the five Central Asian states.&nbsp;Previously, Rosenblum served as Coordinator of U.S. Assistance to Europe, Eurasia and Central Asia, where he was responsible for ensuring the strategic and efficient expenditure of foreign aid budgets averaging over $1 billion annually.&nbsp;He also served as the primary U.S. government liaison with other international donors, including the European Union and multilateral development banks.&nbsp;Earlier, Rosenblum held the positions of Deputy Coordinator, Director of the Eurasia Division, and Special Advisor for Economic Programs in the Assistance Coordinator’s office.&nbsp;Before joining the State Department, Rosenblum spent six years at the Free Trade Union Institute (FTUI), where he managed U.S. government grants related to the post-Communist transition in Eastern Europe and the former Soviet Union.&nbsp;He managed the operation of field offices in Russia, Ukraine, Kazakhstan, and Poland. Rosenblum also worked as a legislative assistant to U.S. Senator Carl Levin, where he advised on foreign affairs and trade policy.&nbsp;Rosenblum received his B.A. in History from Yale University and an M.A. in Soviet Studies and International Economics from the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies.&nbsp;He speaks Russian.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kathleen Ann Kavalec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Romania</u></strong></p>



<p>Kathleen Ann Kavalec, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the Head of Mission at the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe (OSCE) Mission to Bosnia and Herzegovina, on detail from the Department of State since 2019. Previously, she served as Deputy Assistant Secretary in the State Department’s Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs.&nbsp;Prior to that, Kavalec was the Director of the Office of Russian Affairs and the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Mission UNESCO in Paris, France.&nbsp;Kavalec oversaw major U.S. foreign assistance programs as Deputy Coordinator for Assistance in the European Bureau, and as Director for Conflict Prevention in the Office of the Coordinator for Reconstruction and Stabilization.&nbsp;Kavalec’s other overseas assignments include service as Cultural Affairs Officer, U.S. Embassy Bucharest, Romania; Political Counselor, U.S. Embassy Kyiv, Ukraine; and Political Officer, U.S. Embassy Moscow, Russia (twice).&nbsp;In Washington, she served as a Legislative Management Officer in the Bureau of Legislative Affairs, and as Director of the Economic Unit in the Office of the Coordinator for Assistance for the New Independent States.&nbsp;A native of California, Kavalec earned her A.B. in Political Science from the University of California at Berkeley and a Master of Science in Foreign Service from Georgetown University in Washington, D.C.&nbsp;Kavalec is the recipient of numerous State Department awards, as well as the Presidential Rank Award.&nbsp;She speaks Romanian, Spanish, Portuguese, French, and Russian.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Richard K. Delmar, Nominee for the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Richard K. Delmar is the Deputy Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury.&nbsp;He has served as Acting Inspector General and as Counsel.&nbsp;Earlier in his career, Delmar served on active duty in the U.S. Navy Judge Advocate General’s Corps, as a trial attorney in the Department of Justice Tax Division, and as a tax litigator and criminal tax program manager with the Office of Chief Counsel at the Internal Revenue Service. Delmar is a graduate of Georgetown University, the New York University School of Law, and the Naval War College Off-Campus Graduate Program.&nbsp;He is a member of the District of Columbia Bar.</p>



<p><strong><u>Karla Gilbride, Nominee for General Counsel of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Karla Gilbride has litigated on behalf of workers and others denied an equal opportunity because of discriminatory barriers since graduating from Georgetown Law School in 2007. After clerking for Judge Ronald Gould on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, she spent three years at Disability Rights Advocates in Berkeley, CA, where she sought to ensure that people with disabilities received the accommodations they needed on professional licensing exams, and that disabled residents of Los Angeles had access to shelter, transportation and other governmental services in the event of a natural disaster. Gilbride formerly served as an Associate at Mehri &amp; Skalet PLLC in Washington, DC representing workers in discrimination and wage and hour cases, and also worked on a case under the Fair Housing Act to ensure that multi-family housing in Florida was accessible to residents with mobility disabilities.</p>



<p>Gilbride currently works at Public Justice, litigating cases and appeals on behalf of low-wage workers and others who are disproportionately harmed by procedural barriers. Her cases at Public Justice have focused on mandatory, pre-dispute arbitration provisions that prevent workers and consumers from using the public courts when they experience unfair pay, on-the-job harassment or other violations of law. She has successfully argued appeals in U.S. Courts of Appeals on the topic of arbitration, and recently won a unanimous Supreme Court decision involving arbitration. During the COVID-19 pandemic, she represented meatpacking workers at a Smithfield processing plant in Missouri and Amazon workers at a warehouse in New York.</p>



<p><strong><u>Terrence Edwards, Nominee for Inspector General for the National Reconnaissance Office</u></strong></p>



<p>Terrence Edwards is currently the Chief of Staff to the Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence. Prior to serving in this position, Edwards was the Deputy General Counsel for Management in the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, where he oversaw the provisioning of legal advice on a wide array of national security issues. Since 2005, Edwards has held a number of other legal positions within the federal government, including Senior Attorney at the National Security Agency, Senior Acquisition Attorney at the Communications Electronics Command and Attorney-Advisor at the Army Sustainment Command. Edwards has received several awards during his career, including the Presidential Rank Award.&nbsp;Edwards holds a J.D. from The Ohio State University, an M.S.B.A from Texas A&amp;M University Texarkana, and a B.S. from McNeese State University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Richard E. DiZinno, Nominee for Member of the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Richard E. DiZinno currently serves as the Vice President for Strategy, Policy, and Government Affairs at the National Insurance Crime Bureau (NICB). DiZinno oversees the formulation and implementation of NICB policy positions, coordinates strategic planning, and manages the government affairs team. Prior to NICB, DiZinno served as Associate Deputy Attorney General at the U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ), where he advised the Deputy Attorney General on significant national security matters. Before DOJ, he was Chief Counsel for National Security and Crime for the U.S. Senate’s Judiciary Committee. In that role, DiZinno helped shepherd the reauthorization of Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act in 2018; passage of the CLOUD Act, which established a process for law enforcement to request data in other countries; and Senate passage of the USA FREEDOM Act reauthorization in 2020.</p>



<p>DiZinno formerly served as an Assistant U.S. Attorney in the U.S. Attorney’s Office in the District of Columbia. While in the National Security section, he led investigations involving terrorist financing through large financial institutions, illegal exports of U.S.-origin goods, counterintelligence investigations of classified material, and international human smuggling operations. He tried over fifty cases to verdict over eight years. DiZinno spent four years as an Associate at Howrey LLP, a specialty litigation firm in D.C. DiZinno received a B.A. from the College of the Holy Cross, and attended the George Washington University School of Law. After law school, he served as a Judicial Assistant for Chief Judge Thomas Hogan of the U.S. District Court in D.C.</p>



<p><strong><u>Adam Wade White, Nominee for Member of the Tennessee Valley Authority Board of Directors</u></strong></p>



<p>Adam “Wade” White, a Lyon County native, is currently serving his 12th year as Lyon County Judge Executive. During his tenure as Judge Executive, Wade has been a recipient of multiple awards, such as the Kentucky Elected Official Ripple Effect issued by Keep the Tennessee River Beautiful Group. He was inducted into the Freshwater Fishing Hall of Fame in 2016 and in 2018, Wade initiated the “War on Carp” as Asian Carp were having a negative impact on Kentucky Lake and Lake Barkley. Wade graduated from the University of Kentucky in 1995.&nbsp;He currently lives in Lyon County, Kentucky, with his wife.</p>



<p><strong><u>William Renick Sr., Nominee for Member of the Tennessee Valley Authority Board of Directors</u></strong></p>



<p>William J. “Bill” Renick is currently the Chairman of the Commission on the Future of Northeast Mississippi. For the past 13 years, until June 30, 2021, he served as the Workforce Division Director at Three Rivers Planning and Development District in Pontotoc, leading the Mississippi Partnership Local Workforce Area which covers 27 counties in North Mississippi. Renick entered public service at the age of 18, when he was elected to the Board of Aldermen in Ashland, Mississippi and later was elected Mayor. He also previously served on the Benton County Board of Supervisors, and eventually the State Senate. Renick served as Chief-of-Staff to Lt. Governor Eddie Briggs (R-Mississippi) and later as Chief-of-Staff to Governor Ronnie Musgrove (D-Mississippi). In between those years of public service, Renick was Administrator of Holly Springs Memorial Hospital, President of the Retail Association of Mississippi, and Executive Director of the Marshall County Industrial Development Authority. Renick is a native of Ashland, Mississippi.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the May Jobs&#160;Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/03/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-may-jobs-report-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 16:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54723</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rehoboth Beach Convention CenterRehoboth Beach, Delaware 10:48 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning, everyone.&#160; With today’s excellent jobs report and unemployment remaining at a near-historic low of 3.6 percent, I want to speak very briefly today about our economy and what we’re doing to lower the costs for American families. I know that even with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rehoboth Beach Convention Center<br>Rehoboth Beach, Delaware</p>



<p>10:48 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; With today’s excellent jobs report and unemployment remaining at a near-historic low of 3.6 percent, I want to speak very briefly today about our economy and what we’re doing to lower the costs for American families.</p>



<p>I know that even with today’s good news, a lot of Americans remain anxious, and I understand the feeling.&nbsp; I grew up in a family about 100 miles from here that if &#8212; where if the price of gas went up, you felt it.&nbsp; It was a discussion at the kitchen table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there is no denying that high prices, particularly around gasoline and food, are a real problem for people</p>



<p>But there is every reason for the American people to feel confident that we’ll meet these challenges.&nbsp; Because of the enormous progress we’ve made on the economy, the Americans can tackle inflation from a position of strength.&nbsp; Still a problem, but we can tackle it from a position of strength.</p>



<p>That purpose that we’ve set out to accomplish and the progress we’ve made, I think, is critical.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the time I took office, about 16 months ago, the economy had stalled and COVID was out of control.</p>



<p>Today, thanks to the economic plan and the vaccination plan that my administration put into action, America has achieved the most robust recovery in modern history just two years removed from the worst economic crisis since the Great Depression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The job market is the strongest it’s been since just after World War Two.&nbsp; We’ve got more evidence of that today.&nbsp; We learned that in May the economy added another 390,000 new jobs, bringing the total since I took office to 8.7 million new jobs &#8212; an all-time record.</p>



<p>We learned that more Americans entered the labor force in May.&nbsp; In fact, working-age people have come back into the workforce at a faster rate in this recovery than at any point in the last 40 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That means that the unemployment rate is near historic lows.&nbsp; And the number of Americans on unemployment benefits has gone from record highs to record lows, with millions of Americans moving up to better jobs, with better pay.</p>



<p>And Amer- &#8212; and American manufacturing is booming: 600,000 new manufacturing jobs created since I took office.</p>



<p>But it isn’t only about jobs.&nbsp; Since I took office, families are carrying less debt; their average savings are up.</p>



<p>A recent survey from the Federal Reserve found that more Americans feel financially comfortable than at any time since the survey began in 2013.</p>



<p>That confidence and comfortability is part of the reason why Americans applied to start more new small businesses last year than ever before in American history.</p>



<p>And because of our historically strong growth, we have strengthened Medicare and Social Security programs that millions of American families rely on.</p>



<p>Yesterday, I learned that Social Security and Medicare trust funds will be able to pay benefits for longer than previously projected before we passed the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>The reason?&nbsp; A faster-than-expected recovery in jobs, earnings, economic growth has all strengthened the financial prospects for these bedrock programs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, America is stronger economic &#8212; in a stronger economic position today than just about any other country in the world.</p>



<p>Independent experts have projected that the U.S. economy could grow faster than China’s economy this year.&nbsp; That hasn’t happened since 1976, nearly one half century ago.</p>



<p>The point is this: We’ve laid an economic foundation that’s historically strong.&nbsp; And now, we’re moving forward to a new moment where we can build on that foundation, build a future of stable, steady growth so we can bring down inflation without sacrificing all the historic gains we’ve made.&nbsp; And that’s what we’re beginning to see in today’s jobs report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With today’s numbers, the jobs over the last three months have averaged about 400,000 jobs per month.&nbsp; That’s historically robust and a sign we’re beginning a shift to steady growth after rapidly recovering 600,000 jobs per month over the prior six months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as we move to a new period of stable, steady growth, we should expect to see more moderation.&nbsp; We aren’t likely to see the kind of blockbuster job reports month after month like we had over this past year, but that’s a good thing.&nbsp; That’s a sign of a healthy economy with steady growth, rising wages for working families, everyday costs easing up, and shrinking the deficit.</p>



<p>That stability puts us in a strong position to tackle what is clearly a problem: inflation.</p>



<p>I’ve been very clear that fighting inflation is my top economic priority.&nbsp; On Tuesday, I spoke about one element of my inflation plan: giving the Federal Reserve the space they need to operate.</p>



<p>Today, I’d like to address the two additional elements of my plan to tackle inflation:</p>



<p>One, bringing down the cost of everyday goods for families.</p>



<p>And two, bringing down the federal deficit at the same time.</p>



<p>Bringing down the costs &#8212; here’s where we stand: The two challenges on the minds of most working families are prices at the pump and prices at the grocery store.&nbsp; Both of these challenges have been directly exacerbated by Putin’s war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>The price of gas is up $1.40 since the beginning of the year when Putin began amassing troops at the Ukrainian border.&nbsp; This is the “Putin price hike.”</p>



<p>Putin’s war has raised the price of food because Ukraine and Russia are two of the world’s major breadbaskets for wheat and corn &#8212; the basic product for so many foods around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ukraine has 20 million tons of grain in storage right now, and it’s been in storage since the last harvest.&nbsp; Normally, that would have already been exported into the world market.&nbsp; But because of Putin’s invasion and a blockade of the port at which they could take that grain out for the rest of the world, it’s not.&nbsp; It’s not.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And look, I understand that families who are struggling probably don’t care why the prices are up.&nbsp; They just want them to go down.&nbsp; “Joe, what are you going to do to bring them down?”&nbsp; But it’s important that we understand the root of the problem so we can take steps to solve it.</p>



<p>I’ve been up front with the American people from the outset that there would be a cost here at home of Putin’s decision to brutally and savagely invade a sovereign nation.</p>



<p>But as your President, I remain committed to doing everything in my power to blunt the impact on American families, and that’s exactly what I’m doing.</p>



<p>I led the world to coordinate the largest release of global oil reserves in history &#8212; 240 million barrels &#8212; to boost global supply and keep prices from rising even more.</p>



<p>I directed the sale of gasoline using homegrown biofuels this summer.</p>



<p>And I’m working closely with our European partners to get more of the grain locked in Ukraine right now out into the world market, which could help bring down prices.&nbsp; There’s ways to do that over land, which we could talk about at another time.</p>



<p>But actions have already helped to blunt that &#8212; what would have been an even larger Putin price hike.</p>



<p>And as I said, I’m going to continue to use every tool available to me to further blunt those price hikes as we move forward.</p>



<p>But the fact is this: There’s more than one way to solve this problem.&nbsp; If food and gas prices are going to be elevated by Putin’s price hike, one way we can make things a little better for families is by helping them save on other basic items their family needs on a monthly basis, like their utility bills, their Internet bills, their prescription drug bills, and other costs like housing.</p>



<p>My goal is to make sure that at the end of the month families have a little more breathing room than they &#8212; than they have now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, here’s something we can do right now: Congress could help ease the costs for families right away by passing my clean energy investment proposal that I’ve proposed that’s been sitting there.&nbsp; Things like tax credits for businesses to produce clean energy and tax cuts for families to make their homes more energy efficient.&nbsp; That’s what it results in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I met with nearly a dozen CEOs of America’s largest utility companies, such as Southern Company and American Electric Power.&nbsp; They told me that if we pass the investments, they will make immediately lower &#8212; they’ll immediately lower the average family’s energy costs by about $500 a year.&nbsp; That would help a lot.&nbsp; That’d make up for a lot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the long run, it would help families make America truly energy independent so, in the future, American families are no longer subject to the whims of a dictator half a world away, controlling oil.</p>



<p>It’s not just utility bills, though.&nbsp; I’ve laid out a plan to lower prescription drug costs by giving Medicare the power to negotiate with the pharmaceutical companies and how much they can charge, just like they do with the Veterans Administration.&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, they say, “We’re not going to pay X &#8212; more than X amount of dollars for your insulin.”&nbsp; Well, they can decide not to sell it all &#8212; or they can sell it at the price that the government says they’ll pay for it, bringing down the average cost of prescription drugs.</p>



<p>By capping that cost of insulin, by the way, at no more than $35 a month.&nbsp; It costs them less than 10 bucks to make it.&nbsp; And some &#8212; in some families, it means hundreds of dollars a month and sometimes hundreds of dollars a year, depending on what the &#8212; what ailment they’re trying to deal with.<br><br>Someone with diab- &#8212; diabetes, for example, it’s hundreds of dollars per year.&nbsp; Someone with arthritis, it could be thousands of dollars per year.</p>



<p>I’ve laid out a plan to lower rent and mortgage costs &#8212; the largest cost most families face; around a third of a typical family’s budget &#8212; because we have a shortage of housing.&nbsp; Building more than a million more housing units and closing the shortfall in affordable housing in this country will do that.</p>



<p>I’ve laid out a plan to lower the cost of high-speed Internet by working with the 20 leading Internet service providers to cut their prices and raise their speeds.</p>



<p>For tens of millions of households, this could lower what they have to pay for high-speed Internet by $50 a month or more.&nbsp; And nearly 40 percent of households in America qualify for these savings.</p>



<p>And by the way, you can find out if you’d be eligible by visiting &#8212; by vi- &#8212; GetInternet.gov.&nbsp; GetInternet.gov.&nbsp; I’ll say it again: GetInternet.gov.&nbsp; See if you qualify.</p>



<p>I’ve laid out a plan to lower the cost of everyday goods that move through our supply chains to stores and families’ doorsteps.</p>



<p>For example, at the State of the Union, I called on Congress to crack down on foreign-owned shipping companies that have raised their prices to transport goods by as much as 1,000 percent.&nbsp; One thousand percent.&nbsp; And that obviously raises the cost of the goods on those ships to consumers.</p>



<p>The Senate has passed legislation, and I am hopeful the House can do the same to send me legislation in the coming weeks to crack down on these companies and help lower overall costs.</p>



<p>And my plan does all this without raising a penny in taxes on people making less than $400,000 a year and without raising the deficit at all by taxing the super wealthy and big corporations, like the 55 major corporations that don’t pay a single penny in taxes, even though they had a &#8212; $40 billion in profits.</p>



<p>The point is this: I’m doing everything I can on my own to help working families during this stretch of higher prices.&nbsp; And I’m going to &#8212; I’m going to continue to do that.</p>



<p>But Congress needs to act as well.&nbsp; We can do so much more if we come together to lower the costs for American families.</p>



<p>But my congressional Republican friends, led by Rick Scott, have a different approach.&nbsp; He’s actually introduced a plan.&nbsp; He wants to raise taxes on working families by an average of $1,500 a year; put Medicare and Social Security &#8212; Medicaid &#8212; excuse me &#8212; Social Security and Medicaid on the chopping block every five years.&nbsp; In other words: Every five years, they’re &#8212; they’re going no longer exist unless they vote them back into existence.</p>



<p>I disagree with that.&nbsp; What in God’s name are they doing?</p>



<p>And I’ll work with anyone &#8212; Democrat, Republican, independent &#8212; to deliver real solutions and real savings for the American people, not take money out of their pockets.</p>



<p>Now, the other melem- &#8212; other element I’d like to address that has impacts on inflation is to lower the deficit.&nbsp; The reason this matters to families is because reducing the deficit is another way to ease inflation.</p>



<p>My friends on the Republican side like to paint me as the “big spender.”&nbsp; But let’s look at the facts.&nbsp; Facts matter.&nbsp;<br><br>Under my predecessor, the deficit exploded, rising every single year he was in office.&nbsp; Under my plan, we’re on track to cut the federal deficit this year by $1.7 trillion.&nbsp; You hear me now?&nbsp; This year by $1.7 trillion.&nbsp; That’s a fact.&nbsp; The largest decline in American history.</p>



<p>And by the way, those aren’t White House projections.&nbsp; They come from the nonpartisan Congressional Budget Office that you in the press and everybody around the country legitimately quotes all the time.</p>



<p>That progress on tackling the deficit was not pre-ordained.&nbsp; It was my economic strategy built into our historic recovery.&nbsp; That we didn’t anticipate a war in Ukraine at the time.&nbsp; Historic economic growth that not only helped tens of millions of families move up, it has helped our federal deficit come down.</p>



<p>And now, because of that strategy, we’re on track for a deficit to take up a lower share of our economy than it did before the pandemic.</p>



<p>In fact, the Treasury Department is planning to pay down &#8212; pay down &#8212; the national debt this quarter, which never happened under my predecessor.&nbsp; Not once.&nbsp; Not once.&nbsp; Because, unlike my predecessor, the deficit has come down both years I’ve been here.<br><br>I’ve proposed a plan to keep shrinking that deficit by making commonsense reforms to our tax code, leveling the playing field internationally so that the biggest companies no longer have an incentive to shift jobs overseas &#8212; to shift them overseas to make their product because they get charged less in taxes and avoid paying their fair share of taxes here at home.&nbsp; We put together a multi-nation initiative that I’m hopeful will come into play at the G7.&nbsp;<br><br>And ending the outrageous unfairness of our tax system that allows billionaires &#8212; look, if you can make a billion dollars, I’m all for it.&nbsp; Just pay a little bit of your fair share, you know?&nbsp; Just pay your fair share.&nbsp; Billionaires pay a lower rate than a teacher or a firefighter.</p>



<p>The bottom line is this: Part of the reason I ran for President is because I was tired of trickle-down economics.&nbsp; It doesn’t work.</p>



<p>My plans have produced the strongest, fastest, most widespread economic recovery America has ever experienced, with record jobs, a new record of small businesses, and wages rising.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s the foundation for an economy that works for working families.</p>



<p>And because of that foundation, we’re better positioned than any country in the world to overcome the global inflation that we’re seeing and reach a new chapter of stable and steady growth.</p>



<p>So, let’s come together and focus on what’s the matter &#8212; on what matters.&nbsp; Let’s build on the extraordinary progress we’ve made.&nbsp; And let’s continue to build this economy from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; When that happens, everybody does well, including the very wealthy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; And God bless you.&nbsp; And I &#8212; God &#8212; may God protect our troops.</p>



<p>I’ll take a few questions.</p>



<p>Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, are you going to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Saudi Arabia, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me answer her &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, Elon Musk has asked &#8212; has said that he has a “super bad feeling” about the U.S. economy.&nbsp; He is laying off 10 percent of his workforce.&nbsp; What do you say to Elon Musk about his feeling about the economy?&nbsp; Jamie Dimon has said similar things.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, let me tell you.&nbsp; While Elon Musk is talking about that, Ford is increasing their investment overwhelmingly.&nbsp; I think Ford is increasing the investment in building new electric vehicles: 6,000 new employees &#8212; union employees, I might add &#8212; in the Midwest.</p>



<p>The former Chrysler Corporation, Stellantis, they&#8217;re also making similar investments in electric vehicles.</p>



<p>Intel is adding 20,000 new jobs for making computer chips.</p>



<p>So, you know, lots of luck on his trip to the Moon.&nbsp; I mean, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I mean, you know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212; are you going to go to Saudi Arabia, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m not sure whether I’m going.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I have no direct plans at the moment.&nbsp; But let me tell you that I have been engaged in trying to work with how we can bring more stability and peace to the Middle East.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there is a possibility that I would be going to meet with both the Israelis and the Ara- &#8212; some Arab countries at the time &#8212; including, I expect, would be Saudi Arabia &#8212; would be included in that if I did go.</p>



<p>But I have no direct plans at the moment.&nbsp; We’re looking at it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the Kingdom still a pariah, in your eyes?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not going to change my view on human rights.&nbsp; But as President of the United States, my job is to bring peace if I can &#8212; peace if I can.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what I&#8217;m going to try to do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, would you be open to meeting with the Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman if you do end up going to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, we&#8217;re getting way ahead of ourselves here.&nbsp; What I want to do is see to it that we diminish the likelihood that there&#8217;s a continuation of this &#8212; some of the senseless wars between Israel and the Arab nations.&nbsp; And that’s what I’m focused on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is OPEC doing enough on oil production?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, what I recently read and talking to my team that &#8212; they acknowledge that there is an oil shortage, and they have made an announcement, of late, that they&#8217;re going to increase production.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t know enough to know whether it&#8217;s enough, but I know it&#8217;s positive.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, does Ukraine have to cede territory to achieve some peace?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know, you’ve been always fair with me. The &#8212; from the beginning, I&#8217;ve said and I&#8217;ve been &#8212; not everyone has agreed with me &#8212; nothing about Ukraine without Ukraine.&nbsp; It’s their territory.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to tell them what they should and shouldn&#8217;t do.</p>



<p>But it appears to me that, at some point along the line, there&#8217;s going to have to be a negotiated settlement here.&nbsp; And what that entails, I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; I don’t think anybody knows at the time.</p>



<p>But in the meantime, we&#8217;re going to continue to put the &#8212; the Ukrainians in a position where they can defend themselves.</p>



<p>Thank you all so very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, will you go to the Hill next week on guns to meet with lawmakers?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; My staff is &#8212; my staff is dealing &#8212; and have been dealing constantly with every member of the House and Senate who is wanting to talk about guns.&nbsp; It’s been a constant interchange.&nbsp; And I’ve been constantly briefed.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll do what I can to try to see if we have some real progress.</p>



<p>Thank you. </p>



<p>11:08 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and COVID-&#8288;19 Response Coordinator Dr. Ashish&#160;Jha</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/02/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-covid-19-response-coordinator-dr-ashish-jha/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:57 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Hello, good afternoon.  Good afternoon. Good afternoon. Okay.&#160; So, today we have Dr. Jha, the White House COVID Coordinator.&#160; He&#8217;s going to talk about kids COVID vaccines.&#160; And so, he is only going to be here for &#8212; he has about 10, 15 minutes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:57 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Hello, good afternoon.  Good afternoon. Good afternoon.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; So, today we have Dr. Jha, the White House COVID Coordinator.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to talk about kids COVID vaccines.&nbsp; And so, he is only going to be here for &#8212; he has about 10, 15 minutes with us &#8212; I think 15 minutes, looking at the clock.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, he&#8217;s going to open up, and then he&#8217;ll take a few questions, and then we&#8217;ll start the briefing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We want to &#8212; we have a hard time out at 4:00 today, so we&#8217;re going to try and get out of here at 4:00.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for having me.&nbsp; It&#8217;s great to be back.&nbsp; Sorry, it&#8217;s me and not BTS.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>I want to take some time today to explain the timeline of what&#8217;s happening with vaccines for our youngest kids &#8212; for kids under five &#8212; and what parents and pediatricians and Americans should be expecting in the coming weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as you all know, the FDA is currently working through a rigorous and independent scientific process.&nbsp; As part of that, the FDA’s advisory committee &#8212; VRBPAC &#8212; will be meeting on June 14th and 15th.&nbsp; They will review the data submitted by Pfizer and Moderna for their vaccines, and we expect an FDA decision shortly after the advisory committee meeting.&nbsp; And we look forward to this process playing out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, as you all know, because we&#8217;ve been through this many times, the FDA authorization is not the final step in the process.&nbsp; Before vaccinations can begin, CDC must also issue its recommendations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If the FDA authorizes the vaccines, the CDC will have its advisory committee meetings and, ultimately, the CDC Director will make her recommendations.&nbsp; And we expect the CDC to make its dates for its advisory committee meetings public very, very soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let&#8217;s talk about what we know at this moment.&nbsp; We know that many, many parents are eager to vaccinate their youngest kids.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s important to do this right.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what this process has been all about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as I talk through the process today, I want to be very clear that I am not here to prejudge the outcome of the process.&nbsp; But the administration is hard at work planning all sorts of scenarios based on whatever the outcome is from the process that&#8217;s playing out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been working very closely with states, with local health departments, with pediatricians, family physicians, other healthcare providers, and pharmacies to get ready.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We started with the playbook we&#8217;ve used for a rollout of vaccines for other age groups.&nbsp; At the same time, we&#8217;re building this program to meet the specific needs of this specific age group.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We expect that the vast majority of these kids will be vaccinated by their primary care providers.&nbsp; Now, if and when FDA authorizes a vaccine, we&#8217;ll move from planning to execution.&nbsp; So let me highlight a few things of what that will look like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the good news is we have plenty of supply of both Pfizer and Moderna vaccines to start our vaccination program.&nbsp; And we are going to make 10 million doses available to states, pharmacies, and community health centers, and federal entities to order initially.</p>



<p>Starting tomorrow, states can begin to place their orders.&nbsp; We have asked states to distribute the initial tranche of doses to their highest-priority sites, including those serving the highest-risk children and hardest-to-reach areas.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve also asked them to prioritize sites that can handle large volumes, such as children&#8217;s hospitals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve encouraged states and providers to find ways to ensure that parents have access to these vaccines for their kids outside of normal work hours, because we want to make this as easy as possible for working parents and their families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, FDA authorization will allow us to start shipping doses.&nbsp; These doses are specifically formulated for these young kids.&nbsp; These doses will be shipped to thousands of sites across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let me go back and think through the timeline with all of you.&nbsp; VRBPAC meets on June 14th and 15th.&nbsp; We expect FDA to make its decision soon thereafter.&nbsp; Once FDA has authorized &#8212; if they have authorized vaccines &#8212; we can begin shipping.&nbsp; We expect some of the shipments to start arriving to &#8212; in their destination over that long weekend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember, Monday is an important federal holiday, and many doctor&#8217;s offices may be closed.&nbsp; And we can&#8217;t ship vaccines until FDA has authorized these vaccines.&nbsp; And vaccinations can&#8217;t start until CDC has issued its recommendations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we expect that vaccinations will begin in earnest as early as Tuesday, June 21st, and really roll on throughout that week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, it will take some time to ramp up the program and for vaccines to be more widely available.&nbsp; And as doses arrive in places throughout the country, more sites will have vaccines, more appointments will become available.&nbsp; And our expectation is that within weeks, every parent who wants their child to get vaccinated will be able to get an appointment.</p>



<p>We will of course do our part.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue monitoring.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to ship doses out as fast as possible.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to make sure that supply is always meeting demand.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to do everything we can to make it easy for providers and parents alike to get their kids vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let me just close with a few words about the bigger picture about the moment we’re in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s been a long two years.&nbsp; This is the last group of Americans who have not yet been eligible to get vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as we think about getting ready to vaccinate our youngest kids, it&#8217;s worth noting how much progress we&#8217;ve made: Two thirds of all Americans are now fully vaccinated, close to a third of all Americans are boosted, and highly effective treatment &#8212; effective treatments are widely available.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a result, when we look across the country, we see cases rising &#8212; nearly 100,000 cases a day.&nbsp; And yet we&#8217;re still seeing death numbers that are substantially &#8212; about 90 percent &#8212; lower than where they were when the President first took office.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, we know that COVID isn&#8217;t over.&nbsp; We still have work to do.&nbsp; But we have made tremendous progress.&nbsp; And what we know is that we&#8217;ve got to keep vaccinating, keep reaching people who have not gotten vaccinated, keep making treatments widely available.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because what we believe is that with science, with hard work, and with resources, we can continue to protect the American people, from our oldest to our youngest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m looking forward to questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Who has a question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s your expectation on when most kids will be vaccinated?&nbsp; Is it a matter of months?&nbsp; When &#8212; what&#8217;s your estimate?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, we don&#8217;t have an estimate of timelines of when most kids will be vaccinated.&nbsp; What we know is that, obviously, there are a lot of parents who are eager to get their kids vaccinated right away, and they will get vaccinated right away, within weeks, as I &#8212; as I laid out.</p>



<p>There are other parents who are waiting to see how things go.&nbsp; And I think what we have seen in the past is that they will come on board as they see their friends and family getting their kids vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think this is a process that is going to take some time, but we want to make sure that we always have adequate supply and access for parents when they want their kids vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I think you are well aware about how much frustration and anger there&#8217;s been from &#8212; from parents of young children &#8212; the fact we were talking about second boosters for much of the population before even this first one was available.&nbsp; I&#8217;m a parent of a four-year-old who got COVID while we sat around waiting for this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think one point, in all of that, that really is frustrating and raised a lot of questions for parents is why the FDA didn&#8217;t move to hold a hearing right away after Moderna applied, why it waited for Pfizer and Moderna.&nbsp; Can you just explain the thinking behind that delay?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; So, first of all, I have &#8212; I have a 10-year-old, so he has been able to get vaccinated, but I have a lot of friends who have kids under 5.&nbsp; So, let me just say, I feel the frustration and I certainly hear the frustration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Two things.&nbsp; First of all, the FDA makes its decisions on timelines really based on its ability to review the data, to do a careful analysis.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what they&#8217;ve been doing.&nbsp; I think they&#8217;ve done that throughout the entire pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you look at from the early days of the early adult vaccines through this one, they have moved expeditiously and &#8212; and they have made the determinations of when they can be ready to evaluate and when they can make a decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The specifics of it, you&#8217;re going to have to, I think, ultimately talk to the FDA, but I feel like they have moved very quickly to try to &#8212; to consume and analyze a very large tranche of data from &#8212; from Moderna.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, look, at the end of the day, we all want to move fast, but we want to get it right.&nbsp; And that has got to be priority number one, and that&#8217;s what I think the FDA has been focused on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Paxlovid, do you have any information you can share with us on how much Paxlovid has been used so far and how much is left, and whether Congress &#8212; or whether the U.S. is committed to completing its purchase of the 20 million courses?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have the numbers off the top of my head.&nbsp; What I will tell you is we&#8217;re getting out about 30,000 prescriptions a day right now.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s at the end of last &#8212; as of end of last week.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have this week&#8217;s data yet.&nbsp; So about 30,000 doses a day.</p>



<p>We obviously want to continue to expand access to Paxlovid for any high-risk person who is &#8212; who gets infected.&nbsp; We want to make sure they have access to it if they&#8217;re clinically eligible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, the President made a commitment to get 20 million doses, and we remain committed to making that happen.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about your COVID testing program, specifically the one that was launched to order COVID tests at home.&nbsp; Can you talk about what the demand has looked like lately &#8212; now that we&#8217;re seeing the up-and-down with cases is different than what we saw around Christmas; and what you&#8217;re doing and to preserve supply &#8212; I know that these tests eventually expire &#8212; what you&#8217;re doing to preserve supply should there be a big demand again?&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Good &#8212; great question.&nbsp; So, we launched that about two weeks ago, three weeks ago &#8212; I can&#8217;t remember the exact time &#8212; the third round of making tests available.</p>



<p>We actually saw quite a robust demand for that.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;ve had maybe 17, 18 million households order just in the last couple of weeks, so that &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the third round?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; On the &#8212; on round three.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s a lot.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s great.&nbsp; And it means that there are &#8212; people are still using these tests.&nbsp; If you&#8217;ve followed me the last two years, you know I&#8217;m a huge believer in making widespread testing widely available.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think getting people tests at home is a really important part of that.&nbsp; We feel that when you have cases rising, Americans want tests, we want to make those tests available.&nbsp; We also obviously want to make sure that as we have future &#8212; if and or when we have future surges of infections, we will have other tests available for Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you also talk about &#8212; the President was very big at the beginning of that program on equity and that these tests were going to be distributed to populations that were underserved, in addition to populations that might be more well-connected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve thought a lot about equity in this case &#8212; in other areas, too, but certainly on tests.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And so, the way we&#8217;ve done this is &#8212; I mean, obviously the website, but we can &#8212; you can make phone calls, which for some people is easier.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve distributed tests to food banks.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve distributed tests to Federally Qualified Health Centers.&nbsp; We have a whole series of efforts that we have had to make sure that the testing is getting out through a variety of different channels so that people who may not normally be able to access it in other contexts can get access to tests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t hear you &#8212; sorry, one last thing &#8212; I didn&#8217;t hear you say about tests that are expiring.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Oh.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know they must have shelf life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, so, with all these tests we’re &#8212; again, this is a standard issue.&nbsp; Anytime you have new products, they have a &#8212; initially they have a specific shelf life, and then as you do more testing, you can extend that shelf life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, these companies are working with FDA to look at long shelf life.&nbsp; But obviously, we&#8217;re always thinking about that, and making sure that they have &#8212; there&#8217;s plenty of shelf life for these products, as they said, in our stockpiles.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Are there &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Dr. Jha, what was the impact of the &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; any conversations about &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Department of Defense &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about second booster shots for under age 50?&nbsp; Are discussions right now about allowing those second booster shots?&nbsp; Are those conversations taking place?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; You know, so that&#8217;s a decision of the FDA and CDC.&nbsp; They&#8217;re always guided by evidence and data on that.&nbsp; All the data that I have seen &#8212; or most of the data I have seen is in people over 50 &#8212; really, in people over 60.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where the strongest data are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think those conversations are always ongoing.&nbsp; But I think the issue of looking at evidence and making a decision, that&#8217;s really something that the FDA is going to have to think about it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think where cases are right now, that second booster shot should be authorized for people under age 50?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; You know, that &#8212; I really do leave that up to FDA to decide based on, kind of, looking at the evidence.&nbsp; So, I &#8212; and I think they should be making that decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, last question, Tyler.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Do you feel confident that the U.S. has enough supplies for a potential summer surge?&nbsp; And at this point, what are your current predictions about what might happen in the South in the coming weeks and months?&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Supply of?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Vaccines, antiviral treatments, all &#8212; all the various things that are needed to treat COVID.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, so, because &#8212; because of prior funding, we purchased a decent amount of both vaccines and therapeutics.&nbsp; And so, I am very confident that whatever happens this summer, we will have enough tools, tests, treatments, vaccines to get us through the summer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The challenge is &#8212; and, again, we are in the &#8212; I&#8217;m less in the prediction business, more in the planning business.&nbsp; As we plan the fall and winter, and look at a variety of different scenarios, that&#8217;s where I started getting very, very concerned.</p>



<p>And if you want to ask what keeps me awake at night, it is that we are going to run out of vaccines.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to be able to have enough of the next generation of vaccines.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to run out of treatments.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to run out of diagnostic tests, probably in the late fall into winter, if we end up having a significant surge of infections.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We don&#8217;t have the resources to buy those things.&nbsp; And those purchases need to be made now.&nbsp; They cannot be made in the fall.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So if you&#8217;re wondering what is it that that really worries me &#8212; I think we have the tools for the summer.&nbsp; We will not have the tools for the fall and winter, unless Congress steps up and funds us.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And based on your modeling that you do in the government and with partners outside of it, what is your sense of what this potential surge might look like, both this summer and then when you warn that supplies might now &#8212; in the fall and into the winter?&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, so, there are &#8212; as you know, there are a lot of different models; they all come up with a variety of different answers.&nbsp; And we really look across all of them.&nbsp; And we try to plan across all the ones that we think are reasonable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There certainly are models out there that suggest that we could have a sizable wave of infections in the fall and winter, especially if we don&#8217;t have a vaccination campaign in the fall and winter.&nbsp; If we run out of treatments, if we don&#8217;t have enough diagnostic tests, we could be looking at a more complicated situation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we &#8212; those are &#8212; those are models that we look at.&nbsp; We plan for them.&nbsp; Again, as I said, I generally try not to worry too much about predicting what&#8217;s going to happen, and really focusing on planning for a variety of scenarios.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And given what we have in terms of treatments and vaccines and diagnostics, we do not have enough to get us through the fall and winter.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one last one on the vaccination campaign you mentioned.&nbsp; Are you preparing that most Americans who are not yet eligible for that third vaccine, you will &#8212; they will be encouraged to get a fourth one in the fall?&nbsp; And with that, will there be a new vaccine or a formula to adapt toward the newer variants that have emerged in recent months?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; So there were about three or four questions in there &#8212; embedded in there, all of which are FDA questions.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So let&#8217;s just &#8212; FDA is going to have to make decisions about: Do we formulate a new vaccine?&nbsp; There&#8217;s a VRBPAC meeting that&#8217;s going to happen in late June, I think, to look at exactly that question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Based on the data, they&#8217;re going to make determinations.&nbsp; CDC is going to decide who should get it, who should not.&nbsp; I mean, you guys know the process of how that&#8217;s going to play out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I’m just wondering, from your vantage point at the White House as the coordinator of all these different agencies, what your expectation would be.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; My &#8212; I am planning for all of those scenarios.&nbsp; I am pla- &#8212; we need to &#8212; because, again, we don&#8217;t get into the &#8212; we don&#8217;t decide what FDA will decide.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t decide what CDC will decide.&nbsp; They make those decisions.&nbsp; We need to plan for a variety of different scenarios, including planning for a next generation of vaccines for the fall and winter, which we want to make sure we have plenty of for every American.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will not have enough for every American without additional funding from Congress, but we are planning for those scenarios.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Doctor, do you believe all schools will and must be open this coming fall?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We got to go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, I unfor- &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Parents want to know that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; He has to go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; I’m sorry.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We’re over time.&nbsp; We’re over time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sorry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Doctor Jha, why are more boosted Americans having breakthrough cases than non-boosted?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, guys.&nbsp; I have a few things for you at the top.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; So, today, President Biden and Vice President Harris announced the launch of the White House Internship Program and that, for the first time in recent history, we’ll pay our interns.</p>



<p>Since the beginning of his administration, President Biden has committed to advancing equity and opening doors by waiting to launch the White House Internship Program until receiving the statutory authority from Congress to pay interns.&nbsp; President Biden was proud to sign bipartisan legislation earlier this year that provides this authority and funding.</p>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris know that for too long and too often, unpaid federal internships have been a barrier to hardworking and talented students and professionals, preventing many of them from contributing their talents and skills to the country.&nbsp; Paying White House interns will help ensure that those who receive internships at the White House reflect the diversity of America.</p>



<p>Starting today, prosp- &#8212; prospective candidates, as well as college and university administrators and faculty interested in the program can visit WhiteHouse.gov/intern to learn more about the program and apply for the fall 2022 session starting on Monday.</p>



<p> </p>



<p>As the President conveyed earlier, we welcome the announcement today of a continuation of the truce in the Yemen conflict.&nbsp; The last two months in Yemen, thanks to the truce brokered in April, have been among the most peaceful periods since this terrible war began seven years ago.&nbsp; Thousands of lives have been saved as fighting receded.</p>



<p>For the first time in seven years, Yemenis are able to fly from Sana’a to destinations outside of Yemen.&nbsp; We have also seen additional fuel ships moving through the Port of Hudaydah, helping ease Yemen’s fuel crisis.&nbsp; The parties to the conflict have now extended this truce for another two months, and it’s important that work &#8212; that we work from here to make it permanent.</p>



<p>This truce would not happen &#8212; has &#8212; if it was not &#8212; it would not be possible without cooperation &#8212; the cooperative diplomacy from across the region.&nbsp; We specifically recognize the leadership of King Salman and the Crown Prince of Saudi Arabia in helping to consolidate the truce.&nbsp; The Omani Sultan also played a central role in hosting and facilitating dialogue.&nbsp; Egypt and Jordan opened their airports to flights from Yemen over the past month, thereby enabling a key component of the truce process.</p>



<p>The United States will remain engaged in this process over the coming weeks and months.&nbsp; Ending the war in Yemen has been a priority of this administration, and we urge all parties to move expeditiously towards a comprehensive and inclusive peace process.&nbsp; Our diplomacy will not rest until a permanent settlement is in place, and we will continue to support regional diplomacy to de-escalation tensions &#8212; to de-escalate tensions and deter threats to our friends and partners in the Middle East region.</p>



<p> </p>



<p>As the President continues to prioritize reducing costs for families, making historic investments in our infrastructure is a critical component to strengthening our supply chains, moving people and goods more effectively, and ultimately lowering costs of everyday items.&nbsp; This is part of transitioning to stable and steady economic growth for the years ahead.</p>



<p>Today, the Biden administration announced over $368 million in grants to modernize and improve rail infrastructure across the country, and Secretary Buttigieg is in Michigan and Mitch Landrieu is in North Carolina to highlight the impact these investments will have on local economies and regional supply chains.</p>



<p>Thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we will see funding triple for the critical rail infrastructure program to $1 billion a year for the next five years, which will help strengthen critical links in the &#8212; in our supply chains that were weakened by the pandemic.&nbsp; This investment will allow &#8212; will allow trains to get goods to market faster and cheaper and make it easier for Americans to travel where they need to go.</p>



<p> </p>



<p>Two final important announcements that I wanted to make here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you may know, our dear Amanda Finney is leaving us.&nbsp; Though her official title is “Chief of Staff,” Jen long ago gave her the honor &#8212; the title of “Mayor of the West Wing.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>If you know her, and I know many of you do and adore her as we do, you know that Amanda shines thanks to her charisma, her humor, and ability to simply get things done.</p>



<p>Whether it’s leading our team of wranglers or hiring the best of the best to join our team, I don’t know where we would be without Mayor Finney.</p>



<p>She is leaving us to serve as Deputy Director of Public Affairs at the Energy Department, and they’re so, so lucky to have her.</p>



<p>Amanda has been the heart and soul of this team, and she will be truly missed.&nbsp; We love you, Finney.&nbsp; And we wish you the absolute best.&nbsp; And, “what a time,” as you would say.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. FINNEY:&nbsp; What a time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What a time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. FINNEY:&nbsp; What a time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What a time.&nbsp; Amazing.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We get that a lot.&nbsp; Amanda-isms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; One last announcement I want to make.&nbsp; Brittany came into our team very recently &#8212; actually, six months.&nbsp; It feels recently, but it’s been six months.&nbsp; We will be bidding her farewell.&nbsp; Our dear Brittany Caplin, who is returning back to the Department of Commerce after completing her rotation as Assistant Press Secretary here in our office.</p>



<p>Brittany&#8217;s kindness, professionalism, and know- &#8212; know-how have been apparent from day one.&nbsp; She is one of the nicest people that I know, and she has become an integral &#8212; integral part of the &#8212; of this team since then.</p>



<p>Stepping into the White House &#8212; White &#8212; the West Wing Press Office and taking on tough topics like the 5G &#8212; you guys remember that &#8212; and corporate mergers is no small challenge, as she knows.&nbsp; But Brittany has done so, so much, earning praise and respect from across the White House.</p>



<p>Brittany will be returning to Commerce, as I just mentioned, at the &#8212; at the repeated insistence of Secretary Gina Raimondo.&nbsp; I have a story I’ll tell you maybe at drinks.&nbsp; I’ve told Brittany this story about how I was told by Gina to make sure to return Brittany to her many times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anyway.&nbsp; And why &#8212; and it’s abundantly clear to anyone who has worked with you, Brittany, how amazing and how much of a star you are.&nbsp; And it’s &#8212; it’s been exciting to see your accomplishments.&nbsp; And thank you so much for spending six months with us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know.&nbsp; Every day &#8212; every day, I’m going to be give &#8212; doing these little goodbyes, but I promise we will have a press shop.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Not everyone is leaving.<br><br>Let me make sure I went through everything.&nbsp; And that is it.&nbsp; You want to take &#8212; you want to kick us off?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Terrific.&nbsp; I have &#8212; I have two questions.&nbsp; On the speech tonight, I’m wondering why there’s reason to believe that things will be different in Congress, given that we haven’t seen action repeatedly?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me just say, as you guys know, the President is going to give a speech this evening at 7:30.&nbsp; He’s going to renew his call for action to stop the epidemic of gun violence that we’ve seen in Uvalde and in Tulsa and in Bu- &#8212; and Buffalo in just a few short weeks.&nbsp; And in too many communities across the country, we see gun violence tearing up our communities, tearing up families.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, reducing gun violence has been a top priority of this president since his first day of office and throughout his career as a senator, as a vice president and, clearly, as a president.<br><br>He has been crystal clear that Congress needs to act.&nbsp; The President has done more through executive action, as you&#8217;ve heard us say, than any other president in th- &#8212; in his first year &#8212; in their first year in history.&nbsp; And the President has directed his staff to continue to explore additional actions we can take.&nbsp; But we can&#8217;t do this alone, and it&#8217;s time for Congress to act.<br><br>Your second question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On vaccines for &#8212; for those under five, can you tell us: Is the President satisfied with the &#8212; the pace of the FDA review process?&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve already had questions about the frustration among parents.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, I mean, Dr. Jha talked about this and the frustration of parents.&nbsp; And we know parents are incredibly eager to get this done.&nbsp; And, you know, FDA is working rigorously through this process.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an independent scie- &#8212; scientific process, so we do leave it to them.&nbsp; And it is the FDA authorization to get this done.<br><br>But we know many parents are eager to vaccinate their youngest kids.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important to do this right, to do this in a safe way, as Dr. Jha was talking about.&nbsp; And so &#8212; but the most important thing that we want to make sure we come across, which is why we had Dr. Jha here, is that the administration is preparing, we are prepared.<br><br>We&#8217;re working with states, local health departments, pediatricians, family doctors, other health providers, and pharmacies to get ready, as we did with kids that &#8212; between 5 &#8212; 5 and 11.<br><br>So we want to make sure that we get this done swiftly, but also safely and, you know, so &#8212; you know, follow CDC recommendation.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Mary.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yesterday, you noted that the President, given his history in the Senate, knows well how negotiations over gun reform work.&nbsp; And that &#8212; you know, that giving talks a little bit of space, you think, is sometimes, you know, a good strategy, that that can help members come to common ground and work through some of these issues.</p>



<p>But that hasn&#8217;t worked in the past, not on this issue &#8212; right? &#8212; given what we&#8217;ve seen in the past.&nbsp; So why pursue that same strategy now if it hasn&#8217;t worked?&nbsp; Why not have the President play a more direct role in these negotiations now?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I mean, look, the President has been very involved and very direct.&nbsp; And he has done it multiple times throughout the &#8212; this past year and a half, year and six months now.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s done it at his first joint address; he made sure that he talked about gun violence and made that a priority in that speech.&nbsp; He did it in the Rose Garden, when he announced some executive actions on a comprehensive plan from here, from the federal government, from the White House on how to deal with gun violence and do what we can. &nbsp;He did that in the State of the Union and made sure that was &#8212; gun violence was a priority.<br><br>So he&#8217;s been involved.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been engaged.&nbsp; As you just stated, he&#8217;s been doing this all &#8212; for a good &#8212; you know, a good part of his career.<br><br>And I stated this yesterday, but our legislative team has been in close contact with the Hill since the tragedies in Uvalde and Buffalo, including through dozens of phone calls with leadership committees, with jurisdiction, and with the members who are involved directly in negotiations.<br><br>Look, he&#8217;s encouraged.&nbsp; He&#8217;s encouraged by what we&#8217;re seeing on the Hill.&nbsp; You know, this is the first time in a very long time that we have seen this type of bipartisanship.&nbsp; And &#8212; and he&#8217;s done this before, as I mentioned.&nbsp; You know, he has beat the gun lobby before.<br><br>And so, tonight, you&#8217;ll hear from him.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll be basically making sure that he&#8217;s still &#8212; his voice is out there and calling to action and making sure that, you know, the American people know that he is &#8212; he is still continuing to speak on their behalf and making sure that, you know, we get some action taken.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You note the legislative team is making the calls, is, you know, obviously playing a central role in these negotiations.&nbsp; But why isn’t the President picking up the phone and making those calls?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Like I said, he wants to give it some space.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s had conversations in the past with groups.&nbsp; He&#8217;s had conversations with congressional members in the past &#8212; in this past a year and a half on &#8212; on making &#8212; on &#8212; being very clear on Congress acting.<br><br>He&#8217;s going to take this opportunity today at 7:30 this evening, as I just said, so that the American public could hear him directly.<br><br>But we have to remember: The things that we are calling for &#8212; when you think about &#8212; you know, when you think about background checks, expanding that; when you think about, you know, banning assault weapons &#8212; these are items that are incredibly popular with the very constituencies that these congressional members represent.<br><br>When you look at &#8212; when you look at even NRA members, when you look at Republican voters out there, Americans out there, these are &#8212; these are issues and items that we&#8217;re talking about that should be easy.&nbsp; It should not be difficult to do.<br><br>We&#8217;re trying to save our kids.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to save families.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to make it safe for people to go to grocery stores, so our kids could go to elementary school or to school.&nbsp; And so this is what the President is calling for.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more on this.&nbsp; You’ve said you&#8217;re looking into possible additional executive actions that the President might take.&nbsp; Do you have a sense of how long that process may take, when we might learn what options are on the table?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the President said this &#8212; and not just myself, but he said this &#8212; that we can take &#8212; we&#8217;re going to take executive action where we can, and we&#8217;re continuing to explore new &#8212; new steps, we can build on what we&#8217;ve already done.<br><br>I just want to make sure people also know what we&#8217;ve done, which is stemming the flow of ghost guns, which are the weapon of choice of many terrorists and criminals, and which are increasingly being found at crime scenes; cracking down on gun trafficking, including through a zero-tolerance policy for gun dealers willfully selling firearms illegally; as well as DOJ&#8217;s gun trafficking strike forces around the country; and giving cities and states historic funding to keep cops on the beat and fund &#8212; and fund gun violence prevention programs.&nbsp; We announced $10 billion so far with more money on the way.<br><br>Look, we have a team of 13 policy staff working on gun violence at the White House.&nbsp; In addition, numerous staff across agencies.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re constantly &#8212; constantly looking for &#8212; for what else we can do.<br><br>But again, tonight&#8217;s speech is going to focus on what Congress needs to do and Congress action because the President cannot do this alone.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he going to outline specific actions that he&#8217;d like to see, Karine, like you mentioned the background checks?&nbsp; What&#8217;s he going to say in terms of specifics?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s going to make sure that he continues his call to action when it comes to Congress.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; But he&#8217;ll be very clear, and you&#8217;ll hear from him directly.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What role did the U.S. play in persuading both OPEC-Plus to increase capacity?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That is a decision that O- &#8212; OPEC-Plus makes on their own.&nbsp; That is not something that we decide on or that we are involved in.&nbsp; As you know, you&#8217;ve heard us say this before, but we welcome &#8212; we do welcome the announcement today.<br><br>And, you know, we welcome the important decision that OPEC-Plus made to increase supply by more than 200,000 barrels per day in July and August, based on &#8212; on new market conditions. That&#8217;s the analysis that they make. Right?&nbsp; That&#8217;s not &#8212; that&#8217;s for them, again, to decide.<br><br>This announcement brings forward the monthly production increase that was previously planned to take place in September.&nbsp; You know, the United States will continue to use all tools at our disposal to address energy &#8212; energy prices measures.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secondly, does this development, coupled with the extension of the Yemen ceasefire, increase the chances that the President will visit Saudi Arabia?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything for you.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have anything for you on any &#8212; any trip or plan for the President, or any trip to announce today.&nbsp; But I can assure you that what the President is focused on, first and foremost, is how his engagements with foreign leaders advance American interests.&nbsp; That is &#8212; that&#8217;s as true with Saudi Arabia as anywhere else.<br><br>Just as he has engaged recently with leaders of ASEAN in Asia and this week with the Summit of the Americas as it&#8217;s coming up next week in Los Angeles, the President will look for opportunities to engage with leaders from the Middle East region.&nbsp; And I just have nothing to announce for you today.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine, I have a question on formula, but just to follow up &#8212; so, can you say whether or not the President will call for anything new tonight when it comes to guns and what he wants to see Congress do?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, his focus is going to be on &#8212; on making sure and calling &#8212; calling to &#8212; asking Congress to take action because he cannot do this alone.&nbsp; I do not want to get ahead of the President&#8217;s speech.&nbsp; Everyone will hear from him at 7:30.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he won&#8217;t talk about any specific action that he wants to see Congress take besides &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; generally passing something?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve talked about that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked about the actions that he wants to see taken.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve just spoke about them, which is a expand &#8212; expanding background checks.&nbsp; He&#8217;s talked about that.&nbsp; We talked about red flags laws as well.&nbsp; We have talked about banning assault weapons.&nbsp; These are items that the President has been very clear on; has talked about; and also &#8212; also, when you think about this &#8212; the banning assault weapons &#8212; has led on, especially when he was a senator.<br><br>So that&#8217;s &#8212; that is not new.&nbsp; We have made that very clear in all of the remarks and speeches that he has done on gun violence in the past year and a half.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just this time around, I meant, specifically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But on the executive actions, you said, you were exploring what he can still do, what still is left.&nbsp; Have you identified anything specific that he can still do?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce.&nbsp; And &#8212; but the President has said himself, we&#8217;re going to explore where we can to see what else we can do on executive actions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But nothing imminent?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, I don&#8217;t have anything imminent to announce.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on formula: Did the President have any conversations with any Cabinet Secretaries or the FDA commissioner once he was confirmed in February about the formula shortage before April?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any meetings to read out specifically on that for you.&nbsp; Look, you know, as &#8212; as more &#8212; as you all know, the President spoke to &#8212; to this yesterday: As more abnormalities were seen in supply and sales started to decrease in April &#8212; you know, because people have asked about this &#8212; senior White House staff made &#8212; made the President aware of the problem, and this was in April.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any calls to read out for you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Which senior White House staff made the President aware?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; so, as you know, the President deals with issues on a regular basis and that &#8212; that boils up to him.&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just an &#8212; there&#8217;s no specific person that I can call out to you.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s the regular way that we &#8212; we move forward through the regular channels.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a specific person.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s kind of how it goes on any issue, not just this one.&nbsp; It goes through regular channels, and senior &#8212; senior White House staff usually brief him on different issues.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; The speech tonight wasn&#8217;t on the schedule originally when the day began.&nbsp; Was there something specific that prompted the President to want to speak tonight?&nbsp; Was it the shooting yesterday in Tulsa, or was he trying to say remarks before he went out of town for a couple of days?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, the President has been wanting to have an opportunity to speak to the American people about this epidemic that we&#8217;re seeing with gun violence.&nbsp; He wanted to make sure that, again, there was space &#8212; there was space for negotiations, giving space in Congress to the folks who are leading that conversation.&nbsp; And he just felt tonight was the right time to do that.&nbsp; But he has &#8212; he had been wanting to &#8212; to make these co- &#8212; to have this &#8212; this speech.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to clarify, I know you haven&#8217;t disclosed exactly what he&#8217;s going to say tonight that he wants out of legislation from Congress.&nbsp; But is he going to specify exactly what he wants?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, but he has.&nbsp; I mean &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, okay.&nbsp; So that’s what he wants, though?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, I mean &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that will be what he talks about tonight?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m just saying that he has laid out what he wants from Congress.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been very clear.&nbsp; He did that at the State of the Union, most recently.&nbsp; He did that during the &#8212; the &#8212; his comments when we talked about the executive actions for gun violence to &#8212; to reform &#8212; to comprehensive gun violence recently during the Rose Garden; his first joint Congress &#8212; address to Congress.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s done it many times, calling for Congress to act.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s listed it out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So why would he give another speech?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Because he wants to make sure that the American &#8212; that his voice is still out there, and that the American people know that he&#8217;s fighting for them and speaking for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this isn&#8217;t &#8212; this is, as we have said many times, this is a priority for the President.&nbsp; And so, this is what we&#8217;re going to see this evening.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doing it at this time.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, so on &#8212; continuing on that topic.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m still a little confused.&nbsp; So, on the one hand, you’ve said that he is &#8212; he supports and wants an assault weapons ban, universal background checks, and red-flag laws.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s not the conversation that&#8217;s largely going on up on the Hill.&nbsp; The Hill &#8212; to the extent that there are discussions, you know, members on both sides have said they are not engaged in active negotiations over an assault weapons ban or universal background checks.&nbsp; They’re &#8212; it is much more modest than that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I guess the question that &#8212; that we&#8217;re all asking is: Is he going to &#8212; and I think you&#8217;ve used the word “renew” at the beginning &#8212; is he going to repeat his demand that Congress pass an ab- &#8212; a, you know, universal background check bill, a ban on assault weapons, and red-flag laws?&nbsp; Or is he going to lend his voice to the more modest gun control efforts that are actually underway on Capitol Hill?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those are two different things, and I don&#8217;t know that you can &#8212; you can do both at the same time.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Or maybe &#8212; or maybe you can just do one and say, “But if that doesn&#8217;t happen, I&#8217;m happy with the other one,” maybe?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I guess &#8212; I &#8212; we think we can do both at the same time.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; The President has been very clear in laying out his key priorities.&nbsp; He has done that for a year and a half: expand background checks to keep guns out of the hands of criminals; renew our ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazine; pass a red-flag law, which, by the way, is being talked about &#8212; right? &#8212; in Congress; confirm Steve Dettel- &#8212; Dettelbach to lead ATF &#8212; that is something that we have talked about, and Congress is dealing with that.&nbsp; And we are very optimistic that he will be confirmed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So those are &#8212; just listed out a couple of things that are very much a reality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, the President has been very clear: Congress needs to act.&nbsp; They should pass legislation so the President can sign it into law.&nbsp; We are seeing something right now that is encouraging.&nbsp; The process is still happening.&nbsp; Negotiation is still happening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We do not know what it&#8217;s ultimately going to look like, but that doesn&#8217;t mean that the President can&#8217;t call out his key priorities.&nbsp; That doesn&#8217;t mean that the President can&#8217;t list out what he thinks is needed to &#8212; that needs to happen so that we can actually deal with this epidemic.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But so we should expect him to repeat that demand for those &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; he’s repeated it many times.&nbsp; I think &#8212; I think &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I &#8212; I know he’s repeated it in the past.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, what I’m saying is I don’t want to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m asking about tonight for the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; I don’t want to get ahead of what the President &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you just have gotten ahead of him.&nbsp; You &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, but &#8212; no.&nbsp; I &#8212; I haven’t.&nbsp; I said he’s going to call Congress into action.&nbsp; He has talked about these things over and over and over again.&nbsp; The President is going to speak for himself.&nbsp; That is all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve said this before.&nbsp; When you guys have asked us, “Can you please give us a preview on the speech?”&nbsp; Many times, we say, “Let &#8212; we want the President to speak for himself.”&nbsp; That is not new.&nbsp; That is not new here.&nbsp; That is exactly what I&#8217;m saying.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you know his key priorities; he&#8217;s been talking about them.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just had a question we are &#8212; more here on strategy.&nbsp; You said the past couple of days that the President wanted to give space for Congress to work through the negotiations on their own and that he would only get involved when he felt he would be helpful.&nbsp; Tonight, he&#8217;s giving a speech in primetime.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he think it&#8217;s now time for him to be helpful in these negotiations?&nbsp; Or is there a risk that his insertion into this moment could be potentially counterproductive and hurt the ongoing negotiation that doesn’t &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; seem to be finalized yet?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; We have &#8212; our Office of Leg Affairs has been in close consultation with the negotiators on the Hill.&nbsp; So they are &#8212; they were aware that we are &#8212; that the President is going to give these remarks.&nbsp; We &#8212; they &#8212; we talked to them.&nbsp; We had consultation with them.&nbsp; We consulted with them about giving these remarks.&nbsp; So that is not an issue.&nbsp; That is not a problem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President wanted to make sure that the American people heard from him directly.&nbsp; This is a speech that he has been wanting to make, and that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to do this evening.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, there is careful consideration here about what he might say to not interfere with an ongoing negotiation?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m not saying that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; that&#8217;s not what I&#8217;m saying.&nbsp; I&#8217;m saying that the President is going to use this opportunity to speak directly to the American people.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to do tonight.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more on baby formula.&nbsp; I know you got a lot of questions about this yesterday.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you had an opportunity to speak with the President since his comments yesterday, when he said he was not informed about the situation until May.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Is there &#8212; is he &#8212; has he expressed any disappointment in his staff for not bringing the issue to him earlier?&nbsp; Are there any concerns about the information flow in the White House that &#8212; given the manufacturers told him very directly they knew this would be a problem in February and he didn&#8217;t know about it until months later, has he expressed concern about that gap and how that squares with the whole-of-government approach you outlined yesterday?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, just so that we take a little bit of a step back &#8212; you know, Abbott is a major manufacturer and has been clear to the American people that they had shortcomings.&nbsp; They &#8212; they made that clear very, very recently.</p>



<p>The FDA administrator has spoken to this as well.&nbsp; He said the FDA moved too slow, and it has asked Steve Solomon to lead a review into what happened.</p>



<p>The White House took urgent actions as it became clear a shortage emerged and existing actions were not so sufficing.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s hard to understand the scales of actions: DPA, at a historical pace; Operation Fly Formula, expe- &#8212; expediting timelines for millions of bottles from three to four weeks, to 72 hours &#8212; these are incredibly important of what we were able to do; and 80 million safe bottles being imported and counting.</p>



<p>We understand that there&#8217;s more work to be done.&nbsp; We understand what families are feeling.&nbsp; But this is &#8212; we have to remember how this started.&nbsp; We have to also remember what the FDA Administrator said as well.&nbsp; He has spoken to this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, this is &#8212; you know, this is something that we&#8217;re going to continue to work on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; But that doesn’t answer the question about when the President was informed and whether or not he is satisfied with his staff not telling him about what has become a major problem &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, he spoke &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for two months.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; He spoke to when he was informed &#8212; that’s his &#8212; he spoke to that yesterday &#8212; which was in April.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you&#8217;re asking me about the process and is he disappointed?&nbsp; Look, again, I&#8217;m telling you, the Administrator of FDA spoke to this.&nbsp; They moved too slowly.&nbsp; He &#8212; and said that Steve Solomon is going to lead an after-action review on what happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when the shortages emerged and actions by the FDA and USDA did not suffice to prevent any consumer impact, the White House led urgent &#8212; an urgent, emergency, administrative-wide action with FDA &#8212; Fly Formula, as I just mentioned.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But that’s the FDA Administrator; that&#8217;s not the President.&nbsp; Those are two different individuals.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, but I’m telling you the process.&nbsp; I’m telling you what happened.&nbsp; I&#8217;m telling you that the FDA moved too slowly.&nbsp; I&#8217;m telling you that this happened on the side of Abbott.&nbsp; And this &#8212; what FDA tried to do at first was they &#8212; they &#8212; they called out Abbott for safety concerns.&nbsp; Right?</p>



<p>The most important thing here is that we have &#8212; we have &#8212; we have to make sure that babies have fa- &#8212; safe formula.&nbsp; We have to make sure that American families feel comfortable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, FDA did their part here.&nbsp; But he also admitted that they moved too slowly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And once we saw that the supplies were not meeting the demand, we acted.&nbsp; We took urgent action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that is the &#8212; that is the way that it happened.&nbsp; That is the way the timeline was laid out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that is &#8212; I’m &#8212; you may not like my answer, but that is the way that we see it &#8212; in answering your question there.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President expecting his audience tonight should include those negotiators who are working on &#8212; members of Congress who are working on this?&nbsp; Is he directly trying to speak to them?&nbsp; Or are you saying his audience is the broader public?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think &#8212; look, I &#8212; I think the &#8212; the speech that he&#8217;s making &#8212; yes, it&#8217;s to the American public; why we’re &#8212; we&#8217;re having &#8212; making sure that we&#8217;re having it this evening so they can hear directly to the &#8212; to the American people.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s also a call to action for Con- &#8212; to Congress as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, but, again, we have been in constant communication &#8212; dozens of calls have been made &#8212; with members in Congress, including negotiators from the Office of Leg Affairs, and that has been happening for the past couple of weeks.&nbsp; So we have been communicating with them and making sure that we &#8212; you know, we get a sense of what&#8217;s happening and how we can be helpful.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And have you read the remarks yet?&nbsp; Have you seen the President&#8217;s text?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve seen &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen a draft of the remarks.&nbsp; But, again, this is for the President to speak to.&nbsp; He is &#8212; I do not want to get ahead of what he is going to share with the American public and what message he wants to send.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think part &#8212; following up on what Michael said is, I&#8217;m trying to get a sense of if the President is trying to help close a deal and get something accomplished with Congress or if he is going to restate what he could say on any day &#8212; a position he&#8217;s held for decades &#8212; or if he is trying to get this moment to produce a legislative result?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because, really, nobody is talking about banning assault weapons on Capitol Hill at the moment.&nbsp; So, is he going to speak more to the specific elements that they are currently negotiating?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, when it comes to right now, as you all are asking me, look, the President has defeated the gun lobby before.&nbsp; He is the one who was able to pass an assault weapons ban and who was able to help shepherd the legislation that put in place the federal system of background checks.&nbsp; So, he understands how this process works.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President is continuing to press Congress to act and he&#8217;s giving them the room they need to find common ground, but he can still speak to this and speak to the American people.</p>



<p>But as &#8212; as we have said, the President is going to continue to stay closely engaged on this to speak out.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to use his bully pulpit, which is what he’s doing this evening, to press for action, just as he’s done throughout his presidency &#8212; just as we’ve done at the State of the Union earlier this year, just as he’s done when he did his first joint address to Congress, and he’s done this many times.</p>



<p>And so, this is just another opportunity to use the bully pulpit to talk about the actions that he wants to see and also just talk directly to the American people.&nbsp; He thinks this is an important moment to do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can we ask you to go back on the issue of who briefed the President on baby formula?&nbsp; To say there was no specific person is not a satisfactory answer.&nbsp; When you have senior assistants to the President, there&#8217;s a paper trail, I&#8217;m sure, about briefings to the President.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a Domestic Policy Council.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a Chief of Staff.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At some point, we need to know who would have been the most likely person to talk to him about that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think what I&#8217;m trying to say is there&#8217;s so many issues that come up that is presented to the President &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Certainly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; as you know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We do know that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You’ve covered &#8212; you&#8217;ve covered many administrations.&nbsp; And there are just regular channels that that happen that go to the President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It looks like it&#8217;s evasive to not have the most senior people in the White House willing to say, &#8220;I had a conversation with the President about it&#8221; or &#8220;I had…&#8221; or &#8220;We talked about it in this context or that context.&#8221;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re also all reporting on the consumer side of it &#8212; of what you&#8217;re doing, putting out and trying to get information.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re also trying to understand the information flow in this White House, and it&#8217;s important for us to get that answer, which is why we&#8217;re going to keep asking it until we get that answer.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, you have every right to keep asking.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I&#8217;m here.</p>



<p>Look, really, Kelly O., he&#8217;s briefed on countless priorities.&nbsp; He is the President of the United States.&nbsp; There are regular channels.&nbsp; He is briefed by his senior White House staff.&nbsp; And that is just the process that we have.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, should we assume it&#8217;s the Chief of Staff then?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to confirm who it was; I&#8217;m just letting you know that there are regular channels that we use, and, you know, it&#8217;s senior &#8212; again, senior White House staff that elevate issues to him when the time comes.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re just regular channels.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s what I have for you to share there.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; If the President thinks that Congress must act immediately to end this epidemic of gun violence, is he going to bring any of the key players from Capitol Hill to the beach with him tonight?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; So, I don’t have any &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But wasn’t a big part of candidate Biden&#8217;s whole thing that he &#8220;knows how to get things done with Congress&#8221;?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; He does.&nbsp; He does.&nbsp; I mean, he&#8217;s beaten the gun lobby before.&nbsp; He has.&nbsp; But &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Then why not invite these lawmakers who maybe haven’t beat the gun law &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But &#8212; but it’s not &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and say, &#8220;This is how it&#8217;s done&#8221;?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But it&#8217;s not &#8220;his thing&#8221;; it&#8217;s actually fact.&nbsp; We saw he did that in the Senate during his Congress days &#8212; that he beat the gun lobby. Look, I &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m agreeing with you that he has a lot of legislative experience.&nbsp; I&#8217;m asking why it is that you can say he wants to give these negotiations some space &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Do you want to go to the beach with the President tonight?&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re trying to tell me?&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would love to.&nbsp; The weather is not great.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I will &#8212; touché on that one.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; The weather &#8212; it is pouring outside like cats and dogs.&nbsp; It is not great.</p>



<p>Look &#8212; no &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if people are dying every day &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; why would this President then say he wants to &#8220;give it some space&#8221; and let somebody else up the street &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But you&#8217;re also going to hear &#8212; you&#8217;re going to hear from the President tonight.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not that he &#8212; it&#8217;s not that he hasn’t been involved, he has been involved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just listed out all of the conversations &#8212; not conversations but speeches that he&#8217;s made.&nbsp; I just listed out the executive actions that he&#8217;s taken.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I want to make sure that, you know, that it is very clear that the President has indeed taken action.&nbsp; He cannot do it alone, so he&#8217;s asking for Congress to act.&nbsp; The American public is going to hear from him tonight.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any meetings to preview or to lay out for &#8212; I&#8217;m not telling you it&#8217;s not going to happen; I&#8217;m just saying I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I get not &#8212; you don&#8217;t want to preview anything that&#8217;s in the text tonight.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what law could anybody &#8212; the President or anybody else &#8212; propose that would guarantee that somebody who really wants to get their hands on a gun can&#8217;t?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, they&#8217;re having negotiations right now to talk through what the options are.</p>



<p>Look, I mentioned the red flags, right?&nbsp; Red-flag laws.&nbsp; If enacted &#8212; if enacted, that actually we have seen, across the country in different states, where it has been helpful.</p>



<p>But look, we are &#8212; we are &#8212; we&#8217;re going give them some space to see what they come up with.</p>



<p>The President &#8212; the most important thing here is the President wants Congress to take action and to act.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; okay, you got Chicago, for example.&nbsp; They already have plenty of very strict gun laws &#8212; some of the strictest in the country.&nbsp; Forty-seven people shot there over the Memorial Day weekend.&nbsp; Nine of them died.&nbsp; So, which law would have prevented any of that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Well &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do we think that all these people in Chicago who are shooting each other are legally buying their guns?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, here&#8217;s &#8212; here&#8217;s a couple of examples for you.&nbsp; I was just talking about the red-flags law.&nbsp; There are some examples here of how they&#8217;ve prevented tragedies.</p>



<p>In California, a study showed that a California red-flag law has assisted in the prevention of 21 mass shootings between 2016 and 2018.</p>



<p>Florida, since passing a red-flag law in 2018, there have been notable cases of few &#8212; of the law intervening in multiple cases of potential violence &#8212; of potential violence.</p>



<p>In Connecticut and Indiana, for every 10 to 20 preventions under the red-flag laws, there was one fewer death than would otherwise have been expected.</p>



<p>So, when enacted, it does help.&nbsp; There are things that we can do.&nbsp; And one of the things that the President talks about with expanding &#8212; expanding the background checks, if we&#8217;re able to do that, we are going to take more guns out of the hands of criminals.&nbsp; And that is incredibly important.</p>



<p>So, there are things here that can be worked out, that can be done that is not going to prevent every tragedy but will take us to a better place where we can protect our families.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And my last one will be: You guys at the White House had some very hard headlines this week about inflation and about baby formula.&nbsp; If there&#8217;s nothing new that you can point to in the speech tonight, did you just schedule it to get people talking about something else?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; People have died.&nbsp; People have died in the past couple of weeks, in particular.&nbsp; We had 19 kids die in Uvalde just recently of &#8212; a mass shooter came into their classroom and killed them, plus their two teachers.</p>



<p>We had &#8212; we had people doing everyday things on a Saturday, like some of us do, go to the grocery store, and 10 of them were murdered.</p>



<p>Just last night, in Tulsa, we&#8217;re learning of people who were, again, killed.</p>



<p>So, this is not about politics.&nbsp; This is not about partisan politics here.&nbsp; This is something that he has worked on since he was a senator.&nbsp; This is very important and real for the President and for the grieving families that he has met with, sadly, in the last two weeks.</p>



<p>So, this is an opportunity, again, to call for action, to get Congress to move.</p>



<p>And, you know, it is &#8212; it is disheartening to hear that this could potentially or &#8212; if I&#8217;m hearing this right, could be used as a political tool.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s not what this is.&nbsp; This is not about partisan.&nbsp; This is about people&#8217;s lives.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Karine.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s message to people living in violent neighborhoods who can’t escape &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Ed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and can&#8217;t wait for laws to &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Ed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow up on what Kelly was asking about regarding the baby formula shortage: You were asked earlier by a few people &#8212; I want to just ask this again, with all due respect.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Were you able to speak with the President about when he was informed in April?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; here &#8212; he talked about it himself.&nbsp; He said he was informed in April.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t think I need to &#8212; the President mentioned that.&nbsp; He said that.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t need to clear that up.&nbsp; You heard directly from the President on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Part of the reason we &#8212; I ask it, at least, is you talked yesterday about February 17th and February 18th.&nbsp; And what we were trying to figure out is when exactly in April was he told.&nbsp; Was it April 1?&nbsp; Was it April 30th?&nbsp; Was in April 15?&nbsp; Somewhere else in there?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a date to share with you.&nbsp; What I can tell you is he spoke to this yesterday.&nbsp; And he said it was in April, so that &#8212; that matters too.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Take it down &#8212; take it down a level from him &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Yeah, yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; into the staff of the White House.&nbsp; And part of the reason there&#8217;s so much curiosity about this across town is because, as you know, there have been stories written over the last several days and weeks about how things are going here in the West Wing, how things are operating.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, when we ask, “Who was told, either by the FDA or the Department of Health and Human Services or the USDA, here in the West Wing &#8212; who was told first?&nbsp; How did that get from that person, eventually, to the President?” &#8212;</p>



<p>It’s completely understandable.&nbsp; There are thousands of things going on across the federal government today &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; There are thousands of things &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But here’s the issue &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; we were just talking about gun violence.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; something else could crop up suddenly as an unforeseen crisis, like this one.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re trying to get a sense of how do things operate here inside the West Wing and how they eventually rise to the level of presidential involvement that then lead to things like invoking the Defense Production Act five &#8212; four or five months after the initial flags were raised.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, Ed, the President was briefed through his regular channels, as he is briefed on countless priorities that the President of the United States has to deal with.&nbsp; There are countless issues, countless priorities that I talk about here all the time, every day, about different priorities that we have to deal with, whether it&#8217;s the economy, whether it&#8217;s COVID, whether it&#8217;s climate change, whether it&#8217;s foreign policy issues that we have to deal with and assess.<br><br>That is how we run the White House; it’s how any White House is run.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So there are regular channels of White House senior staff, and that&#8217;s how it gets elevated.&nbsp; You&#8217;re asking me for a specific name.&nbsp; I&#8217;m telling you how the process works, and I&#8217;m telling you how it goes from White House staff to regular channels to the President.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Part of why this is intriguing is because we know, from what you&#8217;ve said, from what your colleagues have told us and what we&#8217;ve learned in our reporting over the last year and a half, is that he&#8217;s a voracious consumer of information from across the federal government.&nbsp; And whenever he gets briefed on something like this, he asks a lot of questions.&nbsp; And he usually puts it to the staff to come back with him with some solutions or some answers to these questions.<br><br>So the idea that he was told about this in April and then it didn&#8217;t get elevated until mid-May when Congress and when the press started raising bigger questions about this begs the question of, “Well, then what happened in April, when this very curious, very detail-oriented President, in briefings, would have been told about it and when steps were taken that are now underway?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s part of what is so intriguing and curious about this situation, and why we&#8217;re so desperate for information.&nbsp; Because normally in these situations, we&#8217;re told, “Oh, well, here&#8217;s what he wanted to know.&nbsp; And here&#8217;s who he tasked with doing it.”&nbsp; But we&#8217;re not getting it this time.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I &#8212; look, we’ve laid out timelines over and over again.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, you gave us two dates and then tell us, “Generally, in April he was told about this.”<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, so, by late &#8212; let me try again.&nbsp; Let’s try this again.&nbsp; By late &#8212; by late in April, sales &#8212; sales were going down and shortages were appearing.&nbsp; So that is what we &#8212; we learned in late April.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And since then, through May, across the administration, we&#8217;ve aggressively invoked the DPA and used it three times, as you just mentioned, and that&#8217;s because of the President&#8217;s leadership; launched Operation Fly Formula, again, because of the President&#8217;s leadership; secured 80 million safe infant formula bottles from other countries; and cut red tape and issued WIC waivers in all 50 states, because that&#8217;s what happened in April that triggered our involvement in the way that we did throughout May in doing these four very specific things.<br><br>Look, USDA &#8212; you know, they took immediate action.&nbsp; But USDA and FDA cut red tape and increased supply.&nbsp; A reminder: There was more supply on the market after the recall than prior.&nbsp; That did not happen by &#8212; that didn&#8217;t happen by accident.&nbsp; So these actions were designed to bridge demand while Abbott worked through its safe- &#8212; safely opening to &#8212; safely open and manufacture a product that met FDA’s gold standard.<br><br>So they were acting at USDA, FDA were acting from the moment that the recall happened.&nbsp; But again, the sales were going down and shortages were appearing in late April.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s when &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that’s when he was told?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, he said &#8212; in late April &#8212; right? &#8212; and this &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said in early April.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; In &#8212; in April.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; In April.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; He said in April &#8212; in early April.<br><br>The point that I&#8217;m making is: What we started to see in April were sales were going down and shortages were appearing.&nbsp;&nbsp; And when that happened, we triggered &#8212; we &#8212; the President made sure that the DPA happened, the Operation Fly Formula happened.&nbsp; And that was what &#8212; that was our focus there.&nbsp; And we wanted to make sure we got as much supply out as possible because, again, we saw the sales were going down.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Real quick on Summit of the Americas: I know you said the invite list is coming.&nbsp; There&#8217;s still some time left.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Countries that have been invited &#8212; whoever they are; we&#8217;ll find out about that later &#8212; have they been told what&#8217;s on the agenda for that summit next week?&nbsp; Do they know why they should come to Los Angeles?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we’re still giving our partners time to decide, so &#8212; to answer that question.&nbsp; But, you know, as you see from press reports, there have been quite a few heads of states who have confirmed via their own announcement.<br><br>But again, you know, I always bring this back, because what&#8217;s really important is &#8212; about next week is that the people from around the region are gathering together to address the core challenges facing the people of the hemisphere &#8212; right? &#8212; including economic prosperity, climate change, migration crisis, and the COVID-19 pandemic.<br><br>So there is an array of issues for the region that we &#8212; that we are going to discuss.&nbsp; These are priorities.&nbsp; These are incredibly important.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what you&#8217;re going to see for next week.&nbsp; And others will confirm if they&#8217;re attending.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to do that until we have a final list and give our &#8212; our partners opportunities to decide.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re at your time that you said you were going to wrap.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, my gosh.&nbsp; Okay, go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, the jobs report is going to come out tomorrow morning.&nbsp; The ADP report that came out was &#8212; it came in much lower than what economists had projected.&nbsp; Are you guys expecting a less than optimal jobs report tomorrow?&nbsp; And usually the President speaks on the economy on jobs day.&nbsp; Is he going to do that, even though he&#8217;s going to be in Delaware?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you for tomorrow.&nbsp; Our day ahead, our daily guidance is going to be coming out in a couple of hours.&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t have &#8212; also don&#8217;t have an estimate for you and haven&#8217;t seen the numbers, clearly.&nbsp; But what we can say is that as we transition to this new period of stable, steady growth, we aren&#8217;t looking to see blockbuster job reports month after month, like we have over the last year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that&#8217;s a good thing.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the sign of a healthy economy with steady job growth, rising wages for working Americans, everyday costs easing up, and a shrinking deficit.<br><br>That stability will put us in a strong position to tackle inflation.&nbsp; And in the short time since President Biden came into office, we have had record job numbers, record job creation, I should &#8212; I should say; the unemployment rate is near historic lows; and the number of Americans on unemployment benefits is down from record highs to this historic lows.&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s something that&#8217;s really important that we want to make sure that the American people know what we&#8217;ve been doing.<br><br>Okay, we&#8217;re going to go.&nbsp; It&#8217;s four o&#8217;clock.&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;4:00 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
