<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 07:33:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States and European Commission Announce Task Force to Reduce Europe’s Dependence on Russian Fossil&#160;Fuels</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/fact-sheet-united-states-and-european-commission-announce-task-force-to-reduce-europes-dependence-on-russian-fossil-fuels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen announced a joint Task Force to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian fossil fuels and strengthen European energy security as President Putin wages his war of choice against Ukraine. This Task Force for Energy Security will be chaired by a representative from the White&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen announced a joint Task Force to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian fossil fuels and strengthen European energy security as President Putin wages his war of choice against Ukraine.<br><br>This Task Force for Energy Security will be chaired by a representative from the White House and a representative of the President of the European Commission. It will work to ensure energy security for Ukraine and the EU in preparation for next winter and the following one while supporting the EU’s goal to end its dependence on Russian fossil fuels.<br><br>The Task Force will organize its efforts around two primary goals: (1) Diversifying liquefied natural gas (LNG) supplies in alignment with climate objectives; (2) Reducing demand for natural gas.<br><br><strong>Diversifying LNG Supplies in Alignment with Climate Objectives</strong></p>



<ul><li>The United States will work with international partners and strive to ensure additional LNG volumes for the EU market of at least 15 bcm in 2022, with expected increases going forward.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Commission will undertake efforts to reduce the greenhouse gas intensity of all new LNG infrastructure and associated pipelines, including through using clean energy to power onsite operations, reducing methane leakage, and building clean and renewable hydrogen-ready infrastructure.<br></li><li>The European Commission will prepare an upgraded regulatory framework for energy security of supply and storage, as well as working with EU Member States to accelerate regulatory procedures to review and determine approvals for LNG import infrastructure. The United States will maintain its regulatory environment with an emphasis on supporting this emergency energy security objective and the REPowerEU goals.<br></li><li>The European Commission will work with EU Member States toward the goal of ensuring, until at least 2030, demand for approximately 50 bcm/year of additional U.S. LNG that is consistent with our shared net-zero goals. This also will be done on the understanding that prices should reflect long-term market fundamentals and stability of supply and demand.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Reducing Demand for Natural Gas</strong></p>



<ul><li>The United States and the European Commission will engage key stakeholders, including the private sector, and deploy immediate recommendations to reduce overall gas demand by accelerating market deployment of clean energy measures.<br></li><li>Immediate reductions in gas demand can be achieved through energy efficiency solutions such as ramping up demand response devices, including smart thermostats, and deployment of heat pumps. The REPowerEU plan estimates that reductions through energy savings in homes can replace 15.5 bcm this year and that accelerating wind and solar deployment can replace 20 bcm this year, and through EU’s existing plans such as “Fit for 55” contribute to the EU goal of saving 170 bcm/year by 2030.<br></li><li>As global leaders in renewable energy, the United States and the European Commission will work to expedite planning and approval for renewable energy projects and strategic energy cooperation, including on technologies where we both excel such as offshore wind.<br></li><li>We will continue to collaborate to advance the production and use of clean and renewable hydrogen to displace unabated fossil fuels and cut greenhouse gas emissions, which will include both technology and supporting infrastructure.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Alaska Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-alaska-disaster-declaration-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 01:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Alaska and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and straight-line winds from December 25 to December 27, 2021. Federal funding is available to state, tribal,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Alaska and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and straight-line winds from December 25 to December 27, 2021.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe winter storm and straight-line winds in Fairbanks North Star Borough, Denali Borough, and the City of Nenana.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Thomas J. Dargan as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp;FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Greek Independence Day: A National Day of Celebration of Greek and American Democracy,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/24/greek-independence-day-a-national-day-of-celebration-of-greek-and-american-democracy-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 21:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA A PROCLAMATION In forming a Government that reflected the burgeoning spirit of America and united our young Nation around the core principles of liberty, justice, and the rule of law, our Founders looked to the birthplace of democracy &#8212; Greece.&#160;&#160;Decades after the American Revolution, the people&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">A PROCLAMATION</p>



<p>    In forming a Government that reflected the burgeoning spirit of America and united our young Nation around the core principles of liberty, justice, and the rule of law, our Founders looked to the birthplace of democracy &#8212; Greece.&nbsp;&nbsp;Decades after the American Revolution, the people of Greece came together to bravely affirm their commitment to democracy and declare their own independence from the Ottoman Empire.&nbsp;&nbsp;Today, as we mark the anniversary of Greek independence, we honor our countries&#8217; deep and historic bond &#8212; forged in the struggle for liberty and self-governance &#8212; and the many contributions of the modern Hellenic Republic which promote international peace and stability and uphold our shared values.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Greek bicentennial in 2021 was a year of celebration for Greece, for the Greek American community, and for the strong bilateral relationship between our two nations.&nbsp;&nbsp;The seeds of friendship planted long ago continue to bear fruit for both our people, with Greece and the United States standing together to defend democracy around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;A crucial ally in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, Greece promotes peace and prosperity in the Eastern Mediterranean, Black Sea, and Western Balkans regions, and the United States is grateful for Greece&#8217;s continuing hospitality to the United States Naval Support Activity Souda Bay on Crete.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Greece and the United States are standing together to confront the challenges of our time, from meeting the climate crisis and diversifying the region&#8217;s energy resources to proving that democracies deliver for our people and pushing back against the growing threat of authoritarianism.&nbsp;&nbsp;Through our ongoing Strategic Dialogue, Greece and the United States have increased cooperation across a range of critical issues, and last year&#8217;s update to our Mutual Defense Cooperation Agreement will boost our defense and security cooperation for years to come.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The deep political and historical bonds that unite Greece and the United States are further reinforced by strong ties of family and affection and by the estimated 3 million Americans of Greek descent across our Nation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Throughout my career, I have seen firsthand the courage and determination of the Greek American community, and these qualities have been an invaluable source of strength to our Nation over the past year.&nbsp;&nbsp;Greek Americans have been at the forefront of the fight against the COVID-19 pandemic and our efforts to vaccinate the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;And last November, as Greek Americans proudly celebrated the construction of the Saint Nicholas Greek Orthodox Church and National Shrine in Manhattan 20 years after the original church structure had been destroyed in the September 11th terrorist attacks, they embodied our shared values of perseverance, resilience, and hope for the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;As Greece and the United States look forward to what the next 200 years of partnership will bring, I am confident that our nations and our people will meet every challenge together.&nbsp;&nbsp;On this day, we recommit to the hard work ahead, to fortifying our democracies, and to reaffirming our ironclad friendship.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 25, 2022, as Greek Independence Day:&nbsp;&nbsp;<a>A National Day of Celebration of Greek and American Democracy.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to observe this day with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-fourth day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Readout by the United&#160;States and the European&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/joint-readout-by-the-united-states-and-the-european-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the European Council was joined by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States. The leaders discussed the coordinated and united response of the European Union and the United States to Russia&#8217;s unprovoked and unjustified military aggression in Ukraine. They reviewed their ongoing efforts to impose economic costs on Russia and Belarus, as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the European Council was joined by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States. The leaders discussed the coordinated and united response of the European Union and the United States to Russia&#8217;s unprovoked and unjustified military aggression in Ukraine. They reviewed their ongoing efforts to impose economic costs on Russia and Belarus, as well as their readiness to adopt additional measures and to stop any attempts to circumvent sanctions. Leaders discussed the urgent needs caused by Russia’s aggression, committed to continuing providing humanitarian assistance, including to neighboring countries hosting refugees, and underscored the need for Russia to guarantee humanitarian access to those affected by or fleeing the violence. Leaders welcomed the opening of international investigations, including by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court, and ongoing efforts to gather evidence of atrocities. In addition, leaders discussed EU-U.S. cooperation to reduce dependence on Russian fossil fuels, accelerate the transition to clean energy, as well as the need to respond to evolving food security needs worldwide. The leaders also concurred on the importance of strengthening democratic resilience in Ukraine, Moldova, and the wider Eastern partnership region. Finally, leaders underscored the importance of enhancing transatlantic security and defense, including through robust NATO-EU cooperation as described in the EU’s Strategic Compass.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by President&#160;Biden and President von der&#160;Leyen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/joint-statement-by-president-biden-and-president-von-der-leyen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are united in our condemnation of Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of aggression against Ukraine. We stand in solidarity with the Ukrainian people, who are bravely defending their homeland, and we call on Russia to end the brutal onslaught against its neighbor.&#160; We are united in our support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We are united in our condemnation of Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of aggression against Ukraine. We stand in solidarity with the Ukrainian people, who are bravely defending their homeland, and we call on Russia to end the brutal onslaught against its neighbor.&nbsp; We are united in our support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp; And we are united in our resolve to defend our shared values, including democracy, respect for human rights, global peace and stability, and the rules-based international order.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, we are continuing coordinated transatlantic efforts to support the Ukrainian people, impose severe costs on Russia for its unjustifiable actions, and strengthen the resilience of our democracies, economies, and societies. In particular,&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The United States and the European Union have strengthened and aligned their <strong>sanctions regimes</strong>, together with like-minded partners across the world. Additionally, efforts should be stepped up to coordinate responses against sanctions evasion.<br></li><li>We continue to mobilize and coordinate significant <strong>humanitarian relief</strong> to support people within Ukraine, those who have been forced to flee, and those affected by the severe impacts Russia’s war is causing around the world. This includes more than $1 billion in new humanitarian assistance the United States is prepared to provide on top of the nearly $300 million already contributed and €550 million from the EU.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Union are coordinating closely to ensure that their <strong>efforts on temporary protection and humanitarian admission, including resettlement or transfers,</strong> are complementary and provide much-needed support to Ukraine’s neighbors.<br></li><li>We are announcing new actions to bolster <strong>democratic resilience and defend human rights</strong> in Ukraine and neighboring countries.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Union are supporting the work of <strong>war crimes documentation experts</strong> who are gathering evidence on the ground in Ukraine.<br></li><li>We are taking further, concrete steps in our <strong>energy cooperation </strong>to ensure the security of supply and to reduce dependence on Russian fossil fuels.<br></li><li>In order to prevent a potential <strong>food crisis</strong> triggered by price hikes and disruptions to food supply sparked by Putin&#8217;s war in Ukraine, we intend to redouble our combined efforts to increase global food security and provide direct food aid, where warranted, to our partners worldwide.<br></li><li>We will advance our cooperation on <strong>cybersecurity</strong> through a variety of actions, from supporting the Government of Ukraine on cyber resilience and cyber defense to aiming to combat the abuse of virtual currency.</li></ul>



<p><strong>ANNEX – TRANSATLANTIC COOPERATION AND SUPPORT FOR UKRAINE<br></strong><br><strong>Imposing Additional Costs on Russia</strong><br><br>The United States and the European Union have strengthened and aligned their sanctions regimes, together with our like-minded partners across the world. Today, the United States is sanctioning more than 400 additional individuals and entities to align with measures taken by the EU and our allies and partners. This includes the Duma (Russia’s lower house of parliament) and 328 of its members, dozens of defense companies that fuel Putin’s war machine and sustain its military industrial base, and more than 20 financial elites, including the head of Russia’s largest financial institution. The Commission, in line with its competences, will continue to support further similar measures. Together, we should aim at holding accountable those responsible for the devastation and commit to imposing further costs on Russia until Putin ceases his aggression.<br><br>The United States and the European Union are jointly working to blunt Russia’s ability to deploy its remaining international reserves, including gold, to prop up its economy and fund its illegal war.<br><br>Additionally, as announced in today’s G7 leaders’ statement, we are establishing an initiative to monitor the full implementation of our sanctions measures and coordinate responses against sanctions evasion. This will ensure that Russia will not be able to backfill or find workarounds that undermine the effect of our sanctions.<br><br><strong>Providing Humanitarian Assistance to the Ukrainian People</strong><br><br>We reaffirm our deep support for the Ukrainian people, who are suffering from Russia’s devastating bombing of civilians and civilian infrastructure.&nbsp; We urge Russia to facilitate unhindered humanitarian access and permanent safe passage for civilians. We continue to mobilize humanitarian relief to support people within Ukraine and those who have been forced to flee.&nbsp;&nbsp;The United States and the European Union are responding to the humanitarian needs in Ukraine and in countries impacted by the situation in Ukraine. The United States and the European Commission are coordinating closely on the provision of aid, including a through a newly-established high-level dialogue and a U.S. government liaison in the EU’s Emergency Response Coordination Centre.&nbsp; Today, the United States is announcing it is prepared to provide more than $1 billion in new funding toward humanitarian assistance for those affected by Russia’s war in Ukraine and its severe impacts around the world over the coming months. The European Commission has made available EUR 550 million in emergency and humanitarian assistance and, through the Union Civil Protection Mechanism in cooperation with its partners, it has delivered almost EUR&nbsp;300 million worth of in-kind assistance.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Welcoming Ukrainians Fleeing Violence</strong><br><br>The European Union has generously welcomed almost three and a half million Ukrainians fleeing Russia’s violence, providing them food, shelter, school, and employment opportunities, paying particular attention to the plight of children and providing them protection for the time they need.&nbsp; The United States and the European Union are coordinating closely to ensure that their efforts on temporary protection and humanitarian admission, including resettlement, are complementary and provide much-needed support to Ukraine’s neighbors. Today, the United States is announcing plans to welcome up to 100,000 Ukrainians fleeing Russia’s aggression through the full range of legal pathways, including the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Partnering to Promote Democratic Resilience and Human Rights</strong><br><br>We steadfastly support the democratic aspirations and fundamental freedoms of the Ukrainian people. Today, we are announcing new commitments to bolster societal resilience and defend human rights in Ukraine and neighboring countries, including Moldova.<br><br>To support human rights defenders, anti-corruption watchdogs, journalists, and other members of civil society operating in and around Ukraine, the United States is launching the <em>European Democratic Resilience Initiative</em> (EDRI), which will provide at least $320 million in new funding to these groups and regional governments. The EDRI will support media freedom and counter disinformation, benefit the safety and security of activists and vulnerable groups, strengthen institutions and the region’s rule of law, and help ensure accountability for human rights abuses and violations of international law. And it will expand rapid response capabilities and technical assistance to build resilience to Moscow’s strategic corruption and kleptocracy.<br><br>The European Commission announced plans to reallocate funds from EU programmes to support civil society organizations, human rights defenders, journalists, and pro-democracy activists in Ukraine, Belarus and Moldova. In addition, the European Endowment for Democracy, with EU funding contributions, provided a significant number of emergency grants to contribute to saving and sustaining civic activism and media pluralism in Ukraine. It also opened a Centre for Ukrainian Activists (CUA) in Przemyśl, Poland, to provide support for activists and independent journalists in maintaining and sustaining their connections to their activities inside Ukraine.<br><br><strong>Promoting Accountability<br><br></strong>There should be accountability for any war crimes committed in Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;The United States and the European Union are supporting the important work of war crimes documentation experts who are gathering evidence on the ground in Ukraine. The coordination of documentation and evidence preservation efforts to ensure such accountability should be facilitated.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting Europe’s Energy Security<br></strong><br>We reconfirm our commitment to Europe’s energy security and to accelerating the global transition to clean energy. Energy security and sustainability for the EU and Ukraine are essential for peace, freedom and democracy in Europe.&nbsp; The EU has confirmed its objective to reach independence from Russian gas well before the end of the decade while working to ensure reliable, affordable, and clean energy supplies to citizens and businesses in the EU and its neighbourhood.&nbsp; The United States intends to partner with the EU on these efforts.&nbsp; We understand that the rapid transition to clean energy is essential to advancing EU independence from Russian fossil fuels and are committed to meeting the goals of the Paris Agreement, the objective of net zero emissions by 2050, and keeping a 1.5 degrees Celsius limit on temperature rise within reach. &nbsp;In line with this vision, the European Commission and United States will establish a joint Task Force to address the immediate energy security needs of the EU and accelerate the clean energy transition.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Securing Global Food Supplies</strong><br><br>We are deeply concerned by how Putin’s war in Ukraine has caused major disruptions to international food and agriculture supply chains and the threat it poses to global food security. We recognize that many countries around the world have relied on imported food staples and fertilizer inputs from Ukraine and Russia, with Putin’s aggression disrupting that trade.&nbsp; As the United States and EU comprise many of the world’s major agricultural producers and strong economies, we commit to redoubling our combined efforts to provide direct food aid and other forms of assistance, where warranted, and, to continue the necessary support for agricultural innovation and sustainable productivity growth to ensure global food security, while balancing enhancing climate resilience and reducing agricultural greenhouse gas emissions.<br><br>We are committed to working with partners to address the attendant supply challenges and maintaining strong, ruled-based, and open global markets for staple agricultural commodities that feed the world. Specifically, the United States, through Feed the Future and our nutrition commitments, is providing over $11 billion over the next five years to address food security threats and nutrition across the globe.&nbsp; Additionally, the United States will remain one of the top providers of humanitarian food and nutrition assistance globally, having contributed approximately $4.6 billion in humanitarian food and nutrition assistance in 2021.&nbsp; We are also identifying tools in the U.S. government’s existing food security tool kit and determining whether programs are fit for purpose for this situation and will make strategic adjustments as needed.<br><br>For the period 2021 &#8211; 2024, the EU is pledging at least EUR 2.5 billion for international cooperation related to nutrition.&nbsp; This international cooperation programme will support food systems in about 70 partner countries. The proposed EU Emergency Support Programme for Ukraine of EUR 330 million will secure access to basic goods and services for the Ukrainian population and also support Ukraine’s agricultural sector.<br><br><strong>Ensuring the Security of Cyberspace</strong><br><br>We are committed to advancing our cybersecurity cooperation, both in response to Russia’s illegal further invasion of Ukraine and in support of our longer-term strategic objectives.&nbsp; Together, we will enhance our efforts to coordinate cybersecurity assistance and provide Internet access to the Governments of Ukraine and Moldova, working with Member States and other likeminded partners. In the context of Ukraine and more generally, we will continue to reinforce responsible state behavior in cyberspace and to work together to increase cyber resilience in the face of destructive, disruptive, and destabilizing cyber activity by both States and non-State actors, while also working to hold accountable those responsible for such activity.<br><br>We will work towards establishing more structured cybersecurity information exchanges on threats and threat actors and deepen our cooperation on new cybersecurity technologies and standards.&nbsp; We are committed to our partnership in the Counter Ransomware Initiative to disrupt ransomware groups and reduce related threats to our citizens and businesses. We will enhance efforts to address the abuse of virtual currency; bolster cybersecurity resilience; increase partner capacity for detecting and responding to ransomware activity within their own borders; and work to jointly hold accountable states that act as safe havens for ransomware activity.<br><br><strong>Combatting Illicit Use of Digital Assets</strong><br><br>We intend to announce deeper collaboration to combat the illicit use of digital assets, including their potential misuse in evading multilateral sanctions imposed in response to Russia’s unprovoked military invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; Together, we intend to deepen our shared commitment to advance anti-money laundering and countering financing of terrorism (AML/CFT) for digital assets, consistent with the Financial Action Task Force (FATF) standards.<br><br>We will share best practices and coordinate capacity building efforts to help other countries implement AML/CFT frameworks for digital assets. We intend to form a transatlantic sprint between U.S. and EU government officials and, as appropriate, digital asset service providers, to expedite and increase sharing of financial intelligence on illicit use of digital assets. Finally, we will seek opportunities for joint actions against those who facilitate the misuse of digital assets for illicit activity.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and European Council President Charles Michel Upon Arrival at the European&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/24/remarks-by-president-biden-and-european-council-president-charles-michel-upon-arrival-at-the-european-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Europa Building Brussels, Belgium 7:19 P.M. CET&#160;PRESIDENT MICHEL:&#160; We are very pleased, dear President, dear Joe, to welcome you again in Brussels.&#160; Your presence here and your participation in this European Council meeting is a very strong signal.&#160;&#160;Our unity is rock solid, and we are very, very pleased to coordinate, to cooperate with you.&#160; These&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Europa Building <br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>7:19 P.M. CET<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT MICHEL:&nbsp; We are very pleased, dear President, dear Joe, to welcome you again in Brussels.&nbsp; Your presence here and your participation in this European Council meeting is a very strong signal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our unity is rock solid, and we are very, very pleased to coordinate, to cooperate with you.&nbsp; These are difficult times, challenging times, and we need to take the right and the intelligent decisions for the future and for the security, for the stability.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And thank you for this excellent cooperation and coordination.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I came to congratulate a man who just got reelected without opposition.&nbsp; I dream about that someday.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, look, from the very beginning, I was of the view: The single most important thing that we have to do in the West is be united.&nbsp; I’m not saying that &#8212; that’s not a euphemism.&nbsp; I mean it literally.&nbsp; Literally.<br>&nbsp;<br>I spent some time with Vladimir Putin back in November and December, and we had a conference in &#8212; in Switzerland, at the time.&nbsp; And it was clear to me, and it was to you, that his intentions were very different than benign intentions.<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of the things that he’s tried to do &#8212; his overwhelming objective &#8212; and I’ve been speaking about it for a year and a half.&nbsp; His overwhelming objective is to demonstrate that democracies cannot function in the 21st century &#8212; because things are moving so rapidly, they require consensus, and it’s too difficult to get consensus &#8212; and autocracies are going to rule.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a matter of fact, we’ve lost more democratic in- &#8212; democratic countries &#8212; fewer democratic countries today than there were 10 years ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, from the very beginning, my objective &#8212; and I had a great partner in this &#8212; was to see to it that we built total, complete unity among the major democracies of the world.&nbsp; I’m not joking about that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s why I called just a couple weeks ago and asked NATO to set up a new &#8212; a NATO meeting of the heads of state, and it was took &#8212; which took place today.&nbsp; And I fortunately am able to attend two other conferences.<br>&nbsp;<br>But my point is: unity.&nbsp; Unity.&nbsp; And the very thing that Putin has tried to do from the beginning &#8212; and I’ve been saying this since my days as Vice President of the United States &#8212; is to break up NATO &#8212; break up NATO.&nbsp; He’d rather face 30 independent countries than 30 united countries with the United States of America.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; I’m being deadly earnest.&nbsp; I believe that’s been his intention from the very, very beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, what I want to thank Michel for is the &#8212; Michel &#8212; is that the whole idea of the unity of Europe as a whole, not just NATO &#8212; the G7 and this organization &#8212; really matters.&nbsp; It’s the single most important thing that we can do to stop this guy who’s &#8212; in our country, we believe he’s already committed war crimes.<br>&nbsp;<br>But thank you very much for the time, and thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT MICHEL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you trust China?&nbsp; Do you trust China?<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Well, we’ll discuss China.&nbsp; I’ve spent some time with Xi Jinping.&nbsp; And I hope we’re going to get a chance to discuss China.</p>



<p>7:23 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in Press&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/24/remarks-by-president-biden-in-press-conference-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49664</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NATO HeadquartersBrussels, Belgium 6:32 P.M. CET THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening, everyone.  With all the press that&#8217;s here, you must be getting very tired.  Am I the 16th or 17th?  At any rate, all kidding aside, thank you for taking the time. I &#8212; today marks one month since Russia began its carnage in Ukraine, the brutal&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">NATO Headquarters<br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>6:32 P.M. CET<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening, everyone.  With all the press that&#8217;s here, you must be getting very tired.  Am I the 16th or 17th?  At any rate, all kidding aside, thank you for taking the time.</p>



<p>I &#8212; today marks one month since Russia began its carnage in Ukraine, the brutal invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; And we held a NATO summit the very next day.&nbsp; At that time, my overwhelming objective, wanting that summit, was to have absolute unity on three key important issues among our NATO and European allies.</p>



<p>First was to support Ukraine with military and humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second was to impose the most significant &#8212; the most significant sanctions &#8212; economic sanction regime ever, in order to cripple Putin’s economy and punish him for his actions.</p>



<p>Third was to fortify the eastern flank of our NATO Allies, who were obviously very, very concerned and somewhat at &#8212; worried what would happen.</p>



<p>We accomplished all three of these.&nbsp; And today, we&#8217;re determined to sustain those efforts and to build on them.<br>The United States has committed to provide over $2 billion in military equipment to Ukraine since I became President &#8212; anti-air systems, anti-armor systems, ammunition.&nbsp; And our weapons are flowing into Ukraine as I speak.</p>



<p>And today, I&#8217;m announcing the United States have prepared to commit more than $1 billion in humanitarian assistance to help get relief to millions of Ukrainians affected by the war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Many Ukrainian refugees will wish to stay in Europe, closer to their homes.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve also &#8212; will welcome 100,000 Ukrainians to the United States with a focus on reuniting families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will invest $320 million to bolster democratic resilience and defend human rights in Ukraine and neighboring countries.</p>



<p>We’re also coordinating with the G7 and the European Union on food security, as well as energy security, and I’ll have more to say about that tomorrow.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also announcing new sanctions of more than 400 individuals and entities aligned with &#8212; in alignment with the European Union: more than 300 members of the Duma, oligarchs, and Russian defense companies that fuel the Russian war machine.</p>



<p>In addition to the 100,000 U.S. forces now stationed in Europe to defend NATO territory, NATO established, as you already know, four new battle groups in Romania, Hungary, Bulgaria, and Slovakia to reinforce the eastern front.</p>



<p>Putin was banking on NATO being split.&nbsp; In my early conversation with him in December and early January, it was clear to me he didn&#8217;t think we could sustain this cohesion.</p>



<p>NATO has never, never been more united than it is today. &nbsp;Putin is getting exactly the opposite of what he intended to have as a consequence of going into Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We built that same unity with our European &#8212; the European Union and with the leading democracies of the G7 &#8212; in the G7.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I want to thank you, and I&#8217;ll be now happy to take your questions.&nbsp; Since there&#8217;s so many people out there, I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I’ve been given a list.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, how about Chris with the Associated Press?&nbsp; First question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; So you&#8217;ve warned about the real threat of chemical weapons being used.&nbsp; Have you gathered specific intelligence that suggests that President Putin is deploying these weapons, moving them to position, or considering their use?</p>



<p>And would the U.S. or NATO respond with military action if he did use chemical weapons?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know, on the first question, I can&#8217;t answer that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give you intelligence data, number one.</p>



<p>Number two, we would respond.&nbsp; We would respond if he uses it.&nbsp; The nature of the response would depend on the nature of the use.</p>



<p>Josh, of Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perhaps I&#8217;ll just project, Mr. President.&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If I had your voice, I’d had been elected a lot earlier.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Microphone is extended towards press member.)&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll give &#8212; I&#8217;ll give it a try.&nbsp; It&#8217;s got a long arm.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Can you talk to us about two things, sir: One, since your conversation with President Xi of China, have you seen any indications of action or lack of action from China that has led you to believe whether they will intervene and help Russia either with the sale of arms or the provision of supplies to support this war in Ukraine?<br>And secondly, can you say whether this &#8212; the conversation today turned to the subject of food shortages, and what the U.S. will do to address wheat shortages, in particular, as a result of this war?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; On the first question relating to President Xi Jinping of China, I had a very straightforward conversation with Xi &#8212; now, I guess, it&#8217;s six days ago, seven days ago &#8212; in that range.</p>



<p>And I made it clear to him &#8212; I made no threats, but I made it clear to him that &#8212; make sure he understood the consequences of him helping Russia, as had been reported and as what was expected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I made no threats, but I pointed out the number of American and foreign corporations that left Russia as a consequence of their barbaric behavior.&nbsp; And I indicated that I knew how much he &#8212; because we had long discussions in the past about his interest in making sure he has economic relations and economic growth with Europe and the United States &#8212; and indicated that he&#8217;d be putting himself in significant jeopardy and those &#8212; in those aims if, in fact, he were to move forward.</p>



<p>I am not going to comment on any detail about what we know or don&#8217;t know as a consequence of that conversation.&nbsp; But tomorrow is &#8212; is it tomorrow or next Monday that Ursula is having that conference with China?</p>



<p>WHITE HOUSE AIDE:&nbsp; April 1st.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The 1st &#8212; on April 1st.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve had discussions &#8212; because I think that China understands that its economic future is much more closely tied to the West than it is to Russia.&nbsp; And so I &#8212; I&#8217;m hopeful that he &#8212; he does not get engaged.<br>We also did discuss today that there&#8217;s a need for us to set up, NATO to set up, and &#8212; and the EU &#8212; to set up a system whereby we have an organization looking at who has violated any of the sanctions, and where and when and how they violated them.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something we&#8217;re going to put in train.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not done yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with regard to Xi, I &#8212; I have nothing more to report.<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to food shortage, yes, we did talk about food shortages.&nbsp; And &#8212; and it&#8217;s going to be real.&nbsp; The price of these sanctions is not just imposed upon Russia, it&#8217;s imposed upon an awful lot of countries as well, including European countries and our country as well.&nbsp; And &#8212; because both Russia and Ukraine have been the breadbasket of Europe in terms of wheat, for example &#8212; just to give you one example.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we had a long discussion in the G7 with the &#8212; with both the United States, which has a significant &#8212; the third-largest producer of wheat in the world &#8212; as well as Canada, which is also a major, major producer. &nbsp;And we both talked about how we could increase and disseminate more rapidly food. &nbsp;Food shortages.<br>&nbsp;<br>And in addition to that, we talked about urging all the European countries and everyone else to end trade restrictions on &#8212; on sending &#8212; limitations on sending food abroad.&nbsp; And so, we are in the process of working out, with our European friends, what it would be &#8212; what it would take to help alleviate the concerns relative to food shortages.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also talked about a significant, major U.S. investment, among others, in terms of providing for the need for humanitarian assistance, including food, as we move forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Tarini, of the Wall Street Journal.&nbsp; Watch out you don&#8217;t get hit in the head there now.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, in your view, does President Zelenskyy need to cede any Ukrainian territory in order to gain a ceasefire with Russia?&nbsp; Or is that completely off the table?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then also, do you think that Russia needs to be removed from the G20?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; On the latter point, my answer is yes.&nbsp; That depends on the G20.&nbsp; I &#8212; that was raised today.&nbsp; And I raised the possibility, if that can&#8217;t be done &#8212; if Indonesia and others do not agree, then we should, in my view, ask to have both Ukraine be able to attend the meetings, as well as &#8212; well, basically Ukraine being able to attend the G20 meetings and observe.<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to &#8212; what was the first question?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you think that Ukraine needs to cease &#8212; to give up any territory in order to get a ceasefire.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That is a total judgment based on Ukraine.&nbsp; &#8220;Nothing about Ukraine without Ukraine.&#8221;&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe that they&#8217;re going to have to do that, but that&#8217;s a judgment.&nbsp; There&#8217;s negotiations &#8212; that are discussions, I should say &#8212; that have taken place that I have not been part of, including Ukrainians.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s their judgment to make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Cecilia, ABC.&nbsp; There you are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Oop.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, (inaudible). &nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Sir, you&#8217;ve made it very clear in this conflict that you do not want to see World War Three.&nbsp; But is it possible that, in expressing that so early, that you were too quick to rule out direct military intervention in this war?&nbsp; Could Putin have been emboldened, knowing that you were not going to get involved directly in this conflict?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No and no.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You do not believe that?<br>&nbsp;<br>And to clarify, on chemical weapons: Could &#8212; if chemical weapons were used in Ukraine, would that trigger a military response from NATO?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It would re- &#8212; it would trigger a response in kind, whether or not &#8212; you&#8217;re asking whether NATO would cross; we&#8217;d make that decision at the time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my final question: Because you&#8217;re heading to Poland tomorrow, do you think that getting a firsthand look at the effects of this war on these millions of Ukrainians who have fled their country could change the way that you might respond?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think so, because I&#8217;ve been to many, many warzones.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been in refugee camps.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been in warzones for the last 15 years.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; it’s devastating.&nbsp; And what &#8212; the thing you look at the most is you see these young children, you see children without parents that are in those camps or in &#8212; or refugees.&nbsp; You see women and husbands &#8212; men and women who are completely lost and have no &#8212; you see the look &#8212; that blank look on their face, that absolute feeling of, “My God, where am I?&nbsp; What&#8217;s going to happen to me?”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, it &#8212; what it will do, it will reinforce my commitment to have the United States make sure we are a major piece of dealing with the relocation of all those folks, as well as humanitarian assistance needed both inside Ukraine and outside Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, this is not something that Poland or Romania or Germany should carry on their own.&nbsp; This is an international responsibility.&nbsp; And the United States, as the leader &#8212; one of the leaders in the international community, has an obligation to be engaged &#8212; to be engaged and do all we can to ease the suffering and pain of innocent women and children, and men, for that matter, throughout &#8212; throughout Ukraine and those who have made it across the border.<br>&nbsp;<br>I plan on attempting to see those folks, as well as I hope I&#8217;m going to be able to see &#8212; I guess I&#8217;m not supposed to say where I&#8217;m going, am I?&nbsp; But anyway, I hope I get to see a lot of people.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Markus, with Der Spiegel.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Mr. President.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a presidential election coming up in 2024.&nbsp; And as you know, there are wide- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You’re kidding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It’s true.&nbsp; And there are widespread concerns in Europe that a figure like your predecessor, maybe even your predecessor himself, might get elected president again.&nbsp; So, are there any steps, anything you&#8217;re trying to do and NATO is trying to do here, these days, to prevent what you&#8217;re trying to do becoming undone two years from now?&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I &#8212; that’s not how I think of this.&nbsp; I’ve been dealing with foreign policy for longer than anybody that’s involved in this process right now.&nbsp; I have no concerns about the impact &#8212;</p>



<p>I made a commitment when I ran this time. &nbsp;I wasn’t going to run again, and I mean that sincerely. &nbsp;I had no intention of running for President again and &#8212; until I saw those folks coming out of the fields in Virginia carrying torches and carrying Nazi banners and literally singing the same vile rhyme that they used in Germany in the early ‘20s &#8212; or ‘30s, I should say. &nbsp;And then, when the gentleman you mentioned was asked what he thought &#8212; and a young woman was killed, a protester &#8212; and he asked &#8212; was asked what he thought, he said, “There are very good people on both sides.” &nbsp;And that&#8217;s when I decided I wasn&#8217;t going to be quiet any longer.<br>&nbsp;<br>And when I ran this time &#8212; and I think the American press, whether they look at me favorably or unfavorably, acknowledge this &#8212; I made a determination: Nothing is worth &#8212; no election is worth my not doing exactly what I think is the right thing.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; I&#8217;m too long in the tooth to fool with this any longer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, we&#8217;re a long way off in elections &#8212; a long way off.&nbsp; My focus of any election is on making sure that we retain the House and the United States Senate so that I have the room to continue to do the things that I’ve been able to do in terms of grow the economy and deal in a rational way with American foreign policy and lead the world &#8212; lead the &#8212; be the leader of the free world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; but it&#8217;s not a &#8212; it&#8217;s not an illogical question for someone to ask.&nbsp; I say to people at home: Imagine if we sat and watched the doors of the Bundestag broken down and police officers killed and hundreds of people storming in, or imagine if we saw that happening in the British Parliament or whatever.&nbsp; How would we feel?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of the things that I take some solace from is: I don&#8217;t think you&#8217;ll find any European leader who thinks that I am not up to the job.&nbsp; And I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like, “Whoa…&#8221;&nbsp; It’s that &#8212; that &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>The point is that when &#8212; the first G7 meeting I attended, like the one I did today, was in Great Britain.&nbsp; And I sat down, and I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And one of the &#8212; one of my counterparts, colleagues, a head of state, said, “For how long?”&nbsp; “For how long?”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I don&#8217;t blame &#8212; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t criticize anybody for asking that question. &nbsp;But the next election, I&#8217;d be very fortunate if I had that same man running against me.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you very, very much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, no &#8212; yeah, one final question.&nbsp; Right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Hey, well, wait &#8212; hold on a second, please.&nbsp; I was supposed to be, an hour ago, at the European Union meeting and &#8212; to speak.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I’m not thanking you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Someone I haven’t called on before.&nbsp; You.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Who are you?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m Christina Ruffini from CBS.&nbsp; Thank you, sir.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, deterrence didn&#8217;t work.&nbsp; What makes you think Vladimir Putin will alter course based on the action you&#8217;ve taken today?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let’s get something straight: You remember, if you’ve covered me from the beginning, I did not say that in fact the sanctions would deter him.&nbsp; Sanctions never deter.&nbsp; You keep talking about that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Sanctions never deter.&nbsp;&nbsp;The maintenance of sanctions &#8212; the maintenance of sanctions, the increasing the pain, and the demonstration &#8212; why I asked for this NATO meeting today &#8212; is to be sure that after a month, we will sustain what we&#8217;re doing not just next month, the following month, but for the remainder of this entire year.&nbsp;&nbsp;That&#8217;s what will stop him.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe the actions today will have an impact on making Russia change course in Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not what I said.&nbsp; You &#8212; you &#8212; you&#8217;re playing a game with me.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; (Off-mic.)<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; The answer is no.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think what happens is, we have to demonstrate &#8212; the purpose &#8212; the single-most important thing is for us to stay unified, and the world continue to focus on what a brute this guy is and all the innocent people&#8217;s lives that are being lost and ruined, and what&#8217;s going on.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the important thing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, look, if you&#8217;re Putin and you think that the &#8212; that Europe is going to crack in a month or six weeks or two months, why not &#8212; they can take anything for another month.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we have to demonstrate &#8212; the reason I asked for the meeting &#8212; we have to stay fully, totally, thoroughly united.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>6:51 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Leaders’ Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/g7-leaders-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49661</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, the Leaders of the G7, met today in Brussels at the invitation of the German G7 Presidency, to further strengthen our cooperation in light of Russia’s unjustifiable, unprovoked and illegal aggression and President Putin’s war of choice against independent and sovereign Ukraine. We will stand with the government and people of Ukraine. We are&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<ol><li>We, the Leaders of the G7, met today in Brussels at the invitation of the German G7 Presidency, to further strengthen our cooperation in light of Russia’s unjustifiable, unprovoked and illegal aggression and President Putin’s war of choice against independent and sovereign Ukraine. We will stand with the government and people of Ukraine.<br></li><li>We are united in our resolve to restore peace and stability and uphold international law. Following the United Nations General Assembly resolution on<br>2 March 2022, we will continue to stand with the overwhelming majority of the international community, in condemning Russia’s military aggression and the suffering and loss of life it continues to cause.<br></li><li>We remain appalled by and condemn the devastating attacks on the Ukrainian population and civilian infrastructure, including hospitals and schools. We welcome the investigations of international mechanisms, including by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court. We will work together to support the gathering of evidence of war crimes. The siege of Mariupol and other Ukrainian cities, and the denial of humanitarian access by Russian military forces are unacceptable. Russian forces must immediately provide for safe pathways to other parts of Ukraine, as well as humanitarian aid to be delivered to Mariupol and other besieged cities.<br></li><li>The Russian leadership is obligated to immediately comply with the order of the International Court of Justice to suspend the military operations that it commenced on 24 February 2022 in the territory of Ukraine, without any further delay. We also urge Russia to withdraw its military forces and equipment from the entire territory of Ukraine.<br></li><li>We further call upon the Belarusian authorities to avoid further escalation and to refrain from using their military forces against Ukraine. Moreover, we urge all countries not to give military or other assistance to Russia to help continue its aggression in Ukraine. We will be vigilant regarding any such assistance.<br> </li><li>We will spare no efforts to hold President Putin and the architects and supporters of this aggression, including the Lukashenko regime in Belarus, accountable for their actions. To this end, we will continue to work together, along with our allies and partners around the world.<br></li><li>We underline our resolve to impose severe consequences on Russia, including by fully implementing the economic and financial measures we already imposed. We will continue to cooperate closely, including by engaging other governments on adopting similar restrictive measures to those already imposed by G7 members and on refraining from evasion, circumvention and backfilling that seek to undercut or mitigate the effects of our sanctions. We task the relevant Ministers in a focused initiative to monitor the full implementation of sanctions and to coordinate responses related to evasive measures, including regarding gold transactions by the Central Bank of Russia. We stand ready to apply additional measures as required, continuing to act in unity as we do so. We commend those partners who have aligned with us in these efforts.<br></li><li>Russia’s attack has already risked the safety and security of nuclear sites in Ukraine. Russian military activities are creating extreme risks for the population and the environment, with the potential for catastrophic result. Russia must comply with its international obligations and refrain from any activity that imperils nuclear sites, allowing unhindered control by the Ukrainian authorities, as well as full access by and cooperation with the International Atomic Energy Agency.<br></li><li>We warn against any threat of the use of chemical, biological and nuclear weapons or related materials. We recall Russia’s obligations under the international treaties to which it is a signatory, and which protect us all. In this regard, we categorically denounce Russia’s malicious and completely unfounded disinformation campaign against Ukraine, a state in full compliance with international non-proliferation agreements. We express concern about other countries and actors that have amplified Russia’s disinformation campaign.<br> </li><li>We are resolved in our support to the Ukrainian people in their heroic resistance to Russia’s unjustifiable and illegal aggression. We will step up our support to Ukraine and neighbouring countries. We thank all those who are already providing humanitarian aid to Ukraine and ask others to join. We will furthermore collaborate in our efforts to bolster democratic resilience and defend human rights in Ukraine and neighbouring countries.<br></li><li>We will continue efforts to support Ukraine in defending its networks against cyber incidents. In preparation for any Russian malicious cyber response to the actions we have taken, we are taking steps to increase the resilience of the infrastructure in our respective nations by strengthening our coordinated cyber defences and improving our shared awareness of cyber threats. We will also work to hold accountable those actors that engage in destructive, disruptive, or destabilising activities in cyberspace.<br></li><li>We further commend neighbouring states for their solidarity and humanity in welcoming Ukrainian refugees and third country nationals from Ukraine. We highlight the need to further increase international assistance to countries neighbouring Ukraine, and, as a concrete contribution to this end, underline our commitment to receiving, protecting, and supporting refugees and displaced persons as a consequence of the conflict. We thus all stand ready to welcome them on our territories. We will take further steps to broaden our support to Ukraine and neighbouring countries.<br></li><li>We are concerned by the escalating and reinforced repression against the Russian people and the increasingly hostile rhetoric of the Russian leadership, including against ordinary citizens. We deplore the Russian leadership’s attempt to deprive Russian citizens of access to unbiased information through censorship, and denounce its malicious disinformation campaigns, which we will not leave unaddressed. We express our support to those Russian and Belarusian citizens standing up against the unjustified war of aggression against their close neighbour Ukraine. The world sees them.<br></li><li>The people of Russia must know that we hold no grievances against them. It is President Putin, his government and supporters, including the Lukashenko regime in Belarus, who are imposing this war and its consequences on Russians and it is their decision that besmirches the history of the Russian people.<br></li><li>We are taking further steps to reduce our reliance on Russian energy, and will work together to this end. At the same time, we will ensure secure alternative and sustainable supplies, and act in solidarity and close coordination in the case of possible supply disruptions. We commit to actively support countries willing to phase out their dependency on Russian gas, oil and coal imports. We call on oil and gas producing countries to act in a responsible manner and to increase deliveries to international markets, noting that OPEC has a key role to play. We will work with them and all partners to ensure stable and sustainable global energy supplies. This crisis reinforces our determination to meet the goals of the Paris agreement and of the Glasgow climate pact and limit the rise in global temperatures to 1.5°C, by accelerating reduction of our reliance on fossil fuels and our transition to clean energy. <br></li><li>We stand in solidarity with our partners who have to bear the rising price of President Putin’s unilateral choice to wage war in Europe. His decision is putting the global economic recovery at risk, undermines the resilience of global value chains and will have severe impacts on the most fragile countries. We call on the international community to take action by fully recognising Russia’s responsibility and protecting the most vulnerable countries, with the support of international and regional institutions.<br></li><li>More immediately, President Putin’s war places global food security under increased pressure. We recall that the implementation of our sanctions against Russia takes into account the need to avoid impact on global agricultural trade. We remain determined to monitor the situation closely and do what is necessary to prevent and respond to the evolving global food security crisis. We will make coherent use of all instruments and funding mechanisms to address food security, and build resilience in the agriculture sector in line with climate and environment goals. We will address potential agricultural production and trade disruptions, in particular in vulnerable countries. We commit to provide a sustainable food supply in Ukraine and support continued Ukrainian production efforts.<br></li><li>We will work with and step up our collective contribution to relevant international institutions including the World Food Programme (WFP), in parallel with Multilateral Development Banks and International Financial Institutions, to provide support to countries with acute food insecurity. We call for an extraordinary session of the Council of the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) to address the consequences on world food security and agriculture arising from the Russian aggression against Ukraine. We call on all participants of the Agriculture Markets Information System (AMIS) to continue to share information and explore options to keep prices under control, including making stocks available, in particular to the WFP. We will avoid export bans and other trade-restrictive measures, maintain open and transparent markets, and call on others to do likewise, consistent with World Trade Organization (WTO) rules, including WTO notification requirements.<br></li><li>International organisations and multilateral fora should no longer conduct their activities with Russia in a business as usual manner. We will work closely with our partners to act as appropriate, based on shared interests, as well as rules and regulations of respective institutions.</li></ol>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The White&#160;House Announces 2022 Springtime&#160;Events</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/the-white-house-announces-2022-springtime-events/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 17:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today,&#160;the President and First Lady&#160;are pleased&#160;to announce plans for the following springtime events: Spring Garden Tours and the White House Easter Egg Roll.&#160; &#160; SPRING GARDEN TOURS&#160; The President and First Lady will continue the annual tradition of opening the White House gardens and South Grounds to members of the public for Spring Garden Tours.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today,&nbsp;the President and First Lady&nbsp;are pleased&nbsp;to announce plans for the following springtime events: Spring Garden Tours and the White House Easter Egg Roll.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SPRING GARDEN TOURS&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The President and First Lady will continue the annual tradition of opening the White House gardens and South Grounds to members of the public for Spring Garden Tours. This season’s tour weekend is scheduled for 10:00 AM ET to 4:30 PM ET on Saturday, April 9 and Sunday, April 10.</p>



<p>These&nbsp;tours&nbsp;are free and open to members of the&nbsp;public; however, a ticket is required for all attendees, including small children. The National Park Service (NPS) will distribute free, timed tickets at a tent stationed near the Ellipse Visitors Pavilion each day beginning at 8:30 AM ET. The entry point for all guests will be located near the intersection of 15th Street NW and Constitution Avenue NW. Tickets will be distributed, one ticket per person, on a first-come, first-served basis.</p>



<p><strong>WHITE HOUSE EASTER EGG ROLL</strong></p>



<p>The White House Easter Egg Roll will take place on the South Lawn on Easter Monday, April 18, continuing one of the oldest traditions in White House history.</p>



<p><strong><em>Online Ticket Lottery</em><br></strong>White House Easter Egg Roll tickets are free to the public and may be requested through an online lottery starting on&nbsp;Friday, March 25&nbsp;at 10:00 AM ET, and closing on Thursday, March 31, at 10:00 AM ET.&nbsp;Entering the lottery is free of charge, and randomly selected lottery winners will be notified via email by Thursday, April 7. Tickets are not for sale or resale. Those interested in attending may enter the lottery&nbsp;<a href="https://www.recreation.gov/ticket/facility/250029">here</a>.</p>



<p><em>Additional information and press coverage opportunities to be released in the coming days.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Volunteer Opportunities</em></strong><br>As in past years, the White House will welcome volunteers interested in supporting the White House Easter Egg Roll through an online application. Those interested in applying to volunteer may register <a href="https://events.whitehouse.gov/EventInterestHolidayVol?rid=PBBWVB69PK">here.</a> The deadline to submit a White House Easter Egg Roll Volunteer application is Thursday, March 31, 2022 at 10:00 AM ET.</p>



<p><em>The White House will continue to closely monitor the COVID-19 situation based on recommendations from the CDC and other public health officials and medical experts. The White House reserves the right to adjust availability of the public tours as necessary to adhere to the latest health guidance. Anyone who has tested positive for COVID-19, has had any COVID-19 symptoms, or been in close contact with someone confirmed or suspected to have COVID-19 within 10 days prior to their visit may not attend. Face masks will be available when entering the White House complex for those who choose to wear them.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Meetings with the G7 and the European&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/24/background-press-call-on-president-bidens-meetings-with-the-g7-and-the-european-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Via Teleconference 12:08 P.M. CET MODERATOR:&#160; For the second section, which is embargoed until 2:15 p.m. Central European Time/9:15 a.m. Eastern time, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you [senior administration official] to get us started. SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Thanks, [senior administration official].&#160; And let me follow up from [senior administration official] and just preview some&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"> Via Teleconference</p>



<p>12:08 P.M. CET</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; For the second section, which is embargoed until 2:15 p.m. Central European Time/9:15 a.m. Eastern time, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you [senior administration official] to get us started.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And let me follow up from [senior administration official] and just preview some of the G7 discussions, in particular the actions we have planned on sanctions.</p>



<p>So, today the U.S. will sanction Russian elites, the Duma, and over 300 Duma members, and over 40 Russian defense companies.&nbsp; All of this will align and strengthen our sanctions in close coordination and partnership with the EU and G7.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The G7 and EU will also announce a new sanctions evasion initiative that’s designed to prevent circumvention or backfilling of our unprecedented measures.&nbsp; And that will happen through closing down avenues, for example, for the Russian Central Bank to prop up the ruble.&nbsp; It could be through growing our coalition of countries to deny cutting-edge technology to Russia, or through preventing Russia from designating crony banks to do it business abroad.</p>



<p>In all cases, we’ll use this initiative to share information and coordinate our responses to prevent the emergence of any safe haven for Russia, whether it’s in China or any other country.</p>



<p>Third, the G7 and the EU will also continue to blunt the Central Bank of Russia’s ability to deploy international reserves by making clear that any transaction involving gold related to the Central Bank of Russia is prohibited.</p>



<p>And for context: As of June of last year &#8212; the last official snapshot of Russia’s Central Bank reserves &#8212; gold was 20 percent of the total.&nbsp; And our purpose now is to fully disarm its war chest by making sure its foreign reserves serve no purpose in propping up the Russian currency.</p>



<p>And finally, we and the G7 will join together in saying that international organizations and multilateral fora should no longer conduct their activities with Russia in a business-as-usual manner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our purpose here is to methodically remove the benefits and privileges Russia once enjoyed as a participant in the international economic order.&nbsp; And this follows our actions to remove Russia’s most-favored-nation trading status and to suspend its borrowing privileges from the IMF and the World Bank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You all have the factsheet, so I won’t get into all the detail on the specifics, but let me just step back and put all these actions into context.</p>



<p>All of you will remember that well before Putin invaded Ukraine, we warned that he would face the most severe sanctions ever levied on Russia and ever imposed on a large market economy.&nbsp; We also warned that we would respond to an invasion with unprecedented speed and with a historic degree of coordination.</p>



<p>Over the past month, we’ve done exactly what we said we’d do.&nbsp; Judging from the words and actions of the Russian leadership, this caught the Kremlin by surprise.&nbsp; Putin himself said these sanctions are delivering a profound blow; they&#8217;re causing “unprecedented” pressure, in his own words.&nbsp; And yesterday, Minister Lavrov said no one could have predicted the actions we’d take.&nbsp; But the reality is these are precisely the consequences we&#8217;ve signaled.</p>



<p>And the consequence is that Russia is now looking at a contraction in its economy of 15 percent this year, according to private sector estimates.&nbsp; To put that into perspective, that would be three times as much as the GDP declined after Russia’s debt default in 1998.&nbsp; The Institute for International Finance estimates that the shock to Russia’s GDP this year will wipe out the past 15 years of economic gains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the OECD projects that inflation will spike to 15 percent this year in Russia.&nbsp; More than 400 private sector companies have already quit Russia.&nbsp; And independent observers estimate that over 200,000 people emigrated from Russia just in the past month alone, as the brain drain accelerates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Set against the backdrop of export controls that deny cutting-edge technology and its removal from international supply chains, Russia will soon face an acute shortage of ideas, talent, and technology to compete in the 21st century.&nbsp; And Putin will be left with a strategic failure of his own making.</p>



<p>Let me turn it now to [senior administration official].&nbsp; Sorry, I guess I&#8217;ll take Q&amp;A before turning it to [senior administration official] on refugees, if that’s all right, [moderator].</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; We’ll open it up for a couple of questions for [senior administration official].&nbsp; If you can please indicate you have a question by raising your hand on the Zoom.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ll start with James Politi from the Financial Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I was wondering if you could talk a bit more about energy and the sort of joint strategy that we expect to be announced tomorrow, if possible.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, James.&nbsp; Yeah, you know, I actually would rather &#8212; or not &#8212; I’d rather not get ahead of that announcement.&nbsp; It&#8217;s premature to go into detail, but I guess I&#8217;ll just let you know it&#8217;s something we&#8217;ve been working on for some time, and I think it&#8217;s going to be a meaningful step forward in terms of accelerating Europe’s diversification away from Russian gas and our collective phasing out of gas, both in the U.S. and Europe.&nbsp; So, please stay tuned on that front.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And for our next question, we’ll go to Daniel Bush from Newsweek.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, sorry about that.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I wonder if you could just step back a little bit.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing these sanctions having a huge impact on the economy, as you pointed out in all these different ways.&nbsp; What impact do you see it having on Putin’s ability in the short and medium term to continue carrying out the war on the ground in Ukraine, especially if Russia is continuing to get revenue from oil and gas exports?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, you know, first of all, in oil and gas exports, if you look at Russia&#8217;s oil receipts, they are down.&nbsp; Estimates from the private sector suggest that roughly two to two and a half million barrels of Russian oil are no longer making it to their intended destination.</p>



<p>But, you know, look, if you consider the aggregate impact of these sanctions, what we&#8217;re doing is really depleting President Putin of the resources that he needs to conduct this war.&nbsp; He&#8217;s looking, as I mentioned, at a contraction in his economy; you know, some people estimate 10 percent, others 15 percent, other people say more.&nbsp; That is three times larger than the contraction Russia faced after it defaulted in 1998.&nbsp; Russia used to be the 11th largest economy in the world before its invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you consider the depreciation of the ruble already and the projected shrinking of its economy, it&#8217;s now looking at an economy half of the size that it was before this invasion.&nbsp; So it would fall out of the top 20 economies by ranking.</p>



<p>At the same time, we&#8217;re cutting off all of the sources of potential growth in Russia, whether it&#8217;s cutting-edge technology, or whether it&#8217;s access to supply chains from the West, or human capital.&nbsp; You know, people are leaving Russia by the droves, especially the best and brightest.</p>



<p>All of this will inhibit his ability to continue to execute a military operation and to have sources of growth outside of oil and gas.</p>



<p>Now, we can&#8217;t predict exactly when or how this will change Putin’s calculus.&nbsp; But what we can ensure is that this is going to be a failure; he&#8217;s going to emerge weaker, and we&#8217;re going to emerge stronger.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And next we&#8217;ll turn to Tamara Keith from NPR.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Unmute.&nbsp; So sorry.&nbsp; I just wanted to clarify whether all of these sanctions are being done in conjunction with Allies or whether this is the U.S. moving on its own, and just the &#8212; just the sanctions evasion part is done &#8212; being done in coordination today.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Tamara.&nbsp; So, the sanctions on individuals &#8212; as I mentioned, we’re sanctioning 300-plus members of the Duma, a handful of financial elites and oligarchs.&nbsp; Many of those measures are aligning the U.S. sanctions with those of the EU or G7 partners.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re also taking steps to align with our measures.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s an effort at strengthening our coordinated action.</p>



<p>The other measures I mentioned are being taken by the G7-EU as a whole.&nbsp; So the sanctions evasion initiative is something that you&#8217;ll see in the G7 statement.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll also see language in the G7 statement about prohibiting any transactions with Russia&#8217;s Central Banking goal.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re also going to say together in the G7 statement that it&#8217;s not &#8212; it cannot be business as usual anymore for international organizations or multilateral fora.</p>



<p>So, the overall message here i<a></a><a>s: We have taken historic steps in imposing costs on Russia.&nbsp; Now let&#8217;s make sure we&#8217;re fully aligned and we&#8217;re getting the maximal impact from the measures that we&#8217;ve implemented.</a></p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And next we’ll go to Phil Mattingly from CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official], on the sanctions evasion piece of it that you’re working with on the G7 &#8212; I guess, to start, can you give some examples of, over the course of the last four weeks, places where you&#8217;ve seen gaps or seen areas that could be exploited that will be closed by what you&#8217;re doing right now?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I guess, more broadly, conceptually, how have you approached putting the sanctions evasion piece together?&nbsp; Is it purely through what you&#8217;ve seen in asset flows or what you&#8217;ve seen in gaps, or is there kind of a broader methodology to it?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Phil.&nbsp; Yeah, I’ll give you a couple of examples &#8212; and, actually, one of them is gold.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve heard market chatter that Russia is still using &#8212; trying to use its gold reserves to prop up the ruble &#8212; so, selling its gold in order to buy ruble.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It still has a considerable amount of gold; estimates are that it’s somewhere between $100 billion to $140 billion in market value.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t know for sure because the last snapshot of Russia&#8217;s Central Bank reserves was from last June.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s roughly 20 percent of the total reserves that Russia held prior to the invasion.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We want to shut down any ability for Russia to use its gold to support its currency.&nbsp; And we need to do that as a G7 for it to be effective.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s an example of working together to prevent any circumvention of our sanctions measures.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another is on export controls, Phil.&nbsp; So, as you know, we have collectively denied the inputs for foundational technologies to Russia, whether it&#8217;s semiconductors or artificial intelligence or quantum or hypersonic flight.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we, in the West and the EU, produce and design many of these inputs, but so do our partners in Asia.&nbsp; And we just need &#8212; we want to make sure that for any of these technologies, including technologies that may be produced in China or designed in China, that we&#8217;re shutting down avenues for Russia to benefit from continued transactions with those countries too.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And next we&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to do an overview of our refugees announcement, followed by [senior administration official] to do a preview of the European Council meeting, after which we&#8217;ll open it up for more Q&amp;A.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And good morning, everyone.&nbsp; We&#8217;re happy today to share that the United States is announcing that we will welcome up to 100,000 Ukrainians and others fleeing Russia&#8217;s aggression.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To meet this commitment, we are considering the full range of legal pathways to the United States.&nbsp; So that includes the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program, parole, and immigrant and non-immigrant visas.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have more details to share on this program in the days and weeks to come.&nbsp; But I would note today that we&#8217;re working, in particular, to expand and develop new programs with a focus on welcoming Ukrainians who have family members in the United States.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;ve all heard from many in the diaspora that they are eager to welcome their Ukrainian family members into their homes in the United States as quickly as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re also committed to protecting the most vulnerable among the refugee populations that have already fled, and that includes LGBTQI+ individuals, those with medical needs, third-country nationals who have already sought refuge outside of the &#8212; in Ukraine &#8212; excuse me &#8212; journalists, dissidents, and others who have specific vulnerabilities.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we&#8217;re, of course, coordinating our effort closely with our European allies and partners who are on the frontlines of this refugee crisis.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We still expect most displaced Ukrainian citizens will want to stay in neighboring countries or elsewhere in the EU where they may have family and where there are already large diaspora communities in the hope that they can return home soon.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But at the same time, we recognize that some number of Ukrainians who have fled may wish to come to the United States temporarily, especially those with family in the U.S.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By opening our country to these individuals, we will help relieve some of the pressure on the European host countries that are currently shouldering so much of the responsibilities for what is the largest refugee crisis in Europe since the Second World War.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We commend our European allies and partners for keeping their borders open to those that are seeking international protection.&nbsp; And as [senior administration official] noted, we are particularly grateful to Ukraine&#8217;s neighboring countries, including Poland, Romania, Slovakia, Moldova, and Hungary, who have opened their doors and set up welcome centers for the nearly 3.5 million who have fled Ukraine to date.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States is and will continue to be a global leader in international humanitarian &#8212; in international humanitarian response.&nbsp; And we are asserting humanitarian assistance to provide immediate support for those on the ground in Ukraine and for those who are fleeing Ukraine and dealing with the catastrophic humanitarian consequences that Moscow and Moscow alone is responsible for.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to preview this afternoon&#8217;s EC meetings and our announcements on new humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, thanks for that, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And, yes, just to round out the day, you know, I think this is a banner day of multilateral meetings, starting here at NATO, moving to the G7, and then we will be driving across town for meetings with the EU.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President, this afternoon, will be joining the European Council meeting.&nbsp; That is a fairly regular gathering that the 27 EU heads of state and government have.</p>



<p>You may remember that, almost a year ago to the day, the President joined a meeting of the European Council.&nbsp; This was very early in the administration.&nbsp; He joined it virtually.&nbsp; And this will be the first time in the administration that the President will have sat down with all 27 of the EU heads of state and government in person.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, some of those countries &#8212; many of those countries, in fact &#8212; are here at the NATO summit.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s also an opportunity for him to engage with a number of other countries who are in the EU but not at NATO.</p>



<p>The President will be greeted by Charles Michel, who is the President of the European Council.&nbsp; And then they will have a short bilateral meeting at the top.&nbsp; And then President Michel will escort President Biden into the meeting where he will be then meeting with the 27 EU leaders.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They will then continue on after the President leaves for their own previously scheduled meeting later this afternoon and dinner and then probably much of the day tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we really felt that, in addition to the NATO meeting, it was important for the President to have the opportunity to engage directly with his EU counterparts as well.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One of the main things I think they will discuss is sanctions.&nbsp; [Senior administration official] obviously did the broad laydown of sanctions, including new measures that we are looking at today.&nbsp; And so, in addition to the coordination that we&#8217;ve had with the G7, I think it&#8217;s important to underscore the very close cooperation that we have had with the European Union generally over the last year.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of our approach to sanctions, our aim has always been to work in lockstep with the EU to the extent possible.&nbsp; But I think, particularly over the last month, we have tried to be as closely coordinated with the EU as we could, both in the development and the rollout of our sanctions packages.&nbsp; So this will be a good opportunity for the President to talk directly with EU leaders about that.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, I think the leaders will have a significant conversation about the refugee crisis as well as the humanitarian assistance that we are all providing.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, a very clear recognition by the President that a number of these eastern flank countries, including Poland, Romania, Slovakia, Hungary, as well as some non-EU members, including Moldova, are very much on the frontlines of this.&nbsp; And so I think the President will welcome the opportunity to hear from a number of these countries that are facing these immediate flows of refugees, as well as to hear from a range of EU countries that are taking in a number of refugees.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Those of you that were covering St. Patrick&#8217;s Day last week will have heard the President talk with the Irish Taoiseach about the 7,000 refugees, for example, that Ireland has taken in, which is an example of how various EU member states are stepping up to deal with the humanitarian assistance piece.</p>



<p><a>Third, and related more broadly to the Eastern Partnership, which is what the EU calls these countries on their eastern side &#8212; the Caucasus, Moldova, Belarus, Ukraine</a> &#8212; the leaders are expected to discuss democratic resilience: the need to continue to bolster the ability of these countries to stand strong in the face of some of these autocratic pressures; to underscore the democratic developments that are happening in a lot of their countries; and to ensure that we are working together with the EU to support their resilience, especially at this particular moment.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, I would expect that the leaders will have some discussion of energy security along the broad lines of the G7 talks that [senior administration official] outlined, as well as food security.&nbsp; Food security is an increasing concern for the EU, similar to what it is at the United States.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, coming out of the President’s meeting with the European Council, we are anticipating the announcement of a number of deliverables and new announcements.&nbsp; So, let me run through what those are now, as they are related specifically to the conversation that the President is going to be having with his EU counterparts.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, we’re prepared to provide&nbsp;more than $1 billion in new funding towards humanitarian assistance for those affected by Russia’s war in Ukraine and its severe impacts around the world.&nbsp; So, this funding will be additional to money that we have already provided, and will provide food, shelter, clean water, medical supplies, and other forms of assistance.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, a new commitment to defend global food security. &nbsp;Russia’s war of aggression threatens to disrupt the supply of critical agricultural commodities from the Black Sea region, which jeopardizes global food security, particularly for vulnerable populations in the Middle East and Africa.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ukraine, known globally for its wheat production, for being a “bread basket” for the world, obviously is very much hindered in its ability to do that during this harvest season given the fact that you have Russian tanks rolling across Ukrainian fields and you have Ukrainian farmers who have taken up arms to defend their country.</p>



<p>But the United States, through the Feed the Future initiative and our nutrition commitments, will be providing over $11 billion over the next five years to address food security threats and malnutrition across the globe.&nbsp; And this includes programming in many of the countries that are vulnerable to increases in food and fertilizer prices.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The third thing to highlight is that today we will be launching a European Democratic Resilience Initiative.&nbsp; This initiative will be launched with $320 million in funding.&nbsp; The aim of this initiative is to defend human rights, to strengthen democratic and anti-corruption institutions, to support media freedom, and to increase accountability for human rights abuses and violations of international law.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as I mentioned, there will be a particular focus of these efforts on these countries neighboring the European Union who are currently vulnerable in this space.</p>



<p>So, an important component of this will be support for efforts to document and preserve evidence of potential war crimes being committed in Ukraine.&nbsp; The United States is already supporting several such initiatives.&nbsp; And as I mentioned, this will be an opportunity for the President to talk with EU counterparts about ways in which we can collaborate with the EU on these efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some new lines of efforts, including the establishment of a conflict observatory, will gather information that can be shared with a range of accountability efforts at the national and international level to hold Russia accountable for its actions.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, [moderator], let me stop there.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And now we’ll open it up for Q&amp;A for [senior administration official] or [senior administration official].&nbsp; If folks could please raise your hand using the Zoom function.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’ll get started with Michael Shear from the New York Times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Question, I guess, for [senior administration official] about the 100,000 refugees.&nbsp; As you know, obviously the President said, I think last September, that the cap for refugees &#8212; for the refugee program for the entire world would be 125,000.&nbsp; Very few of those have actually come in.&nbsp; Is the 100,000 going to be part of that 125?&nbsp; Is this an additional 100,000?&nbsp; And do you have to go to Congress to consult for that, or can those just simply come in through the IRAP program?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you for the question.&nbsp; So, a couple of things on this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One, not everyone that comes in under this program would come in as a refugee.&nbsp; Like I mentioned, people could come in as refugees under &#8212; or under humanitarian parole, or using immigrant or non-immigrant visas.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s multiple pathways there.&nbsp; And obviously, only those that came in as refugees would be counted against that ceiling of 125,000.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll also note that the ceiling of 125,000 is for fiscal year 2022.&nbsp; And this commitment of 100,000 is not necessarily timebound to that fiscal year; it&#8217;s a broader commitment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I will say that, you know, we have still a significant capacity within the 125,000, so we don&#8217;t currently envision the need to go beyond that in terms of the portion of the individuals that would come in as refugees during this fiscal year.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next we&#8217;ll go to Geoff Earle with the Daily Mail.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; This is a little bit circling back to earlier in the call, but I was wondering if with President Zelenskyy or some of the other leaders, if there&#8217;s been any discussion of prospects for a negotiated settlement.&nbsp; Because I know a lot of the military aid is &#8212; you know, one aim is to try to force the Russians back to the table.&nbsp; And so, is this, you know, realistic?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, Zelenskyy keeps talking about reparations.&nbsp; Is there going to be an effort to acquire, you know, this impounded money from Russia to go toward that?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much for that question.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have anything new on this beyond what we have talked about in the past, which obviously is continued support for the Ukrainians in their effort and, most importantly, to get the Russians to agree to a ceasefire, especially considering the very dire humanitarian situation that we&#8217;re seeing in a number of parts of Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So far, we have not seen a serious readiness on the part of Russia, certainly, to engage in a ceasefire or even necessarily to engage in serious conversations.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Certainly, if we get to that point, we can look at a broad range of scenarios.&nbsp; But for right now, the focus very much remains on getting to a ceasefire so we can support the people that are suffering.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next we’ll go to David Sanger with the New York Times.</p>



<p>David, if you’re there, please unmute.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; Can you hear me now?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; My question is for [senior administration official], and the question has to do with the European Democratic Resilience plan.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [Senior administration official], is this the kind of plan that the President had in mind when he was first talking about autocracy versus democracy?&nbsp; Or is this specifically tailored to the Russian invasion and so forth?&nbsp; I’m trying to figure out the degree to which you think you have new threats to democracy in the region because of this versus what you faced before?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, David, for that question.&nbsp; So this European Democratic Resilience Initiative is something new that we are standing up to try and provide additional support to countries in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think our approach to the Ukraine crisis more broadly, as I said at the top, has been multifaceted, both in terms of imposing economic costs on Russia, supporting the people of Ukraine, defending the security of the NATO Alliance.&nbsp; And I think you could add a fourth line of effort to that that&#8217;s been implicit in what we&#8217;ve done, as well as in what the EU has done, which is to take steps to bolster the resilience of countries in the neighboring region.&nbsp; This is something that I heard a number of leaders mention in passing in the NATO interventions earlier today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The EU and the United States, they’re obviously very concerned about the situation in Moldova, in terms of refugees.  And a strong desire to ensure that we are doing everything possible to bolster the resilience of those countries as well &#8212; the ones that are not in NATO or the EU but that are, in EU parlance, part of their Eastern Partnership Program and on the eastern part of the European flank. <br><br>     So we&#8217;ve already done a lot with Moldova in terms of Secretary Blinken and others making visits there, with a very strong focus on what we can do on the humanitarian assistance side. <br><br>     The United States has long worked on democratic programs in all of these countries, frankly.  The EU also has programs in all of these countries as part of the Eastern Partnership Program. <br><br>     But I think &#8212; and then, you know, to take your question more broadly: As you rightly said, the President has been, for his entire administration, very focused on these broader questions of democracy and autocracy as well.  And it&#8217;s very much played out in the President&#8217;s Democracy Summit where we had participation from countries like Moldova and Georgia, among others.  It very much ties into what we are trying to do in this democracy “year of action” coming out of the Democracy Summit.  <br><br>     But this specific program that we are launching today is targeted at the countries within this region, with a very specific desire to try and shore up their democratic institutions, their anti-corruption institutions; to support media freedom; as well as accountability for human rights abuses. <br><br>     And part of this is based on the theory that one of the best things we can do for all of these countries and to increase the resilience and security of these countries, as well as our own countries, quite frankly, as the President has talked about, is to ensure that we&#8217;re doing everything we can to shore up the democratic resilience, the good governance, and the rule of law measures there. <br><br>     And then, as I mentioned, there is also an increasing focus on the potential for war crimes in Ukraine and wanting to ensure that we are doing everything we can to be supporting the collection of information there so that that can be fed into broader accountability mechanisms. MODERATOR:  Great, thank you so much.  And with that, those are all the questions we have time for, so we have to wrap. <br><br>     As a reminder of the ground rules, this call was conducted on background, attributable to a senior &#8212; to three “senior administration officials.”  And as a reminder, the second portion of the call is embargoed until 2:15 p.m. local time or 9:15 a.m. Eastern time.  Thank you very much.<br><br>12:39 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
