<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 23:23:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Russian Disinformation and Efforts to Undermine Free&#160;Press</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/05/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-russian-disinformation-and-efforts-to-undermine-free-press/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 23:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We applaud the steps taken by governments, U.S. and global companies, and other institutions around the world to condemn Putin’s war of choice in Ukraine, including those that call out and contest the Russian Government’s further efforts to undermine the free press and spread disinformation. The Russian government’s efforts to propagate lies and obscure the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We applaud the steps taken by governments, U.S. and global companies, and other institutions around the world to condemn Putin’s war of choice in Ukraine, including those that call out and contest the Russian Government’s further efforts to undermine the free press and spread disinformation.</p>



<p>The Russian government’s efforts to propagate lies and obscure the truth have been rejected by the international community:&nbsp; governments, the private sector, and civil society have taken independent action in an unprecedented manner to reject efforts to sell Putin’s war as justified. For our part, the United States has leveraged new sanctions on individuals based in Russia and Ukraine, as well as Russian entities tied to Russian intelligence services, that promulgate destabilizing disinformation, and has provided critical assistance to increase digital safety measures for civil society and media. With our partners, we will continue to condemn Russia’s shuttering of independent media and technology platforms that refuse to allow Putin to run his disinformation campaigns unchecked.</p>



<p>To hide the truth from its own citizens, Russia’s censorship agency has shuttered independent Russian media outlets, blocked social media, and restricted access in Russia to international news outlets. We condemn the move by the Russian Federation Council to approve a law threatening prison sentences of up to 15 years for journalists and ordinary citizens that would spread so-called “false” information about Putin’s unconscionable war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>We urge continued action across all sectors of society to promote human rights and fundamental freedoms online and offline.  This includes disinformation that seeks to divide the global community and conceal the Kremlin’s responsibility for this crisis. The United States firmly believes that the best way to accomplish this goal is to hold accountable the propaganda media and disinformation proxies that disseminate Putin’s lies. Through their principled actions, like-minded governments, private companies, and non-governmental organizations are demonstrating leadership in this moment.  We will continue to work with and support all like-minded partners, and stand with the sovereign nation and people of Ukraine, and with the citizens of Russia speaking out against Putin’s war by the thousands.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki and Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers Cecilia Rouse, March 4,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/04/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-chair-of-the-council-of-economic-advisers-cecilia-rouse-march-4-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:58 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, so we are thrilled to have a very special guest with us today on Jobs Day &#8212; a remarkable Jobs Day it is &#8212; Dr. Cecilia Rouse, Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers. Because we&#8217;re running a bit late, she&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:58 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, so we are thrilled to have a very special guest with us today on Jobs Day &#8212; a remarkable Jobs Day it is &#8212; Dr. Cecilia Rouse, Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers.</p>



<p>Because we&#8217;re running a bit late, she has a very small window but has agreed to take a few questions and also to come back.&nbsp; And then we will have a briefing as long as we can.&nbsp; And for those of you in the pool, we will keep you updated as well.</p>



<p>So, with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over.</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; So I really appreciate this opportunity to talk about today’s job report, as this is a bright spot and a sign of our strong labor market recovery over the past year.</p>



<p>The February jobs report is extremely solid.&nbsp; The economy added 678,000 jobs in February, well above market expectations. &nbsp;Revisions to the prior two months added over 90,000 more jobs than originally reported, with an average monthly gain of 582,000 over the past three months.</p>



<p>Other data demonstrate our strong economic rebound: The unemployment rate ticked down to 3.8 percent, and the labor force participation rate ticked up, reaching a new pandemic high.</p>



<p>Since President Biden took office, the economy created 7.4 million jobs.&nbsp; This includes the greatest single year of job growth in American history and the fastest economic growth in almost 40 years.</p>



<p>This month’s report reflects broad-based growth.&nbsp; For example, the unemployment rate for workers with less than a high school degree is the lowest on record.&nbsp; And employment in all major industries either grew or held steady.&nbsp; Last year, the economy created more manufacturing and trucking jobs than any year since 1994.</p>



<p>While the care industry is still behind the overall labor market in terms of its recovery, we saw meaningful increases in nursing and residential care; childcare; and state and local government, which is often schools.&nbsp; Notably, this month also saw the largest over-the-month increase in employment in home healthcare on record.&nbsp; These are important components in helping those with care responsibilities get back to work.</p>



<p>We look at the prime-age labor force because it is less affected by long-run changes in educational attainment or by the natural slowdown as people age and retire.&nbsp; This month, the employment rate for workers age 25 to 54 rose, part of a relatively consistent rise.</p>



<p>Overall, the recovery from the pandemic recession has been faster than any of the past recessions.&nbsp; For instance, in 2021, job growth averaged 562,000 jobs per month, nearly three times faster than 2011 to 2019 &#8212; the years following the Great Recession.</p>



<p>The share of the labor force experiencing long-term unemployment or involuntary part-time work has fallen dramatically in the pandemic recovery, in part due to the investments of the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; Both of these measures are often sources of “scarring” after an economic downturn, which describes conditions where workers suffer economic impacts for substantial time after the recession ends.</p>



<p>For instance, after the Great Recession, the long-term unemployment rate reached 4.4 percent but did not fall to 1 percent until 2017 &#8212; about seven years later than it reached its peak.</p>



<p>From January to February of this year, the long-term unemployment rate held steady but overall has dropped during the pandemic recovery from a high of 2.6 percent.</p>



<p>We also know that one way “scarring” can affect workers is through increasing the share of workers who cannot get all the hours they want because they cannot find a full-time job or because business conditions are weak.&nbsp; But similar to the long-term unemployment rate, this measure has seen rapid recovery.&nbsp; The percent of the labor force that is working part-time for economic reasons ticked up in February to 2.5 percent but remains below its level in February 2020.</p>



<p>Monthly employment and unemployment data can be volatile, and payroll estimates can be subject to substantial revisions. Therefore, it is important to focus on trends rather than data in a single month, which is what the administration stresses every month.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; And I’m happy to take questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Trevor.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen a fairly substantial slide in the stock market this year.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen rising oil prices.&nbsp; Those are obviously pressures on the economy.&nbsp; Do you think that if those trends continue that they will reverse the gains that you&#8217;ve seen?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; So I think it&#8217;s important to separate the stock market from the real economy.&nbsp; And the growth that we&#8217;ve seen in the real economy has been the fastest in almost 40 years.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen job growth that is historically fast.</p>



<p>You know, obviously, we have &#8212; we are monitoring the financial sector.&nbsp; The actions of the Federal Reserve play a key role there.&nbsp; And obviously, the tensions &#8212; and the invasion of Russia of Ukraine is having an impact there.</p>



<p>So we are monitoring.&nbsp; We are impacting.&nbsp; But quite honestly, we go into 2022 from a position of economic strength.&nbsp; The bones of this economy are strong and has the resilience to weather what is ahead of us in this year ahead.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Phil.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Understanding that &#8212; (clears throat) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; the data is fluid and volatile right now,&nbsp;but given the strength that the U.S. economy has, how long can it withstand the spikes we&#8217;ve seen in commodities, just the general environment before the threat of tipping into a recession becomes real at this point?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; So, look, the economy is very strong.&nbsp; What we saw in February was that we added almost 700,000 jobs over the month as the cases of Omicron were coming down but did not get down to zero.&nbsp; So what we saw was the resilience in this economy that we were able to continue the recovery as we&#8217;re also learning to live alongside of this pandemic and safely get back to our normal lives.</p>



<p>So we are optimistic, if we continue, the President has the &#8212; that we have the tools.&nbsp; The President has asked for Congress to have additional tools, which we know are going to be so important as we &#8212; the pandemic is not over, but we know we have the therapeutics, we have the resources to develop vaccines quickly, we&#8217;ve got masking.&nbsp; We have the tools to navigate the pandemic as we go forward.</p>



<p>So we are optimistic that we can continue this robust recovery.&nbsp; This President has an economic plan to grow this economy from the bottom up and middle out.&nbsp; It’s premised on, you know, making the key investments in this economy that have not been made over decades.&nbsp; So the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law was a key component of that.&nbsp; And there are components of his &#8212; you know, what were parts of Build Back Better, which is the, you know, Child Tax Credit, which has investments in children; paid leave, which help people balance work and home responsibilities; helping people get back to work and balance their care responsibilities; lowering costs for families, whether it&#8217;s in prescription drugs, childcare costs that have been increasing for decades and that are so important to this economy.</p>



<p>So this President is focused on that kind of economic investments, which are premised on increasing our economic capacity, which is the kind of sustainable economic growth that we &#8212; that we&#8217;re looking to see.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kelly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given the good news that you&#8217;ve just mentioned and the trend lines, which have been very positive, why do you think this President is not getting credit from voters for steering the economy in the right direction?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Well, I think that&#8217;s a really complicated question.&nbsp; We know that the American Rescue Plan was really an insurance policy for this economy.&nbsp; What we know is that there are millions more families &#8212; we created &#8212; you know, the economy created 7.4 million jobs over the past year during this presidency, and so we know millions of families are able to, you know, have a job and put food on the table and pay their bills.</p>



<p>What we know in the consumner [sic] &#8212; in the confidence data, a lot of that is premised on inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we do have inflation.&nbsp; The President has acknowledged that; we understand that.&nbsp; He is focused on that.&nbsp; But what people also report is that their own finances are fairly healthy, but they see the kind of uncertainty in the economy that is there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we are &#8212; we’re a pandemic-scarred society.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not just the economy; there&#8217;s uncertainty as we navigate our way out of this pandemic and then the tensions, you know, between Russia and Ukraine are going to add to that uncertainty as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kelly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you described the strength in the economy &#8212; if there were a policy decision made to stop importing Russian oil, what impact would that have?&nbsp; And do you see a resilience in the American economy to withstand that?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; So, again, we&#8217;re in a very good position.&nbsp; What we know is that, you know, from the U.S. economy, we don&#8217;t import a lot of Russian oil, but we are looking at options that we can take right now if we were to cut the U.S. consumption of Russian energy.&nbsp; But what&#8217;s really most important is we &#8212; that we maintain a steady supply of global energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp; Josh.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; Just to follow up on that: We&#8217;re reporting right now that you are considering a ban on U.S. imports of Russian crude.&nbsp; Should I interpret your answer just now that it might be more targeted than that?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; So we are considering a range of options, but what&#8217;s really essential is that we maintain a steady supply of global energy.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t want to disrupt &#8212; look, gl- &#8212; energy is a global market and we do not want to disrupt that market.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on today’s report, the jobs number was great; the wage growth was pretty sluggish.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: Is that normal to expect a disconnect there?&nbsp; Does one typically follow the other?&nbsp; And what do you draw from that?&nbsp; And how can you get wages to keep pace with the actual job numbers themselves?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; So, from month to month, data can be volatile, and so we don&#8217;t &#8212; that’s why we don&#8217;t focus on month-to-month changes, especially in ,like, wages.&nbsp; But we did see robust growth even &#8212; for lower &#8212; in lower-wage industries.&nbsp; And we know that, over the year, wages are up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the President&#8217;s economic plan is really about having increases in wages that are sustained by increases in productivity &#8212; and they&#8217;re really premised on the increase in economic capacity &#8212; and that help families by lowering costs on those &#8212; you know, in those areas &#8212; healthcare, prescription care, childcare &#8212; that we know have been really squeezing pocketbooks over several decades.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Rouse, for joining us.</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You&#8217;re welcome anytime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, I just have two items for all of you at the top.&nbsp; I just wanted to provide &#8212; I know we announced this yesterday or the day before &#8212; but a brief overview on two critical urgent funding needs that the administration has sent to Congress.</p>



<p>First, to provide assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; The United States has already provided over $1.4 billion in assistance to Ukraine since 2021.&nbsp; And together with our European allies and partners, we are holding Russia accountable for its unjustified and unprovoked invasion.</p>



<p>To continue this important work, we’re requesting $10 billion to deliver additional security assistance for Ukraine, to provide lifesaving humanitarian assistance for the Ukrainian people, and more support for stronger sanctions enforcement, and for U.S troop deployments to reinforce NATO’s eastern flank and deter Russian aggression.</p>



<p>This is an urgent priority.&nbsp; I think everybody would agree &#8212; Democrats, Republicans, the American people.&nbsp; And it is urgent that we can continue to deliver on our commitment to support the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>Second, the other part of our request is on COVID-19 response.&nbsp; While we now have tools like vaccines, treatments, tests, and high-quality masks to protect people, we didn’t get here by accident.&nbsp; It’s the result of wise investments over the past 14 months that led to this widespread availability.&nbsp; And I would note that we did that while we had the rise of two variants that weren’t even planned for, of course.&nbsp; Well, they were planned for, but we didn’t &#8212; we had to account for them, I should say, in our spending.</p>



<p>We need additional funding from Congress to secure more medical supplies to keep this country moving forward.&nbsp; And let me be very clear: This is an urgent request.&nbsp; And this is what is at stake in our fight against COVID:</p>



<p>By May, our current supply of monoclonal antibodies will stock out.&nbsp; By July, the current supply of pre-exposure prophylaxis drugs used to protect immunocompromised people will stock out.&nbsp; Funds are needed in March to secure additional supply in July.&nbsp; You have to order them ahead so that you have them when they&#8217;re needed, when you run out of stock.</p>



<p>By September, we anticipate our supply of oral antivirals will run out if additional pills are not purchased now.</p>



<p>So &#8212; and within weeks, we exce- &#8212; expect testing capacity to drop if additional investments are not made soon.</p>



<p>And as I &#8212; I would note, in the President’s State of the Union, he also announced the American people can order more tests.&nbsp; So they&#8217;re &#8212; we obviously want to meet that demand.</p>



<p>Given how costly COVID has been, with so many of our fellow Americans hospitalized or dying and our daily lives disrupted, we simply cannot afford to wait on investing now and keeping people protected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Also, just wanted to give you a preview of the week ahead:&nbsp;<br><br>On Tuesday, the President will travel to Fort Worth, Texas, to speak with veterans, caregivers, and survivors about addressing the health effects of environmental exposures, such as burn pits.&nbsp; Obviously, he talked about this priority in his State of the Union Address earlier this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s part of his Unity Agenda for the nation.&nbsp; He supports legislation that would expand access to healthcare and benefits for veterans affected by these exposures during military service, and he was encouraged by the passage of a bipartisan bill in the House just yesterday.</p>



<p>Wednesday evening, the President will deliver remarks at the Senate Democratic Caucus retreat.</p>



<p>On Thursday &#8212; sorry, I’m going to sneeze at some point &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; on Thursday &#8212; I just wanted to not scare anyone &#8212; the President will welcome the President of Colombia to the White House to celebrate 200 years of positive diplomatic relations and consult on a range of regional and global issues of mutual interest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During their bilat, the leaders plan to reaffirm the bilateral relationship and discuss COVID-19 response, future pandemic preparedness, economic recovery, and regional responses to migration.</p>



<p>That evening, he will deliver remarks to Democratic National Committee members at their Winter Meeting.</p>



<p>And, on Friday, he will travel to Philadelphia, where he will deliver remarks at the House Democratic Caucus retreat.</p>



<p>I would note that Friday is also when we will be marking the anniversary of the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; I’m sure you will all be celebrating with us, voluntarily or not.&nbsp; So, we look forward to that.</p>



<p>With that, Colleen, why don’t you kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So, President Biden has promised that there&#8217;s going to be no American boots on the ground, and he&#8217;s also acknowledging that the war in Ukraine is going to impact pocketbooks.&nbsp; We see, you know, especially with what happened with the nuclear facility in Ukraine, no sign of Putin stopping.&nbsp; And, in fact, he&#8217;s telling Macron that he&#8217;s in this until the end.</p>



<p>So, I wonder what makes the administration confident that Americans are willing to, you know, pay for the price of Ukrainian liberty, especially if this is going to drag on for long?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then I have a separate question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, to be very clear &#8212; and I think you all heard the President convey this in his speech the other night: The reason why we are seeing volatility in the global oil markets, the reason why the price of gas is going up is not because of steps the President has taken; they are because President Putin is invading Ukraine, and that is creating a great deal of instability in the global marketplace.</p>



<p>So, what we are trying to do and what the President is focused on doing is taking every step we can to mitigate the impact of that.&nbsp; Obviously, he announced the release of more oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, did that in a coordinated way.&nbsp; We have a range of options on the table we are considering.</p>



<p>But where we are at in this moment is &#8212; certainly, we are taking steps to stand up for democracy, stand up for democracy versus autocracy, stand up to the actions of a brutal dictator &#8212; but it is because of his actions that we are in this circumstance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other question on the Supreme Court reinstating the death penalty for the Boston bomber &#8212; is a question I have.&nbsp; I wondered &#8212; I know there&#8217;s a moratorium, you know, on the death penalty the DOJ has put in place, but are there any other actions planned or any other steps taken to keep the President&#8217;s pledge to end the death penalty?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President certainly supports the Attorney General&#8217;s decision to issue a moratorium on federal executions while it conducts a comprehensive review of the practice, and that practice and process is ongoing.&nbsp; And the President has expressed before that he has deep concerns about whether capital punishment is consistent with the values that are fundamental to our sense of justice and fairness.</p>



<p>Obviously, I can&#8217;t &#8212; there&#8217;s &#8212; this is a case that the Department of Justice could certainly speak to, but I could &#8212; would just say that President &#8212; the President expressed horror at the events of the Boston Marathon bambing [sic] &#8212; bombing at the time.&nbsp; He believes that Tsarnaev should be punished for responsibility in the murder of three innocent people at the marathon, for wounding dozens of others, and for his role in killing two police officers who were attempting to bring him and his brother to justice.&nbsp; And he knows the deep pain that his crime caused.</p>



<p>As the President said at the one-year commemoration of the bombing, quote, “I know that no memorial, no words, no act can fully provide the solace that your hearts…still yearn to acquire.”</p>



<p>He has made clear, as I noted, his &#8212; his grave concerns about capital punishment as implemented, but he respects the process and the ongoing review that is being &#8212; being led by the Department of Justice and the Attorney General.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Overnight, we saw the Russians attack this nuclear power plant last night.&nbsp; The U.S. Embassy in Kyiv noted on Twitter, “It is a war crime to attack a nuclear power plant.&nbsp; Putin’s shelling of Europe&#8217;s largest nuclear plant takes his reign of terror one step further.”</p>



<p>So, just to be clear: Is it now the position of the U.S. government that Putin has engaged in war crimes?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have an internal review that&#8217;s been ongoing, prior to last night, of &#8212; to collect evidence and data of the targeting of civilians, of the reported use of horrific weapons of war on the ground in Ukraine.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an ongoing process.&nbsp; We have not made conclusions.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a legal review in a process that goes through the administration.</p>



<p>What I will say is that the intentional targeting of civilians or civilian objects would be considered a war crime, even as we are assessing that.&nbsp; Regardless of the legality, this action was the height of irresponsibility.&nbsp; The Kremlin must cease operations around nuclear infrastructure.&nbsp; And we have, of course, remaining concerns.</p>



<p>I would note that just on the &#8212; in the developments that have happened overnight as it relates to the nuclear power plant &#8212; I mean, obviously, the Russian government&#8217;s actions were extremely reckless and dangerous; they could have posed a profound threat to the safety of civilians in the region and beyond &#8212; we do applaud the ability of Ukrainian operators to keep all six reactors in safe conditions while under attack and to report, as they were able to, to the nuclear regulator, which certainly was helpful.</p>



<p>As you know, last night, the President not only spoke with President Zelenskyy, he also spoke last night to the head of the National Nuclear Security Administration for an update on the situation at the plant.&nbsp; So that is a piece of positive news for the moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we remain concerned, of course, about the fact that they have clearly taken control of the plants &#8212; or it appears so &#8212; the Russian military has.&nbsp; The best step for nuclear safety would be for Russia to immediately withdraw its fr- &#8212; its forces around the facility.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the Hill, we&#8217;ve now seen this really, sort of, broad range of bipartisan support behind this legislation to ban Russian oil imports.&nbsp; The Speaker has said she&#8217;s all for banning Russian oil.&nbsp; I guess, the first one: Just what is your stance on the Senate bill, and is this something that the President would sign?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as we &#8212; as we talked about a little bit yesterday, how the President has been approaching any of the steps we&#8217;ve taken as it relates to Russia and the actions of Russia and holding President Putin accountable is to take every step to the maximum impact that will impact President Putin, the Russian economy.</p>



<p>I mean, the stock market has been closed now for the longest time in history.&nbsp; Russia is in a full-blown financial crisis.&nbsp; According to JP Morgan analysts, there will be a coll- &#8212; a collapse in the Russian GDP.</p>



<p>So, clearly those actions are working.&nbsp; We will have had &#8212; one of his principles from the beginning has been to do that in a unified way, in a coordinated way &#8212; because we are stronger if we are together, as we work with the Europeans.</p>



<p>The third principle &#8212; or another principle, I&#8217;m not sure what number I&#8217;m on right now &#8212; has been to, while we&#8217;re maximizing the impact, to minimize it on the American people, on the global markets, on &#8212; and certainly we are mindful as we look at all of these options of making sure we&#8217;re not having that impact.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we want to maintain, as Dr. Rouse said, a steady global supply of energy with whatever actions we take.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, is that a &#8220;No, he would not sign this legislation&#8221;?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, we remain in contact and in discussion with members of Congress.&nbsp; We are looking at options we could take right now to cut U.S. consumption of Russian energy, but we are very focused on minimizing the impact of families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you reduce supply in the global marketplace, you are going to rise &#8212; raise gas prices; you&#8217;re going to raise the &#8212; raise the price of oil; and that is something the President is very mindful of and focused on.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) alluded to something several officials have &#8211; and you kind of just did too &#8212; that there &#8212; there’s a review of options that would allow you to cut consumption but maintain market stability and supply.&nbsp; Can you outline any of those options in detail that are under review right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there are both international and domestic options.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into too much detail because our focus is on discussing what&#8217;s possible, what will have the maximum impact and not putting any of them at risk.</p>



<p>But part of &#8212; broadly speaking, part of what we&#8217;re trying to do internationally is have conversations, as we have been for weeks now, with global suppliers about meeting the needs &#8212; the supply needs in the marketplace.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reduction of supply, the reduction of oil would raise prices &#8212; right?&nbsp; So that is one of the things that we have been focused on.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked a little bit about engagements that Brett McGurk has had, that Amos Hochstein have had.&nbsp; These are ongoing discussions.&nbsp; There&#8217;s not a day that goes by &#8212; or maybe even an hour that goes by, probably &#8212; where members of our national security team and economic team aren’t communicating with their counterparts around the world about exactly this issue.</p>



<p>There are also a range of domestic options that are out there.&nbsp; Obviously, the President announced the release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; That is something where the process is just getting going right now.&nbsp; It takes a little bit to get that going.&nbsp; And then, you know, he&#8217;ll consider and continue to discuss with his team other steps that we could take domestically.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the potential for an Iran deal factor into the supply considerations at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that the biggest priority with the Iran deal is having visibility into and preventing Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; Obviously, as a part of that, if you go back to the implementation of the JCPOA, would be the availability of oil.&nbsp; But &#8212; but I would say that our first-and-foremost priority focus is on preventing Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then last one.&nbsp; There was significant preparation &#8212; that lead-up to the Russian invasion &#8212; in terms of cyber defenses in the U.S. with the private sector.&nbsp; Does the U.S. intelligence community have any analysis as to why there has not been any offensive Russian action on the cyber front as it pertains to the United States?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a really good question, Phil.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think anything that I could provide to you from the podium.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say that these &#8212; the cyber preparations &#8212; as you noted, but just for others &#8212; you know, those began in earnest back in the fall, just as all of our engagements with foreign counterparts; preparations and discussions about efforts to avoid challenges in the global &#8212; global oil markets; you know, making sure we were unified with our European partners &#8212; those engagements with the private sector began &#8212; I mean, they continued back in the fall, but as it relates to this potential threat, they escalated, they increased back in the fall.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of why not yet, I can&#8217;t speak to that.&nbsp; But we are certainly prepared if they &#8212; if that does happen.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The President is meeting with the Finnish President shortly.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does President Biden want Finland to join NATO?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That would be up to leaders of Finland and the NATO Alliance to determine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Senator Lindsey Graham said last night that someone ought to assassinate President Putin.&nbsp; Does the White House have any take on that statement?&nbsp; Is it helpful at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is not the position of the United States government and certainly not a statement you&#8217;d hear from come from the mouth of anybody working in this administration.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It sounds like the Vice President is going to be heading abroad.&nbsp; Can you tell us a little bit more about where she&#8217;ll be going and what the goal of that trip will be?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not yet.&nbsp; But certainly, the Vice President has been deeply engaged.&nbsp; She&#8217;s obviously already made a trip to Europe.&nbsp; I expect there&#8217;ll be more soon, but I don&#8217;t have anything to report out to you at this particular moment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, finally, yesterday, you said the U.S. doesn&#8217;t have a strategic interest in reducing the global supply of energy, but it &#8212; now it sounds like the White House actually is considering cutting off Russian oil imports.&nbsp; What changed?&nbsp; Is it just this drumbeat coming from both sides of the aisle on Capitol Hill that&#8217;s getting really, really loud?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t say our position has changed in any way since yesterday.&nbsp; Our &#8212; there isn&#8217;t a strategic interest in reducing global oil supply because that will ri- &#8212; that will increase the price of barrels of oil and increase gas prices.&nbsp; So, we are looking at ways to &#8212; and I said yesterday, I believe, that we are looking at ways to reduce the import of Russian oil while also making sure that we are maintaining the global supply needs out there.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have anything to predict in terms of what that will look like.&nbsp; And we, of course, remain engaged with &#8212; with our friends in Congress.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; There have been some calls to establish safe-passage corridors for humanitarian aid purposes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that something that the U.S. is at all working on?&nbsp; And then, how would it be enforced?&nbsp; Because, in 2014, the Russians killed a whole bunch of Ukrainians who were trying to flee in a similar fashion.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we are in close contact with Ukrainian leadership to support their efforts.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re absolutely right &#8212; humanitarian corridors are absolutely critical to help evacuate civilians; provide urgently needed humanitarian aid, such as food, water, medical supplies; to ensure civilians can travel safely.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve seen and continue to see devastating attacks on cities and infrastructure, including schools, hospitals, and houses that are catastrophic at the hands of the Russian military.</p>



<p>So, what we need to see is sincerity about the implementation of humanitarian access, work to establish that quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of the implementation of that, I don&#8217;t think I have any more details to convey here.&nbsp; But I think, obviously, saying you&#8217;re going to do humanitarian corridors or conveying an openness to that, to your point, is very different from allowing food, you know, water, medical supplies, and civilians to move.&nbsp; And certainly, there would need to be an implementation component and they would need to take the implementation of it seriously.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is that something that then the U.S. is going to discuss with NATO about potentially getting involved in doing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have more details on the implementation for you to outline from here.&nbsp; But certainly, you know, the establishment and the &#8212; of humanitarian corridors; the implementation of it; the Russian leadership taking that &#8212; that effort seriously would be &#8212; would be something we would welcome.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then following up on Phil&#8217;s question about the cyberattacks.&nbsp; Obviously, it didn&#8217;t happen leading up to the invasion, but do we have, as the U.S., a capability of knowing whether or not they tried to do something like that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have a range of capabilities.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into them from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then what happens if &#8212; you talked about the legal review is happening for the war crime element, earlier.&nbsp; What happens next if the review finds that Putin did commit war crimes?&nbsp; Then what happens?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s a range of means.&nbsp; I would say, first, while we have our own internal review going on and if we &#8212; and as we continue that, we will provide any information to both the International Criminal Court, the U.N., other entities that are investigating from an international standpoint.</p>



<p>We also helped pass a resolution at the U.N. Human Rights Council to establish a commission of inquiry which would be an entity where we could provide information that could support future investigations and also determine &#8212; to your question, I think &#8212; accountability measures.</p>



<p>We also joined 44 other countries in establishing an expert mission through the OSCE to investigate possible violations and abuses of international human rights and humanitarian law by Russia and its forces.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So typically, obviously, we have a range of resources here, as other countries do.&nbsp; And our focus would be feeding that into the international process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of what you all &#8212; what you just laid out there &#8212; and I know yesterday you said that you didn&#8217;t see Russia being booted from the U.N. Security Council because they have a permanent seat.&nbsp; How do you reconcile the potential that you have, you know, a member of the Security Council that’s flagrantly undermining the Charter?&nbsp; Is there anything that can be done, especially if he is found to be committing war crimes?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that&#8217;s part of the accountability question.&nbsp; Right, Jacqui?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And obviously, determination about the future role of any &#8212; of any country in an organization would be up to the member countries of that organization.&nbsp; We are one; we are not the only one.&nbsp; But certainly, accountability would be a part of that process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because it would be a concern for the U.S. &#8212; or for the U.N. for their &#8212; you know, sort of &#8212; for everything they stand for to have that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the U.N. has been and the vast majority of countries in the U.N. have been incredibly aligned and outspoken about the horrific and barbaric actions that they have seen by Russia &#8212; the Russian military and by &#8212; at the direction of President Putin on the ground.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last one.&nbsp; Zelenskyy said yesterday that he felt like the world &#8212; the whole world was too late.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s response to that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that, one, President Zelenskyy has been standing up courageously and bravely in a moment where his country, his own security &#8212; you know, his own concerns about his security are understandably under threat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have been &#8212; the United States has been working for months to build a global coalition that will hold President Putin accountable.&nbsp; We have been providing a historic amount of security assistance, military assistance, humanitarian assistance, economic assistance to President Zelenskyy and the Ukrainian leaders.&nbsp; And we will certainly continue to stand by his side.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Kelly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us any sense of a timeline or a triggering event that would result in this policy change regarding Russian oil and any decisions that may be forthcoming?&nbsp; Is that imminent?&nbsp; Or is there something that &#8212; you know, is there an event &#8212; an outside event that you&#8217;re waiting for?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t say, Kelly, it&#8217;s an outside event.&nbsp; I think our continuing concern continues to be &#8212; you know, everybody wants to hold President Putin and the Russian leadership accountable.&nbsp; Everybody supports the efforts that the Pres- &#8212; President Biden has been leading around the world to take &#8212; put in place crippling financial sanctions, and they have had an enormous impact.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we are also mindful of is not taking steps that have &#8212; would have the impact of raising energy prices, raising oil prices, raising gas prices for the American public.&nbsp; And we also are mindful of doing things in a way that is unified with our partners around the world.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak to how the President has steeled himself, hardened himself, if you will?&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;s made a commitment not to put American troops in a military position in Ukraine.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve outlined all the steps the U.S. and allies are taking.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s also watching what is happening, as are many Americans who are concerned about the atrocities that are taking place, the loss of life, the civilians that are being affected.&nbsp; Does the U.S. just watch this get worse?&nbsp; Is that what we should all be prepared for?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would just argue we&#8217;re hardly “watching.”&nbsp; We have been &#8212; we have provided a billion dollars in military and security assistance, including a range of defensive weapons that we have expedited delivery to the Ukrainian leadership and Ukrainian military.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have been the largest provider of economic and humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; We have rallied the world to stand up against President Putin.&nbsp; We are not “watching”; the President is leading the world in responding to this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, he is not going to put U.S. military men and women serving on the front lines of battle in Ukraine to fight Russia.&nbsp; That has never chan- &#8212; that has never been his plan, never been his policy, and he has no intention of doing that.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Understanding it’s not the position of the U.S. government, what Lindsey Graham said last night, what Lindsey Graham did suggest is that there&#8217;s no peaceful resolution here while Vladimir Putin is still in power in Russia.&nbsp; Does the President share that view?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President believes there continues to be a diplomatic path forward.&nbsp; That is the path forward that will help resolve what we&#8217;re seeing on the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Putin has the ability to deescalate.&nbsp; We have left the door open for months now to be engaged through de-escalation if de-escalation occurs.</p>



<p>Obviously, humanitarian corridors, a ceasefire &#8212; those would all be steps that would be welcomed.&nbsp; But, no, we are not advocating for killing the leader of a foreign country or regime change.&nbsp; That is not the policy of the United States.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick question on the Iran talks.&nbsp; There was a British diplomat that tweeted this morning that the talks are close.&nbsp; One of the reported demands of the Iranians is that this administration reversed the policy of the last one and removed the IRGC from the list of foreign terrorist organizations.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the U.S. position on that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, there &#8212; we are close.&nbsp; We are making progress.&nbsp; But we are &#8212; there&#8217;s still more work to be done, and I&#8217;m just not going to negotiate from here.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the NATO Secretary General gave a really pessimistic assessment of the conflict.&nbsp; He said, “The days to come are likely to be worse, with more death, more suffering, [and] more destruction.”&nbsp; Is that an assessment that the White House shares at this point?&nbsp; And is there a concern that the tide may be turning here in the favor of Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t know that the tide has ever turned against them in the sense that we&#8217;ve seen the Ukrainian military and Ukrainian leadership act incredibly courageously, bravely, stand up and hold off &#8212; I think to the surprise of the world &#8212; the Russian military longer than many would have assessed possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the ambitions of President Putin have never changed.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; The efforts of the Russian military to charge towards Kyiv have never changed.&nbsp; So, we are continuing our &#8212; and our assessment has not changed on what their attention &#8212; intentions are.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just &#8212; Zelenskyy said &#8212; he reiterated his interest in talking to Putin.&nbsp; He said he “need[s] to talk to Putin.&nbsp; The world needs to talk to Putin.&nbsp; There is no other way to stop [the] war.”&nbsp;<br><br>What conditions does the President need in order to have a conversation with Putin?&nbsp; And does he see any kind of engagement with Putin directly as constructive at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; For President Putin &#8212; I mean, for President Biden or for President Zelenskyy?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For President Biden.&nbsp; Biden.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, the &#8212; President Biden has no intention at this moment of engaging directly with President Putin.&nbsp; He is in the middle of an escalatory war in a sovereign foreign country.&nbsp; This is not the moment for the President of the United States to engage directly with President Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would say is that he leaves the door open to diplomacy.&nbsp; That has never closed shut.&nbsp; There are certainly steps &#8212; while I&#8217;m not going to outline from here, because we&#8217;ll engage on this through diplomatic channels, what exactly it would look like, there are obvious steps that can be taken &#8211;humanitarian corridors, a ceasefire.&nbsp; Those would all be welcomed steps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of what conditions, it&#8217;s not the moment now and I can&#8217;t predict for you if and when the moment would be.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just ask briefly: The presidents spoke, of course, about the need to confirm his Fed nominees in his State of the Union speech.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Republicans on the committee issued a statement yesterday, digging in, essentially, on Sarah Bloom Raskin.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering whether the White House remains committed and &#8212; with Senator Brown in advancing all the nominees in one slate and if you have any responses to the Republicans, on the latter?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, we absolutely do.&nbsp; All five of our nominees, including Sarah Bloom Raskin, are well qualified for these positions, and we&#8217;re calling on the Senate to confirm them as soon as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s important to remember what is happening here: The Republicans are not showing up to a committee vote.&nbsp; If one of them sho- &#8212; showed up, there would be a quorum to have a vote.&nbsp; And there are enough votes to move her past the committee.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not doing their job here, which is just to show up.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t have to vote for her; they just have to be in the room, which is essentially what people have elected them to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we stand by all of our nominees.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to engage with Senator Brown on moving them forward.&nbsp; And certainly, we believe, at this moment &#8212; when inflation is on the minds of Americans, when rising costs is on the minds of Americans &#8212; one thing that the Senate could do is confirm these nominees.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Russia has cut off access to Facebook inside of Russia.&nbsp; How does that affect U.S. efforts?&nbsp; Does the White House have concerns about that source of information to Russian citizens being cut off?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, this is part of their effort, as you know, I mean, to cut off a range of information from their public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They had &#8212; I talked about this a little bit yesterday, but there are concerning steps they have taken to crack down on any form of information being shared with their public.&nbsp; Certainly, Facebook is a part of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They&#8217;ve also threatened fines for journalists reporting on the ground.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve threatened &#8212; they&#8217;ve conveyed that there are only certain words their own Russian media can use, at the risk of being fined or even jailed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a pattern &#8212; this is not necessarily a new approach that they have taken &#8212; but to crack down on information in their country to reach the Russian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, certainly, we are deeply concerned about this and concerned about the threat on freedom of speech in the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other completely unrelated question: Loved ones who have lost people to COVID &#8212; some of them are advocating for a “COVID Memorial Day” or a physical memorial.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House have any view on that?&nbsp; Would you support something like that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s no question the President feels it&#8217;s important to remember, to memorialize, to take a moment to think of all of the people who have lost &#8212; whose lives have been lost, and all the loved ones who have lost loved ones.&nbsp; He talked about this in the State of the Union, right?</p>



<p>In terms of a memorial, I would say there&#8217;s an openness, but right now, we&#8217;re still battling the virus and still battling the pandemic and working to get funding from Congress to make sure we can continue to do that and moving towards hopefully getting vaccines approved for kids under five.</p>



<p>So, there&#8217;s more steps we&#8217;re taking.&nbsp; And right now, I just don&#8217;t have any prediction of what that may look like.&nbsp; But certainly, memorializing lives lost is something we are open to.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions for you.&nbsp; First of all, just on the idea of a Russian &#8212; a ban on purchasing Russian oil.&nbsp; The Wall Street Journal had a pretty good story earlier this week noting that the price of Russian oil has declined as the price of other oil has increased.&nbsp; And I wonder how much of this idea might already be sort of baked in &#8212; how much of the pricing might already be baked in &#8212; you know, whether that is something that you&#8217;re thinking &#8212; the White House is thinking about as it&#8217;s deciding whether or not to do this ban.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean how much of it is baked into the Russian economy in terms of having an impact?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, how much of it&#8217;s baked into the rise in oil that &#8212; you know, given that Russian oil prices are going down and people are &#8212; and it&#8217;s not being purchased out of the concern that, you know, there&#8217;s some uncertainty about delivery and there&#8217;s some uncertainty about, you know, whether there could be larger-scale bans; that the ensuing prices are all going up anyway, so you&#8217;re not really losing that much by banning Russian oil because nobody is really buying it.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what most experts in the global oil markets would say, though, is that reducing global oil supply would have an impact on the price of barrels of oil and, ultimately, gas prices.&nbsp; So, that is our concern.</p>



<p>Now, again, we will continue to have a range of conversations, but I think part of our assessment here is that, while maximizing the impacts by taking a range of steps we&#8217;ve already taken, you know, we are mindful of minimizing the impacts on the public.&nbsp; And certainly, the rising price of oil would &#8212; and the impact on gas prices is one we are focused on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just quickly: There was a Washington Post event earlier today where John Bolton said that Trump, quote, “may well have withdrawn from NATO” in a second term and that Putin was, quote, “waiting for that.”&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if you had any comment on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that&#8217;s &#8212; I saw those comments &#8212;&nbsp; you know, another reason why the American people are grateful &#8212; the majority of the American people &#8212; that President Biden has not taken a page out of his predecessors’ playbook as it relates to global engagement and global leadership, because, certainly, we could be in a different place.</p>



<p>I mean, there&#8217;s no question that the strength and unity of NATO has been a powerful force in this moment.&nbsp; And it may take longer time to have the &#8212; the hopeful impact.&nbsp; But, you know, that is &#8212; the strengthening of NATO, we think, is no &#8212; is unquestionably good for our security here in the United States and for the global sec- &#8212; for global security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Trevor.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, you said earlier in the briefing that you&#8217;d be providing information to the International Criminal Court about any war crimes being committed by Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; It&#8217;s long been the position of this administration that the ICC should not get involved in case &#8212; in countries where they don&#8217;t have jurisdiction.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve made that argument about the U.S., you&#8217;ve made that argument about Israel.&nbsp; Do you have a different position when it comes to Russia?&nbsp; And, if so, why?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&nbsp; think my point is that we would provide any information through our own process that became available to all of the international entities that are looking into and exploring this exact question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So there&#8217;s no change in your overall view that they shouldn&#8217;t take action?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we’re not a member of the ICC &#8212; right? &#8212; neither is Russia.&nbsp; They are exploring this.&nbsp; There are other entities I mentioned the &#8212; that we were a part of moving forward a commission through the U.N., which is certainly another entity that is looking into this and exploring this question.</p>



<p>Q    Okay.  And then, on Finland: Can you confirm that Finland is asking for the United States’ support in becoming a major non-member ally to NATO?  And would you support that?  Would you oppose it?  Where are you guys on that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  It’s a mouthful of a title, isn’t it?<br><br>Q    It &#8212; it is.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I know.  You got it out there though. <br><br>Look, I think the President is meeting with his counterpart shortly this afternoon.  I will let them speak to what their aspirations are.  And again, it would be up to NATO &#8212; the NATO Alliance to make any determinations about next steps.<br><br>Q    And just more broadly &#8212; just on, kind of, security guarantees to Finland.  I mean, they&#8217;re kind of in a similar position to Ukraine, right?  They&#8217;re &#8212; they&#8217;re thinking about what kind of alliances they &#8212; military alliances they want to have with the West.  And as they&#8217;re having that conversation and that thought process, Russia invaded one. <br><br>So, does Finland need some kind of similar security guarantees?  Do they need more security guarantees than Ukraine got?  And what is the U.S. willing to provide?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, without getting ahead of the meeting, I expect they will discuss, of course, the strong history of the U.S.-Finland&#8217;s defense relationship, which is complemented by Finland&#8217;s close relationship with NATO.<br><br>Finland&#8217;s current status as an Enhanced Opportunity Partner for the Alliance helps ensure strong defense and close security ties in the Baltic Sea region.&nbsp;<br><br>But again, you know, this is a continuing conversation.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure that their defense and security and our close ties will be a part of it.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ll let them have the meeting, and then we will have more to say, I&#8217;m sure, after it concludes.<br><br>Go ahead, David.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just following on the Finland thing briefly before I get to my question.&nbsp; I think the phrase is a “Major Non-NATO Ally,” and that is something the U.S. can designate by itself without having to go NATO, as you’ve suggested.&nbsp; Pakistan, for example, is a Major Non-NATO Ally.&nbsp; Is that something that we are considering in Finland’s case?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to let the meeting take place, and then we will have more to say after the meeting concludes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On your answer before on Iran: Has the President reviewed the current draft agreement?&nbsp; I understand there are some issues, including some with the IAEA, that are going to get addressed tomorrow when the chief of the IAEA is in Tehran.&nbsp; But has he reviewed and approved the agreement as it now stands?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has been regularly briefed on the status of the negotiations, but I&#8217;m not going to get into more specifics beyond that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is it his belief that any of this has to go to Congress?&nbsp; You&#8217;ve gotten that letter from 30-odd members of Congress on the issue.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve &#8212; we are aware of the letter.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to convey on that either.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see where this lands.&nbsp; Obviously, there&#8217;s more work to be done &#8212; pivotal pieces at the very end.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have anything to convey officially on that at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the very last is just to follow up on Phil&#8217;s question.&nbsp; So, on the question of why it is that we have not seen more cyber activity by the Russians at this point, do you believe it has to do more with the defenses, as you described &#8212; in other words, “passive deterrence” &#8212; that wouldn&#8217;t be able to affect us?&nbsp; Or do you think it has to do with something that was happening inside Russia &#8212; decisions that they made about when to go use these weapons?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a place I can get into from here, David.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say, though: We continue to be prepared.&nbsp; We continue to be prepared for retaliatary act- &#8212; retaliatory action, whether it is cyber or other means.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s something we&#8217;ve been preparing for for several months.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A couple of questions.&nbsp; President Zelenskyy said yesterday that if the West is unwilling to put in place a no-fly zone, it should at least provide Ukraine with warplanes so it can defend itself.&nbsp; Is that something that the U.S. is considering?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have provided a range of security and military assistance, including defensive assistance.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve recently provided helicopters that I think my Defense colleagues confirmed earlier today or yesterday.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything in addition to predict on that front.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And on a different topic, Ron Klain was on a podcast yesterday, and he suggested that the President was considering further extending the student loan moratorium, which expires in May.&nbsp; What can you tell us about that?&nbsp; When would &#8212; when can we expect a decision?&nbsp; And is he looking at another 90-day extension?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I certainly understand your question.&nbsp; That is obviously something we will continue to assess and review as we get closer to May.<br><br>Typically, there&#8217;s a period of time where you need to make a decision or you at least need to convey to the lenders what they should prepare for.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to predict at this point in time.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Karen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Since the mask rules here have changed &#8212;<br><br>(A cellphone disrupts the briefing.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh.&nbsp; It’s like hearing your own voice on the, you know, answering machine.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since the mask rules at the White House have changed this week, has there been any change to the testing protocols for the President? &nbsp;How regularly is he getting tested for COVID?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There have not been changes to the testing protocol that I&#8217;m aware of.&nbsp; I would note that, for all of us, we are still tested.&nbsp; If you see the President, you&#8217;re tested that day.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re not going to see the President, everybody is on a different version of a testing protocol.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has he been tested since Tuesday night&#8217;s State of the Union?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me check, and we will get the answer back out to all of you after the briefing.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ukraine asked for foreign reinforcements.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House position on volunteer international fighters who want to go to Ukraine?&nbsp; Would you encourage Americans go there to fight, or would you rather warn because they are not protected by Geneva Convention and it maybe also it would play in the hand of Putin&#8217;s narrative of &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our guidance continues to be that American citizens should not travel to Ukraine for any reason, so that&#8217;s where it stands.</p>



<p>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; A very factual question first.&nbsp; Could you maybe give us the exact number of how many Russian people and entities have been sanctioned by the United States, and how it compares to the European Union where, altogether, 680 people and 53 entities have been subjected to you know (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we can get you that.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have it at my fingertips &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, that would be wonderful.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; but let us get that to you after the briefing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And another one on oil imports, again &#8212; sorry about that.&nbsp; Do I understand it right that the United States won’t take that decision unless the Europeans take a similar decision, because Europeans rely way more heavily on Russian gas?&nbsp; And is that this idea that making that decision from here would somehow, you know, not work well with Allies?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have, from the beginning, taken steps in coordination with our Allies and partners in Europe, and that continues to be the first principle for the President.&nbsp; And obviously, as we&#8217;re making any decisions in this space, that would apply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But also &#8212; what also applies to this space is our focus, and I think the focus of the Europeans as well, on not taking steps that would create &#8212; increase volatility in the global oil markets, increase the price of oil &#8212; a barrel of oil, or increase gas prices.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re looking at all of that.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; Okay, guys, got to be the last one.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Quickly, then.&nbsp; So would the President then welcome Iranian oil coming into the United States in order to increase that supply?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, there&#8217;s not a &#8212; an Iran &#8212; there&#8217;s not a deal at this point in time.&nbsp; While we&#8217;re close, we&#8217;re not there.&nbsp; So, if and when we get to that point, we can speak to that question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; So, yesterday, you said, you know, less oil supply &#8212; you said it again today &#8212; raises prices.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you said ask the &#8212; so I asked the American Petroleum Institute about those 9,000 leases &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; which you’ve been talking about.&nbsp; The president and CEO of that group says that a lot of policies that have been put in place by this administration, including a ban on new development of federal lands and federal waters, is really “hindering American energy development” during a critical time.&nbsp; Also, he says the royalty fees increasing on drilling discourages investments.&nbsp; So, are there any plans to reverse any of these policies to encourage investment?&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think he may have avoided your question.&nbsp; I mean, because the fact is that onshore alone, as of the start of this year, the industry had more than 9,000 unused approved permits to drill in the United States.</p>



<p>And I didn&#8217;t hear him speak to that, in particular.&nbsp; And of the more than 37 million acres under lease offshore and onshore to the oil and gas industry, nearly 60 percent are currently non-producing.</p>



<p>Now, obviously, our view on drilling over the long term is different, I would suspect, than the person you spoke to, which is that what overall we need to do here is reduce our dependence on oil.&nbsp; Europeans are doing that; we&#8217;re doing that.&nbsp; And I think what we&#8217;re all going through now in this discussion of banning oil imports and the volatility in the global markets &#8212; oil markets is a reminder of that.</p>



<p>So &#8212; but there&#8217;s no shortage of drilling leases that can be used domestically to enhance production in this moment.&nbsp; They &#8212; the oil and gas industry is literally sitting on stockpiled leases and permits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, we &#8212; I think everybody has to wrap and go to the next engagement here.&nbsp; But see you all on Monday or later today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>2:50 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President of Finland Sauli&#160;Niinistö</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/04/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-of-finland-sauli-niinisto/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President of Finland Sauli Niinistö to discuss strengthening bilateral relations and ensuring strong defense and deterrence in northern Europe. The leaders also discussed ongoing transatlantic coordination to impose costs on Russia for its unprovoked and unjustified military invasion of Ukraine, and their respective efforts to provide security&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President of Finland Sauli Niinistö to discuss strengthening bilateral relations and ensuring strong defense and deterrence in northern Europe. The leaders also discussed ongoing transatlantic coordination to impose costs on Russia for its unprovoked and unjustified military invasion of Ukraine, and their respective efforts to provide security and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine. The Presidents committed to start a process that would strengthen U.S.-Finnish security cooperation, which would be conducted in close consultation with other Nordic countries. The Presidents also discussed the importance of NATO’s Open Door policy. In addition, they discussed energy security and efforts to address climate change.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden on Delivering On Made In America&#160;Commitments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/04/remarks-by-president-biden-on-delivering-on-made-in-america-commitments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 22:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium 1:29 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; What Johnny didn&#8217;t tell you: He&#8217;s a breakdancer.&#160; (Laughs) But he&#8217;s not going to do it on the stage right now.&#160; (Laughter.) Before I begin officially today, I want to thank the Made in America Director, Celeste Drake.&#160; I also want to acknowledge it’s her birthday today.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium</p>



<p>1:29 P.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What Johnny didn&#8217;t tell you: He&#8217;s a breakdancer.&nbsp; (Laughs) But he&#8217;s not going to do it on the stage right now.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Before I begin officially today, I want to thank the Made in America Director, Celeste Drake.&nbsp; I also want to acknowledge it’s her birthday today.&nbsp; And it’s really tough turning 30, so be nice to her.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Happy birthday, kid. (Applause.)<br><br>MS. DRAKE:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT: (Laughs.)<br><br>And, Johnny, thank you.&nbsp; Thanks to all your coworkers I just had a chance to meet before you all came in.<br><br>And I want to thank Barbara &#8212; Barbara Humpton, Siemens.&nbsp; Lonnie Stephenson, President of the IBEW &#8212; one of my closest buddies, and he&#8217;s been my friend for a long, long time.<br><br>Earlier this week, in my State of the Union Address,<br>I said there was something happening in America, starting with a historic economic recovery that we’re seeing right now.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, we&#8217;ve learned that in February, our economy created 678,000 new jobs.&nbsp; Six hundred and seventy-eight thousand new jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>And over the course of my presidency, our economy has now created 7.4 million jobs &#8212; more jobs created in a 13-month period than at any time ever before in our history.<br><br>And we&#8217;ve learned that, in February, the unemployment rate fell to 3.8 percent &#8212; down from 6.4 percent the day I took office, beginning in 2021 &#8212; which is the fastest decline in the unemployment rate in recorded history because of all of you.<br><br>And, by the way, before the American Rescue Plan passed,<br>the Congressional Budget Office didn’t project our unemployment rate to hit 3.8 percent at any time over the entire decade.<br><br>Americans are back to work.<br><br>Yes, family budgets are still tight, but a lot of Americans are getting paychecks this year more than they got last year.&nbsp; And restoring the dignity of work so they can show up at work with some pride.<br><br>You know, job gains in February were broad based across sectors, from construction to retail to manufacturing to leisure and hospitality.<br><br>The decline in the unemployment rate was broad based as well.&nbsp; In fact, the unemployment rate among workers without high school degrees fell to 4.3 percent &#8212; the lowest on recorded &#8212; that was &#8212; since we&#8217;ve been keeping records.&nbsp; 4.3 percent.&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s amazing.<br><br>Workers’ weekly earnings rose in February.&nbsp; The people in working-class sectors like transportation and warehousing saw some of the strongest wage gains.<br><br>This is what it looks like to grow an economy from the bottom up and the middle out.<br><br>Because of the progress we’ve made in fighting COVID, Americans can not only get back to work but they can going to the office and safely fill our great downtown cities again and &#8212; creating more commerce.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>With 75 percent of adult Americans fully vaccinated and hospitalizations down by 77 percent, most Americans can remove their masks, return to work, and move forward safely.<br><br>Today’s news is a welcome reminder that we’re coming back stronger as a country and as a people.<br><br>You know, we&#8217;ve been through two of the hardest years this nation has ever faced.&nbsp; The pandemic has been punishing, as many of you know.&nbsp; And some of you may know it from a personal standpoint.&nbsp; Maybe you lost someone in this process; you got up this morning and looked at an empty chair.&nbsp; Well, it’s been punishing, but we’re coming back.&nbsp;<br><br>And so many families are still struggling, though, to make ends meet because of inflation.<br><br>I understand.&nbsp; Our top priority must be getting prices under control.<br><br>Look, our economy roared back faster than most predicted,&nbsp;<br>but the pandemic meant that businesses had a hard time hiring enough workers to keep up and &#8212; production in their factories.<br><br>The pandemic also dir- &#8212; disrupted the global supply chains.<br><br>Factories &#8212; when factories close, it takes longer to make goods and to get them to the warehouse and to get them to the store, and prices go up.<br><br>Just take a look at cars.&nbsp; Last year, there weren’t enough semiconductors to make all the automobiles people wanted to buy.&nbsp; They had a lot more money in their savings accounts and in their paychecks, but they weren’t able to go out and to spend it on leisure because of COVID.&nbsp;<br><br>So, what happened?&nbsp; They decided to &#8212; they were purchasing products like everything from homes to automobiles to hard products.&nbsp;<br><br>And the price of automobiles, for example, went way up &#8212; more people seeking them and fewer being made.<br><br>And we have a choice.&nbsp; We have a choice.&nbsp; The way to fight inflation is to drive down wages and make Americans poorer or have a better plan to fight inflation: Lower costs and not your wages.&nbsp;<br><br>The more semiconductors we make in America &#8212; and, by the way, they were invented here in America.&nbsp; The semiconductor was invented in America when we went to the Moon.&nbsp;<br><br>And when we do that, when we focus on making sure that we make those again in the Unites States of America &#8212; so few are being made &#8212; we make &#8212; we make a heck of a lot more cars and you bring prices down; the supply chain is filled.&nbsp;<br><br>Investment in America &#8212; rebuilding roads, bridges, airports, ports.&nbsp; We invest in innovation in America.&nbsp; That’s exactly what we’re doing.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, as a result, we’re seeing more jobs, more hope, and we’re also seeing something else: the rebirth of pride &#8212; the rebirth of pride that comes from stamping products “Made in America.”<br><br>And we’re seeing the revitalization of American manufacturing.&nbsp; And that’s what I want to talk a little bit about for the next few minutes.<br><br>Today, companies are choosing to build new factories when, just a few years ago, they would’ve built them overseas.&nbsp; They&#8217;re investing right here in America.&nbsp;<br><br>On this very stage, we were standing before &#8212; Intel &#8212; the chairman of the board of Intel was here.&nbsp; He announced a $20 billion investment to build a sumicondecter [sic] &#8212; semiconductor mega site outside of Columbus, Ohio, creating 10,000 new good-paying jobs.&nbsp; A portion of that went to construction jobs, but the full-time jobs &#8212; the average salary in those places is going to be $135,000 a year.&nbsp;<br><br>And if Congress passes the Bipartisan Innovation Act, Intel is ready to increase their investment from $20 billion to $100 billion.<br><br>You know, as I said, we invented the semiconductor, but we haven’t been making them in America for a long time.&nbsp; We had to import them.&nbsp; We had to wait.&nbsp; It costs more.&nbsp; And that’s what I mean when I say “dealing with the supply chains”<br><br>Since I took office, companies have announced investments<br>totaling more than $100 billion in electric vehicle industry for the future, from the iconic companies like Ford, GM &#8212; new electric vehicle production; Tesla &#8212; our nation’s largest electric vehicle manufacturer; to innovate and &#8212; and inspire younger companies &#8212; like Rivian, building electric trucks; Proterra, building electric buses.<br><br>Last month, the &#8212; MP Materials, which operates only rare earth &#8212; the only rare earth mine in the United States, announced a $700 million investment by 2025 that will have fully dome- &#8212; it will have &#8212; have a fully domestic end-to-end supply chain for the magnets that are used in electric vehicle motors, wind turbines, and defense systems.&nbsp; They&#8217;re investing that money here in the United States.<br><br>And the Union Pacific Railroad announced the largest purchase of American-made battery-electric locomotives in history.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; They’re built in Western Pennsylvania.<br><br>All told, the economy created 423,000 new manufacturing jobs in America, paying decent salaries, just since I entered office.<br><br>There’s also a reason this &#8212; another reason this is happening.&nbsp; We’re not waiting for others to manufacture the products we invented.&nbsp; We know what to do.&nbsp; We know how to manufacture things in America.<br><br>And today, that progress continues.<br><br>I just had a chance to visit &#8212; have a&nbsp;<s>viral</s>&nbsp;[virtual] tour of both the Siemens faci- &#8212; facilities &#8212; one in Pomona and the other in Grand Prairie, Texas &#8212; a chance to talk with some of the IBEW members working there.<br><br>Because our Infrastructure Law provides $7.5 billion &#8212; $7.5 billion &#8212; to build a national network of 500,000 electric vehicle charging stations across America.&nbsp; And it also provides $16.5 billion to modernize our power grid, how we move electricity across America.&nbsp; Companies like Siemens are investing here in the United States of America.<br><br>And you just heard from Barbara, Siemens is announcing a $54 million investment to upgrade and expand those facilities in Texas and California that develop the high-tech, high-value electrical equipment that is used in electric circuitry,&nbsp;<br>switchboards, electric vehicles, chargers out on the highways, and data centers.&nbsp; This announcement alone is going to create 300 new good-paying, cutting-edge manufacturing jobs.<br><br>Folks, America is coming back.&nbsp; It really is.<br><br>In addition to Siemens &#8212; in addition, Siemens will be building an entirely new facility to make charging equipment for electric vehicles.&nbsp; The location of that facility will be announced later this year.&nbsp; I don’t know where it is, so don’t ask.&nbsp; (Laughter.) &nbsp;A lot of my colleagues in the Congress are going to be saying, “Joe, where is going to go?”&nbsp; I don’t know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But it’s going to be in America and help us continue to grow our clean-energy economy.<br><br>Look, folks, when I ran and got elected, I said I wanted to&nbsp;rebuild America.&nbsp; This is what I was talking about.&nbsp; And we want to see a lot more stories like this one.<br><br>So when &#8212; with the taxpayers&#8217; dollars to rebuild America &#8212; when they’re &#8212; and that’s what they are: taxpayers’ dollars &#8212;&nbsp; we’re going to buy American.&nbsp; Buying American products to support American jobs.&nbsp; And by the way, these are the best products in the world.<br><br>The federal government spends about $600 billion a year<br>in goods and services to fulfill its responsibilities to the American people &#8212; from the Defense Department, to healthcare, to education, and beyond.<br><br>The fact &#8212; in fact, what’s happening is the federal government is Siemens’ largest customer, for example.<br><br>Most people don’t know there’s been a law on the books<br>for almost a century to make sure your tax dollars support American jobs and American businesses.&nbsp; Every administration says they’re going to use that &#8212; that law.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But when it comes time to make these purchases &#8212; whether that’s the deck of an aircraft carrier or a ventilation system in a school &#8212; the response is often is from the &#8212; from the government: “We can’t find an American company, so we need to issue a waiver and buy the product that was made overseas” &#8212; not by an American worker &#8212; so, “Buy American” became a hollow promise.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, in my administration, “Buy American” is a reality.&nbsp; We’ve created a “Made in America” Office in the White House to oversee our efforts.&nbsp; And you just heard from Celeste who runs that office.<br><br>In my first Cabinet meeting, I told everyone that if their agency wants to issue a waiver to purchase something for their agency and what they have a responsibility for, they don’t have to use an &#8212; and they think they don’t have to use an American company, well, guess what?&nbsp; They have to come to the White House office and set up and explain to me why they have to post that request &#8212; why they have to do that.&nbsp; And they’re going to have to post the request publicly on our sites so American manufacturers and businesses have a chance to raise their hand and say: “No, no, I can do that.&nbsp; Here &#8212; here &#8212; I can do that in my shop, in my town.”<br><br>Today, we’re going even further.&nbsp; I’m announcing the biggest change in the Buy American Act in 70 years.&nbsp; Right now, if you’re manufacturing a product that gets purchased by the federal government, the law says that it has to be “substantially all”&nbsp;of that product should be made in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>But because of loopholes over time, you know what “substantially all” means when I took office?&nbsp; If 55 percent is made in America, it’s “substantially all.”&nbsp; To me, 55 percent isn’t “substantially all;” it’s slightly over half.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, we’re issuing a rule to raise the amount of domestic content required to be considered Made in America from 55 percent to 75 percent.&nbsp; “Substantially all” is going to start meaning substantially all.<br><br>And, today, we’re also announcing a new framework for critical products where we know we need stronger, more resilient, domestic supply chains.&nbsp;<br><br>We saw it during the pandemic that supply chain disruptions<br>can put American lives and livelihoods at risk.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, when we &#8212; what &#8212; when we needed them most, we were short of masks, gowns, gloves, ventilation, and other essential health products we had to buy abroad.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we’re creating a new “price preference.”&nbsp; What this means is that if we’re identifying some product that is so critical to our national security, health, or resilience, that we’re going to create rules to allow us to pay a little more for them if they’re made in America.<br><br>We’re talking about things like semiconductors, some pharmaceutical ingredients, advanced batteries &#8212; among other things.<br><br>It’s worth it for us to ensure we have a domestic capacity to protect us from shortages and price spikes in the future.<br><br>And, yes, we’re going to keep trading with our allies and friends, and we’re going to work with them to ensure every single country can create global chokepoints for critical goods &#8212; can’t have those chokepoints.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But we also need a resilient supply chains of our own so that we’re never at the mercy of other countries for critical goods ever again.<br><br>And by the way, when I say “Buy American,” I mean buy all &#8212; all American.&nbsp; I want to increase the share of federal spending on goods and services that goes to small businesses in America &#8212; the backbone of our country.<br><br>Last year, I released a plan to increase the number of&nbsp;<s>contacts</s>&nbsp;[contracts] that go to small disadvantaged businesses by 50 percent by 2025.&nbsp;<br><br>This means more contracts will go to Black, Brown, Native American, women-owned, veteran-owned small businesses in every state and territory, in every industry &#8212; from services to manufacturing to agriculture.<br><br>Already, we’re seeing success.&nbsp; Woman-owned businesses have won contracts to provide masks for the government, clothing for the Marines.<br><br>Veteran-owned small business are now producing specialty trucks and trailers for the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Army.<br><br>And we’re seeing other “Buy American” successes, which will allow us to make synthetic rubber gloves in Alabama, fibers that go into N95 masks in New Hampshire, shipping containers in Maryland &#8212; the list goes on.<br><br>And here’s what it all adds up to: Today, I’m placing a bet on America.&nbsp; Everyone here is going to make sure that it pays off &#8212; everyone on this stage.<br><br>What I say today &#8212; what I’ve &#8212; what we’ve seen in the past months is more reason why we need to reject the defeatist view that the forces of automation and globalization mean we can’t have good-paying union jobs &#8212; manufacturing &#8212; here in America.<br><br>Our manufacturing future, our economic future, our solutions to the climate crisis: They’re all going to be made in America.&nbsp;<br><br>And what that means to build a better America &#8212; well, it does.&nbsp; We’re going to build a better America as a consequence.&nbsp;<br><br>So, thank you all very much.&nbsp; And I thank my colleagues for being here.&nbsp; And I understand a lot of the Siemens folks are in the front row there too &#8212; welcome.&nbsp; And you thank you all in California and in Texas.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>1:46 P.M. EST</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>###</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Niinistö of the Republic of Finland Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/04/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-niinisto-of-the-republic-of-finland-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 21:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 2:56 P.M. EST PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Welcome.&#160; I’m delighted to have a good friend here with us today, the President of Finland, in the White House in what is a critical moment involving all of Europe. And, you know, we&#8217;ve been in regular touch for some time now and coordinated a united, transatlantic response&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>2:56 P.M. EST<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Welcome.&nbsp; I’m delighted to have a good friend here with us today, the President of Finland, in the White House in what is a critical moment involving all of Europe.<br><br>And, you know, we&#8217;ve been in regular touch for some time now and coordinated a united, transatlantic response to the Russians and holding Russians accountable for their unprovoked and unjustifiable aggression against Ukraine.<br><br>And we agreed it&#8217;s not only an attack on Ukraine, it&#8217;s an attack on the security of Europe and on the global peace and stability.<br><br>And Finland is a critical partner of the United States, a strong defense partner as well, a partner to NATO, especially in &#8212; on strengthening the security of the Baltic Sea area.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;re committed to helping Ukraine defend itself and &#8212; in support of the humanitarian needs of Ukraine and its people.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re coordinated on everything from sanctions to export controls and broader global issues of energy, security, climate, and human rights.<br><br>So, I want to thank you for making the trip, Mr. President.&nbsp; Our bilateral relati- &#8212; relationship is vitally important to the United States, and I think you see it the same way.&nbsp; And this is another opportunity for us to further strengthen that relationship.<br><br>So, thank you for being here.&nbsp; Welcome to the Oval Office.&nbsp; And the floor is yours.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT NIINISTÖ:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Thank you very much for the opportunity to have this discussion with you.&nbsp; We are really living in very difficult times.&nbsp; I want to thank you also for the leadership you have showed.&nbsp; We need it now.<br><br>Our thoughts today undoubtedly are with the Ukrainian people who are fighting bravely for their country.&nbsp; And we do our best to help them.<br><br>Like you, Mr. President, said, we have a long-lasting partnership &#8212; very good relations &#8212; and I hope that during this meeting and discussion, we can strengthen them more between the United States and Finland and the Nordic countries all together.<br><br>Thank you, Mr. President.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, you know, as my predecessor who sat in this seat, President Obama, used to say, we&#8217;d be alright if we left everything to the Nordic countries.&nbsp; Everything would be fine.<br><br>PRESIDENT NIINISTÖ:&nbsp; Well, we usually don&#8217;t start wars.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; Anyway, well, thank you very much.<br><br>Thank you all for being here.<br><br>2:59 P.M. EST</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>###</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Deputy Press Secretary Sabrina Singh on Vice President Harris’s Travel to Poland and&#160;Romania</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/04/statement-by-deputy-press-secretary-sabrina-singh-on-vice-president-harriss-travel-to-poland-and-romania-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48413</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris will travel to Warsaw, Poland and Bucharest, Romania March 9-11. Her visit will demonstrate the strength and unity of the NATO Alliance and U.S. support for NATO’s eastern flank allies in the face of Russian aggression. It will also highlight our collective efforts to support the people of Ukraine. During her meetings&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris will travel to Warsaw, Poland and Bucharest, Romania March 9-11. Her visit will demonstrate the strength and unity of the NATO Alliance and U.S. support for NATO’s eastern flank allies in the face of Russian aggression. It will also highlight our collective efforts to support the people of Ukraine.<br> <br>During her meetings with the leaders of Poland and Romania, the Vice President will advance our close coordination in response to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. They will discuss our continuing support for the people of Ukraine through security, economic, and humanitarian assistance and our determination to impose severe economic consequences on Russia and those complicit in Russia’s invasion. The Vice President’s meetings will also focus on how the United States can further support Ukraine’s neighbors as they welcome and care for refugees fleeing violence.<br> <br>More details on the Vice President’s engagements will be forthcoming in the coming days.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Consumer Protection Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/04/national-consumer-protection-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 19:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As our Nation recovers and our economy continues its historic growth following a global pandemic, it is important that consumers are fully informed about their rights and the potential risks in the marketplace.&#160;&#160;Hardworking American families deserve to feel secure in the knowledge that, as we&#160;build back better, we are building an economy based on principles&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As our Nation recovers and our economy continues its historic growth following a global pandemic, it is important that consumers are fully informed about their rights and the potential risks in the marketplace.&nbsp;&nbsp;Hardworking American families deserve to feel secure in the knowledge that, as we&nbsp;build back better, we are building an economy based on principles of fairness, privacy, and equity.&nbsp;&nbsp;During National Consumer Protection Week, we recommit ourselves to those basic rights, to protecting consumers, to raising awareness about bad&nbsp;actors and deceptive practices in the marketplace, and to empowering people to make informed financial decisions so that&nbsp;our economy works for everyone.</p>



<p>My Administration has zero tolerance for criminals who steal Americans&#8217; hard-earned dollars or abuse their personal information.  Particularly in moments of crisis, like this pandemic, unscrupulous individuals have tried to take advantage of struggling Americans by price gouging, stealing money, harvesting personal information, and offering false hope for economic assistance, jobs, treatments, and cures.  We are committed to halting these practices and protecting all consumers, including small businesses and gig workers, from fraud and unlawful business practices.  Our Nation&#8217;s consumer protection agencies &#8212; including the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, and Consumer Product Safety Commission &#8212; work with the Department of Justice and law enforcement agencies nationwide to fight fraud, predatory practices, and data exploitation by abusers large and small.  These agencies work every day to protect consumers and ensure product safety through investigations, law enforcement actions, and free, actionable, plain-language consumer education resources.</p>



<p>Abusive practices have an especially harmful impact on communities of color, who are often targeted by bad actors.  A report from the FTC &#8212; <em>Serving Communities of Color</em> &#8212; found that people living in majority-Black and Latino communities were more likely to experience problems with credit bureaus, banks and lenders, and used car issues than those living in majority-white communities.  That is why my Administration is reviving the Government&#8217;s top consumer watchdog, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, to address racial disparities in access to loans, capital, and credit, while protecting consumers in historically underserved communities. </p>



<p>As a Nation, let us work together to create an environment that protects and educates American consumers and communities.  This National Consumer Protection Week, and all year long, my Administration is committed to ensuring that every American has access to information that can help protect themselves and their communities.  To learn more about these resources, please visit <a href="https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/features/national-consumer-protection-week">consumer.ftc.gov</a>.  To learn how to get involved with National Consumer Protection Week, you can visit <a href="https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/features/national-consumer-protection-week">ftc.gov/ncpw</a>. </p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 6, 2022, through March 12, 2022, as National Consumer Protection Week.  I call upon government officials, industry leaders, and advocates across the Nation to share information about consumer protection and provide our citizens with information about their rights as consumers.     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fourth day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Meeting with Crown Prince Salman bin Hamad Al Khalifa of&#160;Bahrain</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/04/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-crown-prince-salman-bin-hamad-al-khalifa-of-bahrain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 19:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Crown Prince Salman bin Hamad Al Khalifa of Bahrain in Washington, D.C. The Vice President underscored the U.S. commitment to strengthening the U.S.-Bahrain partnership and expressed appreciation for Bahrain’s collaboration on a range of bilateral, regional and global issues.  The Vice President and the Crown Prince discussed Russia’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Crown Prince Salman bin Hamad Al Khalifa of Bahrain in Washington, D.C. The Vice President underscored the U.S. commitment to strengthening the U.S.-Bahrain partnership and expressed appreciation for Bahrain’s collaboration on a range of bilateral, regional and global issues.  The Vice President and the Crown Prince discussed Russia’s unprovoked, unjustified further invasion of Ukraine and the international community’s collective response. They also discussed regional issues, such as the challenges posed by Iran, and the opportunities presented by the historic Abraham Accords. The Vice President reiterated the Biden-Harris Administration’s support for human rights in Bahrain and around the world. The Vice President also welcomed Bahrain joining the Artemis Accords, a set of rules and norms to guide international cooperation in space.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the United Arab Emirates to Attend the United&#160;States National Day at the Expo 2020&#160;Dubai</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/04/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-united-arab-emirates-to-attend-the-united-states-national-day-at-the-expo-2020-dubai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 19:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEMarch 4, 2022 President Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the United Arab Emirates to Attend the United States National Day at the Expo 2020 Dubai&#160; President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the United Arab Emirates to attend the United States National Day at Expo 2020&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE<br>March 4, 2022</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>President Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the United Arab Emirates to Attend the United States National Day at the Expo 2020 Dubai&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the United Arab Emirates to attend the United States National Day at Expo 2020 Dubai on March 6, 2022.  <br><br>The Honorable Gina M. Raimondo, Secretary of Commerce, will lead the delegation.<br><br><strong><u>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</u></strong><br><br>Mr. Sean Murphy, Chargé d’Affaires ad interim, U.S. Embassy Abu Dhabi<br><br>The Honorable Roy Blunt, United States Senator (R), Missouri<br><br>Ms. Jennifer Hall Godfrey, Senior Official for Public Diplomacy and Public of Affairs, U.S. Department of State<br><br>The Honorable Maria Rosario Jackson, Ph.D., Chair of the National Endowment for the Arts<br><br>The Honorable Robert Clark, U.S. Commissioner General at Expo 2020 Dubai<br><br>Mr. Dilawar Syed, Special Representative for Commercial and Business Affairs, <br>U.S. Department of State<br><br>The Honorable Barbara Leaf, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for the Middle East and North Africa, National Security Council<br><br>Ms. Meghan Gregonis, Consul General, U.S. Consulate Dubai</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call With President Andrzej Duda of&#160;Poland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/04/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 19:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Andrzej Duda of Poland to discuss our countries’ response, in close coordination with our Allies and partners, to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine, including ongoing efforts to impose severe consequences on Russia.  President Biden underscored the United States’ commitment to the security of Poland&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Andrzej Duda of Poland to discuss our countries’ response, in close coordination with our Allies and partners, to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine, including ongoing efforts to impose severe consequences on Russia.  President Biden underscored the United States’ commitment to the security of Poland and all of our NATO Allies.  He welcomed Poland’s partnership in hosting 9,000 U.S. forces, including 4,700 additional servicemembers deployed there in recent weeks, to reassure eastern flank Allies, deter Russian aggression against NATO, and stand shoulder to shoulder with their Polish counterparts to maintain security and stability in Europe.  The two leaders affirmed their commitment to the people of Ukraine, including the importance of providing urgent humanitarian assistance. President Biden thanked President Duda and the people of Poland for their hospitality in hosting and assisting nearly 700,000 Ukrainians and others who have fled the war so far.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
