<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:24:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Day Of Remembrance Of Japanese American Incarceration During World War&#160;II</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/18/day-of-remembrance-of-japanese-american-incarceration-during-world-war-ii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Eighty years ago, on&#160;February 19, 1942, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed Executive Order 9066, stripping people of Japanese descent of their civil rights. &#160;That order and the subsequent actions carried out by the Federal Government represent one of the most shameful chapters in our Nation&#8217;s history. &#160;On this Day of Remembrance of Japanese American Incarceration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Eighty years ago, on&nbsp;February 19, 1942, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed Executive Order 9066, stripping people of Japanese descent of their civil rights. &nbsp;That order and the subsequent actions carried out by the Federal Government represent one of the most shameful chapters in our Nation&#8217;s history. &nbsp;On this Day of Remembrance of Japanese American Incarceration During World War II, we acknowledge the unjust incarceration of some 120,000 Japanese Americans, approximately two-thirds of whom were born in the United States.<br><br>Despite never being charged with a crime, and without due process, Japanese Americans were forcibly removed from their homes and communities and incarcerated, simply because of their heritage.&nbsp; For years, many Japanese Americans lived in harsh, overcrowded conditions, surrounded by barbed wire fences and armed guards. &nbsp;Not only did they lose their homes, businesses, property, and savings &#8212; they also lost their liberty, security, and the fundamental freedoms that belong to all Americans in equal measure.<br><br>I have always believed that great nations do not ignore their most painful moments &#8212; they confront them with honesty and, in doing so, learn from them and grow stronger as a result.&nbsp; The incarceration of Japanese Americans 80 years ago is a reminder to us today of the tragic consequences we invite when we allow racism, fear, and xenophobia to fester.<br><br>Today, we reaffirm the Federal Government&#8217;s formal apology to Japanese Americans whose lives were irreparably harmed during this dark period of our history, and we solemnly reflect on our collective moral responsibility to ensure that our Nation never again engages in such un-American acts.&nbsp; We acknowledge the intergenerational trauma and loss that the incarceration of Japanese Americans has caused. &nbsp;We also uplift the courage and resilience of brave Japanese Americans who, despite being unjustly incarcerated, formed powerful communities and marshalled incredible dignity and strength.<br><br>Many of those whose families were incarcerated volunteered or were drafted to serve in combat &#8212; courageously serving in the 100th Infantry Battalion, Military Intelligence Service, Women&#8217;s Army Auxiliary Corps, Army Nurse Corps, and the 442nd Regimental Combat Team with unwavering patriotism.&nbsp; The all-Japanese American 100th Infantry Battalion and the 442nd Regimental Combat Team became two of the most decorated and distinguished military units in our Nation&#8217;s history.&nbsp; Countless Japanese Americans carry forward this legacy of extraordinary service today, and their work to preserve the history of this period strengthens our Nation and our democracy.<br><br>We reflect on the bravery of civil rights leaders like Fred Korematsu, Minoru Yasui, Gordon Hirabayashi, and Mitsuye Endo, and that of every Japanese American who organized and sought redress. &nbsp;Their efforts helped bring about the first Day of Remembrance, led President Jimmy Carter to sign the law creating the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians, and spurred President Ronald Reagan to sign the Civil Liberties Act of 1988, which provided monetary reparations to living survivors and an official apology to the Japanese American community. &nbsp;At the same time, we also acknowledge the painful reality that Japanese Latin Americans, who were taken from their Central and South American homes and incarcerated by the United States Government during World&nbsp;War&nbsp;II, were excluded from the Civil Liberties Act of 1988.<br><br>Today, the National Park Service helps preserve several Japanese American incarceration camps. &nbsp;These tangible reminders of our history provide important spaces for reflection and learning about the injustices born of prejudice. &nbsp;Preserving incarceration sites as national parks and historic landmarks is proof of our Nation&#8217;s commitment to facing the wrongs of our past, to healing the pain still felt by survivors and their descendants, and to ensuring that we always remember why it matters that we never stop fighting for equality and justice for all.&nbsp; My Administration is committed to maintaining these national parks and landmarks for future generations and to combating xenophobia, hate, and intolerance &#8212; including through the reestablished White House Initiative on Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders. &nbsp;In the words of&nbsp;Dr. Frank Kitamoto, who was incarcerated as a child, &#8220;This is not just a Japanese American story but an American story with implications for the world.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>The words we use to describe the historical and present treatment of communities of color and other underserved communities have profound meaning. &nbsp;Today, we recognize that euphemistic terms that we have collectively used in the past &#8212; such as &#8220;assembly centers,&#8221; &#8220;relocation,&#8221; or &#8220;internment&#8221; &#8212; do not adequately describe the injustice experienced by some 120,000 people; we recognize the forced removal and mass incarceration of Japanese Americans and others during World War II; and we reaffirm our commitment to <em>Nidoto Nai Yoni</em><em>,</em> which translates to &#8220;Let It Not Happen Again.&#8221;<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim&nbsp;February&nbsp;19, 2022, as a Day of Remembrance of Japanese American Incarceration During World War II. &nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to commemorate this injustice against civil liberties and civil rights during World&nbsp;War&nbsp;II; to honor the sacrifice of those who defended the democratic ideals of this Nation; and to commit together to eradicate systemic racism to heal generational trauma in our communities.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighteenth day of February, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Eating Disorders Awareness Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/18/a-proclamation-on-national-eating-disorders-awareness-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Eating Disorders Awareness Week provides an opportunity to draw attention to one of the most serious mental health conditions impacting the lives of Americans and their families today.&#160; Eating disorders &#8212; including binge-eating, bulimia nervosa, and anorexia nervosa &#8212; affect people of all backgrounds and genders. &#160;Nearly 1 in 10 Americans are expected to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Eating Disorders Awareness Week provides an opportunity to draw attention to one of the most serious mental health conditions impacting the lives of Americans and their families today.&nbsp; Eating disorders &#8212; including binge-eating, bulimia nervosa, and anorexia nervosa &#8212; affect people of all backgrounds and genders. &nbsp;Nearly 1 in 10 Americans are expected to develop an eating disorder in their lifetime.&nbsp; In recent years, there has been a troubling surge in eating disorders among children, older adults, military service members, and transgender individuals. &nbsp;When undiagnosed or untreated, eating disorders can have serious &#8212; even fatal &#8212; consequences, which is why improving mental health services and support is so important.</p>



<p>The COVID-19 pandemic has been especially challenging for individuals with eating disorders.&nbsp; National eating disorder hotlines have seen a more than 70&nbsp;percent spike in the volume of calls and chats since the pandemic started.&nbsp; Research shows that the number of hospitalizations for eating disorders has doubled during that same time period.</p>



<p>Despite the fact that eating disorders have among the highest mortality rate of any mental illness, the shame and stigmatization of eating disorders often prevent people who are suffering from seeking help.&nbsp; That is why it is important to make more people aware that, with early detection and medical intervention, full recovery from an eating disorder is possible.</p>



<p>My Administration is working to improve access to treatment, recovery, and social support for everyone currently living with an eating disorder as well as for their caregivers, families, and friends.&nbsp; Through the National Institute of Mental Health, we are working to develop better therapies and interventions.&nbsp; My Administration is also working to ensure that eating disorder care and treatment are treated the same as any other medical conditions by health insurance plans.&nbsp; Funding from the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) provides health care providers, families, caregivers, and community members the tools, training, and resources to recognize the symptoms of an eating disorder so that referrals to specialty providers and treatment can be provided as early as possible.</p>



<p>We are also working to increase access to mental health services and support for young people, who are uniquely vulnerable to eating disorders.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan included $122 billion to help schools reopen safely, enabling them to support the mental health of their students.&nbsp; I have also called for doubling the number of school-based health counselors, social workers, and nurses.&nbsp; Together, these resources will be essential to addressing the mental health needs of our Nation&#8217;s youth.</p>



<p>To all those families who have watched a loved one face an eating disorder and to all those who are currently facing or recovering from an eating disorder &#8212; you are in our hearts and you are not alone.  It is within our power to reduce the burden of eating disorders on the lives of Americans and their families.  As we work toward these improvements, immediate assistance is available for those in need of help.  The SAMHSA National Helpline at 1-800-662-4357 is a confidential, free, 24-hour-a-day, 365-days-a-year information and referral service.  For anyone experiencing a crisis, immediate help is also available by calling the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline at 1-800-273-TALK.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim February 21 through February 27, 2022, as National Eating Disorders Awareness Week.&nbsp; I encourage citizens, government agencies, private businesses, nonprofit organizations, and other interested groups to join in activities that will increase awareness of what Americans can do to prevent eating disorders and improve access to care and other support services for those currently living with an eating disorder.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighteenth day of February, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 15:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47483</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Commerzbank Filiale München Munich, Germany 1:22 P.M. CEST VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&#160; Mr. Secretary General, thank you for all of the work that you have been doing over the course of eight years in your role of leadership.&#160; As I mentioned to you earlier, this is the first meeting that I&#8217;m taking in Munich, and that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Commerzbank Filiale München </em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Munich, Germany</em></p>



<p>1:22 P.M. CEST<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Mr. Secretary General, thank you for all of the work that you have been doing over the course of eight years in your role of leadership.&nbsp;<br><br>As I mentioned to you earlier, this is the first meeting that I&#8217;m taking in Munich, and that is intentional.&nbsp; The President and I feel very strongly, as does our country, that our Alliance and our relationship and commitment to NATO is enduring, that it is being highlighted without any question over the course of the last several months.<br><br>We believe that the relationship has only strengthened.&nbsp; And as we go forward, we believe that it will continue to be one of the most critical relationships that we have.&nbsp;<br><br>I also want to thank you for the commitment that you have made throughout your career to the importance of the transatlantic Alliance &#8212; understanding its history and understanding its role in terms of international norms and rules, what we must do to ensure security, also with the interests of mutual prosperity.&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, we are obviously dealing with the concern about what is happening in Ukraine.&nbsp; As a member of NATO, we feel very strongly and will always be committed to the principle of territorial integrity and sovereignty.&nbsp;<br><br>I am here to ensure that through our discussions and the discussions I will have with other of our Allies, that we continue, as these hours and days progress, to stay in close contact.<br><br>We understand this is a dynamic moment in time.&nbsp; And so, the work that we are doing on a daily basis and sometimes on an hourly basis &#8212; to strengthen the relationship; to check in, in terms of our strategic imperative &#8212; is critically important.&nbsp; And that is one of the reasons that I am here.<br><br>So, I thank you again for all that you do and all that you have done.&nbsp; We remain, of course, open to and desirous of diplomacy as it relates to the dialogue and the discussions we have had with Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>But we are also committed if Russia takes aggressive action to ensuring there will be severe consequence in terms of the economic sanctions we have discussed. And we know the Alliance is strong in that regard.&nbsp;<br><br>And again, I thank you for your leadership as a partner in that effort.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really a great pleasure to meet you and to be able to sit down and to address some of the very serious and security challenges we face together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And NATO remains the cornerstone for our security &#8212; the security of Europe and for North America.&nbsp; And therefore, I&#8217;m extremely grateful for your personal commitment to our Alliance, to the transatlantic bond, and also the very strong and staunch commitment to NATO from the Biden-Harris administration not only in words, but also in deeds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We see it on the ground in Europe now.&nbsp; On Friday, I went to Romania and met U.S. troops there.&nbsp; And they always impress me with their professionalism, their dedication.&nbsp; And, of course, to have U.S. troops &#8212; more U.S. troops in Europe now, in this critical time for our security, really demonstrates the North American and the U.S. commitment to our shared security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also welcome the fact that European Allies are stepping up, also increasing their presence in the eastern part of the Alliance and also investing more in defense.</p>



<p>So, the reality is that North America and Europe are doing more together now than have done for many years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS: &nbsp;Yes.</p>



<p>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; That&#8217;s important to deal with the aggressive actions of Russia, but also to address a more competitive world, the security consequences of the rise of China.&nbsp; We have to stand together in North America and Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, yeah, thank you for your leadership, your commitment, and I look forward to our meeting.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 1:26 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Kansas Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/17/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-kansas-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 02:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Kansas and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms and straight-line winds on December 15, 2021. Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Kansas and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms and straight-line winds on December 15, 2021.<br> <br>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storms and straight-line winds in the counties of Barton, Brown, Clay, Cloud, Doniphan, Edwards, Ellis, Ellsworth, Ford, Geary, Gove, Graham, Grant, Gray, Greeley, Hamilton, Haskell, Hodgeman, Jewell, Kearny, Lane, Lincoln, Logan, Marshall, Meade, Mitchell, Morris, Morton, Nemaha, Ness, Osborne, Ottawa, Pawnee, Republic, Rice, Riley, Rooks, Rush, Russell, Saline, Scott, Sheridan, Smith, Stafford, Stanton, Stevens, Sumner, Trego, Wabaunsee, Wallace, Washington, Wichita, and Wyandotte.<br> <br>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.<br> <br>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named DuWayne Tewes as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.<br> <br>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.<br> <br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Draghi of&#160;Italy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/17/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-draghi-of-italy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 23:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy.&#160;The leaders reviewed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. They&#160;reaffirmed their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and their readiness to impose severe economic costs on Russia if it further invades Ukraine.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy.&nbsp;The leaders reviewed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. They&nbsp;reaffirmed their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and their readiness to impose severe economic costs on Russia if it further invades Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Middle East and North Africa Coordinator McGurk’s Travel to Saudi Arabia and United Arab&#160;Emirates</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/17/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-middle-east-and-north-africa-coordinator-mcgurks-travel-to-saudi-arabia-and-united-arab-emirates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 21:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47460</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Coordinator for the Middle East and North Africa Brett McGurk traveled this week to Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates to ensure the United States is doing everything possible to support the territorial defense of both countries against Iranian-enabled missile and UAV attacks. Mr. McGurk reaffirmed the President’s commitment to supporting the defense of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Coordinator for the Middle East and North Africa Brett McGurk traveled this week to Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates to ensure the United States is doing everything possible to support the territorial defense of both countries against Iranian-enabled missile and UAV attacks. Mr. McGurk reaffirmed the President’s commitment to supporting the defense of U.S. partners, reviewed ongoing efforts with our diplomatic and military teams in both capitals, and discussed the need to combine pressure on the Houthis in Yemen with a concerted UN-led effort to end the war there. In Saudi Arabia, State Department Special Envoy for Energy Affairs Amos Hochstein joined Mr. McGurk to discuss a collaborative approach to managing potential market pressures stemming from a possible Russian invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and Great Lakes&#160;Restoration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/17/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-and-great-lakes-restoration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The ShipyardsLorain, Ohio 12:15 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:  Thank you.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  They&#8217;re all for Marcy.  God love you, kiddo.  You&#8217;re the best. Before I begin, I want to just point out I was having a &#8211;just sitting and talking for a second with the Director&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The Shipyards<br>Lorain, Ohio</p>



<p>12:15 P.M. EST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Thank you.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  They&#8217;re all for Marcy.  God love you, kiddo.  You&#8217;re the best.<br><br>Before I begin, I want to just point out I was having a &#8211;just sitting and talking for a second with the Director of HUD and a former congresswoman just on the other side of this district.  And she said something that reminded me of what I miss as well.  She said, &#8220;It&#8217;s so good to be home in Ohio.&#8221;  No, I really mean it.<br><br>And I said, &#8220;You&#8217;re probably the only one here that understands that every time I get a chance, I go home to Delaware.&#8221;  (Laughter.)  You think I&#8217;m joking.  I&#8217;m not.  I represented Delaware for 36 years as a United States senator.<br><br>And just like most congressional districts, the good news is the bad news: Everybody knows you.  (Laughs.)<br><br>But it&#8217;s great to &#8212; it&#8217;s great hearing you say that.  It&#8217;s great hearing you say that.<br><br>Well, Administrator Regan &#8212; I talked him into coming out of what they consider God&#8217;s country down in the North Carolina area.  And he came up and took on this job. <br><br>And &#8212; and as I said, and a proud daughter of Ohio, Secretary of Housing and Urban Affairs Marcy &#8212; Marcia Fudge, who&#8217;s represented the district as well.<br><br>And Mitch Landrieu, who is leading the implementation of our infrastructure &#8212; where are you, Mitch?  They don&#8217;t know anybody from New Orleans down here.  He used to be the mayor of New Orleans.  And I called him &#8212; mayors know how to get things done, as the Mayor will tell you here.  And I called him, asking if will he be the hands-on guy to actually implement the law &#8212; implement it, get it done, and let people know how they can access it.<br><br>And Brenda &#8212; Brenda <s>Malloy</s> [Mallory], Chair of our Council <s>of Economic</s> [on Environmental] Quality.  Brenda, where are you?  There you are.  Thank you, Brenda.  We rode up together on the aircraft together, and it&#8217;s great to have you as well.<br><br>I also asked to say hello from someone who you know in Lorain but couldn’t be here today.  A tremendous fighter and Ohio &#8212; for Ohio workers and a guy who could easily be standing where I&#8217;m standing right now: Sherrod Brown.  (Applause.)  He &#8212;  Sherrod Brown, working in the Senate and keeping an eye on those other team &#8212; that other team to see what&#8217;s going on.<br><br>It’s good to see you, Congresswoman Shontel Brown.  Where are you, Shontel?  I said &#8212; there you go.  Right in front there.  Congratulations.  And it&#8217;s great to &#8212; great to have you here.<br><br>And, of course, Marcy &#8212; Marcy Kaptur.  Marcy has not only made history as the longest-serving woman in the history of the House of Representatives, every day she’s making a difference.  She never, ever slows up.  And she&#8217;s helping this region compete, thrive, and come back.   <br><br>You know, that’s what I want to talk a little about today &#8212; (coughs) &#8212; excuse me: the historic investment we’re making to restore the Great Lakes, strengthen the region’s economy, provide clean drinking water, clean up our communities, and create good-paying jobs. <br><br>A year ago, when I spoke at a joint session of the Congress, I was coming off the podium &#8212; the platform &#8212; and Marcy came up to me and, with all the press in the gallery looking down, handed me a note &#8212; a letter.<br><br>And the commentators and reporters were so damn curious.  &#8220;What did she hand you?  What’s in that note?”  And I said, &#8220;I can&#8217;t tell you.”  No, I &#8212;<br><br>But &#8212; well, if you know Marcy, you know what that letter was about: the Great Lakes.  The Great Lakes.<br><br>She described the treasure &#8212; the treasure the Great Lakes are.  They connect eight states, two nations.  They provide more drinking water than any set of lakes in the world, that more than 40 million people benefit from that.  They support more than 1,300,000 jobs in manufacturing, tourism, transportation, warehousing, farming, and fishing.  And they&#8217;re essential to shipping goods made in the Midwest, all across the country, and around the world.<br><br>Generations of families have depended on them being boating &#8212; on the boating and fishing and hunting and swimming that they provide for everyone in this region and those who come and visit.<br><br>They are home to countless natural and cultural wonders that &#8212; that should be conserved for all to enjoy today, tomorrow, and for generations to come.<br><br>     And Marcy &#8212; by the way, I saw her today.  She said, “I got another letter for you.”  I don’t what the hell &#8212; (laughter) &#8212;<br><br>     Marcy, I promise you, I’m working like hell.  (Laughter.)  But I’ll read it, I promise.  Whatever you say, I’ll do.<br><br>But Marcy’s letter said &#8212; and this is why I want &#8212; why I bring it up.  She said, and I quote, “[The Great Lakes] undergrid [undergird] life, work, and recreation for millions of people…”<br><br>And we need them &#8212; we need to invest in them if we want a brighter, more prosperous future for the region.<br><br>Well, they are.  They are.  And we are going to.  We’re investing like never, ever in history. <br><br>Back in 1987, an independent commission identified 43 places called “areas of concern” along the Great Lakes.  They’re areas where pollution, as &#8212; as the EPA director said, where pollution from industry, runoff from agriculture, poor wastewater treatment put the Great Lakes and everyone who depends on them at risk.<br><br>Twenty-six of these areas are in the United States side of the border.  Twelve of them are in Canada.  And five are shared between the United States and Canada.<br><br>And our mutual nations made a commitment to clean them up, to be good partners, to protect these shared treasures.<br><br>And for decades, there was a lot of talk, a lot of plans, but very little progress.  It was slow. <br><br>That changes today.<br><br>Today, we’re announcing an investment of $1 billion &#8212; $1 billion &#8212; (applause) &#8212; from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill.  It’s going to allow the most significant restoration of the Great Lakes in the history of the Great Lakes. <br><br>We’re going to accelerate cleanup of sites across six states in the Great Lakes Basin &#8212; from Duluth, Minnesota, to Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Gary, Indiana, to Buffalo, New York, and everywhere in between.<br><br>And we know these sites were dangerously polluted for decades.<br><br>We’re committed to clean them up.  Three decades ago, we made this commitment.<br><br>And, yes, we’ve gotten a couple of them done, like right here, like the &#8212; one of my old hangouts as well.  I went to Syracuse University.  I was a lifeguard on Lake Oswego.  I &#8212; and I &#8212; and I know the Oswego River up in New York.  That was another one that’s been taken care of.<br><br>Now we’re talking about cleaning up the Cuyahoga River behind the Cuyahoga Gorge Dam and in the process &#8212; and it passes through Cleveland.<br><br>The &#8212; the &#8212; I always mispronounce it &#8212; the Wa- &#8212; Wa- &#8212; <s>Mauwamee</s> [Maumee] River.  Right?<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:  Maumee.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Maumee River in Toledo.  I can say “Toledo.”  (Laughter and applause.)<br><br>Restoring the shoreline around the Detroit River in Michigan, the St. Louis River in Minnesota and Wisconsin, the Grand Calumet River in Indiana, and so much more.<br><br>Dredging polluted sediment; restoring wetlands and habitats; making the water safer for swimming and fishing and drinking; providing habitats for wildlife and wildfowl.  <br><br>And the study found that every dollar we spend<br>cleaning up the Great Lakes generates between three and four dollars in economic benefit.  That’s a fact.  And it’s a really good investment.  These are not the only investments in making &#8212; that we’re making in the Great Lakes.<br><br>Last month, we announced over $500 million to upgrade the Soo Locks in Michigan, which connect Lake Superior and the Great Lakes.<br><br>Seven thousand vessels and 90 percent of our country’s iron ore moves through these locks every single year.  That ore makes nearly all the high-strength steel that goes into U.S.-made cars and appliances.<br><br>Replacing and modernizing the locks will not only create good jobs doing that, it’s going to strengthen our supply chains and get goods moving faster and reduce cost.<br><br>This is not the totality of what we’re going to do, but it’s an example of what I’ve said from day one: We’re rebuilding America.  We’re going to invest in America and build a better America than we found.<br><br>And for the better part of the 20th century, we used to lead the world by a significant margin because we invested in ourselves.  We invested in our infrastructure, our roads, our highways, bridges, ports, airports &#8212; the arteries of the nation that allow commerce to function smoothly and move swiftly.<br><br>And we invested in our people and in opportunity.  We were among the first nation to provide universal high school at the turn of the 20th century.<br><br>We invested to win the Space Race that facilitates &#8212; that &#8212; in facilities like the Lewis Research Center in Cleveland, which is now named for my buddy John Glenn.  God rest his soul.<br><br>And we led the world in research and development that led to the creation of the Internet.<br><br>But somewhere along the way, we took our eye off the ball.  We took our eye off the ball.<br><br>Our infrastructure used to be rated number one in the world.  Today, according to the World Economic Forum, we rank number 13 in the world.  China and the rest of the world is catching up and passing us.</p>



<p>But now, with our infrastructure law, we’re reinvesting in our economy and in our &#8212; and in our people, reclaiming our leadership, and creating millions of jobs for building a better America. &nbsp;That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to do.<br><br>But as we rebuild America, we’re buying American and betting on American workers.&nbsp;<br><br>This Buy American law makes the most significant investment in roads and bridges and highways in nearly 70 years through the &#8212; through the infrastructure law, fixing as many as 1,300 bridges and nearly 5,000 miles of highway right here in Ohio that are in poor condition.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;d note, parenthetically, I was &#8212; not long ago, I went to visit a place in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, where a bridge that was well over 100 feet off the ground, going over a gorge, completely collapsed at 6:30 in the morning.&nbsp; Thank God it was only three vehicles on it and no one died.&nbsp; But had it been during rush hour, kids in school buses &#8212; there would have been numerous people that would have been killed or maimed.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>American workers building these roads and bridges with American-made steel is how we&#8217;re going to do it.&nbsp;<br><br>Jobs making high-speed Internet affordable and available to the 14 percent of households in the state of Ohio that don’t have the Internet.&nbsp;<br><br>We also know that Ohio has the second most lead pipes<br>in the country.&nbsp; You have 60- &#8212; 650,000 lead pipes here in the state of Ohio.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re going to start undoing the legacy of lead which has poisoned too many of the region’s children.&nbsp; That means replacing 100 percent of the lead water pipes and service lines and addressing what they call PFAS &#8212; a dangerous forever chemical that are a threat to the drinking water here in Ohio and other parts of America.&nbsp;<br><br>Every American and every child should be able to turn on a faucet and know that the water they&#8217;re drinking is clean and safe.&nbsp; We&#8217;re also going to create thousands of good-paying jobs in the process with union plumbers and pipefitters.<br><br>For generations, the industries that built and defined America &#8212; steel, cars, tires, paint &#8212; all of them grew and thrived right here in Ohio.&nbsp;<br><br>Right here on the backs &#8212; the banks of the Black River, workers built and launched 900 vessels.&nbsp; Freighters, tugboats, tankers, minesweepers, cruisers built right here were part of our &#8220;Arsenal of Democracy&#8221; in World War Two.<br><br>Making it in America is what this region was built on &#8212; making it in America.&nbsp; This region built America.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not just saying that because I&#8217;m here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp; The Midwest built America, and we&#8217;re building it again.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Again, I&#8217;ve &#8212; you&#8217;ve heard me say this often.&nbsp; You know, if Wall Street is a good &#8212; there are a lot of good people on Wall Street.&nbsp; They do good things &#8212; a lot of them &#8212; not all, but a lot of them.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; The fact of the matter is Wall Street didn&#8217;t build America.&nbsp; Ordinary, middle-class people built America, and manufacturing and unions built the middle class.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So, we’re bringing manufacturing jobs back, taking supply chains back home from abroad so we have better jobs and lower prices.<br><br>And now, instead of losing manufacturing jobs, since I came to office, with the help of the congressional delegation down here, we have added 375,000 manufacturing jobs in one year.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>In 2021, we saw the highest increase in un- &#8212; in un- &#8212; in <s>union</s> [U.S.] manufacturing jobs in nearly 30 years.<br><br>A couple of weeks ago, the CEO of Intel joined me and Senator Brown and Senator Portman.&nbsp;<br><br>And, by the way, I grew up in a Senate that really was bipartisan.&nbsp; Senator Portman played an important role in this legislation.<br><br>And so, at the White House, we &#8212; they came to see me and the head of the org- &#8212; the Intel came.&nbsp; They wanted to annou- &#8212; he wanted to announce at the White House &#8212; $20 million investment &#8212; $20 billion investment in a semiconductor campus outside of Columbus, Ohio.<br><br>Now, semi-conductors are badly needed &#8212; those computer chips &#8212; to manufacture automobiles, appliances, cell phones, and so much more.&nbsp; We invented them, but we don&#8217;t make them anymore and &#8212; relative to the rest of the world.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s going to create 10,000 jobs &#8212; 10,000 jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And, by the way, 7,000 jobs constructing this massive facility and 3,000 jobs running the facility, making an average salary at that facility of $135,000 a year &#8212; blue-collar workers.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Pretty good money.<br><br>Manufacturing essential products that are stamped “Made in America.”<br><br>And there’s more.&nbsp; Just a couple of weeks ago, General Motors announced a $7 billion investment in Michigan to manufacture electric vehicles, creating 4,000 new quality jobs.&nbsp; That’s on top of the announcement &#8212; did I say Ford?&nbsp; That was General Motors.&nbsp; And Ford made last year an $11 billion investment in electric vehicles, creating 11,000 new jobs.<br><br>Three weeks ago, in Western Pennsylvania, after I went to look at that bridge, the Union Pacific Railroad announced the largest purchase of American-made battery-electric locomotives in history.&nbsp; In history.<br><br>And because of the infrastructure law, it also delivers 7 billion &#8212; $7.5 billion to build a national network of 500,000<br>electric vehicle charging stations all across America and along<br>our new highways.&nbsp; And I might add, built by the I- &#8212; installed by the IBEW.<br><br>Last week, a company called Tritium announced a new manufacturing facility in Lebanon, Tennessee, to build 30,000 electric vehicle charging stations per year using American iron and American steel and American workers, creating 500 new permanent jobs in Tennessee.<br><br>We’re seeing a drumbeat of good-paying jobs unlike anything we’ve seen in our history.<br><br>But not only that.&nbsp; With these announcements, we’re also showing that growing the economy and creating jobs can go hand-in-hand with protecting the environment, not decimating it, meeting the moment on climate change, like our program to clean up abandoned mines and cap and plug orphaned oil and gas wells sweeping and spewing methane into the air.<br><br>Thousands of those wells and mines are right here in the Ohio River Valley, here in the Ohio &#8212; get &#8212; and they&#8217;re going to get paid the same amount capping them as it would cost to dig them and create those.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re, again, good union jobs.<br><br>And as good as these jobs are, folks digging those wells are proud what they&#8217;re about to do, because now they&#8217;re going to cap them.&nbsp;<br><br>The Infrastructure Law also helps us invest in a cleaner, stronger, more resilient electric grid, with 100 percent clean electric energy being generated by the year 2035.<br><br>And some of those utility poles and transformers are going to be installed by machines that are right here at a place like Skylift.<br><br>You know, all of this is doing &#8212; going to do is create more good-paying jobs and make more &#8212; make us more globally competitive and help us fight climate change and get to net zero, to get to &#8212;<br><br>Look, there&#8217;s so much more to say.&nbsp; I&#8217;m inclined to go on, but I&#8217;ve kept you too long.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me close with this: If you’ve done &#8212; what you’ve done here in Lorain shows what’s possible.&nbsp; You’ve reclaimed your waterfront; cleaned your drinking water; restored wetlands, which will help protect against storms and flooding from extreme weather and the spring thaw; and set the stage for jobs and businesses of the future.<br><br>You know, tomorrow would’ve been the birthday of Lorain &#8212; one of Lorain’s most famous daughters: Toni Morrison &#8212; Nobel Prize winner, Pulitzer Prize winner.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, I might add, my wife was an English teacher and professor in college.&nbsp; The First Lady’s absolute &#8212; one of her favorite authors.<br><br>I remember her going over to Princeton to interview Toni Morrison for a &#8212; a paper she was doing for one of her doctorates &#8212; her doctorate.&nbsp; Not one &#8212; she has a couple: a masters and one doctorate.&nbsp;<br><br>Toni Morrison was also the mother-in-law of the chair of my economic &#8212; Council of my Economic Advisers &#8212; Council of Economic Advisers, Dr. Cecilia Rouse.<br><br>Toni passed away a couple of years ago.&nbsp; The reason I mention her is not because of her relationships to the administration, but her words that she told us to live by.<br><br>She once wrote, quote, “We got more yesterday[s] than anybody.&nbsp; We need some kind of tomorrow.”&nbsp; “We need some kind of tomorrow.”<br><br>Places like Lorain have a lot of proud yesterdays.&nbsp; Now you’re going to have some brighter tomorrows and because of all of you.<br><br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; May God protect our troops.&nbsp; And the reason they tell me I&#8217;ve got to head out &#8212; I hadn’t planned on going immediately &#8212; is because the weather going back to Washington.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a little thing going on in Europe right now.&nbsp;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so &#8212; so may God bless you all, as I said.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>12:35 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and Environmental Protection Agency Administrator Michael&#160;Regan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/17/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-environmental-protection-agency-administrator-michael-regan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 19:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Cleveland, Ohio 10:09 A.M. EST&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; So, hi, everyone.&#160; It’s great to be joined by EPA Administrator Michael Regan on our trip to Lorain, Ohio.&#160;Building a better America requires us to confront legacy pollution and clean up the environment, ensuring our kids drink clean water and creating good-paying union&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Cleveland, Ohio</p>



<p>10:09 A.M. EST<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, hi, everyone.&nbsp; It’s great to be joined by EPA Administrator Michael Regan on our trip to Lorain, Ohio.<br>&nbsp;<br>Building a better America requires us to confront legacy pollution and clean up the environment, ensuring our kids drink clean water and creating good-paying union jobs in the process.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, today, President Biden will announce $1 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to accelerate cleanup and restoration of the Great Lakes’ most environmentally degraded sites.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks to these investments, we are tackling climate change, strengthening our nation’s resilience to extreme weather, and providing clean drinking water, all while creating good-paying union jobs.<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I will turn it over to Administrator Regan who will give out &#8212; give a topper for you guys and then take maybe two or three questions, and then head back.<br>&nbsp;<br>Administrator?<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Listen, it&#8217;s an honor to join President Biden for this $1 billion investment in the restoration of Great Lakes.&nbsp; This is good all around.&nbsp; You know, the Great Lakes support drinking water for about 40 million residents.&nbsp; And also, this billion dollars will support about 1.3 million jobs while also protecting ecosystems so we can have a balanced ecosystem.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re really excited about that.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is a shot in the arm.&nbsp; Of the 25 sites along the Great Lakes that are listed as areas of concern, we believe that this billion-dollar investment will allow for us to clean up 23 of those 25 by the year 2030, so &#8212; 22 of 25 by 2030.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re really excited about expediting some of these projects, expediting the cleanup, continuing to provide safe drinking water, but also looking at infrastructure investments and work that will create a more resilient Great Lakes from climate change, as well as from pollution like PFAS and some of the legacy pollutions that we&#8217;ve seen in the Great Lakes.&nbsp; So, exciting day for the folks in Ohio as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Administrator, I have a climate change question for you.&nbsp; What timeline do you see the remaining U.S. coal plants getting shut down?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And if the Supreme Court limits the EPA&#8217;s ability to regulate greenhouse gas emissions, how much of a blow will that be to the President&#8217;s climate agenda, and how will you decarbonize the power sector?<br>&nbsp;<br>ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;re paying close attention to this Supreme Court case.&nbsp; Obviously, that case is focused on the specific regulation of greenhouse gases and whether we can regulate outside the fence line.&nbsp; But nevertheless, you know, EPA has bread-and-butter regulations that also focus on the power sector as well.&nbsp; We focus on regional haze, regulating mercury, coal ash contamination.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we are aligning all of our regulations so that we can basically present a suite of regulations to the industry at one time so that they can understand all of the investments that they will need to protect public health and the environment.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ll have to determine whether or not those investments warrant the longevity of these coal plants.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, when you look at the bread-and-butter regulations that are true to the Clean Air Act, which we&#8217;re obligated to execute on, plus what the Supreme Court is going to do, we see a future of tremendous economic pressure on this industry.&nbsp; And I think the industry will have to determine how they close and when they close.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, regardless of where the Supreme Court goes, you think that the economic pressure will be enough?<br>&nbsp;<br>ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; I think that there are a lot of public health regulations that span air quality, water quality, and land management that these utilities have to take into consideration to determine, again, what investments will they have to make today to comply with those laws and what the longevity of these various coal plants are across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It will vary from state to state, plant to plant, but at least we are in a position where we want to begin rolling out these regulations so that there&#8217;s no surprise.&nbsp; We want certainty.&nbsp; We want the industry to have certainty.&nbsp; But we also want the environmental community and our folks that are looking at public health to understand that EPA is going to do its job.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to do our job.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to follow our statutory authority, our regulatory authority.&nbsp; And we hope many of the aspects that the President is advocating for in Build Back Better will help complement this glide path.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Administrator, how much of today&#8217;s announcement is due to the fact that the President&#8217;s Build Back Better plan has stalled on Capitol Hill?&nbsp; There isn&#8217;t much sign of progress up there.&nbsp; How much of today&#8217;s announcement is due to that and the fact that that plan, which has a lot of climate and environmental provisions that a lot of supporters were hoping would pass, has stalled out right now and that fate is uncertain?<br>&nbsp;<br>ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; Which announcement are you referring to?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today.&nbsp; The Great Lakes and promoting what the infrastructure bill does for the environment.<br>&nbsp;<br>ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; Oh, I think that this announcement is a wonderful opportunity to highlight why the President led this effort for the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; I mean, this at heart is an infrastructure action.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the infrastructure bill.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, again, $1 billion investing in shoring up the drinking water for over 40 million people; all of the projects that go into ecosystem protection &#8212; dredging, pollution contamina- &#8212; pollution containment &#8212; this is an opportunity to highlight that the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law really does focus on infrastructure, people, jobs, and the environment.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>None of this is &#8212; you know, you don&#8217;t have to choose between a healthy environment and economic prosperity.&nbsp; And the President is demonstrating that they actually go hand-in-hand.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Administrator.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Can we ask you some Russia questions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, no, absolutely.&nbsp; Are you guys done?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, give me one second, guys.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, Karine, if you could just speak up; it was hard to hear your opening.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I’m sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard. &nbsp;Yeah. &nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m trying to be safe here, so I apologize.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Zeke.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; First, does the White House have any response to Moscow expelling the deputy chief of mission?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, so Russia&#8217;s actions against our deputy chief of mission, who was a key member of the embassy&#8217;s leadership team, was unprovoked.&nbsp; Now more than ever, it is critical that our countries have the necessary diplomatic personnel in place to facilitate communication between our governments.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The State Department has said they consider this as an escalatory step.&nbsp; And I would refer you &#8212; I would refer you to them for further comment on this.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On that subject, the President said that he believes there’s a &#8220;high&#8221; risk now of a &#8212; of a further Russian invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; Does the President plan to adjust his travel schedule or his meetings in the next couple of days to monitor the situation?&nbsp; Was there any discussion of canceling this trip so that he could monitor the situation in Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; any updates on any travel for this President.&nbsp; As you know, the &#8212; a President deals with multiple things at one time.&nbsp; And so, what &#8212; but as the President said, this is a &#8220;very high&#8221; risk &#8212; the question that he was asked on his way to Air Force One.<br>&nbsp;<br>But as we have said, we are in the window where we believe an attack could come at any time and that it would be preceded by a fabricated pretext that the Russians use as an excuse to launch an invasion, which could take many forms.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we believe it&#8217;s important that the world be watching for that pretext and that people treat any such claims with the appropriate skepticism, especially when they come from Russian state media sources and aren&#8217;t backed up by the independent media reporter &#8212; reporting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Russia relies on confusion and obfuscation to cover its attacks.&nbsp; We would all expect &#8212; expect it and be ready for it.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s just from the (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just pick up on the pretext, Karine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would one of those pretexts be where Moscow might be planning to stage an incident in the rebel-held areas to justify an attack on Ukraine from the east?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, just &#8212; let me just give you some examples.&nbsp; So that false pretext could take a number of different forms: a provocation in Donbas; a claim about NATO activity by land, at sea, or in the air; an incursion into Russian territory.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so we are &#8212; already have seen an increase in false claims by the Russians in the past few days, including reports of an unmarked grave of civilians &#8212; of civilians allegedly killed by the Ukrainian armed forces; statements Ukraine is committing genocide in eastern Ukraine; that the U.S. and the Ukraine are developing biological or chemical weapons; and what the West &#8212; that the West is funneling in guerrillas to kill locals.&nbsp; Each of these allegation is categorically false.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve been very clear about this, and we should expect more false, again, reports from Russian state media over the coming days.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen this playbook before from Russia: their previous military incursions into Ukraine and in Georgia.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, again, this is &#8212; this is something that we are anticipating and that the President has talked about to expect a potential pretext.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can the White &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President planning to do anything to change Putin’s mind?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me &#8212; I just want to &#8212; I also want to lay out some stuff that we’re doing today.&nbsp; So you guys &#8212; I think you guys saw the reporting that Secretary Blinken will speak directly to the U.N. Council this morning on his way to Munich about the gravity of the situation in Ukraine, and signal our intense commitment to diplomacy, to offer and emphasize the path toward de-escalation, and to make it clear to the world that we are doing everything we can to prevent war.<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; but the evidence on the ground is that Russia is moving toward an imminent invasion.&nbsp; This week, the Russian government said that it would withdraw troops from the broder [sic] &#8212; from the Ukraine border.&nbsp; And they received a lot of attention for that claim but &#8212; here and around the world.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we know that is absolutely false, which you&#8217;ve heard us say from &#8212; coming from our administration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, we have now confirmed that, in the last several days, Russia has increased its troops presence along that Ukraine border by as many as 7,000 troops, with some arriving in the past 24 hours.&nbsp; This is cause of serious concerns.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So the Russians have also said in recent days that they are prepared to engage in diplomacy as we and our allies have repeatedly offered.&nbsp; But every indication we now know is they mean only to engage in Potemkin diplomacy where they publicly offer to talk and make claims about de-escalation while privately mobilizing for war.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we continue to receive indications that they could launch a false pretext, as I just mentioned, and so we just want to make sure that the world is aware and knows that this is a possibility, because it is indeed part of the Russian playbook.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ukraine says that pro- &#8212; Ukraine says that pro-Russian forces &#8212; excuse us.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>(Gaggle interrupted.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ukraine says that pro-Russian forces have &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, the door is broken, guys.&nbsp; Hold on one second.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ah.&nbsp; Please hold.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; A broken door.&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Try &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let’s try this again.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Trying again.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Ukraine says that pro-Russian forces have shelled a kindergarten.&nbsp; Can the White House confirm that that is the case?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that one more time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That pro-Russian forces have shelled a kindergarten in Ukraine &#8212; i.e. attacked a kindergarten.&nbsp; Is that intelligence that the White House can confirm?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I cannot confirm that from here.&nbsp; That is something that the Department of Defense can &#8212; we should &#8212; I refer you to them.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have that intel or information, and so I don&#8217;t have anything here to share on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And in terms of the false-flag warnings that you said, do you have any sense of &#8212; I mean, the President said the invasion could happen at any time.&nbsp; Do you have any sense of timing for these false-flag operations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we have said that we are within the window of an invasion happening, which could be led by a pretext.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have an exact timing for you, but we had said it could happen before the &#8212; during the Olympics or after.&nbsp; And so we are in that window, which is why you heard from the President directly, saying that it is a very high possibility.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just last on this topic for me.&nbsp; What else is the White House doing or planning to do to prepare Americans for the possibility of a war in Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, one of the reasons that the President spoke the other day is to speak directly to the American public and to the world about what to expect and what process and &#8212; what process we were taking in this crisis that Russia, remember, has created.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, he wanted to be direct.&nbsp; He wanted to lay down what we&#8217;ve been doing for the last several months, the last several weeks for the American public, and talked about the impact of this potential &#8212; if Russia decides to invade, how this would impact the American public.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s one way that the President is communicating with the American public.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we have been very, very clear, the President has been very clear for the last several months, the last several weeks, and being &#8212; and being transparent about how we&#8217;re moving forward with our European allies and partners in this moment, and what we&#8217;re trying to do to deter and how we&#8217;re trying to go to the direction of diplomacy.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so that is &#8212; that is the direction that we&#8217;re still working on, hence why Secretary Blinken is up in New York today and will continue to have those conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, are there any plans for the President to pick up the phone and call Vladimir Putin?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think he answered that himself not too &#8212; moments ago.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to read out.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more to add to what the President said.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on a quick, separate issue: Does the President have confidence that the Senate will be able to avert a government shutdown?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; As you know, we work closely with the Senate and with Congress in general, and that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s our &#8212; that&#8217;s our path: is to avert a government shutdown.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s our what?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That&#8217;s our path: to avert a government shutdown.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he received assurances from congressional (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more to say except that that is something, clearly, that is a priority for us to make sure that there is not a government shutdown, and we are in constant communication with members on the Hill.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, has President Biden been able to review the written response from Russia?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s his reaction to that so far?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; This is the &#8212; the written &#8212; the response?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I can confirm we just received a response from the Russian Federation, and we will refer you to State.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything yet specific to share.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say &#8212; has he been able to see it this morning before coming on this trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I cannot confirm.&nbsp; I think he did answer this question on his way here, but I don&#8217;t have anything more to share.&nbsp; I would refer you to State on any specifics.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, Taiwan&#8217;s ambassador to the U.S. has said that they want to be part of this Indo-Pacific new economic framework that you guys are about to launch, but instead they have applied for the CPTPP instead.&nbsp; Do you have any comment on this and on the broader fact that, you know, allies and partners in the region are, frankly, unhappy that the Indo-Pacific economic framework does not include opening up American markets, which is the thing that they most want in order to become closer to the U.S. rather than China?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, that work is well underway as we consult with the Indo-Pacific partners, Congress, and other stakeholders.&nbsp; We’ll have more to share as the process is ongoing.&nbsp; As I just started saying, it&#8217;s underway.<br>&nbsp;<br>This framework would define our shared objectives around trade facilitation, standards for a digital economy and technology, supply chain resiliency, decarbonization and clean energy, infrastructure, worker standards, and other areas of share interest.<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t have more information to share at this time, but we are committed to strengthening trade and investment in the region in a manner that promotes good-paying American jobs, high standards, and supply chain resiliency, and offer the same benefits for our Indo-Pacific partners.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the other thing that you&#8217;ve been promising to launch early this year is the Build Back Better World plan, which was supposed to be early this year.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s still another one of those things that you&#8217;ve been promising since June.&nbsp; And so, what&#8217;s the holdup?&nbsp; We know that Daleep Singh has made these listening tours to Latin America, to Africa.&nbsp; Is it that you&#8217;re not finding enough pilot projects, or is it COVID? Or what&#8217;s the holdup?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, the President is very committed to his Build &#8212; the Build Back Better World plan.&nbsp; So, at the United State- &#8212; as the United States and our partners further develop and implement the Build Back Better World initiative, we recognize that robust, meaningful partnership will be critical to ensure that Build Back Better World delivers infrastructure that meets the needs of middle- and lower-income countries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s what our team has been doing: traveling to South &#8212; South America, as you just mentioned, Africa, and the Middle East.&nbsp; We will have more details to come in the coming months on how to continue to implement this initiative and the projects the U.S. government is investing with allies and partners.&nbsp; And like I said, this is something that the President is committed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you’re confirming that the launch is going to be delayed?&nbsp; Just confirming that the launch of BW- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We’ll just &#8212; we’ll have more to share in the next several months.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re &#8212; continue to work with &#8212; yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, has the President interviewed any potential Supreme Court nominees?&nbsp; And where is he right now in this process of evaluating potential picks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, the President has had &#8212; he&#8217;s had a series of discussions with lawmakers from both sides of the aisle.&nbsp; You know, he continues to review materials as he considers deeply qualified candidates, as you’ve heard us say &#8212; immensely qualified candidate with strong experience, character, integrity, dedication to the Constitution and the rule of law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Potentially, you know, he could begin talking to &#8212; interviewing nominees as soon as this week, but I don&#8217;t have any specifics to share.&nbsp; The thing that I can confirm is that &#8212; and as you&#8217;ve heard me say before and as you’ve heard Jen say before &#8212; is that we are going &#8212; he is going to have a selection by the end of this month.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, I couldn’t hear.&nbsp; You said “he could begin” &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So he could begin interviewing potential nominees as soon as this week, but I do not have any &#8212; anything to provide.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today is Thursday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Good &#8212; good point.&nbsp; Good point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does that mean that he has not &#8212; does that mean that he has not done an interview yet?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I just don&#8217;t have anything to confirm for you right now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Monday, you were able to tell us that he hadn&#8217;t interviewed anyone then.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Because you had asked over the weekend and what he was doing that weekend.&nbsp; And I was able to &#8212; I &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, he’s just not been working for four days?&nbsp; Like, what&#8217;s going on? &nbsp;(Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to share or to confirm or not confirm on this.&nbsp; This is something &#8212; again, he&#8217;s reviewing materials &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Don’t the American people deserve to know what the President is doing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; I think the President &#8212; they’ll know when he makes his selection and how he came to that process once he has selected that person.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, this is something that the President knows how this goes, as being the Chair of the Judiciary Committee for many years, having to &#8212; having oversaw &#8212; overseen many Supreme Court nomination hearings.&nbsp; He knows how this process works &#8212; being the Vice President. &nbsp;So this is nothing new to him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But he wants to make sure &#8212; again, this is a rigorous process.&nbsp; He wants to make sure that this important life- &#8212; lifetime commitment is done in a way that&#8217;s, again, rigorous and has &#8212; and lands with the most qualified &#8212; he picks the most qualified person to have (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jenny &#8212; Jenny hasn’t had a chance yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jenny.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On &#8212; back on the Russia issue and the sanctions package and the Congress that&#8217;s broken down, you could say, on the bipartisan measures.&nbsp; Right now, it seems like they&#8217;re just headed towards a resolution to support Ukraine.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; do you think that&#8217;s sufficient, or would you want to see a bipartisan sanctions package to show resolve?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, it&#8217;s important to show a united front to Russia.&nbsp; We appreciate the bipartisanship support for actions we&#8217;ve taken and will take if Russia further invades Ukraine.&nbsp; So that is important to show that force of bipartisanship.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, we continue to believe that a bipartisan bill will send the strongest message to Putin and serve as a united show of force.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s &#8212; you know, that&#8217;s &#8212; we think it&#8217;s important that they&#8217;re doing that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it doesn’t seem like they&#8217;re headed that way.&nbsp; I mean, the Republicans basically pulled out of negotiations, and now it just seems like a non-binding resolution.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, we&#8217;ll leave that process to Congress.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re saying is: We appreciate the bipartisan support that we have seen from Congress in the past several weeks for the actions and what we&#8217;re trying to do, clearly in partnership, in lockstep &#8212; partnership with European allies and partners.&nbsp; And so, we think that&#8217;s important, showing that force.&nbsp; But anything with Congress, I will leave it to them to talk about and see (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more on another issue in Congress that is important to you and has sort of broken down: on the competition China bill.&nbsp; That also seems to have stalled. &nbsp;There&#8217;s not really any sign that they&#8217;re moving to conference or that, you know, either &#8212; both chambers are in at the same time.&nbsp; So the timing and the substance seem to be a problem here.&nbsp; Can you lay out a little bit how you&#8217;re trying to get this over the finish line?&nbsp; Of course, this won&#8217;t be doable before the State of the Union.&nbsp; How important is it for the President what you&#8217;re doing there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, it&#8217;s important.&nbsp; And, you know, we are in constant communication with Congress on a whole &#8212; whole list of issues.&nbsp; And that, clearly, is one that&#8217;s critical and important.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll just continue to have those conversations with Congress.&nbsp; It is important to us to make &#8212; to move forward with that.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to continue to make sure that we&#8217;re talking to Congress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any sense of timing on when this would &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a sense of timing on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one follow-up on the deputy ambassador who was pushed out of Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Expelled.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Will there be any retaliation from the U.S. side for that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything. &nbsp;Literally, that just happened, so I don&#8217;t have anything to share on what happens next.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to pick up on the State of the Union &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just to put a fine point on Zeke&#8217;s question about today&#8217;s trip, you know, a senior State Department official said this morning that this &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; On whose trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I said: Just to put a fine point on Zeke’s question about this trip today &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; a senior State Department official this morning said that this is “perhaps the most perilous moment for peace and security since the end of the Cold War.”&nbsp; So can &#8212; you know, is there concern that this trip could distract the President from thinking about Ukraine and Russia?&nbsp; Is there a member of his national security team traveling today who&#8217;s going to keep him updated?&nbsp; Like, how are you managing to juggle, you know, both of these things?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I go back to what I said before: Every President, whether it&#8217;s a Democrat President &#8212; a Democratic President or a Republican, has dealt with multiple crises at once.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what this President is doing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He was Vice President before.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been in the Senate.&nbsp; He knows how to deal with diff- &#8212; you know, multiple &#8212; again, multiple crises at the same time.&nbsp; We have an NSC person that travels with him at all trips, and he will be kept updated.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is not going to deter him from what he needs to do for the American public.&nbsp; This is just part of the job.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, the President has been very clear.&nbsp; He has spoken about how we are moving with our &#8212; again, with our European allies and partners forward with dealing with the crisis that Russia has created on the Ukraine border.&nbsp; And that has not changed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He &#8212; as you know, we&#8217;ve read out multiple conversations that he&#8217;s had with leaders.&nbsp; He spoke to the Germany Chancellor yesterday to get an update from him.&nbsp; He spoke to Putin just on Saturday.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s continuing to have conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our &#8212; his NSC staff, and Secretary Blinken, the Department of Defense &#8212; Secretary Austin &#8212; are all talking to their counterparts practically every day.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; he&#8217;s going to keep &#8212; he&#8217;s going to be able to keep up to date on what&#8217;s happening.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who has the President called today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who &#8212; is the President calling anyone today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a call to read out today.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a call to (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more follow-up.&nbsp; Does this &#8212; given what the President just said, that it seems like it&#8217;s headed towards a potential invasion in the coming days, does this make him change his weekend plans at all?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new on his &#8212; on his weekend pro- &#8212; plans or change in plans.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to pick up on the State of the Union, does the President expect to deliver his speech in a chamber where people don&#8217;t have to wear masks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, I &#8212; look, we&#8217;re going to follow the guidance &#8212; the CDC guidance.&nbsp; And clearly, we&#8217;ll be in touch with &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But where is he right now in terms of lifting up federal &#8212; you know, CDC guidance in terms of masks and other health protocols?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Just in general?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we follow &#8212; I mean, we&#8217;ve been pretty clear about this: We follow the CDC guidance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we follow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; And Jeff Zients is saying that they&#8217;re going to change it sometimes, maybe this week or next.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right, well, they&#8217;re looking at all of the guidance; that&#8217;s what Dr. Walensky said yesterday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; No, what I mean is: The last time the President spoke, he said that, you know, he &#8212; he feels like it&#8217;s too early, too premature.&nbsp; Is that changing at all?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, what he said was: We have to look at the science and we got to look at what &#8212; and listen to the experts.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing by allowing CDC to go through their process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As to what comes next, I don&#8217;t have anything to do.&nbsp; They&#8217;re an independent body.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to make that decision.&nbsp; And Dr. Walensky spoke to that specifically yesterday, and I&#8217;ll leave that to what she said.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one last thing from me.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President still expecting to host in person the U.S.-ASEAN Summit in Washington?<br>&nbsp;<br>(The plane experiences turbulence.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, my gosh.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s also supposed to happen early this year.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Give me one second as I try to hold on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; President Biden looks for &#8212; looks forward &#8212; looks forward to welcoming ASEAN leaders to Washington, D.C., for a U.S.-ASEAN special summit in the coming months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t have more details to share at this time, but we&#8217;ll keep you all posted.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are committed to strengthening our partnership with ASEAN as well as its &#8212; as to its cert- &#8212; centrala- &#8211;centrality.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been working to deepen our cooperation in the region and promote a free and open Indo-Pacific.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, will he address the Ukraine situation at all at the top of his speech today in Ohio, or is just going to be Great Lakes?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, the focus here is the billion-dollar initiative that we &#8212; that you just heard from the EPA Administrator focusing on the Great Lakes and what we&#8217;re doing, how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is delivering in that component of what &#8212; what we talk about, and making sure that the climate change &#8212; and we&#8217;re doing what we can to clean &#8212; to clean the Great Lakes.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s going to be the focus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;s going to talk about that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be there with the local representative who&#8217;s going to meet us on the ground.&nbsp; As you know, the EP- &#8212; the EPA Administrator is there &#8212; is here joining us for this trip, and that&#8217;s going to be the focus of today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, does he plan on meeting with the congressional delegation, the local &#8212; Tim Ryan who is running for Senate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, today &#8212; we&#8217;ll &#8212; I don&#8217;t think any &#8212; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t think we have anybody else besides the re- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kaptur?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s anybody else that&#8217;s going to be on the ground.&nbsp; I think the two senators had other &#8212; have other things.&nbsp; Like, I think they had some votes that they needed to get to or deal with.&nbsp; So, we don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; anything more to share on their involvement for today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you say &#8212; the Ohio governor is not here, correct?&nbsp; Not going to meet him &#8212; meet with him today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No. No.&nbsp; Though I &#8212; we&#8217;ll have a list of who is going &#8212; who is going to be on the ground with us.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was the Ohio governor invited?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; You know, we &#8212; we &#8212; you know, when we visit a state, we always reach out to the governor and to the local electeds in that state, include &#8212; including congressional members that represent that district.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re in constant communication with folks when we come into the state.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything else on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have &#8212; do you have one more comment on Iran?&nbsp; It&#8217;s going &#8212; moving into, like, the final phases.&nbsp; Do you have anything to comment on the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, I do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the latest &#8212; on negotiations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have the latest on negotiations, but I &#8212; you know, I do have what we have been &#8212; what we have said with talks before, which is that Iran &#8212; with Iran, you know, it reached an urgent point on mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We won&#8217;t negotiate in public, as we have said before, but we can say a deal that addresses the core concerns of all sides is in sight.&nbsp; If it&#8217;s not reached in the coming weeks, however, Iran&#8217;s ongoing nuclear advances will make it impossible for us to return to the JCPOA.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here&#8217;s the bottom line here: We&#8217;re confronting a very dangerous situation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Under the JCPOA, Iran&#8217;s nuclear program was slightly constrained and monitored by international inspectors.&nbsp;&nbsp;Since the previous administration ceased U.S. participation in the deal, Iran has rapidly accelerated its nuclear program and reduced cooperation with international inspectors in nonperformance of JCPO- &#8212; commitments.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Thanks, Karine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>10:39 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Marine One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/17/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 15:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 9:17 A.M. EDT    Q    Mr. President, how high is the threat of a Russian invasion right now?  THE PRESIDENT:  It&#8217;s very high. Q    Why? THE PRESIDENT:  It’s very &#8212; because they have not &#8212; they have not moved any of their troops out.  They’ve moved more troops in, number one.  Number two, we have reason to believe&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>9:17 A.M. EDT   <br> <br>Q    Mr. President, how high is the threat of a Russian invasion right now? <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  It&#8217;s very high.<br> <br>Q    Why?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  It’s very &#8212; because they have not &#8212; they have not moved any of their troops out.  They’ve moved more troops in, number one.  Number two, we have reason to believe that they are engaged in a false-flag operation to have an excuse to go in.  Every indication we have is they&#8217;re prepared to go into Ukraine, attack Ukraine &#8212; number one. <br> <br>Number two, I&#8217;ve been waiting for a response from Putin for my letter that &#8212; my response to him.  It’s come to that Moscow embassy.  They&#8217;re faxing it here.  Not faxing it, they&#8217;re sending it here.  I have not read it yet.  I cannot comment on it.<br> <br>Q    Have you been briefed on it in any way?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  No- &#8212;<br> <br>Q    Do you think he&#8217;s going to go through with this, sir?  Is your sense that this is going to happen now?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Yes.  Not &#8212;<br> <br>Q    When?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I &#8212; my sense is this will happen within the next several days. <br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>Q    How many days are we talking?<br> <br>Q    Is there any diplomatic path still available, Mr. President? <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Yes, there is.  There&#8217;s a clear diplomatic path.  That&#8217;s why I asked Senator &#8212; Senator &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; Secretary Blinken to go to the United Nations and make his statement today.  He&#8217;ll lay out what that path is.  I&#8217;ve laid out a path to Putin as well on, I think, Sunday.  And so, there is a path.  There is a way through this, but by diplomacy.<br> <br>Q    Will you speak to Putin again? <br> <br>Q    Are you going to call Putin?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m not calling Putin.  I have no plans to call Putin right now.  Thank you.<br> <br>9:18 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call Previewing the Vice President&#8217;s Trip to Munich,&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/16/background-press-call-previewing-the-vice-presidents-trip-to-munich-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 02:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  6:18 P.M. EST &#160;MODERATOR:&#160; Hey, thanks.&#160; And thank you, everyone, for joining us today.&#160; As mentioned, today&#8217;s call is to preview the Vice President&#8217;s trip to Munich.&#160; This call will be on background, attributed to &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;&#160; And the contents are embargoed until the end of the call.&#160; And by joining the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Via Teleconference</em><strong> </strong></p>



<p>6:18 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hey, thanks.&nbsp; And thank you, everyone, for joining us today.&nbsp; As mentioned, today&#8217;s call is to preview the Vice President&#8217;s trip to Munich.&nbsp; This call will be on background, attributed to &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;&nbsp; And the contents are embargoed until the end of the call.&nbsp; And by joining the call you are agreeing to those ground rules.<br><br>For your awareness, our speakers today are [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].&nbsp;Hereinafter&nbsp;they&#8217;ll&nbsp;be&nbsp;referred to as &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;<br><br>But before we get to the Vice President&#8217;s program in Munich, I wanted to turn over to another speaker, [senior administration official], who will offer some brief opening remarks.&nbsp;<br><br>So, over to you, [senior administration official].<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I just wanted to give everybody an update on the latest situation in Russia and Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>So, yesterday, the Russian government said it was withdrawing troops from the border with Ukraine.&nbsp; They received a lot of attention for that claim both here and around the world, but we now know it was false.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, we have now confirmed that in the last several days, Russia has increased its troop presence along the Ukrainian border by as many as 7,000 troops, with some arriving as recently as today.&nbsp;<br><br>The Russians have also said in recent days that they are prepared to engage in diplomacy as we and our Allies have repeatedly offered.&nbsp; But every indication we have now is they mean only to publicly offer to talk and make claims about de-escalation while privately mobilizing for war.&nbsp;<br><br>We continue to receive indications that they could launch a false pretext at any moment to justify an invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; That false pretext could take a number of different forms: a provocation in the Donbas; a claim about NATO activity by land, at sea, or in the air; an incursion into Russian territory.&nbsp;<br><br>We have already seen an increase in false claims by the Russians in the past few days, including reports of an unmarked grave of civilians allegedly killed by the Ukrainian armed forces, statements that the U.S. and Ukraine are developing biological or chemical weapons, and that the West is funneling in guerrillas to kill locals.&nbsp; Each of these allegations is categorically false, and we should expect more false reports from Russian state media over the coming days.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen this playbook before: their previous military incursions into Ukraine and in Georgia.&nbsp;<br><br>We don&#8217;t know what form the false pretext will take, but we hope the world is ready.&nbsp; Just as Russia&#8217;s claims about withdrawing troops were false, so will be whatever false pretext they invent to justify this war of choice.&nbsp; No one should take these claims at face value.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Nevertheless, we will continue to pursue diplomacy over the coming days while being prepared to respond swiftly and decisively if Russia chooses to launch a new attack on Ukraine.<br><br>Russia keeps saying it wants to pursue a diplomatic solution; their actions indicate otherwise.&nbsp; We hope they will change course before starting a war that will bring catastrophic death and destruction.&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks.&nbsp; And I will now turn it over to the other senior administration officials.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; And just before we get there &#8212; just to confirm, all the speakers that are speaking today are on background to be referred to as &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;&nbsp; So, all the remarks here are as &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>With that, thank you to our first speaker.&nbsp; We’ll now turn it over to preview the Vice President&#8217;s trip to Munich.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a pleasure to have this opportunity to talk with everybody.&nbsp; As you all have just heard, we are in a very decisive moment.&nbsp; And the Vice President is leading the U.S. delegation to the Munich Security Conference this year as a resounding signal that engagement with our Allies and partners is an absolutely critical part of our overall diplomacy and our approach to this situation.&nbsp;<br><br>Throughout the course of her trip, you can expect that she will be discussing the full range of issues:&nbsp;<br><br>First, the unity that we have achieved with our European allies and that we are determined to maintain.&nbsp;<br><br>Second, the economic measures that we have prepared and may need to deploy depending on how things play out.&nbsp;<br><br>Third, U.S. and NATO force posture.<br><br>Fourth, support for Ukraine.<br><br>And five, the diplomatic path to de-escalation that we have offered, that we hope the Russians will take us up on.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll just have to wait and see.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, as you know, we have already undertaken very intensive engagements with our Allies and partners over the course of the last several months, and the Vice President&#8217;s trip will be a high-level continuation of those efforts.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>At Munich, there will be several dozen world leaders present, and all of them are going to be focused on this very pressing challenge that is at the top of mind for us.&nbsp; So, we expect that the conference, but particularly the Vice President&#8217;s schedule, is going to be very intense and it will include a series of high-stakes, high-level diplomatic talks.<br><br>She will be engaging with a number of leaders, and I&#8217;m going to mention just a few.&nbsp;<br><br>On Friday, she is going to meet with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg.&nbsp; She will also have a multilateral meeting with the leaders of the three Baltic states: Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia.&nbsp;<br><br>In both of these meetings, she will discuss the latest developments related to Russia&#8217;s build-up on Ukraine&#8217;s border, our work together on deterrence and diplomacy, our force posture and our readiness to further reinforce NATO Allies on the eastern flank.&nbsp; And, of course, she will, as she always does, reaffirm our sacred commitment to NATO&#8217;s Article 5 commitment.<br><br>In addition to those international meetings, the Vice President will also hold a separate engagement with the congressional members who are attending the Munich Security Conference.&nbsp; There will be a very large contingent of congressional members &#8212; two large bipartisan, bicameral codels are attending.&nbsp; And their intention is to use their participation to demonstrate the commitment of the United States to our Allies and our partners, and to show that it is both bipartisan and very, very strongly held.<br><br>So, with that, let me turn it over to my colleague, who will take us&nbsp;through Saturday&nbsp;and address a couple of other issues.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; I’ll walk you through the second day, Saturday, of what is really a busy weekend of activities.&nbsp; And the main event on Saturday will be the Vice President’s speech as a formal part of the Munich Security Conference.&nbsp; And in this speech, as throughout her public engagements over the weekend, she will be addressing the situation on Ukraine’s border and the threat of Russian aggression and the latest state of play in what obviously has been &#8212; remains a fluid situation.</p>



<p>I won’t get into hugely specific details about her speech, but I can give you some of the themes I think you can expect her to address.&nbsp; And one would be stock-taking of the really remarkable unity that we’ve achieved across the transatlantic community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reality is we think that the West is more united and NATO is stronger than they have been in decades.&nbsp; And that applies to our diplomacy, where we have together put forward our diplomatic approach to Russia; militarily, where we&#8217;ve coordinated extremely closely on force posture adjustments that we&#8217;ve been making together with our NATO Allies; and then on the economic side as well, including the severe sanctions that we intend to impose on Russia if it further invades Ukraine.</p>



<p>The Vice President will underscore how that unity is a source of strength that will allow us to respond swiftly and severely to any further Russian aggression.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would just note on that, on these themes, you know, this is something that the Biden-Harris administration has emphasized from day one &#8212; the importance of allies and partners across the board, not just in security issues and not just in Europe, but, in general, the importance of allies and alliances.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;re seeing that play out in this crisis in Europe today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Her speech will also focus on reassuring our allies and partners of our commitments and how we&#8217;re committed to bolstering NATO and reinforcing our allies in the face of Russian aggression.&nbsp; And she&#8217;ll talk about how a further invasion of Ukraine, we believe, will leave Russia weaker and not stronger.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, lastly, she will also address the broader stakes here.&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;re focused mostly on the very serious threat to the country of Ukraine.&nbsp; But it goes beyond that.&nbsp; Russia poses a threat, in what it&#8217;s doing here, to the European and international order.&nbsp; And the Vice President will underscore that and make it clear.</p>



<p>After the speech, she&#8217;ll have a number of other engagements with other world leaders on the margins of the conference, and we&#8217;ll provide details as they happen.&nbsp; I suspect it&#8217;ll be a large numbers &#8212; large number.&nbsp; As you know, there are a lot of leaders at the conference, but I&#8217;ll just flag two of particular importance here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One is that she’ll meet with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine.&nbsp; And that&#8217;ll be a real opportunity to underscore our commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and to further coordinate the diplomatic efforts that have been underway to provide economic and defensive security assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, secondly, we anticipate she&#8217;ll have the opportunity to engage with Chancellor Scholz of Germany &#8212; I should say “further opportunity” to engage.&nbsp; As you know, he was here at the White House just last week.&nbsp; And the Vice President looks forward to the opportunity to speak further with him about this crisis and more.</p>



<p>So that is a sense of the speech and what we have planned for the second day in Munich.</p>



<p>The last thing I would say before we look forward to your questions: Just to note that, in addition to Vice President Harris&#8217;s engagement &#8212; engagements with heads of state in Munich, some of which we&#8217;ve described, the State Department announced earlier today that Secretary Blinken is also traveling to Munich to engage with his foreign ministry counterparts.&nbsp; Our Ambassador to NATO, Julie Smith, will also be there.&nbsp; And this just further underscores the importance of this gathering at this particular critical time.<br>Thanks a lot.&nbsp; And with that, maybe over to my colleague to open it up for questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Moderator, could you please provide instructions to ask questions?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; Can you hear me?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I am just curious about, you know, a lot of the details that were laid out, obviously, at the top of the call.&nbsp; And how does sort of the calculus change if Russia does invade Ukraine when the Vice President is in Munich?&nbsp; If you can just talk a little bit about the contingencies that have been planned for a situation like that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Nandita.&nbsp; Thanks very much for the question.&nbsp; As my colleague said at the start, we are in a fluid situation.&nbsp; This is something that we&#8217;ve talked about from the very beginning in terms of what we have seen in terms of the buildup and the fact that it is continuing.</p>



<p>And our determination to stand together with our Allies, to have very strong unity within NATO as well as across the European Union is unflagging.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Her reason for going to Munich is to meet with what we think is over three dozen heads of state who will be there.&nbsp; She will hold these highest-level meetings to consult with them on the latest developments and to ensure that the transatlantic community, the NATO Alliance, that we speak with one voice that is strong and resolute.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
