<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 20:20:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Release: Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/press-release-nominations-sent-to-the-senate-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 20:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Carmen G. Cantor, of Puerto Rico, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Interior, vice Douglas W. Domenech. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Shefali Razdan Duggal, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of the Netherlands. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Rebecca F. Dye, of North Carolina,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Carmen G. Cantor, of Puerto Rico, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Interior, vice Douglas W. Domenech.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Shefali Razdan Duggal, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of the Netherlands.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rebecca F. Dye, of North Carolina, to be a Federal Maritime Commissioner for a term expiring June 30, 2025.&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Susie Feliz, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce, vice Michael Platt Jr., resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Janet Keller, of California, to be a Member of the United States Advisory Commission on Public Diplomacy for a term expiring July 1, 2023, vice Elizabeth F. Bagley, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Brendan Owens, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense, vice Lucian Niemeyer.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rheanne Wirkkala, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense, vice Robert R. Hood, resigned.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Supply Chain Event Launching Data Initiative for Greater Supply Chain&#160;Resilience</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/readout-of-supply-chain-event-launching-data-initiative-for-greater-supply-chain-resilience/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 19:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49162</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Director of the National Economic Council Brian Deese and Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg met with key stakeholders in the country’s goods movement supply chain to launch a new initiative that will help to speed up the movement of goods, reducing delays and costs for American consumers. &#160; NEC and DOT leaders discussed with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Director of the National Economic Council Brian Deese and Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg met with key stakeholders in the country’s goods movement supply chain to launch a new initiative that will help to speed up the movement of goods, reducing delays and costs for American consumers. &nbsp;</p>



<p>NEC and DOT leaders discussed with port directors and business leaders the value of the new initiative. Freight Logistics Optimization Works (FLOW), an information sharing initiative to pilot key freight information exchange between parts of the supply chain. This commitment to moving the transportation logistics system to 21<sup>st</sup> century digitization follows the commitment to move toward 24/7 operations many made last fall.</p>



<p>Participants discussed the progress made to date in working collaboratively across private sector stakeholders and with federal and state governments to address supply chain bottlenecks at ports including the decline in long-term dwelling containers (by 60% at the Ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach since November), a reduction in empty containers (by more than 30% at the Port of Los Angeles since the beginning of the year), and the creation of pop-up sites for containers around the Port of Savannah. In particular, participants discussed the success of pop-up sites at restoring fluidity over the past year and how they will be needed in the future.</p>



<p>They underscored the value of greater data transparency across the supply chain and how this would benefit not only their respective companies but also the system more broadly, cutting waste and reducing costs for consumers. Participants acknowledged the current system is underperforming and needs greater investment and more collaboration in creating ship to shelf visibility into the primarily private-sector owned supply chain. A more reliable, predictable, and accurate information exchange about goods movement is the hallmark of a globally competitive 21<sup>st</sup> century goods movement chain and is especially important for small- and medium-sized businesses who lack visibility into the current system. Participants highlighted that this type of digital infrastructure was more important than ever in the face of supply chain disruptions caused by global events like the pandemic and Russia’s unprovoked aggression in Ukraine.</p>



<p><strong>Here’s what industry leaders across the supply chain are saying about this critical initiative: </strong><a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/industry-leaders-endorse-biden-harris-administration-initiative-improve-supply-0">https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/industry-leaders-endorse-biden-harris-administration-initiative-improve-supply-0</a></p>



<p><strong>Participants included:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Port of Long Beach</li><li>Port of Los Angeles</li><li>Georgia Ports Authority*</li><li>Gemini Shippers Association</li><li>DCLI</li><li>FlexiVan</li><li>Prologis</li><li>CMA CGM</li><li>MSC*</li><li>C.H.Robinson*</li><li>Target*</li><li>True Value</li><li>Land ‘O Lakes</li><li>FedEx</li><li>UPS</li></ul>



<p>*denotes virtual participant</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on the Withdrawal of Sarah Bloom Raskin’s Nomination to Serve as Vice Chair for Supervision of the Federal Reserve Board of&#160;Governors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/statement-from-president-biden-on-the-withdrawal-of-sarah-bloom-raskins-nomination-to-serve-as-vice-chair-for-supervision-of-the-federal-reserve-board-of-governors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 19:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After serving as the second-in-command at Treasury and with prior service on the Federal Reserve Board of Governors, Sarah Bloom Raskin knows better than anyone how important the Federal Reserve is to fighting inflation and continuing a sustainable economic recovery. She has unparalleled experience pursuing solutions to enhance our country’s critical financial infrastructure, with expertise&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>After serving as the second-in-command at Treasury and with prior service on the Federal Reserve Board of Governors, Sarah Bloom Raskin knows better than anyone how important the Federal Reserve is to fighting inflation and continuing a sustainable economic recovery. She has unparalleled experience pursuing solutions to enhance our country’s critical financial infrastructure, with expertise in cybersecurity and climate risk, and protecting consumers in the financial marketplace.</p>



<p>Sarah’s nomination had broad support—from the banking and financial services community, former members of the Board of Governors, multiple Nobel Prize winners, consumer advocates, and respected economists from around the country. That experience and support are among the many reasons why I nominated Sarah to be the Vice Chair for Supervision, a critical role in regulating our nation’s financial institutions.</p>



<p>Despite her readiness—and despite having been confirmed by the Senate with broad, bipartisan support twice in the past—Sarah was subject to baseless attacks from industry and conservative interest groups. Unfortunately, Senate Republicans are more focused on amplifying these false claims and protecting special interests than taking important steps toward addressing inflation and lowering costs for the American people.</p>



<p>I am grateful for Sarah’s service to our country and for her willingness to serve again, and I look forward to her future contributions to our country.</p>



<p>I urge the Senate Banking Committee to move swiftly to confirm the four eminently qualified nominees for the Board of Governors—Jerome Powell, Lael Brainard, Philip Jefferson, and Lisa Cook—who are still waiting for an up-or-down vote. This group has the experience, judgment, and talent necessary to lead the Federal Reserve at this critical moment in our economic recovery, and the Senate should move their nominations forward.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;2471</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/03/15/bill-signed-h-r-2471/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 19:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, March 15, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 2471, the &#8220;Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022,&#8221; which provides full-year funding through September 30, 2022 for projects and activities of the Federal Government. Division N provides supplemental appropriations for fiscal year (FY) 2022 for Ukraine activities. Remaining divisions provide authorizations and extensions on a wide&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, March 15, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 2471, the &#8220;Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022,&#8221; which provides full-year funding through September 30, 2022 for projects and activities of the Federal Government. Division N provides supplemental appropriations for fiscal year (FY) 2022 for Ukraine activities. Remaining divisions provide authorizations and extensions on a wide variety of Government programs and activities.</p>



<p>Thank you to Speaker Pelosi, Leader Schumer, Leader McConnell, Leader McCarthy, Chairman Leahy, Vice Chairman Shelby, Chair DeLauro, Ranking Member Granger, and the Appropriations Committees.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meetings with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy and Diplomatic Advisor to the Prime Minister Luigi&#160;Mattiolo</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meetings-with-prime-minister-mario-draghi-of-italy-and-diplomatic-advisor-to-the-prime-minister-luigi-mattiolo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 19:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On March 15, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met in Rome with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy to discuss international cooperation in response to Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. This followed Mr. Sullivan’s meeting with Luigi Mattiolo, Diplomatic Advisor to the Prime Minister. The two senior officials discussed continued measures, including in coordination with the G7&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On March 15, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met in Rome with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy to discuss international cooperation in response to Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. This followed Mr. Sullivan’s meeting with Luigi Mattiolo, Diplomatic Advisor to the Prime Minister. The two senior officials discussed continued measures, including in coordination with the G7 and EU, to impose costs on Russia for its war on Ukraine and to provide humanitarian assistance to those fleeing the conflict. They also talked about U.S. support for European efforts to establish alternative energy sources.  In addition, the two sides discussed Transatlantic approaches to the People’s Republic of China, as well as further enhancement of the US-Italian relations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the President’s Travel to&#160;Belgium</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-presidents-travel-to-belgium/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 18:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to Brussels, Belgium later this month. President Biden will join an extraordinary NATO summit on March 24 to discuss ongoing deterrence and defense efforts in response to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack on Ukraine as well as to reaffirm our ironclad commitment to our NATO Allies. President Biden&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to Brussels, Belgium later this month. President Biden will join an extraordinary NATO summit on March 24 to discuss ongoing deterrence and defense efforts in response to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack on Ukraine as well as to reaffirm our ironclad commitment to our NATO Allies. President Biden will also join a scheduled European Council Summit to discuss our shared concerns about Ukraine, including transatlantic efforts to impose economic costs on Russia, provide humanitarian support to those affected by the violence, and address other challenges related to the conflict.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on COVID Response and Funding&#160;Needs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/15/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-covid-response-and-funding-needs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:36 A.M. EDT      MR. MUNOZ:  Hey, everybody.  Thanks you for joining us &#8212; Happy Tuesday &#8212; for this press call today.  We are going to outline the consequences that a lack of COVID-19 response funding will have on the United States if Congress fails to act.      The call and the accompanying&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>10:36 A.M. EDT<br><br>     MR. MUNOZ:  Hey, everybody.  Thanks you for joining us &#8212; Happy Tuesday &#8212; for this press call today.  We are going to outline the consequences that a lack of COVID-19 response funding will have on the United States if Congress fails to act.<br><br>     The call and the accompanying factsheet that you all just received before this will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and embargoed until 11:30 a.m. Eastern.<br><br>     On today’s call, we have [senior administration officials].<br><br>     With that, I will kick it to [senior administration official] for some opening remarks.<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Kevin.  Good morning, everyone.  Thanks for joining us.<br><br>Today, we want to cover the consequences of a lack of additional funding for the nation’s COVID response.<br><br>I’ll discuss the near-term impacts, and then I’ll turn to [senior administration official] to discuss the impacts on our longer-term preparedness.<br><br>First, I want to step back and provide some context on how we view this moment in the pandemic.<br><br>Over the past 14 months, the country has made critical investments, using resources that Congress provided on a bipartisan basis, to make sure the American people have access to free and widely available tools: vaccines, boosters, treatments, tests, and high-quality masks.<br><br>As a result, the U.S. has made tremendous progress: Cases are down 95 percent since the peak of Omicron.  Hospitalizations are down 85 percent.  Over 215 million Americans are fully vaccinated, and over 95 million Americans have received a booster shot.<br><br>But as the President said in the State of the Union, we still have more work to do.<br><br>Our scientific and medical experts have been clear that in the next couple of months we could see COVID cases increase here in the U.S., just as we’re seeing cases rising abroad right now.<br><br>That’s why we remain laser-focused on fighting COVID and preparing for the future.<br><br>The President has laid out a comprehensive National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan to continue the progress we’ve made and to ensure we keep the country moving forward safely.<br><br>We asked for immediate funding needed to start to implement that plan.<br><br>In fact, for months, we’ve made clear to Congress, on a bipartisan basis, that the funding for tests, treatments, and vaccines was drying up and that additional funds would be needed.<br><br>In January, we notified the Hill that funding would be needed after the Omicron surge.  In February, we briefed appropriators and authorizers about the status of funds and the consequences if there were no additional funds.<br><br>We sent a formal request of $22.5 billion to the Hill, again being clear of what we could not do without more funding.<br><br>The President called for additional funding in his State of the Union address; outlined in a 96-page plan, made clear that more funding is needed. <br><br>And our team has held more than two dozen calls and meetings with members of Congress about this emergency funding request. <br><br>We have been clear: We hoped Congress would provide these resources, as lawmakers have done multiple times on a bipartisan basis under the prior administration.<br><br>Further inaction will set us back; leave us unprepared &#8212; less prepared; and cost us more lives.<br><br>We need Congress to provide the $22.5 billion in emergency immediate funding.<br><br>Now, let me walk through some of the immediate consequences of a lack of funding.<br><br>First, on vaccines: Without additional funding, we do not have the adequate resources to purchase enough booster shots for all Americans if an additional shot is needed.<br><br>Keep in mind, when Congress passed the supplemental bill in December of 2020 and the American Rescue Plan, the mRNA vaccines were envisioned as a two-shot vaccine.  We’ve now administered nearly 100 million booster shots, and four shots are now recommended and available for immunocompromised people.<br><br>To ensure enough fourth doses for all Americans or a variant-specific vaccine should we ever need them, we must have funding in hand.<br><br>Vaccines are our most effective tool.  We cannot be caught without the ability to move quickly to get more of the most effective vaccines available as soon as we are able.<br><br>Next, on treatments: To date, we have shipped over 7 million courses of treatments to the American people.  And in many cases, we have sent federal medical personnel to states to help administer those treatments.  When Omicron hit, the federal government stepped in to ramp up delivery of the last remaining treatment that worked.<br><br>These efforts have saved lives in every state in the country.<br><br>We have planned &#8212; we had planned to purchase additional monoclonals as soon as next week.  Without additional funding, we are cancelling those plans.  And as we will make clear to governors later this morning, we also need to cut the number of monoclonal antibody treatments we send to states by 30 percent starting next week.<br><br>Even with these cuts, we anticipate that our supply of monoclonal antibody treatments will run out as soon as late May.<br><br>Next, on the preventative treatments for immunocompromised Americans: We have purchased 1.7 million doses of AstraZeneca’s Evusheld &#8212; all that they could produce to date.<br><br>AstraZeneca recently told us that they will be &#8212; they will have additional supply that will be available for delivery starting in September.  These are doses we had planned to purchase as soon as the end of March.<br><br>Without more funding, the federal government will now be forced to scale back on that purchase.  So, we’ll likely run out of treatments for our most vulnerable Americans by the end of the year, if not sooner.<br><br>The bottom line on treatments is this: Without additional funding soon, thousands of patients could lose access to treatments, and these companies will have little incentive to continue investing in the development and manufacturing of these treatments.<br><br>Next, on the uninsured fund: <s>The Office of Management and Budget</s> [The Administration] notified Congress in February that this fund that reimburses doctors and other medical providers for caring for uninsured individuals was running out of money and would have to stop taking new claims in March.<br><br>Unfortunately, we’re now having to take that action.<br><br>HHS will begin to scale back this program starting next week and end it completely in early April.<br><br>This means doctors, nurses, pharmacists, labs, and other healthcare providers will no longer be reimbursed for tests, treatments, and vaccinations for people without health insurance.<br><br>And finally, in addition to all of these impacts to our domestic response, the lack of funding greatly impacts our global response.<br><br>Without more funding, USAID and our interagency partners will have to cut short efforts to turn vaccines into vaccinations around the world.<br><br>In fact, the administration won’t be able to extend surge support to over 20 additional under-vaccinated countries that will need intensive support this year to get shots in arms.<br><br>This will devastate our ability to ensure these countries can effectively deploy safe and effective vaccines.  And leaving large unvaccinated populations worldwide will increase the risk of new deadly emerging &#8212; of variants emerging that could evade our current vaccines and treatments. <br><br>Without additional funding, USAID will also be unable to provide lifesaving supplies, tests, therapeutics, oxygen, and other humanitarian aid to countries still struggling to manage a continued COVID disease burden.<br><br>Now, I’ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to discuss some of the long-term preparedness efforts at risk.  [Senior administration official]?<br><br>One second.<br><br>[Senior administration official], can you unmute?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  [Senior administration official], do you have me now?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  I got you.  Go for it.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Oh, my goodness.  Okay, sorry about that.<br><br>All right.  So, thanks, [senior administration official].  Thanks, everybody.  Let me also start with vaccines.<br><br>Without additional support from Congress, NIH and BARDA will lack the funding needed to accelerate research and development of next-generation vaccines that provide broader and more durable protection, including a vaccine that protects against a range of variants.<br><br>We’ll face a similar challenge on treatments.  The current antivirals require multiple pills over several days.  We think it’s possible to get treatment courses down to one or two pills, but that requires additional research and funding.<br><br>And when a new vaccine or treatment becomes available, it’s important for us to have the funding to secure enough doses for the American people.<br><br>Over the past 14 months, we’ve put the massive purchasing power of the federal government to use, making sure America is first in line for promising treatments.<br><br>That’s the reason we’ve been able to secure more Pfizer antiviral pills than anyone else in the world.  These pills cut the risk of hospitalization and death by 90 percent.<br><br>Without additional funding, we lack the resources needed to get behind promising new treatments, meaning less supply available to the American people.<br><br>So the failure to invest in the research and the advanced purchase of lifesaving treatments and new vaccines now will leave the nation vulnerable in the face of a new variant or a new surge.<br><br>Finally, on testing: We have significantly increased our testing capacity in this country through targeted federal investments.<br><br>Without additional funding, we do not have the ability to maintain our domestic testing capacity beyond June.<br><br>So, after spending the last year building up our testing capacity, Congress now risks squandering that capacity heading into the second half of this year. <br><br>And because it takes months of ramp-up to rebuild capacity, failure to invest now will leave us less prepared for any potential future surges.  So providing funding only when cases rise is far too late to make a difference.<br><br>Bottom line: We need funding now so we’re prepared for whatever comes next.<br><br>With that, back over to you, [senior administration official].<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, [senior administration official].  Let me just close with a few thoughts here.<br><br>We have been clear-eyed and we are clear-eyed moving forward about how unpredictable this virus has been and can be moving forward.<br><br>Omicron was the most contagious variant we’ve ever seen.  It led to an unprecedented increase in cases.  But because we had the resources, we were able to surge support to Americans that needed it.<br><br>We sent tests to homes, masks to pharmacies, over 2,500 federal personnel to states, more treatments to providers.  We kept our businesses open and almost all of our kids learning in person. <br><br>That was because we had resources at our disposal to act and to act quickly. <br><br>We have a plan to keep it that way, but we need the resources to execute that plan. <br><br>The failure to provide additional resources soon will have severe consequences in the near term, as I’ve outlined: fewer monoclonal antibodies treatments, fewer tests, fewer treatments for the immunocompromised, and a risk of running short on vaccines.<br><br>We want to be clear: Waiting to provide funding until we’re in a worse spot with the virus will be too late.<br><br>Importantly, when you consider the cost of all these investments compared to the cost of what we will prevent &#8212; in terms of hospitalizations, deaths, and damage to our healthcare system and our economy &#8212; it is not a close call.<br><br>With that. let&#8217;s open up for questions. <br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Thanks.  We have time for a few questions.  First, let&#8217;s go to Josh Wingrove at Bloomberg. <br><br>Q    Hi there.  Thank you.  Can you tell us a little bit more about the monoclonal order in terms of the scale?  Like how many were you planning to order?  If you don&#8217;t order it now, do you lose your spot in line?  And, you know, if new funding came in the following weeks, would you still be able to place that order?<br><br>And, more broadly, you mentioned, on fourth shots &#8212; can you specify: Right now, you think you have enough for immunocompromised people that are currently eligible, but without new funding, you might not have enough in the event that the broader population would need a fourth shot or be given the option to get a fourth shot? <br><br>Thank you. <br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Josh.  I&#8217;ll start, and maybe, [senior administration official], you can add.<br><br>On your first question on monoclonals, the purchase was likely to be in the hundreds of thousands of more doses.  We had planned to place that order next week on March 25th. <br><br>I can&#8217;t say whether those &#8212; you&#8217;d have to ask the company whether those would be available to us if we purchased at a later date.  That was the plan.  And as we know, these are &#8212; these are treatments that are highly sought after not just in this country but in other countries. <br><br>And so, we have to end that purchase and we have to reduce the allocations to our states by 30 percent but that we&#8217;re stretching out the supply as long as we possibly can. <br><br>On the fourth shot, we have enough now for immunocompromised individuals who need to seek a fourth shot.  What we don&#8217;t have the funding for is if all Americans were needed to get an additional dose, we would need additional funding from Congress. <br><br>And importantly, Josh, I would add that if we need a variant-specific testing, which heretofore we have been lucky enough not to need, but we want to be ready for that.  And if we need a new vaccine, we have &#8212; our gap in resources is even more severe if we need a variant-specific vaccine. <br><br>{Senior administration official}, anything you would add?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Sure, [senior administration official].  Thank you.  I think you said it exactly right. <br><br>The other thing I would just add is we have to make these purchases now so the product is available in the coming months.  It requires several months for some of the manufacturing to take place.  So, to secure our place in line, we have to make the purchases now to bring these doses forward in the coming weeks to months. <br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Thanks.  Next question.  Let&#8217;s go to Jeremy Diamond at CNN. <br><br>Q    Hey, thanks very much for doing this.  Just searching for some more concrete numbers on the testing front.  What are we at now in terms of tests per month?  And how would that number be impacted after June?<br><br>And then secondly, if there were to be a game-changing variant spreading wildly in the U.S., you know, say, tomorrow, is the U.S. prepared for that?<br><br>And after which point in time would we not be prepared without additional funding?<br><br>Thanks. <br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Jeremy.  It&#8217;s a good question. <br><br>On tests per month, we&#8217;re in the hundreds of millions of tests per month now.  That&#8217;s because of the investments over the last 14 months in getting to that point. <br><br>We don&#8217;t know, after June, if we can maintain the domestic manufacturing capabilities that we have today.  In fact, we were told by the domestic test manufacturers that they cannot.  We&#8217;ve made investments to get us to June.  We need additional funding from Congress to not lose the gains that we&#8217;ve made over the last 14 months in the domestic testing manufacturing. <br><br>So, it&#8217;s vitally important that we continue that manufacturing so we don&#8217;t lose everything that we&#8217;ve done in over-the-counter testing in the last year. <br><br>On variants, look, what I can say, Jeremy, is we will &#8212; we are well less prepared without additional funding than we would be otherwise.  We laid out an entire plan in 96 pages of detail for how we want to be prepared moving forward and to be prepared.  We were clear in that plan, we were clear in the State of the Union, and we&#8217;ve been clear with Congress for the past few months that we need additional funding to do that. <br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Let&#8217;s go to Rachel Roubein at the Washington Post. <br><br>Q    Hi, thanks for taking my question.  I was wondering: Have you guys had any conversations in the past few days with Congress about lowering the funding number at all from 15.6 billion? <br><br>And then, also, have you talked with lawmakers in recent days on additional pay-fors out of existing funds to replace the state and local aid pay-for that was taken out of the bill?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Rachel.  On your first question on the conversations with Congress to reduce the funding, the answer is no.  We need &#8212; we&#8217;ve submitted emergency requests for $22.5 billion, and we stand by that request.<br><br>On the pay-fors, you know, we&#8217;ll leave it to Congress the details of how they get this over the finish line in Congress.  But I think there&#8217;s bipartisan recognition that we need this money.  There&#8217;s recognition of the money they provided over a year ago has been well spent.  And we defer to Congress on the specific legislative approach. <br><br>But I will say that there is precedence, including in the prior administration multiple times, to provide direct COVID response funding on a bipartisan basis without offsets.<br><br>And so, we hope and expect that we&#8217;ll be able to rely on that precedent moving forward. <br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Let&#8217;s go to Tamara Keith at NPR. <br><br>Q    Apologies.  Two years in, I can&#8217;t figure out mute. <br><br>Thank you for taking my question.  I&#8217;m hoping that you can sort of explain the mechanics of the markets for these various things, like why the government still needs to be involved in making these large purchases; why, you know, large hospital groups couldn&#8217;t be buying the vaccines or buying the monoclonal antibodies; like, why &#8212; why it is all so contingent on federal funds.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah.  Tamara, it’s a good question.<br><br>Look, in our preparedness plan, we outlined that we want to explore in the future the ability to transition some of COVID treatments and potentially other tools to insurance-based market, like other healthcare. <br><br>But I think our priority from the beginning is to make sure that in a once-in-a-generation pandemic that has killed over 960,000 Americans, that we&#8217;re taking the measures that are necessary to make those widely available, free, and accessible to all Americans. <br><br>That&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve done with monoclonal antibody.  That&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve done with the Pfizer pills and the Merck pills.  That’s what we’ve done with testing.  And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve done with, obviously, vaccines.<br><br>We think it&#8217;s the right thing at this moment to continue to move forward with that. <br><br>And I&#8217;d say most important, when we have a variant that strikes like we had with Omicron, our ability as the federal government to use our purchasing power as a government to purchase all of those things, all of those tools, and get them available to all Americans on an equitable basis saves lives.  And it was fundamental in Omicron, and I would &#8212; we would argue it&#8217;s fundamental if a variant were to come in the next few months.<br><br>So, yes, we want to explore over the long term a safe, a smooth transition.  But right now, we have immediate needs, and we need Congress to act.<br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Let’s go to Sheryl Stolberg at the New York Times.<br><br>Sheryl?  All right, Sheryl, we&#8217;ll come back to you.<br><br>Let&#8217;s go to Zeke Miller at the AP.<br><br>Q    Hey.  Thanks for doing this.  Just to follow up on Tam&#8217;s question there: So, why not, if &#8212; you know, if the need is immediate and Congress right now shows no sign of budging, aren&#8217;t you exploring those alternate avenues?  You know, you just required private insurers to cover the cost of at-home tests.  Why not have them cover the cost of vaccines and Paxlovid and other things like that? <br><br>Why does the government still need to be the middleman there, given the current rate of COVID-impacted society and mortality?  I mean, how is that different than, you know, cancer or heart disease, other things where insurance is &#8212; the private insurance market is already effective there?<br><br>And then, separately, lawmakers on Capitol Hill have been, you know, complaining about that lack of outreach over the last several week &#8212; several weeks from the White House.  Why did it take until, you know, just the last couple of months for the White House to sort of sound the alarm here?  Shouldn’t this have been something that you all raised the alarm on last year as this &#8212; as these funds were being rapidly depleted?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Zeke.  So, on your first question, I&#8217;d say, look, we are exploring those alternatives.  We made that clear in the &#8212; in the Preparedness Plan that we released a few weeks ago.  But it takes time, as you know, to move to that &#8212; to such a system.  We &#8212; it needs to be an orderly, smooth transition.  So we&#8217;re working through that. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;d also say, though, especially for things like vaccines, but in fact for all of our tools, the United States competes against other countries to get access &#8212; preferential access, as much as we can, to those tools.&nbsp; So we shouldn&#8217;t be fooled that if we move to this market that we would still be able to provide Americans the early access to the tools that we have worked really hard for the last 14 months to be able to provide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So if you think about a scenario where we had another variant or if we need a variant-specific vaccine, if the U.S. government sees our responsibility to provide and purchase those, you know, insurance companies would be competing against other countries to provide those, to try to purchase those, as opposed to the U.S. government stepping in and making sure that all Americans have easy, free access to something that can save their life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So it&#8217;s certainly something we’re exploring.&nbsp; But it needs to be a smooth transition, an orderly transition, and there are certain places where we want to make sure that we are able to step in as the federal government and provide that access where we think it is merited.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To your second question on outreach: You know, we have been clear with Congress since mid-January that funds in our existing balances were low.&nbsp; We briefed appropriators and authorizers in February on our immediate needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also in February, we sent a document to the Hill clearly outlining the near-term consequences of no funding, which included specifically saying things like the uninsured fund would have to stop taking claims in March &#8212; we are now in March; monoclonals would stock out in May if we didn&#8217;t have funds by March; that AstraZeneca for immunocompromised would stock out this summer if we didn&#8217;t have funds in March.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We then &#8212; the Acting Director of OMB, Shalanda Young, sent a letter to Congress in March &#8212; early March asking for the $22.5 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve been clear with Congress on how funds were dwindling in these accounts and that there were &#8212; there were going to be immediate consequences of that.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re making that &#8212; those consequences clear again today.</p>



<p>     MR. MUNOZ:  Next question, let’s go to Jeff Mason at Reuters.<br><br>Q    Thanks very much.  Two questions.  One, can you &#8212; I know, [senior administration official], that you said you would leave the mechanics of how Congress did this to Congress, but can you just outline what the options are at this point?  Do you expect that Democrats would have to put this into a separate bill or the reconciliation bill?  Or what is your expectation at least for options on how on how to get this across the finish line?<br><br>And secondly, I saw that Punchbowl wrote a story this morning about a letter that you&#8217;ve written to Congress about this.  Can you get us that letter or confirm that that was written?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Jeff.  So, [senior administration official] on mechanics, and I welcome [senior administration official] to jump in here after I talk if they want to add. <br><br>But, you know, I think, as I mentioned, there are many avenues that Congress can do to move to move this funding forward.  The &#8212; what we see is past precedent under the prior administration for bipartisan support for funds for direct COVID response to save lives that were provided multiple times without offsets.  So we think there&#8217;s clearly a precedent for that.  We&#8217;re asking for $22.5 billion for immediate funding, and we think Congress should move on that.<br><br>I say on reconciliation &#8212; again, I defer to Congress, but we need this money now.  These are immediate, near-term consequences, some of which we&#8217;re having to act on this week, next week, and the first week of April.  So, time is not on our side; we need we need the funding immediately.<br><br>And then on the letter to Congress that&#8217;s being sent today &#8212; and we&#8217;ll make sure that folks have access to that.<br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Last question, let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett at ABC News.<br><br>Q    Thank you.  Hi, guys.  So, I wanted to clarify on testing: Is capacity declining this month, as we previously heard in March, or do you have enough on that front to get through June unscathed, [senior administration official], as you said, just a bit ago?<br><br>And then on Test to Treat: Can that new program still go on?  Are there enough antivirals to support that or is that going to have to be scaled back?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks.  On testing capacity, [senior administration official], I don&#8217;t know if you want to add here, but we have domestic manufacturing capability to sustain our domestic manufacturing capability until June.  And at that point, it will greatly diminish.<br><br>[Senior administration official], anything you’d add on testing?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Well, I think that&#8217;s exactly right.  Due to federal support, we&#8217;ve been able to maintain this manufacturing capacity, even though as [senior administration official] mentioned, we are hearing from our domestic manufacturers that demand from other places is starting to crater. <br><br>So, it&#8217;s very important that we have this federal funding to support that manufacturing.  And we anticipate we can keep it going through June.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks.  And then, Cheyenne, just on your second question: We do have the pills to do Test to Treat.  We do not, however, have funding &#8212; and this is clear in the materials we put out &#8212; to make any additional purchases of Pfizer pills beyond the ones that we&#8217;ve made.<br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  All right.  Well, thank you, everybody, for joining today.<br><br>As a reminder, this call is embargoed until 11:30 and attributable to “senior administration officials.”<br><br>Let me know if you have any other questions, and have a good day.<br><br>11:03 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The White&#160;House Announces 2022 Public&#160;Tours</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/the-white-house-announces-2022-public-tours/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is pleased to announce public tours of the White House will begin on Friday, April 15, 2022.&#160; Public tours will initially be available from 8:00 AM to 12:30 PM on Fridays and Saturdays, excluding Federal holidays or unless otherwise noted. All White House tours are free of charge. The White House&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is pleased to announce public tours of the White House will begin on Friday, April 15, 2022.&nbsp; Public tours will initially be available from 8:00 AM to 12:30 PM on Fridays and Saturdays, excluding Federal holidays or unless otherwise noted. All White House tours are free of charge. The White House tour schedule is subject to change based on inclement weather or official use.</p>



<p><strong>PUBLIC WHITE HOUSE TOUR REQUESTS</strong></p>



<p>Public tour requests are scheduled on a first come, first served basis and must be submitted through a Member of Congress and their Congressional Tour Coordinator. Constituents may reach your Member of Congress and Congressional Tour Coordinator through the U.S. House of Representative’s Switchboard at 202-225-3121, the U.S. Senate Switchboard at 202-224-3121, or online at <a href="http://www.congress.gov/members">www.congress.gov/members</a>.</p>



<p>Consistent with prior practices, public White House tour requests must be submitted a minimum of 21 days in advance and no more than 90 days in advance of the requested tour date(s). Reservations cannot be accepted for tour dates outside this 21 – 90-day window. Congressional Tour Coordinators will be able to submit tour requests beginning Monday, March 21, 2022.&nbsp; <a></a></p>



<p>The White House will continue to closely monitor the COVID-19 situation with guidance based on recommendations from the CDC, and other public health officials and medical experts, and reserves the right to adjust availability of the public tours as necessary to adhere to the latest health guidance. Within the 10 days prior to the public tour, anyone who has tested positive for COVID-19, has had any COVID-19 symptoms, or been in close contact with someone confirmed or suspected to have COVID-19, should stay home. Face masks will be available when entering the White House complex for those who choose to wear them.</p>



<p><em>Information regarding additional springtime events at the White House, including the Spring Garden Tours and the White House Easter Egg Roll, will be released in the coming days.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Consequences of Lack of Funding for Efforts to Combat COVID-&#8288;19 if Congress Does Not&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/fact-sheet-consequences-of-lack-of-funding-for-efforts-to-combat-covid-19-if-congress-does-not-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. has made tremendous progress in our fight against COVID-19. Over the past 14 months, the Biden Administration has made vital investments – using resources Congress provided on a bipartisan basis – to make sure the American people have free and widely available access to lifesaving tools: vaccines, booster shots, treatments, tests, and high-quality&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The U.S. has made tremendous progress in our fight against COVID-19. Over the past 14 months, the Biden Administration has made vital investments – using resources Congress provided on a bipartisan basis – to make sure the American people have free and widely available access to lifesaving tools: vaccines, booster shots, treatments, tests, and high-quality masks. As we enter a new moment in the pandemic, Congress has not provided us with the funding we need to continue the COVID-19 response and minimize the pandemic’s impact to the Nation and our economy. With cases rising abroad, scientific and medical experts have been clear that in the next couple of months there could be increasing cases of COVID-19 here in the U.S as well. As the Administration has warned, failure to fund these efforts now will have severe consequences as we will not be equipped to deal with a future surge. Waiting to provide funding once we’re in a surge will be too late.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without funding, the United States will not have enough additional boosters or variant specific vaccines, if needed, for all Americans. The federal government is unable to purchase additional life-saving monoclonal antibody treatments and will run out of supply to send to states as soon as late May. The federal government cannot purchase sufficient quantities of treatments for immunocompromised individuals. And, the federal government will be unable to sustain the testing capacity we built over the last 14 months, as we head into the second half of the year.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, President Biden laid out a comprehensive plan to ensure that the country can continue to move forward safely and remain prepared to fight new variants and future surges of the virus. And the Administration has been clear that we need Congress to provide additional resources, including $22.5 billion in immediate emergency funding. Inaction will set us back in this fight, leave us less prepared, and cost us more lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Consequences of lack of critical funding include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Inability to Secure Sufficient Booster Doses and Variant Specific Vaccines, If Needed: </strong>The federal government does not have adequate resources to purchase enough booster vaccine doses for all Americans, if additional doses are needed. The shortages will be even more acute if we need a variant-specific booster vaccine, since we will not have any existing supply.<strong></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Providers No Longer Able to Submit Claims for Testing, Treating, and Vaccinating the Uninsured:&nbsp;</strong> The fund that reimburses doctors and other medical providers for caring for uninsured individuals will start to be scaled back this month and end completely in early April.&nbsp;&nbsp; Specifically, one week from today – March 22 &#8212; the Uninsured Program will stop accepting new claims for testing and treatment due to lack of sufficient funds. Providers will no longer be able to submit claims for providing these services to uninsured individuals, forcing providers to either absorb the cost or turn away people who are uninsured, increasing the disparity in access to critically needed health care and putting additional burdens on safety net providers. Three weeks from today—April 5—the Uninsured Program will also stop accepting vaccination claims due to a lack of sufficient funds.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ending the Purchase of Monoclonal Antibody Treatments, Scaling Back State/Territory Allocations:</strong> The federal government has no more funding f0r additional monoclonals, including a planned order for March 25. To date, the federal government has been able to provide these life-saving treatments free of charge to Americans and work with states to make sure they get to as many people as possible who need them. In order to keep these treatments free and available to the American people for as long as possible, the Administration will now have to stretch our current supply and, starting next week, will be forced to cut state allocations of our limited existing supply of life-saving monoclonal antibody treatments by more than 30%.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Halting Critical Testing, Vaccine, Treatment Efforts</strong>: The President’s National Preparedness Plan was clear that the federal government must invest in next-generation vaccines and treatments and maintain our testing capacity in order to fight COVID-19 in the future. Now, without additional funding, we do not have the ability to:<ul><li><em>Purchase additional oral antiviral pills beyond the 20 million already secured.</em></li></ul><ul><li><em>Pre-purchase promising new antivirals</em>. The reason why the Administration has been able to secure more oral antiviral pills than any other country is because we committed to purchasing them early, even prior to an Emergency Use Authorization (EUA). As even more effective pills potentially become available, the federal government is no longer able to make advance purchase commitments to ensure America is one of the first countries in line.&nbsp;</li></ul><ul><li><em>Accelerate the creation of a next-generation, pan-COVID vaccine that would provide broad protection against a range of variants</em>. Vaccines are the most effective tool to prevent COVID-19, and the Administration does not have the funding for necessary investments in research and to support the development of promising new vaccine candidates.&nbsp; Such next-generation vaccines hold potential to broaden protection against known and future variants, reduce dosing through single-dose primary regimens with extended duration of protection (i.e., longer interval between boosters or possible elimination of boosters altogether), and reduce costs by increasing manufacturing yields and extending shelf life.</li></ul><ul><li><em>Maintain our domestic testing capacity beyond June.</em> After spending the last year building up our testing capacity, that progress will be squandered, the Administration will be unable to help keep domestic manufacturers online starting in June. That means, heading into the second half of the year, there will be significantly diminished domestic testing capacity and we may be unprepared for surges.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Scaling Back Planned Purchases of Preventive Treatments for Immunocompromised:</strong> The federal government has been planning to move forward with a purchase of preventative treatments for the immunocompromised as soon as March 31 that would begin delivery in September, once the treatments are manufactured. &nbsp;However, absent additional funding the federal government will now be forced to scale back that purchase of treatments for our most vulnerable. Because these treatments take more than 6 months to manufacture, the United States will likely not have enough of these treatments by the end of the year. &nbsp;And being unable to make additional purchase commitments now likely means that fewer treatments will be available next year as well. &nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Reducing Ability to Rapidly Identify and Assess Emerging Variants.&nbsp; </strong>Robust surveillance and research are critical to identify, understand and monitor emerging variants.&nbsp; With reduced capability to perform adequate surveillance, the country will be prone to being “blindsided” by future variants. In the absence of funding to immediately assess lab-based efficacy and real-world effectiveness of existing vaccines and treatments as new variants emerge, health care professionals will be forced to make insufficiently informed treatment decisions. The Administration will need to wind down some COVID surveillance investments, leaving us less able to detect the next variant.<strong></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Damage to Global Vaccination and COVID-19 Treatment Efforts:  </strong>Without additional funding to support getting shots into arms, USAID and interagency partners will have to cut short efforts to turn vaccines into vaccinations across the globe.  Leaving large unvaccinated populations worldwide will increase the risk of new deadly variants emerging that could evade our current vaccines and treatments.  Without additional funds, the Administration would be unable to extend Global VAX surge support to 20+ additional under-vaccinated countries that will need intensive support this year to get shots in arms. This will devastate our ability to ensure those countries can effectively deploy safe and effective vaccines. USAID will also be unable to provide life-saving supplies, tests, therapeutics, oxygen, and humanitarian aid to countries still struggling to manage a continuing COVID disease burden. </li></ul>



<p>In addition to the immediate need for funding, in order to facilitate a smooth transition to insurance coverage of life-savings COVID treatments the Administration is requesting that Congress provides authority to ensure seamless access to Medicare and insurance coverage for treatments under an Emergency Use Authorization (EUA).</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the March National Climate Task Force&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/readout-of-the-march-national-climate-task-force-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 15:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Task Force discussed ways to lower prices at the pump and secure true energy independence Yesterday, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the tenth meeting of the National Climate Task Force with Cabinet members and senior leadership from across the Biden-Harris Administration. The Task Force focused on how agencies can continue supporting the President’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>National Task Force discussed ways to lower prices at the pump and secure true energy independence</em></p>



<p>Yesterday, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the tenth meeting of the National Climate Task Force with Cabinet members and senior leadership from across the Biden-Harris Administration. The Task Force focused on how agencies can continue supporting the President’s commitment to addressing Putin’s Price Hike from his unprovoked war against Ukraine, minimizing pain at the pump here at home, continue rapidly deploying clean energy, and keep reducing emissions that cause climate change.</p>



<p>The Task Force echoed the President’s belief that this moment underscores the need to accelerate – not slow down – our transition to a clean energy future that will strengthen U.S. energy independence. They noted when electric cars are powered by clean energy, homes run on clean electricity, and our grid is more resilient and reliable, autocrats like Putin won’t be able to weaponize fossil fuels against other nations. Officials discussed building a clean energy future by furthering the Task Force’s work every day and advancing the President’s legislative agenda that provides tax credits to save families money, lower energy bills, boost U.S. manufacturing jobs, and promote competition.</p>



<p>Task Force members also discussed progress across government to achieve the President’s ambitious climate goals. A new Climate-Smart Infrastructure Working Group outlined efforts to ensure Bipartisan Infrastructure Law investments are resilient to future climate impacts and utilize low-carbon and carbon-free materials. Energy Secretary Granholm previewed upcoming work to make schools more energy efficient and cleaner for our children. Interior Secretary Haaland discussed how the Department of the Interior is leveraging Bipartisan Infrastructure Law investments to reclaim abandoned mines and plug orphan oil and gas wells across the country. Lastly, the Council on Environmental Quality highlighted the Administration’s continued commitment to environmental justice and their progress deploying the Climate and Economic Justice Screening Tool.</p>



<p>As outlined by President Biden’s January 27&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/executive-order-on-tackling-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad/">Executive Order on Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad</a>, the Task Force is chaired by the National Climate Advisor and includes Cabinet-level leaders from 21 federal agencies and senior White House officials to mobilize the Biden-Harris Administration’s implementation of a whole-of-government approach.</p>



<p>Task Force membership is comprised of the following government officials:</p>



<ul><li>National Climate Advisor (Chair)</li><li>Secretary of the Treasury</li><li>Secretary of Defense</li><li>Attorney General</li><li>Secretary of the Interior</li><li>Secretary of Agriculture</li><li>Secretary of Commerce</li><li>Secretary of Education</li><li>Secretary of Labor</li><li>Secretary of Health and Human Services</li><li>Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Secretary of Transportation</li><li>Secretary of Energy</li><li>Secretary of Homeland Security</li><li>Administrator of General Services</li><li>Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality</li><li>Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration</li><li>Director of the Office of Management and Budget</li><li>Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs</li><li>Assistant to the President for Homeland Security and Counterterrorism</li><li>Assistant to the President for Economic Policy</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
