<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 15:29:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Joint Statement Following Meeting Between President&#160;Biden and Egyptian President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi in&#160;Jeddah</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/16/joint-statement-following-meeting-between-president-biden-and-egyptian-president-abdel-fattah-al-sisi-in-jeddah/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 15:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met with Egyptian President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi today in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia to reaffirm their shared commitment to the U.S.-Egypt strategic partnership, consult on a broad range of global and regional security challenges, and advance the U.S.-Egypt relationship.  In celebrating the milestone of 100 years of U.S.-Egypt diplomatic relations,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met with Egyptian President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi today in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia to reaffirm their shared commitment to the U.S.-Egypt strategic partnership, consult on a broad range of global and regional security challenges, and advance the U.S.-Egypt relationship.  In celebrating the milestone of 100 years of U.S.-Egypt diplomatic relations, President Al Sisi and President Biden expressed their intention to meet again in the near future to further enhance the two countries’ multi-faceted partnership.  The two leaders renewed their commitment to the U.S.-Egypt Strategic Dialogue co-chaired by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Minister of Foreign Affairs Sameh Shoukry and welcomed the continued implementation of its outcomes.<br> <br>Strengthening our shared security<br> <br>The decades-long U.S.-Egypt defense partnership remains a key pillar of regional stability.  Both Presidents affirmed the importance of this partnership, which serves the interests of both countries.  President Biden reiterated that the United States aims to continue to support Egypt in providing for its own defense, including through the continued provision of security assistance in consultation with the U.S. Congress.  Both Presidents affirmed their commitment to cooperate on counter-terrorism and welcomed the notable achievements of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS.  President Al Sisi expressed Egypt’s appreciation for military equipment and security assistance from the United States.<br> <br>Advancing economic prosperity<br> <br>Both Presidents expressed their commitment to furthering bilateral economic cooperation for the mutual benefit of the Egyptian and American people.  They decided to explore new ways to expand bilateral trade, increase private sector investments, and collaborate on clean energy and climate technology.  The leaders welcomed the recent U.S. GreenTech Mission to Egypt, the largest in history, and committed to launch the high-level Joint Economic Commission.<br> <br>The impact of the war in Ukraine<br> <br>The United States and Egypt underlined that peace, security and a multilateral, rules-based order lie at the heart of their longstanding partnership.  Recalling the March 2<sup>nd</sup> and March 24<sup>th</sup> United Nations General Assembly resolutions on Ukraine, which both voted in favor of, they reaffirmed their shared principles enshrined in the UN Charter, including the respect for international law, territorial integrity, and national sovereignty.  The two Presidents emphasized the need to refrain from the use of force, solve conflicts by peaceful means, and end violations of human rights in conflict areas.  The United States and Egypt share particular concerns over the severe global consequences that stem from the war in Ukraine, including on global supply chains and energy and commodity prices.  For example, the blockading of Black Sea ports has triggered rising food insecurity and levied significant economic pressures on Egypt. <br> <br>President Biden underscored U.S. support for the Egyptian people in responding to these challenges.  To this end, the United States commends Egypt’s consultations with the International Monetary Fund and supports the provision of additional funding to Egypt through the IMF’s Resilience and Sustainability Trust.  The United States also lends its full support to Egypt’s engagement with the World Bank to seek financing options to stabilize its economy and strengthen the well-being of Egyptian households, in particular through the Crisis Response Finance Package recently announced by the Bank.  President Biden conveyed that the United States is providing $1 billion in new assistance to address the food security situation in the Middle East, with $50 million specifically for Egypt. These funds aim to bolster food security and offset the effects of the disruption in agricultural supply chains and higher food prices due to the blocking of ports.  President Biden assured President Al Sisi that the United States will advocate for Egypt and its food security needs.<br> <br>Promoting regional stability<br> <br>The United States and Egypt are cooperating closely to mediate solutions to regional conflicts and promote peace.  The two leaders stressed that a two-state solution remains the only viable path to achieve a lasting resolution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict and to realize a secure, prosperous, and dignified future for Israelis and Palestinians alike.  President Biden expressed support for Egypt’s vital leadership and historic role in promoting peace and an end to the conflict, thereby expanding the circle of peace between Israel and its Arab neighbors and globally, as well as preserving sustainable calm between Israelis and Palestinians. <br> <br>The two leaders underscored the need to implement United Nations Security Council resolutions 2570, 2571 (2021), reaffirming the necessity of holding presidential and parliamentary elections in tandem as soon as possible in Libya.  They emphasized the importance of the full withdrawal of all foreign forces, mercenaries, foreign fighters, and the pivotal role of the 5+5 Joint Military Committee in this regard, including the prompt development of timelines.  President Biden thanked President Al Sisi for Egypt’s role in helping to consolidate the Yemen Truce, particularly through facilitating commercial flights from Sana’a to Cairo, an important component of the UN-mediated truce arrangement.  The two Presidents committed to regular consultations to resolve regional conflicts and humanitarian crises in Syria, Lebanon, and Sudan.  Regarding the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam (GERD), President Biden reiterated U.S. support for Egypt’s water security and to forging a diplomatic resolution that would achieve the interests of all parties and contribute to a more peaceful and prosperous region.  The two leaders reiterated the imperative of concluding an agreement on the filling and operation of the GERD without further delay as stipulated in the Statement of the President of the United Nations Security Council dated September 15, 2021, and in accordance with international law.<br> <br>Promoting human rights<br> <br>President Biden and President Al Sisi emphasized their mutual commitment to a constructive dialogue on human rights, which is an integral component of the strong U.S.-Egypt partnership.  They will continue to consult closely on ensuring the promotion and protection of human rights and fundamental freedoms in political, civil, economic, social and cultural fields.  The two leaders reaffirmed the important role that civil society can play in these areas.<br> <br>Accelerating global efforts to tackle the climate crisis<br> <br>President Biden congratulated President Al Sisi for Egypt presiding over the 27<sup>th</sup> United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP 27) in Sharm El Sheikh in November 2022 and reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to a successful Conference.  The United States welcomes Egypt’s leadership in accelerating global ambition and action to tackle the climate crisis.  President Biden welcomed Egypt’s submission of its updated nationally determined contribution (NDC).  Both leaders emphasized their countries’ support for the Global Methane Pledge (GMP) and the new GMP Energy Pathway, which Egypt has joined with respect to the oil and gas sector.  The two leaders reaffirmed the U.S. and Egypt’s new partnership on Adaptation in Africa, which the U.S. and Egypt will co-lead, focused on delivering concrete initiatives that will improve people’s lives and help build resilience to a changing climate.  The leaders committed to convene the Joint U.S.-Egypt Climate Working Group as soon as possible.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What They Are Reading in the States: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Touts Historic Gun Law &#038; Rescue Plan Relief; Urges Passage of Semiconductor&#160;Bill</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/16/what-they-are-reading-in-the-states-biden-harris-administration-touts-historic-gun-law-rescue-plan-relief-urges-passage-of-semiconductor-bill/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 15:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[‘Biden signs landmark bipartisan gun measure, says &#8216;lives will be saved’’‘Wolf visits White House, says American Rescue Plan funds &#8216;greatly benefited&#8217; Pennsylvania&#8217;s workforce, COVID-19 economic recovery’‘Intel CEO, Commerce secretary push for Congress to act on aid package’ This week, Americans are reading about how Members of Congress, state and local leaders, gun violence survivors, families,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>‘Biden signs landmark bipartisan gun measure, says &#8216;lives will be saved’’<br>‘Wolf visits White House, says American Rescue Plan funds &#8216;greatly benefited&#8217; Pennsylvania&#8217;s workforce, COVID-19 economic recovery’<br>‘Intel CEO, Commerce secretary push for Congress to act on aid package’</em></p>



<p>This week, Americans are reading about how Members of Congress, state and local leaders, gun violence survivors, families, and advocates joined President Biden at a White House event commemorating the passage of the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act – the most significant legislation to reduce gun violence in 30 years.</p>



<p>Governors, mayors, and local leaders joined Vice President Harris, Labor Secretary Marty Walsh, American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling, and White House Office of Intergovernmental Affairs Director Julie Rodriguez for a White House American Rescue Plan Summit. Following the half-day Summit, elected officials spoke to local reports about how more than $40 billion of American Rescue Plan funds have been committed to strengthening and expanding our workforce in the states.</p>



<p>Infrastructure Coordinator Mitch Landrieu also traveled to Milwaukee, Wisconsin and spoke with local press outlets about President Biden&#8217;s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which is rebuilding infrastructure in the Badger State by improving roads and bridges, replacing lead pipes to provide clean water, expanding high speed internet, and creating millions of good-paying union jobs that don’t require a college degree.</p>



<p>And Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo led a White House Regional Press Call for reporters in Indiana, Missouri and Ohio to underscore the urgent need for Congress to pass the Bipartisan Innovation Act, which will spur American manufacturing, strengthen our supply chains, and help lower costs for families.</p>



<p>See a round-up of the local coverage below.</p>



<p><em><strong>President Biden Highlights Bipartisan Safer Communities Act &amp; Actions to Reduce Gun Violence at White House Event</strong></em></p>



<ul><li>Detroit News: <a href="https://www.detroitnews.com/story/news/politics/2022/06/25/biden-signs-landmark-bipartisan-gun-measure-says-lives-saved/7733468001/">Biden signs landmark bipartisan gun measure, says &#8216;lives will be saved&#8217;</a></li><li>Chicago Sun Times: <a href="https://chicago.suntimes.com/columnists/2022/7/11/23204282/white-house-gun-law-event-week-parade-massacre-biden-wears-highland-park-strong-ribbon">At White House gun law event a week after parade massacre, Biden wears ‘Highland Park Strong’ ribbon</a></li><li>Colorado Springs Gazette: <a href="https://gazette.com/news/us-world/u-s-president-biden-holds-event-to-mark-passage-of-gun-safety-law-at-the/image_365b7f83-bf28-5593-bcca-4c4cdfd3800f.html">U.S. President Biden holds event to mark passage of gun safety law at the White House in Washington</a></li><li>Orange County Register:<a href="https://www.ocregister.com/2022/07/11/biden-gun-violence-has-turned-communities-into-killing-fields/"> Biden: Gun violence has turned communities into ‘killing fields’</a></li><li>San Antonio Express: <a href="https://www.expressnews.com/news/legislature/article/Uvalde-doctor-historic-gun-law-17297251.php">Uvalde doctor who treated kids shot at Robb Elementary speaks as Biden Touts Historic Gun Law</a></li><li>St. Louis Post Dispatch: <a href="https://www.stltoday.com/news/local/govt-and-politics/st-louis-mayor-joins-biden-others-to-tout-new-federal-gun-law/article_f1f2c1e9-436f-566f-aa6a-9ee032e58ff4.html">St. Louis mayor joins Biden, others to tout new federal gun law</a></li><li>Kansas City Star: <a href="https://www.kansascity.com/news/politics-government/article263372273.html">‘It is astonishing to me’: KC mayor lauds federal gun law, decries Westport shooting</a></li><li>Colorado Public Radio: <a href="https://www.cpr.org/2022/07/11/columbine-aurora-shooting-victim-families-visit-white-house-for-first-gun-law-passage-in-decades/">Columbine, Aurora shooting victim families visit White House for first gun law passage in decades</a></li><li>WCTV (CBS Tallahassee, FL): <a href="https://www.wctv.tv/2022/07/11/tallahassee-mayor-attends-gun-legislation-event-dc/">Tallahassee mayor attends gun legislation event in D.C.</a></li><li>WSVN (FOX Miami, FL): <a href="https://wsvn.com/news/politics/several-families-of-parkland-shooting-victims-invited-to-signing-of-bipartisan-gun-safety-law/">Several families of Parkland shooting victims invited to signing of bipartisan gun safety law</a></li></ul>



<p><em><strong>Vice President Harris, Labor Secretary Walsh, American Rescue Plan Coordinator Sperling, and Local Leaders Tout American Rescue Plan Workforce Funding at White House Summit</strong></em></p>



<ul><li>Pittsburgh Post Gazette: <a href="https://www.post-gazette.com/news/politics-state/2022/07/13/wolf-visits-white-house-american-rescue-plan-pennsylvania-economic-recovery-workforce-covid-19/stories/202207130093">Wolf visits White House, says American Rescue Plan funds &#8216;greatly benefited&#8217; Pennsylvania&#8217;s workforce, COVID-19 economic recovery</a></li><li>News &amp; Observer: <a href="https://www.newsobserver.com/news/politics-government/article263395033.html">NC Gov. Cooper part of White House summit Wednesday</a></li><li>Commercial Appeal: <a href="https://www.commercialappeal.com/story/news/2022/07/12/memphis-mayor-jim-strickland-white-house-opportunity-r-3/10040839002/">Strickland headed to White House to tout youth initiative</a></li><li>Houston Chronicle: <a href="https://www.houstonchronicle.com/news/houston-texas/houston/article/Harris-County-expands-pilot-to-pay-homeless-15-17302984.php">Harris County expands pilot to pay homeless $15 to clean public spaces</a></li><li>WAVE (NBC Louisville, KY): <a href="https://www.wave3.com/2022/07/13/mayor-fischer-attends-arp-summit-white-house/">Mayor Fischer attends ARP Summit at White House</a></li><li>Spectrum: <a href="https://spectrumnews1.com/ky/louisville/news/2022/07/13/fischer-attends-white-house-summit-">Louisville mayor stresses importance of apprenticeships at White House summit</a></li><li>LA Daily News: <a href="https://www.dailynews.com/2022/07/12/la-county-supervisor-holly-mitchell-to-meet-with-vp-kamala-harris-at-white-house-wednesday/">LA County Supervisor Holly Mitchell to meet with VP Kamala Harris at White House Wednesday</a></li><li>WJET (ABC Erie, NY): <a href="https://www.yourerie.com/digital-first/digital-exclusive/erie-county-exec-davis-will-take-part-in-white-house-virtual-summit/">Erie County Exec Davis will take part in White House virtual summit</a></li><li>New Hampshire Union Leader: <a href="https://www.unionleader.com/news/politics/manchester-mayor-joyce-craig-headed-to-white-house-to-talk-up-phast-program/article_4692b759-e605-53bc-aa5c-2f38c18b0acf.html">Manchester Mayor Joyce Craig headed to White House to talk up PHAST program</a></li><li>St. Paul Pioneer Press: <a href="https://www.twincities.com/2022/07/12/ramsey-county-commissioner-mary-jo-mcguire-to-highlight-nursing-childcare-incentive-programs-at-white-house/">Ramsey County Commissioner Mary Jo McGuire to highlight nursing, childcare incentive programs at White House</a></li><li>Pittsburgh Post-Gazette: <a href="https://www.post-gazette.com/news/politics-state/2022/07/12/tom-wolf-to-visit-white-house-to-laud-federal-covid-19-relief-funds-for-pennsylvania-health-care-workforce/stories/202207120097">Wolf to visit White House to laud federal COVID-19 relief funds for Pennsylvania health care workforce</a></li><li>Buffalo News: <a href="https://buffalonews.com/news/local/at-white-house-summit-poloncarz-touts-erie-countys-effort-to-train-health-care-workers/article_fe847070-02dc-11ed-bdd4-d35fa3469679.html">At White House summit, Poloncarz touts Erie County&#8217;s effort to train health care workers</a></li><li> WHTM (ABC Harrisburg, PA): <a href="https://www.abc27.com/this-week-in-pennsylvania/pennsylvania-politics/pennsylvania-governor-tom-wolf-to-attend-white-house-arp-summit/">Pennsylvania Governor Tom Wolf attends White House ARPA Summit</a></li><li>WLKY (NBC Louisville, KY): <a href="https://www.wlky.com/article/mayor-fischer-white-house-summit-vice-president-harris/40605820">Mayor Fischer visits the White House, participates in summit with Vice President Harris</a></li><li>Erie News Now: <a href="https://www.erienewsnow.com/story/46876279/erie-county-executive-brenton-davis-participates-in-white-house-summit">Erie County Executive Brenton Davis Participates in White House Summit</a></li><li>The Daily Breeze: <a href="https://www.dailybreeze.com/2022/07/13/la-county-supervisor-holly-mitchell-speaks-at-white-house-panel-touts-equitable-job-creation-programs/">LA County Supervisor Holly Mitchell speaks at White House panel, touts equitable job creation programs</a></li><li>Twin Cities Pioneer Press: <a href="https://www.twincities.com/2022/07/13/st-paul-ramsey-county-partner-on-24-8-million-in-investments-for-young-workers/">St. Paul, Ramsey County partner on $24.8 million in investments for young workers</a></li></ul>



<p><em><strong>White House Infrastructure Coordinator Mitch Landrieu Touts the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s Investments in Milwaukee, WI</strong></em></p>



<ul><li>Milwaukee Journal Sentinel: <a href="https://www.jsonline.com/story/news/local/milwaukee/2022/07/12/white-house-infrastructure-czar-mitch-landrieu-visit-milwaukee-talk-lead-pipes/10038249002/">Biden&#8217;s infrastructure czar Mitch Landrieu visits Milwaukee as city aims to speed lead pipe replacements</a></li><li>WISN (ABC Milwaukee, WI): <a href="https://www.wisn.com/article/wisconsin-will-receive-dollar79-million-to-replace-lead-pipes/40603866">Wisconsin will receive $79 million to replace lead pipes</a></li><li>WITI (FOX Milwaukee, WI): <a href="https://www.fox6now.com/news/milwaukee-replacing-lead-laterals-federal-funds">Milwaukee replacing lead pipes; federal funds to help</a></li><li>WisPolitics.com: <a href="https://www.wispolitics.com/2022/wisconsin-afl-cio-welcomes-infrastructure-investment-as-white-house-infrastructure-coordinator-mitch-landrieu-visits-milwaukee/">Wisconsin AFL-CIO: Welcomes infrastructure investment as White House Infrastructure Coordinator Mitch Landrieu visits Milwaukee</a></li><li>Urban Milwaukee: <a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2022/07/13/biden-admins-infrastructure-czar-visits-milwaukee-to-tout-lead-lateral-replacement/">Biden’s Infrastructure Czar Visits City, Touts Lead Lateral Funding</a></li><li>UpNorthNews: <a href="https://upnorthnewswi.com/2022/07/14/white-house-official-talks-up-the-many-benefits-coming-to-wisconsin-from-bidens-infrastructure-law/">White House Official Talks Up the Many Benefits Coming to Wisconsin from Biden’s Infrastructure Law</a></li></ul>



<p><em><strong>Commerce Secretary Raimondo Underscores Urgent Need for Passage of the Bipartisan Innovation Act</strong></em></p>



<ul><li>Columbus Dispatch: <a href="https://www.dispatch.com/story/business/2022/07/15/intel-ceo-commerce-secretary-push-congress-act-aid-package/10067687002/">Intel CEO, Commerce secretary push for Congress to act on aid package</a></li><li>Cleveland Plain Dealer: <a href="https://www.cleveland.com/news/2022/07/semi-conductor-subsidy-bill-to-get-votes-next-week-commerce-secretary-urges-its-passage-to-enable-construction-of-new-intel-plant-in-ohio.html">Semi-conductor subsidy bill to get votes next week; Commerce Secretary urges its passage to enable construction of new Intel plant in Ohio</a></li><li>Idaho Statesman: Opinion: <a href="https://www.idahostatesman.com/opinion/readers-opinion/article263301548.html">Bipartisan Innovation Act would help Idaho semiconductor manufacturers be competitive</a></li><li>Nexstar: <a href="https://www.mystateline.com/news/washington-dc/us-leaders-stress-urgency-in-push-to-pass-semiconductor-legislation/">US leaders stress urgency in push to pass semiconductor legislation</a></li><li>Sinclair: <a href="https://katu.com/news/nation-world/biden-administration-pushes-congress-to-pass-chips-bill-for-national-security-gina-raimondo-lloyd-austin-commerce-department-defense-department-pentagon-semiconductors">Congress pushed to move on semiconductor bill to compete with China</a></li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan of the United Arab Emirates Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/16/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-mohamed-bin-zayed-al-nahyan-of-the-united-arab-emirates-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 14:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1:06 P.M. AST&#160;&#160;PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, folks, welcome.&#160; And we’re here with the President of the UAE.&#160; It’s really good to see you again, Sheikh Mohamed.&#160; Thank you.&#160;And after our virtual I2U2 Summit earlier this week, let me congratulate you again and &#8212; on your election as President of the UAE.&#160; And I look forward to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1:06 P.M. AST&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, folks, welcome.&nbsp; And we’re here with the President of the UAE.&nbsp; It’s really good to see you again, Sheikh Mohamed.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>And after our virtual I2U2 Summit earlier this week, let me congratulate you again and &#8212; on your election as President of the UAE.&nbsp; And I look forward to another period of strong and growing cooperation between our countries and under your leadership.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our relationship covers a wide array of things &#8212; everything from security to economic development to advancing cooperation in science, technology, and space.&nbsp; And we both understand that the challenge we face today will only make it a heck of a lot more important that we spend more time together.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to formally invite you to the States before &#8212; to the Oval &#8212; before this year is out.&nbsp; But &#8212; because we’re not going to get a lot of time, I know they tell me, to talk today.&nbsp; But I want to talk to you a lot &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; a lot of things I have to raise with you.<br>&nbsp;<br>But at any rate, thank you.&nbsp; And welcome.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIN ZAYED AL NAHYAN:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; It’s really my pleasure to meet you &#8212; to meet you today.&nbsp; We are very proud of the relationship we have.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And before I forget, I just want to thank you and the delegation you sent &#8212; the Vice President &#8212; during the ceremony we had.&nbsp; And condolences (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I’m sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIN ZAYED AL NAHYAN:&nbsp; I &#8212; I’m new in this job, but I’m working very hard to see how we can bridge the relationship with you and build a very strong bridge between our two countries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I’m new in this job too &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; so maybe we can do it quickly.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:09 P.M. AST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Amir Sheikh Tamim Bin Hamad Al Thani of&#160;Qatar</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/16/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-amir-sheikh-tamim-bin-hamad-al-thani-of-qatar-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 14:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57722</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today in Jeddah, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met with Amir Sheikh Tamim Bin Hamad Al Thani of Qatar.  The two leaders reaffirmed their desire to continue working together to address regional and global challenges and to deepen defense and security cooperation as Major Non-NATO Allies.  The two leaders also discussed Qatar’s preparations to host the 2022 World&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today in Jeddah, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met with Amir Sheikh Tamim Bin Hamad Al Thani of Qatar.  The two leaders reaffirmed their desire to continue working together to address regional and global challenges and to deepen defense and security cooperation as Major Non-NATO Allies.  The two leaders also discussed Qatar’s preparations to host the 2022 World Cup, and the importance of continuing to implement labor reforms in the lead up to this seminal event.  President Biden expressed appreciation for Qatar’s role in promoting security and stability for the Afghan people, and Qatar’s exceptional efforts in the evacuation of Afghans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with King Hamad bin Isa Al Khalifa of&#160;Bahrain</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/16/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-king-hamad-bin-isa-al-khalifa-of-bahrain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 13:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with King Hamad bin Isa Al Khalifa of Bahrain in Jeddah.  The President underscored the United States’ appreciation for the longstanding strategic partnership with Bahrain, including its hosting of the U.S. Navy Forces Central Command/5th Fleet.  The two leaders affirmed their commitment to strengthening defense, security, economic, commercial, and people-to-people ties. President Biden commended Bahrain’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with King Hamad bin Isa Al Khalifa of Bahrain in Jeddah.  The President underscored the United States’ appreciation for the longstanding strategic partnership with Bahrain, including its hosting of the U.S. Navy Forces Central Command/5<sup>th</sup> Fleet.  The two leaders affirmed their commitment to strengthening defense, security, economic, commercial, and people-to-people ties.<br><br>President Biden commended Bahrain’s expanded ties with Israel through the Abraham Accords and the Negev process. The two leaders discussed mutual efforts to foster regional integration and deepen security cooperation.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement Following Meeting of President Joseph R. Biden and His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan in&#160;Jeddah</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/16/joint-statement-following-meeting-of-president-joseph-r-biden-and-his-majesty-king-abdullah-ii-of-jordan-in-jeddah/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 13:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57716</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and His Majesty King Abdullah II met today in Jeddah and reaffirmed the enduring strength of the strategic friendship between the United States and Jordan. The meeting took place during the Summit of the leaders of the United States, the Gulf Cooperation Council members, Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan. The two leaders&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and His Majesty King Abdullah II met today in Jeddah and reaffirmed the enduring strength of the strategic friendship between the United States and Jordan. The meeting took place during the Summit of the leaders of the United States, the Gulf Cooperation Council members, Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan.<br> <br>The two leaders discussed efforts to further advance the close and historic partnership between the United States and Jordan, and coordination in addressing regional and international challenges. They noted the political and economic value of regional integration, for which Jordan can serve as an important hub for cooperation and investment in infrastructure, energy, water, food security and climate. The President noted the importance of the trilateral cooperation mechanism with Egypt and Iraq as an example of positive regional collaboration.<br><br>President Biden announced the intention of the United States to enter into a new memorandum of understanding (MOU) for assistance for Jordan, in which the United States plans to make a commitment to support the provision of no less than $1.45 billion per year in U.S. bilateral foreign assistance to Jordan, beginning in FY 2023 and ending in FY 2029. One of the most significant bilateral instruments of its kind, the MOU represents a major U.S. political commitment to Jordan’s stability and the durability of the partnership. The MOU is designed to address Jordan’s extraordinary needs, supports King Abdullah II’s economic reform program, and ensure the long-term strength of the close partnership between the United States and Jordan.<br><br>King Abdullah II thanked the President for the United States’ friendship and continued support for Jordan. He stressed the importance of this support to the Kingdom’s economic reform plans, its efforts to realize more sustainable economic growth, and to mitigate the impact of regional crises.<br> <br>President Biden reaffirmed the United States’ unwavering support to Jordan as a key ally and a force for peace in the region, and for King Abdullah II’s leadership.<br> <br>King Abdullah II underlined the crucial role of the United States in efforts to support regional security, stability, peace and prosperity.<br> <br>President Biden and King Abdullah II highlighted the strong defense partnership between the two countries, and reiterated commitment to their partnership in the fight against terrorism, including through cooperation within the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS and the Aqaba Process.<br><br>The two leaders reaffirmed their commitment to continue working for a just, lasting and comprehensive peace between Israel and the Palestinians on the basis of the two-state solution. They stressed the importance of fostering political and economic horizons through confidence-building measures that would set the ground for meaningful Palestinians-Israeli negotiations.  The also emphasized the importance of including the Palestinians in regional cooperation projects. The two leaders stressed the necessity of upholding the historic status quo in Jerusalem’s holy sites, and the President underlined the key role of the Hashemite Custodianship in that regard. King Abdullah II also expressed appreciation for U.S. support to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA). <br><br>Recalling United Nations General Assembly resolutions ES-11/1 and ES-11/2, on March 2 and March 24, respectively, demanding the Russian Federation to immediately, completely and unconditionally withdraw all of its military forces from the territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders, the two leaders reaffirmed their commitment to the sovereignty, independence, territorial integrity and unity of Ukraine. They condemned violations of international humanitarian law and violations of human rights in areas of conflict, calling for abiding by international humanitarian law. The leaders also confirmed their intention to increase cooperation to counter the impact of the conflict in Ukraine on global food and energy security.<br> <br>President Biden and King Abdullah II stressed the need to find a political solution to the Syrian crisis, consistent with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2254 (2015). President Biden expressed appreciation for Jordan’s hosting of Syrian refugees. His Majesty thanked the President for continued U.S. support to help Jordan in its efforts to meet the needs of refugees. The two leaders urged sufficient international support to refugees and host countries.<br> <br>The two leaders emphasized commitment to the stability and security of Iraq, and the need to protect the significant progress the country has made towards peace and stability.<br><br>The two leaders intend to remain in close consultation and further develop the deep friendship between the United States and Jordan.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the GCC + 3 Summit&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/16/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-gcc-3-summit-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 12:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2:09 P.M. AST&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, thank you.&#160; It’s good to be once more together with so many vital partners and to strengthening our cooperation on the future of this consequential region of the world. &#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; I’d like to thank our Saudi hosts for inviting the United States to join this summit and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>2:09 P.M. AST&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; It’s good to be once more together with so many vital partners and to strengthening our cooperation on the future of this consequential region of the world. &nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’d like to thank our Saudi hosts for inviting the United States to join this summit and for their hospitality in welcoming all of us.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A great deal has changed since I visited this region when I served as Vice President of the United States, both on the world stage and in the Middle East.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Around the world, we’re seeing efforts to undermine the rules-based order: with China’s increasingly coercive actions in the Indo-Pacific and beyond; with Russia’s brutal and unprovoked war against its neighboring Ukraine; and with Iran’s destabilizing activities. &nbsp;Here in the Middle East, we’ve also seen critical changes.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For the first time since 9/11, an American President is visiting this region without American troops being engaged in combat &#8212; in a combat mission in the region.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’ll always honor the bravery, the selfishness [sic] &#8212; selflessness of the &#8212; and the sacrifices of the Americans who served, including my son, Major Beau Biden, who was stationed in Iraq for a year.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we’ll never forget the memory of the seven thousand fifty- &#8212; 7,054 American troops who made the ultimate sacrifice while serving in Iraq, Afghanistan, and elsewhere over the last two decades.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But today, I am proud to be able to say that the era of land wars in the region &#8212; wars involving huge numbers of American forces &#8212; is not underway.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We &#8212; but we maintain both the capacity and the absolute determination to suppress the terrorist threat wherever we find it.&nbsp; We’ve demonstrated that this year &#8212; eliminating the Emir of ISIS on a daring operation, and just this week, taking out another key leader of ISIS.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re going to continue our counterterrorism efforts working with a broad coalition of countries, including everyone around this table.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we will turn our attention and our resources to supporting our partners, strengthening our alliances, and building coalitions to solve the problems facing this region and the world &#8212; and the world today.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States is clear-eyed about the challenges in the Middle East and about where we have the greatest capacity to help drive positive outcomes.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our objectives are focused on &#8212; are &#8212; excuse me, are focused, realistic, and achievable so that we can target our resources, rebuild trust, and deliver real results.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we will operate in the context of the Middle East as it is today: a region more united than it has been in years.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The GCC is a prime example of that.&nbsp; Former rivals have<br>reestablished diplomatic and economic ties.&nbsp; New memberships are being forged.&nbsp; And increasingly, the world is seeing the Mideast &#8212; the Middle East through the lens of opening and opportunity.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me state clearly that the United States is going to remain an active, engaged partner in the Middle East.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As the world grows more competitive and the challenges we face more complex, it is only becoming clearer to me that &#8212; how closely interwoven America’s interests are with the successes of the Middle East.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We will not walk away and leave a vacuum to be filled by China, Russia, or Iran.&nbsp; And we’ll seek to build on this moment with active, principled American leadership.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our new framework for the Middle East has five key principles, and I’d like to very briefly share them with you today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, the United States will support and strengthen partnerships with countries that subscribe to the rules-based international order.&nbsp; And we will make sure that these &#8212; those countries can defend themselves against foreign threats.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States and each of the countries around this table are an essential part of that order because we reject the use of brute force to change borders.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When the entire GCC, plus Egypt and Jordan, voted in the United Nations General Assembly to condemn Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, it was a watershed moment.&nbsp; It showed that the core values of sovereignty and territorial integrity are truly universal.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to be clear: Supporting a rules-based order doesn’t mean we always have to agree on every issue, but it does mean we align around core principles that allow us to work together on the most pressing global challenges.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For example, on food security, we are collectively committing billions of dollars to alleviate the crisis here in the region, with more than $1 billion coming from the United States.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On energy security, we agree on the need to ensure adequate supplies to meet global needs.&nbsp; Energy producers have already increased production, and I look forward to seeing what’s coming in the &#8212; in the coming months.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the climate crisis, we’re collectively investing hundreds of billions of dollars in clean energy initiatives, increasing our climate ambition, and working together to diversify supply chains and invest in critical infrastructure.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we’re looking forward to Egypt and the UAE hosting the next two major U.N. climate conferences.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, the United States will not allow &#8212; will not allow foreign or regional powers to jeopardize the freedom of navigation through the Middle East’s waterways, including the Strait of Hormuz and the Bab al-Mandab.&nbsp; Nor will we tolerate efforts by any country to dominate another in the region through military buildups, incursions, and/or threats.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The free flow of commerce and resources through the Middle East is the lifeblood of a global economy.&nbsp; That’s as true today as it been &#8212; as it has been for decades.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when nations adhere to international rules, it works.&nbsp; So my administration has made it a priority to protect those vital waterways.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’ve established a new naval task force to work in partnership with many of your navies to help secure the Red Sea.&nbsp; That includes the first naval task force to use&nbsp;<s>multi-manned</s>&nbsp;[un-manned] surface vessels and artificial intelligence technology to enhance marine &#8212; maritime awareness.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re also integrating air defenses and early warning systems to ensure that we can defeat airborne threats.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Third, the United States will not just aim to deter threats of regional &#8212; to regional stability; we will work to reduce tensions, de-escalate, and end conflicts wherever possible.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This approach is already reaping dividends.&nbsp; As was mentioned: In Yemen, working closely with Saudi Arabia, Oman, the UAE, and the U.N., we forged a truce that is now in its 15th week.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’ve welcomed the leadership Of Iraqi Prime Minister Kadhimi to bring countries from the nei- &#8212; from the neighbor- &#8212; from the region together for talks in Baghdad.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks to the months of quiet, persistent diplomacy, we helped finalize an agreement to remove international peacekeepers from Tiran Island in the Red Sea, and transform an area that once sparked wars into a future hub of peaceful tourism and economic development.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as we continue to work closely with many of you to counter the threats posed by &#8212; posed to the region by Iran, we’re also pursuing diplomacy to return constraints on Iran’s nuclear program.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But no matter what, the United States is committed to ensuring that Iran never gets a nuclear weapon.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fourth, the United States will build political, economic, and security connections between the United States &#8212; between the U.S. partners wherever possible, while respecting each country’s sovereignty and independent choices.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Integration, interconnection &#8212; these are the underlying themes of our meeting today.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How many years have we been trying to connect Iraq’s electricity to the &#8212; to the G- &#8212; to the GCC grids?&nbsp; I remember being briefed on it in 19- &#8212; in 2016, when I was Vice President of the United States.&nbsp; I said, “Let’s get it done.”</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, today, finally, after years of failed efforts and false starts, thanks to the efforts of so many around this table, it’s done.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; New energy projects linking the region, a new free trade deal and investments between neighbors, like the Saudi investments in Egypt and Jordan.&nbsp; The more we build these connections, the more we’ll see the benefits that return to our peoples and will grow.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fifth, the United States will always promote human rights and the values enshrined in the U.N. Charter.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Foundational freedoms are foundational to who we are as Americans.&nbsp; It’s in our DNA.&nbsp; But it’s also because we know that fai- &#8212; that the future will be won by the countries that unleash the full potential of their populations, where women can exercise equal rights and contribute to building stronger economies, resilient societies, and more modern and capable militaries; where citizens can question and criticize their leaders without fear of reprisal.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’ve gotten plenty of criticism over the years.&nbsp; It’s not fun.&nbsp; But the ability to speak openly and exchange ideas freely is what unlocks innovation.&nbsp; Accountable ins- &#8212; accountable institutions that are free from corruption, that act transparently, and respect the rule of law are the best way to deliver growth, respond to people’s needs, and, I believe, ensure justice.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And no country gets it right all the time &#8212; even most of the time &#8212; including the United States.&nbsp; But our people are our strength.&nbsp; Our countries, with the confidence to learn from their mistakes, grow stronger.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So let me conclude by summing all this up in one sentence: The United States is invested in building a positive future in the region, in partnership with all of you, and the United States is not going anywhere.<br><br>This is a table full of probi- &#8212; problem solvers.&nbsp; There are a lot of &#8212; there’s a lot of good we can do if we do it together.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you again for inviting me to participate in this summit today, and thank you for the many years of partnership between your countries and the United States.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;2:20 P.M. AST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement Following Meeting Between President&#160;Biden and Iraqi Prime Minister Kadhimi in&#160;Jeddah</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/16/joint-statement-following-meeting-between-president-biden-and-iraqi-prime-minister-kadhimi-in-jeddah/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 09:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden Jr. met today with Prime Minister Mustafa Al-Kadhimi of Iraq in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, in a bilateral meeting during the Summit of the United States and the Gulf Cooperation Council and Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan.&#160; During the meeting, the two leaders reaffirmed their shared commitment to the strong bilateral partnership between&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden Jr. met today with Prime Minister Mustafa Al-Kadhimi of Iraq in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, in a bilateral meeting during the Summit of the United States and the Gulf Cooperation Council and Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan.&nbsp; During the meeting, the two leaders reaffirmed their shared commitment to the strong bilateral partnership between Iraq and the United States under the Strategic Framework Agreement and their determination to continue security coordination to ensure that ISIS can never resurge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden and Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi also consulted on a range of regional issues.&nbsp; The leaders agreed that the relationship between the U.S. and Iraq is based on a shared interest in Iraq’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, security, and stability and committed to bolstering the bilateral partnership for the benefit of their two nations.</p>



<p>They also reaffirmed the importance of forming a new Iraqi government responsive to the will of the Iraqi people and their respect for Iraq’s democracy and independence. &nbsp;President Biden underscored the importance the United States places on a stable, united, sovereign, and prosperous Iraq, to include Iraq’s Kurdistan region.</p>



<p><strong><u>Strategic Framework Agreement</u></strong></p>



<p>The President and Prime Minister renewed their commitment to the Strategic Framework Agreement for a Relationship of Friendship and Cooperation between the United States and the Republic of Iraq, which guides the overall political, economic, cultural, and security relationship between the two countries.&nbsp; President Biden reiterated his support to Iraq in its fight against terrorism and emphasized that a strong Iraq capable of self-defense is essential for achieving stability in the region.</p>



<p>The President and the Prime Minister also reinforced the importance of strengthening Iraq’s democratic institutions, to include empowering Iraqi security forces, to advance security and stability in Iraq and the region.&nbsp; President Biden expressed appreciation for Iraq’s efforts to repatriate and rehabilitate Iraqi families and children as well as to prosecute Iraqi ISIS fighters from Syria and welcomed further cooperation to address this critical issue.&nbsp; Both leaders agreed that close cooperation on military and security issues and overall support for Iraq against terrorism was critical to ensure the enduring defeat of ISIS.</p>



<p><strong><u>Promoting Stability</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden and Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi discussed the important role of Iraq in the region, especially in facilitating communication and building confidence among the countries of the region. &nbsp;President Biden particularly commended the significant diplomatic efforts led by Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi to foster a more stable, prosperous, and interconnected region. &nbsp;The historic new agreements between Iraq and the GCC Interconnection Authority will bring affordable energy to Iraq and help meet the needs of the Iraqi people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden reaffirmed the importance to the United States of building a prosperous and diversified economy in Iraq that is integrated in the regional and global economic system and capable of meeting the essential needs of the Iraqi people.&nbsp; The President and the Prime Minister highlighted the importance of fighting corruption to both build public trust in Iraqi institutions and to support economic growth. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The President and Prime Minister discussed efforts to collectively advance sustainable development of the region’s resources, to address the impacts of climate change including water insecurity, and to expand U.S.-Iraq coordination on energy modernization and economic reform.</p>



<p>President Biden also welcomed Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi’s initiative to bring Saudi Arabia and Iran together for talks in Baghdad.&nbsp; The President expressed his appreciation for the Prime Minister’s forward-thinking diplomacy in the interest of a safer, more stable region.&nbsp; He also commended the Baghdad Summit, and the unique relationship between Iraq, Jordan, and Egypt, which the United States stands ready to support.</p>



<p>Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi emphasized his commitment to pursuing initiatives to bring together Iraq’s neighbors and friends to find home-grown solutions for regional challenges and to achieve sustainable stability.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement From Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on the Passing of the Women’s Health Protection Act and the Ensuring Access to Abortion&#160;Act </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-passing-of-the-womens-health-protection-act-and-the-ensuring-access-to-abortion-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 01:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57689</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, we’ve seen the deeply different approaches that Congressional Democrats and Congressional Republicans have for women’s health. Today, House Democrats took an important step in passing the Women’s Health Protection Act and Ensuring Access to Abortion Act. These bills would ensure women’s access to essential health care services, regardless of where they live, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, we’ve seen the deeply different approaches that Congressional Democrats and Congressional Republicans have for women’s health. Today, House Democrats took an important step in passing the Women’s Health Protection Act and Ensuring Access to Abortion Act. These bills would ensure women’s access to essential health care services, regardless of where they live, and protect the bedrock right to cross state lines for medical care. A majority of Americans across the country support them. Every single Republican voted against the bill to codify women’s right to choose and nearly every single House Republican voted against the right to travel. Senate Republicans blocked a similar bill that would make the right to travel to access medical care a law. It’s extreme and it’s out of touch.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Jeddah Communique:  A Joint Statement Between the United&#160;States of America and the Kingdom of Saudi&#160;Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/the-jeddah-communique-a-joint-statement-between-the-united-states-of-america-and-the-kingdom-of-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 23:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jeddah, Saudi Arabia At the invitation of the Custodian of the Two Holy Mosques, King Salman Bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud, President Joseph R. Biden conducted an official visit to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia July 15-16, 2022.  Following the meeting with King Salman, President Biden and Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman held an official meeting, attended&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Jeddah, Saudi Arabia</strong></p>



<p>At the invitation of the Custodian of the Two Holy Mosques, King Salman Bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud, President Joseph R. Biden conducted an official visit to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia July 15-16, 2022.  Following the meeting with King Salman, President Biden and Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman held an official meeting, attended by senior officials from both sides. The two sides reviewed in detail the many shared priorities that contribute to the partnership between the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United States.</p>



<p>At the end of this meeting, the two sides issued this communique outlining the strategic partnership between the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United States over the coming decades with the aim of advancing their mutual interests and advancing a common vision for a more peaceful, secure, prosperous, and stable Middle East.</p>



<p><strong><u>Strategic Partnership</u></strong></p>



<p>The two sides reviewed the historical relations and partnership between the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United States of America that was established nearly eight decades ago with the meeting between King Abdulaziz Al-Saud and President Franklin D. Roosevelt on board the USS Quincy. They underscored the importance of continuing to strengthen their strategic partnership to serve the interests of the governments and peoples of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United States. The two sides also emphasized the pivotal role this historic partnership has played in promoting regional stability and prosperity. They stressed that the U.S.-Saudi partnership has been a cornerstone of regional security over decades, and affirmed that the two countries share a vision of a more secure, stable, and prosperous region, interconnected with the world.</p>



<p>The two sides affirmed the importance of resolving international disputes through peaceful and diplomatic means, and alleviating humanitarian crises through economic and financial support to the region’s countries most in need. They affirmed the importance of the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity. They stressed the need for supporting governments in the region facing threats from terrorists or proxy groups backed by outside powers.</p>



<p>The two sides noted the historic ties between the peoples of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United Stated. They welcomed, in this regard, extending the validity of business and tourism visas to 10 years to facilitate closer people-to-people ties and economic cooperation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The two sides then reviewed cooperation and achievements in the following areas:</p>



<p><strong>Energy Security and Climate Cooperation</strong></p>



<p>The two sides underscored the importance of strategic economic and investment cooperation, particularly in light of the current crisis in Ukraine and its consequences, and reaffirmed their commitment to a stable global energy market.&nbsp; The U.S. welcomed Saudi Arabia’s commitment to support global oil markets balancing for sustained economic growth.&nbsp; Both sides decided to consult regularly on global energy markets in the near- and long-term, as well as work together as strategic partners in climate and energy transition initiatives, recognizing Saudi Arabia’s leading role in the future of energy.</p>



<p>The U.S. side commended the Saudi Green Initiative and Middle East Green Initiative, and welcomed Saudi Arabia’s participation at the recent Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate, joining of the Global Methane Pledge, its status as a founding member of the Net-Zero Producers Forum, and the Kingdom’s announcement to meet fifty percent of its electricity generation from renewables by 2030.</p>



<p>The two sides welcomed the finalization of a Partnership Framework for Advancing Clean Energy, with substantial investments in clean energy transition and addressing climate change, with particular focus on renewable energy, clean hydrogen, human capacity-building in the nuclear energy field, and cooperation in nuclear-regulatory aspects, carbon capture utilization and sequestration, development of sustainable materials, and other initiatives&nbsp;under the Circular Carbon Economy Framework, where Saudi Arabia aims to be a global leader..</p>



<p><strong>Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment (PGII)</strong></p>



<p>The two sides emphasized that the energy transition and the national security of both countries require stable and diversified supply chains, and in this regard, the United States welcomed Saudi Arabia’s support for the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment, which President Biden announced at the G7 Summit on June 26, 2022. Through this historic partnership, the United States and Saudi Arabia aim to strategically invest in projects that support digital connectivity, supply chain sustainability, and climate and energy security focused on low- and middle-income countries.</p>



<p><strong>Security and Defense</strong></p>



<p>President Biden strongly affirmed the United States’ continued commitment to supporting Saudi Arabia’s security and territorial defense, and facilitating the Kingdom’s ability to obtain necessary capabilities to defend its people and territory against external threats.</p>



<p>The two sides underscored the need to further deter Iran’s interference in the internal affairs of other countries, its support for terrorism through its armed proxies, and its efforts to destabilize the security and stability of the region.&nbsp; The Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United States stressed the importance of preventing Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p>Both sides stressed the importance of preserving the free flow of commerce through strategic international waterways like the Bab al-Mandab and the Strait of Hormuz.&nbsp; They welcomed the newly-established Combined Task Force 153 with a focus on the Red Sea’s Bab al-Mandab passageway and further deterring illicit smuggling into Yemen.&nbsp; They also welcomed Saudi Arabia’s assumption of command of Combined Task Force 150, which reinforces shared maritime security objectives in the Gulf of Oman and North Arabian Sea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To improve and streamline the exchange of information in the maritime domain, cooperation between the Royal Saudi Naval Forces and Combined Task Force 153 will be enhanced in the regionally-networked coordination center led out of the U.S. Fifth Fleet Headquarters in Bahrain.&nbsp; The United States also emphasized the growing cooperation between the Royal Saudi Naval Forces and U.S. Fifth Fleet’s Task Force 59, which leads an expanding fleet of cutting edge, integrated unmanned surface vessels using artificial intelligence to improve maritime security and domain awareness in support of regional security.</p>



<p><strong>5G/6G Open-RAN Cooperation</strong></p>



<p>The two sides welcomed a new Memorandum of Cooperation that will connect U.S. and Saudi technology companies in the advancement and deployment of 5G using open radio access networks, enable the development of 6G through similar technologies, an advance partnerships in cloud&nbsp;infrastructure and related technologies. The partnerships built under the MOU confirms Saudi Arabia’s leadership as a regional hub for 5G deployments and 6G future developments.</p>



<p><strong>Cybersecurity</strong></p>



<p>The two sides emphasized their mutual cooperation in the field of cybersecurity and its importance to protect the vital interests and national security of both countries. &nbsp;&nbsp;The United States and Saudi Arabia welcomed the recent signing of memoranda of understanding on cybersecurity cooperation and decided to continue strengthening real-time information sharing, building human and technical capabilities, and cybersecurity industry development.</p>



<p><strong>Space Exploration</strong></p>



<p>The two sides further welcomed the enhancement of cooperation in all fields of space exploration, including human spaceflight, earth observation, commercial and regulatory development, and responsible behavior in outer space.&nbsp; President Biden welcomed the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia signing the Artemis Accords and applauded the Kingdom for affirming its commitment to the responsible, peaceful, and sustainable exploration and use of outer space.</p>



<p><strong>Development of Tiran Island</strong></p>



<p>President Biden welcomed the arrangements by Saudi Arabia to remove the Multinational Force and Observers (MFO) from the Island of Tiran, including the removal of U.S. troops there as part of the MFO mission, while preserving and continuing all existing commitments and procedures in the area. &nbsp;This area of the Red Sea will now be developed for tourism and economic purposes, contributing to a more secure, peaceful, and prosperous region.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Expanding Overflights</strong></p>



<p>Within the framework of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia&#8217;s keenness to fulfill its obligations under the Chicago Convention of 1944, which stipulates non-discrimination between civil aircraft used in international air navigation, the Saudi General Authority for Civil Aviation (GACA) announced its decision to open the Kingdom&#8217;s airspace for all air carriers that meet the requirements of GACA to fly over the Kingdom’s airspace. &nbsp;The United States welcomed this announcement, which will enhance global air connectivity and help cement the Kingdom’s position as a global hub connecting Africa, Asia, and Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Vision 2030</strong></p>



<p>The U.S. welcomed the Kingdom’s Vision 2030, its blueprint for transformative economic and social reforms, and its efforts to increase women’s economic participation and promote interfaith dialogue.&nbsp; Saudi Arabia welcomed greater U.S. private sector investment in the Kingdom, as well as increasing Saudi investments in the American private sector for the benefit of both countries.</p>



<p>The U.S. side welcomed Saudi Arabia’s bid to host World Expo in 2030, and other events to be held over the course of that milestone year, the culmination of Saudi Arabia’s Vision 2030 reform program. &nbsp;The Saudi side noted the importance for the region of the World Cup being hosted by Qatar later this year and welcomed the United States serving as host for the World Cup in 2026.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Regional Cooperation</u></strong></p>



<p>The two sides then addressed particular regional and global issues, including:</p>



<p><strong>Yemen</strong></p>



<p>Both sides affirmed their strong support for the UN-brokered truce in Yemen and stressed the importance of&nbsp;extending the truce and&nbsp;making progress to transform the truce into a lasting peace agreement. President Biden expressed his appreciation for the role King Salman and Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman have played in achieving and renewing the truce.&nbsp; The two sides stressed their long-stated goal to end the war in Yemen, and called on the international community to take a unified position calling on the Houthis to return to peace talks under the auspices of the United Nations based on the three references, including UN Security Council Resolution 2216 (2015).&nbsp; Only a political agreement between the Yemeni parties can durably resolve the conflict and reverse the dire humanitarian crisis.</p>



<p>The two sides also affirmed their support for Yemen&#8217;s Presidential Leadership Council and thanked the Council for its commitment&nbsp;to the truce and steps that have improved the lives of Yemenis across the country, including facilitating fuel imports and restarting flights from Sana’a.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They also stressed the need to remove all impediments to the flow of essential goods and&nbsp;delivery of aid inside Yemen, and the importance&nbsp;of the Houthis&nbsp;opening&nbsp;the main roads to Taiz – Yemen’s third largest city which has been under siege conditions since 2015.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Saudi Arabia and the United States encouraged all regional actors to fully support the truce, which has resulted in the longest period of peace in Yemen in six years.&nbsp;Saudi Arabia welcomed the United States’ support of the truce and its contribution to the efforts to advance the political process in Yemen.</p>



<p><strong>Iraq</strong></p>



<p>President Biden welcomed the leading role played by the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia in strengthening relations with Republic of Iraq, and the historic agreements to be signed on the margins of the Jeddah Security and Development Summit on July 16, 2022, to link the electricity networks of Saudi Arabia and the Gulf Cooperation Council countries to the Iraqi grid, in order to provide Iraq and its people with new and diversified electricity sources.</p>



<p><strong>Israel-Palestinian Issues</strong></p>



<p>Regarding Israel-Palestinian issues, the two sides underscored their enduring commitment to a two-state solution, wherein a sovereign and contiguous Palestinian state lives side-by-side in peace and security with Israel, as the only way to resolve the Israeli-Palestinian conflict in accordance with the internationally-recognized parameters and the Arab Peace Initiative.&nbsp; The leaders noted their determination to remain closely coordinated on efforts to encourage the parties to demonstrate – through policies and actions – their commitment to a two-state solution. The United States and Saudi Arabia welcomed all efforts that contribute to reaching a just and comprehensive peace in the region.</p>



<p><strong>Syria</strong></p>



<p>The two sides reiterated their commitment to preserving the unity, stability, and territorial integrity of Syria and expressed their support for the efforts of the Special Envoy of the Secretary-General of the United Nations to reach a political solution to the conflict consistent with the formula outlined in the UN Security Council Resolution 2254 (2015), stressing at the same time the need to prevent renewed of violence, to maintain established ceasefires, and to allow the unhindered delivery of humanitarian aid to all Syrians in need.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Lebanon</strong></p>



<p>The two sides affirmed their continued support for Lebanon’s sovereignty, security and stability, and their support for the Lebanese Armed Forces that protect its borders and resist the threats of violent extremist and terrorist groups. They also noted the importance of forming a Lebanese government and implementing comprehensive structural political and economic reforms to ensure that Lebanon overcomes its political and economic crisis, and that it does not become a launching point for terrorists, drug smuggling, or other criminal activities that threatens the stability and security of the region.</p>



<p>They emphasized the importance of the control of the government of Lebanon over all Lebanese territory, including with reference to fulfilling the provisions of the relevant UN Security Council resolutions and the Taif Accord, and for it to exercise full sovereignty, so there will be no weapons without the consent of the government of Lebanon or authority other than that of the government of Lebanon.</p>



<p><strong>Ukraine</strong></p>



<p>The two sides underscored that a rules-based order lies at the heart of international security, emphasizing the importance of the respect for international law, territorial integrity, and national sovereignty.&nbsp; They reaffirmed the principles as set forth in the March 2, 2022, UN General Assembly Resolution ES-11/1, endorsed by all GCC members.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The leaders reaffirmed their commitment to providing critical assistance to the Ukrainian people, and to ensure the unhindered export of grain and wheat products to alleviate the global food crises, which threatens to acutely impact a number of Middle Eastern and African states.</p>



<p><strong>Sudan</strong></p>



<p>The two sides underscored the importance of the dialogue between Sudanese parties and reviving the political process.&nbsp; They commended the efforts made by the United Nations Mission to support the return to the foundations of a political solution in Sudan, and expressed their satisfaction with the active role of the Quad for Sudan, wishing Sudan and its people peace and prosperity.</p>



<p><strong>Libya</strong></p>



<p>Both sides affirmed their support for the Libyan people as they engage in the UN-brokered political process to prepare for presidential and parliamentary elections as soon as possible.&nbsp; They expressed their full support for the Libyan ceasefire agreement concluded on October 23, 2020 and the Libyan call for the complete departure of foreign forces, foreign fighters, and mercenaries without further delay, in accordance with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2570 (2021).&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Afghanistan</strong></p>



<p>The two sides stressed the need to support Afghanistan’s security and to address the threat posed by Afghanistan-based terrorists. They also underscored the importance of continuing to support humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan.&nbsp; They expressed support for addressing the needs and promoting the rights of the Afghan people including the rights of women and girls to education and enjoyment of the highest attainable standard of health and, for women, the right to work.</p>



<p><strong>Counter-Terrorism</strong></p>



<p>The two sides underscored the importance of confronting terrorism and violent extremism. They expressed their continued commitment to countering al-Qaeda and ISIS, stemming the flow of foreign fighters, countering violent extremist propaganda, and cutting off terrorist financing streams.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The two sides highlighted the joint efforts through the Terrorist Financing Targeting Center, which is based in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; They reviewed and commended the exceptional success of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS, established in Jeddah in 2014, and stressed the need for this coalition to continue, and to make long-term and multi-year efforts to return both detained ISIS fighters and the tens of thousands of ISIS family members from northeastern Syria to their home countries. &nbsp;They welcomed the next Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS ministerial meeting to be held in Saudi Arabia in early 2023.</p>



<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>



<p>The two sides decided to expand and strengthen bilateral cooperation in all areas discussed in this meeting, prior to the next annual Strategic Dialogue between Saudi Arabia and the United States to be held in the Kingdom later this year.&nbsp; This Jeddah Communique should form the basis of work going forward to consolidate and enhance the strategic partnership between the two countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
