<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 20:23:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Johnson of the United&#160;Kingdom</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/14/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-johnson-of-the-united-kingdom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 20:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom. The leaders discussed their recent diplomatic engagements with Ukraine and Russia. They also reviewed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders and reaffirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. They&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom. The leaders discussed their recent diplomatic engagements with Ukraine and Russia. They also reviewed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders and reaffirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. They discussed efforts to reinforce the defensive posture on NATO’s eastern flank and underlined the continued close coordination among Allies and partners, including on readiness to impose severe consequences on Russia should it choose further military escalation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Celebrates First Anniversary of the Reestablishment of the White&#160;House Office of Faith-Based and Neighborhood&#160;Partnerships</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/14/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-celebrates-first-anniversary-of-the-reestablishment-of-the-white-house-office-of-faith-based-and-neighborhood-partnerships/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 18:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47242</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Partnerships have helped heal, unite, and rebuild, with expanded collaborations expected in the year ahead&#160; A year ago today, President Biden signed an executive order reestablishing the White House Office of Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships and urged the Office to “work with leaders of different faiths and backgrounds who are the frontlines of their communities&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Partnerships have helped heal, unite, and rebuild, with expanded collaborations expected in the year ahead&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>A <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/02/14/fact-sheet-president-biden-reestablishes-the-white-house-office-of-faith-based-and-neighborhood-partnerships/">year ago today</a>, President Biden signed an executive order reestablishing the White House Office of Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships and urged the Office to “work with leaders of different faiths and backgrounds who are the frontlines of their communities in crisis and who can help us heal, unite, and rebuild.” In keeping with its proud bipartisan tradition, the Office’s mission is to promote partnerships to serve people in need by working with interested religious and secular leaders and organizations.<br><br>To advance this mission, the White House Office has worked closely with agency Centers for Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships at the Departments of Health and Human Services (HHS), Homeland Security (DHS), Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Agriculture (USDA), Veterans Affairs (VA), and Education (ED); the United States Agency for International Development (USAID); and the Small Business Administration (SBA); as well as staff at AmeriCorps, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and the Departments of Treasury (UST) and Commerce (DOC). In turn, this team has partnered with faith and community leaders across the nation and around the world.</p>



<p>Our country has made great progress thanks to neighborhood partnerships and compassionate leaders of all faiths and beliefs, whether it was hosting vaccination clinics, preventing evictions, helping to ensure that children get back to school and workers get jobs, or countless other acts of service. The Biden-Harris Administration is also working tirelessly to advance policies promoting religious equity, diversity, inclusion, and accessibility and protecting the fundamental right to practice faith without fear, especially in light of the troubling rise of antisemitic, xenophobic, and bigoted attacks against people of faith—targeting synagogues, predominantly Black churches, and Muslim and Sikh communities, among other communities. In addition, the Administration has prioritized the cultivation of a spirit of welcome for people of all religious, political, and ideological stripes; a commitment to treating everyone with equal respect and dignity; and the hard but essential work of building bridges across differences in background and beliefs.<br><br>Administration achievements that advance these partnerships and policies include:<br><br><strong>Addressing the COVID-19 Pandemic and Boosting Economic Recovery</strong><br></p>



<ul><li><a href="https://religionnews.com/2021/03/16/why-we-need-to-work-with-houses-of-worship-on-covid-19-vaccinations/">Strongly advocated</a> for <a href="https://religionnews.com/2021/03/17/fauci-and-collins-join-interfaith-leaders-at-cathedral-vaccine-confidence-event/">collaborations</a> <a href="https://religionnews.com/2021/05/27/faith-government-health-leaders-collaborate-for-next-stage-of-vaccine-push/">between the government and faith and community organizations</a> to convey the facts about the COVID-19 virus and the vaccine and widely promoted <a href="https://globalhealthc3.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GHC3_WAC-Facilitating-COVID-Vaccine-Access-v2.pdf">guidance</a> for faith and community leaders on how to organize vaccination clinics.</li><li>Encouraged greater faith and community involvement in vaccinations through visits by <a href="https://religionnews.com/2021/04/07/biden-says-seminary-covid-19-vaccine-clinic-is-example-of-america-at-its-finest/">President Biden</a> and <a href="https://news.yahoo.com/jill-biden-dr-fauci-visit-214156010.html">the First Lady</a> to pop-up vaccination clinics in houses of worship.</li><li>Enlisted diverse faith and community leaders as founding members of <a href="https://wecandothis.hhs.gov/members-covid-19-community-corps">COVID Community Corps</a>, the group committed to taking action to encourage their families, friends, and members of their communities to get vaccinated for COVID-19. Faith and community partners account for close to a third of all founding Corps members.</li><li>Identified, scheduled, coordinated, and monitored volunteers as they facilitated <a href="https://www.fema.gov/blog/voluntary-organizations-play-crucial-role-femas-response-covid">more than 300,000 COVID-19 vaccinations throughout the nation</a>.</li><li>Worked with faith and community groups to publicize <a href="https://www.covidtests.gov/">COVIDtests.gov</a> and distributed millions of face coverings to community and faith-based partners in line with the Center for Disease Control’s (CDC’s) COVID-19 prevention recommendations.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Produced and promoted videos to address vaccine concerns featuring faith and community leaders, including “<a href="https://youtu.be/OKXi7lEwajA">Trusted Voices on COVID-19 Vaccine Acceptance: Reverend Walter Kim</a>,” and <a href="https://fb.watch/b2ECgyuvJT/">Facebook Live with My Halal Kitchen</a> by Yvonne Maffei.</li><li>Promoted the adoption of best practices on COVID-19 through webinars such as <a href="https://www.fema.gov/event/impact-federal-faith-and-community-partnership-frontlines-covid-19-vaccine-distribution">The Impact of Federal, Faith and Community Partnership on the Frontlines of COVID-19 Vaccine Distribution</a>.</li><li>Met with faith-based and community partners to discuss the COVID-19 pandemic and its impact on students’ <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-releases-new-resource-supporting-child-and-student-social-emotional-behavioral-and-mental-health-during-covid-19-era?utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_name=&amp;utm_source=govdelivery&amp;utm_term">social, emotional, and academic needs</a>.</li><li>Provided weekly updates for faith and community leaders on vaccine safety and COVID-19 variants; how to host vaccination clinics and promote vaccination in communities; and on COVID-19 treatment and calls for plasma donations.</li><li>Conducted more than a dozen trainings for hundreds of faith-based and community-based organizations on the <a href="https://www.childtaxcredit.gov/">Child Tax Credit</a>, and connected congregations and nonprofits around the country with multilingual toolkits and resources to help members of their communities access this tax credit and other American Rescue Plan relief programs.</li><li>Helped prevent evictions by increasing awareness of the <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/coronavirus/assistance-for-state-local-and-tribal-governments/emergency-rental-assistance-program">Emergency Rental Assistance Program</a> (ERAP) among faith and community leaders across the nation, including outreach commitments from more than 250 faith and community partners representing reach to more than 5 million people. Also encouraged more than 850 faith and community leaders to make sure landlords in their communities know how to connect renters to supports available through ERAP and the <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/coronavirus/mortgage-and-housing-assistance/renter-protections/find-help-with-rent-and-utilities/">Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</a>.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Increasing Opportunity and Mobility for Historically Disadvantaged Communities and Combatting Systematic Racism</strong><br></p>



<ul><li>As part of its equity focus, AmeriCorps awarded grants to support projects aimed at removing structural racial inequities, advancing racial equality, and increasing economic opportunity in order to achieve sustainable change in communities.</li><li>Deployed to several disasters, including <a href="https://www.wwltv.com/article/news/local/lafourche-terrebonne/fema-working-with-churches-community-groups-to-better-serve-hurricane-ida-victims/289-b0bba719-bb05-494a-9b54-bf536e736f8a">Hurricane Ida</a> and the <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/jose-diaz-balart/watch/behind-the-recovery-effort-to-aid-those-effected-by-deadly-tornadoes-128793669899">Kentucky tornadoes</a>, to help facilitate response and recovery efforts. This included engaging underrepresented communities and amplifying FEMA’s policy to <a href="https://www.fema.gov/emergency-managers/national-preparedness/equity">advance equity for disaster survivors</a>, which includes <a href="https://www.fema.gov/press-release/20210902/fema-makes-changes-individual-assistance-policies-advance-equity-disaster">improving&nbsp;access to disaster assistance for underserved communities</a>.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Led efforts to bolster engagement in the COVID-19 National Action Month, including with a national collaboration with the Historic Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) through <a href="https://www.huttc.org/hbcu-emc/hbcu-card.php">HBCU COVID-19 Awareness and Resilience Day</a>, which spurred more than 30 HBCUs to take action.</li><li>Augmented outreach to communities of color by inviting a diverse array of faith and community-based organizations to be included in the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/oce/sustainability/foodsystems/dialogues">U.S. Food Systems Dialogues</a> hosted by the <a href="https://www.fas.usda.gov/">USDA Foreign Agricultural Service</a>.</li><li>In partnership with the <a href="https://www.state.gov/senior-policy-operating-group-public-awareness-and-outreach-committee-guide-for-public-awareness-materials-non-binding/">President’s Interagency Task Force, Senior Policy Operating Group on Public Awareness and Outreach on Trafficking in Persons</a> and <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/blue-campaign">Blue Campaign</a>, invited more than 3,500 faith-based and community organizations to get involved in combating human trafficking, including by adopting practices highlighted in the <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/publications/18_0926_bc_faith-based-community-toolkit.pdf">Blue Campaign faith-based and community toolkit</a>. Engagements included recommendations on <a href="https://register.gotowebinar.com/recording/717468041650715919">Addressing Racial Equity in Communities Vulnerable to Human Trafficking</a>.</li><li>Reconvened the Small Business Administration’s <a href="https://www.sba.gov/about-sba/organization/sba-initiatives/council-underserved-communities">Council on Underserved Communities</a> and worked with its field offices, stakeholders, and others to host webinars for faith and community leaders on COVID-EIDL, EIDL Targeted Advance, and EIDL Supplemental Grants.</li><li>In coordination with <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/allieswelcome">Operation Allies Welcome</a>, launched <a href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLboghAh_6lzM7AGqQSyPdZBUJcjT3LJg8">a webinar series</a> for faith and community leaders on supporting the resettlement of Afghan allies in the United States.</li><li>Assisted with implementation of a comprehensive strategy for the <a href="https://www.hudexchange.info/programs/cdbg-colonias/colonias-history/">improvement of Colonias communities</a>, which are substandard housing areas that lack basic services such as potable water, electricity, paved roads, proper drainage, and waste management.</li><li>Hosted a series of calls, roundtables, and workshops on nutrition security to increase the capacity of faith and community-based organizations in this area. These events have also addressed the intersections of food security and equity; conservation; rural food insecurity; emergency feeding and supply chain resilience; urban and community agriculture; access to nutrition benefits; as well as climate-smart agriculture and forestry.</li><li>Conducted over 34 nationwide webinars for faith and community leaders on serving and honoring veterans, including 14 veteran suicide-prevention webinars and a webinar focusing on the needs of LGBTQI+ individuals and communities. In this and related work, consistently focused on outreach to a diverse range of communities.</li><li>Engaged faith-based and community organization leaders about their eligibility to apply for and participate in the <a href="https://oese.ed.gov/offices/office-of-formula-grants/school-support-and-accountability/21st-century-community-learning-centers/">21st Century Community Learning Centers grant program</a>.</li><li>Coordinated multiple events on COVID-19 in Spanish for Spanish-speaking audiences.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Strengthening Pluralism and Protecting the Right to Practice Faith Without Fear</strong><br></p>



<ul><li>Provided technical assistance to more than 7,000 faith-based and community leaders on taking action to protect places of worship, including by providing information on the <a href="https://www.fema.gov/grants/preparedness/nonprofit-security">Non-Profit Security Grant Program</a> and the <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/faith-based-organizations-houses-worship">Mitigating Attacks on Places of Worship</a>.&nbsp;Engagements included elevating featured multi-faith voices and recommendations for “<a href="https://www.fema.gov/event/preventing-targeted-violence-and-protecting-safety-and-security-houses-worship-through-faith">Preventing Targeted Violence and Protecting the Safety and Security of Houses of Worship through Faith and Community Based Approaches in the US and in Europe.</a>”</li><li>Implemented a major funding increase for the Department of Homeland Security’s <a href="https://www.fema.gov/grants/preparedness/nonprofit-security">Nonprofit Security Grant Program</a>, which makes funding available to threatened nonprofits, including houses of worship and other religious affiliated entities, to improve their safety and security.</li><li>Established the Protecting Places of Worship Interagency Policy Committee to address increased threats and acts of violence against houses of worship.</li><li>Strengthened the federal workforce with President Biden’s<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/25/executive-order-on-diversity-equity-inclusion-and-accessibility-in-the-federal-workforce/"> executive order</a> promoting diversity, equity, inclusion and accessibility, including on the basis of religion.</li><li>President Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/10/08/memorandum-for-the-secretary-of-state-on-presidential-determination-on-refugee-admissions-for-fiscal-year-2022/">raised the refugee ceiling</a> from historic lows to 125,000 for FY 2022 and expanded the categories of those eligible to participate in the program, enabling many more persecuted people, including people persecuted because of their faith and beliefs, to find a home here in the United States.</li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/president-biden-announces-intent-to-nominate-and-appoint-leaders-to-serve-in-key-religious-affairs-roles/">Demonstrated commitment</a> to advancing religious freedom around the globe with President Biden’s nomination of Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain, who was <a href="https://religionnews.com/2021/12/17/rashad-hussain-confirmed-as-first-muslim-u-s-religious-freedom-ambassador/">overwhelmingly confirmed</a> by the United States Senate, and with diverse appointments to the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom. President Biden also nominated Professor Deborah Lipstadt, a renowned scholar of the Holocaust and antisemitism, to serve as Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism with the Rank of Ambassador.</li><li>Marked holidays celebrated by <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/26/statement-by-president-biden-on-vesak/">Buddhist</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/07/orthodox-christmas-statement/">Christian</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/04/statement-of-president-joe-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-on-diwali/">Hindu</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/04/statement-of-president-joe-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-on-diwali/">Jain</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/28/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-hanukkah/">Jewish</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/?s=eid">Muslim</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/19/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-anniversary-of-guru-nanak-dev-jis-birth/">Sikh</a>, and other communities, including hosting the first-ever virtual Passover, Easter, and Eid White House events that were open to the public and included the participation of both the President and First Lady.</li><li>Held the first <a href="https://twitter.com/USCIS/status/1482075721698795520">naturalization ceremony</a> in honor of National Religious Freedom Day.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Advancing Global Development and Humanitarian Work</strong><br></p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/feb-14-2022-usaid-signs-mou-with-faiths4vaccines-promote-covid-19-year-of-action">Partnered </a>with Faiths4Vaccines, an inclusive, multifaith movement composed of local, national and international religious leaders and medical professionals working on COVID-19 response, to launch a Year of Action to drive demand for vaccination, overcome access and distribution barriers, and build long-term sustainable solutions to ensure that the most vulnerable, marginalized, and hard-to-reach populations have equal access to the vaccine.</li><li>Updated religious-engagement training curriculum for USAID and State Department foreign service officers and reconstituted the Strategic Religious Engagement and International Religious Freedom Sector Council within USAID, creating communities of practice in Washington, D.C., as well as in USAID missions around the world.</li><li>Engaged leaders globally, including through meetings in Rome, Berlin, Bologna, Honduras and Guatemala, <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/may-10-2021-administrator-power-meetings-faith-based-engagement-human-rights">to strengthen faith-based engagement at USAID</a> and demonstrate the <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/speeches/jul-14-2021-administrator-power-2021-international-religious-freedom-summit">administration’s recommitment to multilateral engagement</a>.</li><li>Launched <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/nov-4-2021-usaid-announces-centroamerica-local-initiative-empower-local">USAID’s Centroamérica Local initiative</a> which will support locally-led actors, including faith-based and indigenous organizations, to address drivers of irregular migration through a $300 million regional investment in aid localization, with $100 million in Guatemala over the next five years. </li><li>Worked with the journal <em>Review of Faith &amp; International Affairs</em> to publish a special edition representing <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/toc/rfia20/19/sup1">the first-ever compilation of peer-reviewed evidence in the growing academic field of religion in development</a>. This publication lays the groundwork for future research on the role of faith-based engagement in global development.</li><li>Continued relationships with Global Religious Communities via <a href="https://www.huduser.gov/portal/elist/2016-october_18.html">HUD’s Office for International and Philanthropic Innovation</a> (OIPI). OIPI advances HUD’s strategic priorities and policy and collaborates with international non-governmental organizations, foreign government agencies, and domestic and international foundations. </li></ul>



<p><strong>Working with Faith and Community Groups to Protect Our Environment</strong><br></p>



<ul><li>Prepared to implement <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build/">a new program</a> that will <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/equilibrium-sustainability/582041-religious-institutions-say-infrastructure-funds-will-help">help nonprofits and religious institutions</a> upgrade churches, synagogues, mosques, and community centers to become more energy efficient, advance climate solutions, and save money.&nbsp;</li><li>The <a href="https://www.2030districts.org/detroit">Detroit 2030 District</a> used <a href="https://www.energystar.gov/buildings/training">ENERGY STAR tools, training, and tech support</a> over nine months in 2021 to help inner-city congregations reduce utility costs and carbon emissions, and also promote economic and environmental justice in the community. EPA plans to leverage this success with 22 additional 2030 Districts across the country.</li><li>Presented an EPA <em>Resources for the Faith Community </em>webinar in August 2021, explaining ten major programs and additional resources of value to worship facilities.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces 10 Million Households Enroll in Broadband Affordability Program, Thanks to Bipartisan Infrastructure&#160;Law</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/14/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-10-million-households-enroll-in-broadband-affordability-program-thanks-to-bipartisan-infrastructure-law/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47235</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Announcement made during White House event with Vice President Kamala Harris, Federal Communications Commission Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel, Senior Advisor Mitch Landrieu &#160;Today, during a White House event with Vice President Harris, Federal Communications Commission Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel, and Senior Advisor Mitch Landrieu, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing more than 10 million households are enrolled in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Announcement made during White House event with Vice President Kamala Harris, Federal Communications Commission Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel, Senior Advisor Mitch Landrieu</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>&nbsp;Today, during a White House event with Vice President Harris, Federal Communications Commission Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel, and Senior Advisor Mitch Landrieu, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing more than 10 million households are enrolled in the Affordable Connectivity Program, the nation’s largest ever broadband affordability program.&nbsp;The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to removing barriers to high-speed, affordable internet access. Thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, millions of families who previously could not get online or struggled to pay for this modern-day necessity are now connected.&nbsp;<br><br>The President and Vice President have made it a top priority to ensure all Americans have access to reliable, affordable, high-speed internet to learn, work, and participate in the 21st century economy. Broadband connectivity is vital for work, school, health care and more. But affordable broadband remains out of reach for too many, with one estimate showing almost one out of three internet users worried about paying their internet bills during the pandemic. President Biden, Vice President Harris, and the entire Administration are committed to changing this through implementation of the broadband provisions of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that address the affordability of internet service, a modern-day necessity.<br><br>WHAT IS THE AFFORDABLE CONNECTIVITY PROGRAM?<br><br>The Affordable Connectivity Program is the nation’s largest broadband affordability program.&nbsp; Created through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, it is a $14.2 billion successor program to the Emergency Broadband Benefit.&nbsp; Low-income households are encouraged to apply to receive a discount of up to $30 per month toward internet service and up to $75 per month for eligible households on Tribal lands.&nbsp; Eligible households can also receive a one-time discount of up to $100 to purchase a laptop, desktop computer, or tablet from participating providers if the household contributes more than $10 and less than $50 toward the purchase price.<br><br>WHO IS ELIGIBLE FOR THE AFFORDABLE CONNECTIVITY PROGRAM?<br><br>A household is eligible for the Affordable Connectivity Program if the household income is at or below 200% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines, or if a member of the household meets at least&nbsp;<em>one</em>&nbsp;of the criteria below:</p>



<ul><li>Participates in certain assistance programs, such as SNAP, Medicaid, Federal Public Housing Assistance, SSI, WIC, or Lifeline;</li><li>Participates in Tribal specific programs, such as Bureau of Indian Affairs General Assistance, Tribal TANF, or Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations;</li><li>Eligible to participate in the National School Lunch Program or the School Breakfast Program, including through the USDA Community Eligibility Provision;</li><li>Received a Federal Pell Grant during the current award year; or</li><li>Meets the eligibility criteria for a participating broadband provider&#8217;s existing low-income internet program.</li></ul>



<p>WHERE CAN I GET MORE INFORMATION ABOUT THE AFFORDABLE CONNECTIVITY PROGRAM?</p>



<p>The FCC is joining with ACP outreach partners to host ten local enrollment events in different areas of the country over the next month. These events will build program awareness and train grassroots navigators on ACP eligibility and the enrollment process. Event times and locations will be announced in the coming days. You can learn more about the Affordable Connectivity Program and sign up to be an outreach partner, by visiting&nbsp;<a href="http://www.fcc.gov/ACP">www.fcc.gov/ACP</a>. To find a list of participating providers in the program, please visit&nbsp;<a href="http://www.fcc.gov/affordable-connectivity-program-providers">www.fcc.gov/affordable-connectivity-program-providers</a>. To enroll for the Affordable Connectivity Program, eligible households should visit&nbsp;<a href="http://www.acpbenefit.org/">www.ACPbenefit.org</a>, or mail in an application, a household worksheet, and supporting documentation to ACP Support Center, PO Box 7081, London, KY 40742.&nbsp; More information on how to apply can be found at&nbsp;<a href="https://acpbenefit.org/how-to-apply/">https://acpbenefit.org/how-to-apply/</a>&nbsp;or by calling (877) 384-2575.</p>



<p>WHAT CAN I DO TO SPREAD AWARENESS ABOUT THE NATION’S LARGEST BROADBAND AFFORDABILITY PROGRAM?</p>



<ul><li>Enroll Today: Qualifying households can enroll in the Affordable Connectivity Program by visiting&nbsp;<a href="http://www.acpbenefit.org/">www.ACPbenefit.org</a>&nbsp;or by calling (877) 384-2575 to request a mail-in application.</li><li>Help Your Community Enroll: The FCC is mobilizing people and organizations to help share important consumer information about the new Affordable Connectivity Program.&nbsp; Sign up as an enrollment partner today at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.fcc.gov/ACP">www.fcc.gov/ACP</a>.</li><li>Spread the Word: Are you organizing school packet pick-ups or a local food drive? Print out flyers to include in pick-up materials.&nbsp; Print off your choice of flyers in a variety of sizes and languages by visiting&nbsp;<a href="http://www.fcc.gov/acp-consumer-outreach-toolkit">www.fcc.gov/acp-consumer-outreach-toolkit</a></li><li>Connect with Anchor Institutions: Ensure your local schools, libraries, and community centers know about the ACP and have the information they need to help their eligible students and patrons enroll.</li><li>Share information about ACP on Social Media: The FCC has ready-to-post graphics, videos, and PSA’s ready for you to share with your network. Download the sample graphics/explore the gallery here&nbsp;<a href="http://www.fcc.gov/acp-consumer-outreach-toolkit">www.fcc.gov/acp-consumer-outreach-toolkit</a>.</li><li>Request a Speaker for an Event: Have a local event coming up?&nbsp; Do you host a local news program? Want to train your members to serve as local ambassadors for the program? Request a speaker to share more information about the Affordable Connectivity Program by emailing&nbsp;<a href="mailto:ACPspeakers@fcc.gov">ACPspeakers@fcc.gov</a>.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden Four Years After the Parkland&#160;Shooting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/14/statement-by-president-biden-four-years-after-the-parkland-shooting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 14th, 2018, a gunman stole the lives of 14 students and 3 educators at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida. It was the deadliest high school shooting in a nation with far too many of them, and it left another community — and our country — shattered by grief. On this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On February 14<sup>th</sup>, 2018, a gunman stole the lives of 14 students and 3 educators at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida. It was the deadliest high school shooting in a nation with far too many of them, and it left another community — and our country — shattered by grief.</p>



<p>On this difficult day, we mourn with the Parkland families whose lives were upended in an instant; who had to bury a piece of their soul deep in the earth. We pray too for those still grappling with wounds both visible and invisible. And, as we remember those lost in Parkland, we also stand with Americans in every corner of our country who have lost loved ones to gun violence or had their lives forever altered by a shooting, in tragedies that made headlines and in ones that did not.</p>



<p>Out of the heartbreak of Parkland a new generation of Americans all across the country marched for our lives and towards a better, safer America for us all. Together, this extraordinary movement is making sure that the voices of victims and survivors and responsible gun owners are louder than the voices of gun manufacturers and the National Rifle Association.</p>



<p>My Administration stands with those working to end this epidemic of gun violence. I have put forward a comprehensive plan to reduce gun crime that includes curbing the proliferation of “ghost” guns, cracking down on gun dealers who willfully violate the law, issuing model extreme risk protection order legislation for states, and promoting safe firearm storage, among other efforts. The Department of Justice is also helping more cities adopt smart law enforcement models like the one I recently saw in New York City, in which federal, state, and local law enforcement work together to share intelligence and remove shooters from our streets.</p>



<p>I’ve asked Congress to pass a budget that provides an additional half billion dollars for proven strategies we know reduce violent crime — accountable community policing and community violence interventions. I have also requested increased funding for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives and the U.S. Marshals. And Congress must do much more — beginning with requiring background checks on all gun sales, banning assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, and eliminating immunity for gun manufacturers.</p>



<p>We can never bring back those we’ve lost. But we can come together to fulfill the first responsibility of our government and our democracy: to keep each other safe. For Parkland, for all those we’ve lost, and for all those left behind, it is time to uphold that solemn obligation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Homeland Security Advisor Dr. Liz Sherwood-Randall</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/13/statement-by-white-house-homeland-security-advisor-dr-liz-sherwood-randall/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 18:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are working closely with our Canadian counterparts to end the blockade of key bridges and crossings between the United States and Canada and to restore vital commerce between our two nations.&#160; Following the President’s video teleconference with Prime Minister Trudeau on Friday, I spoke with Canadian National Security and Intelligence Advisor Jody Thomas again&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We are working closely with our Canadian counterparts to end the blockade of key bridges and crossings between the United States and Canada and to restore vital commerce between our two nations.&nbsp; Following the President’s video teleconference with Prime Minister Trudeau on Friday, I spoke with Canadian National Security and Intelligence Advisor Jody Thomas again last night to express appreciation for the decisive law enforcement efforts that are underway along the border to advance toward full resolution of the blockades. &nbsp;We discussed the widespread damaging impacts the obstructions have already had on the lives and livelihoods of people in both our nations and the imperative of taking swift, strong action and deterring future blockades.</p>



<p>This morning, Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro Mayorkas and Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg also spoke with their Canadian counterparts.  The updates they received indicate that most protestors have been cleared from the Ambassador bridge, barriers are being removed, and the corridor is being secured.  Canadian authorities are taking proactive steps to ensure no further unlawful disruption of the flow of people and goods occurs.  Individuals trespassing on property located on the road to the bridge will be cited for trespassing and their vehicles will be towed.   Canadian authorities intend to reopen the Ambassador Bridge today after completing necessary safety checks.  We stand ready to support our Canadian partners wherever useful in order to ensure the restoration of the normal free flow of commerce.   </p>



<p>Senior White House staff are also remaining in close contact with Governor Gretchen Whitmer and Northern Border Governors and Members of Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to Attend the Bicentennial Celebration of the Arrival of the First Free Black Americans to the Republic of&#160;Liberia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/13/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-attend-the-bicentennial-celebration-of-the-arrival-of-the-first-free-black-americans-to-the-republic-of-liberia-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Liberia to attend the Bicentennial Celebrations in Monrovia, Liberia on February 14, 2022.&#160; This marks the arrival of the first Free Black Americans to Providence Island in 1822, which led to the establishment of the City of Monrovia,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Liberia to attend the Bicentennial Celebrations in Monrovia, Liberia on February 14, 2022.&nbsp; This marks the arrival of the first Free Black Americans to Providence Island in 1822, which led to the establishment of the City of Monrovia, and in 1847, the Republic ofLiberia.</p>



<p>The Honorable Dana Banks, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Africa, National Security Council</p>



<p><strong><u>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</u></strong></p>



<p>The Honorable Michael A. McCarthy, United States Ambassador to the Republic of Liberia</p>



<p>Mr. Lonnie G. Bunch III, Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution</p>



<p>Rev. Dr. Teresa Jefferson-Snorton, Bishop of the Fifth Episcopal District of the Christian Methodist Episcopal Church, Chair of the Governing Board, National Council of Churches in the United States</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Zelenskyy of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/13/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-zelenskyy-of-ukraine-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 17:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine.  President Biden reaffirmed the commitment of the United States to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.  President Biden made clear that the United States would respond swiftly and decisively, together with its Allies and partners, to any further Russian aggression against Ukraine.  The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine.  President Biden reaffirmed the commitment of the United States to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.  President Biden made clear that the United States would respond swiftly and decisively, together with its Allies and partners, to any further Russian aggression against Ukraine.  The two leaders agreed on the importance of continuing to pursue diplomacy and deterrence in response to Russia’s military build-up on Ukraine’s borders.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on the President&#8217;s Call with Russian President Vladimir&#160;Putin</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/12/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-the-presidents-call-with-russian-president-vladimir-putin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47224</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 12:53 P.M. EST MODERATOR:&#160; Thanks, everyone, for joining us today.&#160; Today&#8217;s call will be on background, attributed to a “senior administration official.”&#160; And contents will be embargoed until the conclusion of the call.&#160;&#160;Today&#8217;s speaker will be [senior administration official], who will have some comments at the top and then take a few questions.&#160;Over&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>12:53 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining us today.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s call will be on background, attributed to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And contents will be embargoed until the conclusion of the call.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today&#8217;s speaker will be [senior administration official], who will have some comments at the top and then take a few questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Over to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And thanks, everybody, for taking the time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the call between the two presidents was professional and substantive.&nbsp; It lasted a bit over an hour.&nbsp; There was no fundamental change in the dynamic that has been unfolding now for several weeks, but we believe that we have put ideas on the table that would be in our and our allies’ interest to pursue, that would enhance European security, and that would also address some of Russia&#8217;s stated concerns, just as we have been clear that we are committed to upholding Ukraine&#8217;s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and the rights of states to choose their own security arrangements.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But it remains unclear whether Russia is interested in pursuing its goals diplomatically as opposed to through the use of force.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We remain committed to keeping the prospect of de-escalation through diplomacy alive.&nbsp; But we are also clear-eyed about the prospects of that, given the readily apparent steps Russia is taking on the ground in plain sight, right before our eyes.&nbsp; Stakes &#8212; the stakes of this are too high not to give Russia every chance to avoid an action that we believe would be catastrophic.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as always, we continue along two paths: diplomacy, including maintaining close alignment with our partners and allies, as evidenced by the President&#8217;s repeated bilateral engagements, including with President Zelenskyy, his call yesterday with key allies, and today&#8217;s call with President Putin, as well as other senior officials’ calls with their counterparts in all of these same categories.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Meanwhile, we are intensifying our efforts to deter Russia and to impose costs should it decide to go ahead with military action anyway.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You will have seen the announcement yesterday of an additional 3,000 U.S. forces headed to Poland.&nbsp; Our deliveries of security assistance to Ukraine have continued in recent days, and our discussions with the EU, UK, Canadian, and other partners and Allies to ensure that we are prepared to immediately impose severe financial sanctions and export controls are also reaching a culmination point.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are continuing to reduce our diplomatic presence in Kyiv, as you&#8217;ve seen, and the President was very direct with President Putin about our concern for the safety and security of Americans still in Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Whatever Russia decides, our assessment is that their efforts to improve their strategic position are already failing and that this will only be exacerbated should they decide to take military action.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The transatlantic relationship is more closely aligned than it has been in quite some time.&nbsp; NATO is stronger and more purposeful.&nbsp; Russia is already finding itself increasingly isolated from the wider world and more dependent on China, having together revealed a fundamentally different worldview at odds with the principled, affirmative, international law-abiding worldview and values that we stand for.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And Russia is finding itself on defense in the information space, given our own transparency about its intention.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Over time, if Russia invades, this list will also include a severe economic cost that I’ve already described and irrevocable reputational damage caused by taking innocent lives for a bloody war choice.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The two presidents agreed that our teams will stay engaged in the days ahead.&nbsp; Russia may decide to proceed with military action anyway.&nbsp; Indeed, that is a distinct possibility.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If it does, the damage to Ukraine, to European security, and, yes, to Russia will be profound.&nbsp; That is an outcome President Biden believes we should continue to work hard to avert.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Operator, we&#8217;re ready for questions now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing the call.&nbsp; Could you talk a little bit about, you know, anything that President Biden brought to the table today in terms of proposals, as far as an off-ramp that he thinks can get us to de-escalation?&nbsp; And then, could you also talk a little bit about if you had any signs that an operation was more imminent than thought before?&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Trevor.&nbsp; So, look, our view is that we have brought serious, substantive ideas to the diplomatic table for a period of weeks now.&nbsp; Many of those ideas are in the public domain already.&nbsp; We have offered those directly to the Russians in diplomatic discussions.&nbsp; We have developed them in close consultation with our partners and Allies.&nbsp; And President Biden continued to take that approach in the call with President Putin.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have also been very clear that our strong preference is not to negotiate in public because we don&#8217;t believe that that is the best way to find a path to de-escalation, which is our main priority for these diplomatic conversations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I am not going to get into very many of the details of this portion of the conversation, but I would say the President continued down the path that we have been on for quite some time, which is a mode of problem solving and finding solutions that are in our interest, the interest of our partners and Allies, and that can address at least some of the concerns that Russia has raised.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for doing this, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; You said that an attack was a “distinct possibility.”&nbsp; The tone of the briefing yesterday was that the attack was imminent and the decision had been taken.&nbsp; Can you elaborate on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, in terms of continuing to provide Ukraine with military equipment, would that continue after a military attack by Russia, and might the nature of that support change?&nbsp; I&#8217;m thinking of things like anti-aircraft weapons and so on.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I guess I&#8217;d say two things: I would direct you to comments that my colleague, Jake Sullivan, made on this notion of whether President Putin has made a decision.&nbsp; You know, I think the honest answer to that question is we don&#8217;t have full visibility into President Putin’s decision making.&nbsp; You&#8217;d have to direct that question to the Kremlin or to President Putin himself.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, you know, we are not basing our assessment of this on what the Russians say publicly.&nbsp; We are basing this assessment on what we are seeing on the ground with our own eyes, which is a continued Russian build-up on the border with Ukraine and no meaningful evidence of de-escalation or, really, of any interest in de-escalation.&nbsp; So, our sense is that the trends that we&#8217;ve been seeing and talking about for many weeks now are continuing.&nbsp; And, you know, beyond that, I don&#8217;t think we have any real insights to offer.<br>&nbsp;<br>As to our plans going forward, I think President Biden and other officials have been clear that should Russia continue down the path to escalation, the United States will continue to increase our support to Ukraine to enable it to defend itself.&nbsp; And, you know, that approach has not changed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; So, I’m wondering if you can talk a little bit about whether or not the alleged false-flag plans were discussed in the call, and what &#8212; if so, if you can characterize Putin&#8217;s response at all.<br>&nbsp;<br>And also, there were reports of a sort of close encounter between Russian and American submarines today, and I&#8217;m wondering if they discussed that as well.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on your first point, I mean, I think, as a general matter, you can conclude that the issues that we raised concerns about publicly are raised privately between the two presidents.&nbsp; They have conversations that are quite direct, I would say, on both sides.&nbsp; And so, if there&#8217;s an issue that we have been bringing to your attention through briefings and in other fora, you can conclude that the presidents have widely discussed that as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>But beyond that, I don’t want to get into the specifics of what we raised, and certainly not &#8212; I certainly don’t go &#8212; we don’t go down the road of characterizing President Putin’s response.&nbsp; That&#8217;s just not something we tend to do with the other sides of these conversations in these readouts.<br>&nbsp;<br>On this close encounter, I would really direct you to the Pentagon for that.&nbsp; You know, I don&#8217;t have any information to provide about that on this call.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, thanks, everyone.&nbsp; We have to wrap now.&nbsp; With the conclusion of the call, the embargo is lifted.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>A friendly reminder, we’re on background, attributed to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; Thanks all.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>1:03 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Vladimir Putin of&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/12/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-vladimir-putin-of-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 17:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Vladimir Putin of Russia about Russia’s escalating military buildup on the borders of Ukraine. President Biden was clear that, if Russia undertakes a further invasion of Ukraine, the United States together with our Allies and partners will respond decisively and impose swift and severe costs on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Vladimir Putin of Russia about Russia’s escalating military buildup on the borders of Ukraine. President Biden was clear that, if Russia undertakes a further invasion of Ukraine, the United States together with our Allies and partners will respond decisively and impose swift and severe costs on Russia. President Biden reiterated that a further Russian invasion&nbsp;of Ukraine&nbsp;would produce widespread human suffering and diminish Russia’s standing.&nbsp;President Biden was clear with President Putin that while the United States remains prepared to engage in diplomacy, in full coordination with our Allies and partners, we are equally prepared for other scenarios.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Video Call with Bjoern Seibert, Head of Cabinet of the President of the European&#160;Commission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/11/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-video-call-with-bjoern-seibert-head-of-cabinet-of-the-president-of-the-european-commission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 23:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan held a secure video call with Bjoern Seibert, Head of Cabinet of the President of the European Commission on February 10. They discussed their concerns about Russia’s continued build-up of military forces around Ukraine, as well as preparations to impose massive consequences and severe economic costs on Russia should it&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan held a secure video call with Bjoern Seibert, Head of Cabinet of the President of the European Commission on February 10. They discussed their concerns about Russia’s continued build-up of military forces around Ukraine, as well as preparations to impose massive consequences and severe economic costs on Russia should it choose military escalation.  They coordinated the details of a potential transatlantic response, including both financial sanctions and export controls, imposed in coordination by the United States, the European Union, and other partners and Allies.  They also agreed to continue the close partnership between the United States and the European Union on a wide range of issues including energy security, COVID-19, health security, and partnership on international infrastructure development through the Build Back Better World and Global Gateway initiatives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
