<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 18:21:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Honoring the Super Bowl LV Champions, the Tampa Bay Buccaneers</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/20/remarks-by-president-biden-honoring-the-super-bowl-lv-champions-the-tampa-bay-buccaneers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 18:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:39 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good morning, I think &#8212; still &#8220;good morning.&#8221;&#160; And it’s great to see everybody here.&#160; I want to thank the &#8212; the representatives here.&#160; The Second Gentleman is here.&#160; Representative Castor, Crist &#8212; PARTICIPANT:&#160; (Inaudible.) THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Okay, you got &#8212; (laughs).&#160; I&#8217;ll tell you, that Florida thing is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:39 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good morning, I think &#8212; still &#8220;good morning.&#8221;&nbsp; And it’s great to see everybody here.&nbsp; I want to thank the &#8212; the representatives here.&nbsp; The Second Gentleman is here.&nbsp; Representative Castor, Crist &#8212;<br><br>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay, you got &#8212; (laughs).&nbsp; I&#8217;ll tell you, that Florida thing is something else.&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And Soto and Murphy and Franklin.&nbsp; And one of my best friends in the world &#8212; now he&#8217;s coming back from outer space &#8212; Bill Nelson, who runs NASA now.<br><br>We’re here today to congratulate and welcome to the White House the Super Bowl Champion Tampa Bay Buccaneers.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; To the players, the coaches, and the Glazer family &#8212; my good friends &#8212; it’s an honor to have you here.<br><br>We have to say that the fans down in Western Florida are having a pretty good year this year.&nbsp; I tell you, you know, the Stanley Cup and &#8212; in addition to the Super Bowl.&nbsp; But, you know, we’re making a pretty strong case to start calling Tampa the &#8220;City of Champions.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the &#8212; this Buccaneer team is a testament of the fact that it’s never too late to come together and achieve extraordinary things.&nbsp; Three quarters of the way through the season, they found themselves in the middle of the pack: seven wins and five losses.&nbsp;<br><br>But this is a team that didn’t fold and always got up, dug deep.&nbsp; They won their last four games of the season and then stormed through the playoffs &#8212; winning on the road in Washington, New Orleans, and Green Bay &#8212; and capping it all off back home in Tampa to become the first team to win the Super Bowl on their home turf in a decisive victory against the defending champs, the Kansas City Chiefs.<br><br>You know, it&#8217;s an incredible run by one of the most well-rounded teams in recent memory.&nbsp; A pair of All-Pro linebackers. Star pass rushers.&nbsp; A dangerous secondary.&nbsp; A dominant offensive line.&nbsp; And a legendary tight end who gave up what, I’m told, was a promising career to return to &#8212; acting career &#8212; to return to the game.&nbsp;<br><br>And most importantly, you’ve got a star receiver from Delaware.&nbsp; I&#8217;m mildly prejudiced about that.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; Where’s Chris?&nbsp; Where are you, Chris?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I called him before the game to tell him &#8212; to give him some tips on how to run some patterns.&nbsp; That was a &#8212; (laughter).<br><br>But, you know, born in Pennsylvania, raised in Delaware.&nbsp; Where I come from, that’s a heck of a combination, man.&nbsp; You know, Chris and I had a chance to speak before the Super Bowl.&nbsp; And I know, like me, he takes a lot of pride in his home state of Delaware.&nbsp; Chris, you’re inspiring a whole lot of kids back home in Delaware.<br><br>And he went to a &#8212; by the way, he went to a high school called Middletown &#8212; a perennial winner of the state championship.&nbsp; But I pointed out to him, when my son, Hunter, was a senior, he went to my Alma Mater&#8217;s high school named &#8212; by the way, all sit down.&nbsp; What are we &#8212; just standing?&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>I &#8212; you know, and I told him my son scored the scoring touchdown at Archmere and won the state championship that year.&nbsp; But, anyway, that’s &#8212; we don’t &#8212; we don’t count those things.&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;ve never met an athlete that doesn’t remember every damn play he made.<br><br>And, of course, two other guys worth mentioning: the coach and the quarterback.&nbsp; You know, a lot has been made about the fact that we have the oldest coach ever to win a Super Bowl and the oldest quarterback to win the Super Bowl.<br><br>Well, I’ll tell you right now: You won’t hear any jokes about that from me.&nbsp; As far as I’m concerned, there’s nothing wrong with being the oldest guy to make it to the mountaintop.&nbsp; That’s how I look at it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And, Tom, looking at you, you’ve got about 20 more years left.&nbsp; You’re just about the best ever to play.&nbsp; And making it to 10 Super Bowls in the last 20 years &#8212; that ain’t bad, man. (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’ll tell you what, we’ve never seen anything like it in the game.&nbsp;<br><br>And, of course, these guys all know that sports are more than just a game.&nbsp; It’s something &#8212; some of my strongest memories, most enduring memories and lessons and cherished friendships come from the days I played &#8212; not went anywhere near anybody on that stage.&nbsp; I started in grade school playing in CYO league.&nbsp;<br><br>And I’ll never forget getting knocked out when I was in fifth grade, and my dad &#8212; walking off &#8212; he said, “Get up.&nbsp; Get up.&nbsp; Get up.&nbsp; Unless something is broken, get up.”&nbsp; Well, I think that’s what sports tell you: You just get up.&nbsp; You get up.<br><br>I went to the University of Delaware to play football, although it didn’t very do much for my career &#8212; I didn’t do very well.&nbsp; But, you know, I found out that your career can be embellished a little over time.&nbsp; It’s an amazing kind of thing.<br><br>You know, there’s an awards banquet that, many years later &#8212; which is called the Timmie Awards &#8212; was it?&nbsp; &#8212; and was held here in Washington.&nbsp; Supreme Court Justices and Presidents would show up to this big banquet.&nbsp; And the University of Delaware football program received the award, and I had a chance to introduce a Hall of Fame coach, one of my &#8212; the backfield coach when I played.&nbsp; I didn’t play much.&nbsp; His name was Tubby Raymond.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so, I got up and I said, “Here is my coach, Tubby Raymond.”&nbsp; Made &#8212; said some nice things about Tubby.&nbsp;<br><br>Tubby was really, kind of, nervous and &#8212; standing in front of Presidents and Supreme Court Justices and so many distinguished people.&nbsp; And he went up on &#8212; on to talk about what an incredible ball player I was at the University of Delaware.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It was amazing.&nbsp; It was amazing.&nbsp; That’s why I decided to run for President.&nbsp; I figured, if he was still around and I&#8217;d get to be elected President, I would’ve been an All-American.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I could’ve been big.&nbsp; I could’ve been big.&nbsp;<br><br>But all kidding aside, you guys did it the hard way. &nbsp;And I hope you all know just how important it was for &#8212; after such a tough year for the nation.&nbsp; In the middle of a long, dark winter, every Sunday, people were able to sit down and watch you play.&nbsp; You created memories that helped folks make it through and believe that we could get back to normal again.&nbsp; And you did it as a team, trailblazing, including the first team with two women full-time coaching positions.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And realizing that of the &#8212; of the 25 or 26 Glazer grandchildren and about 24 of them being women &#8212; you had no choice.&nbsp; It’s about time they stepped up.&nbsp; Right, guys?&nbsp;<br><br>Anyway, all kidding aside, the step &#8212; your team stepped up off the field, too, donating millions of meals to families in need; helping Americans exercise their sacred right to vote, including at Raymond James Stadium.&nbsp; Your stadium also became a lifeline for families in Tampa Bay this spring, administering nearly 200,000 vaccine shots.&nbsp; And you all who don’t have a shot, man: Get one, okay?<br><br>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; Amen.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Get one.&nbsp; Get one.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And you’re saving lives &#8212; helping us get back our lives and loved ones.<br><br>And I want to thank the NFL for setting strong vaccination goals so fans can go see a game without it becoming a super-spreader event.<br><br>Getting vaccinated is about staying healthy and understanding that no one is invincible, even if you are young and you’re fit.&nbsp; It’s about looking out for those and the frontline workers out there, like the ones the team played in front of on Super Bowl Sunday.<br><br>Those workers remind us of a quintessential lesson about sports and America itself.&nbsp; That no matter how much and how many times we get knocked down, we always get up.&nbsp; We come back.&nbsp; We come back stronger together and achieve incredible things &#8212; just like your team did, just like we’re doing as a country.<br><br>So, congratulations, and thank you all for being here.&nbsp; Good luck to you all this season.&nbsp; And now let me bring up Bryan to say a few words.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>MR. GLAZER:&nbsp; Mr. President, on behalf of our family, the Tampa Bay Buccaneers coaches, players, and staff, and all of our loyal fans, thank you for hosting us today.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an honor for us to be at the White House.<br><br>For our family and fans, this day has been nearly 20 years in the making.&nbsp; Because despite this being our second Super Bowl Championship, this our first visit to the White House.&nbsp; In 2003, following our Super Bowl 37 victory, there were world events that prevented us to visit.&nbsp; So that makes today even more special.<br><br>And we&#8217;re here today because this team did the impossible: new players, including a new quarterback; no offseason mini camps; no preseason; limitations on meetings,\; rules and regulations were changing every day.&nbsp; But they stayed focused and went on to win their final eight games, as the President spoke about, and became the first team to win the Super Bowl at home.&nbsp; Amazing.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s only fitting that as we enter the 46th season in Tampa Bay Buccaneer history that we celebrate it with the 46th President of the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We start this season with only one goal in mind: It’s to come back here next summer and spend a Super Bowl victory again with you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>MR. ARIANS:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President, for giving us this day.&nbsp; It &#8212; I get emotional, but it&#8217;s very, very special.&nbsp; This is actually my third time; it never gets old.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to thank our coaches, our players, our entire organization &#8212; men, women that did such a great job last year of coming together and banding together &#8212; not to beat the other team; we had to beat the virus first.&nbsp; And you sacrificed more than any team I&#8217;ve ever been around &#8212; players, coaches, your families &#8212; to make sure that we had our team on the field every Sunday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s a great compliment to all of you.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t say enough about our owners, the Glazer family.&nbsp; They’re the best owners I&#8217;ve ever known and ever been around.&nbsp; Our players are outstanding.&nbsp; They do what they&#8217;re supposed to do on and off the field because they take care of each other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We live by three words: trust, loyalty, and respect.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any rules.&nbsp; If you have those, you&#8217;ll have accountability and you&#8217;ll be able to do anything you want.&nbsp; One team, one cause.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I hope the Senate and the House start helping you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; One team, one cause.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Again, thank you all for having us here.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President. &nbsp;And Go Bucs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And Tom has got some stuff to say.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. BRADY:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s certainly an honor to be here.&nbsp; Thank you very much for your hospitality your entire staff has given us today.&nbsp; I think what &#8212; behind me is an amazing group of players.&nbsp; We have a bunch of coaches and staff here sitting down.&nbsp;<br><br>And it was actually a very challenging season for a lot of reasons, but we bonded together, we worked really hard, we put all our individual agendas aside, and we came together as a team.</p>



<p>And sports has an amazing way of bringing people together.&nbsp; If you look at us, we&#8217;re all a little bit different ages.&nbsp; I&#8217;m a little older than most of them.&nbsp; But we come from a lot of different places across the country, a lot of different schools, a lot of different backgrounds, but we love each other; we&#8217;re committed to one another.&nbsp; And when you do that, amazing things happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And these guys are amazing group of men.&nbsp; It didn&#8217;t look great there at one point.&nbsp; We were seven and five, struggling a little bit, as the President alluded to.&nbsp; But we found our rhythm.&nbsp; We got on a roll.</p>



<p>Not a lot of people, you know, think that we could have won.&nbsp; And, in fact, I think about 40 percent of the people still don&#8217;t think we won.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I understand that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MR. BRADY:&nbsp; You understand that, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I understand that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. BRADY:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And personally, you know, it&#8217;s nice for me to be back here.&nbsp; We had a game in Chicago where I forgot what down it was.&nbsp; I lost track of one down in 21 years of playing, and they started calling me “Sleepy Tom.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Why would they do that to me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don’t know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MR. BRADY:&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s great to be &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re on the eve of football season.&nbsp; We start, tomorrow, practice.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to do everything we can to work to achieve another one of those Lombardi trophies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s a different group of men.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll be a different challenge, but we&#8217;re excited for it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re excited for the opportunity to compete and work hard and show everyone what we&#8217;re made of.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re not going to throw the Super Bowl trophy this time, Cam, but we&#8217;re going to offer President Biden a special presentation from Mr. Glazer.&nbsp; And then we&#8217;re going to challenge 11 of us, 11 White House interns to game of football here on the lawn, and we intend to run it up on you guys, so &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; get ready to go.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>(The President is presented with a Buccaneers jersey.)&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you, man.&nbsp; Unusual number, huh?&nbsp; Forty-six.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>11:53 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Jonathan Kanter for Assistant Attorney General for Antitrust</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/20/president-biden-announces-jonathan-kanter-for-assistant-attorney-general-for-antitrust/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 18:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate Jonathan Kanter for Assistant Attorney General for the Antitrust Division at the Department of Justice. Jonathan Kanter, Nominee for Assistant Attorney General, Antitrust Division, Department of Justice Jonathan Kanter is a distinguished antitrust lawyer with over 20 years of experience. Throughout his career, Kanter&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate Jonathan Kanter for Assistant Attorney General for the Antitrust Division at the Department of Justice.<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Jonathan Kanter, Nominee for Assistant Attorney General, Antitrust Division, Department of Justice</u></strong></p>



<p>Jonathan Kanter is a distinguished antitrust lawyer with over 20 years of experience. Throughout his career, Kanter has also been a leading advocate and expert in the effort to promote strong and meaningful antitrust enforcement and competition policy. He is currently a partner at The Kanter Law Group LLP, which is a boutique antitrust law firm that advocates in favor of federal and state antitrust law enforcement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Prior to founding The Kanter Law Group, Kanter was Co-Chair of the antitrust practice at Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton, and Garrison LLP. Jonathan also served as an attorney for the U.S. Federal Trade Commission’s Bureau of Competition.&nbsp; Kanter earned his J.D. from Washington University in St. Louis and his B.A. from State University of New York at Albany.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Listening Session with Cuban American Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/19/readout-of-white-house-listening-session-with-cuban-american-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24483</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Senior Advisor and Director of the White House Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond and Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere for the National Security Council Juan Gonzalez met with Cuban American leaders to listen to their policy recommendations and concerns in light of the recent, unprecedented demonstrations unfolding across Cuba. Administration officials underscored that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Senior Advisor and Director of the White House Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond and Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere for the National Security Council Juan Gonzalez met with Cuban American leaders to listen to their policy recommendations and concerns in light of the recent, unprecedented demonstrations unfolding across Cuba. Administration officials underscored that the White House is monitoring the situation in Cuba closely and that addressing the moment and ongoing situation in Cuba is a top priority for the Administration. They also affirmed what the President said last week: that the demonstrations are the direct result of a failed communist government, and reminded the leaders that the President stands firmly with the people of Cuba. Stakeholders shared what they’ve done over the last week to help elevate the voices of demonstrators in Cuba and provided their recommendations for how the U.S. government can help. Today’s was the latest event in ongoing work the White House has done to reach Cuban American leaders following the historic demonstrations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the Occasion of Eid al-Adha</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/19/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-occasion-of-eid-al-adha/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I send our warmest greetings to those celebrating Eid al-Adha around the world. The Eid traditions and Hajj rituals of providing for those less fortunate in commemoration of Abraham and his son’s devotion to God carry a special meaning this year as we continue to navigate the challenges of COVID-19 and work to&#160;respond&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I send our warmest greetings to those celebrating Eid al-Adha around the world. The Eid traditions and Hajj rituals of providing for those less fortunate in commemoration of Abraham and his son’s devotion to God carry a special meaning this year as we continue to navigate the challenges of COVID-19 and work to&nbsp;respond to and&nbsp;recover from the global pandemic. The American people are proud to be helping lead the fight to end COVID-19 globally by donating more than half a billion vaccines to countries around the world, including Muslim-majority nations. We must all work together to save lives and end this pandemic everywhere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Hajj, which convenes people from all walks of life&nbsp;and&nbsp;from&nbsp;every corner&nbsp;of the globe, is also a reminder of Islam’s commitment to equality and the shared roots of&nbsp;the world’s Abrahamic faiths.&nbsp;The United States is committed to working&nbsp;with the international community to emerge stronger from the pandemic,&nbsp;and&nbsp;thousands of Muslim Americans are among those eager to perform the pilgrimage next year, God willing. &nbsp;</p>



<p>On behalf of the American people, we wish all those celebrating a safe and wonderful holiday. Eid Mubarak.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/19/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 23:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Julie Chung, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka. &#160; &#160; &#160;Janet Louise Yellen, of California, to be United States Governor of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Julie Chung, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Janet Louise Yellen, of California, to be United States Governor of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, vice Steven T. Mnuchin.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Janet Louise Yellen, of California, to be United States Governor of the Inter-American Development Bank for a term of five years; United States Governor of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development for a term of five years; and United States Governor of the International Monetary Fund for a term of five years, vice Steven T. Mnuchin.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Meeting with King Abdullah II of Jordan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/19/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-meeting-with-king-abdullah-ii-of-jordan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 22:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan to reaffirm the enduring strength of the partnership between the United States and Jordan. President Biden confirmed unwavering U.S. support for Jordan and His Majesty’s leadership. He was proud to announce the delivery of over 500,000 COVID-19 vaccines to Jordan,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan to reaffirm the enduring strength of the partnership between the United States and Jordan. President Biden confirmed unwavering U.S. support for Jordan and His Majesty’s leadership. He was proud to announce the delivery of over 500,000 COVID-19 vaccines to Jordan, underscoring the U.S. commitment to bringing the same urgency to international vaccination efforts that we have demonstrated at home.</p>



<p>The leaders discussed pressing economic challenges exacerbated by the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic, both at home and across the globe.&nbsp; They focused on the benefits of investing in infrastructure, and discussed the President’s infrastructure plan as well as Jordan’s plans for a desalination project and Jordan’s potential for greater regional economic integration through investments in energy infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The leaders also consulted on opportunities to enhance peace and stability in the Middle East. In that regard, the President expressed his strong support for a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict and respect for Jordan’s special role as custodian of Muslim holy places in Jerusalem. The President expressed U.S. support for engagement between Jordan and the new Israeli Government, as demonstrated by their bilateral agreement earlier this month to improve Jordan’s access to fresh water and increase Jordan’s exports to the West Bank.</p>



<p>President Biden commended the important role Jordan plays in the wider stability of the region and welcomed the recent trilateral summit in Baghdad between Iraq, Jordan, and Egypt. The two leaders discussed the enormous challenges in Syria and the importance of a broad humanitarian initiative to reach all Syrians in need.</p>



<p>The leaders reflected on the strategic U.S.-Jordan defense relationship. They discussed U.S. support for the modernization of Jordan’s fleet of F-16 fighter jets, which will allow for greater interoperability and effectiveness of the Jordanian Armed Forces.&nbsp; President Biden thanked Jordan for its important early contributions to the successful campaign to defeat ISIS, and honored the memory of Captain Muath al-Kasasbeh as an example of Jordanian courage and heroism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden reaffirmed that his administration looks forward to strengthening bilateral cooperation in multiple areas over the coming months, including the promotion of economic opportunities that will be vital for a bright future in Jordan.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 19, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/19/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-19-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 21:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1:06 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI: Hi, everyone. Good morning &#8212; or good afternoon. Happy Monday. Okay, one item for all of you at the top. The United States continues its tremendous efforts to donate COVID-19 vaccines from the U.S. global supply. Today, we can announce that we have over a million Johnson &#38; Johnson vaccines&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1:06 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Hi, everyone. Good morning &#8212; or good afternoon. Happy Monday.</p>



<p>Okay, one item for all of you at the top. The United States continues its tremendous efforts to donate COVID-19 vaccines from the U.S. global supply. Today, we can announce that we have over a million Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccines headed to Gambia, Senegal, Zambia, and Niger. We&#8217;re also pleased to announce 3 million vaccines going to Guatemala tomorrow, continuing our prioritization of Latin American countries.</p>



<p>As these shipments demonstrate, the United States is fulfilling our promise to be an arsenal of vaccines for the world, and we&#8217;re proud to be donating these doses to save lives and help those in need.</p>



<p>Josh, why don&#8217;t you kick us off.</p>



<p>Q Thanks, Jen. Two subjects. First, the President&#8217;s remarks on why China didn&#8217;t face sanctions for cyberattacks but Russia did: Could you clarify, since both countries are accused of protecting criminal hacker groups? And then, along the same lines, the U.S. imports about $435 billion dollars in goods from China. To what degree do economic concerns play a role in how to address cyberattacks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, let me say that, today, an unprecedented group of allies and partners &#8212; including the European Union, the United Kingdom, Australia, Canada, New Zealand, Japan, and NATO &#8212; are joining the United States in exposing and criticizing the PRC’s Ministry of State Security’s malicious cyber activities. And this is the first time NATO has condemned PRC cyber activities.</p>



<p>So, I would note that we are actually elevating and taking steps to not only speak out publicly, but certainly take action as it relates to problematic cyber activities from China &#8212; in a different way, but as we have from Russia as well. We are not differentiating one as, you know, out of the realm of condemnation or out of the realm of consequence from the United States.</p>



<p>In terms of the economic pieces, I think you&#8217;re asking me &#8212; give me a little more on your question we’re trying to get at.</p>



<p>Q I mean, basically the U.S. economy depends a lot on Chinese imports. We only get $16 billion worth of goods from Russia. If we were to come with major sanctions on China, is there a risk that we can be hurting our own economy?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I would say, first, that we take cyber actions against our country and against private-sector entities quite seriously.</p>



<p>The Department of Justice is imposing costs and today announced criminal charges against four MSS hackers. These charges address activities concerning a multi-year campaign targeting foreign governments and entities in key sectors.</p>



<p>We also have, of course, through the National Security Agency, Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, and Federal Bureau of Investigation, exposed over 50 tactics, techniques, and procedures Chinese state-sponsored cyber actors used when targeting U.S. and allied networks.</p>



<p>My point is we are not holding back. We are not allowing any economic circumstance or consideration to prevent us from taking actions where warranted. And also, we reserve the option to take additional actions where warranted as well. This is not the conclusion of our efforts as it relates to cyber activities with China or Russia.</p>



<p>Q And then, secondly, with Facebook: The President suggested that executives look in the mirror and change their practices. Does that mean the administration isn&#8217;t considering any regulatory or legal moves to possibly address disinformation on social media?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;ve taken any options off the table. That&#8217;s up to Congress to determine how they want to proceed moving forward.</p>



<p>But let me just note that we&#8217;re not in a war or a battle with Facebook; we&#8217;re in a battle with the virus. And the problem we&#8217;re seeing, that our Surgeon General elevated just last week, is that disinformation, traveling through a range of mediums &#8212; some of them are a range of social media platforms, some of them are media, some of them are through the mouth of public officials &#8212; that bad information, inaccurate information about vaccines is killing people.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s where our concern is, and that&#8217;s what we &#8212; the President is working to express and also what the Surgeon General expressed in his report just last week.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Steve.</p>



<p>Q Now that you&#8217;ve levelled these charges on China, do you plan to raise them with them?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: We, of course, will continue to be in touch with Chinese officials at a high level, and that &#8212; that will be the case in these regards as well.</p>



<p>Q Is the Chinese government actively doing the hacking or contracting it out?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t have any more detail than that, Steve. Let me check and see if there&#8217;s more we can provide to you about &#8212;</p>



<p>Q Lastly, the Belarus opposition leader is in Washington this week. I think she&#8217;s going to meet Tony Blinken today. Is the President going to meet with her?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: We are still finalizing what the details are. She will be meeting with White House officials. I wouldn&#8217;t say it will be the President, but she will be meeting with White House officials when she&#8217;s here. We&#8217;ll have more to report on that once those details are finalized.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Phil.</p>



<p>Q Just to follow up: The statement said the Ministry of State Security was directly paying hackers, which is, I think, why it was elevated. The President kind of compared it to the Russia situation but said that maybe they&#8217;re protecting them or accommodating them, which doesn&#8217;t seem to be a direct link. That’s what the statement said this morning. I&#8217;m just trying to square kind of where things stand in terms of how the White House views what has actually transpired.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: As it relates to the cyber activities and the attribution that was put out earlier this morning?</p>



<p>Q Yeah. Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I would say that we felt it was important to be clear that &#8212; as was clear when we made the announcement this morning, that the former attribution of the malicious cyber campaign utilizing the zero-day vulnerabilities in the Microsoft Exchange serv- &#8212; server, which was disclosed in March 2021 &#8212; two malicious cyber actors, affiliated with the MSS with high confidence. That was the information put out by the intelligence community or by our national security team earlier today. That is accurate.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we worked also &#8212; and it’s significant, which is why I pointed this out initially &#8212; that we worked in coordination with Eur- &#8212; with many partners around the world &#8212; the European Union, the United Kingdom, Australia, Canada, New Zealand, Japan and NATO &#8212; to criticize, expose, and call out these malicious cyber activities. But that is the information that&#8217;s accurate about the attribution.</p>



<p>Q And then, just one more on that and then one quick other one. The President said he&#8217;s going to be briefed on it or &#8212; in his remarks, when he was asked about it, he said he was going to be briefed on it. This is a pretty significant el- &#8212; escalation of things from the U.S. and its allies. What more does the President need to be briefed on in terms of the process, going forward?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I would say, first: The President is regularly briefed. He certainly is aware of attributions that are determined by the U.S. government, including the one announced earlier today. But this is an ongoing effort, an ongoing consideration of how to prevent these malicious actions from happening in the future to other private-sector companies &#8212; certainly something that the President will continue to speak with his national security team about.</p>



<p>Q And then, just one more on the economic side. Obviously, the President kind of addressed inflation head on today. One thing that Chair Powell says &#8212; and I know you guys are in the same place on the idea that it&#8217;s transitory right now &#8212; but Chair Powell said, in congressional testimony, “We&#8217;re humble about what we understand,” given the fact this &#8212; there&#8217;s no real roadmap coming out of a once-in-a-century pandemic, economically.</p>



<p>Is the White House economic team, when it comes to the inflation, also humble about what they understand &#8212; that maybe they don&#8217;t necessarily know what&#8217;s going to happen next as it pertains to inflation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Absolutely. We take inflation very seriously. It is under the purview of the Federal Reserve. As you know, they have regular quarterly meeting where they put out that information and any considerations publicly.</p>



<p>Their projection continues to be that, while there&#8217;s an &#8212; a projected increase in inflation this year, it&#8217;s expected to come back down to about 2.2 next year. They have not changed that, and that is aligned with a number of outside economists as well.</p>



<p>You&#8217;re also correct that when the economy is turning back on from a global pandemic, there isn&#8217;t a lot of historic precedent for that.</p>



<p>And certainly, we&#8217;re seeing prices go back to pre-pandemic levels in some cases. We&#8217;re also seeing a range of factors, including shortages in the supply chain &#8212; from chips shortages that are impacting the auto industry, to lumber shortages that are impacting the housing industry &#8212; that are also factors here as we&#8217;re seeing price increases.</p>



<p>But we do look at all of that. We take it incredibly seriously. And we respect the role of the Federal Reserve as well.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Rachel.</p>



<p>Q Thanks, Jen. Two questions &#8212; one on &#8212; just to follow-up on and China and the cyberattacks. A senior administration official said that no one country acting on its own can change China&#8217;s behavior. So, if the United States were to take action against China, would it do so alone, or does the administration feel like you need allies on board to take that step?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, it&#8217;s a good question, Rachel. I think as we&#8217;ve approached our China strategy from the beginning and our policy as it relates to China, we&#8217;ve always felt that going &#8212; working together, working in partnership with allies around the world, and also with &#8212; in partnership with members of the federal government, members of Congress from both sides of the aisle, was how we approached it from a position of strength.</p>



<p>So, what&#8217;s significant today is that while we&#8217;re all calling out these malicious cyber activities, so are a number of our key partners around the world: the European Union, the United Kingdom, Australia, Canada, New Zealand, Japan.</p>



<p>These malicious cyber activities are not only impacting the United States. They&#8217;re impacting a range of countries, a range of partners. And, yes, we would, of course, like to work with countries and work with our key partners around the world moving forward. And, you know, obviously we can&#8217;t determine steps and consequences on their behalf, but that is certainly our objective and how we&#8217;ve approached our strategy to date.</p>



<p>Q But you&#8217;re not ruling out taking action on your own if you felt like it was necessary?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: No, we&#8217;re not. But we also, from the beginning, have felt that working in partnership, working in coordination is &#8212; and working together is a stronger way to approach malicious activity &#8212; cyber activity and others &#8212; with &#8212; in areas of concern around the world.</p>



<p>Q One quick follow-up just on infrastructure. You know, Republicans are saying that they don&#8217;t want to move forward with this test vote that’s scheduled for Wednesday without knowing exactly how they&#8217;re going to pay for everything in that bipartisan infrastructure bill.</p>



<p>Senator Bill Cassidy, over the weekend, said the White House is not working with Republicans on the payfors and that he feels like they&#8217;re competing with Democrats’ $3.5 trillion plan. So does the administration feel like these differences can be resolved in the next 48 hours?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I think it&#8217;s important to take a step back and remember that, a month ago, a bipartisan group of senators stood outside of the White House with the President to announce an agreement on infrastructure framework. There&#8217;s been a lot of progress since then &#8212; a lot of late nights, a lot of coffee drinking &#8212; and important legislating, bill writing that&#8217;s happened.</p>



<p>But the American people have waited a long time. The American people are ready to see progress. And we believe it&#8217;s time for progress to happen and time for this legislation to move forward. We also work in close contact or close coordination with, of course, Leader Schumer, and we defer to him and other leaders in Congress on the timeline and the sequencing of legislation moving forward.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q On that discussion with Leader Schumer, has he talked in the last few days, at all, with any of the Republicans<br>who are negotiating (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: The &#8212; the President? I don&#8217;t have any calls to read out for you. I can tell you that our team, senior White House officials, have been in close to- &#8212; contact with Democrats and Republicans, members, and their offices. And, whenever it warrants, the President is always happy to pick up the phone.</p>



<p>Q And then, on the Guantanamo Bay announcement today: Senior officials said 10 of the remaining detainees are eligible for repatriation. Any sense yet of the targeted timelines for transferring them? And is there a broader goal within this administration of closing Guantanamo Bay? Has that timeline been set?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yes, our goal is to close Guantanamo Bay. I can tell you that there&#8217;s 39 &#8212; I think you know some of this, but for others who are following it &#8212; there are 39 detainees who remain at Guantanamo Bay: 10 are eligible for transfer, 17 are eligible for a Periodic Review Board, 10 are involved in the military commissions process, and 2 detainees have been convicted.</p>



<p>This individual who we announced the transfer of &#8212; the Department of Defense announced the transfer of &#8212; had been &#8212; had started moving through the process during the Obama-Biden administration and was on pause for some period of time over the last four years.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you. As you know, there&#8217;s a process. There are different layers of the process. But that remains our goal, and we are considering all available avenues to responsibly transfer detainees and, of course, close Guantanamo Bay.</p>



<p>Q We and a few other outlets have reported that the administration is now planning to send about 2,500 Afghan translators and, I believe, members of their family to Fort Lee in Virginia as they complete the steps to have their legal status in this country reviewed. Will there be other U.S. military bases in the United States also used to house them temporarily?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, any confirmation and final details of military base usage would be from the Department of Defense and the State Department, given they&#8217;re implementing these programs. I expect they will have more to share with you, Ed. I just want to defer to them, given it is their programs.</p>



<p>I will say that when I went through the programs and how the process worked last week, one of the things I tried to note but I will &#8212; I will elevate again here is that individuals who have completed the process &#8212; the security review &#8212; the vetting and security process could be relocated to the United States. That would be certainly military &#8212; U.S. military bases, and the Department of Defense will assess how many of those and how many facilities they would need for those transfers.</p>



<p>Q Two real quick scheduling things.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>Q Is he &#8212; is the President at all scheduled to meet any time soon with members of the Texas Democratic House delegation that&#8217;s here in Washington?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t have any meetings to preview for you at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q And I hesitate to ask this because I&#8217;m only (inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Don&#8217;t hesitate. It&#8217;s okay. It&#8217;s a Monday.</p>



<p>Q Is Tom Brady joining the Buccaneers here at the White House tomorrow? I&#8217;ve been asked to ask this by several (inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: (Laughs.) It&#8217;s okay. I don&#8217;t have the list of Buccaneers attending tomorrow in front of me. We will see if we can venture to get that for you all by the end of the day.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Thank you, Jen. And great throw yesterday &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Thank you.</p>



<p>Q &#8212; at the Nationals.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Thank you very much. I appreciate it.</p>



<p>Q On vaccine hesitancy: As COVID-19 cases rise, if this is becoming a “pandemic of the unvaccinated” and you guys are having a hard time getting a certain part of the population to go get the shot, would President Biden ever call former President Trump and say, “I need your help. Let&#8217;s cut a PSA and tell people to go do it”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I would say that what we&#8217;ve seen in our data is that the most trusted voices are local officials, doctors, medical experts, civic leaders, clergy, from time to time &#8212; and that is where we have really invested our funding and our resources.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve seen almost every former President play a role in putting out a PSA, making sure people understood in the country that the vaccine is safe and effective. We don&#8217;t believe that requires an embroidered invitation to be a part of.</p>



<p>But certainly, any role of anyone who has a platform where they can provide information to the public that the vaccine is safe, it is effective, we don&#8217;t see this as a political issue, we&#8217;d certainly welcome that engagement.</p>



<p>Q And about those Texas Democrats, since the Vice President met with these Texas Democratic lawmakers, five of them have now tested positive for COVID-19. Is there any safety concern about her spending time around the President until a certain amount of time has passed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I would say the &#8212; I think the Vice President’s Office put out that she was tested, and that she did &#8212; there was no detection of COVID-19. They also put out some specific details about their proximity to the individuals who tested positive as well.</p>



<p>We take these precautions incredibly seriously and abide by the health &#8212; the guidance of our health and medical experts.</p>



<p>Q Do officials here wish that those Texas Democrats would have been more careful and taken more precautions like wearing masks on the flight here?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Again, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m going to be in a position here to assess what safety precautions they may or may not have taken. Obviously, these individuals were out there trying to elevate the issue of an individual&#8217;s right to vote. We &#8212; we, of course, hope everybody abides by public health guidelines. That&#8217;s what we certainly recommend.</p>



<p>But the Vice President &#8212; what’s important for everybody to know is that the Vice President was tested. She, of course, takes these precautions seriously, and we would follow any advice our public health officials give us.</p>



<p>Q And can you tell us anything else about the nature of her trip to Walter Reed yesterday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yes. She was &#8212; it was a &#8212; it was a visit that was scheduled for several weeks, long before the visit of the Texas legislators &#8212; a routine appointment, which she had had again scheduled several weeks ago.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Kelly.</p>



<p>Q And just to button that up: She and the President have been in the same room since she had that test? There&#8217;s no separation of the President and the Vice President?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: There haven&#8217;t been additional precautions taken, no.</p>



<p>Q On China, can you help us understand why the President &#8212; I asked a couple of questions today &#8212; was not, sort of, in the same posture we&#8217;ve seen toward Russia, where he has called out Russia publicly to stop?</p>



<p>And from what we know based on the administration&#8217;s findings, this is China paying cyber criminals to carry out &#8212; whereas, in Russia, our understanding is Putin may have some looser relationship or perhaps some ability to direct criminal actors, but not that connection. So, we gave the President an opportunity to address the China issue today; he seemed to pull his punches and not go after China. Why?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I would say, first, Kelly, that that was not the intention he was trying to project. He takes malicious cyberactivity incredibly seriously. The effort and the &#8212; to engage and unite an unprecedented group of our allies and partners was something that was under his direction.</p>



<p>And he felt &#8212; he continues to feel it&#8217;s important to lead from a position of strength in close coordination with our partners and allies around the world. And he takes malicious cyberactivity &#8212; whether it&#8217;s from Russia or China; whomever the actors may be &#8212; quite seriously. And I think our efforts to lead on this should be an indication of that.</p>



<p>Q On COVID, does the administration think it is appropriate, at this time, to try to do more tracking on breakthrough cases since there are more reports of that, and that&#8217;s not something the CDC has been following, except when it&#8217;s hospitalizations? Should more data collection take place?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: It&#8217;s a great question. I&#8217;ll have to talk to my health &#8212; our health and medical experts about the benefits of that tracking, and how they see that as a public health priority.</p>



<p>I will note that what we&#8217;ve continued to see is that the individuals &#8212; 99.5 percent of people who are being hospitalized and dying of COVID are not vaccinated. The individuals who &#8212; who are &#8212; who have been &#8212; who have gotten COVID, I should say &#8212; a number of these individuals we&#8217;ve been talking about from a public manner have been getting mild cases, have not been hospitalized.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s, of course, no one&#8217;s preference to get any form, but they have been asymptomatic and that is showing that the vaccine is actually working.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q On the virus, the President spoke this morning about the economic boom the country is undergoing.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yep.</p>



<p>Q But stock and oil prices fell today, in part because of rising concerns about the Delta variant. Is the administration &#8212; is the President considering reinstating mask requirements at all &#8212; both for health, but also for economic reasons?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I would say that we are &#8212; we look &#8212; our health and medical experts &#8212; look closely at the broad swath of data across the country. And I would remind you all that almost 70 percent of adults are still vaccinated in this country. We are not in the place we were two months, three months, six months ago, as it relates to our fight with the virus.</p>



<p>It is still underway. We are still battling the virus. There&#8217;s no question. And as the President said just on Friday, this has become a &#8220;pandemic of the unvaccinated,&#8221; in that that is where we are seeing hospitalizations, where we are seeing deaths.</p>



<p>We certainly have seen &#8212; we, of course, have seen the movements in the stock market. We also know that unemployment is down, economic growth is up, job creation is up, wages are up, and we can assure people we are still at war with the virus, even as we&#8217;ve seen progress made over the last several months.</p>



<p>Q One more also on COVID. I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve seen an alternate on the women&#8217;s gymnastics team has tested positive while in Japan. Any specific precautions the White House is taking with the First Lady&#8217;s travel to ensure her safety as she goes over there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, we are aware of, of course, COVID-19 cases among a handful of athletes. We’re monitoring the situation, wishing a speedy recovery to those who have tested positive.</p>



<p>Public health remains a central priority for the games. The government of Japan and the IOC have very strict protocols, and they are taking careful safety precautions to keep the athletes and the public safe.</p>



<p>Nothing has changed in terms of our plans for the U.S. delegation. Our team will be following very strict protoc- &#8212; safety and health protocols, limiting engagement with the public, and keeping our footprint as small as possible.</p>



<p>Our COVID team at the White House, as well as health officials at the IOC and the government of Japan all agree that the stringent protocols and health measures in place will keep &#8212; will keep them safe. But, of course, we continue to monitor individuals (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q Anything specific with the First Lady&#8217;s travel?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: There is nothing new. Nothing has changed as it relates to her travel or the travel of the delegation.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Earlier today, the President said he wasn&#8217;t sure whether Facebook had done enough since last week to combat misinformation. Is there anything that the White House can point to generally that perhaps indicates that companies are getting the message?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I think it&#8217;s a &#8212; as I, kind of, started off in response to Josh, I would just go back to the point that our fight is not with one social media platform; it is with the virus. And we have a role, who &#8212; everybody has a role in combating misinformation.</p>



<p>In terms of monitoring whether there have been steps that have been taken, I mean, there are things that you all can assess. There&#8217;s no secret monitoring, right? You all can assess as media organizations and companies as well. Do you have access to information from these platforms as to who is receiving misinformation? I don&#8217;t think that information has been released. Do you know how the algorithms are working at any of these platforms? I don&#8217;t think that information has been released.</p>



<p>But again, this is not about one platform. This is about misinformation that we&#8217;re seeing travel around, into the minds &#8212; the inboxes, the minds, the &#8212; of individuals, of people around the country &#8212; inaccurate information that is preventing people from taking the step to getting vaccinated. And that is, of course, a public health concern for us.</p>



<p>Q One quick follow-up, just to button it down: On the Senate calendar for Wednesday &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yeah?</p>



<p>Q So, the White House has no pause at this point about going forward with the cloture vote on Wednesday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: It is the decision of the Leader &#8212; of Leader Schumer on the timing and schedule of the Senate votes.</p>



<p>I will note, again, that it has been about four weeks since the President and bipartisan members stood outside together and announced an agreement. Lots of work has happened. Lots of good work together &#8212; bipartisan work &#8212; has happened, but we believe it&#8217;s time to move forward with &#8212; with this vote with congressional action.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Anne.</p>



<p>Q Two quickly on Guantanamo, and then I have one other thing. Can you be a little more precise about what the President’s timeline is for closure of Guantanamo? For example, does he think, as some advocates have suggested, that it should be closed in this, his first year in office? If not, does he have a deadline?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t have a new deadline to outline here for you today.</p>



<p>Q So, just closure when it can be closed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, as you know, Anne, there are several components of this process. It includes notifications and consultations with Congress. It&#8217;s not something where one individual, even the President of the United States, can do it on his own.</p>



<p>Q And then on military commissions, 10 of the remaining 39 detainees are eligible for military commission prosecution. As you know, the chief prosecutor has retired with no announcement of a replacement ahead of the first major trial of the Biden administration under that protocol. What is the administration&#8217;s plan for military commissions? And does the President continue to believe that it is an appropriate way to deal with the remaining detainees?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I &#8212; nothing has changed about the appropriateness of &#8212; or his view &#8212; our view, the President&#8217;s view of the appropriateness of the commissions. I can certainly check with the Department of Defense and national security team if there&#8217;s additional &#8212;</p>



<p>Q And lastly, there&#8217;s some new Havana Syndrome cases or suspected cases. Is the administration now prepared to say that it believes Russia is responsible for this string of attacks? And what is the President doing to protect U.S. diplomats and others from these kinds of attacks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, the NSC &#8212; the National Security Council &#8212; is coordinating a full review of intelligence reporting to ascertain whether there may be previously unreported incidents that fit a broader pattern.</p>



<p>At this time, we still don&#8217;t know the cause of these incidents or whether they constitute an attack of some kind by a foreign actor. These are areas of active inquiry, something that our intelligence community is working on and very focused on.</p>



<p>Go ahead</p>



<p>Q Jen, thanks so much.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yeah.</p>



<p>Q The infrastructure framework: If it fails to advance on Wednesday, what&#8217;s the backup plan? Is the President committed to making sure there is a bipartisan component, or will Democrats go it alone?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: We&#8217;re not quite there yet. There is a lot of good work that&#8217;s happened. Two days is a lifetime in Washington, so I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re going to make predictions of the death of the infrastructure package.</p>



<p>Q Can you share some more about what possible payfors the President&#8217;s team has proposed that might fall into the category of things Republicans have not already rejected and that the White House has not already rejected?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I understand the question, certainly. I &#8212; those conversations and discussions are having &#8212; are being had among the bipartisan group that is finalizing this piece of legislation.</p>



<p>And while there was agreement, of course, on the support for the IRS step that would have just ensured that some of the wealthiest Americans paid what they owed in taxes, some have backed away from that.</p>



<p>There are other ways that they&#8217;re discussing. We&#8217;re open to alternatives &#8212; very open to alternatives from this end, but we&#8217;ll let those conversations happen privately and be supportive of them from our end.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Another payfors question: The President was, of course, insistent that the payfors not include an increase in the gas tax, but the agreement does rely on things like public-private partnerships that typically use tolls to pay for the infrastructure.</p>



<p>So can you talk about the difference in user fees? Is it &#8212; why &#8212; why is tolling and other user fees okay, but gas taxes are not as a mechanism for being for some of this?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I mean, his fundamental base point is that we can&#8217;t raise taxes for individuals making less than $400,000 a year. In terms of the specific tolling payfor, I&#8217;d have to get more specific details on that. But in his view, nothing violates his commitment on the $400,000.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q Thanks, Jen. The American Academy of Pediatrics today recommended that everyone wear a mask in schools this fall, regardless of their vaccination status &#8212; that that&#8217;s the only way to keep kids safe.</p>



<p>The CDC guidance does not go that far. It says if you are vaccinated, you can go without a mask, but locals could decide universal masking.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve heard you say repeatedly that the President leans on his trusted medical and health advisors, but would the President like to see masking in all schools this fall?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: The President is going to rely on the recommendations of the CDC, and also local school districts will make their own decisions based on the public avail- &#8212; publicly available health guidelines. That&#8217;s always how it&#8217;s worked, and I think it will continue to work that way moving forward.</p>



<p>Q Dr. Fauci, today, on CNN gave an interview, and he said that these different recommendations &#8212; the Pediatric Association, the CDC, local jurisdictions &#8212; that these types of recommendations can be confusing because they are conflicting or different in some places. What does the White House say to Americans and to parents who may be confused hearing one thing this morning from the AAP, knowing the CDC has something different. How do you sort through all of that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: As a parent myself, it can be confusing. I think we acknowledge that. We rely, from the federal government, on the guidance of the CDC, and that&#8217;s how we make recommendations on public health issues from the federal government.</p>



<p>There will be different decisions made by school districts, just like there will be different decisions made by local communities. We certainly understand and recognize that, but we will continue to rely on the CDC for guidelines and guidance.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q So, now that caseload numbers are rising with the Delta variant, is there something that the Biden administration wished it had done differently to avoid getting to this point, to get us to a better position by now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I don&#8217;t know that there were many people who were predicting different impacts of different variants over time. I mean, the steps that we took &#8212; we ensured there was enough vaccine across the country and in communities to make sure anybody who wanted to get vaccinated could get vaccinated. We&#8217;ve invested in local messengers to ensure that trusted voices are getting out into local communities. We&#8217;ve relied on tactics that we&#8217;ve seen work effectively, whether it&#8217;s mobile units or empowering and engaging and funding doctors and medical experts to get out into local communities.</p>



<p>We also always knew there would be ups and downs in the fight against a virus that is evolving and changing. And that&#8217;s one of the reasons that we&#8217;ve been calling out misinformation &#8212; the impact of misinformation.</p>



<p>I mean, we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; just over the last couple of days, there was a poll that showed that about 20 percent of the public thinks that microchips are embedded in vaccines. Now, we all know that&#8217;s inaccurate and not true. But why does 20 percent of the public think it? Is it is it one platform&#8217;s fault? No. Is it one outlets fault? No. But we all have a responsibility to make sure accurate information is out there.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s one &#8212; that is our effort to make sure people know they need to be informed and be thoughtful about information they&#8217;re getting and the sources of it.</p>



<p>Q One question on the cybersecurity issue. Obviously, the attribution to China today on the ransomware attack &#8212; does the United States use ransomware attacks in its cyber-offensive programs?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I don’t have anything about our intelligence or use of cyber act- &#8212; or actions or intelligence that I&#8217;m going to convey from here.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Following up about misinformation &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Oh, go ahead. I&#8217;ll go to you at &#8212; well, let me just go like that. Go ahead. Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Does the President believe that those who mislead Congress should be prosecuted?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Who mislead Congress?</p>



<p>Q Yeah. I mean, it&#8217;s the Department of Justice&#8217;s decision not to prosecute Wilbur Ross. Just wondering if there&#8217;s a general rule of whether he feels he should be prosecuted if they mislead Congress.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I would point you to the Department of Justice on that case. I don&#8217;t have any more details from here.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q A follow-up on misinformation on social media. I heard you say that all options are on the table, including maybe legal. Would that mean potential legal action against the 12 that have come of concern for misinformation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: All I was conveying is I&#8217;m not taking &#8212; I think the question was about legislative action, and I said that&#8217;s up to Congress and I&#8217;m not here to take options off of the table. That&#8217;s Congress&#8217;s purview to determine how they&#8217;re going to move forward.</p>



<p>Q (Inaudible.) And a follow-up: Does that mean if is up to the purview of Congress that the administration or President Biden is seeing Section 230 a little differently &#8212; reforms to Section 230 that protect social media companies for third-party information?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: You know, I think the President has been pretty clear in the past that he believes there&#8217;s a responsibility of all platforms, including social media platforms, about the information that is traveling on their sites, but I don&#8217;t have anything new &#8212; nothing new about his position on that issue.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Francesca.</p>



<p>Q Thanks, Jen. Quick point of clarification on immigration first, though.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Sure.</p>



<p>Q Is the pathway to citizenship that the President supports in the budget bill for all undocumented immigrants? Or is it the more narrow group of TPS holders, essential workers, DREAMers, as well as farm laborers?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: We&#8217;ll let Senate leaders put out the specifics in the reconciliation bill. We certainly support the &#8212; using the reconciliation package as a &#8212; as a platform and a forum for moving immigration protections forward, but we&#8217;ll let leaders in Congress speak to what&#8217;s included.</p>



<p>Q Okay. And on voting rights, is the White House worried that if new federal voting legislation does not pass before August 6th, which is the anniversary of the signing of the Voting Rights Act of 1965, that it won&#8217;t happen before next November?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t think we draw that timeline conclusion, no.</p>



<p>Go ahead. Oh, go ahead, Asma. Go ahead. Go ahead, Asma.</p>



<p>Q Okay, sure. On immigration, some leading immigration advocates have suggested they do intend &#8212; expect the Supreme Court to uphold Judge Hanen&#8217;s ruling on the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals program. At this point, does the administration have any other options to protect DACA or DREAMer kids? Or is, really, a congressional route the only route that you all see?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I think, as the President&#8217;s statement made clear, a congressional route is the way to make it permanent. And certainly, our Department of Justice has also indicated their intention to fight this effort even after the ruling on Friday as well.</p>



<p>Q So, any interim actions, I guess, before Congress were to act, specifically on the DACA program?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I think, again, as the statement made clear, congressional action is the way to make it permanent. And that&#8217;s something the President has long supported and will continue to advocate for.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Going back on voting rights real quick, I spoke with Texas State Representative Bowers this morning, who now says it&#8217;s actually six members who have COVID that are in the delegation. But she said that they are worried that nothing is going to come from the administration by that August 6th &#8212; when (inaudible) ends.</p>



<p>And so she&#8217;s wondering: Is there any kind of movement that we can see from the President coming out by that time? I know we still don&#8217;t &#8212; you know, we don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s going &#8212; anything on the schedule, but is there anything that he&#8217;s planning to say or do?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Do you mean the passage of the Voting Rights &#8212; of the bill? Or what would do you mean exactly?</p>



<p>Q On &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, what are they &#8212; are they expecting in terms of the passage of the legislation or what are &#8212;</p>



<p>Q Exactly. She&#8217;s wor- &#8212; they&#8217;re worried that nothing is going to happen by August the 6th, and so that was a big concern when I spoke with her this morning, that there&#8217;s no movement that&#8217;s going to be coming from the administration.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, it would require Congress passing the For the People Act for the President to sign it into law. He can&#8217;t &#8212; that&#8217;s &#8212; the action would be first on Congress, not on the President.</p>



<p>Q But him saying anything &#8212; coming out and saying, &#8220;I know we&#8217;ve already talked about the filibuster like 50 million times…&#8221;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Beyond the speech he gave last week?</p>



<p>Q Yes. That is exactly what they are &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I think he will continue to advocate for voting rights as a fundamental right for people across the country. That is something he has &#8212; gave a major speech on six days ago, and he will continue to look for opportunities to elevate that moving forward as well. Absolutely.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Thanks, Jen. I have a follow up to Peter&#8217;s question about Trump &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Sure.</p>



<p>Q &#8212; and I have my own vaccine question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Okay.</p>



<p>Q In my follow up, even if the administration doesn&#8217;t partner with the former President, would it consider highlighting or acknowledging, in a greater way, his role in creating the vaccines to assure the rural voters who still support President Trump and are hesitant to get the vaccine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I think you&#8217;re &#8212; do you have data to suggest that that&#8217;s the issue that&#8217;s preventing people from getting vaccinated?</p>



<p>Q Well, we&#8217;re seeing that the communities &#8212; the communities that have the lowest vaccination rates did seem to vote for President Trump.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Okay. But what I&#8217;m asking you is if information related to whether or not the former President got credit is leading people not to get vaccinated, or is it information like microchips in vaccines and it causing fertility issues, causing health issues. Because you&#8217;re drawing a few conclusions there that I haven&#8217;t seen in data, but maybe you have that information to provide.</p>



<p>Q No, but I think it&#8217;s just &#8212; it&#8217;s a &#8212; I think it&#8217;s an issue &#8212; I mean, I think it&#8217;s a common sense that these are people who supported him. These are people who are hesitant to get vaccinated. I don&#8217;t think it takes a lot to draw the conclusion.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, let me &#8212; let me be very clear. Our &#8212; our objective is to ensure all Americans will get vaccinated. That would be &#8212; of course, we&#8217;d love &#8212; we&#8217;d love that. Democrats, Republicans, independents &#8212; it&#8217;s not a political issue to us. The virus does not &#8212; (the Press Secretary swats at a fly) &#8212; sorry &#8212; the virus does not look at people&#8217;s party affiliation. We recognize that. The President is going to govern for all people.</p>



<p>What I&#8217;m conveying to you is you&#8217;re jumping to a few conclusions that I don&#8217;t think data backs up, in terms of what the impacts are. And what we&#8217;re seeing is that misinformation, traveling in a range of means &#8212; whether it&#8217;s social media platforms, some forms of media, some elected officials &#8212; is having the biggest factor as it relates to individuals not getting vaccinated because people don&#8217;t have access to accurate information.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Thank you, Jen. The President is about to meet with the King of Jordan shortly. This visit comes at a pivotal time, considering what&#8217;s happened in Jordan, the constant attack on U.S. forces in Syria and Iraq, and the Israeli government, to name a few. Does that mean that the White House is paying more attention now to the White &#8212; to the Middle East? And what do you hope this visit will achieve?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, we &#8212; we have been paying quite a bit of attention, we would argue, to the Middle East on a range of issues that you&#8217;ve highlighted, Nadia, whether it is the attacks that we&#8217;ve seen on bases in parts of the Middle East, or whether it is our desire, of course, to &#8212; to even move forward on lasting peace between the Israelis and the Palestinians.</p>



<p>And Jordan has been a key partner for some time, long before President Biden took office, to the United States, through many Presidents, in these efforts and these endeavors.</p>



<p>So, during &#8212; (the Press Secretary swats at a fly) &#8212; sorry, this is an aggressive fly. During the meeting &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; during the meeting, today &#8212; I apologize, this is a very &#8212;</p>



<p>Q It&#8217;s D.C.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: It is.</p>



<p>During the meeting today, we hope this will be an opportunity to highlight the enduring and strategic partnership between the United States and Jordan &#8212; a key security partner.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s also an opportunity to discuss the many challenges facing the Middle East and showcase Jordan&#8217;s leadership role in promoting peace and stability in the region. And certainly, we expect that everything from Middle East peace, to security in the region to be points of discussion &#8212; to Syria &#8212; to be points of discussion during the meeting this afternoon. We&#8217;ll have a readout after the meeting concludes.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Jen &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Thank you, Jen.</p>



<p>Q (Inaudible.) Oh, go ahead.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Oh, I&#8217;m sorry. We&#8217;ll go to your next. Go ahead. Yeah.</p>



<p>Q Let me take you to Ethiopia.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yeah.</p>



<p>Q The U.S. and the other countries have been supporting and end to the fighting in the Tigray region. And as the first step to end the fighting, the government in Ethiopia declared a unilateral ceasefire for the troops from the region. But TPLF &#8212; the Tigray Liberation Front &#8212; rejected the ceasefire, calling it a “sick joke.” And the TPLF continues the war, especially by deploying child soldiers in this conflict. And if the war continues there, thousands and thousands people will die. What is the Biden&#8217;s administration statement on TPLF’s refusal to accept the ceasefire and the use of children as soldiers? Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, certainly we take security and stability in Ethiopia quite seriously. I would point you to the State Department. I know my colleague Ned Price is briefing later this afternoon and giving you more details on what are work is, and engagement, and our view from the U.S. government.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Is the White House seeking any meetings with social media companies when you&#8217;re talking about misinformation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: We have been in regular touch from the beginning of the administration as &#8212; because we knew from the beginning that misinformation or disinformation and how it would travel out there into the world was going to be a challenge. So that has been something that has been ongoing since the beginning of the administration.</p>



<p>Q I also wanted to ask you &#8212; someone asked earlier about Republicans backing off the idea of increasing funding for the IRS.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yep.</p>



<p>Q When you&#8217;re talking about that and the President being open to other proposals, are you talking within the framework &#8212; the bipartisan framework or the reconciliation package or both?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: The bipartisan framework. That&#8217;s the deal we&#8217;re kind of &#8212; that is the discussion with Republicans. Of course, we would welcome Republican support for the reconciliation package, but we&#8217;re talking about specifically the payfors on the bipartisan infrastructure framework.</p>



<p>Q Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Go ahead, in the back.</p>



<p>Q Thank you. Will the White House publicly release information on posts that it considers misinformation on vaccines that it&#8217;s asked Facebook to block?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: First of all, we&#8217;ve not asked Facebook to block any individual posts. The way this works is that there are trending &#8212; there are trends that are out there on social media platforms. You&#8217;re aware of them. We&#8217;re aware of them. Anyone in the public can be aware of them.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also data that we look at that many media platforms, like many of you, also look at data in terms of trends and you report on it, which is not &#8212; to be expected, given the number of people who get their information from social media.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s up to social media platforms to determine what their application is of their own rules and regulations. And so we just certainly raise where we have concerns about information that&#8217;s inaccurate that is traveling out there in whatever platform it&#8217;s traveling on.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Thank you, Jen. Does the White House welcome the news that the Haitian Interim Prime Minister, Claude Joseph, is stepping aside and handing power to Ariel Henry?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, we have been encouraging, for several days now, Haitian political actors to work together and find a political way forward. So we&#8217;ve certainly seen news reports; we have not received an official notification through our embassy, but we welcome reports that Haitian political actors are working together to determine a path forward.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Yeah, thank you, Jen. As you know, the leader of the Belarusian opposition, Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, is in the country right now.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>Q She&#8217;s meeting with Jake Sullivan; she&#8217;s meeting with Secretary of State Blinken. Any chance that she will meet with President Biden?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: So, I think somebody asked this question a &#8212;</p>



<p>Q I&#8217;m sorry.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &#8212; little bit &#8212; oh no, it&#8217;s okay. It&#8217;s okay. It&#8217;s okay. She will be meeting with senior White House officials. There is not currently a meeting scheduled for her with the President.</p>



<p>Oh, go, Josh. What&#8217;s happening?</p>



<p>Q I just wanted to thank you, Jen, but, as a point of privilege, wanted to jump in: Canada announced it&#8217;s going to reopen its borders for U.S. citizens who are vaccinated on August 9th. Does the United States plan to reciprocate?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: We are continuing to review our travel restrictions. Any decisions about reopening travel will be guided by our public health and medical experts. We take this incredibly seriously, but we look and are guided by our own medical experts and not in a reci- &#8212; we&#8217;re not &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t look at it through a reciprocal intention.</p>



<p>Q Thanks.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Go ahead. Go ah- &#8212; Go ahead, in the middle. Yeah, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q Thank you. As you know, Senate Republicans have been calling on the President to withdraw his nominee to lead the Bureau of Land Management, Tracy Stone-Manning, over connections to this tree spiking incident in 1989. That escalated last week with this former Forest Service investigator coming forward with an account that contradicts what she&#8217;s told senators, as well as a man who was convicted in that case. Have those revelations changed the President&#8217;s view on that nominee at all?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: It has not. He stands by his nominee and looks forward to her getting confirmed.</p>



<p>Go ahead, in the middle.</p>



<p>Q Thanks, Jen. I appreciate it. I just had a quick follow up on the Facebook stuff. Did anybody from the administration this weekend talk with Facebook officials, given the President&#8217;s comments on Friday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Again, I think it&#8217;s important for all of you to note that we are not at war with any social media platform; we are at war with the virus &#8212;</p>



<p>Q (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &#8212; and we have been in regular touch since the beginning of the administration, as we knew that there are a range of entities, platforms, media organizations, public officials who all have a role in combating misinformation.</p>



<p>This is not personal. It is about fighting a virus that is still killing thousands of people. That&#8217;s our objective.</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone. Have a great day. I&#8217;ll talk to you tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q Jen, when will the President open up his East Room events to the full press like every other President?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: We’ll look forward to seeing you soon, Brian.</p>



<p>1:50 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and His Majesty King Abdullah II ibn Al Hussein, King of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan, Before Bilateral Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/19/remarks-by-president-biden-and-his-majesty-king-abdullah-ii-ibn-al-hussein-king-of-the-hashemite-kingdom-of-jordan-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 21:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 2:33 P.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, I&#8217;m &#8212; I want to welcome back to the White House a good, loyal, and decent friend, His Majesty.&#160; And we&#8217;ve been hanging out together for a long time.&#160; I met him back when he was in the situation his son is, when his father was alive&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>2:33 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m &#8212; I want to welcome back to the White House a good, loyal, and decent friend, His Majesty.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been hanging out together for a long time.&nbsp; I met him back when he was in the situation his son is, when his father was alive and I was a young senator.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s good to have him back in the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I want to thank you, Your Majesty, for your enduring and strategic relationship with the United States.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve always been there, and we will always be there for Jordan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in addition to that, we &#8212; we were talking &#8212; we had an opportunity to speak just a moment in the Diplomatic Room.&nbsp; And we talked about how our &#8212; our children and my children were &#8212;&nbsp; had to finish off their senior year in college on Zoom.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we talked about the COVID pro- &#8212; crisis.&nbsp; We were able to be a little bit of help to Jordan, and we hope to be able to help some more and &#8212; in this pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I also want to thank you for your vital leadership in the Middle East.&nbsp; You live in a tough neighborhood.&nbsp; And the fact is, I look forward to hearing from His Majesty about the pressing challenges that &#8212; (a cellphone disrupts the event) &#8212; that Jordan faces.&nbsp; And whoever&#8217;s &#8212; is that a call for me on the phone?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to stre- &#8212; to strengthen our bilateral cooperation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The world is changing.&nbsp; And you always &#8212; they always kid me.&nbsp; I’m always quoting Irish poets.&nbsp; It says &#8212; there was a famous poem &#8212; “All changed, changed utterly.&nbsp; A terrible beauty has been born.”&nbsp; But a lot has changed and a lot of opportunity, but also a lot of difficulty we’re going to have to work our way through.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, welcome.&nbsp; Welcome, welcome, welcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>KING ABDULLAH II:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Mr. President, thank you, as always, for the kindness that you showed me.&nbsp; And as you alluded to, I had the honor and the privilege of knowing you with my father decades ago.&nbsp; And so this is very warming for me to be able to see you in this position and to thank you for the generosity you always have shown me and my country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You alluded to supporting us with vaccines.&nbsp; So, on behalf of Jordan and the people of Jordan, thank you so much for the leadership you’ve shown not only in supporting our country, but fighting COVID internationally.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve set the standard for the rest of us to follow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We come together as always strong partners.&nbsp; We have, as you said, many challenges in our part of the world.&nbsp; I think many of us leaders from our part of the world will do the heavy lifting, which is what we need to do, on behalf of the United States.&nbsp; But you can always count on me, my country, and many of our colleagues in the region.&nbsp; A lot to do, sir, but with your leadership, we will prevail.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: &nbsp;Well, as my grandfather used to say: “With the grace of God and the goodwill to the neighbors,&#8221; we’ll be able to get a lot done.</p>



<p>Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>2:37 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Three Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/19/president-biden-announces-three-key-nominations-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 20:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following three individuals to serve in key roles: Tamara Cofman Wittes, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Middle East, United States Agency for International Development Judith D. Pryor, Nominee for First Vice President of the Export-Import Bank Graham Steele, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following three individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Tamara Cofman Wittes, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Middle East, United States Agency for International Development</li><li>Judith D. Pryor, Nominee for First Vice President of the Export-Import Bank</li><li>Graham Steele, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Financial Institutions, Department of the Treasury</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Tamara Cofman Wittes, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Middle East, United States Agency for International Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Tamara Cofman Wittes is a senior fellow in the Center for Middle East Policy at the Brookings Institution, where she focuses on U.S. policy in the Middle East. Wittes served as deputy assistant secretary of state for Near Eastern affairs from November of 2009 to January 2012. Wittes is a co-host of Rational Security, a weekly podcast on foreign policy and national security issues. Wittes joined Brookings in December of 2003. Previously, she served as a Middle East specialist at the U.S. Institute of Peace and director of programs at the Middle East Institute in Washington. She has also taught courses in international relations and security studies at Georgetown University. Wittes was one of the first recipients of the Rabin-Peres Peace Award, established by President Bill Clinton in 1997.</p>



<p>Wittes is the author of &#8220;Freedom’s Unsteady March: America’s Role in Building Arab Democracy&#8221; (Brookings Institution Press, 2008) and the editor of &#8220;How Israelis and Palestinians Negotiate: A Cross-Cultural Analysis of the Oslo Peace Process&#8221; (USIP, 2005). She holds a bachelor&#8217;s in Judaic and Near Eastern studies from Oberlin College, and a master&#8217;s and doctorate in government from Georgetown University. She is a founder of the Leadership Council for Women in National Security, and serves on the board of the National Democratic Institute. She is also a member of the Council on Foreign Relations and Women in International Security.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judith D. Pryor, Nominee for First Vice President of the Export-Import Bank</u></strong></p>



<p>Judith D. Pryor has over 25 years of leadership experience in international business, finance, trade, and public policy, primarily in the high tech, satellite, and international finance sectors. She currently serves as a Senate-confirmed member of the Export-Import Bank of the United States (EXIM) Board of Directors. Her portfolio encompasses Africa and the Middle East, renewable energy, storage and efficiency, and women and minority-owned businesses.</p>



<p>Ms. Pryor previously served for nearly seven years in the Obama-Biden Administration at OPIC, now the U.S. International Development Finance Corp. As Vice President, External Affairs she was responsible for congressional and public affairs, communications, and U.S. small business development. During her nearly seven-year tenure and as a member of the executive leadership team, OPIC’s portfolio grew by 50% to $21 billion.</p>



<p>Before entering public service, Ms. Pryor held senior leadership positions with companies in the satellite industry including WorldSpace Satellite Radio and COMSAT. She began her career in the Washington offices of Gray &amp; Co., continuing with the firm after its acquisition by Hill and Knowlton Public Affairs Worldwide. A native of Cleveland, Ohio, she holds a B.A. in Communication from Bowling Green State University and served on the BGSU Foundation Board from 2016-2019. She resides in Washington, DC with her husband and son.</p>



<p><strong><u>Graham Steele, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Financial Institutions, Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Graham Steele is an expert on financial regulation and financial institutions, with more than a decade of experience working at the highest levels of law and policy in Washington, D.C. Steele is currently the director of the Corporations and Society Initiative at Stanford Graduate School of Business, a research initiative that examines issues at the intersection of markets, business, and government to promote more accountable capitalism and governance.</p>



<p>Prior to joining Stanford GSB, Steele was a member of the staff of the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco. From 2015 to 2017, Graham was the Minority Chief Counsel for the United States Senate Committee on Banking, Housing &amp; Urban Affairs. From 2010 to 2015 he was a Legislative Assistant for United States Senator Sherrod Brown (D-OH), handling the Senator’s work as a member of the Senate Banking Committee. During that time, he also spent four years as the staff director of the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions &amp; Consumer Protection. Prior to joining Senator Brown’s staff, Steele was a policy counsel at Public Citizen’s Congress Watch in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>Steele received his bachelor’s degree in political science from the University of Rochester and his law degree from The George Washington University Law School. He is originally from Brookline, Massachusetts, and is a member of the Massachusetts State Bar.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/19/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-economy-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 18:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:43 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good morning.&#160; Tomorrow marks exactly six months since my administration began.&#160; I think it’s a fitting moment to take a look at our economy &#8212; where we were six months ago, what we’ve achieved since then, and what I believe we’ve &#8212; I believe where we’re headed.&#160;Before I took&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:43 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good morning.&nbsp; Tomorrow marks exactly six months since my administration began.&nbsp; I think it’s a fitting moment to take a look at our economy &#8212; where we were six months ago, what we’ve achieved since then, and what I believe we’ve &#8212; I believe where we’re headed.&nbsp;<br>Before I took office, there was a lot of folks out there &#8212; a lot of folks out there making some pretty bold predictions about how things would turn out.&nbsp; You might remember some of the predictions.&nbsp; That if I became President, we’d, quote, “see a depression the likes of which we’ve never seen.”&nbsp; End of quote.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, it’s true that the economy was sputtering before I got here, adding only 60,000 jobs per month for the three months before I was sworn in.&nbsp; But now, six months later, we’ve changed that.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ve gone from 60,000 jobs per month to 60,000 jobs every three days &#8212; more than 600,000 jobs per month since I took office.&nbsp; More than 3 million new jobs all told.&nbsp; That’s the fastest growth, I’m told, at this point in any administration’s history.<br><br>Another prediction &#8212; that is my favorite one, I must add &#8212; is that if I got elected, I’d bring the end to capitalism.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I never understood that one, but we’ve heard &#8212; we’ve heard it an awful lot.&nbsp; Well, in six months into my administration, the U.S. economy has experienced the highest economic growth rate in nearly 40 years.&nbsp;<br><br>And we know we’ve &#8212; and now we knew that we needed to launch a war-time effort to get the &#8212; America vaccinated and pass a powerful American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;<br><br>We did both those things.&nbsp; And now, the forecasters have doubled their projections for growth this year in the economy to 7 percent or higher. &nbsp;In fact, the U.S. is the only developed country in the world where growth projections today are stronger than they were before the pandemic hit.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, companies across the country are giving workers a raise.&nbsp; Unusual thing.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; And the number of new unemployment claims has been cut by more than half since I took office.&nbsp;<br><br>And by the way, two weeks ago, I issued a major executive order promoting fair and open competition, which is the cornerstone &#8212; the cornerstone of American capitalism, banning non-compete clauses that suppress workers’ wages; lowering the price of things like hearing aids, prescription drugs, Internet service; along with dozens of other actions.&nbsp;<br><br>Folks, it turns out capitalism is alive and very well.&nbsp; We’re making serious progress to ensure that it works the way it’s supposed to work: for the good of the American people.<br><br>So, for all those predictions of doom and gloom, six months in, here’s where we stand: record growth, record job creation, workers getting hard-earned breaks.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, we’ve brought this economy back from the brink.&nbsp; And we designed our strategy not only to provide for a temporary boost, but to lay the foundation for a long-term boom that brings everyone along.<br><br>You know, that’s why we designed the American Rescue Plan to help not just all those &#8212; everyone at once, but over the course of a full year and beyond so we could help families and small businesses weather the ups and downs of our &#8212; as the economy recovers from an historic pandemic. &nbsp;And I &#8212; there are going to be ups and downs.<br><br>We saw a great example of that just last week.&nbsp; For the first time, monthly payments began going out to nearly every working family raising a child in the United States of America.&nbsp; Thanks to the expanded Child Tax Credit in the American Rescue Plan: $300 a month going out for each child under the age of six, and $250 for every child 6 through 17, every month for the next six months, with more coming in the spring.&nbsp;<br><br>That money is a game-changer.&nbsp; For some, it’s a lifesaver.&nbsp; Think of the single mom, struggling to put food on the table each month.&nbsp; The parent who has to tell their kid, “I’m sorry, honey, but we can’t afford those dance classes or the sports team you want to play on this fall.&nbsp; We can’t do it.”&nbsp; You know, they can’t wait for the credit against their taxes to be coming next year as a tax credit.&nbsp; They need cash in their pockets today.&nbsp;<br><br>For families with the least, this money will do the most &#8212; dramatically reducing child poverty in America.&nbsp; And for millions of middle-class families, it will give them a little bit of breathing room every month.&nbsp; That’s just one example of how we’re building an economy from the bottom up and the middle out. &nbsp;<br><br>But despite that progress, we cannot afford to be complacent.&nbsp; We know that our economic recovery hinges on getting the pandemic under control.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, and by fully vaccinating 160 million Americans, 80 percent of our seniors, we’ve fundamentally changed the course of the pandemic &#8212; from one that threatens all Americans, to a disease that has the most severe impacts only on the unvaccinated people in the country.&nbsp; But we can’t let up, especially since and because of the Delta variant, which is more transmis- &#8212; more transmissible and more dangerous.&nbsp;<br><br>Unfortunately, cases are now rising, particularly in communities with very low vaccination rates.&nbsp; Just four states account for nearly 40 percent &#8212; four states, 40 percent of all cases last week.&nbsp; Virtually all hospitalizations and deaths are occurring among unvaccinated Americans.&nbsp; These tragedies are avoidable.&nbsp;<br><br>The data couldn’t be clearer: If you’re fully vaccinated, you have a high degree of protection against severe illness, hospitalization, and death.&nbsp; If you’re unvaccinated, you are not protected.&nbsp;So, please, please get vaccinated. &nbsp;Get vaccinated now. &nbsp;It works. &nbsp;It’s safe. &nbsp;It’s free. &nbsp;It’s convenient.<br><br>You know, this virus doesn’t have to hold you back any longer.&nbsp; It doesn’t have to hold our economy back any longer.&nbsp; But the only way we put it behind us is if more Americans get vaccinated.<br><br>We also know that as our economy has come roaring back, we’ve seen some price increases.&nbsp; Some folks have raised worries that this could be a sign of persistent inflation.&nbsp; But that’s not our view.&nbsp; Our experts believe and the data shows that most of the price increases we’ve seen are &#8212; were expected and expected to be temporary.<br><br>The reality is, you can’t flip the global economic light back on and not expect this to happen.&nbsp; As demand returns, there’s going to be global supply chain challenges.&nbsp; We’ve seen that in semi-conductors, which are used in automobiles.&nbsp; That global shortage has slowed vehicle production, creating a temporary spike in car prices.&nbsp; That’s a real challenge.&nbsp; And my administration is doing everything we can to address it.&nbsp; But again, these disruptions are temporary.&nbsp;<br><br>Lumber prices are another example.&nbsp; They spiked early in our recovery, but in recent weeks, they’ve began to fall &#8212; they’ve fallen by more than 50 percent.&nbsp;<br><br>In the hospitality industry, prices are returning to where they used to be.&nbsp; Economists call all of these things “transitory effects.”&nbsp; And they account for about 60 percent of the price increases we’ve seen over the last few months.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, I want to be clear: My administration understands that if we were to ever experience unchecked inflation over the long term that would pose real challenges to our economy.&nbsp; So while we’re confident that isn’t what we are seeing today, we’re going to remain vigilant about any response that is needed.&nbsp;<br><br>As I made clear to Chairman Powell of the Federal Reserve when we met recently, the Fed is independent.&nbsp; It should take whatever steps it deems necessary to support a strong, durable economic recovery.&nbsp; But whatever different views some might have on current price increases, we should be united on one thing: passage of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, which we shook hands on.&nbsp; We shook hands on it.&nbsp; And my Build Back Better plan will be a force for achieving lower prices for Americans looking ahead.&nbsp; It’s another reason why these investments are so important.&nbsp;<br><br>If we make a prudent, multi-year investments in better roads, bridges, transit systems, and high-speed Internet, and a modern, resilient electric grid, here’s what will happen: It breaks up the bottlenecks in our economy. &nbsp;Goods get to consumers more rapidly and less expensively.&nbsp; Small businesses create and innovate much more seamlessly.&nbsp; If we increase the availability of quality, affordable childcare, eldercare, paid leave, more people will enter the workforce.&nbsp;<br><br>These steps will enhance our productivity &#8212; raising wages without raising prices.&nbsp; That won’t increase inflation.&nbsp; It will take the pressure off of inflation, give a boost to our workforce, which leads to lower prices in the years ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>So, if your primary concern right now is inflation, you should be even more enthusiastic about this plan.&nbsp; And as we promote &#8212; as we promote fair competition in our economy through the executive order I mentioned, it will drive down prices even further.&nbsp; New businesses will get in the game, competing against those giant corporations who have been free to ramp up prices because they haven’t had any real competition.<br><br>Look, the bottom line is this: What the best companies do and what we as a country should do is make smart, sustainable investments with appropriate financing to make this nation more productive, to advance America’s leadership on clean energy to win the jobs of the future while meeting the threat of climate change, and to ensure that all working Americans benefit from the growth they’re helping produce.&nbsp;<br><br>The independent experts who have analyzed my plans have found that they would do just that: expand output and enable millions of Americans to enter the labor workforce now, just this year &#8212; not just for the next &#8212; but not just this year, but for decades in the future.&nbsp; It’s not temporary.<br><br>This is the best strategy to create millions of jobs and lift up the middle-class families and grow wages and keep prices affordable for the long term.&nbsp;<br><br>What we can’t do is go back to the&nbsp;same old trickle-down theories that gave us nearly $2 trillion in deficit-financed corporate tax giveaways that did nothing to make our economy more productive or resilient. &nbsp;The same people who cheered on that approach are now telling us it isn’t [is] a problem if big companies have actually to compete for workers and offer them a fair wage with some dignity.<br><br>I could not disagree more.&nbsp; We can’t go back to the old, failed thinking.&nbsp; We need to grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out, as I’ve said before.&nbsp;<br><br>The investments I’m proposing are investments the American people want and investments that our country needs.&nbsp; And if we get this done, a wide range of independent forecasters project that it will have an incredibly significant impact on GDP and jobs &#8212; good-paying jobs with prevailing wages.&nbsp; And the majority of these jobs will go to people without a college degree.&nbsp;<br><br>I’ve said it before, and it’s true: This is a blue-collar blueprint for building an American economy back.&nbsp; Simply put, we can’t afford not to make these investments.&nbsp; And we’re going to pay for them responsibly as well, by ensuring that our largest corporations and the very wealthiest among us pay their fair share by reforming our international tax system with a minimum global tax, which we’ve led the world to agree to.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me close with this: When I arrived in office, it had been a long time since the government had worked for the people.&nbsp; Things had been great for big corporations and folks at the top.&nbsp; Those 55 major corporations that paid zero in income tax while making billions in profits, they had no complaints.&nbsp;<br><br>But when I took office, I made a commitment &#8212; a commitment to the American people that we were going to change that paradigm so working families could have a fighting chance again to get a good education; to get a good job and a raise; to take care of the elderly parent or the child with the disability and still be able to go out and earn a good living; to stop losing hours of their lives stuck in traffic because the streets are crumbling; or waiting for slow, spotty Internet to connect them to the world.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s what the economy we’re building is all about. &nbsp;That’s why we passed the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; And that’s why we need the investment of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and my Build Back Better plan.&nbsp;<br><br>Our economy has come a long way over the last six months.&nbsp; We can’t slow down now.&nbsp; We can make this boom we’re experiencing today one that will ensure that all Americans have an opportunity to share in it for years to come.&nbsp; And we can show the world that American democracy can deliver for the people.&nbsp;<br><br>I look forward to continuing to build this economy.&nbsp; And I’m incredibly optimistic about what we’re going to be able to build together in the next six months and the years to come.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all for listening.&nbsp; May God bless you.&nbsp; And I’ll take a few questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, you said last week that companies and platforms like Facebook are “killing people” by letting them &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me (inaudible) precisely what I said.&nbsp; I’m glad you asked me that question.&nbsp; One, I had just read that &#8212; on the Facebook &#8212; Facebook pointed out that &#8212; it was pointed out that Facebook, of all the misinformation, 60 percent of that misinformation came from 12 individuals.&nbsp; That’s what the article said.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I was asked that question about what do I think is happening.&nbsp; Facebook isn’t killing people; these 12 people who are out there giving misinformation &#8212; anyone listening to it is getting hurt by it.&nbsp; It’s killing people.&nbsp; It’s bad information.<br><br>My hope is that Facebook, instead of taking it personally &#8212; that somehow I’m saying Facebook is killing people &#8212; that they would do something about the misinformation &#8212; the outrageous informa- &#8212; misinformation about the vaccine.&nbsp; That’s what I meant.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have they done enough in your opinion to stop &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I haven’t &#8212; to be completely honest with you, I don’t know that they did anything today.&nbsp; Up to &#8212; over the weekend, I don’t think they had.&nbsp; But I don’t know.&nbsp; I don’t know the answer to that question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you hold them accountable if they don’t do more to stop the spread?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m &#8212; when you say “hold accountable,” I just want to &#8212; I’m not trying to hold people account- &#8212; I’m trying make people to look at themselves.&nbsp; Look in the mirror.&nbsp; Think about that misinformation going to your son, your daughter, your relatives, someone you love.&nbsp; That’s what I’m asking.<br><br>All the way in the back.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; At what point would you consider inflation unchecked to a point at which you would either consider taking action or you would want to see the Fed take action?<br><br>And secondly, why do you believe that the budget bill is appropriate legislation for a pathway to citizenship?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, first of all, I think we need to find pathways to citizenship.&nbsp; The budget bill is an appropriate way to get around the filibuster to be able to make a judgment as to whether or not they should have a pathway.&nbsp; That’s for the Parli- &#8212; Parliamentarian to decide, though &#8212; not for Joe Biden to decide.<br><br>Your first ques- &#8212; part of the question was?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It was on inflation.&nbsp; You mentioned unchecked inflation.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nobody suggesting there&#8217;s unchecked inflation on the way &#8212; no serious economist.&nbsp; That’s totally different.&nbsp;<br><br>I mean, look, the stock market is higher than it has been in all of history, even went down this month &#8212; even down this month.<br><br>Now, I don’t look at the stock market as a means by which to judge the economy like my predecessor did.&nbsp; But he&#8217;d be very &#8212; he’d be talking to you every day for the last five months about how the stock market is so high &#8212; higher than any time in history, still higher than any time in history.<br><br>So, that’s not how I judge whether or not we have economic growth.<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, on China and cyber hacking &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; She jumps up before you do.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Effectively, your administration is naming and shaming China, but no sanctions.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; And is that effective enough?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They’re still determining exactly what happened.&nbsp; The investigation is not finished.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all very much.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On China real quick &#8212; on China real quick: What is your understanding of the biggest difference between what they&#8217;ve done versus what Russia has done in terms of cyber hacking?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’d take a longer explanation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have all the time in the world.&nbsp; What is it?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, we don’t.&nbsp; I have to go see the King of Jordan.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, to the best of my knowledge &#8212; and I’m getting a report tomorrow morning on this, a detailed report &#8212; my understanding is that the Chinese government, not unlike the Russian government, is not doing this themselves, but are protecting those who are doing it and maybe even accommodating them being able to do it.&nbsp; That may be the difference.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should the Olympics go forward, Mr. President?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They are.<br><br>12:02 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
