<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 13:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Joint Statement Following Meeting of President Joseph R. Biden and His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan in&#160;Jeddah</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/16/joint-statement-following-meeting-of-president-joseph-r-biden-and-his-majesty-king-abdullah-ii-of-jordan-in-jeddah/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 13:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57716</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and His Majesty King Abdullah II met today in Jeddah and reaffirmed the enduring strength of the strategic friendship between the United States and Jordan. The meeting took place during the Summit of the leaders of the United States, the Gulf Cooperation Council members, Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan. The two leaders&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and His Majesty King Abdullah II met today in Jeddah and reaffirmed the enduring strength of the strategic friendship between the United States and Jordan. The meeting took place during the Summit of the leaders of the United States, the Gulf Cooperation Council members, Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan.<br> <br>The two leaders discussed efforts to further advance the close and historic partnership between the United States and Jordan, and coordination in addressing regional and international challenges. They noted the political and economic value of regional integration, for which Jordan can serve as an important hub for cooperation and investment in infrastructure, energy, water, food security and climate. The President noted the importance of the trilateral cooperation mechanism with Egypt and Iraq as an example of positive regional collaboration.<br><br>President Biden announced the intention of the United States to enter into a new memorandum of understanding (MOU) for assistance for Jordan, in which the United States plans to make a commitment to support the provision of no less than $1.45 billion per year in U.S. bilateral foreign assistance to Jordan, beginning in FY 2023 and ending in FY 2029. One of the most significant bilateral instruments of its kind, the MOU represents a major U.S. political commitment to Jordan’s stability and the durability of the partnership. The MOU is designed to address Jordan’s extraordinary needs, supports King Abdullah II’s economic reform program, and ensure the long-term strength of the close partnership between the United States and Jordan.<br><br>King Abdullah II thanked the President for the United States’ friendship and continued support for Jordan. He stressed the importance of this support to the Kingdom’s economic reform plans, its efforts to realize more sustainable economic growth, and to mitigate the impact of regional crises.<br> <br>President Biden reaffirmed the United States’ unwavering support to Jordan as a key ally and a force for peace in the region, and for King Abdullah II’s leadership.<br> <br>King Abdullah II underlined the crucial role of the United States in efforts to support regional security, stability, peace and prosperity.<br> <br>President Biden and King Abdullah II highlighted the strong defense partnership between the two countries, and reiterated commitment to their partnership in the fight against terrorism, including through cooperation within the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS and the Aqaba Process.<br><br>The two leaders reaffirmed their commitment to continue working for a just, lasting and comprehensive peace between Israel and the Palestinians on the basis of the two-state solution. They stressed the importance of fostering political and economic horizons through confidence-building measures that would set the ground for meaningful Palestinians-Israeli negotiations.  The also emphasized the importance of including the Palestinians in regional cooperation projects. The two leaders stressed the necessity of upholding the historic status quo in Jerusalem’s holy sites, and the President underlined the key role of the Hashemite Custodianship in that regard. King Abdullah II also expressed appreciation for U.S. support to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA). <br><br>Recalling United Nations General Assembly resolutions ES-11/1 and ES-11/2, on March 2 and March 24, respectively, demanding the Russian Federation to immediately, completely and unconditionally withdraw all of its military forces from the territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders, the two leaders reaffirmed their commitment to the sovereignty, independence, territorial integrity and unity of Ukraine. They condemned violations of international humanitarian law and violations of human rights in areas of conflict, calling for abiding by international humanitarian law. The leaders also confirmed their intention to increase cooperation to counter the impact of the conflict in Ukraine on global food and energy security.<br> <br>President Biden and King Abdullah II stressed the need to find a political solution to the Syrian crisis, consistent with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2254 (2015). President Biden expressed appreciation for Jordan’s hosting of Syrian refugees. His Majesty thanked the President for continued U.S. support to help Jordan in its efforts to meet the needs of refugees. The two leaders urged sufficient international support to refugees and host countries.<br> <br>The two leaders emphasized commitment to the stability and security of Iraq, and the need to protect the significant progress the country has made towards peace and stability.<br><br>The two leaders intend to remain in close consultation and further develop the deep friendship between the United States and Jordan.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the GCC + 3 Summit&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/16/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-gcc-3-summit-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 12:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2:09 P.M. AST&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, thank you.&#160; It’s good to be once more together with so many vital partners and to strengthening our cooperation on the future of this consequential region of the world. &#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; I’d like to thank our Saudi hosts for inviting the United States to join this summit and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>2:09 P.M. AST&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; It’s good to be once more together with so many vital partners and to strengthening our cooperation on the future of this consequential region of the world. &nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’d like to thank our Saudi hosts for inviting the United States to join this summit and for their hospitality in welcoming all of us.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A great deal has changed since I visited this region when I served as Vice President of the United States, both on the world stage and in the Middle East.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Around the world, we’re seeing efforts to undermine the rules-based order: with China’s increasingly coercive actions in the Indo-Pacific and beyond; with Russia’s brutal and unprovoked war against its neighboring Ukraine; and with Iran’s destabilizing activities. &nbsp;Here in the Middle East, we’ve also seen critical changes.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For the first time since 9/11, an American President is visiting this region without American troops being engaged in combat &#8212; in a combat mission in the region.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’ll always honor the bravery, the selfishness [sic] &#8212; selflessness of the &#8212; and the sacrifices of the Americans who served, including my son, Major Beau Biden, who was stationed in Iraq for a year.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we’ll never forget the memory of the seven thousand fifty- &#8212; 7,054 American troops who made the ultimate sacrifice while serving in Iraq, Afghanistan, and elsewhere over the last two decades.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But today, I am proud to be able to say that the era of land wars in the region &#8212; wars involving huge numbers of American forces &#8212; is not underway.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We &#8212; but we maintain both the capacity and the absolute determination to suppress the terrorist threat wherever we find it.&nbsp; We’ve demonstrated that this year &#8212; eliminating the Emir of ISIS on a daring operation, and just this week, taking out another key leader of ISIS.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re going to continue our counterterrorism efforts working with a broad coalition of countries, including everyone around this table.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we will turn our attention and our resources to supporting our partners, strengthening our alliances, and building coalitions to solve the problems facing this region and the world &#8212; and the world today.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States is clear-eyed about the challenges in the Middle East and about where we have the greatest capacity to help drive positive outcomes.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our objectives are focused on &#8212; are &#8212; excuse me, are focused, realistic, and achievable so that we can target our resources, rebuild trust, and deliver real results.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we will operate in the context of the Middle East as it is today: a region more united than it has been in years.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The GCC is a prime example of that.&nbsp; Former rivals have<br>reestablished diplomatic and economic ties.&nbsp; New memberships are being forged.&nbsp; And increasingly, the world is seeing the Mideast &#8212; the Middle East through the lens of opening and opportunity.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me state clearly that the United States is going to remain an active, engaged partner in the Middle East.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As the world grows more competitive and the challenges we face more complex, it is only becoming clearer to me that &#8212; how closely interwoven America’s interests are with the successes of the Middle East.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We will not walk away and leave a vacuum to be filled by China, Russia, or Iran.&nbsp; And we’ll seek to build on this moment with active, principled American leadership.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our new framework for the Middle East has five key principles, and I’d like to very briefly share them with you today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, the United States will support and strengthen partnerships with countries that subscribe to the rules-based international order.&nbsp; And we will make sure that these &#8212; those countries can defend themselves against foreign threats.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States and each of the countries around this table are an essential part of that order because we reject the use of brute force to change borders.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When the entire GCC, plus Egypt and Jordan, voted in the United Nations General Assembly to condemn Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, it was a watershed moment.&nbsp; It showed that the core values of sovereignty and territorial integrity are truly universal.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to be clear: Supporting a rules-based order doesn’t mean we always have to agree on every issue, but it does mean we align around core principles that allow us to work together on the most pressing global challenges.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For example, on food security, we are collectively committing billions of dollars to alleviate the crisis here in the region, with more than $1 billion coming from the United States.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On energy security, we agree on the need to ensure adequate supplies to meet global needs.&nbsp; Energy producers have already increased production, and I look forward to seeing what’s coming in the &#8212; in the coming months.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the climate crisis, we’re collectively investing hundreds of billions of dollars in clean energy initiatives, increasing our climate ambition, and working together to diversify supply chains and invest in critical infrastructure.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we’re looking forward to Egypt and the UAE hosting the next two major U.N. climate conferences.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, the United States will not allow &#8212; will not allow foreign or regional powers to jeopardize the freedom of navigation through the Middle East’s waterways, including the Strait of Hormuz and the Bab al-Mandab.&nbsp; Nor will we tolerate efforts by any country to dominate another in the region through military buildups, incursions, and/or threats.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The free flow of commerce and resources through the Middle East is the lifeblood of a global economy.&nbsp; That’s as true today as it been &#8212; as it has been for decades.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when nations adhere to international rules, it works.&nbsp; So my administration has made it a priority to protect those vital waterways.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’ve established a new naval task force to work in partnership with many of your navies to help secure the Red Sea.&nbsp; That includes the first naval task force to use&nbsp;<s>multi-manned</s>&nbsp;[un-manned] surface vessels and artificial intelligence technology to enhance marine &#8212; maritime awareness.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re also integrating air defenses and early warning systems to ensure that we can defeat airborne threats.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Third, the United States will not just aim to deter threats of regional &#8212; to regional stability; we will work to reduce tensions, de-escalate, and end conflicts wherever possible.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This approach is already reaping dividends.&nbsp; As was mentioned: In Yemen, working closely with Saudi Arabia, Oman, the UAE, and the U.N., we forged a truce that is now in its 15th week.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’ve welcomed the leadership Of Iraqi Prime Minister Kadhimi to bring countries from the nei- &#8212; from the neighbor- &#8212; from the region together for talks in Baghdad.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks to the months of quiet, persistent diplomacy, we helped finalize an agreement to remove international peacekeepers from Tiran Island in the Red Sea, and transform an area that once sparked wars into a future hub of peaceful tourism and economic development.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as we continue to work closely with many of you to counter the threats posed by &#8212; posed to the region by Iran, we’re also pursuing diplomacy to return constraints on Iran’s nuclear program.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But no matter what, the United States is committed to ensuring that Iran never gets a nuclear weapon.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fourth, the United States will build political, economic, and security connections between the United States &#8212; between the U.S. partners wherever possible, while respecting each country’s sovereignty and independent choices.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Integration, interconnection &#8212; these are the underlying themes of our meeting today.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How many years have we been trying to connect Iraq’s electricity to the &#8212; to the G- &#8212; to the GCC grids?&nbsp; I remember being briefed on it in 19- &#8212; in 2016, when I was Vice President of the United States.&nbsp; I said, “Let’s get it done.”</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, today, finally, after years of failed efforts and false starts, thanks to the efforts of so many around this table, it’s done.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; New energy projects linking the region, a new free trade deal and investments between neighbors, like the Saudi investments in Egypt and Jordan.&nbsp; The more we build these connections, the more we’ll see the benefits that return to our peoples and will grow.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fifth, the United States will always promote human rights and the values enshrined in the U.N. Charter.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Foundational freedoms are foundational to who we are as Americans.&nbsp; It’s in our DNA.&nbsp; But it’s also because we know that fai- &#8212; that the future will be won by the countries that unleash the full potential of their populations, where women can exercise equal rights and contribute to building stronger economies, resilient societies, and more modern and capable militaries; where citizens can question and criticize their leaders without fear of reprisal.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’ve gotten plenty of criticism over the years.&nbsp; It’s not fun.&nbsp; But the ability to speak openly and exchange ideas freely is what unlocks innovation.&nbsp; Accountable ins- &#8212; accountable institutions that are free from corruption, that act transparently, and respect the rule of law are the best way to deliver growth, respond to people’s needs, and, I believe, ensure justice.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And no country gets it right all the time &#8212; even most of the time &#8212; including the United States.&nbsp; But our people are our strength.&nbsp; Our countries, with the confidence to learn from their mistakes, grow stronger.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So let me conclude by summing all this up in one sentence: The United States is invested in building a positive future in the region, in partnership with all of you, and the United States is not going anywhere.<br><br>This is a table full of probi- &#8212; problem solvers.&nbsp; There are a lot of &#8212; there’s a lot of good we can do if we do it together.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you again for inviting me to participate in this summit today, and thank you for the many years of partnership between your countries and the United States.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;2:20 P.M. AST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement Following Meeting Between President&#160;Biden and Iraqi Prime Minister Kadhimi in&#160;Jeddah</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/16/joint-statement-following-meeting-between-president-biden-and-iraqi-prime-minister-kadhimi-in-jeddah/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 09:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden Jr. met today with Prime Minister Mustafa Al-Kadhimi of Iraq in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, in a bilateral meeting during the Summit of the United States and the Gulf Cooperation Council and Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan.&#160; During the meeting, the two leaders reaffirmed their shared commitment to the strong bilateral partnership between&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden Jr. met today with Prime Minister Mustafa Al-Kadhimi of Iraq in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, in a bilateral meeting during the Summit of the United States and the Gulf Cooperation Council and Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan.&nbsp; During the meeting, the two leaders reaffirmed their shared commitment to the strong bilateral partnership between Iraq and the United States under the Strategic Framework Agreement and their determination to continue security coordination to ensure that ISIS can never resurge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden and Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi also consulted on a range of regional issues.&nbsp; The leaders agreed that the relationship between the U.S. and Iraq is based on a shared interest in Iraq’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, security, and stability and committed to bolstering the bilateral partnership for the benefit of their two nations.</p>



<p>They also reaffirmed the importance of forming a new Iraqi government responsive to the will of the Iraqi people and their respect for Iraq’s democracy and independence. &nbsp;President Biden underscored the importance the United States places on a stable, united, sovereign, and prosperous Iraq, to include Iraq’s Kurdistan region.</p>



<p><strong><u>Strategic Framework Agreement</u></strong></p>



<p>The President and Prime Minister renewed their commitment to the Strategic Framework Agreement for a Relationship of Friendship and Cooperation between the United States and the Republic of Iraq, which guides the overall political, economic, cultural, and security relationship between the two countries.&nbsp; President Biden reiterated his support to Iraq in its fight against terrorism and emphasized that a strong Iraq capable of self-defense is essential for achieving stability in the region.</p>



<p>The President and the Prime Minister also reinforced the importance of strengthening Iraq’s democratic institutions, to include empowering Iraqi security forces, to advance security and stability in Iraq and the region.&nbsp; President Biden expressed appreciation for Iraq’s efforts to repatriate and rehabilitate Iraqi families and children as well as to prosecute Iraqi ISIS fighters from Syria and welcomed further cooperation to address this critical issue.&nbsp; Both leaders agreed that close cooperation on military and security issues and overall support for Iraq against terrorism was critical to ensure the enduring defeat of ISIS.</p>



<p><strong><u>Promoting Stability</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden and Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi discussed the important role of Iraq in the region, especially in facilitating communication and building confidence among the countries of the region. &nbsp;President Biden particularly commended the significant diplomatic efforts led by Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi to foster a more stable, prosperous, and interconnected region. &nbsp;The historic new agreements between Iraq and the GCC Interconnection Authority will bring affordable energy to Iraq and help meet the needs of the Iraqi people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden reaffirmed the importance to the United States of building a prosperous and diversified economy in Iraq that is integrated in the regional and global economic system and capable of meeting the essential needs of the Iraqi people.&nbsp; The President and the Prime Minister highlighted the importance of fighting corruption to both build public trust in Iraqi institutions and to support economic growth. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The President and Prime Minister discussed efforts to collectively advance sustainable development of the region’s resources, to address the impacts of climate change including water insecurity, and to expand U.S.-Iraq coordination on energy modernization and economic reform.</p>



<p>President Biden also welcomed Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi’s initiative to bring Saudi Arabia and Iran together for talks in Baghdad.&nbsp; The President expressed his appreciation for the Prime Minister’s forward-thinking diplomacy in the interest of a safer, more stable region.&nbsp; He also commended the Baghdad Summit, and the unique relationship between Iraq, Jordan, and Egypt, which the United States stands ready to support.</p>



<p>Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi emphasized his commitment to pursuing initiatives to bring together Iraq’s neighbors and friends to find home-grown solutions for regional challenges and to achieve sustainable stability.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement From Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on the Passing of the Women’s Health Protection Act and the Ensuring Access to Abortion&#160;Act </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-passing-of-the-womens-health-protection-act-and-the-ensuring-access-to-abortion-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 01:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57689</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, we’ve seen the deeply different approaches that Congressional Democrats and Congressional Republicans have for women’s health. Today, House Democrats took an important step in passing the Women’s Health Protection Act and Ensuring Access to Abortion Act. These bills would ensure women’s access to essential health care services, regardless of where they live, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, we’ve seen the deeply different approaches that Congressional Democrats and Congressional Republicans have for women’s health. Today, House Democrats took an important step in passing the Women’s Health Protection Act and Ensuring Access to Abortion Act. These bills would ensure women’s access to essential health care services, regardless of where they live, and protect the bedrock right to cross state lines for medical care. A majority of Americans across the country support them. Every single Republican voted against the bill to codify women’s right to choose and nearly every single House Republican voted against the right to travel. Senate Republicans blocked a similar bill that would make the right to travel to access medical care a law. It’s extreme and it’s out of touch.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Jeddah Communique:  A Joint Statement Between the United&#160;States of America and the Kingdom of Saudi&#160;Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/the-jeddah-communique-a-joint-statement-between-the-united-states-of-america-and-the-kingdom-of-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 23:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jeddah, Saudi Arabia At the invitation of the Custodian of the Two Holy Mosques, King Salman Bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud, President Joseph R. Biden conducted an official visit to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia July 15-16, 2022.  Following the meeting with King Salman, President Biden and Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman held an official meeting, attended&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Jeddah, Saudi Arabia</strong></p>



<p>At the invitation of the Custodian of the Two Holy Mosques, King Salman Bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud, President Joseph R. Biden conducted an official visit to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia July 15-16, 2022.  Following the meeting with King Salman, President Biden and Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman held an official meeting, attended by senior officials from both sides. The two sides reviewed in detail the many shared priorities that contribute to the partnership between the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United States.</p>



<p>At the end of this meeting, the two sides issued this communique outlining the strategic partnership between the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United States over the coming decades with the aim of advancing their mutual interests and advancing a common vision for a more peaceful, secure, prosperous, and stable Middle East.</p>



<p><strong><u>Strategic Partnership</u></strong></p>



<p>The two sides reviewed the historical relations and partnership between the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United States of America that was established nearly eight decades ago with the meeting between King Abdulaziz Al-Saud and President Franklin D. Roosevelt on board the USS Quincy. They underscored the importance of continuing to strengthen their strategic partnership to serve the interests of the governments and peoples of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United States. The two sides also emphasized the pivotal role this historic partnership has played in promoting regional stability and prosperity. They stressed that the U.S.-Saudi partnership has been a cornerstone of regional security over decades, and affirmed that the two countries share a vision of a more secure, stable, and prosperous region, interconnected with the world.</p>



<p>The two sides affirmed the importance of resolving international disputes through peaceful and diplomatic means, and alleviating humanitarian crises through economic and financial support to the region’s countries most in need. They affirmed the importance of the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity. They stressed the need for supporting governments in the region facing threats from terrorists or proxy groups backed by outside powers.</p>



<p>The two sides noted the historic ties between the peoples of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United Stated. They welcomed, in this regard, extending the validity of business and tourism visas to 10 years to facilitate closer people-to-people ties and economic cooperation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The two sides then reviewed cooperation and achievements in the following areas:</p>



<p><strong>Energy Security and Climate Cooperation</strong></p>



<p>The two sides underscored the importance of strategic economic and investment cooperation, particularly in light of the current crisis in Ukraine and its consequences, and reaffirmed their commitment to a stable global energy market.&nbsp; The U.S. welcomed Saudi Arabia’s commitment to support global oil markets balancing for sustained economic growth.&nbsp; Both sides decided to consult regularly on global energy markets in the near- and long-term, as well as work together as strategic partners in climate and energy transition initiatives, recognizing Saudi Arabia’s leading role in the future of energy.</p>



<p>The U.S. side commended the Saudi Green Initiative and Middle East Green Initiative, and welcomed Saudi Arabia’s participation at the recent Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate, joining of the Global Methane Pledge, its status as a founding member of the Net-Zero Producers Forum, and the Kingdom’s announcement to meet fifty percent of its electricity generation from renewables by 2030.</p>



<p>The two sides welcomed the finalization of a Partnership Framework for Advancing Clean Energy, with substantial investments in clean energy transition and addressing climate change, with particular focus on renewable energy, clean hydrogen, human capacity-building in the nuclear energy field, and cooperation in nuclear-regulatory aspects, carbon capture utilization and sequestration, development of sustainable materials, and other initiatives&nbsp;under the Circular Carbon Economy Framework, where Saudi Arabia aims to be a global leader..</p>



<p><strong>Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment (PGII)</strong></p>



<p>The two sides emphasized that the energy transition and the national security of both countries require stable and diversified supply chains, and in this regard, the United States welcomed Saudi Arabia’s support for the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment, which President Biden announced at the G7 Summit on June 26, 2022. Through this historic partnership, the United States and Saudi Arabia aim to strategically invest in projects that support digital connectivity, supply chain sustainability, and climate and energy security focused on low- and middle-income countries.</p>



<p><strong>Security and Defense</strong></p>



<p>President Biden strongly affirmed the United States’ continued commitment to supporting Saudi Arabia’s security and territorial defense, and facilitating the Kingdom’s ability to obtain necessary capabilities to defend its people and territory against external threats.</p>



<p>The two sides underscored the need to further deter Iran’s interference in the internal affairs of other countries, its support for terrorism through its armed proxies, and its efforts to destabilize the security and stability of the region.&nbsp; The Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the United States stressed the importance of preventing Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p>Both sides stressed the importance of preserving the free flow of commerce through strategic international waterways like the Bab al-Mandab and the Strait of Hormuz.&nbsp; They welcomed the newly-established Combined Task Force 153 with a focus on the Red Sea’s Bab al-Mandab passageway and further deterring illicit smuggling into Yemen.&nbsp; They also welcomed Saudi Arabia’s assumption of command of Combined Task Force 150, which reinforces shared maritime security objectives in the Gulf of Oman and North Arabian Sea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To improve and streamline the exchange of information in the maritime domain, cooperation between the Royal Saudi Naval Forces and Combined Task Force 153 will be enhanced in the regionally-networked coordination center led out of the U.S. Fifth Fleet Headquarters in Bahrain.&nbsp; The United States also emphasized the growing cooperation between the Royal Saudi Naval Forces and U.S. Fifth Fleet’s Task Force 59, which leads an expanding fleet of cutting edge, integrated unmanned surface vessels using artificial intelligence to improve maritime security and domain awareness in support of regional security.</p>



<p><strong>5G/6G Open-RAN Cooperation</strong></p>



<p>The two sides welcomed a new Memorandum of Cooperation that will connect U.S. and Saudi technology companies in the advancement and deployment of 5G using open radio access networks, enable the development of 6G through similar technologies, an advance partnerships in cloud&nbsp;infrastructure and related technologies. The partnerships built under the MOU confirms Saudi Arabia’s leadership as a regional hub for 5G deployments and 6G future developments.</p>



<p><strong>Cybersecurity</strong></p>



<p>The two sides emphasized their mutual cooperation in the field of cybersecurity and its importance to protect the vital interests and national security of both countries. &nbsp;&nbsp;The United States and Saudi Arabia welcomed the recent signing of memoranda of understanding on cybersecurity cooperation and decided to continue strengthening real-time information sharing, building human and technical capabilities, and cybersecurity industry development.</p>



<p><strong>Space Exploration</strong></p>



<p>The two sides further welcomed the enhancement of cooperation in all fields of space exploration, including human spaceflight, earth observation, commercial and regulatory development, and responsible behavior in outer space.&nbsp; President Biden welcomed the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia signing the Artemis Accords and applauded the Kingdom for affirming its commitment to the responsible, peaceful, and sustainable exploration and use of outer space.</p>



<p><strong>Development of Tiran Island</strong></p>



<p>President Biden welcomed the arrangements by Saudi Arabia to remove the Multinational Force and Observers (MFO) from the Island of Tiran, including the removal of U.S. troops there as part of the MFO mission, while preserving and continuing all existing commitments and procedures in the area. &nbsp;This area of the Red Sea will now be developed for tourism and economic purposes, contributing to a more secure, peaceful, and prosperous region.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Expanding Overflights</strong></p>



<p>Within the framework of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia&#8217;s keenness to fulfill its obligations under the Chicago Convention of 1944, which stipulates non-discrimination between civil aircraft used in international air navigation, the Saudi General Authority for Civil Aviation (GACA) announced its decision to open the Kingdom&#8217;s airspace for all air carriers that meet the requirements of GACA to fly over the Kingdom’s airspace. &nbsp;The United States welcomed this announcement, which will enhance global air connectivity and help cement the Kingdom’s position as a global hub connecting Africa, Asia, and Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Vision 2030</strong></p>



<p>The U.S. welcomed the Kingdom’s Vision 2030, its blueprint for transformative economic and social reforms, and its efforts to increase women’s economic participation and promote interfaith dialogue.&nbsp; Saudi Arabia welcomed greater U.S. private sector investment in the Kingdom, as well as increasing Saudi investments in the American private sector for the benefit of both countries.</p>



<p>The U.S. side welcomed Saudi Arabia’s bid to host World Expo in 2030, and other events to be held over the course of that milestone year, the culmination of Saudi Arabia’s Vision 2030 reform program. &nbsp;The Saudi side noted the importance for the region of the World Cup being hosted by Qatar later this year and welcomed the United States serving as host for the World Cup in 2026.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Regional Cooperation</u></strong></p>



<p>The two sides then addressed particular regional and global issues, including:</p>



<p><strong>Yemen</strong></p>



<p>Both sides affirmed their strong support for the UN-brokered truce in Yemen and stressed the importance of&nbsp;extending the truce and&nbsp;making progress to transform the truce into a lasting peace agreement. President Biden expressed his appreciation for the role King Salman and Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman have played in achieving and renewing the truce.&nbsp; The two sides stressed their long-stated goal to end the war in Yemen, and called on the international community to take a unified position calling on the Houthis to return to peace talks under the auspices of the United Nations based on the three references, including UN Security Council Resolution 2216 (2015).&nbsp; Only a political agreement between the Yemeni parties can durably resolve the conflict and reverse the dire humanitarian crisis.</p>



<p>The two sides also affirmed their support for Yemen&#8217;s Presidential Leadership Council and thanked the Council for its commitment&nbsp;to the truce and steps that have improved the lives of Yemenis across the country, including facilitating fuel imports and restarting flights from Sana’a.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They also stressed the need to remove all impediments to the flow of essential goods and&nbsp;delivery of aid inside Yemen, and the importance&nbsp;of the Houthis&nbsp;opening&nbsp;the main roads to Taiz – Yemen’s third largest city which has been under siege conditions since 2015.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Saudi Arabia and the United States encouraged all regional actors to fully support the truce, which has resulted in the longest period of peace in Yemen in six years.&nbsp;Saudi Arabia welcomed the United States’ support of the truce and its contribution to the efforts to advance the political process in Yemen.</p>



<p><strong>Iraq</strong></p>



<p>President Biden welcomed the leading role played by the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia in strengthening relations with Republic of Iraq, and the historic agreements to be signed on the margins of the Jeddah Security and Development Summit on July 16, 2022, to link the electricity networks of Saudi Arabia and the Gulf Cooperation Council countries to the Iraqi grid, in order to provide Iraq and its people with new and diversified electricity sources.</p>



<p><strong>Israel-Palestinian Issues</strong></p>



<p>Regarding Israel-Palestinian issues, the two sides underscored their enduring commitment to a two-state solution, wherein a sovereign and contiguous Palestinian state lives side-by-side in peace and security with Israel, as the only way to resolve the Israeli-Palestinian conflict in accordance with the internationally-recognized parameters and the Arab Peace Initiative.&nbsp; The leaders noted their determination to remain closely coordinated on efforts to encourage the parties to demonstrate – through policies and actions – their commitment to a two-state solution. The United States and Saudi Arabia welcomed all efforts that contribute to reaching a just and comprehensive peace in the region.</p>



<p><strong>Syria</strong></p>



<p>The two sides reiterated their commitment to preserving the unity, stability, and territorial integrity of Syria and expressed their support for the efforts of the Special Envoy of the Secretary-General of the United Nations to reach a political solution to the conflict consistent with the formula outlined in the UN Security Council Resolution 2254 (2015), stressing at the same time the need to prevent renewed of violence, to maintain established ceasefires, and to allow the unhindered delivery of humanitarian aid to all Syrians in need.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Lebanon</strong></p>



<p>The two sides affirmed their continued support for Lebanon’s sovereignty, security and stability, and their support for the Lebanese Armed Forces that protect its borders and resist the threats of violent extremist and terrorist groups. They also noted the importance of forming a Lebanese government and implementing comprehensive structural political and economic reforms to ensure that Lebanon overcomes its political and economic crisis, and that it does not become a launching point for terrorists, drug smuggling, or other criminal activities that threatens the stability and security of the region.</p>



<p>They emphasized the importance of the control of the government of Lebanon over all Lebanese territory, including with reference to fulfilling the provisions of the relevant UN Security Council resolutions and the Taif Accord, and for it to exercise full sovereignty, so there will be no weapons without the consent of the government of Lebanon or authority other than that of the government of Lebanon.</p>



<p><strong>Ukraine</strong></p>



<p>The two sides underscored that a rules-based order lies at the heart of international security, emphasizing the importance of the respect for international law, territorial integrity, and national sovereignty.&nbsp; They reaffirmed the principles as set forth in the March 2, 2022, UN General Assembly Resolution ES-11/1, endorsed by all GCC members.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The leaders reaffirmed their commitment to providing critical assistance to the Ukrainian people, and to ensure the unhindered export of grain and wheat products to alleviate the global food crises, which threatens to acutely impact a number of Middle Eastern and African states.</p>



<p><strong>Sudan</strong></p>



<p>The two sides underscored the importance of the dialogue between Sudanese parties and reviving the political process.&nbsp; They commended the efforts made by the United Nations Mission to support the return to the foundations of a political solution in Sudan, and expressed their satisfaction with the active role of the Quad for Sudan, wishing Sudan and its people peace and prosperity.</p>



<p><strong>Libya</strong></p>



<p>Both sides affirmed their support for the Libyan people as they engage in the UN-brokered political process to prepare for presidential and parliamentary elections as soon as possible.&nbsp; They expressed their full support for the Libyan ceasefire agreement concluded on October 23, 2020 and the Libyan call for the complete departure of foreign forces, foreign fighters, and mercenaries without further delay, in accordance with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2570 (2021).&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Afghanistan</strong></p>



<p>The two sides stressed the need to support Afghanistan’s security and to address the threat posed by Afghanistan-based terrorists. They also underscored the importance of continuing to support humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan.&nbsp; They expressed support for addressing the needs and promoting the rights of the Afghan people including the rights of women and girls to education and enjoyment of the highest attainable standard of health and, for women, the right to work.</p>



<p><strong>Counter-Terrorism</strong></p>



<p>The two sides underscored the importance of confronting terrorism and violent extremism. They expressed their continued commitment to countering al-Qaeda and ISIS, stemming the flow of foreign fighters, countering violent extremist propaganda, and cutting off terrorist financing streams.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The two sides highlighted the joint efforts through the Terrorist Financing Targeting Center, which is based in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; They reviewed and commended the exceptional success of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS, established in Jeddah in 2014, and stressed the need for this coalition to continue, and to make long-term and multi-year efforts to return both detained ISIS fighters and the tens of thousands of ISIS family members from northeastern Syria to their home countries. &nbsp;They welcomed the next Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS ministerial meeting to be held in Saudi Arabia in early 2023.</p>



<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>



<p>The two sides decided to expand and strengthen bilateral cooperation in all areas discussed in this meeting, prior to the next annual Strategic Dialogue between Saudi Arabia and the United States to be held in the Kingdom later this year.&nbsp; This Jeddah Communique should form the basis of work going forward to consolidate and enhance the strategic partnership between the two countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Results of Bilateral Meeting Between the United&#160;States and the Kingdom of Saudi&#160;Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/fact-sheet-results-of-bilateral-meeting-between-the-united-states-and-the-kingdom-of-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 23:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden met in Jeddah with the leaders of Saudi Arabia, our hosts for the upcoming Summit with the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) Council (GCC) countries plus Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan.  In a meeting with King Salman and then an extended working session with Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman and their respective delegations, the United States and Saudi Arabia finalized a number of international and bilateral&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden met in Jeddah with the leaders of Saudi Arabia, our hosts for the upcoming Summit with the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) Council (GCC) countries plus Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan.  In a meeting with King Salman and then an extended working session with Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman and their respective delegations, the United States and Saudi Arabia finalized a number of international and bilateral agreements that serve the interests of the American people and a more integrated, stable, and prosperous Middle East region.</p>



<p>These results&nbsp;of this meeting&nbsp;include the following:</p>



<p><a></a><strong>Removing Peacekeepers from Tiran Island:</strong>&nbsp;Since shortly after the 1978 Camp David Accords, U.S. troops have served as peacekeepers on Tiran Island as part of the Multinational Force and Observers (MFO) under the Treaty of Peace signed between Israel and Egypt.&nbsp; Five Americans were killed on the island in 2020 in a helicopter crash. Tonight, arrangements were finalized&nbsp;to remove the MFO peacekeepers and develop this area – which once sparked multi-state wars in the region – for tourism, development, and peaceful pursuits.&nbsp; Saudi Arabia has agreed to preserve and continue all existing commitments and procedures in the area.&nbsp; President Biden welcomed this arrangement, which was negotiated over many months and fully took into consideration the interests of all parties.&nbsp; The MFO peacekeepers, including U.S. soldiers, will depart Tiran by the end of the year.&nbsp;The MFO will carry out alternative arrangements to ensure the present freedom of navigation to all parties, including Israel.</p>



<p><strong>Opening Saudi Airspace to Civilian Aircraft Flying to and from Israel:&nbsp;</strong>To date, civilian aircraft flying to and from Israel, with rare exceptions, could not&nbsp;fly over Saudi Arabia, leading to increased hours of flying time, significant expenses, and unnecessary impact on our climate. Today,&nbsp;President Biden welcomed&nbsp;Saudi Arabia’s decision to expand overflight of Saudi Arabia for all&nbsp;civilian aircraft,&nbsp;including airlines&nbsp;flying to and from Israel, based on the principles of the Chicago Convention of 1944. This was an important step forward towards a more integrated Middle East region, interconnected with the world. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Sustaining the UN-Mediated Truce in Yemen:&nbsp;</strong>The two delegations held a detailed discussion of the situation in Yemen, and both committed to&nbsp;taking steps to&nbsp;doing everything possible to extend and strengthen the UN-mediated truce, which has led to fifteen weeks of peace, the quietest period in Yemen&nbsp;in years, and translate it into a durable ceasefire and political process. President Biden reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to help Saudi Arabia protect and defend its territory and people from all external attacks, particularly those launched by the Iranian-backed Houthis in Yemen.&nbsp;&nbsp;He also welcomed Saudi Arabia’s strong commitment to the truce, particularly leading, in tandem with the Yemen government,&nbsp;efforts&nbsp;to resume direct commercial flights from Sana&#8217;a to Amman and Cairo for the first time in seven years. &nbsp;The President also welcomed the Kingdom’s&nbsp;financial support to Yemen’s Presidential Leadership&nbsp;Council, which will help improve basic services and economic stability to ease the suffering of Yemenis. This support includes a pledge to provide over $1 billion for development projects and fuel support,&nbsp;in addition to a joint Saudi and Emirati $2 billion deposit to the Central Bank of Yemen. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Support for PGII: &nbsp;</strong>President Biden welcomed Saudi Arabia’s plan to&nbsp;strategically invest in projects aligning with U.S. Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment (PGII) goals, which the&nbsp;President and G7 leaders unveiled&nbsp;at the June 26, 2022, G7 Summit. &nbsp;Together, the United States and Saudi Arabia will&nbsp;mobilize hundreds of billions of dollars to deliver quality, sustainable infrastructure that makes a difference in people’s lives around the world, strengthens and diversifies our supply chains, creates new opportunities for American workers and businesses, and advances our national security.</p>



<p><strong>New Bilateral Framework for Cooperation on 5G/6G:&nbsp;</strong>President Biden welcomed the signing of&nbsp;a new Memorandum of Cooperation between the U.S. National Telecommunication and Information Administration and the Saudi Ministry of Communications and Information Technology, which&nbsp;will connect U.S. and Saudi technology companies in the advancement and deployment of 5G using open,&nbsp;virtualized, and cloud-based radio access networks and the development of 6G through similar technologies.&nbsp;The partnerships built under the MOU will also support 5G deployment in Saudi Arabia and in developing and middle-income states thereafter&nbsp;through the PGII.&nbsp;&nbsp;Saudi Arabia has committed to a significant investment for this project under the umbrella of the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>New&nbsp;Cooperation on Energy Security:&nbsp;</strong>Saudi Arabia has committed to support global oil market balancing for sustained economic growth. The United States has welcomed the increase in production levels 50 percent above what was planned for July and August. These steps and further steps that we anticipate over the coming weeks have and will help stabilize markets considerably.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>New Bilateral Framework on Clean Energy Cooperation:&nbsp;</strong>President Biden welcomed the signing of a bilateral&nbsp;Partnership Framework for Advancing Clean Energy, with new Saudi investments to accelerate the energy transition and combat the effects of climate change.&nbsp; This Framework focuses particularly on solar, green hydrogen, nuclear, and other clean energy initiatives. &nbsp;By building upon existing collaboration between energy experts in our countries, we seek to enhance our efforts to tackle climate change and advance greater deployment of clean energy resources around the world.&nbsp; The Partnership will leverage public and private sector collaboration to advance the deployment of clean energy solutions while accelerating research, development, and demonstration of innovative technologies needed to decarbonize the global economy and achieve net-zero emissions.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Underscoring Human Rights Concerns:&nbsp;</strong>The President underscored the United States’ conviction that respect for and promotion of human rights and fundamental freedoms promotes stability and strengthens national security. Over the course of the discussion, he raised specific cases of concern. He also raised the egregious murder of Jamal Khashoggi, described the accountability measures the United States has put in place in response, and received commitments with respect to reforms and institutional safeguards in place to guard against any such conduct in the future. &nbsp;The United States will continue to engage in a regular and direct dialogue with Saudi Arabia and other partners on these important issues, and raise our concerns with human rights at every opportunity.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Cybersecurity Cooperation:&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>President Biden welcomed the signing of two bilateral agreements on cybersecurity with Saudi Arabia’s National Cybersecurity Authority – one with the Federal Bureau of Investigations and the other with the Department of Homeland Security’s Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA).&nbsp; Through these memoranda of cooperation, the United States and Saudi Arabia will expand their existing bilateral relationship on this critical issue, share information about cybersecurity threats and activities of malicious actors to enhance the shared defense of our nations, and collaborate on best practices, technologies, tools, and on approaches to cybersecurity training and education.</p>



<p><strong>Cooperation in Space Exploration:&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;The U.S. and Saudi Arabia are expanding cooperation in all fields of space exploration, including human spaceflight, earth observation, commercial and regulatory development, and responsible behavior in outer space.&nbsp; President Biden welcomed the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia signing the Artemis Accords and reaffirming its commitment to the responsible, peaceful, and sustainable exploration and use of outer space.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Public Health Cooperation:&nbsp;</strong>President Biden welcomed a new Memorandum of Understanding between&nbsp;the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services and the Saudi Ministry of Health to continue strengthening their relationship and working together to solve common health issues.&nbsp; The forthcoming areas of collaboration include&nbsp;health information systems, capacity building in the delivery of health services, disease surveillance, emerging infectious diseases, addressing the health-related concerns of women and special needs populations, and public policies oriented to disease prevention and health promotion.</p>



<p><strong>Enhanced&nbsp;Maritime Security Cooperation: &nbsp;</strong>The&nbsp;U.S.&nbsp;and Saudi Arabia reaffirmed their commitment to&nbsp;preserving the free flow of commerce through strategic international waterways like the Bab al-Mandab and the Strait of Hormuz, through which 40 percent of the world’s energy passes every day, through multiple joint naval task forces, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Red Sea:</strong>&nbsp;Newly-establish Combined Task Force 153, focused on international maritime security and capacity building efforts.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Gulf of Oman and North Arabian Sea:</strong>&nbsp;Saudi Arabia will&nbsp;soon&nbsp;assume command of Combined Task Force 150, which reinforces shared maritime security objectives.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Unmanned and AI&nbsp;Integration:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;Saudi Arabia will soon participate&nbsp;as part of the 5th Fleet’s Task Force 59, which for the first time integrates advanced technologies like unmanned vessels and artificial intelligence to enhance maritime domain awareness.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Integrated Air Defense Cooperation:  </strong>The two sides reviewed developments in improving air defense integration and protection of Saudi Arabia’s territory and people from external threats, including missiles, drones, and UAVs.  This cooperation includes U.S. military support and far-reaching foreign military sales cases with emphasis on defensive systems and advanced technology.  The United States affirmed it would accelerate our cooperation with Saudi Arabia and other partners in the region to counter unmanned aerial systems and missiles that threaten the peace and security of the region.  President Biden affirmed the United States’ commitment to working with Saudi Arabia and other allies and partners in the Middle East to integrate and enhance security cooperation.  In particular, the United States is committed to advancing a more integrated and regionally-networked air and missile defense architecture and countering the proliferation of unmanned aerial systems and missiles to non-state actors that threaten the peace and security of the region. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on His Meetings in Saudi&#160;Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/15/remarks-by-president-biden-on-his-meetings-in-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 23:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57695</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waldorf Astoria JeddahJeddah, Saudi Arabia 10:45 P.M. AST THE PRESIDENT: I know it’s late, but thank you for being here. I had a good series of meetings. I just finished more than two hours of meetings with Saudi leadership here in Jeddah, meeting with the King for about a little over half an hour, a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Waldorf Astoria Jeddah<br>Jeddah, Saudi Arabia</p>



<p>10:45 P.M. AST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: I know it’s late, but thank you for being here. I had a good series of meetings. I just finished more than two hours of meetings with Saudi leadership here in Jeddah, meeting with the King for about a little over half an hour, a working session with the Crown Prince and all the ministers from the &#8212; from the energy minister to the sports minister, all the way down the line. And got the chance to talk to basically the entire Saudi government.</p>



<p>And thanks to many months of quiet diplomacy by the staff, we&#8217;ve accomplished some significant business today.</p>



<p>First, as you saw this morning, the Saudis will open their airspace to all civilian carriers. That is a big deal. A big deal. Not only substan- &#8212; not only symbolically, but substantively, it&#8217;s a big deal. It means Saudi airspace is now open to flights to and from Israel. This is the first tangible step in the path of what I hope will eventually be a broader normalization of relations.</p>



<p>Second, we concluded a historic deal that &#8212; to transform a flashpoint at the heart of the Middle East wars into an area of peace. International peacekeepers, including U.S. troops, will leave Tiran Island in the Red Sea, where they&#8217;ve been for over 40 years since the Camp David Accords. Five American soldiers died on this strategically located island in 2020, and it&#8217;s important to remember them today.</p>



<p>Now, thanks to the break- &#8212; this breakthrough, this island will be open to tourism and economic development while retaining all the necessary security arrangements and &#8212; and the present freedom of navigation of all parties, including Israel.</p>



<p>Third, we agreed to work together to deepen and extend the Yemen ceasefire. And you know there&#8217;s been &#8212; there’s carnage been in Yemen of late. And it’s been in place more than three months, resulting in the most peaceful period in Yemen in seven years.</p>



<p>We further agreed to pursue a diplomatic process to achieve a wider settlement in Yemen. The Saudi &#8212; and Saudi leadership also committed to continue to facilitate the delivery of food and humanitarian goods to civilians. In this context, we discussed Saudi Arabia’s security needs to defend the Kingdom, given very real threats from Iran and Iran&#8217;s proxies.</p>



<p>Fourth, we concluded several new arrangements to better position our nations for the coming decades. Saudi Arabia will invest in new U.S.-led technology to develop and secure reliable 5G and 6G networks, both here and in the future, in developing countries to coordinate with the Partnership for Global Initiative &#8212; the Global Infrastructure and Investment, which I put together at the G7. This new technology solution for 5G, called Open RAN, will outcompete other platforms, including from China.</p>



<p>Saudi Arabia will also partner with us on a far-reaching clean energy initiative focused on green hydrogen, solar, carbon capture, nuclear, and other projects to accel- &#8212; to accelerate the world&#8217;s clean energy transition and to help the U.S. clean energy industry set global standards.</p>



<p>And fifth, we had a good &#8212; we had a good discussion on ensuring global energy security and adequate oil supplies to support global economic growth. And that will begin shortly. And I&#8217;m doing all I can to increase the supply for the United States of America, which I expect to happen. The Saudis share that urgency, and based on our discussions today, I expect we&#8217;ll see further steps in the coming weeks.</p>



<p>Finally, we discussed human rights and the need for political reform. As always &#8212; as I always do, I made clear that the topic was vitally important to me and to the United States.</p>



<p>With respect to the murder of Khashoggi, I raised it at the top of the meeting, making it clear what I thought of it at the time and what I think of it now. And it was exactly &#8212; I was straightforward and direct in discussing it. I made my view crystal clear. I said very straightforwardly: For an American President to be silent on an issue of human rights, is this consistent with &#8212; inconsistent with who we are and who I am? I’ll always stand up for our values.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s a quick summary of tonight&#8217;s outcomes.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, with nine leaders from around the region, we&#8217;ll have more. One thing we will discuss is the multibillion-dollar commitment of the GCC to invest in the Partnership for Global Infrastructure Investment, which I announced at the G7 last month, to help address infrastructure needs of low- and middle-income countries that don&#8217;t have the wherewithal to borrow the funds to meet the needs of their people.</p>



<p>And after years of failed efforts, we have now finalized an agreement to connect Iraq’s electric grid to the GCC grids through Kuwait and Saudi Arabia, and deepening Iraq’s integration into the region and reducing its dependence on Iran. And it was pointed out to me that remi- &#8212; I was reminded by staff at the time, at the meeting, that I tried to do that back when I was &#8212; in the early days of my vice presidency. Finally, it&#8217;s done &#8212; being done.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, I&#8217;ll also be laying out an affirmative framework for America&#8217;s engagement in the Middle East to build on these important steps going forward.</p>



<p>The bottom line is: This trip is about once again positioning America in this region for the future. We are not going to leave a vacuum in the Middle East for Russia or China to fill. And we&#8217;re getting results.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll take a couple of questions now.</p>



<p>Q    What was the Crown Prince’s response to your comments about Khashoggi?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: He basically said that he &#8212; he was not personally responsible for it. I indicated that he probably was. He said he was not personally responsible for it and he took action against those who were responsible. And &#8212; and we &#8212; and then I went on to talk more about how that dealing with any opposition to the &#8212; or criticism of the Saudi administration in other countries was viewed as, to me, a violation of human rights. There was no (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q Sir, two quick questions, if I may. First, we just heard from Jamal Khashoggi’s wife, who said, “After this visit, the blood of MBS’s next victim is on your hands.” What do you say to Mrs. Khashoggi?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: I&#8217;m sorry she feels that way. I was straightforward back then. I was straightforward today.</p>



<p>What I &#8212; this is a meeting not &#8212; I didn&#8217;t come here to meet with the Crown Prince.  I came here to meet with the GCC and nine nations to deal with the security and &#8212; and the needs of the free world, and particularly the United States, and not leave a vacuum here, which was happening as it has in other parts of the world.</p>



<p>Q On gas prices, if I may, you said that we’ll see relief at some point in the not-too-distant future. What is the message to Americans who are looking for that relief now? When should they expect to see a real change in prices, though they&#8217;ve already been coming down?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: But there’s been a real change.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: That’s right. They&#8217;ve been coming down every single day, to the best of my knowledge.</p>



<p>Q When will we see the impact of this visit?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: I suspect you won&#8217;t see that for another couple weeks. And we’ll see more when we see gas stations start to lower their price consistent with what they’re paying for the oil. That’s another issue.</p>



<p>Q Mr. President, do you regret calling the Saudis a “pariah” during your campaign?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: I don’t regret anything I said.</p>



<p>Next question.</p>



<p>Q Do you still feel that way though, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: I just answered your question, “Do I regret it?” I don’t regret anything that I said. What happened to Khashoggi was outrageous.</p>



<p>Q Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: Yes.</p>



<p>Q You’re coming under a lot of fire for your fist bump with the Crown Prince. Why &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q    I just wanted to give you a chance to respond to that. </p>



<p>And &#8212; but also, how can you be sure that another incident, another murder like Jamal Khashoggi’s won’t happen again?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: Well &#8212; God love you. What a silly question. How could I possibly be sure of any of that? I just made it clear if anything occurs like that again, they’ll get that response and much more.</p>



<p>Look, you’ve heard me say before &#8212; and when I criticized Xi Jinping for slave labor and what they’re doing in the &#8212; in the western mountains of China, and they said I had no right to criticize China. And I said, “Look, I am President of the United States of America. For the United States President to remain silent on a clear violation of human rights is totally inconsistent with who we are, what we are, and what we would do, what we believe.” And so I’m not going to remain silent.</p>



<p>Can I predict anything is going to happen, let alone here, let alone in any other part of the world? No.</p>



<p>But I don’t know why you’re all so surprised the way I react. No one has ever wondered did I mean what I say. The question is I sometimes say all that I mean.</p>



<p>Q    And what &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: That’s the &#8212;</p>



<p>Q But what about your response to the despots?</p>



<p>Q Did you manage to &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: Thank you.</p>



<p>Q On the issue of climate, Joe Manchin obviously made significant news right now, which appears to be torpedoing what was one of your biggest priorities as it relates to energy and to climate back at home. Your message to those Americans right now who are looking for that relief that would have a wide impact as it affects the climate and energy specifically?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: I am not going away. I’m going to use every power I have as President to continue to fulfill my pledge to move toward dealing with global warming.</p>



<p>Thank you very much.</p>



<p>Q Mr. President, is Joe Manchin negotiating in good faith?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: I didn’t negotiate with Joe Manchin. I have no idea.</p>



<p>END 10:55 P.M. AST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Appointments to Boards and&#160;Commissions</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/president-biden-announces-key-appointments-to-boards-and-commissions-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles: Margaret Aitken Haggerty, Member and Chair, Commission on Presidential Scholars Jennifer D. Bishop, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars Kenneth Vernon Brittingham, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars Clifford K. Chiu, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars Mary Quinn Delaney,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Margaret Aitken Haggerty, Member and Chair, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Jennifer D. Bishop, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Kenneth Vernon Brittingham, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Clifford K. Chiu, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Mary Quinn Delaney, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Ryan D. Easterly, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Peter Van D. Emerson, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Antonio Farias, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Neil J. Horgan, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Frank F. Islam, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Cynthia Jackson Hammond, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Dan J. Kessler, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Domenika Lynch, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Sarah McBride, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Rodin A. Mehrbani, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Brian O’Dwyer, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Stephanie Robinson, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Kurt Russell, Sr., Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Juan Antonio Sepúlveda, Jr., Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Terrance Blackman Stroud, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li><li>Jason Sung Won Yoon, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</li></ul>



<p>The Commission on Presidential Scholars is a group of eminent private citizens appointed by the President to select and honor the Presidential Scholars. Commissioners are selected from across the country, representing the fields of education, medicine, law, social services, business, and other professions. The Commissioners make the final selection of the 161 Presidential Scholars. The Scholars demonstrate exceptional accomplishments in academics, the arts, career and technical education and an outstanding commitment to public service.<br><br><strong>Margaret Aitken Haggerty, Member and Chair, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Margaret Aitken Haggerty is a seasoned communications professional who works with local, national, and international businesses and nonprofit organizations, providing them with strategic communication counsel, crisis communication planning, messaging strategy, and media intervention. Prior to founding her own firm, for more than a decade Aitken served as the Spokesperson and Press Secretary for then-Senator, now President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Throughout her career, she has collaborated with and advised top government officials, political candidates, and business executives and has served on the boards of several philanthropic organizations.<br><br>Aitken is a native Delawarean and resides in Wilmington with her husband Chris, and sons Ronan and Cullen. She is a graduate of the University of Delaware and holds a master’s degree in Communication and Media Studies from Johns Hopkins University.<br><br><strong>Jennifer D. Bishop, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Born in Chicago, Illinois and raised in Atlanta, Georgia, Dr. Jennifer Bishop has wide-ranging experience as an entrepreneur, author, speaker, philanthropist, and faith and community leader. In addition to serving as Chief Executive Officer for the Savannah Communications Group, BishopSpeaks, and Grace Academy Child Development Center, Bishop also serves in the non-profit sector as Chief Executive Officer for RARE Leaders and the APEX Institute. She is currently seated as the Chairwoman for the City of Columbia Commercial Revolving Loan Fund Committee. Bishop earned her Bachelor of Arts in History and Master of Public Administration at Savannah State University and her Ph.D. in Organizational Leadership from Columbia International University. Bishop has committed herself to expanding educational opportunities through her professional activity as well as working with organizations like the Children’s Trust of South Carolina, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc., and Jack &amp; Jill of America. Making her home in Columbia, South Carolina, Bishop is married to Dr. Aaron Bishop, and they are the proud parents of one son, Peyton.<br><br><strong>Kenneth Vernon Brittingham, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Ken Brittingham is a leader in learning whose working life has been devoted to improving the quality of education for children, youth, families, and adult learners. As a counselor, school psychologist, principal, school superintendent, state education director, and technical college board Vice Chairman and Board President, Brittingham has provided leadership at the elementary, middle school, high school, higher education, and state education department levels. His lifetime work has centered on creating the conditions where all learners achieve at high levels. At the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction, he served as the State Director of the Bureau of Exceptional Children and co-authored a statewide distributed book on improving career development programs in local schools. He has a bachelor’s degree in Industrial Technology, a masters in school counseling, and a masters in school psychology. His Doctorate of Philosophy was earned at the University of Wisconsin, and he was invited to the American Association of Educational Research annual convention to present his dissertation on improving school community relationships.<br><br><strong>Clifford K. Chiu, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Clifford K. Chiu serves as a senior adviser to Vista Equity Partners and its executive committee. Chiu sits as a corporate director on the boards of Aquia, Allvue Systems, Apptio, Finastra, Fusion Risk Management, Logic Monitor, Securonix, and TIBCO, as well as a senior adviser to Neuberger Berman in Hong Kong. He is a member of the National Committee on United States-China Relations and a public appointee on the advisory panel of Cyberport Hong Kong. With a career spanning over four decades, Chiu was a partner of Kohlberg Kravis Roberts &amp; Co. where he founded and led capital raising and investor relations for the Asia Pacific region. He was previously at JP Morgan Asset Management and at Salomon Smith Barney/Citigroup and its predecessors based in New York, Hong Kong, and Tokyo.<br><br>Chiu is a director or trustee of the Seton Fund, Greater Austin Asian Chamber of Commerce, Health Alliance for Austin Musicians, and St. James Settlement. A lifelong champion of education and healthcare, Chiu has served on the global advisory boards of the Weingarten Learning Resources Center at the University of Pennsylvania and of the University of Chicago Booth School of Business where in 2015 he was appointed the first “distinguished executive-in-residence” at its Hong Kong campus. Through the Clinton Global Initiative, Chiu launched a 2015 commitment to action, “K-12 Learning Through Global Connectivity” in language arts and STEM skills. Chiu also endowed annual scholarships at his alma maters Chicago Booth and the University of Pennsylvania as well as the Hong Kong University Medical School, Pomona College, and the Tuck School of Business at Dartmouth. Chiu has partnered with Dell Seton and Ascension Seton Medical Centers in student mental health, underinsured COVID-19 pandemic patients, and maternal morbidity. Chiu proudly underwrote Stop AAPI Hate&#8217;s first-ever impact report (“Turning a Moment into a Movement”) that was released in January 2022.<br><br><strong>Mary Quinn Delaney, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Quinn Delaney is the Founder and Board Chair of Akonadi Foundation, located in Oakland, California, which supports the development of powerful social change movements to eliminate structural racism and create a racially just society. Delaney has spent over thirty-five years working in social change philanthropy.<br><br>In addition to Akonadi Foundation, she currently serves on the boards of East Bay Community Foundation, the Oakland Museum of California, Planned Parenthood Action Fund, Women Donors Network Action, and Smart Justice California, which works on criminal justice reform. Over the years, she has served on many other boards, including the ACLU of Northern California, Community Change, the Democracy Alliance, Tides Foundation, and Pitzer College. In 2019, Delaney was appointed to the California Commission on the Status of Women and Girls where she continues to serve as a Commissioner championing the power and strength of women and girls. She is married to Wayne Jordan and has two adult sons and two grandchildren.<br><br><strong>Ryan D. Easterly, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Ryan Easterly serves as executive director of the WITH Foundation. An experienced grantmaker, strategist, and advocate, Easterly lives and works at the intersections of race, class, disability, and sexual orientation and is driven by a desire to effect meaningful change. Before joining WITH, he served on its Board of Directors, which advanced his commitment to disability justice and the need for broader access to comprehensive healthcare for adults with developmental disabilities. Easterly has worked in the federal sector and within community outreach and advocacy efforts. He is a co-founder and previous director of Northern California Community Relations at MySupport, Inc. As manager of the National Youth Transitions Initiative for The HSC Foundation, a Washington, DC operating foundation of a health system for children and young adults with complex medical needs, he provided funding and programmatic support for a grantee and collaborative network serving young people with disabilities and young veterans. Easterly also worked at the U.S. Department of Labor’s Office of Disability Employment Policy.<br><br>Easterly regularly advises on issues such as community participatory grantmaking, inclusive philanthropy, leadership development, employment, and healthcare impacting communities of color, the foster care system, and the LGBTQ+ community. He is a member of the Presidents’ Council on Disability Inclusion in Philanthropy, the Disability &amp; Philanthropy Forum Steering Committee, and co-chairs Exponent Philanthropy’s Disability Funders Peer Circle. Easterly hails from Alabama, and after moving to the West Coast, often wonders when he will find his next glass of sweet tea.<br><br><strong>Peter Van D. Emerson, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Peter Van D. Emerson is an entrepreneur in business and public policy. He is co-founder of KAPE International, LLC, a global strategic communications firm, an Advisor on Policy for the Division on Addiction, Cambridge Health Alliance, a teaching affiliate of Harvard Medical School, and Chairman, College Task Force on College Gambling and Alcohol Policies. As a teaching assistant at Harvard College, he was twice awarded a Certificate of Distinction in Teaching. Emerson works with students on the critical challenges of addiction and mental health.<br><br>Emerson has served on the Board of Visitors for the University of North Carolina-Wilmington. He was elected to the American Academy of Underwater Sciences and The Explorers Club. Emerson served on the Ocean Futures’ Board and the Advisory Committee for the NY Aquarium, part of the Wildlife Conservation Society. His previous public service includes the National Advisory Committee on Oceans and Atmosphere and the President’s Commission on White House Fellowships. Emerson received a BA from New York University, <em>magna cum laude,</em> and a MPA from the Harvard Kennedy School.<br><br><strong>Antonio Farias, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Antonio Farias serves as the Vice Chancellor for Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion responsible for driving and developing initiatives that build on and advance CU Denver’s commitment to equity and justice. Farias joined CU Denver from the University of Florida, where he served as its inaugural Chief Diversity Officer and Senior Advisor to the President. There he oversaw university-wide efforts to advance The Big I.D.E.A! – Inclusion, Diversity, Equity, &amp; Access. Farias worked closely with cabinet members, deans, and a network of campus diversity liaisons embedded in the leadership teams of each college and business unit, who advanced I.D.E.A. within their respective micro cultures. Farias was previously Vice President for Equity and Inclusion at Wesleyan University and, before that, the inaugural Chief Diversity Officer for the U.S. Coast Guard Academy. He has bachelor’s and master’s degrees from the University of California, Berkeley and a Master of Fine Arts from the University of California, Riverside. He worships his daughter, reenergizes through a plant-based diet, runs ultra-marathons to test the limits of WHY, fly fishes to commune with the divine, and believes failure is the greatest teacher. He is currently failing to publish his first novel.<br><br><strong>Neil J. Horgan, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Horgan was born in Chester, Pennsylvania and raised in Wilmington, Delaware, and is a graduate of Archmere Academy. He earned a Bachelor’s of Science in Business Administration from Georgetown University with a major in Accounting and a Master of Taxation from Villanova University. Horgan is presently the Vice President for Finance and Chief Financial Officer at Villanova University. He lives in Havertown, PA with his wife Kathryn and their two children. Horgan previously served on the Board of Directors of the Mercy Health System of Southeastern Pennsylvania.<br><br><strong>Frank F. Islam, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Frank Islam is an entrepreneur, philanthropist, and civic leader with a special commitment to civic, educational, and artistic causes. He currently heads the FI Investment Group, a private investment holding company that he founded after he sold his information technology firm, the QSS Group, in 2007. Islam serves and has served on numerous boards and advisory councils including the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, the U.N. Foundation, the U.S. Institute of Peace, and the Woodrow Wilson Center. He has also served or serves on boards and councils at several universities including John Hopkins, American University, George Mason University, the University of Maryland, and Harvard University.<br><br>Islam has written two well-regarded books on the American condition: <em>Working the Pivot Points: To Make America Work Again</em> and <em>Renewing the American Dream: A Citizen’s Guide for Restoring Our Competitive Advantage</em>. He blogs regularly on Medium and was a contributor to the Huffington Post for nearly a decade. In 2018, Islam established the Frank Islam Institute for 21<sup>st</sup> Century Citizenship which maintains a website and publishes a monthly newsletter featuring articles and other material directed at addressing the civic engagement deficit and challenges to democracy in the U.S. and internationally. Islam received his B.S. and M.S. in Computer Science from the University of Colorado at Boulder.<br><br><strong>Cynthia Jackson Hammond, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Dr. Cynthia Jackson Hammond is President of the Council for Higher Education Accreditation (CHEA). As President, she has led several initiatives including the development and adoption of CHEA’s value statement on diversity, equity, and inclusion and an enhanced focus on service to CHEA’s over 1,900 member institutions. Jackson Hammond has been a member of the higher education community for more than 30 years. Her professional career has included tenured and administrative positions at universities throughout the United States, including the University of Louisiana Monroe, California State University Dominguez Hills, Delaware State University, the University of North Carolina Charlotte, Winston-Salem State University, and Coppin State University. Most recently, she completed her tenure as President of Central State University in Ohio. She holds graduate degrees in Communications, Counseling Education, Student Personnel Services, and Higher Education Administration.<br><br>Jackson Hammond has served on many national boards including the Thurgood Marshall College Fund, NCAA Division II Presidents Council, the American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, and the Council for Higher Education Accreditation. She has appeared several times on Capitol Hill providing testimony regarding the status of 1890 Land-Grant institutions. Throughout her career, Jackson Hammond has been committed to advancing college success, equity, and integrity in higher education. She is an ardent advocate for quality assurance and transparency in higher education.<br><br><strong>Dan J. Kessler, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Dan Kessler is the Co-Founder and Managing Partner of K2 Developers, a company developing and repurposing existing buildings into dignified, economical housing for essential workers in ski, sand, and entertainment destinations across the United States. Working with K2, a public REIT and an investment fund, Kessler has worked to close $4 billion and 10 million square feet of real estate transactions. Prior to co-founding K2 Developers, Kessler worked in hospitality in executive leadership programs at Marriott International and MGM Resorts International in Las Vegas.<br><br>Kessler’s civic activity began with his days as a White House Intern for President Obama. He is currently a Political Partner with the Truman National Security Project and a New Leaders Council Fellow. Kessler has received various awards and recognitions, including a 40Under40 Award from both the Philadelphia Business Journal and City &amp; State Pennsylvania, and received a 30Under30 Award from Politics PA. Kessler was invited by The Council of Europe and delivered a speech at the World Forum for Democracy in Strasbourg, France, where his grassroots engagement strategy placed second amongst thousands for the “Democracy Innovation Award” and was published in MIT Sloan Experts. Kessler graduated with his MBA from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology’s Sloan School of Management and BBA<em>, summa cum laude</em>, from The George Washington University School of Business.<br><br><strong>Domenika Lynch, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Domenika Lynch is the Executive Director of the Aspen Institute Latinos and Society Program, with the mission of empowering Latino communities and promoting long-term economic growth and resiliency. Over the course of two decades in leadership roles, Lynch has overseen strategic planning, policy advocacy, and public affairs campaigns for nonprofits and corporations, increasing donor and stakeholder support and raising millions of dollars for organizational endowments.<br><br>Prior to joining the Aspen Institute, Lynch served as president and CEO of the Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute, the preeminent Latino Leadership Institute founded by Hispanic members of Congress in Washington, DC. She previously spent more than a decade as executive director of the Latino Alumni Association at the University of Southern California. Her professional breadth extends into the corporate sector, with previous leadership positions at Bank of America and Univision. Lynch currently serves on the Board of Directors of the Congressional Management Foundation and serves on Bank of America’s National Community Advisory Council, which advises the bank on community development, environmental, and consumer policy issues. She also serves on the Council on Underserved Communities, which provides the U.S. Small Business Administration with input, advice, and recommendations on strategies to help strengthen competitiveness and sustainability for small businesses in underserved communities. A graduate of the USC Price School of Public Policy, Lynch holds a master’s degree from the USC Rossier School of Education. She is the proud parent of her son Jacob, also a USC alumnus.<br><br><strong>Sarah McBride, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Senator Sarah McBride represents the First Senate District in the Delaware Senate. McBride serves as the chair of the Health and Social Services Committee, where she has championed health care reforms that lower costs, expand access, and improve quality. In just her first term, McBride successfully passed paid family and medical leave in the First State, marking the largest expansion of Delaware&#8217;s social safety net in decades. Prior to her service in the state senate, McBride was a national leader in the fight for LGBTQ equality and served as the spokesperson for the Human Rights Campaign. When she was elected, McBride became the first openly transgender state senator in American history.<br><br><strong>Rodin A. Mehrbani, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Rudy Mehrbani is the senior director of the Governance Program at Democracy Fund, an independent foundation. Mehrbani is also a senior practitioner fellow at the University of Chicago’s Center for Effective Government. He was previously a senior fellow and senior counsel at the Brennan Center for Justice, a nonpartisan law and policy center, where he worked to protect voting rights and directed the National Task Force on Rule of Law and Democracy. From 2016 to 2021, he was a member of the J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board, where he served as the Board’s vice chair from 2019 to 2020.<br><br>Mehrbani served in a variety of senior roles in the Obama-Biden Administration. From 2016 to 2017, he was an Assistant to the President and Director of the Presidential Personnel Office in the White House. In that role, he was also a member of the White House Transition Coordinating Council. He was the General Counsel of the Peace Corps from 2014 to 2016, serving as the principal legal officer and a senior advisor to the Director of the Peace Corps. Before that, he served as an Associate Counsel and Special Assistant to the President in the White House Counsel’s Office. Earlier in his career, Mehrbani was a litigation associate at Kirkland &amp; Ellis LLP. He received a BA from Emory University and a JD from the University of Virginia School of Law.<br><br><strong>Brian O’Dwyer, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Brian O’Dwyer has distinguished himself in the law and education. He is a founder of the Emerald Isle Immigration Center dedicated to providing assistance to all immigrants. His work in promoting peace in Ireland was acknowledged when he was named Grand Marshall of the New York Saint Patrick’s Day Parade. A longtime advocate for equal access to higher education, he has served as Chair of the CUNY Law School Foundation, Chair of the Advisory Council of the George Washington University Graduate School of Political Management, and Board Member of Dublin City University Educational Trust.<br><br>O’Dwyer has earned an AB and LLM from the George Washington University, a JD from Georgetown University, and an MA from Middlebury College. He is a member of Sigma Delta Pi national Spanish honorary and has been awarded the honorary degrees of Doctor of Philosophy from Dublin City University and Doctor of Humane Letters from Middlebury College.<br><br><strong>Stephanie Robinson, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Stephanie Robinson is a Board Member and advisor to educational, healthcare, and cultural organizations. She currently serves as a publicly-elected Trustee for the Ross School District in California, a position she has held since 2015, and as a Director and Vice Chair of the MarinHealth Foundation. Previously, Robinson worked as a Vice President in Health Care Investment Banking at Bankers Trust and as a management consultant at the Boston Consulting Group. She is active in local, state, and national politics as a fundraiser, community organizer, and voter protection volunteer. She holds an MBA from Harvard Business School, a JD from Harvard Law School, and a BA from UC Berkeley in Economics.<br><br><strong>Kurt Russell, Sr., Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Kurt Russell, the 2022 National Teacher of the Year, is a veteran teacher at Oberlin High School in the Oberlin City Schools district who believes education can transform students’ lives. For the past twenty-five years, Russell has included cultural relevance in the curriculum for the 9<sup>th</sup>-12<sup>th</sup> grade classes he teaches: African American History, U.S. History, IB History of the Americas, and Race, Gender, and Oppression. Russell received the teacher of the year awards from the Oberlin Heritage Center and the Oberlin Chapter of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. In addition to teaching history classes, Russell also serves as a lead teacher at Oberlin High School and advisor for the Black Student Union, Student Council, and Junior Class.<br><br><strong>Juan Antonio Sepúlveda, Jr., Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Sepúlveda currently serves as the President’s Special Advisor for Inclusive Excellence and the Ron Calgaard Distinguished Professor of Practice in the Political Science Department at Trinity University in San Antonio, Texas. Prior to Trinity, he was Senior Vice President of Station Services at PBS, where he collaborated with more than 160 PBS stations across the country to strengthen their connections to their local communities and to each other as a national public media network. Sepúlveda joined PBS from the Democratic National Committee, where he was Senior Advisor for Hispanic Affairs helping re-elect President Barack Obama with record-level Hispanic support. In 2008, Sepúlveda served as the Texas State Director for the Obama for America campaign.</p>



<p>In the Obama-Biden Administration, Sepúlveda served as Executive Director of the White House Initiative on Educational Excellence for Hispanics, where he designed and led the first-ever White House Hispanic Policy Conference along with a series of White House Hispanic Community Action Summits. His national strategy consulting organization, the Common Enterprise, which grew out of a national Rockefeller Foundation initiative, took him to more than 35 states where he worked with communities in urban and rural settings. Sepúlveda was the third Latino awarded a Rhodes Scholarship. He graduated from Harvard College with a Bachelor of Arts in Government. He also holds a Master of Arts in Politics, Philosophy &amp; Economics from The Queen’s College, Oxford University, a Juris Doctorate from Stanford Law School, and has been admitted to the Texas Bar.<br><br><strong>Terrance Blackman Stroud, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Terrance Blackman Stroud is a Deputy Commissioner at the New York City Department of Social Services leading the Office of Training &amp; Workforce Development, which manages the development and implementation of the agency’s learning strategy. Stroud serves on the National Staff Development Training Association’s Executive Advisory Council and the Public Sector Network’s Leadership Advisory Board. He is also one of the Tri-chairs of the American Public Human Services Association’s Equity Diversity and Inclusion Peer Community.<br><br>Stroud is a fourth-generation educator whose focus is on the intersection of academic institutions and the global workforce. He is a New York-based adjunct faculty member at Indiana University Bloomington. He is the inaugural Global Affairs Fellow at the Hamilton Lugar School of Global and International Studies where he leads the Global Leaders and Professionals Program. In addition, Stroud is an Adjunct Professor of Law overseeing the Maurer School of Law’s New York Externship Program and is the first Black recipient of the Adjunct Faculty Teaching Award. Stroud is a graduate of Brooklyn Technical High School, Brooklyn College, and Indiana Maurer School of Law.<br><br><strong>Jason Sung Won Yoon, Member, Commission on Presidential Scholars</strong><br>Jason Yoon has dedicated much of his career to supporting the talent and creativity of America’s young people. He has served as the executive director of New Urban Arts, a nationally recognized nonprofit youth arts studio (winner of a 2009 National Arts and Humanities Youth Program Award); the Director of Education at the Queens Museum, a museum renowned for its commitment to art, education, and social justice; and the executive director of Atlas: DIY, a nonprofit that worked with immigrant youth through legal services, educational programs, and leadership development. For several years, he also taught art and social change in Goucher College’s MA program in Cultural Sustainability. Currently, Yoon is working on several personal creative writing projects and as the interim development manager for Sakhi for South Asian Women, a groundbreaking gender justice organization. Yoon has a Bachelor of Fine Arts from the Rhode Island School of Design and a Masters in Public Administration from NYU’s Wagner School of Public Service.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Signs Executive Order Creating a Presidential Emergency&#160;Board </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/president-biden-signs-executive-order-creating-a-presidential-emergency-board/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order establishing a Presidential Emergency Board, effective July 18, 2022, to help resolve an ongoing dispute between major freight rail carriers and their unions. Keeping supply chains running means keeping America’s railways running. In making the decision to create the Presidential Emergency Board, the President has considered input from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order establishing a Presidential Emergency Board, effective July 18, 2022, to help resolve an ongoing dispute between major freight rail carriers and their unions.<br><br>Keeping supply chains running means keeping America’s railways running. In making the decision to create the Presidential Emergency Board, the President has considered input from relevant stakeholders. The President’s goal is to make sure America’s freight rail system continues to run without disruption, delivering the items that our families, communities, farms and businesses rely on.<br><br>The Presidential Emergency Board will provide a structure for workers and management to resolve their disagreements.  The Board will investigate the dispute and, within 30 days of its establishment, deliver a report recommending how the dispute should be resolved.<br><br>By statute, the Executive Order triggers a “cooling off” period intended to keep the parties working toward a negotiated settlement.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Establishing an Emergency Board to Investigate Disputes Between Certain Railroads Represented by the National Carriers’ Conference Committee of the National Railway Labor Conference and Their Employees Represented by Certain Labor&#160;Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/15/executive-order-on-establishing-an-emergency-board-to-investigate-disputes-between-certain-railroads-represented-by-the-national-carriers-conference-committee-of-the-national-railway-labor-co/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Disputes exist between certain railroads represented by the National Carriers&#8217; Conference Committee of the National Railway Labor Conference and their employees represented by certain labor organizations. &#160;The railroads and labor organizations involved in these disputes are designated on the attached list, which is made part of this order. The disputes have not heretofore been&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Disputes exist between certain railroads represented by the National Carriers&#8217; Conference Committee of the National Railway Labor Conference and their employees represented by certain labor organizations. &nbsp;The railroads and labor organizations involved in these disputes are designated on the attached list, which is made part of this order.</p>



<p>The disputes have not heretofore been adjusted under the provisions of the Railway Labor Act, as amended, 45 U.S.C. 151-188 (RLA).</p>



<p>I have been notified by the National Mediation Board that in its judgment these disputes threaten substantially to interrupt interstate commerce to a degree that would deprive a section of the country of essential transportation service.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, by the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including section 10 of the RLA (45 U.S.C. 160), it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1. &nbsp;Establishment of Emergency Board (Board). &nbsp;There is established, effective 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on July 18, 2022, a Board composed of a chair and two other members, all of whom shall be appointed by the President to investigate and report on these disputes. &nbsp;No member shall be pecuniarily or otherwise interested in any organization of railroad employees or any carrier. &nbsp;The Board shall perform its functions subject to the availability of funds.</p>



<p>Sec. 2. &nbsp;Report. &nbsp;The Board shall report to the President with respect to the disputes within 30 days of its creation.</p>



<p>Sec. 3. &nbsp;Maintaining Conditions. &nbsp;As provided by section 10 of the RLA, from the date of the creation of the Board and for 30 days after the Board has submitted its report to the President, no change in the conditions out of which the disputes arose shall be made by the parties to the controversy, except by agreement of the parties.</p>



<p>Sec. 4. &nbsp;Records Maintenance. &nbsp;The records and files of the Board are records of the Office of the President and upon the Board&#8217;s termination shall be maintained in the physical custody of the National Mediation Board.</p>



<p>Sec. 5. &nbsp;Expiration. &nbsp;The Board shall terminate upon the submission of the report provided for in section 2 of this order.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 15, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
