<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 13:59:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Senior Administration Official Travel to&#160;Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-senior-administration-official-travel-to-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden’s&#160;National&#160;Security Advisor Jake Sullivan,&#160;DHS Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas, and Under Secretary of State&#160;Uzra Zeya traveled&#160;to Mexico&#160;on August 10&#160;to advance U.S.-Mexico cooperation across&#160;our&#160;bilateral agenda. &#160;NSC Senior Director Juan Gonzalez,&#160;National Security Advisor to the Vice President Ambassador Nancy McEldowney, Ambassador Julissa Reynoso, State Department Senior Western Hemisphere Bureau Official Ricardo Zuniga, and Department of Homeland Security Assistant&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden’s&nbsp;National&nbsp;Security Advisor Jake Sullivan,&nbsp;DHS Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas, and Under Secretary of State&nbsp;Uzra Zeya traveled&nbsp;to Mexico&nbsp;on August 10&nbsp;to advance U.S.-Mexico cooperation across&nbsp;our&nbsp;bilateral agenda. &nbsp;NSC Senior Director Juan Gonzalez,&nbsp;National Security Advisor to the Vice President Ambassador Nancy McEldowney, Ambassador Julissa Reynoso, State Department Senior Western Hemisphere Bureau Official Ricardo Zuniga, and Department of Homeland Security Assistant Secretary David&nbsp;Shahoulian&nbsp;also traveled with the delegation. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>National Security Advisor Sullivan and his team met with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador, Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard, Attorney General Gertz, and Secretary of Finance Ramirez de la O, as well as other senior Mexican government representatives. The visit followed a phone call between Vice President Kamala Harris and President López Obrador on August 9, and provided an opportunity to discuss economic and security priorities, such as competitiveness, our shared border, COVID-19 recovery, security cooperation, and development in southern Mexico and Central America.</p>



<p>During the visit, U.S. and Mexican officials reaffirmed the strategic relationship between our two countries. Given the strong economic ties binding us, the delegations advanced preparations for the upcoming relaunch of the U.S.-Mexico High-Level Economic Dialogue (HLED), which will be held in Washington on September 9. They discussed opportunities to better integrate our economies to make them more resilient, including the potential to strengthen and pivot supply chains in alignment with our domestic efforts to build back better. National Security Advisor Sullivan also affirmed our cooperation on health security, including assessing the current COVID-19 situation on the ground in both countries and collaborating to manage the pandemic together.<br><br>Officials underscored the importance of fostering development in southern Mexico and Central America to address the root causes of irregular migration, and will work toward deeper collaboration within the Root Causes Strategy. They discussed current irregular migration flows and committed to jointly managing safe, orderly migration that respects human rights. The National Security Advisor and Mexican leaders also affirmed their commitment to a regional approach to migration. In addition, Mexican and U.S. officials spoke about plans for strategic security cooperation, a central pillar of our relationship. They discussed next steps toward the commitment made during Vice President Harris’ visit in June to hold a High-Level Security Dialogue with Mexico.<br><br>During his visit, National Security Advisor Sullivan stressed that the United States and Mexico share democratic values and joint priorities, including improving global health, security, and economic prosperity for all.<br><br>Additional representatives of the Government of Mexico included National Migration Institute Commissioner Francisco Garduno, Mexican Army Major General and Southern Border Coordinator General Vicente Hernandez,  Army Lieutenant General and Commander of Military Operations General Guillermo Briseno, Mexican Navy Rear Admiral and Undersecretary for Administration Vice-Admiral Benito Galeana, Undersecretary of Public Security Ricardo Mejia, and Chief of the Secretariat of Foreign Relations North America Unit Roberto Velasco.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on the Need for Reliable and Stable Global Energy&#160;Markets</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-the-need-for-reliable-and-stable-global-energy-markets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26825</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Higher gasoline costs, if left unchecked, risk harming the ongoing global recovery. The price of crude oil has been higher than it was at the end of 2019, before the onset of the pandemic. While OPEC+ recently agreed to production increases, these increases will not fully offset previous production cuts that OPEC+ imposed during the pandemic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">Higher gasoline costs, if left unchecked, risk harming the ongoing global recovery. The price of crude oil has been higher than it was at the end of 2019, before the onset of the pandemic.<br><br>While OPEC+ recently agreed to production increases, these increases will not fully offset previous production cuts that OPEC+ imposed during the pandemic until well into 2022. At a critical moment in the global recovery, this is simply not enough. <br><br>President Biden has made clear that he wants Americans to have access to affordable and reliable energy, including at the pump. Although we are not a party to OPEC, the United States will always speak to international partners regarding issues of significance that affect our national economic and security affairs, in public and private. We are engaging with relevant OPEC+ members on the importance of competitive markets in setting prices. Competitive energy markets will ensure reliable and stable energy supplies, and OPEC+ must do more to support the recovery.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-34/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 12:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Elizabeth Prelogar, of Idaho, to be Solicitor General of the United States, vice Noel J. Francisco. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Ramin Toloui, of Iowa, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Economic and Business Affairs), vice Manisha Singh. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Elizabeth Prelogar, of Idaho, to be Solicitor General of the United States, vice Noel J. Francisco.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ramin Toloui, of Iowa, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Economic and Business Affairs), vice Manisha Singh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Nominates Elizabeth Prelogar for Solicitor&#160;General</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/president-biden-nominates-elizabeth-prelogar-for-solicitor-general/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced he has nominated Elizabeth Prelogar as Solicitor General at the Department of Justice. Elizabeth Prelogar, Nominee for Solicitor General, Department of JusticeElizabeth Prelogar began serving as the Acting Solicitor General at the U. S. Department of Justice in January 2021. Prelogar has focused her career on Supreme Court and appellate litigation. From 2014 to 2019, she served&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced he has nominated Elizabeth Prelogar as Solicitor General at the Department of Justice.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Elizabeth Prelogar, Nominee for Solicitor General, Department of Justice<br></span></strong><br>Elizabeth Prelogar began serving as the Acting Solicitor General at the U. S. Department of Justice in January 2021. Prelogar has focused her career on Supreme Court and appellate litigation. From 2014 to 2019, she served as an Assistant to the Solicitor General.  During her prior tenure at the Department of Justice, Prelogar was asked to serve on the Special Counsel’s Russia investigation and was an Assistant Special Counsel to Robert S. Mueller III. Prelogar has also spent time as a partner at Cooley LLP and an associate at Hogan Lovells, and she taught a course at Harvard Law School on Supreme Court and appellate advocacy. <br><br>After graduating from Harvard Law School, Prelogar clerked for Judge Merrick B. Garland of the U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit. She then completed consecutive Supreme Court clerkships for Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg and Justice Elena Kagan. Prelogar previously completed a master’s degree in creative writing at the University of St. Andrews in Scotland, earned her undergraduate degree in English and Russian from Emory University, and was a Fulbright Fellow in St. Petersburg, Russia. Born and raised in Idaho, Prelogar lives in Washington, D.C. with her husband and their two sons.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden to Convene Leaders’ Summit for&#160;Democracy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/president-biden-to-convene-leaders-summit-for-democracy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26773</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President has said that the challenge of our time is to demonstrate that democracies can deliver&#160;by improving the lives of their own people and by addressing the greatest problems facing the wider world. In his first six months in office, the President has reinvigorated democracy at home, vaccinating 70% of population, passing the&#160;American Rescue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President has said that the challenge of our time is to demonstrate that democracies can deliver&nbsp;by improving the lives of their own people and by addressing the greatest problems facing the wider world. In his first six months in office, the President has reinvigorated democracy at home, vaccinating 70% of population, passing the&nbsp;American Rescue plan, and advancing bipartisan legislation to invest in our infrastructure and competitiveness. And&nbsp;he has rebuilt our alliances with our democratic partners and allies, rallying the world to stand up against human rights abuses, to address the climate crisis, and to fight the global pandemic, including by donating hundreds of millions of vaccine doses to countries around the globe.</p>



<p>In keeping this commitment, today President Biden is pleased to announce that in December he will bring together leaders from a diverse group of the world’s democracies at a virtual Summit for Democracy, to be followed in roughly a year’s time by a second, in-person Summit. The virtual Summit, to take place on December 9 and 10, will galvanize commitments and initiatives across three principal themes: defending against authoritarianism, fighting corruption, and promoting respect for human rights. Following a year of consultation, coordination, and action, President Biden will then invite world leaders to gather once more to showcase progress made against their commitments. Both Summits will bring together heads of state, civil society, philanthropy, and the private sector, serving as an opportunity for world leaders to listen to one another and to their citizens, share successes, drive international collaboration, and speak honestly about the challenges facing democracy so as to collectively strengthen the foundation for democratic renewal.</p>



<p>Find more here: <a href="https://www.state.gov/summit-for-democracy/">https://www.state.gov/summit-for-democracy/</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-33/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 01:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Jessica D. Aber, of Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Virginia for the term of four years, vice G. Zachary Terwilliger, resigned. &#160; &#160; &#160;Nicole L. Angarella, of Virginia, to be Inspector General, United States Agency for International Development, vice Ann Calvaresi Barr,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jessica D. Aber, of Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Virginia for the term of four years, vice G. Zachary Terwilliger, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Nicole L. Angarella, of Virginia, to be Inspector General, United States Agency for International Development, vice Ann Calvaresi Barr, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Samuel R. Bagenstos, of Michigan, to be General Counsel of the Department of Health and Human Services, vice Robert Charrow.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Alexandra Baker, of New Jersey, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense, vice James H. Anderson, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jainey Kumar Bavishi, of New York, to be Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, vice Timothy Gallaudet.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Sarah H. Cleveland, of New York, to be Legal Adviser of the Department of State, vice Jennifer Gillian Newstead, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;John Patrick Coffey, of New York, to be General Counsel of the Department of the Navy, vice Robert John Sander.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Chester John Culver, of Iowa, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation, vice Myles J. Watts.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Melissa Griffin Dalton, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense, vice Kenneth P. Rapuano.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Carla B. Freedman, of New York, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of New York for the term of four years, vice Richard S. Hartunian, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;David R. Gilmour, of the District of Columbia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Equatorial Guinea.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Todd M. Harper, of Virginia, to be a Member of the National Credit Union Administration Board for a term expiring April 10, 2027. &nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Owen Edward Herrnstadt, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States for a term expiring January 20, 2025, vice Judith Delzoppo Pryor, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;William J. Ihlenfeld, II, of West Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of West Virginia for the term of four years, vice William J. Powell, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Maria Fabiana Jorge, of the District of Columbia, to be United States Alternate Executive Director of the Inter-American Development Bank, vice Eliot Pedrosa.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Christopher R. Kavanaugh, of Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Western District of Virginia for the term of four years, vice Thomas T. Cullen, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Victoria Reggie Kennedy, of Massachusetts, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Austria.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Alexia Marie Gabrielle Latortue, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Treasury, vice Mitchell A. Silk.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Amy Loyd, of New Mexico, to be Assistant Secretary for Career, Technical, and Adult Education, Department of Education, vice Scott Stump.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Darcie N. McElwee, of Maine, to be United States Attorney for the District of Maine for the term of four years, vice Halsey B. Frank, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Scott Miller, of Colorado, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Swiss Confederation, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Principality of Liechtenstein.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Brent Neiman, of Illinois, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of the Treasury, vice Ramin Toloui.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Leopoldo Martinez Nucete, of Virginia, to be United States Executive Director of the Inter-American Development Bank for a term of three years, vice Eliot Pedrosa.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Breon S. Peace, of New Jersey, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of New York for the term of four years, vice Robert Lloyd Capers, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Marc R. Stanley, of Texas, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Argentine Republic.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;William S. Thompson, of West Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of West Virginia for the term of four years, vice Michael B. Stuart, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Damian Williams, of New York, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of New York for the term of four years, vice Preet Bharara, term expired.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWAL SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Chester John Culver, of Iowa, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation, vice Charles A. Stones, which was sent to the Senate on July 15, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before a Briefing from the FEMA Administrator, Homeland Security, and COVID-&#8288;19 Response&#160;Teams</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/10/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-briefing-from-the-fema-administrator-homeland-security-and-covid-19-response-teams/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 4:46 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, folks.  I’ll make a brief opening statement here.  I want to thank you, Administrator Criswell, for the job you’ve been doing &#8212; outstanding work helping our country navigate what is overlapping challenges we’ve been facing.  And you’ve been very busy. We’ve got wildfires in the West. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>4:46 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, folks.  I’ll make a brief opening statement here.  I want to thank you, Administrator Criswell, for the job you’ve been doing &#8212; outstanding work helping our country navigate what is overlapping challenges we’ve been facing.  And you’ve been very busy.<br><br>We’ve got wildfires in the West.  We’ve got &#8212; approaching the peak of Atlantic hurricane season.  All across the country, the Delta variant is spreading, as Dr. Fauci and others can tell you, and it&#8217;s spreading rapidly &#8212; rapidly among the unvaccinated.  When these crises intersect, they compound one another &#8212; natural disasters and the Delta variant.<br><br>And that’s what we’re going to be discussing today with the group I’ve assembled here.  We need to be ready to manage our natural disasters caused by hurricanes hitting the Southeast and the environment and with a broad community spread of COVID-19.<br>And the best thing we can do is &#8212; to prepare for that is for everyone who is not vaccinated &#8212; I know it’s a broken record, and I keep saying it &#8212; but to get vaccinated.<br><br>With the Delta variant, we’re seeing a pandemic of the unvaccinated.  Cases and hospitalizations are rising faster in states with low vaccination rates, such as Florida, Texas, Louisiana, Alabama, and Mississippi, which are the states that &#8212; from a hurricane-prone &#8212; they’re the states that are most at risk.<br><br>And so, we don’t wait until it’s too late.  And if, God forbid, a natural disaster strikes, we have to make sure we’re ready to be protected against COVID-19 as well.<br><br>Let me be clear: If you’re in a state where hurricanes often strike &#8212; like Florida or the Gulf Coast or into Texas &#8212; a vital part of preparing for hurricane season is to get vaccinated now.  Everything is more complicated if you’re not vaccinated and a hurricane or a natural disaster hits.<br><br>If you wind up having to evacuate, if you wind up having to stay in a shelter, you don’t want to add COVID-19 to the list of dangers that you’re going to be confronting. <br><br>Get vaccinated now so you’re ready for whatever may come this month.  And it’s likely some serious hurricanes are going to come this month. <br><br>So, go to Ready.gov to make sure that you’re prepared with the hurricane &#8212; with a hurricane plan.  Know your evacuation zones.  Have a plan with your family.  And get your emergency supplies and a go-bag ready, and don’t forget to pack one for your pets as well.  I mean that seriously.<br><br>And if you’ve got older neighbors or people in your community who might need your help, check in to see if you can help them make a plan as well. <br><br>And the bottom line is this: The more we do to prepare, the better off we are when disaster strikes.<br><br>We can’t prevent hurricanes making landfall, but we can prevent people from getting seriously sick and dying from COVID-19.  Get vaccinated and make a plan.<br><br>Thank you, all.  That’s what we’re going to discuss in some detail today with my team.  Thank you all very much.<br><br>4:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Meeting on Hurricane Preparedness During COVID-&#8288;19&#160;Pandemic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-meeting-on-hurricane-preparedness-during-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 23:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26803</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden met with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell, Chief Medical Advisor and NIAID Director Dr. Anthony Fauci, Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall, and COVID-19 Response Coordinator and Counselor to the President Jeff Zients, as well as members of his Homeland Security and COVID-19 Response teams, for a briefing on the state of the COVID-19&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden met with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell, Chief Medical Advisor and NIAID Director Dr. Anthony Fauci, Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall, and COVID-19 Response Coordinator and Counselor to the President Jeff Zients, as well as members of his Homeland Security and COVID-19 Response teams, for a briefing on the state of the COVID-19 pandemic in hurricane-prone states in the South and Southeast.  They discussed efforts underway to protect public health, enhance preparedness, and adapt response and recovery operations to meet the challenges of the combined effects of hurricanes and the spread of the Delta variant. </p>



<p>The President was briefed on the data that demonstrates that the most important preparatory step people can take to prepare for peak hurricane season is to get vaccinated to ensure they will be protected from COVID-19 if they have to evacuate their homes. They also discussed how FEMA is innovating during the pandemic by working with partner organizations to enable COVID-safe sheltering, providing vaccination options at shelters and recovery centers, and protecting its workforce so they maintain mission readiness.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Eight New Nominees to Serve as U.S.&#160;Attorneys</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/president-biden-announces-eight-new-nominees-to-serve-as-u-s-attorneys/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 22:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is announcing eight new nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys across the country, officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law as the top federal law enforcement officials for their districts. These individuals were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the law, their professionalism, their experience and credentials in this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is announcing eight new nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys across the country, officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law as the top federal law enforcement officials for their districts.<br><br>These individuals were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the law, their professionalism, their experience and credentials in this field, their dedication to pursuing equal justice for all, and their commitment to the independence of the Department of Justice.<br><br>The President has launched a comprehensive effort to take on the uptick in gun crime that has been taking place for the last 18 months—putting more cops on the beat, supporting community prevention programs, and cracking down on illegal gun trafficking. Confirming U.S. Attorneys as the chief federal law enforcement officers in their district is important for these efforts.<br><br><strong>Jessica D. Aber, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Eastern District of Virginia</strong><br><br>Jessica D. Aber is an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Virginia, where she has served since 2009. Since 2016, Ms. Aber has been the Deputy Chief of the Criminal Division for the office. From 2015 to 2016, she served on a detail assignment as Counsel to the Assistant Attorney General for the Criminal Division of the United States Department of Justice. Prior to joining the Department of Justice, Ms. Aber was an associate at McGuireWoods LLP from 2007 to 2008. Ms. Aber served as a law clerk for then-Magistrate Judge Hannah Lauck on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia from 2006 to 2007.<br><br>Ms. Aber received her J.D. from William &amp; Mary Law School in 2006 and her B.A., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from the University of Richmond in 2003.<br><br><strong>Carla B. Freedman, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Northern District of New York</strong><br><br>Carla B. Freedman is an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Northern District of New York, where she has served since 2007. Since 2018, Ms. Freedman has served as the Narcotics Chief for the office. From 1988 to 2004, Ms. Freedman was an Assistant District Attorney in the New York County District Attorney’s Office in Manhattan, where she led a unit that focused on investigating organized crime from 1997 to 2004.<br><br>Ms. Freedman received her J.D. from New York Law School in 1988 and her B.A. from Syracuse University in 1985.<br><br><strong>William J. Ihlenfeld, II, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Northern District of West Virginia</strong><br><br>William J. Ihlenfeld is a special counsel at Bowles Rice LLP, where he is a member of the firm’s Litigation and Cybersecurity practice groups. Since he joined Bowles Rice in 2019, Mr. Ihlenfeld has also been a member of the West Virginia State Senate. Mr. Ihlenfeld was a partner at Bailey Glasser LLP from 2017 to 2019, and served as United States Attorney for the Northern District of West Virginia from 2010 to 2016. Prior to that, from 2007 to 2010, he was a state prosecutor in Brooke County, West Virginia. From 1997 to 2007, Mr. Ihlenfeld prosecuted domestic violence cases in Ohio County, West Virginia. Throughout his legal career, Mr. Ihlenfeld has advocated for victims of domestic and sexual violence through pro bono legal representation and service to local and statewide nonprofit organizations.<br><br>Mr. Ihlenfeld received his J.D. from the West Virginia University College of Law in 1997 and his B.S. from Ohio University, with honors, in 1994.<br><br><strong>Christopher R. Kavanaugh, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Western District of Virginia</strong><br><br>Christopher R. Kavanaugh is Senior Counsel to the Deputy Attorney General at the Department of Justice in Washington, D.C. He is currently on detail from the United States Attorney’s Office for the Western District of Virginia, where he has served as an Assistant United States Attorney since 2014. In his role as Assistant United States Attorney, Mr. Kavanaugh is the chief national security prosecutor, senior litigation counsel, and counsel to the United States Attorney for the Western District of Virginia. From 2007 to 2014, Mr. Kavanaugh was an Assistant United States Attorney for the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia. Since 2011, Mr. Kavanaugh has been an adjunct professor at the University of Virginia School of Law, where he teaches federal criminal practice and trial advocacy. Mr. Kavanaugh served as a law clerk for Judge James C. Cacheris on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia from 2006 to 2007.<br><br>Mr. Kavanaugh received his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 2006 and his B.S. in engineering, <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Georgia Tech in 2002.<br><br><strong>Darcie N. McElwee, U.S. Attorney nominee for the District of Maine</strong><br><br>Darcie N. McElwee is an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Maine, where she has served since 2002. She has served as the Project Safe Neighborhoods Coordinator for the office since 2005. Between 2005 and 2008, Ms. McElwee was an adjunct professor of advanced trial advocacy at the University of Maine School of Law.  Ms. McElwee began her legal career as an Assistant District Attorney for the Penobscot and Piscataquis Counties in Maine from 1998 to 2002.<br><br>Ms. McElwee received her J.D. from the University of Maine School of Law in 1998 and her A.B. from Bowdoin College in 1995.<br><br><strong>Breon S. Peace, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Eastern District of New York</strong><br><br>Breon S. Peace has been a partner at Cleary Gottlieb Steen &amp; Hamilton LLP in New York since 2007, and previously worked as an associate at the firm from 1996 to 1997, 1998 to 1999, and from 2003 to 2007. He was an Acting Assistant Professor of Clinical Law at New York University School of Law from 2002 to 2003. Mr. Peace previously served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of New York from 2000 to 2002. Pearce served as a law clerk for Judge Sterling Johnson, Jr. on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of New York from 1997 to 1998.<br><br>Mr. Peace received his J.D. from New York University School of Law in 1996 and his B.A. from the University of California, Berkeley in 1993.<br><br><strong>William S. Thompson, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Southern District of West Virginia</strong><br><br>Judge William S. Thompson is a judge for the 25th Judicial Circuit of West Virginia. He was appointed to that position in 2007 and re-elected in 2008 and 2016. As a part of his duties, Judge Thompson presides over several treatment courts, including the first family treatment court in West Virginia. Prior to his appointment, he was an associate at the law firm of Cook and Cook in Madison, West Virginia from 1995 to 2007. His primary focus was litigation, which included representing several hundred indigent clients in criminal defense and other matters. Judge Thompson also served as President of Madison Healthcare, Incorporated from 1997 to 2007, and as Vice President of Danville Lumber Company from 1994 to 2007.<br><br>Judge Thompson received his J.D. from West Virginia University in 1995 and his B.S. from West Virginia University in 1992.<br><br><strong>Damian Williams, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Southern District of New York</strong><br><br>Damian Williams is an Assistant United States Attorney for the United States Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of New York, where he has served since 2012. He has served as a Chief of the Securities and Commodities Fraud Task Force for the office since 2018. From 2009 to 2012, he was a litigation associate at Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton &amp; Garrison LLP. Mr. Williams served as a law clerk for Justice John Paul Stevens on the United States Supreme Court from 2008 to 2009 and Judge Merrick B. Garland on the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit from 2007 to 2008.<br><br>Mr. Williams received a J.D. from Yale Law School in 2007, a M.Phil. in International Relations from the University of Cambridge in 2003, and an A.B. in Economics from Harvard University in 2002.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Senate Passage of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/10/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-senate-passage-of-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-investment-and-jobs-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 3:10 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, thank you, Madam Vice President. First of all, I want to thank the group of senators &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; for doing what they told me they would do.&#160; The death of this legislation was mildly premature, as reported.&#160; They said they were willing to work&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>3:10 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Madam Vice President.<br><br>First of all, I want to thank the group of senators &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; for doing what they told me they would do.&nbsp; The death of this legislation was mildly premature, as reported.&nbsp; They said they were willing to work in a bipartisan manner, and I want to thank them for keeping their word.&nbsp; That’s just what they did.&nbsp;<br><br>After years and years and years of “Infrastructure Week,” we’re on the cusp of an infrastructure decade that I truly believe will transform America.<br><br>As you all know, just a short while ago the United States Senate passed the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act &#8212; the very legislation I ran on when I announced my candidacy for the nomination for President &#8212; a historic investment in the nation’s roads and highways, bridges and transit; in our drinking water systems; in broadband, clean energy, environmental clean-up; and making infrastructure more resilient and the climate crisis much more in our minds as to how do we deal with it.<br><br>You know, we&#8217;re poised once again &#8212; and I mean this in a literal sense &#8212; to make the same kind of historic investments that have so often made possible &#8212; made it possible for America to build the future and allow us to outcompete the rest of the world.<br><br>From building the Erie Canal in the early 1800s &#8212; a bipartisan effort; to the Transcontinental Railroad, to construction &#8212; that was constructed during the Civil War; to Dwight Eisenhower’s Interstate Highway System in the 1950s &#8212; the investments that literally connected our entire nation and fundamentally changed the pattern of life in America. &nbsp;<br><br>To the public investments that took us to the Moon, and the discovery of lifesaving medicines and vaccines, and gave us the Internet &#8212; America has often had the greatest prosperity and made the most progress when we invest in America itself.<br><br>And that’s what this infrastructure bill does with overwhelming support from the United States Senate &#8212; 69 votes in the Senate &#8212; a vote margin bigger than when the Interstate Highway System passed in the Senate in 1956.<br><br>It makes key investments that will, one, create millions of good union jobs all across the country in cities, small towns, rural and Tribal communities.<br><br>America &#8212; America, this is how we truly Build Back Better.&nbsp;<br><br>This bill is going to put people to work modernizing our roads and our highways and our bridges so commuters and truckers don’t lose time in traffic, saving billions of dollars nationally.<br><br>Today, up to 10 million homes in America and more than 400,000 schools and schools &#8212; and childcare centers have pipes with lead in them, including for drinking water.&nbsp; This is a clear and present danger to the health of America, particularly to our children’s health.&nbsp;<br><br>This bill is going to put plumbers and pipefitters to work replacing all of the nation’s lead pipes so every child, every American can turn on a faucet at home or in school and know they&#8217;re drinking clean water.<br><br>During remote learning in the &#8212; during the pandemic last year, we saw too many families forced to sit &#8212; literally sit &#8212; in their vehicles in a fast food parking lot so their children could get on the Internet they couldn’t afford and didn’t have access to at home.&nbsp; This bill will deliver affordable, high-speed Internet to every American &#8212; a necessity for the 21st century.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ll also see in the last &#8212; we’ve seen in the last couple of years the damage done in Texas and other places when transmission lines carrying power were taken down by extreme and unanticipated weather, leaving millions of folks without electricity for weeks and weeks, and costing our economy billions and billions of dollars.&nbsp; This bill provides upgrades to our power grid so that more secure and resilient and cleaner energy can be transferred across those wires.<br><br>Down in New Orleans, I met with the incredible women and men who are in charge of the water system, some of it running on technology that is literally 100 years old.&nbsp; This bill is going to provide opportunities to upgrade their system.&nbsp;<br><br>It also allows American workers to strengthen our national &#8212; our natural infrastructure, like our levees.&nbsp; These are at risk of catastrophic collapse in the face of extreme weather like superstorms, wildfires, droughts, hurricanes, and heat waves.<br><br>Last week, I stood &#8212; and many of you were with me &#8212; on the South Lawn of the White House with the United Auto Workers and the leaders from the Big Three automobile companies in America, surrounded by iconic American vehicles that will all be electric and made right here in America in the not-too-distant future.<br><br>This bill is also going to put IBEW workers &#8212; electrical workers &#8212; to work installing a truly national network of electric vehicle charging stations that will transform the way we travel and move commerce.&nbsp;<br><br>And, by the way, around those charging stations, you&#8217;ll see &#8212; just like around &#8212; we put in gas stations in our state highways &#8212; you&#8217;ll see other industries build up.&nbsp; We have the benefit of significantly reducing pollution from vehicles on our roads.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, this bill, I believe, will make the most important investment in public transit in American history.<br><br>When I went to Philadelphia not too long ago for Amtrak’s 50th anniversary, I was proud to be able to say that this bill was in the works and that it would be the most important investment in rail since the creation of Amtrak itself.&nbsp; This bill will upgrade railroad tracks so people can get to work and their destinations faster, and it will build new lines to get people to more places faster &#8212; reducing, I might add, pollution, as well.<br><br>And here’s another critical part of the bill: 90 percent of the jobs created don’t require a college degree.&nbsp; You&#8217;re tired of hearing me saying it, I know, but this is a blue-collar blueprint to rebuild America.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re going to do all of this by keeping my commitment.&nbsp; We will not raise taxes by one cent on people making less than $400,000 a year.<br><br>Everyone from union to business leaders to economists &#8211;left, right, and center &#8212; believe the public investments contained in this bill will generate more jobs, higher productivity, higher growth for our economy over the long term.<br><br>Forecasters on Wall Street project that over the next 10 years our economy will expand by trillions of dollars, and it will create an additional 2 million jobs a year beyond what was already projected &#8212; good-paying jobs all around the country.&nbsp;<br><br>Experts believe that the majority of the bill’s benefits will flow to working families: faster commutes, cleaner water, less expense, available and affordable Internet &#8212; these are the things that working families needs &#8212; that they need.<br><br>As last week’s jobs report shows, our economy is recovering at a record rate &#8212; 934,000 new jobs created in July.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to go up and down, but 4 million jobs created since I took office.<br><br>This bill is going to help make a historic recovery a long-term boom.<br><br>Folks, above all, this historic investment in infrastructure is what I believe you, the American people, want &#8212; what you’ve been asking for for a long, long time. &nbsp;This bill shows that we can work together.<br><br>I know a lot of people &#8212; some sitting in the audience here &#8212; didn’t think this could happen.&nbsp; This bill was declared dead more often than &#8212; anyway.&nbsp; That bipartisanship was a thing of the past.&nbsp; From the time I announced my candidacy (inaudible) bringing the country together and doing things in a bipartisan way, it was characterized as a relic of an &#8212; an earlier age.&nbsp;<br><br>As you may well remember, I never believed that.&nbsp; I still don’t.<br><br>So, I want to thank those senators who worked so hard to bring this agreement together.&nbsp; I know it wasn’t easy.<br><br>For the Republicans who supported this bill, you showed a lot of courage.&nbsp; And I want to personally thank you for that, and I’ve called most of you on the phone to do just that.<br><br>You have &#8212; and no doubt, you will –- disagree with me on many issues.&nbsp; But where we can agree, we should.&nbsp; And here, on this bill, we proved that we can still come together to do big things, important things for the American people.<br><br>For the Democrats who supported this bill, we can be proud of these unprecedented investments that are going to transform this nation and change millions of lives for the better.<br><br>Think about what’s going to happen, in a practical sense.&nbsp; Clogged arteries at the heart of our economy &#8212; they’re going to be opened up.&nbsp; That will reduce transportation costs, reduce commuting costs, and, as a result, reduce costs overall for families and businesses.<br><br>And there’s safety provisions being &#8212; as I said not long ago, everyone can tell you what the most dangerous intersections in their communities are.&nbsp; There’s money in there to deal with those pac- &#8212; those specific needs.&nbsp;&nbsp; Thousands of bridges will be safer and more accessible.<br><br>And, by the way, as you’ve heard me say before, some bridges are so weak that they couldn’t have a firetruck go across it &#8212; requiring the fire department to go 10, 12 miles out of the way to get just, literally, a mile away to put out a fire.<br><br>Millions of lead pipes carrying drinking water to our homes and schools and daycare centers &#8212; they’re finally going to rep- &#8212; be replaced.&nbsp; Never again can we allow what happened in Flint, Michigan; and Jackson, Mississippi.&nbsp; Can never let it happen again.<br><br>High-speed Internet &#8212; going to be available and affordable everywhere, to everyone, so farmers nationwide can get the brest [sic] prices for their products at home and abroad by knowing when to sell, and children in Chicago or Philadelphia never have to again sit in a McDonald&#8217;s parking lot to do their homework.<br><br>This is transformational.&nbsp; I know compromise is hard for both sides, but it’s important &#8212; it’s important, it’s necessary &#8212; for a democracy to be able to function.<br><br>So, I want to thank everyone on both sides of the aisle for supporting this bill.&nbsp; Today, we proved that democracy can still work.&nbsp; A lot more work to do.<br><br>But I want to thank the Republican &#8212; Senate Republican Leader Mitch McConnell for supporting this bill.<br><br>And I want to give special thanks to Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer.&nbsp; Your leadership, Chuck, in the Senate was masterful.<br><br>But, look, let’s be clear: The work is far from done.&nbsp; The bill now has to go the House of Representatives, where I look forward to winning its approval.&nbsp;<br><br>And we have to get to work on the next critical piece of my agenda &#8212; my Build Back Better plan &#8212; making housing more affordable &#8212; it’s so unaffordable to so many Americans; providing clean energy tax cuts, including homeowners to make energy efficiency improvements in their homes; bringing down the cost of prescription drugs; making eldercare more affordable; and continuing to give middle-class families with children a tax break &#8212; a tax cut &#8212; the one they’re receiving now &#8212; well-deserved childcare and healthcare that gives them just a little bit of breathing room.<br><br>This is a plan that invests in the American people &#8212; in their future and their success.&nbsp; And it will be paid for by having the largest corporations &#8212; including 55 of them who didn’t pay a single penny in federal income tax &#8212; and the super-wealthy to begin to pay their fair share.&nbsp;<br><br>I want you to be able to be millionaires and corporations to do incredibly well, but this isn’t going to change anything for you.&nbsp; You’ll still have your three homes.&nbsp; You’ll still have whatever you need.&nbsp; And corporations will continue to do well.<br><br>I’ll have more to say about this later as the Senate continues its work.&nbsp; But today, I’m happy to mark this significant milestone on the road toward making what we all know are long-overdue, much-needed investments in basic, hard infrastructure of this nation.<br><br>I truly believe that this bill proves the voice of the people will be heard and that we can all come together to make a difference in people’s lives.&nbsp; As you heard me say it before and I apologize for repeating it, but there are no Republican bridges or Democratic roads.<br><br>This is a moment that lives beyond the headlines, beyond partisan soundbites, beyond the culture of instant outrage,<br>disinformation, and conflict-as-entertainment.<br><br>This is about us doing the real, hard work of governing.&nbsp; This is about democracy delivering for the people.&nbsp; This is about winning the future.&nbsp; It’s about doing our job.&nbsp; This is about building an economy from the bottom up and the middle out, giving everyone a decent chance at a decent life.<br><br>And by the way, when the bottom and middle do well, the wealthy do very, very well.&nbsp; Nobody, nobody, nobody gets hurt.&nbsp;<br>This is what I call governing and government doing its job &#8212; ensuring everybody is better off.<br><br>As I’ve said many times and I’ll say it again today: We are the United States of America.&nbsp; And there is nothing &#8212; nothing –- we can’t do if we do it together.<br><br>So, thank you.&nbsp; God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.<br><br>Darlene at AP.&nbsp; Darlene, AP.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, thank you.&nbsp; What is your reaction to Governor Cuomo&#8217;s &#8212; his announcement that he is stepping down?&nbsp; You called on him to resign.&nbsp; Did you think he would?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I respect the governor&#8217;s decision and &#8212; I respect the decision he made.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how concerned are you right now about children in schools, given that 94 percent of children, many of them unable to get vaccinated because they&#8217;re too young, have now tested positive?&nbsp; What are your concerns, and how concerned are you that schools will not be able to stay open as you&#8217;ve asked for?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; My concerns are deep and I&#8217;m very concerned, and we all know why.<br><br>Look, I understand that there are millions of people who decided &#8212; adults &#8212; who decided not to get vaccinated.&nbsp; And I understand that to badger those folks is not likely to get them to move and get vaccinated.&nbsp; But I also understand that the reason children are becoming infected is because, in most cases, they live in low-vaccination-rate states and communities, and they&#8217;re getting it from unvaccinated adults.&nbsp; That is what is happening.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, my plea is that for those who are not vaccinated: Think about it.&nbsp; God willing, the FDA is going to be coming out in a reasonable timeframe to say this vaccine is totally safe.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen millions of doses around the world &#8212; a billion doses already &#8212; and we know how it&#8217;s transmitted.&nbsp;<br><br>And one of the things that I find a little disingenuous: When I suggest that people in zones where there is a high risk wear the masks like you all are doing, I&#8217;m told that government should get out of the way and not do that; they don’t have the authority to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>And I find it interesting that some of the very people who are saying that, who hold government positions, are people who are threatening that if a schoolteacher asks a student if they&#8217;ve been vaccinated, or if a principal says that, &#8220;Everyone in my school should wear a mask,&#8221; or the schoolboard votes for it, that governor will nullify that. &nbsp;That governor has the authority to say, &#8220;You can&#8217;t do that.&#8221; &nbsp;I find that totally counterintuitive and, quite frankly, disingenuous.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have presidential powers to intervene in states like Texas and Florida where they are banning mask mandates?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe that I do thus far.&nbsp; We&#8217;re checking that.&nbsp; We &#8212; but there are on &#8212; federal workforce, I can.<br><br>And I think that people should understand, seeing little kids &#8212; I mean, four, five, six years old &#8212; in hospitals, on ventilators, and some of them passing &#8212; not many, but some of them passing &#8212; it&#8217;s almost, I mean, it&#8217;s just &#8212; well, I should not characterize beyond that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Andrew Cuomo, his resignation: What impact &#8212; as the head of the Party, what impact does his resignation have on the Democratic Party?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think the impact is all on Andrew Cuomo and his decision to make that judgement, and I respect his decision.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, on Afghanistan: In just the last few days, multiple cities in Afghanistan have fallen to the Taliban. There&#8217;s irrefutable evidence that a vast majority of those Afghan forces cannot hold ground there.&nbsp; Has your current plan to withdraw U.S. troops changed at all?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; Look, we spent over a trillion dollars over 20 years.&nbsp; We trained and equipped with modern equipment over 300,000 Afghan forces.&nbsp; And Afghan leaders have to come together.&nbsp; We lost thousands &#8212; lost to death and injury &#8212; thousands of American personnel.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve got to fight for themselves, fight for their nation.<br><br>The United States &#8212; I&#8217;ll insist we continue to keep the commitments we made of providing close air support, making sure that their air force functions and is operable, re- &#8212; resupplying their forces with food and equipment, and paying all their salaries.&nbsp; But they&#8217;ve got to want to fight.&nbsp; They have outnumbered the Taliban.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;m getting daily briefings.&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s still a possibility &#8212; you have a significant new Secretary of Defense &#8212; our equivalent of a Secretary of Defense in Afghanistan, Bismillah Khan, who is a serious fighter.&nbsp;<br><br>I think they&#8217;re beginning to realize they&#8217;ve got to come together politically at the top and &#8212; but we&#8217;re going to continue to keep our commitment.&nbsp; But I do not regret my decision.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; To this side.&nbsp; Yes, ma&#8217;am.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, on the issue of the infrastructure bill and the work that you have ahead of you now, are you concerned that you &#8212; are you confident that you have the support of all the Democrats on board to get this $3.5 trillion package through?&nbsp; I keep asking you that.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know you do.&nbsp; As my mother would say, &#8220;God love you, dear.&#8221;<br><br>Look, I have, as I said &#8212; and I&#8217;m not referring to you, in particular, just overall.&nbsp; I was going over some of the quotes from the moment that I got elected how my plan was &#8220;dead.&#8221;&nbsp; This is the exact same plan I ran on.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ll see.&nbsp; I continue to be an optimist.&nbsp; As I told you, I was once referred to by a doctor as a &#8220;congenital optimist.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>I think that we can get a significant portion of the &#8212; if not all &#8212; of the reconciliation bill, the budget &#8212; they&#8217;re doing &#8212; they&#8217;re having the vote-a-thon now.<br><br>I think, over the next month, which is the way it&#8217;s going to work, they vote on all of these amendments, and then they get to the business of seeing how they can make it work, and then come back &#8212; I know you understand this well, but the public wonders what we&#8217;re talking about sometimes &#8212; and decide exactly what&#8217;s in that reconciliation bill and how much is going to be spent.<br><br>I think we will get enough Democrats to vote for it, and I think that the House will eventually put two bills on my desk: one on infrastructure, and one on reconciliation.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212; thank you so much, Mr. President.&nbsp; Just sort of turning to the Delta &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just turning to the Delta variant for a moment, I wanted to see if, in retrospect, you think your administration put enough mitigation measures in place early enough, and whether or not you should&#8217;ve, perhaps, heeded some of the lessons from other countries that had data as early as May and June about how the variant spread?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, we knew how the variant spread, and we know the vaccines prevent the spread.&nbsp; So &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; it&#8217;s like &#8212; you know, a lot of countries didn’t have the vaccines we were able to put together to make sure every single American &#8212; we have over 300 million dos- &#8212; 600 million doses of vaccine for Americans.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve exported over a half a billion &#8212; we will over a half a billion.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we knew &#8212; what is disappointing is that more people were not willing to take the vaccine.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve done everything in our power &#8212; well, I shouldn&#8217;t say &#8212; there&#8217;s probably more &#8212; we will do more.&nbsp; But we continue to try to make the case to the American people who haven&#8217;t taken the vaccine that it&#8217;s in your interest, can save your life, and can fundamentally impact on the lives of your children or people you love.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, one of the things that&#8217;s happening, as bad as things have gotten, the death rate is one fiftieth &#8212; or, I don&#8217;t &#8212; don&#8217;t hold me to the number, but significantly, significantly lower than when the &#8212; when I inherited this job &#8212; inherited the job &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; when I inherited the &#8212; the coronavirus pandemic when I first got elected.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the thing that I &#8212; I continue to hope that people will overcome their fears because their fears are based on &#8212; some are just as a political statement, but very few.&nbsp; I think most people are worried.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why I&#8217;m hoping that the FDA will say that we permanently approve of these vaccines, because we have enough for everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;m hoping that, as people realize &#8212; and it is picking up.&nbsp; Vaccines are picking up, but not at the rate they were before.&nbsp;<br><br>Remember, I was setting up, you know, stadiums &#8212; sports stadiums, and we were doing thousands of vaccines a day.&nbsp; And I wish I could have thought of something beyond what we&#8217;ve thought of that would make everybody want to get the vaccine, but that hadn&#8217;t been the case.<br><br>Now, at a federal level, what I&#8217;m going to be doing is more &#8212; is making sure that they understand that I do have authority to say, &#8220;If you&#8217;re going to come into this building &#8212; into a federal building that you have to have been vaccinated or show that, or be wearing a mask.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>And I think that I&#8217;m going to use &#8212; and I anticipate that it&#8217;s probable that the Defense Department will &#8212; as they put in place all the mechanisms needed to be able to, in fact, impose or initiate a mandate for all the regular forces and reserves to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>But I continue to be hopeful.&nbsp; You see, I had a long talk &#8212; not a long &#8212; I had a talk with Governor Asa Hutchin- &#8212; Asa Hutchinson, who said he made a mistake.&nbsp; And he is working really hard, going around.&nbsp; And he told me that he&#8217;s doing a lot of town meetings &#8212; not all of which are being embraced, but he&#8217;s making the case.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to make the case.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I may, ironically, one of the &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, I do have a question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; one of the Democrats, through the years, that you spoke with about infrastructure the most was Andrew Cuomo, who is resigning &#8212; who announced he&#8217;s resigning today.&nbsp; You had traveled New York with him when you were Vice President to the launch of the reconstruction on LaGuardia.&nbsp; He was someone who supported your campaign early on.&nbsp;<br><br>I know you called on him to resign.&nbsp; I know you condemned the alleged behavior.&nbsp; But you&#8217;re someone who spends a lot of time with mayors and governors.&nbsp; How would you assess his 10 and a half years as governor of the state?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; In terms of his personal behavior, or what he&#8217;s done as a governor?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What he&#8217;s done as a governor.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s done a hell of job.&nbsp; I thought he&#8217;s done a hell of a job.&nbsp; And, I mean, both on &#8212; everything from access to voting, to infrastructure, to a whole range of things.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so sad.<br><br>Okay.&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Right here.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Mr. President, I have a question about the significance of the bipartisan nature of the infrastructure agreement.&nbsp; Are there lessons learned from that agreement that can be applied to voting reform, police reform, or LGBTQ civil rights?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; By you guys or by me?&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By anyone.&nbsp; By &#8212; and &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I shouldn&#8217;t kid, because I was just reading about 50 statements from very serious press people about how I &#8212; my whole plan was &#8220;dead&#8221; from the beginning.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, the lesson learned is being willing to talk and listen.&nbsp; Listen.&nbsp; Call people in.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no, let me finish it.&nbsp; And I think the lesson learned is exposing people to other views.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s why, from the beginning, on all the subjects you raised, I&#8217;ve sat with people and listened to their positions, some in agreement with where I am and some disagreement.&nbsp; And so, I think it&#8217;s a matter of listening.&nbsp; It&#8217;s part of democracy.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all so very much.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why have you not named an FDA commissioner, sir, to this point?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, should Andrew Cuomo resign immediately?&nbsp; He&#8217;s leaving in 14 days.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to comment anymore on Andrew Cuomo.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the FDA, you haven&#8217;t &#8212; you haven&#8217;t named an FDA commissioner.&nbsp; Why have you not yet named an FDA commissioner, sir?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Say again.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You haven&#8217;t named an FDA commissioner yet.&nbsp; I was wondering why you haven&#8217;t found or named a permanent FDA commissioner yet.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We&#8217;re working on that very hard to make sure we can get it passed.<br><br>Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a question for you on infrastructure, but &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would you like to see &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; can I quickly follow up on your &#8212; your comment on Governor Cuomo?&nbsp; Can you really say that he has done a, quote, &#8220;hell of a job&#8221; if he&#8217;s accused of sexually harassing women &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Now, look, you asked two different questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the job?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I asked the substantive &#8220;Should he remain as governor&#8221; as one question.&nbsp;<br><br>And women should be believed when they make accusations that are able to &#8212; on the face of them, makes sense &#8212; and investigated &#8212; they&#8217;re investigated and the judgement was made and what they said was correct.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one thing.<br><br>The question is, &#8220;Did he do a good job on infrastructure?&#8221;&nbsp; That was the question.&nbsp; He did.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, the question was, &#8220;How did he do as a governor?&#8221;&nbsp; He was accused of &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, the question was &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; sexually harassing women.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Correct me if I&#8217;m wrong.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About &#8212; about how was he as a governor, generally &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, as a governor, generally, obviously &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; outside of his personal behavior.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Outside of his personal behavior.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But can you separate the two since he was (inaudible) &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m not.&nbsp; I was asked a specific question.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, how &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m trying to answer it specifically.&nbsp; What do you want to ask me, specifically?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;d like to ask you about infrastructure as well.&nbsp; Given that you have said this is such an urgent bill that needs to be passed, why not have the House take it up immediately for a vote?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; We&#8217;ll get it done.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll get both.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>3:40 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
