<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 20:19:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-76/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 20:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Shailen P. Bhatt, of Michigan, to be Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, vice Nicole R. Nason. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Jeffrey Matthew Marootian, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy), vice Daniel Simmons. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Stephen A. Owens, of Arizona, to be Chairperson of the Chemical Safety&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Shailen P. Bhatt, of Michigan, to be Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, vice Nicole R. Nason.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jeffrey Matthew Marootian, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy), vice Daniel Simmons.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Stephen A. Owens, of Arizona, to be Chairperson of the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board for a term of five years, vice Katherine Andrea Lemos, resigning.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 19:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&#160; Shailen P. Bhatt, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, U.S. Department of Transportation Jeff Marootian, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, U.S. Department of Energy Stephen A.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Shailen P. Bhatt, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, U.S. Department of Transportation</li><li>Jeff Marootian, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, U.S. Department of Energy</li><li>Stephen A. Owens, Nominee for Chairman of the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board</li></ul>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Shailen P. Bhatt, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, U.S. Department of Transportation</strong><br></span><br>Shailen Bhatt is Senior Vice President of Global Transportation Innovation and Alternative Delivery at AECOM, a multinational infrastructure consulting firm. Bhatt previously served as the Executive Director of the Colorado Department of Transportation, Cabinet Secretary of the Delaware Department of Transportation, and as a presidential appointee at the U.S. Department of Transportation. In these roles, Bhatt spearheaded innovative solutions, collaborations, and partnerships to support the delivery of safe, sustainable, and cost-effective transportation systems for the 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century.&nbsp;He previously worked as the CEO of the Intelligent Transportation Society of America,&nbsp;Chair of the Board of Directors for the National Operations Center of Excellence (NOCoE), Chair of&nbsp;the Executive Committee of the I-95 Corridor Coalition, and was&nbsp;a member of the World Economic Forum’s Global Agenda Council on the Future of Automotive and Personal Transport.<br><br>Bhatt chairs an external advisory board for the United States Department&nbsp;of Energy, is a member of the Aurora Safety Advisory Board for autonomous driving,&nbsp;and is the Chair of the ITS World Congress Board of Directors.&nbsp;Bhatt is a proud husband and father to two daughters. He graduated summa cum laude from Western Kentucky University with a degree in Economics.&nbsp;<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Jeff Marootian, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, U.S. Department of Energy</strong><br></span><br>Jeff Marootian currently serves as a Special Assistant to the President in the White House Office of Presidential Personnel. Prior to his service in the Biden-Harris Administration, he was a member of the Biden-Harris Transition Team. Marootian previously served in Washington D.C government as the Director of the District Department of Transportation, where he piloted sustainable transportation technologies, oversaw the effort to electrify the city’s Circulator bus fleet, and led the city’s early adoption of the Transportation and Climate Initiative. Marootian oversaw the modernization of hundreds of miles of roads and sidewalks and advanced critical infrastructure projects, such as the reconstruction of the Frederick Douglass Memorial Bridge and expansion of dedicated bus and bike lanes.<br><br>Marootian previously served in the Obama-Biden Administration as the Assistant Secretary for Administration and Chief Sustainability Officer at the U.S. Department of Transportation. He is an alumnus of The George Washington University where he has also taught as an adjunct faculty member in the Trachtenberg School of Public Policy and Administration.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Stephen A. Owens, Nominee for Chairman of the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board</strong><br></span><br>Steve Owens is a member of the U.S. Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board (CSB), appointed by President Biden and confirmed by the U.S. Senate in December 2021. Since being sworn in, Owens has worked to increase transparency and information-sharing by the CSB, identify ways to reduce the backlog in the CSB’s investigative reports, and increase collaboration and communications between agency leadership and CSB career professional staff and stakeholders.&nbsp;Prior to joining the CSB, he was an attorney in Phoenix, Arizona, focusing on environmental, safety, and health issues, and also advising clients on a range of matters relating to chemical safety and safe chemical practices.&nbsp;Owens previously served as the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency’s (EPA) Assistant Administrator for the Office of Chemical Safety and Pollution Prevention, where he was responsible for overseeing EPA’s chemical regulatory programs. He also previously served as Counsel to the Subcommittee on Investigations and Oversight of the U.S. House Committee on Science and Technology, and Chief Counsel and later State Director for then-U.S. Senator Al Gore (D-TN).<br><br>Before serving at EPA, Owens was Director of the Arizona Department of Environmental Quality (ADEQ).&nbsp;As ADEQ Director, Owens oversaw the department’s policies and regulations relating to chemical safety and hazardous substances, including responding to chemical hazards and other emergency situations.&nbsp;He graduated with honors from Brown University and received his law degree in from Vanderbilt Law School, where he was Editor-in-Chief of the Vanderbilt Law Review.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Launches Effort to Create More Affordable and Equitable Outdoor Recreation&#160;Opportunities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-effort-to-create-more-affordable-and-equitable-outdoor-recreation-opportunities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 15:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of the President’s America the Beautiful Initiative, the Biden-Harris Administration today launched an interagency effort, called the Federal Interagency Council on Outdoor Recreation (FICOR), that will work to create more safe, affordable, and equitable opportunities for Americans to get outdoors. The FICOR – which includes leaders from the Departments of the Interior, Agriculture,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As part of the President’s America the Beautiful Initiative, the Biden-Harris Administration today launched an interagency effort, called the Federal Interagency Council on Outdoor Recreation (FICOR), that will work to create more safe, affordable, and equitable opportunities for Americans to get outdoors.</p>



<p>The FICOR – which includes leaders from the Departments of the Interior, Agriculture, Commerce, and Defense – will focus on improving access to nature, expanding outdoor recreation opportunities, and providing the public with improved and more affordable experiences on America’s public lands and waters.</p>



<p>Increasing access to outdoor recreation is one of the six areas of focus outlined in President Biden’s America the Beautiful Initiative. The FICOR will help coordinate policies, facilitate partnerships, and improve implementation on issues such as: &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Investing in resilient recreation infrastructure, such as electric vehicle charging stations, trails, campgrounds, visitor centers, docks, and boating access;</li><li>Bolstering education and career opportunities in conservation, outdoor recreation, habitat restoration, and resource management work, and &nbsp;providing comprehensive visitor information for the hunting, fishing, hiking, biking, birding, climbing, and boating communities;</li><li>Cooperating with State, Tribal, territorial, and local governments, including those in communities near Federal lands and waters; and</li><li>Improving equitable access to Federal lands and waters and creating a welcoming visitor experience in collaboration with private, public, Tribal, and nonprofit organizations.</li></ul>



<p>The launch of the FICOR renews and re-energizes a body that was originally created in 2011 but was suspended by the previous administration. Prior to being suspended, the FICOR successfully launched <a href="https://www.recreation.gov/">recreation.gov</a>, helped the <a href="https://www.bea.gov/news/2021/outdoor-recreation-satellite-account-us-and-states-2020">Bureau of Economic Analysis</a> begin tracking outdoor recreation as an economic sector, and worked to establish the <a href="https://www.everykidoutdoors.gov/pass.htm"><em>Every Kid </em><em>Outdoors</em><em> Pass</em></a>.</p>



<p>With outdoor recreation continuing to grow rapidly as an economic sector, including by contributing <a href="https://www.bea.gov/news/2021/outdoor-recreation-satellite-account-us-and-states-2020">1.8 percent of GDP and generating $374.3 billion</a> in economic output, and America&#8217;s parks and public lands experiencing record-level visitation, the Biden-Harris Administration is taking unprecedented steps to expand equitable access to the outdoors and to protect natural, cultural, and historic resources.</p>



<p>In addition to launching the FICOR, the Administration has:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Launched historic investments through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law in the restoration of Federal lands and waters, including by improving availability of and equitable access to outdoor recreation opportunities</strong>.<ul><li>Commerce Secretary Gina M. Raimondo announced funding opportunities from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration’s (NOAA) $2.96 billion in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funds to address the climate crisis and strengthen coastal resilience and infrastructure. Over the next five years, NOAA’s targeted investments in the areas of habitat restoration, coastal resilience, and climate data and services will advance ongoing Federal efforts toward building climate resilience. Projects focused on building “Climate Ready Coasts” will invest in natural infrastructure projects that power outdoor recreation along our coasts by restoring coastal habitats, removing marine debris, storing carbon, and creating jobs.</li></ul><ul><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2022/04/11/biden-harris-administration-launches-1-billion-america-the-beautiful-challenge-to-support-and-accelerate-locally-led-conservation-and-restoration-projects/">Established the America the Beautiful Challenge</a>, a $1 billion public-private competitive grant program which funds locally led, voluntary conservation and restoration activities, including the development of outdoor recreation access and workforce development. The <a href="https://www.nfwf.org/programs/america-beautiful-challenge">first round of grants</a> – totaling $85 million – will be released in November 2022.</li></ul><ul><li>The Interior Department announced more than $61 million in grant funding to communities in 26 cities to create new parks and trails, or substantial renovations to existing parks, through the <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-haaland-announces-61-million-increase-outdoor-access-urban-spaces">Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership</a> program. The program, established in 2014 and supported by the Land and Water Conservation Fund, enables urban communities to create new outdoor recreation spaces, reinvigorate existing parks, and form connections between people and the outdoors in economically underserved communities.</li></ul><ul><li>As the largest Federal provider of water-based outdoor recreation in America, the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers (USACE) is investing $120 million from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and the Disaster Relief Supplemental Appropriations Act of 2022 to improve recreation facilities across the nation. These investments will promote equitable access to outdoor recreation opportunities and support local communities. USACE recreation areas had 268 million visits in the last fiscal year, resulting in spending that supports approximately 217,000 jobs and generates nearly $14.5 billion for local economies.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Expanded hunting and sport fishing opportunities on National Wildlife Refuge System lands and waters.</strong><ul><li>The U.S. Department of the Interior <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-announces-largest-expansion-fishing-and-hunting-us-fish-and">expanded hunting and fishing access on 2.1 million acres of National Wildlife Refuge System</a> lands and waters in 2021, the largest expansion of outdoor recreation opportunities in recent history. The Department is continuing to explore opportunities to provide additional access to refuge system lands. Hunting, fishing, and other outdoor activities contributed more than $156 billion in economic activity in communities across the United States in 2016, according to the Service’s National Survey of Fishing, Hunting, and Wildlife-Associated Recreation, published every five years. More than 101 million Americans — 40 percent of the U.S. population age 16 and older — pursue wildlife-related recreation, including hunting and fishing.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Focused acquisitions and improvements of Federal lands and waters under the Great American Outdoors Act (GAOA) of 2020, which passed with overwhelming bipartisan support.</strong><ul><li>The U.S. Department of Agriculture <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/06/06/usda-announces-503-million-improve-outdoor-recreation-and">announced more than $503 million in funding</a> for National Forests and Grasslands. The funds will go to projects to address deferred maintenance and improve campgrounds, trails, and facilities on National Forests. Funds will also be spent on land acquisition to expand recreation opportunities for visitors and strengthen resource protection partnerships with State agencies and private organizations.</li></ul><ul><li>The Department of the Interior <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/department-interior-announces-279-million-support-public-parks-expand-outdoor">announced $279 million</a> to support Federal lands and waters and expand outdoor recreation access utilizing the Land and Water Conservation Fund (LWCF) to all 50 states, U.S. territories, and the District of Columbia for state-identified outdoor recreation and resource protection projects.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Expanded outdoor recreation opportunities by protecting areas for future generations.</strong><ul><li>In celebration of National Trails Day, Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-haaland-promotes-outdoor-recreation-designates-ten-new-national-recreation">announced the designation of nine new National Recreation Trails</a> in seven states, adding nearly 600 miles to the National Trails System.</li></ul><ul><li>Secretary Deb Haaland <a href="https://www.fws.gov/press-release/2022-07/secretary-haaland-announces-lost-trail-conservation-area-montana">announced the establishment of the Lost Trail Conservation Area</a> in Northwest Montana as the 568th and newest unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System, managed by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. This expansion – the first new unit in the Refuge System for the Biden-Harris Administration – is the culmination of a 20-year, locally-led effort to conserve important big game corridors and recreational areas in the region. The Service worked in partnership with the Trust for Public Land and the Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes (CSKT) to purchase the 38,052-acre conservation easement from its continuing owner, Southern Pine Plantations.</li></ul><ul><li>The Bureau of Land Management, the U.S Department of Agriculture&#8217;s Forest Service, and the five Tribes of the Bears Ears Commission <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/blm-forest-service-and-five-tribes-bears-ears-commission-commit-historic-co-management">formalized their partnership</a> for co-management of the Bears Ears National Monument. The Hopi Tribe, Navajo Nation, Ute Mountain Ute Tribe, Ute Indian Tribe of the Uintah and Ouray Reservation, and the Pueblo of Zuni will be joint managers of the National Monument and will receive resources from Federal agencies to participate in and take leadership on the management of their ancestral lands.</li></ul><ul><li>The USDA Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/06/23/usda-forest-service-announces-plans-open-comments-rainy-river">are considering</a> a 20-year withdrawal of 225,000 acres of U.S. Forest System lands in Minnesota to protect the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness – the most visited wilderness area in the country. The Rainy River watershed flows north toward the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness and Voyageurs National Park, landscapes renowned for high-quality fishing, wildlife viewing, and recreational opportunities due to the large number of interconnected lakes and pristine water quality. The proposed mineral withdrawal aims to prevent further negative environmental impacts from future mining operations. It also evaluates the impacts of future mining on important social, cultural, and economic values.</li></ul><ul><li>On World Oceans Day, NOAA Administrator Rick Spinrad announced NOAA’s initiation of the designation process for a new national marine sanctuary <a href="https://sanctuaries.noaa.gov/hudson-canyon/">to conserve Hudson Canyon</a> in the Atlantic Ocean. A sanctuary designation would help conserve the area’s rich marine wildlife and habitats, and promote scientific research, ocean education, and recreation opportunities such as whale watching, recreational fishing, and boating.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Created workforce development opportunities with the establishment of an Indian Youth Service Corps Program.</strong><ul><li>The Biden-Harris Administration announced the launch of the <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-haaland-launches-new-indian-youth-service-corps-program">Indian Youth Service Corps Program</a>, which will provide meaningful education, employment, and training opportunities to Indigenous youth through conservation projects on Federal and Indian lands – thereby putting young people on a path to good-paying jobs while helping to address the climate crisis.</li></ul></li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Transnational Criminal&#160;Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/21/message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-transnational-criminal-organizations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 15:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#160;emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&nbsp;emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date. &nbsp;In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations that was declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13581 of July&nbsp;24, 2011, under which additional steps were&nbsp;taken in Executive Order 13863 of March 15, 2019, is&nbsp;to&nbsp;continue in effect beyond July 24, 2022.</p>



<p>The activities of significant transnational criminal organizations have&nbsp;reached such scope and gravity that they threaten the stability of international political and economic systems. &nbsp;Such&nbsp;organizations are becoming increasingly sophisticated and dangerous to the United States; they are increasingly entrenched in the operations of foreign governments and the international financial system, thereby weakening democratic institutions, degrading the rule of law, and undermining economic markets. &nbsp;These organizations facilitate and aggravate violent civil conflicts and increasingly facilitate the activities of other dangerous persons.</p>



<p>Significant transnational criminal organizations continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States. &nbsp;Therefore, I&nbsp;have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency with respect to&nbsp;significant transnational criminal organizations declared in&nbsp;Executive Order 13581.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">    July 21, 2022 </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Transnational Criminal&#160;Organizations.</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-transnational-criminal-organizations-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 15:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 24, 2011, by Executive Order 13581, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by significant transnational criminal organizations. On March&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 24, 2011, by Executive Order 13581, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by significant transnational criminal organizations.</p>



<p>On March 15, 2019, by Executive Order 13863, the President took additional steps to deal with the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations in view of the evolution of these organizations as well as the increasing sophistication of their activities, which threaten international political and economic systems and pose a direct threat to the safety and welfare of the United States and its citizens, and given the ability of these organizations to derive revenue through widespread illegal conduct, including acts of violence and abuse that exhibit a wanton disregard for human life as well as many other crimes enriching and empowering these organizations.</p>



<p>Significant transnational criminal organizations continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.  For these reasons, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13581 on July 24, 2011, under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13863 on March 15, 2019, must continue in effect beyond July 24, 2022.  Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations declared in Executive Order 13581.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 21, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter from Dr. Kevin O&#8217;Connor: President&#160;Biden Screened &#8220;Positive&#8221; for&#160;SARS-CoV-2</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/letter-from-dr-kevin-oconnor-president-biden-screened-positive-for-sars-cov-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 14:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57981</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To view the letter from the Physician to the President, visit: https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Letter-7.21.pdf]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>To view the letter from the Physician to the President, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Letter-7.21.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Letter-7.21.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary Karine&#160;Jean-Pierre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 14:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning, President Biden tested positive for COVID-19.&#160; He is fully vaccinated and twice boosted and experiencing very mild symptoms.&#160; He has begun taking Paxlovid. Consistent with CDC guidelines, he will isolate at the White House and will continue to carry out all of his duties fully during that time.&#160; He has been in contact&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This morning, President Biden tested positive for COVID-19.&nbsp; He is fully vaccinated and twice boosted and experiencing very mild symptoms.&nbsp; He has begun taking Paxlovid. Consistent with CDC guidelines, he will isolate at the White House and will continue to carry out all of his duties fully during that time.&nbsp; He has been in contact with members of the White House staff by phone this morning, and will participate in his planned meetings at the White House this morning via phone and Zoom from the residence.&nbsp;<br><br>Consistent with White House protocol for positive COVID cases, which goes above and beyond CDC guidance, he will continue to work in isolation until he tests negative.&nbsp; Once he tests negative, he will return to in-person work.<br><br>Out of an abundance of transparency, the White House will provide a daily update on the President’s status as he continues to carry out the full duties of the office while in isolation.<br><br>Per standard protocol for any positive case at the White House, the White House Medical Unit will inform all close contacts of the President during the day today, including any Members of Congress and any members of the press who interacted with the President during yesterday’s travel.&nbsp; The President’s last previous test for COVID was Tuesday, when he had a negative test result.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on Senior Administration Official Travel to&#160;Colombia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-senior-administration-official-travel-to-colombia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Principal Deputy National Security Advisor Jon Finer will travel to Colombia July 21-22 for official meetings with President Ivan Duque, President-Elect Gustavo Petro, and Vice President-Elect Francia Marquez. He will be accompanied by National Security Advisor to the Vice President Phil Gordon, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian Nichols, and National Security&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Principal Deputy National Security Advisor Jon Finer will travel to Colombia July 21-22 for official meetings with President Ivan Duque, President-Elect Gustavo Petro, and Vice President-Elect Francia Marquez. He will be accompanied by National Security Advisor to the Vice President Phil Gordon, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian Nichols, and National Security Council Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere Juan Gonzalez. The delegation will engage in discussions on a range of issues including combatting climate change, support for peace implementation and rural development, working together to reduce violence and combat criminal groups, advancing equitable and sustainable economic growth for both our countries, and other regional and global issues.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Safer America&#160;Plan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/fact-sheet-president-bidens-safer-america-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden knows what works to make our communities safer: investing in community policing and crime prevention. We need to fund police who walk the beat, know the neighborhood, are accountable to those they are sworn to serve, and build community trust and safety. We need to invest in mental health and substance use treatment&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden knows what works to make our communities safer: investing in community policing and crime prevention. We need to fund police who walk the beat, know the neighborhood, are accountable to those they are sworn to serve, and build community trust and safety. We need to invest in mental health and substance use treatment services, crisis responders, and social workers to reduce the burden on police officers and prevent violent crime. We need to expand community violence interventions – led by trusted messengers breaking the cycle of violence and trauma. We need to enforce our commonsense gun laws, require background checks for all gun sales in order to keep firearms out of the hands of felons and domestic abusers, and ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines – weapons of war that have no place in our communities.<br><br>President Biden has taken action to make our communities safer during his first 18 months in office:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Funded the police and improved police accountability</strong>. Other politicians talk about funding the police, but President Biden and Congressional Democrats actually got it done by enacting the American Rescue Plan (ARP). <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/13/fact-sheet-president-biden-issues-call-for-state-and-local-leaders-to-dedicate-more-american-rescue-plan-funding-to-make-our-communities-safer-and-deploy-these-dollars-quickly/">Over $10 billion in ARP funds</a> have already been committed to policing and other public safety efforts – including at least $6.5 billion in State and Local funds committed in more than 300 communities across the country. Along with ongoing support from the Justice Department, ARP investments made 2021 among the largest single-year commitments of federal resources for state and local law enforcement and public safety on record. President Biden also signed a historic <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/25/executive-order-on-advancing-effective-accountable-policing-and-criminal-justice-practices-to-enhance-public-trust-and-public-safety/">executive order</a> to advance effective, accountable policing that will build public trust and strengthen public safety. Leading civil rights organizations and law enforcement organizations such as the International Association of Chiefs of Police and the Fraternal Order of Police support this order.<br></li><li><strong>Tackled gun violence</strong>. President Biden is implementing his comprehensive <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">strategy</a> to reduce gun crime. The Biden Administration has taken <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-21-executive-actions-to-reduce-gun-violence/">more executive action</a> to reduce gun violence than any other president at this point in their Administration, including by reining in the proliferation of ghost guns and cracking down on gun traffickers and rogue gun dealers. The President was the first president in nearly 30 years to bring together Members of Congress from both parties to take action on gun violence, signing the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act. The President also secured Senate confirmation of career prosecutor Steve Dettelbach to serve as Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, empowering this law enforcement agency with its first confirmed leader since 2015.<br></li><li><strong>Investing in community-led crime prevention and intervention.</strong> States and cities across the country have used ARP funding to invest in public safety strategies such as summer jobs for young adults and substance use and mental health services. Through the bipartisan budget deal and the Bipartisan Safer communities Act, the President has secured $300 million to expand community violence interventions. The Biden Administration has also made changes to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/07/fact-sheet-more-details-on-the-biden-harris-administrations-investments-in-community-violence-interventions/">26 different federal programs</a> to direct additional funding to evidence-based violence interventions. And, the Department of Labor is <a href="https://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/eta/eta20220307">investing in job programs</a> to help formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter their communities.</li></ul>



<p>The President believes we can and must do more to reduce crime and save lives. Today, President Biden is building on this progress with his Safer America Plan<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/budget_fy2023.pdf">. President Biden’s fiscal year 2023 budget</a> requests a fully paid-for new investment of approximately $35 billion to support law enforcement and crime prevention – in addition to the President’s $2 billion discretionary request for these same programs. The plan he is releasing today outlines, for the first time, how this $37 billion will be used to save lives and make communities safer.<br><br>Specifically, the Safer America Plan:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Funds the police and promotes effective prosecution of crimes affecting families today.</strong> The Safer America Plan will provide communities the resources they need to keep our streets safe, including by helping them hire and train 100,000 additional police officers for accountable community policing (nearly $13 billion over the next five years through the COPS Hiring Program) and setting aside dedicated funds for small law enforcement agencies. At the same time, this plan will invest nearly $3 billion to help communities clear court backlogs and solve murders so we can take shooters and other violent criminals off the streets, including by helping communities set up task forces to share intelligence to bring down the gun violence rate. The plan also aims to crack down on other serious crimes affecting families today. The plan will impose tougher penalties for fentanyl trafficking. To tackle organized retail theft, the plan calls on Congress to pass legislation to require online marketplaces, like Amazon, to verify third-party sellers’ information, and to impose liability on online marketplaces for the sale of stolen goods on their platforms.<br></li><li><strong>Invests in crime prevention and a fairer criminal justice system. </strong>The Safer America Plan will invest in services that address the causes of crime and reduce the burdens on police so they can focus on violent crime, including mental health and substance use disorder services; crisis responders, violence interrupters, and social workers; and expanding access to job training, education, housing, and other supportive services that prevent crime and advance equity. The Plan establishes a new $15 billion grant program called Accelerating Justice System Reform that cities and states can use over the next 10 years to advance strategies that will: (1) prevent violent crime and/or (2) ease the burden on police officers by identifying non-violent situations that may merit a public health response or other response. It also invests an additional $5 billion in evidence-based community violence intervention programs. The plan proposes to end the crack-powder disparity, making the fix retroactive. The plan will help formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter society, including by lifting nearly all restrictions on eligibility and access to vital federal benefits and programs that people need to get back on their feet after leaving incarceration.<br></li><li><strong>Takes additional commonsense steps on guns</strong> <strong>to keep dangerous firearms out of dangerous hands. </strong>The President has already proposed to increase funding for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) by 13% so ATF can hire new agents and investigators to help cities trace firearms and analyze ballistics from crime scenes. The President will also continue to call on Congress to take additional actions on guns, including requiring background checks for all gun sales, banning assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, closing the dating violence restraining order loophole, and banning the manufacture, sale, or possession of unserialized “ghost guns.”</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Vice President Harris Marks Important New Milestone in Administration’s Efforts to Cut Costs for American&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-highlights-milestone-of-1-million-new-participants-on-reducing-high-speed-internet-cost-for-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President announces that since GetInternet.gov launch in May, Administration has signed up 1 million new households to save hundreds of dollars a year on internet service Access to high-speed internet is no longer a luxury. Still, too many families go without high-speed internet because of the cost or have to cut back on other&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President announces that since GetInternet.gov launch in May, Administration has signed up 1 million new households to save hundreds of dollars a year on internet service</em></p>



<p>Access to high-speed internet is no longer a luxury. Still, too many families go without high-speed internet because of the cost or have to cut back on other essentials to make their monthly internet service payments.  That’s why President Biden and Vice President Harris worked with Democrats, Republicans, and Independents to include the Affordable Connectivity Program (ACP) in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which <a href="https://www.internetforall.gov/">provides $65 billion</a> to provide Internet for All — to ensure that every American has access to reliable and affordable high-speed internet.  <br><br>The ACP, administered by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), provides eligible households up to $30/month (or $75/month on Tribal lands) off internet bills, as well as a one-time $100 discount off a connected device. To further lower costs, in May, President Biden and Vice President Harris announced commitments from internet service providers across the country to offer high-speed plans that are fully covered by the ACP—meaning millions of working families can now get high-speed internet without paying a dime. They simultaneously launched <a href="https://getinternet.gov/">GetInternet.gov</a>—a one-stop shop to check eligibility and sign up.<br><br>Today in North Carolina, Vice President Harris is announcing that, <strong>thanks to the Administration’s “all of government” enrollment drive,1 million new households have signed up to save on home broadband through the ACP.</strong><br>The Administration’s efforts increased the rate of ACP enrollments by about 35%.<br><br>To build on this success, today the Vice President called on the nation’s governors to join the Administration’s enrollment drive, sending them letters describing key steps they can take to boost enrollment in their states. For example, today, the State of North Carolina committed to email 5 million households to let them know they can lower their internet bill by visiting GetInternet.gov to check eligibility and sign up.<br><br><br><strong><u>THE BIDEN-HARRIS ADMINISTRATION’S “ALL OF GOVERNMENT” ENROLLMENT DRIVE</u></strong><br><br><strong><em>Partnering with state and local governments</em></strong>: The Vice President’s call to action today builds on the Administration’s existing successful partnerships with state and local governments to spread the word. For example:</p>



<ul><li>Michigan texted about 1.3 million likely eligible Michiganders and gained 25,000 new ACP enrollees as a result.</li><li>Albemarle County, Virginia now includes a “P.S.” about GetInternet.gov in every client communication by county social service workers.</li><li>Massachusetts recently texted more than 1 million Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) and Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) beneficiaries about GetInternet.gov and saw their rate of enrollments double in the five days following the text.</li><li>The City of Mesa, Arizona reports that constituents who hear about ACP are extremely interested. Mesa’s texts to residents about GetInternet.gov have a 10% clickthrough rate, as compared to a usual 1-5% rate for other Mesa governmental outreach.</li><li>New York City sent backpack flyers about ACP home via 1,700 principals to reach about 1 million children who attend Free and Reduced-Price School Lunch Community-Eligible Schools, and it will advertise GetInternet.gov at bus stops in zip codes with a high number of households likely eligible for ACP.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Leveraging all of the federal government</em></strong>: In addition to working with state and local partners, the Administration is using every tool in its toolbox to get the word out—including communicating directly with households that are automatically eligible for ACP due to their participation in other federal government programs. For example:</p>



<ul><li>The Social Security Administration (SSA) emailed all 1.7 million Supplemental Security Income recipients who have a “my social security” account letting them know that they are eligible for ACP. SSA plans to send a second email to recipients this summer. The agency is also running PSAs on Social Security Television, broadcast in more than 1,200 local social security offices nationwide.</li><li>This summer, the Department of Education will email over 6 million Pell grant recipients who are eligible for ACP. It will also conduct a Back-To-School campaign with information about ACP.</li><li>The Department of Veterans Affairs sent information to its 12 million VetResources email subscribers and 120 Community Veteran Engagement Boards, as Veterans Pension and Survivors Benefit recipients are eligible for ACP. This summer the Veterans Benefits Administration will also directly mail all 380,000 Veterans and Survivors currently receiving pension benefits a notification letter and flyer.</li><li>The Department of Housing and Urban Development emailed over 3,000 Public Housing Authorities with information about the ACP to share with their over 3 million families who receive Federal Public Housing Assistance and are eligible, and is currently doing follow-up engagement.</li><li>The Department of the Interior’s Bureau of Trust Funds Administration reached out to over 400,000 beneficiaries with a direct mailing to let them know about ACP. The Department also trained over 200 call center and field staff who work at the Bureau of Trust Funds Administration to disseminate information and answer questions about eligibility and how to enroll in ACP.</li><li>Broadband infrastructure grant programs operated by the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Commerce are all requiring grant funding recipients to participate in the ACP, helping ensuring federal funds are used to deploy networks that are actually affordable.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Working with advocates and digital navigators</em></strong>: The Administration is also working with trusted community leaders to get the word out and enroll eligible households. For example:</p>



<ul><li>The FCC has registered over 40,000 individuals and organizations to be ACP outreach partners. To build on these efforts, the FCC is in the process of standing up a new grant program to empower partners to engage their communities and has reserved up to $100 million of Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding to conduct ACP outreach efforts, including consumer research, focus groups, paid media campaigns, and grants to outreach partners over the next five years.</li><li>The Administration partnered with civil rights groups to kick off a Week of Action in June, in which the Leadership Conference and partner civil rights organizations reached out to communities to encourage households to sign up for ACP.</li><li>Thanks to Administration outreach, United Way will share information about ACP in communications reaching at least 15,000 people per month.</li><li>The Administration also worked with Propel, a financial technology platform used by SNAP beneficiaries that reaches over 5 million low-income households. Propel is running an ACP promotion campaign through July.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>THE AFFORDABLE CONNECTIVITY PROGRAM (ACP)</u></strong></p>



<p>The ACP is a key part of the Administration’s <a href="https://www.internetforall.gov/">Internet for All</a> initiative and the largest internet affordability program in our nation’s history. Experts estimate that&nbsp;<a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/610831a16c95260dbd68934a/t/62785ccb671629771cd1a60d/1652055243247/Broadband-Connectivity-Fact-Sheet-CPSP-2022.pdf">48 million households</a>—or nearly 40% of households in the country—qualify for the ACP either because their income is at or below 200% of the Federal Poverty Level, or because a member of the household meets one of the other criteria below:</p>



<ul><li>Participates in one of the following programs:<ul><li>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as Food Stamps</li><li>Medicaid</li><li>Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC)</li><li>Supplemental Security Income (SSI)</li><li>Federal Public Housing Assistance (FPHA)</li><li>Veterans Pension and Survivors Benefit</li><li>Free and Reduced-Price School Lunch Program or School Breakfast Program, including at U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) Community Eligibility Provision schools</li><li>Federal Pell Grant (received in the current award year)</li><li>Lifeline</li><li>Certain Tribal assistance programs, including Bureau of Indian Affairs General Assistance, Head Start (only households meeting the income qualifying standard), Tribal Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (Tribal TANF), and Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations</li></ul></li><li>Meets the eligibility criteria for a participating broadband provider’s existing low-income internet program.</li></ul>



<p>As of now, more than 1,300 internet service providers participate in the program, and about 13 million households have signed up to receive the ACP benefit.<br><br>Households can check their eligibility for ACP, sign up, and find fully covered plans by visiting <a href="https://getinternet.gov/">GetInternet.gov</a>. They can also learn more by calling (877) 384-2575.<br><br>The ACP enrollment drive is just one part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s <a href="https://www.internetforall.gov/">Internet for All Initiative</a> to ensure that every American has access to reliable and affordable high-speed internet. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides a $65 billion investment in high-speed internet access—on top of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-over-25-billion-in-american-rescue-plan-funding-to-help-ensure-every-american-has-access-to-high-speed-affordable-internet/">billions</a> in funding for high-speed, affordable internet provided by the American Rescue Plan that is currently being deployed across the nation.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
