<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 12:04:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Announces New Actions to Address Putin’s Price Hike, Make Food More Affordable, and Lower Costs for&#160;Farmers </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-new-actions-to-address-putins-price-hike-make-food-more-affordable-and-lower-costs-for-farmers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 12:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pandemic-related supply chain disruptions and Putin’s Price Hike are increasing the price of food for working families here at home and leading to shortages of food in countries across the globe. Today, President Biden will visit a family farm to announce actions his administration is taking to support American farmers, reduce food prices, and feed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Pandemic-related supply chain disruptions and Putin’s Price Hike are increasing the price of food for working families here at home and leading to shortages of food in countries across the globe. Today, President Biden will visit a family farm to announce actions his administration is taking to support American farmers, reduce food prices, and feed the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Putin’s unjustified invasion of Ukraine has cut off a critical source of wheat, corn, barley, oilseeds, and cooking oil. It has also disrupted global supply chains for fertilizer, which farmers depend on to maximize yields. These and other actions, combined with the ongoing pandemic-related disruptions to global supply chains, have put pressure on food prices, with global food prices increasing nearly 13 percent following Putin’s invasion.</p>



<p>America’s farmers are the breadbasket of democracy and are already playing a critical role in the fight against Putin’s Price Hike. During President Biden’s first year in office, American agricultural exports shattered all previous records, reaching a combined $177 billion, generating an estimated $378 billion in total economic output, and supporting 1.3 million jobs here in the United States.</p>



<p>Last month, the President mobilized American farmers to fuel America when he announced that his Administration would allow E15 gasoline—gasoline that uses a 15 percent ethanol blend—to be sold this summer. Today, the President is announcing new actions to give farmers the tools and resources they need to boost production, lower food prices and feed the world. As the world’s second largest exporter of wheat and soybeans, these actions will help grow new markets for American-grown food, supporting jobs in rural communities across America. Specifically, the Biden-Harris Administration will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Increase the number of counties eligible for double cropping insurance.</strong> Double cropping allows farmers to plant a second crop on the same land in the same year, helping boost production without relying on farmers to substitute crops or cultivate new land. But it is not free from risk and some farmers who practice double cropping cannot obtain crop insurance.  The Biden-Harris Administration is seeking to expand insurance for double cropping to as many as 681 additional counties, bringing the total number of counties where this practice qualifies for crop insurance to as many as 1,935, so more American farmers have the financial security they need to start or expand double cropping. <br></li><li><strong>Cut costs for farmers by increasing technical assistance for technology-driven “precision agriculture” and other nutrient management tools. </strong>Precision agriculture is a farm management system that allows farmers to use technology to target application of inputs to soil and plant needs, resulting in less fertilizer usage without reducing yields, saving farmers money over time and extending the usefulness of critical products in short supply worldwide. The U.S. Department of Agriculture has planning and cost sharing assistance programs available to help American farmers with nutrient management. The Biden-Harris Administration is working to boost outreach to farmers, streamline the application process, and prioritize application approvals to expand access to these critical programs. <br></li><li><strong>Double funding for domestic fertilizer production. </strong>Fertilizer prices have more than doubled since last year, due in part to supply chain disruptions created and exacerbated by Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, including rising energy costs. Today, President Biden is announcing that he is doubling his initial $250 million investment in domestic fertilizer production to $500 million to lower costs and boost availability for farmers, so they can obtain the inputs they need at prices they can afford to maximize yields. </li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Releases Permitting Action Plan to Accelerate and Deliver Infrastructure Projects On Time, On Task, and On&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-permitting-action-plan-to-accelerate-and-deliver-infrastructure-projects-on-time-on-task-and-on-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is making a once-in-a-generation investment in America’s infrastructure and competitiveness that will create good-paying union jobs, grow our economy, invest in communities, combat climate change, and help lower costs for families. To make the most of these historic investments and ensure infrastructure projects are delivered on time and on budget, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is making a once-in-a-generation investment in America’s infrastructure and competitiveness that will create good-paying union jobs, grow our economy, invest in communities, combat climate change, and help lower costs for families.<br><br>To make the most of these historic investments and ensure infrastructure projects are delivered on time and on budget, the Biden-Harris Administration is releasing a new <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Biden-Harris-Permitting-Action-Plan.pdf">Permitting Action Plan</a> to strengthen and accelerate Federal permitting and environmental reviews by fully leveraging existing permitting authorities, as well as new provisions in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br><br>The Action Plan outlines the Administration’s strategy for ensuring that Federal environmental reviews and permitting processes are effective, efficient, and transparent, guided by the best available science to promote positive environmental and community outcomes, and shaped by early and meaningful public engagement. Taken together, these new steps will help strengthen supply chains, lower costs for families, grow our clean energy economy, revitalize communities across the country, support good-paying jobs, and deliver infrastructure investments on task, on time, and on budget without unnecessary bureaucratic delay.&nbsp;<br><br>Long overdue improvements to our nation’s ports, airports, rail, and roads will help ease inflationary pressures, create conditions for businesses to thrive, and strengthen supply chains – which will ultimately lower costs for families. Building new clean energy generation and transmission projects will improve access to affordable clean energy that powers homes and businesses at lower costs. Responsible and sustainable domestic sourcing of critical minerals and materials will power our clean energy economy and reduce reliance on unreliable foreign supply chains. And delivering clean residential water supplies, high-speed internet, healthy forests and open space to all Americans, especially those historically underserved, is critical to make us stronger.<br><br>The Action Plan is the latest example of the Administration taking action to swiftly deliver the benefits of infrastructure investment to the American people through well-designed projects that support the President’s ambitious climate and clean energy goals. Putting the Action Plan into place will result in better permitting outcomes, enhanced predictability for project sponsors, and increased accountability across Federal agencies to execute efficiently and effectively.<br><br>The Permitting Action Plan is built on five key elements that will help ensure the timely and effective delivery of crucial upgrades to America’s infrastructure.<br><br><strong><em>Accelerating Smart Permitting through Early Cross-Agency Coordination</em></strong></p>



<p>Ensuring early coordination and effective communication across Federal agencies is critical for moving infrastructure projects forward efficiently and on-time. Under the Permitting Action Plan, the Administration will:</p>



<ul><li>Leverage the interagency Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council’s expanded authorities under the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to improve coordination among agencies, help avoid and resolve potential conflicts and bottlenecks, identify and share best practices, and accelerate information sharing and troubleshooting;<br></li><li>Convene sector-specific teams of experts to facilitate interagency coordination on siting, permitting, supply chain, and related issues, and promote efficient and timely reviews;<br></li><li>Leverage the Department of Transportation’s Interagency Infrastructure Permitting Improvement Center to help facilitate environmental review and permitting for Bipartisan Infrastructure Law-funded transportation projects by developing guidance, sharing best practices, coordinating reviews, tracking project milestones and outcomes, and exploring innovative approaches;<br></li><li>Develop and prepare new approaches to permitting and environmental review that help address common issues, eliminate duplication, and site and design projects in a way that reduces resource conflicts and incorporates a climate-smart approach; and<br></li><li>Work to reform outdated permitting laws and regulations, such as the Mining Law of 1872, to establish stronger environmental, sustainability, safety, Tribal consultation, and community engagement standards.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Establishing Clear Timeline Goals and Tracking Key Project Information</em></strong><br><br>Communities and project proponents all benefit from having clear information about the schedules, key milestones and deadlines, and public comment opportunities for the environmental review and permitting of major projects. Timeline goals and up-to-date information increase accountability, encourage efficiency, enable greater public participation in project decisions, and build greater trust in government. Under the Permitting Action Plan, agencies will:</p>



<ul><li>Create permitting schedules with clear timeline goals that are both ambitious and realistic, contain relevant milestones, and meet all requirements in applicable law to complete environmental review and permitting in a sound and timely manner;<br></li><li>Increase transparency and accountability by tracking key project information, including timetables and milestones, on the <a href="https://www.permits.performance.gov/">Federal Permitting Dashboard</a>; and<br></li><li>Identify the lead Federal agency that will be responsible for working with other agencies in the permitting processes to develop and implement coordination plans, interagency agreements, or other tools designed to ensure sustained and effective coordination and accountability.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Engaging in Early and Meaningful Outreach with States, Tribal Nations, Territories, and Local Communities</em></strong><br><br>Proactive, early, and ongoing engagement with the public, including disadvantaged, underserved, or overburdened communities, and State, Tribal, local, and territorial partners is fundamental to delivering timely projects that serve the needs and priorities of communities across the country. As part of a robust engagement strategy, which will help inform agencies’ decision-making, agencies will:</p>



<ul><li>Consult with affected Tribal Nations as early as possible, in a sustained manner, and in a fashion that respects the Nation-to-Nation relationship;<br></li><li>Proactively partner and coordinate with relevant State, territorial, and local governments as early as possible and in a sustained manner; and<br></li><li>Review and update policies, procedures, and staffing to ensure that the public, including disadvantaged communities, has a meaningful opportunity to participate in decision-making.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Improving Agency Responsiveness, Technical Assistance, and Support</em></strong><br><br>Providing responsive technical assistance and support helps project sponsors, permit applicants, affected communities, Tribal communities, and other stakeholders navigate the environmental review and permitting process effectively and efficiently. To address this need, agencies will:</p>



<ul><li>Identify, share, or develop resources, trainings, and tools to help stakeholders navigate the environmental review and permitting process effectively and efficiently; and<br></li><li>Review environmental review and permitting information collection requirements to help consolidate or simplify reporting requirements, and identify ways that information can be collected more efficiently.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Using Agency Resources and Environmental Reviews to Improve Impact</em></strong><br><br>Timely, informative environmental reviews that are guided by the best available science and help deliver positive environmental and community impact require sufficient levels of skilled agency staff and effective use of budgetary resources. Agencies should therefore:</p>



<ul><li>Prioritize available resources to address workforce needs and implementation of the initiatives in this Action Plan;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Use best practices for accelerated hiring and coordinating with other agencies to efficiently use existing resources, such as conducting collaborative field studies and funding liaison positions; and<br></li><li>Use technology, data, and tools to efficiently and holistically assess environmental and community effects, including information on climate change effects, and identify ways to use new technology to collect, analyze, share, and publicly communicate relevant information.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on House Passage of the Ukraine&#160;Supplemental</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-house-passage-of-the-ukraine-supplemental/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 03:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The House took a critical step today in sending a clear, bipartisan message to Ukraine, to Russia, and to the world that the United States stands with the people of Ukraine as they defend their democracy against Russian aggression. We thank House leadership and members of the Appropriations committee for working across the aisle to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The House took a critical step today in sending a clear, bipartisan message to Ukraine, to Russia, and to the world that the United States stands with the people of Ukraine as they defend their democracy against Russian aggression. We thank House leadership and members of the Appropriations committee for working across the aisle to get this done, and appreciate the strong bipartisan support for the President’s proposal to provide much needed security, economic, humanitarian, and food assistance to Ukraine, across the region, and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our assistance to date, together with the contributions of our Allies and partners, has been critical in helping Ukrainians win the battle for Kyiv and defend their freedoms. The additional resources included in this bill will allow us to send more weapons, such as artillery, armored vehicles, and ammunition, to Ukraine. And they will help us replenish our stockpile and support U.S. troops on NATO territory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President said yesterday, we cannot afford any delay in this vital effort. We look forward to continuing to work with Senate leadership to get this bill to the President’s desk quickly and keep assistance flowing to Ukraine without interruption.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Meeting with Prime Minister Kiril Petkov of Bulgaria&#160;</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-prime-minister-kiril-petkov-of-bulgaria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Prime Minister Kiril Petkov of Bulgaria. The Vice President expressed her appreciation for the strong alliance and warm friendship between the United States and Bulgaria. She thanked the Prime Minister for Bulgaria’s support to Ukraine and affirmed U.S. solidarity in the face of Russia’s latest attempt to use&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Prime Minister Kiril Petkov of Bulgaria. The Vice President expressed her appreciation for the strong alliance and warm friendship between the United States and Bulgaria. She thanked the Prime Minister for Bulgaria’s support to Ukraine and affirmed U.S. solidarity in the face of Russia’s latest attempt to use energy as a weapon. They agreed on the need to strengthen European resilience by further diversifying energy supplies away from Russia and the importance of continued strong defense and deterrence along NATO’s Eastern flank.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Readout of the Meeting Between President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and Prime Minister Mario&#160;Draghi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/joint-readout-of-the-meeting-between-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-and-prime-minister-mario-draghi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 23:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States and Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy met today at the White House. The leaders reaffirmed the strong and broad U.S.-Italian partnership reflected in the deep and enduring ties between our people and our countries, of which our alliance through NATO and the U.S. partnership with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States and Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy met today at the White House. The leaders reaffirmed the strong and broad U.S.-Italian partnership reflected in the deep and enduring ties between our people and our countries, of which our alliance through NATO and the U.S. partnership with the EU are critical components. They discussed recent developments in Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified war in Ukraine. They underscored their continued commitment to&nbsp;pursuing peace by&nbsp;supporting Ukraine and imposing costs on Russia.&nbsp;In the face of the global economic challenges created by Russia’s actions, they discussed measures aimed at fostering food security and reshaping global energy markets. They committed to maintaining their work together on global crises from COVID-19 to climate change, as well as to continuing their cooperation on shared foreign policy challenges, including China and Libya. The leaders looked forward to further discussions at the G-7 Summit and NATO Summit in June.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki,&#160;May 10, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/10/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-may-10-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:40 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  Okay.  It’s a little rowdy in here today.  All right.  Tomorrow, the President will visit a family farm in Kankakee, Illinois, with the Secretary of Agriculture, Tom Vilsack, to discuss the impact of President Putin’s invasion of Ukraine on the rise in food&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:40 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  Okay.  It’s a little rowdy in here today. <br> <br>All right.  Tomorrow, the President will visit a family farm in Kankakee, Illinois, with the Secretary of Agriculture, Tom Vilsack, to discuss the impact of President Putin’s invasion of Ukraine on the rise in food prices at home and abroad.<br> <br>He’s going to talk about the support we need to continue to give to farmers to help continue to produce more and more domestically to help address the food shortages that we’re seeing in some parts of the world.<br> <br>We know that U.S. agricultural exports can help address that and can play an important role.  Just as we are providing weapons, we are going to work on doing more we can to support farmers to provide more wheat and other food around the world.  He’ll talk about that tomorrow.<br> <br>We’ll also &#8212; we’ll also see tomorrow morning the latest inflation numbers for the month of April.  And the President will deliver remarks on the effect of Putin’s price hike on the cost of food and energy, and his administration’s actions to support farmers and food processers, lower their costs, and lower prices for families.<br> <br>Later in the day, the President will give remarks at the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers’ &#8212; IBEW &#8212; 40th Convention in Chicago, Illinois, on his support for union jobs in the infrastructure and energy industries.<br> <br>I also wanted to note for all of you that this afternoon, soon, in the next couple of hours, the President will host Speaker Pelosi and other members of a congressional delegation who recently traveled to Ukraine in the Situation Room. <br> <br>The President previously spoke to Speaker Pelosi about the delegation’s trip by phone.  As we said earlier this month, he wanted to hear a more thorough account of their time in Ukraine, in person, after they returned to the United States.  So this is an opportunity to do exactly that.<br> <br>The President is eager to hear from them and to continue working together on their shared bipartisan goal of providing Ukraine with additional urgensly [sic] &#8212; urgently needed security and economic assistance as soon as possible.  And we&#8217;ve heard good news about that, hopefully moving forward soon.<br> <br>With that, go ahead, Josh.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Three things.  First, I wanted to &#8212; I was hoping to clarify something President Biden said today on inflation.  He said his policies helped, rather than hurt, on inflation.  Does the President believe that his COVID relief package played any role in the increase in inflation last year?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  The President believes, as many economists, including within the government, that the main drivers of inflation were the pandemic &#8212; have been the pandemic and our ongoing fight to address that, as well as President Putin&#8217;s invasion into Ukraine and the impact on energy prices.<br> <br>What the President has done is taken steps to address both of those enormous, enormous challenges and tried to put forward solutions to them. <br> <br>We&#8217;ll leave it to the Federal Reserve, outside economists, inside economists to make other projections on what&#8217;s next.  They&#8217;ve already made projections about when they expect inflation to come down.<br> <br>As he noted today, he is the President.  We do- &#8212; do control all forms of &#8212; branches of government.  That&#8217;s why he laid out very clearly what he&#8217;ll continue to do as President to bring down prices. <br> <br>Q    So then, just to make sure, like, what he’s saying is: The pandemic is distinct from the spending in response to the pandemic, and he does not believe the size of the spending mattered with regard to inflation?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Again &#8212; no.  He &#8212; and we have &#8212; we have spoken to this in the past, Josh, as you know.  The President made a decision that in order to address what was in part a<br>economic crisis that came in, in conjunction with the pandemic, that we needed to put forward the American Rescue Plan. <br> <br>And without it, the economy would have gotten worse.  People would not have been able to put food on the table.  We would not have 100 percent of schools open today.<br> <br>So, no, he does not think that is the driver.  He knows the pandemic was the driver.  There was, of course, an accompanying economic downturn as a result.  And we&#8217;ve seen in recent months the impact of President Putin&#8217;s invasion and the energy prices that have gone up and been a main driver of inflation.<br> <br>Q    Gotcha.  Secondly, Italian Prime Minister Mario Draghi just now pushed for a limited ceasefire to allow talks to resume between Russia and Ukraine.  Does the U.S. believe that these talks would be productive?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We certainly believe that this will be resolved through a diplomatic process and a diplomatic solution.  But we know and you heard, I think, our Director of National Intelligence on Capitol Hill today say that we don&#8217;t see a sign from the Russians that they are open to or eager to invade &#8212; engage in those discussions.<br> <br>There have been several fits and starts at attempts at ceasefires, even in smaller parts of the country, in Ukraine, as you know.  We&#8217;ve been supportive of all of those, but it requires the Russians being at the table and being willing to take part in a diplomatic process.<br> <br>And then lastly, Mexico&#8217;s President said he might not go to Los Angeles for the Summit of the Americas if the U.S. doesn&#8217;t invite Cuba and Nicaragua and Venezuela.  What does President Biden plan to do?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, the invitations have not yet been issued.  The summit is not until early June &#8212; June 10th &#8212; 6th through the 10th, I should say.  We know that the summit is a valuable opportunity to focus on some of the most important shared issues, like the ongoing fight for freedom and democracy for every country; our shared climate goals; a stronger, more collaborative COVID-19 response; and addressing the root causes of migration, like going after organized crime and economic instability.<br> <br>But no invitations have been issued at this point.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    On gas prices, despite the steps the President has taken, despite tapping the strategic oil reserve, prices have hit a new high at $4.37 a gallon.  How long should Americans be prepared to pay this much at the pump?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say &#8212; you heard the President say today and reiterate today that he is relentlessly focused on easing Putin&#8217;s price hike at the pump.  And that means taking as many steps as he can to continue to lower costs for Americans. <br> <br>Now, the steps that he can take and he has taken, of course, include a historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, leading the world in their release to ensure there&#8217;s more supply in the global markets, to reduce the price of oil &#8212; which is exactly what it has done.<br> <br>He&#8217;s also taken steps that are definitely smaller but meant to do anything possible, including issuing a waiver for E15 so that thousands of pumps in the Midwest could have gasoline that &#8212; and make it available to Americans so that that&#8217;s 10 cents less. <br> <br>But he also has noted, and we would note &#8212; and he noted this this morning &#8212; that oil companies should also do their part in ensuring they&#8217;re not price gouging customers at the pump.  As oil prices come down, so should gas prices at the pump.  And that&#8217;s also something that we are going to continue to watch closely and continue to call on steps to be taken.<br> <br>But given that the steps taken so far haven’t been able to bring down prices, can Americans be confident that some of the steps that you&#8217;re outlining now will be able to have an effect?  Or is it just going stay this way &#8212; is Putin’s price hike going to stay until Putin’s war is over?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we certainly won&#8217;t accept that.  But what I think is important to note is the oil market is global.  And what the President can do and will continue to do is ensure he&#8217;s doing everything in his power to ensure that supply in the market meets the demand out there in the market.<br> <br>But the point is: When there is enough oil out there in the market, oil prices come down, as we&#8217;ve seen them come down, and gas prices should also come down.  And that is something that Americans should be watching closely and be clear about where we&#8217;re seeing price hikes come from.<br> <br>Q    I just have a question on messaging.  Who came up with this phrase “Ultra-MAGA”?  Why the need to kick it up a notch?  MAGA wasn&#8217;t enough?  I mean, why now use this phrase?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I will tell you, it is &#8212; it is the President&#8217;s phrase, and the President made those comments himself just last week, as you know. <br> <br>And I think what has struck him is how extreme some of the policies and proposals are that a certain wing of the Republican Party &#8212; that is taking up too much of the Republican Party &#8212; are for and are advocating for.<br> <br>And you &#8212; you&#8217;ve heard the President talk about this.  It&#8217;s &#8212; but it&#8217;s not just obviously putting at risk a woman&#8217;s right to make choices about her own healthcare. <br> <br>It is also, as you heard him talk about this morning, Rick Scott&#8217;s extreme plan that will raise taxes on 75 million Americans making less than $100,000 a year. <br> <br>It is Rick Scott&#8217;s plan to get rid of, eliminate &#8212; that&#8217;s what “sunset” means: “get rid of” &#8212; Medicare and Social Security, something people over 70 in this country rely on. <br> <br>And it&#8217;s also the obsession with culture wars and wars against Mickey Mouse and banning books.  The President thinks that&#8217;s extreme.  That is not what the American people care about or what they want.<br> <br>And so, to him, adding a little “ultra” to it, give it a little extra pop.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    So then who is an “Ultra-MAGA” Republican?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I would say people who support that portion of the Republican agenda.<br> <br>Q    So, Rob Portman, Susan Collins, Mitt Romney, would they be “Ultra-MAGA” Republicans?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  They can all make their own choices, Ed.  And I can &#8212; we can let others evaluate that.<br> <br>But I would say that the President&#8217;s view is: Those who support a plan by Rick Scott &#8212; by Chairman Scott, that would raise taxes on 75 million Americans and get rid of, “sunset,” eliminate &#8212; whatever you want to call it &#8212; Medicare and Social Security, that&#8217;s a MAGA position.<br> <br>And that includes the Chairman of the Republican National Committee.  That&#8217;s a MAGA position.  That is the chairman of the party.<br> <br>So that&#8217;s what the President considers.  But also, obviously, given two thirds of the American people, according to a Fox News poll, believe that women&#8217;s &#8212; that Roe v. Wade should be protected, if you&#8217;re on the other side of that, you&#8217;re supporting an “Ultra-MAGA” position, in the President&#8217;s view.<br> <br>So we&#8217;ll let &#8212; we don&#8217;t need to name-call individuals unless they have positions that are aligned with what he feels is the “Ultra-MAGA” wing of the party.<br> <br>Q    Two other quick on foreign affairs.  Just to follow up on Josh&#8217;s question, you said invites to the Summit of the Americas haven&#8217;t gotten out.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Can you confirm, though, that someone from Venezuela, someone from Nicaragua, someone from Cuba will actually be invited to the summit?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I can&#8217;t because a final decision has not been made yet.<br> <br>Q    You don’t rule out that those three countries might be exempted?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We haven&#8217;t made a decision about who will be invited, and no invitations have been issued yet.<br> <br>Q    And then, last night at a fundraiser in suburban Washington, the President said this about Vladimir Putin, quote: “He is a very, very, very calculating man.  And the problem I worry about now is that he doesn’t have a way out right now, and I’m trying to figure out what we do about that.”<br><br>Can you describe how that process is going?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  What we do &#8212;<br><br>Q    Does it involve &#8212; does it involve, for example, considering the Italian Prime Minister’s suggestion that there be a temporary ceasefire for talks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think, to be clear, we’ve long supported ceasefires.  It requires both the parties, including the party that has invaded the other country, to be a part of that, and they haven’t shown a willingness to sit at the negotiating table. <br><br>So I think there have been efforts, as you know &#8212; humanitarian ceasefires and others &#8212; in a limited fashion in the past and in the past couple of months, which the Russians have failed to implement.<br><br>What the President meant by this, and I &#8212; and I talked to him about exactly that this morning &#8212; or what he was referring to is the fact that, as we all know and we all have seen and you all have reported, this war has not gone as President Putin has planned.  You know, he has seen his military be demoralized.  He did not march through the city of Kyiv yesterday.  NATO and the West are united.  And right now, he&#8217;s dealing with crippling financial sanctions in his country while he has become a pariah in the world.<br><br>So what the President&#8217;s point was is that we have to be clear-eyed about the impact that has on a dictator that has invaded another country, a sor- &#8212; a sovereign country that it hasn&#8217;t gone as plan- &#8212; as he thought it would go.<br> <br>Q    If he’s so concerned, why not try to directly engage Putin himself?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I would say our role right now &#8212; we feel the most constructive role is to continue to support the Ukrainians’ hands at the negotiating table and support them militarily.  And I would note that our support &#8212; obviously, their bravery and courage has been what has helped them win the Battle of Kyiv, but our military assistance, the assistance &#8212; our humanitarian and economic assistance is a &#8212; is a close second.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    So, today, the President said that a “majority” of Republicans have signed on to Senator Scott&#8217;s tax plan.  That does not seem to be the case.  Senator Scott said that today.  Mitch McConnell had said that the party is not behind this.  Are there any Republicans that you can think of or the President might be referencing that is currently behind this?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Do you count the chairman of the Republican Committee as an important Republican?<br> <br>Q    He is the chairman of a committee.  But if no other Repub- &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  She.  It’s actually a “she.”  The chairman of the Republican Party &#8212;<br><br>Q    I thought you were referring to Scott there.  I &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  So, Chairman Ronna McD- &#8212; Ronna McDaniel praised Senator Scott&#8217;s proposal as a, quote, “clear plan” for Republicans that offers, quote, “real solutions.”<br><br>She&#8217;s the chairwoman of the party.  Rick Scott is not a random senator.  He is literally in charge of winning back the Senate for Republicans and what the plan is.  So he is the person who&#8217;s put forward this plan. <br>    <br>Senator Ron Johnson has called the Congressional GOP plan a, quote, “positive thing.”  Senator Mike Braun has said he was, quote, “glad Rick did it.”  Senator Tommy Tuberville said he was, quote, “on board” with the Congressional GOP plan.  Congressman Matt Gaetz said he was, quote, “proud of Senator Rick Scott for <s>providing</s> [producing] this bold agenda.”<br><br>So not only that, which seems to be quite a range of Republicans, but there isn&#8217;t an alternative plan they&#8217;ve put forward.  So it&#8217;s either this, put together by the person who is leading the effort to win back the Senate, or nothing.<br><br>And the President this morning talked about what his plan is.  If they have an alternative plan, we would welcome them putting it forward.<br> <br>Q    And he did say one was coming in this summer.  And as far as Senator Scott goes, he acknowledged today that a majority is not behind him.  He says this is his individual plan for this.<br><br>I do want to ask, as well &#8212; I mean, the Department of Justice was very swift in responding to school board members who felt like they were being harassed and intimidated a couple months back.  Does the President feel that the demonstrations outside of, say, Justice Alito’s home &#8212; are those attempts to interfere or intimidate?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think I said yesterday, but I&#8217;m happy to repeat because I think it&#8217;s important for everybody to hear, that the President&#8217;s longstanding view has been that violence, threats, and imitat- &#8212; intimidation of any kind have no place in political discourse.  And we believe, of course, in peaceful protest.<br><br>What I do find is interesting, and I think most &#8212; many people have noted, is that there are voices on the right who have called out this &#8212; protests that are happening &#8212; while remaining silent for years on protests that have happened outside of the homes of school board members, the Michigan Secretary of State, or including threats made to women seeking repo- &#8212; reproductive healthcare, or even an insurrection against our Capitol.<br><br>So I know that there&#8217;s an outrage right now, I guess, about protests that have been peaceful to date &#8212; and we certainly continue to encourage that &#8212; outside of judges’ homes.  And that&#8217;s the President&#8217;s position.  But the silence is pretty deafening about all of the other intimidation that we&#8217;ve seen to a number of people.<br><br>Q    This is a pending court case though.  That’s where the federal law comes into place.  This is a pending court case.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, but I think that intimidation and protests &#8212; and intimidation outside of the homes of school board members, the Michigan Secretary of State &#8212; you know, intimidation and threats against people seeking legal reproductive healthcare &#8212; and against our Capitol and American democracy also warrant some outrage.  And we haven&#8217;t really seen that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Jen, you mentioned this a bit yesterday, but the situation has changed since then: We&#8217;ve now heard a bipartisan Senate proposal resolution from Senators Blumenthal and Graham who are urging the Biden &#8212; or would be urging the Biden administration to designate Russia as a state sponsor of terrorism under Vladimir Putin.  Is there any new information, from your view, on that?  Is that something the President supports?  And if not, why not?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we expect, certainly &#8212; and Speaker Pelosi said this yesterday, that this is a topic she will raise &#8212; or we&#8217;ll leave it to her if she wants to raise it when she meets with the President today.<br><br>Q    What’s his view?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would note, as the President has said in the past, this is a process that &#8212; a legal process that the State Department goes through and reviews.  And what they look at &#8212; it&#8217;s defined by statute &#8212; by Congress, actually.  They take a look at the law and undergo a review of whether somebody has violated or a country has violated international terrorism laws.  And that is what they look closely at.<br><br>I would note &#8212; and when Speaker Pelosi spoke to this yesterday, and others, they expressed a desire and an interest in making sure we were doing everything we could &#8212; maximum efforts &#8212; to hold Russia accountable.<br><br>And &#8212; and they looked at, understandably, what has been done to other countries that have been labeled state sponsors of terrorism.  Only four, of course, have &#8212; have been designated that way.<br><br>And we have been doing, already, what has happened to those other countries.  So, extensive financial sanctions, export controls, also working diplomatically to limit investment by other countries in &#8212; in the &#8212; the pariah states &#8212; the other four and, certainly, Russia.<br><br>So we&#8217;ve already been taking those steps. <br><br>There &#8212; there’ll be an ongoing review at the State Department.  That process should see itself out &#8212; itself through.  And that&#8217;s where the President thinks it should be.<br><br>Q    On the Ukrainian package that the President is proposing, Congress is now, you know, working on such a package.  We heard from Mitch McConnell on the Hill a short time ago saying the Republicans don&#8217;t want, in his words, “extraneous items to be included.”  Does the White House believe that the Afghanistan Advancement Act should be included in there &#8212; in there, Ukraine refugee aid, oligarch sanctions?  I’ll start with Afghanistan Act.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think as you&#8217;re touching on here, but just to get others up to speed on where it stands, the House proposal that they&#8217;re expected to introduce is about $40 billion, which is larger than the package that we had proposed &#8212; about $7 billion over our initial request.<br><br>So, while it has $3.4 billion more for security and humanitarian assistance, it doesn&#8217;t &#8212; it&#8217;s not expected to include some items, including, as you touched on, providing a pathway to permanent status for African refugees &#8212; something we certainly support, right?<br><br>Q    So do you believe that that should be included in this package?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  There’ll be a negotiation and a discussion in Congress.  I&#8217;m not going to prejudge that.  We&#8217;ve supported that being included.  But obviously, there&#8217;s an urgency to getting this funding done, given we have nine more days until we run out of money.<br> <br>Q    Okay.  I guess the question is: If &#8212; if this is to delay your ability to accomplish this within nine days, is the President &#8212; would he be okay with that being not included in the final package?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  If what were to delay?<br> <br>Q    If this were to delay the nine days, you said, until money runs out.  If you were not to include the Afghan aid, for example, the President would be okay with that being out, is what you’re saying?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, again, this hasn&#8217;t even been formally introduced by the House.  We have supported that.  But the President &#8212;<br><br>Q    (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  &#8212; has been &#8212; has been very clear &#8212; it&#8217;s not being discussed upstairs, it&#8217;s &#8212; well, being discussed with Speaker Pelosi when she comes.  Sure.  But the President has been clear we need to get this funding and security assistance funding so that we can continue to provide assistance to the Ukrainians.<br><br>Q    Let me ask one last question, because I asked the President earlier and he said it was being weighed &#8212; this was as it related to dropping the China tariffs right now &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br><br>Q    &#8212; to help the &#8212; to help the domestic economy here.  Is the President sensitive that doing that could actually &#8212; would be a political liability if it may help Americans in the near term, in terms of their pocketbook, their costs?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  A political &#8212; so &#8212; say that one &#8212;<br><br>Q    Does the President have concerns that, basically, lifting tariffs on China &#8212; which could be used as a battering ram by political opponents saying you’re being soft on China &#8212; would be a political challenge for him, even if it would help Americans, in terms of their pocketbook issues in the near term, (inaudible)?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we already &#8212; we already announced some tariffs that we were lifting back in March.  So it&#8217;s been an ongoing review.  And we expect to do more.  And his &#8212;<br><br>Q    But he said he’s weighing new ones, so (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  He’s weighing new ones.  Yes.  Because it&#8217;s an ongoing process, and there are more that are still in place.  And we didn&#8217;t feel that the ones that were in place when the President took office were all advantageous and were doing what they needed to do to make clear what our positions were on China&#8217;s approach to investment and economic engagement, which we&#8217;ve obviously been clear about our issues with. <br><br>And we have &#8212; but we are &#8212; we are continuing to review where it would be advantageous to take steps that would help, you know, reduce wages &#8212; or increase wages and help certain industries that are &#8212; that are impacted by these tariffs in a way that &#8212; that we don&#8217;t feel is effective.<br><br>So, there will be more and he&#8217;s continuing to weigh them.  But Ambassador Tai is &#8212; is leading that effort.<br><br>Q    Is Jill Biden going to be in the Situation Room for that meeting, given her experience?<br>MS. PSAKI:  Dr. Biden?  I don&#8217;t know that she will be in the meeting.  But the President &#8212; she and the President obviously had a number of conversations since she returned.  She &#8212; he was talking just this morning about how proud he was of her trip and how grateful he was that she traveled there.<br> <br>Go ahead.  Go ahead, Jeff.<br> <br>Q    Jen, just to follow up on the tariffs: Do you have a sense of the timeframe for when the next round or when the next decision on lifting tariffs could come?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have a prediction of that.  What we&#8217;re looking at is how to evaluate what&#8217;s working for American workers, industry, farmers, and consumers and change what is not.<br> <br>I mean, I expect we&#8217;ll have more to say in the coming weeks, but I don&#8217;t have an assessment for you on how expensive that will be or how many decisions about tariffs there will be at that point in time.  But we expect we&#8217;ll have more to say in the coming weeks.<br> <br>Q    Elon Musk today said that he would reverse the decision to have Twitter &#8212; that Twitter made to ban President Trump.  I’m wondering if the White House has a reaction to that and how that would impact this White House’s dealing with misinformation.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say it&#8217;s the decision by a private sector company to make on who will or will not be allowed on their platforms.<br> <br>What I will say, broadly speaking, is that our effort is to, of course, make sure that freedom of speech is protected across the country but that, also, these platforms are not used for format &#8212; forums for disinformation. <br> <br>And we have seen a history of that not just on Twitter but also on Facebook.  The President believes there&#8217;s more that needs to be done in reforming Section 230.  And there&#8217;s a lot of bipartisan interest in that, so this may be a reminder of the urgency of doing that.<br> <br>Q    And lastly, the United States is about to hit a grim milestone of a million COVID-related deaths.  How does the President plan to commemorate this?  And looking back at the last two years, why has that number gotten so high in this country?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we&#8217;re facing &#8212; we&#8217;ve been battling a historic pandemic, Jeff, I think.  And while we have more than 75 percent of the country vaccinated, which is a significant number, we still know that far too many people are &#8212; have not been vaccinated, have not taken the maximum protections, even if they’re vaccinated and not yet boosted, to massively reduce their likelihood of hospitalization and death.<br> <br>It is still incumbent upon us and we are still working every day on increasing the number of vac- &#8212; people vaccinated, the number of people boosted, and expanding the protections.  In terms of how we&#8217;re going to mark that moment, the President will certainly be marking that day.  I expect we’ll have more to say soon.  We look at the CDC data and the Johns Hopkins data.<br> <br>I know different news organizations evaluate it differently.  But in terms of when we will mark it, it will be aligned with when that data hits the number.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Last November, President Biden asked the Federal Trade Commission to look into whether oil and gas companies were playing a role in keeping gas prices high.  Has he gotten the results of that investigation?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, they&#8217;re independent, so they would make any announcements about any intention to take steps on their own &#8212; of their own accord, out publicly to all of you.  And obviously, they have not done that.<br> <br>But what we can certainly see and watch, Kaitlan, even without any announcement or indication by the FTC, is, as we see the price of oil &#8212; barrels of oil come down, the price of gas should also come down at the pump.  And we haven&#8217;t always seen that trend take place.  And that is something we are also closely watching and certainly the FTC would be watching as well.<br> <br>Q    Is it the White House’s understanding that they&#8217;re actually investigating that?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Again, you&#8217;d have to speak to them.  They’re independent.  The President sent a letter.  He&#8217;s spoken about this a number of times publicly, but they would speak to any intention of investigating, given they’re independent.<br> <br>Q    And what&#8217;s the White House&#8217;s expectation for the inflation report that is expected to come out this week?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have a prediction.  I know I sometimes do, but I don&#8217;t have a prediction on it at this moment from here.<br> <br>Obviously, once it comes out, I expect we&#8217;ll have more to say.  And our focus continues to be on taking steps to lower costs.  And obviously, the President addressed this morning and outlined this morning what his plan is to do exactly that.<br> <br>Go ahead.  Oh, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Last question on Ukraine.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    The President&#8217;s comment last night that he&#8217;s worried Putin does not have a way out of this that he can see &#8212; what does he believe Putin&#8217;s goal is right now?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think what the President was referring to is the fact that this has not gone as President Putin planned and that &#8212; while he had predicted in a very public speech we all talked about at the time in February that he would not only subsume Ukraine and to make that a part of Russia, he would be marching through the streets and maybe he’d do more from there.  And that obviously hasn&#8217;t happened.<br> <br>The Ukrainians won the battle of Kyiv.  He obviously &#8212; he also thought that NATO would be divided, that the West would be divided &#8212; that has not happened.  And he certainly did not predict he would be facing the level of crippling sanctions enforced by all Western countries together that he is today.<br> <br>So, the point he was making is that, you know, we have to be cleareyed about the fact that this war is not over, that they are &#8212; he still has ambitions and he is still fighting the war.  And we&#8217;ve seen that on the ground every day.  But even as the Ukrainians have had successes, as Director Haines said today, this is going to be a long war and we need to prepare ourselves for that.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Jen, on Monday, you tweeted out that the President strongly believes in the right to protest, that such protests should never include violence, threats, or vandalism.  And you specifically mentioned the ability of judges to be able to do their jobs. <br> <br>Is the administration worried that abortion rights protests may turn violent?  And was there any specific group of protesters that that tweet was geared towards?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think, to be very clear, the protests outside of judges’ homes have not turned violent.  And I don&#8217;t think we need to make a prediction of that from here.  Just because people are passionate, it does not mean they&#8217;re violent.  And I think that&#8217;s probably why you&#8217;re asking the question, Ashley. <br> <br>But I think it is important to &#8212; the President felt it was important for us to be clear that as people&#8217;s passions are high, as people are fearful about their own healthcare, that should never resort to violence, it should never resort to vandalism.  And we have seen some elements of that &#8212; vandalism.  And he wanted to be clear that his position was to call for peaceful protests.<br> <br>Q    And on a similar theme, Senator Collins called the police over the weekend after someone wrote a non-threatening abortion rights message in sidewalk chalk in front of her house in Maine.  I was just curious, sort of, what you made of that &#8212; of her response.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have any specific comment on her response, other than to say that: Even as passions are high, even as people are fearful, even as people are scared and frustrated, which is understandable, we should not &#8212; no one should resort to violence, of course, nor threats, nor intimidation, nor vandalism, and that those are not effective means.<br> <br>Q    Do you consider sidewalk chalk vandalism?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;ll let others define that.  But there are lots of ways to peaceful protest.<br> <br>What&#8217;s also important to note here is what I would call the hypocrisy of the silence on the other side when there have been intimidation, protests outside of the homes of school board members, the Michigan Secretary of State.  There have been countless women who have dealt with and navigated through threats made as they&#8217;re seeking repro- &#8212; reproductive healthcare, which, by the way, has been legal for 50 years.  And there has been no outcry about that.<br> <br>There has been outcry about &#8212; about protests that have been peaceful outside of judges’ homes, which, again, you know, have been peaceful and have not been violent.  And the President has been clear about his view on them.<br> <br>Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Thank you.  I wanted to ask you about another aspect of what the President might call the “Ultra-MAGA Agenda,” which is election denial.  More than 140 House and Senate Republicans voted against certifying his victory in January 2021.  There are many more candidates running for seats in this election that have pledged that they would have done that and may do the same in the future.<br> <br>The President&#8217;s ramping up his rhetoric and going after Republicans on economic policies, tax policies.  Is he planning to go to voters and tell them that their vote this November could impact their ability to have their vote counted two Novembers hence?  Or is he not concerned that a Republican House would refuse to certify a Democratic victory in 2024?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think the way you can expect &#8212; without getting into the politics of it, which I have to be careful of from here &#8212; the President to talk about voting and voting rights is about his view and belief that we should have people elected across the country stand up for protecting and expanding access, and not questioning and making it more difficult or oppressing people&#8217;s right to exercise their right to vote.<br> <br>Q    Just a follow-up.  It seems more and more that a tenet of the Republican agenda is to denigrate him as illegitimate or &#8212; or worse.  Is &#8212; is it hard for him to hear these things?  What&#8217;s his reaction every day to hearing that there are people referring to his administration as “the regime” and talking about him as if he&#8217;s a dictator?  Is &#8212; is he bothered by that, or does he just see it as politics as usual these days?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I haven&#8217;t heard that one as much.  But I would say that you heard the President &#8212; Ed asked him earlier today about Senator Scott&#8217;s comments about him.  And, you know, the President&#8217;s response was, “[He] has a problem.”<br> <br>And his view of a lot of these comments is that people are freaking out in some capacity.  Because if you look at Senator Scott, his &#8212; his plan that is going to raise taxes on 75 million Americans, even peo- &#8212; some people in his own party &#8212; not enough, but some people in his own party are backing away from. <br> <br>So, you know, I don&#8217;t think he spends a lot of time worried about people&#8217;s angry tweets or &#8212; or angry verbal, you know, missives.  He spends time on laying out the contrast of what he&#8217;s going to present with what their plans are.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Briefly, to follow up on the questions about gas prices &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Can you give us a little more specifics about any new policies the administration might be considering to address high gas prices?  And how seriously is the administration considering calling for a suspension of the federal gas tax?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say, on the federal gas tax, that is an option on the table.  There &#8212; it would lower gas, I think, about &#8212; you can check me on this; I think you know the answer &#8212; about 18 cents, I believe.  And certainly, that&#8217;s something that remains on the table. <br> <br>There are a lot of ideas in Congress about steps that can be taken to lower gas prices even temporarily or provide some relief to Americans, so we&#8217;re in a constant discussion about that.<br> <br>He does continue to view the challenge as one being about ensuring there is supply in the marketplace.  And obviously, he&#8217;s taken the steps he took with the &#8212; this historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.  We’ll continue to talk with big global producers about what steps we can take.  And he&#8217;s going to continue to look at steps we can take to provide relief to Americans.<br> <br>I would say the other piece that&#8217;s very much on his mind is that when we look at inflation and what the impact of inflation is on Americans, we know that it has driven, at this point, 60 to 70 percent &#8212; depending on the data you&#8217;re looking at &#8212; by energy prices.<br> <br>And so, in addition to addressing that, he wants to think about how to bring down costs for Americans in a range of ways. <br> <br>And, you know, a couple of weeks ago, he announced fixes to the “family glitch” in the Affordable Care Act.  He&#8217;s announced a pause on the repayment of student loans. <br> <br>And if you&#8217;re a family at home balan- &#8212; you know, trying to figure out how you&#8217;re going to pay bills, you&#8217;re looking at what your costs are incoming, and he is going to take every step he can to provide relief as people need it in this moment, and he certainly recognizes that.<br> <br>Q    And speaking of inflation, is he concerned at all that widespread loan forgiveness would actually increase inflation and further exacerbate it by pumping money into the economy (inaudible)?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I know some economists &#8212; and I don&#8217;t have an official assessment from here &#8212; but I would say that Jared Bernstein, who is one of our economists, has spoken to this.  And he&#8217;s talked about &#8212; more about the impact of pausing federal loan repayments and the fact that, in his view &#8212; and you can quote him directly &#8212; it would be something like 0.001 percent, which, in his view, the impact of that &#8212; the impact of giving people relief who need relief, who are stressed and can&#8217;t repay these loans right now as they&#8217;re having higher costs in other areas, outweighs that impact.<br> <br>But again, I don&#8217;t have a projection here on specifically what the inflationary impact would be.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Just two things up.  Can you offer any further details on what the Women&#8217;s Health Policy Council has in mind on executive orders for abortion rights, since you all seem to (inaudible) that issue?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  Well, we&#8217;ve talked about &#8212; it may not all be executive orders.  I mean, there&#8217;s &#8212; a lot of this is ensuring that we have increased access and funding so that women who are living in the states, if Roe were to be overturned, would be able to have expanded access and capabilities.  And some of that could be from the Department of Justice, obviously, which they would make final decisions about.<br> <br>We&#8217;ve said that we weren&#8217;t going to preview until there&#8217;s a final opinion because we&#8217;re still speaking about a potential opinion that has not yet been released.  But what I would point you to is what we did around S.B. 8 and the law in Texas, which was to take steps, including by creating new grants to increase funding, given the fact that we know that 75 percent of women who seek an abortion are under 200 percent of the poverty level.  So increase funding to ensure we&#8217;re making it more &#8212; you know, making sure that funding is available to people.<br> <br>HHS has also started a number of programs with the exact same objective intended to protect patients and providers in response to the law.<br> <br>And the Department of Justice has also issued statements in response to S.B. 8 that reaffirm their commitment to using existing federal law to protect the safety of patients seeking access to reproductive health services.<br> <br>So what we&#8217;re looking at and what we&#8217;re trying to address is our assessment and understanding of what the impact will be that 13 states have trigger laws, 26 states have indicated that they could overturn or ban or take immediate action should this &#8212; should this be the final opinion.  And we know who is most &#8212; would be most impacted.<br> <br>So, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point.  As we said, we wouldn&#8217;t before there&#8217;s a final opinion.  But those are the factors we&#8217;re looking at.<br> <br>Q    And just one more question.  Where does the White House stand on whether the DOJ Antitrust Chief, Jonathan Kanter, should be recused from Google cases?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I will check and see if we have a position on that or if it’s something we&#8217;d punt to the Department of Justice.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    With the COVID funding now separated from the Ukraine funding, what is the path for the COVID funds to pass?  And also, should Americans start preparing for shortages of tests or vaccines or treatments this fall?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, on the second part of your question, I think we don&#8217;t want to sugarcoat it that we need more money.  We don&#8217;t have a plan B here.  We will use the few funds we have remaining to continue getting tests, treatments, and vaccines out to Americans for as long as we can.<br> <br>And we&#8217;re going to continue to work the phones, hold briefings, and make our case publicly and privately with lawmakers, imploring Congress to act immediately after our long &#8212; after &#8212; to help us on our long-overdue COVID needs.<br> <br>I will say that we are having conversations at a bipartisan level with a bi- &#8212; bicameral about what the impact will be, which the President said in a statement yesterday, “More Americans will die needlessly.” <br> <br>And why?  Because we&#8217;re going to exhaust our treatment supply, we&#8217;ll lose out to other countries on promising new treatments, we&#8217;ll lose our place in line for America to order new COVID vaccines, we’ll be unable to maintain our supply of COVID tests, and our effort to get &#8212; help lower-income countries get COVID vaccines into arms will stall, which is especially relevant given the international summit we&#8217;re hosting.<br> <br>So, we will use the remaining funds we have to kind of spread it as we can, but we need more money in order to continue to effectively run the programs we&#8217;ve been running to date.<br> <br>Q    If it takes a vote on Title 42, would the President be okay with a vote happening to try to block Title 42 going away in order to get a vote on the COVID funds?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I know there&#8217;s a lot of talk on this out there, and so I understand why you&#8217;re asking.  But right now, there&#8217;s a lot of steps that would need to happen before that came to the President&#8217;s desk.<br> <br>I would say our view &#8212; or his view continues to be that the lifting of Title 42 is a decision made by the CDC.  It was the authority given to them by Congress.  That should not be holding up funding that&#8217;s necessary to save the lives of Americans. <br> <br>But again, those are ongoing discussions in Congress at this point.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  I have two questions: oil and inflation.  Oil first.  The President referred to the Strategic Reserve, and then there&#8217;s this &#8212; we talked about that again &#8212; but the rallying our allies to release the additional 60 million barrels of oil from different countries.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    How successful has he been on this, on this very &#8212; convincing allies to release more oil?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say it&#8217;s the largest historic release ever by the global community, so I would say that&#8217;s pretty successful.<br> <br>In terms of the status of when the releases would happen, we said at the beginning that it would be over the course of time.  What we&#8217;re trying to do is fill the needs for the next several months until a number of oil companies have said they would be able to pump more.<br> <br>Q    Have you been &#8212; have you had commitment on that?  I mean &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We announced commitments just a few weeks ago.<br> <br>Q    On countries?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    From countries.  I&#8217;ll go back in my notes then.<br> <br>As for inflation, I just want to check something with you.  Because as you know, the eight-foot two-by-four goes to between $6 and $7 each these days.  Some construction is &#8212; construction is getting more and more costly.  I was reading a report from Habitat for Humanity saying 30,000 houses are $30,000 more expensive because of the cost of the &#8212; of material.<br> <br>As you know, the tariff on Canadian softwood is still over 11 percent.  Is that a way to get rid of part of the inflation by getting rid of these tariffs &#8212; which, actually, Canadian softwood is secure, strong, you know, easily accessible?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  You love &#8212; you love some good Canadian lumber.<br> <br>I don&#8217;t have anything to predict in terms of tariffs on Canadian lumber.  I will say that, obviously, taking steps not just to address the supply chain but to manufacture more at home, here in the United States, is part of the President&#8217;s longer-term plan to address these increasing costs over the long term.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thank you so much.  Would you have a comment on the presidential election in the Philippines?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  On the presidential election in the Philippines &#8212; I believe I have something in here.  There’s a lot happening today.  If not, we will get you something right after the briefing because I believe we may have something on that.  So why don’t we venture to do that.<br> <br>Q    And also, I had one on Afghanistan as well.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br> <br>Q    There were, like, dozens of women today in Kabul protesting the latest restriction, which is that they now must fully cover their faces and bodies in public.  And this is just the latest in a series of restrictions.<br> <br>Is the administration surprised that this is all happening?  And what is the administration doing to assist women and girls in Afghanistan?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, on the &#8212; let me just get &#8212; let me give you a comment on the Philippines first, because I found it, and then I&#8217;ll get to your Afghanistan question.<br> <br>So we are &#8212; this is not very exciting, I will just preface for you &#8212; but we are monitoring election results.  We look forward to renewing our partnership and to working with the next administration on key priorities, including strengthening our alliance; advancing a free, open Indo-Pacific; and promoting human rights.<br> <br>We understand that vote tabulation is well underway and that candidate Ferdinand Marcos Jr. stands in the lead, but we&#8217;re going to wait for the official call before we have a more formal comment.<br> <br>In terms of Afghan women in the street, I would say: One, even as the President made the choice to pull our troops out of Afghanistan after a 20-year failed war that cost thousands of American lives and spent billions of dollars of American taxpayer dollars, we still have committed to be supporters &#8212; humanitarian supporters through a range of NGOs and other organizations of the amazing courage of Afghan women and girls.<br> <br>And does it surprise us that they&#8217;re protesting in the streets?  No.  These are women who have been courageously standing up against oppression, against the Taliban for decades. And, you know, we will continue to be supporters, through any means possible, of their efforts and their bravery and courage they&#8217;re showing today.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Nancy asked you a little bit about the substance of some potential abortion EOs.  But I want to ask you about something Majority Leader Schumer said just a little while ago &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; to reporters on the Hill.  He said that President Biden is meeting with what he said was a group of people today to discuss possible executive action on abortion.  Is there such a meeting on the President&#8217;s schedule today?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say that one of the steps we&#8217;ve said we&#8217;ve been taking all along is having the Gender Policy Council, our Counsel&#8217;s Office, and the Department of Health and Human Services come up with options and proposals for what we would do were this opinion issued to be final or a version of it to be final. <br> <br>So those are ongoing internal meetings.<br> <br>Q    So can I ask who he&#8217;s meeting with today?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not aware of a meeting today but these are ongoing meetings, including with the President, that have been happening for the last several days.<br> <br>Q    And on the potential abortion EOs, is that something &#8212; in terms of the timetable, is it safe to assume that that&#8217;s something that you wouldn&#8217;t do until after you get the Supreme Court ruling or maybe sooner, given the things that have already happened and (inaudible)?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I think we&#8217;ve been clear from the beginning that we are not going to announce specific steps until we have a final opinion. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Also on abortion, Jen, we&#8217;ve seen the President speak out against states that had passed laws that he disagreed with.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Voting rights especially.  But last year, he supported calls for Major League Baseball to move the All-Star Game out of Georgia because of their voting laws.  Would the President support private businesses pulling out of states that are passing or will pass restrictive abortion laws?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I haven&#8217;t had that discussion with the President, so I don&#8217;t have anything to comment on at this point.<br> <br>Yeah, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Yeah.  So &#8212; thanks, Jen.  So the President said today that inflation is his top domestic priority.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Has that replaced climate change, then, for this administration as the top priority?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say first that inflation and the rise in cost for people across the country has long been the top issue for peo- &#8212; for &#8212; in every poll we&#8217;ve seen and certainly has been the number one issue for the President for some time.<br> <br>When he came into office, he said that his agenda was going to focus on four major priorities.  That includes addressing the climate crisis, of course, and he will continue to do that. <br> <br>But we are certainly aware that right now, in this moment, that inflation and reducing costs is what is most on the minds of Americans.<br> <br>Q    So the President was also asked if he took responsibility for any of his policies related to inflation &#8212; not just gas prices, but inflation.  When he took office, inflation was 2.5 percent year over year.  It&#8217;s now 8.5 percent. The invasion didn&#8217;t happen until about one year into his term. So why doesn&#8217;t the President take any responsibility?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI: I think the President said today that he&#8217;s President and that we control all three &#8212; obviously Congress, the House and Senate as well. <br> <br>What is also true is that the pandemic was going on before he took office; that fighting this historic pandemic &#8212; which has been front and center for his agenda, we know, and every economist will tell you this &#8212; has been the major driver of inflation over the past year-plus and we&#8217;ve continued to fight the pandemic since then.<br> <br>We&#8217;ve also heard Chairman Powell, Secretary Yellen, and others convey &#8212; and we&#8217;ve seen this in nearly every element of data we&#8217;ve seen on inflation since Pu- &#8212; President Putin invaded Ukraine &#8212; that energy prices account for the majority of inflationary increases over the past several weeks since the war began. <br> <br>So, you don&#8217;t have to take my word for it; that&#8217;s what economists and data have told us.<br> <br>What our focus is on &#8212; and you heard the President say this today &#8212; is not whether inflation is or isn&#8217;t an issue.  We all agree it&#8217;s an issue.  What our plan is and what the President&#8217;s plan is to address costs and bring down costs is what he outlined this morning.  It&#8217;s a multi-step plan. <br> <br>What are we seeing on the other side?  We&#8217;re seeing the plan proposed by Chairman Scott, which would instead raise costs on the American people and sunset or end &#8212; whatever you want to call it &#8212; Medicare and Social Security.<br> <br>Q    But last week, Chairman Powell did say that partly what the Fed did, as well as spending from Congress, is the reason that we&#8217;re in this high inflation environment.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He also talked about energy pri- &#8212; the invasion and the impact on energy prices, did he not? <br> <br>Q    He did.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, that seems like an important part of context, doesn&#8217;t it?<br> <br>Q    But it wasn&#8217;t until one year into the presidency that the invasion happened.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  And you&#8217;re asking me about recent inflationary data, which we know 60 to 70 percent of is because of energy prices, which even Chairman Powell quoted and said was because of the invasion of Ukraine.  Right?  Okay.<br> <br>Go ahead, April.<br> <br>Q    Jen, a couple of questions &#8212; one on abortion, following up on these meetings.  Has the President in recent weeks been more deliberate in his conversations as to who he&#8217;s talking with about the issue of abortion and this leaked draft has come &#8212; that came out on the opinion &#8212; possible opinion?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  When you say “more deliberate,” do you mean have we been having more conversations?  Or tell me more about what you mean.<br> <br>Q    (Inaudible) the President of the United States been more deliberate in who he&#8217;s talking with &#8212; abortion advocates or pro-lifers, pro-choicers?  Has he been talking to &#8212; more deliberate in talking to Schumer?  Has he been more deliberate in his conversations about abortion since this leak?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yes, but so has the entire administration.  And he has asked the Gender Policy Council, the Department of Health and Human Services, his Counsel&#8217;s Office to put together a plan and proposal, which he&#8217;s been engaged in meetings about, to discuss what we should prepare to do to protect women&#8217;s basic fundamental rights that have been the law of the land for 50 years. <br> <br>I think there&#8217;s no question, not just for Americans who care deeply about this but for the President as well, that this leaked opinion, whether it&#8217;s final or not &#8212; which we know the Supreme Court has said it&#8217;s not and they need to issue a final one at the appropriate time &#8212; has raised the alarm bells about what is at risk here, even though we have seen prior to this, you know, a number &#8212; 288 Republicans sign on to the amicus brief on the Mississippi case. <br> <br>So, it&#8217;s not that the effort to overturn Roe v. Wade is new; that has been ongoing for decades.  But certainly, this leaked draft raised the concern, raised the alarms, and certainly has heightened our focus on preparing what options are possible.<br> <br>Q    Right, since 1973.  You know, there&#8217;s been a stronger fight since all this happened.  But now you have people like Elizabeth Warren and Senator Schumer who are pushing this hard.  Has he been in conversations with both of them, and is he planning on talking to them before tomorrow?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We&#8217;ve been in touch with a range of senators.  We don&#8217;t read out those conversations as it relates to him from here.<br> <br>Q    (Inaudible) from the President.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I understand.  We don&#8217;t read them out per his ask.  So, he has a range of conversations.  It&#8217;s rare that I&#8217;m in the Oval Office and he doesn&#8217;t pick up the call &#8212; pick up the phone and call a member of Congress.  So, I can assure you he is in touch with a range of members.  And, obviously, this is front and center on their minds as are other issues. <br> <br>But certainly we will continue to assess directly with Congress.<br> <br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br> <br>Q    Wait a minute.  I&#8217;m not finished.  Please!<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Go ahead, April.<br> <br>Q    All right, so the next question on inflation.  The President has drilled down and administration officials have drilled down on issues of price gouging &#8212; going back to Kaitlan’s question, but this is more on a broader scale. <br> <br>The Agriculture Secretary came here a few months ago &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; talking about price gouging.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    He called out Tyson Foods &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; people who are profiting.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Record profits yesterday.<br> <br>Q    Right.  What&#8217;s hap- &#8212; across the board, you have gas companies that are profiting.  You have food companies that are profiting.  Consumers are having a hard time dealing with what&#8217;s at the grocery store and at the pump.<br> <br>Is the President going to start putting more of a focus on this profiteering or price-gouging issue?  Because you&#8217;re seeing these numbers from Tyson, you&#8217;re hearing about what&#8217;s happening at the pump.  And he even talked about &#8212; he asked local gas stations to look at the prices and see if they could make a cut themselves.  Is there going to be an extra focus or a more concerted focus on this issue of price gouging?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah &#8212; you heard the President talk about it this morning.  And tomorrow, he&#8217;s going to be traveling to Illinois where he&#8217;s going to be talking about how we need to continue to help small farmers on agriculture. <br> <br>So, we have talked about this, we have elevated it, and we want to make sure people across the country understand that some of these conglomerates &#8212; you mentioned the meat industry, but also oil and gas industry &#8212; should not be raising prices on consumers while they are making record profits. <br> <br>Okay, thank &#8212; let me &#8212; let me do Lynn Sweet because I have a soft spot for her. <br> <br>Lynn Sweet, go ahead.  Lynn Sweet.  Lynn Sweet, let&#8217;s hear it.  Lynn Sweet is going to ask a question.<br> <br>Q    Thank you.  And this relates to his visit to Kankakee.  And &#8212; (laughs) &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Lynn, thank you.  I should have found a friend on the pronunciation.  I practiced it.  I didn&#8217;t get it right.  I should have seen you here. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Okay, so on his visit to Kankakee and Chicago, I have noticed, as others have, that &#8212; the language that you used today and a bit in recent days on calling this “Putin’s price hike” and “Ultra-MAGA.”  I&#8217;m curious: When you go to the IBEW to talk about supporting the new jobs, infrastructure, energy issues, and the record on those issues, is this effective language to use in that kind of audience?  Because when you go to Kankakee, it&#8217;s really your event.  And it&#8217;s clear you don&#8217;t have to worry about an audience reacting one way or the other.  Could you speak to that?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think when he goes &#8212; he&#8217;s visiting a family farm in Kankakee.  How did I do there?  Okay.  And so, when he&#8217;s there, he&#8217;s really going to talk about the role of American farmers and the amazing agricultural sector we have in this country and the role that all Americans are playing in standing up for democracy and against autocracy. <br> <br>We think of it often as weapons &#8212; and obviously he went to the Javelin plant last week &#8212; but it&#8217;s also about providing American food that&#8217;s produced here in this country and what can we do more to produce more.  So that&#8217;s what those remarks will be more about.<br> <br>I have not yet looked at the remarks he will give at the IBEW tomorrow afternoon, but I can tell you you will &#8212; whether it&#8217;s tomorrow or in days and weeks ahead, people &#8212; you will all continue to hear him talk more about his concern about Ultra-MAGA Republicans and their agenda.  And, of course, this is not the last you&#8217;ve heard from us about Chairman Scott&#8217;s tax plan that will raise taxes. <br> <br>Okay, thanks, everyone.<br> <br>3:30 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden&#160;and Prime Minister Draghi Of Italy&#160;Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/10/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-draghi-of-italy-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 20:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 2:02 P.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, Mr. Prime Minister, it’s great to have you here.&#160; You’ve been a good friend and a great ally.&#160; And it’s my pleasure to welcome you to the White House and have a chance to repay some of the hospitality that you &#8212; you extended to me at&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>2:02 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, Mr. Prime Minister, it’s great to have you here.&nbsp; You’ve been a good friend and a great ally.&nbsp; And it’s my pleasure to welcome you to the White House and have a chance to repay some of the hospitality that you &#8212; you extended to me at the G20 Summit and in Rome.</p>



<p>And I guess we’re &#8212; in the G7, we&#8217;re going to be meeting a little bit later.&nbsp; On Sunday, we had that meeting.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to have a second COVID meeting as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; So, we’re spending a lot of time together.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a></a><a></a>You’ve been one of the closest allies we’ve had in responding to (inaudible) brutality of Putin.&nbsp;&nbsp;And I just think that your cooperation at &#8212; sometimes at a greater cost to others to take on Putin and what&#8217;s going on in Ukraine has been really incredible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you know, Mr. Prime Minister, Italy and the United States have a long history of shared bonds and so many &#8212; so many Italian Americans who are so proud of their heritage here, as you’ve observed.</p>



<p>Congratulations on your award.&nbsp; That&#8217;s pretty good.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; That’s pretty cool.</p>



<p>And so, welcome.&nbsp; We have a lot to talk about.&nbsp; And the floor is yours.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Let me say that it&#8217;s a great pleasure to be with you here today.&nbsp; Thanks for this invitation.&nbsp; Thanks for this magnificent hospitality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our two countries &#8212; the ties between our two countries have always been very strong.&nbsp; And, if anything, this war in Ukraine made them stronger.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I agree.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; If Putin ever thought that he could divide us, he failed.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question about that.</p>



<p>We stand together in condemning the invasion of Ukraine, on sanctioning Russia, and on helping Ukraine, as President Zelenskyy is asking us to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I have to tell you that in Italy and in Europe now, people want to put an end to this massacres &#8212; to these massacres, to this violence, this butchery that’s happening.&nbsp;&nbsp; And people think about what can we do to bring peace.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We certainly have to use any direct, indirec- &#8212; indirect channel of communication.&nbsp; But is that enough?&nbsp; What can we do?</p>



<p>People think that &#8212; at least they want to think about the possibility of bringing a ceasefire and starting again some credible negotiations.  That&#8217;s the situation right now.  I think that we have to think deeply on how to address this.  <br><br>We will continue, you and I, to work on energy security &#8212;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Yes, we will.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:  &#8212; food security, especially, which is now another issue there.  We&#8217;ll talk later about that, what to do. <br><br>And &#8212; and then, the other thing that I want to say, just at the opening &#8212; and then I don&#8217;t think we will discuss this later &#8212; but what happened in Ukraine is going to bring a drastic change in European Union. </p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I agree.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve always been close.&nbsp; Now we&#8217;re going to be much closer.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I know I can &#8212; I can count on your support as a true friend of Europe and of Italy, of course.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, Joe.&nbsp;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, look, and just one &#8212; I want to add one thing that.&nbsp; I believe that a strong European Union is in the interest of the United States.&nbsp; Granted, that&#8217;s competition, economically, but it&#8217;s good.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I joked when the Union was formally formed, saying this is like &#8212; we have a thing called the “Commerce Clause.”<br><br>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; You go from one state to the other &#8212;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; I remember.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; you don&#8217;t have to go through checkpoints.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s sort of Europe’s Commerce Clause.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; And it&#8217;s good for everyone.&nbsp; And the thing that I most appreciate about you is that our effort from the very beginning to bring NATO and the EU in lockstep &#8212; Putin really believed he could split us.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; And we got &#8212; we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve all stepped up.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But at any rate, I&#8217;m delighted you&#8217;re here, anxious to talk to you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And watch how they get out of here without getting hurt.&nbsp; They actually walk out of the room without knocking each other down.<br><br>2:08 P.M. EDT&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden on the&#160;Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/10/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-economy-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 18:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:58 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Today I’d like to talk about two potential paths forward to address the number-one challenge facing families today: inflation.&#160; This will not be my only speech on inflation, I’m sure.&#160; But when you look at the economy today, it’s clear that we’ve made enormous strides. And our plans&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:58 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Today I’d like to talk about two potential paths forward to address the number-one challenge facing families today: inflation.&nbsp;<br><br>This will not be my only speech on inflation, I’m sure.&nbsp; But when you look at the economy today, it’s clear that we’ve made enormous strides.<br><br>And our plans and our policies have produced the strongest job creation economy in modern times.&nbsp; In addition, 8.3 million jobs in my first 15 months in office &#8212; a record.<br><br>Unemployment rates are down to 3.6 percent &#8212; the fastest decline in unemployment to start a presidential term ever recorded.<br><br>And in addition, Americans have applied to start three- &#8212; 5.4 million new small businesses last year &#8212; 20 percent more than any other year on record.<br><br>And I see &#8212; and as I see it, everything &#8212; everything across the country is &#8212; as I go across the country, our economy has gone from being on the mend to on the move.<br><br>But for every worker I met who’s gained a little bit of breathing room to seek out a better-paying job, for every entrepreneur who’s gained the confidence to pursue their&nbsp;small-business dreams, I know that families all across America are hurting because of inflation.<br><br>I understand what it feels like.&nbsp; I come from a family where when the pr- &#8212; when the price of gas or food went up, we felt it.&nbsp; It was a discussion at the kitchen table.<br><br>I went &#8212; I want every American to know that I’m taking inflation very seriously and it’s my top domestic priority.<br><br>And I’m here today to talk about solutions.&nbsp; And there’s going to be more we’re going to have to talk about as well.<br><br>But first, I want us to be crystal clear about the problem.&nbsp;<br><br>There are two leading causes of inflation we’re seeing today.&nbsp; The first cause of inflation is a once-in-a-century pandemic.&nbsp; Not only did it shut down our global economy, it threw the supply chain and demand completely out of whack, especially in countries where more effective recovery responses weren&#8217;t available, especially in those sectors that rely on semiconductors.<br><br>These supply challenges have been further hampered by the onset of Delta and Omicron viruses.&nbsp; And you’ve all seen it and you’ve all felt it.&nbsp;<br><br>And this year we have a second cause &#8212; a second cause: Mr. Putin’s war in Ukraine.<br><br>You saw &#8212; we saw in March that 60 percent of inflation that month was due to price increases at the pump for gasoline.<br><br>Putin’s war has raised food prices as well, because Ukraine and Russia are two of the world’s major breadbaskets of &#8212; for wheat and corn &#8212; are, essentially, completely stalled.<br><br>Ukraine has 20 &#8212; 20 million tons of grain in storage in silos right now.&nbsp; They’re trying to figure out how to get it out of the country to market, which would reduce prices around the world.<br><br>Normally &#8212; normally, we’d have already begun to export them into the market.&nbsp; But it &#8212; but it hasn’t because of Putin’s invasion.<br><br>So we’re working with our European partners to get this food out into the world so that it could help bring down prices.&nbsp; But it’s difficult because, again, of Putin and the Russian invasion of Ukraine.<br><br>And those two major contributors to inflation are both global in nature.&nbsp; That’s why we’re seeing historic inflation in countries all over the world.<br><br>But here’s the good news: Because of the actions we’ve taken, America is in a stronger position to meet this challenge than just about any other country in the world.<br><br>Some of the roots of the inflation are outside of our control, to state the obvious.&nbsp; But there are things we can do and we can address and we need to do.<br><br>That starts with the Federal Reserve, which plays a primary role in fighting inflation in our country.<br><br>I’ve put forward a highly qua- &#8212; highly qualified nominees to lead that institution.&nbsp; And I strongly urge the Senate confirm them without delay.<br><br>The Fed has dual responsibilities.&nbsp; First is achieving maximum employment, and second is stable prices.<br><br>And while I’ll never interfere with the Fed’s judgments, decisions, or tell them what they have to do &#8212; they’re independent; they’re independent &#8212; I believe that inflation is our top economic challenge right now, and I think they do too.<br><br>I’ve built a strong ec- &#8212; we’ve built a strong economy with a strong job market.&nbsp; And I agree with what Chairman Powell said last week that the number-one threat is the strength &#8212; and that strength that we built is inflation.<br><br>So the Fed should do its job and it will do its job, I’m convinced, with that in mind.<br><br>Now, as I said when I came to &#8212; to what Congress and the President can do to fight inflation, Americans have two potential paths forward.&nbsp; The first is my plan, the Democratic plan.&nbsp; A plan put forward by congressional Republicans is a second alternative.<br><br>Here’s how each of us would tackle inflation:<br><br>My plan is to lower employer [sic] &#8212; lower everyday costs for &#8212; everyday costs for hardworking families and lower the deficit by asking large corporations and the wealthiest Americans to not engage in price gouging and to pay their fair share in taxes.<br><br>The Republican plan is to increase taxes on the middle-class families and let billionaires and large companies off the hook as they raise profit and &#8212; raise prices and reap profits at record number &#8212; record amounts.&nbsp;<br><br>And it’s really that simple.&nbsp;<br><br>But let me explain why this choice is so important.&nbsp; Let me start &#8212; let me start with the Putin price hike: high gas prices and energy prices.<br><br>My plan is already in motion.&nbsp; I led the world and other countries to join with us to coordinate the largest release of oil from our stockpiles of all the countries in history &#8212; 240 million barrels to boost global supply.<br><br>Here at home, U.S. oil and gas production is approaching record levels.&nbsp; In fact, we produced more oil domestically in my first year in office than my predecessor did in his first year.<br><br>To further drive down prices, my administration is allowing the sta- &#8212; the sale of gasoline using homegrown biofuels &#8212; biofuels this summer, which wasn’t allowed before.<br><br>And to reduce our dependence on foreign oil and reckless autocrats like Putin, I’m working with Congress to pass landmark investments to help build a clean energy future as well &#8212; from tax credits for businesses to produce renewable energy to tax credits for families to make their homes more energy efficient.<br><br>I met with nearly a dozen CEOs of America’s largest utility companies.&nbsp; And they, to a person, told me that &#8212; and including Southern Company, American Electric Power, and 10 others &#8212; they confirmed that if we pass the investments I’m talking about, it will immediately lower families’ utility bills by as much as $500 a year, according to one estimate.&nbsp; That’s &#8212; it’s going to make their homes more secure in terms of heat not getting out and air conditioning not escaping, because they have good insulation.<br><br>Now, what’s the congressional Republican plan with respect to energy?<br><br>First of all, their plan is to give oil companies a free pass.&nbsp; For example, right now, oil companies are sitting on 9,000 unused leases &#8212; oil leases &#8212; which are the property of the federal government &#8212; on the property of the federal government.<br><br>Under my plan, they would have to pay taxes and &#8212; if they don’t use those leases to produce more oil.&nbsp; They just can’t sit on it.<br><br>Unlike &#8212; under the Republican plan, they’d be allowed to continue to sit on this land without producing while shipping record profits back to their investors.<br><br>The fact is the average cost of a barrel of oil has been steady for weeks.&nbsp; So &#8212; so why do gas prices keep going up so high?<br><br>Republicans have offered plenty of blame but not a single solution to actually bring down the energy prices.<br><br>You know, we have no plan &#8212; they have no plan to bring down energy prices today; no plan to get us to a cleaner, energy-independent future tomorrow so, in the future, American families are no longer subject to the whims and &#8212; of dictators half a way around the world.<br><br>The next thing is: Let’s compare our plans when it comes to lowering everyday costs.&nbsp; My plan is to make concrete &#8212; concrete, commonsense steps to bring down the biggest expenses that families are facing.<br><br>Let’s take drug prices.&nbsp; My plan would let Medicare negotiate prices for prescription drugs, like they do with the &#8212; with the Department of &#8212; with the military as it relates to what the administration is able to negotiate for prices for military.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The cap &#8212; and I also call for a cap on the price of insulin, which 200 million &#8212; excuse me, I beg your pardon &#8212; 200,000 American children rely on because they have Type 2 diabetes, at $35 a month &#8212; it costs $10 to make the insulin; they make a significant profit &#8212; instead of the average price of about $640 a month.<br><br>Think of the difference it will make in millions of American families, like the family I met in Virginia about three weeks ago struggling every day, every single month to afford their son’s insulin.<br><br>On this and other issues, I’ve laid out specific proposals to Congress to bring down the cost of &#8212; everyday costs all American fam- &#8212; many American families face.<br><br>And that’s in addition to the work my administration has already done to lower prices.<br><br>Another reason why prices are up for products people need relates to whether or not the manufacturer has access to all the materials they need to build a product.<br><br>Think of the materials you need to build a house.&nbsp; If you can’t get materials from ship to shore, from the &#8212; from the shore to the home, the prices are going to go up.<br><br>That’s why we brought labor and industry together on the West Coast to improve operations at the ports to speed up the transfer of products from abroad to shore, from shore to the location where they’re going to be used so that those products can move more quickly and cheaply.<br><br>We haven’t had enough truckers, for example, to deliver the lumber or other goods.&nbsp; That’s why we’re executing a plan to get more truckers on the job.&nbsp; It reduces the time it takes to move the goods quickly.<br><br>Another problem we face is: In some industries, there’s just &#8212; there isn’t enough competition.&nbsp; And I’ve often said that capitalism without competition isn’t capitalism, it’s exploitation.&nbsp; So, we’re promoting competition for everything from Internet services to meat processing.<br><br>We basically have four meat processors in the whole country.&nbsp; They process the meat that goes into the hamburgers you buy, so they set the price.&nbsp; When there’s no competition, they can set the price higher and higher.&nbsp; So, we’re helping smaller companies get into the game to compete and help&nbsp;bring down the overall prices.<br><br>The bottom line is: Easing &#8212; easing these bottlenecks and making our supply chains more secure is a major focus of my economic strategy so things move more quickly, prices go down, not up.<br><br>You know, some parts of my plan I’ve been able to get done on my own &#8212; I mean, just without congressional approval.&nbsp; Some parts are being held up by Congress.&nbsp; But all of my plan is focused on lowering costs for the average family in America to give them just a little bit of breathing room.<br><br>Now, what’s the congressional Republican plan?<br><br>They don’t want to solve inflation by lowering your costs.&nbsp; They want to solve it by raising your taxes and lowering your income.<br><br>I happen to think it’s a good thing when American families have a little more money in their pockets at the end of the month.&nbsp; But Republicans in Congress don’t seem to think so.<br><br>Their plan has actually made working families &#8212; is going to make working families poorer.<br><br>You don’t have to take my word for it; it’s in writing.&nbsp;&nbsp; They’ve made their intentions perfectly clear.<br><br>Senator Rick Scott&nbsp;of&nbsp;<s>Wisconsin</s>&nbsp;[Florida], a member of the Senate Republican leadership, laid it all out in a plan.&nbsp; It’s the Ultra-MAGA Agenda.<br><br>Their plan is to raise taxes on 75 million American families, over 95 percent of whom make less than $100,000 a year, total income.&nbsp; The average tax increase would be about $1,500 per family.</p>



<p>They’ve got it backwards, in my view.&nbsp; I’ve proposed a minimum tax for billionaires.&nbsp; In recent years, the average billionaire has paid about 8 percent in federal taxes.<br><br>Congressional Republicans have proposed increasing taxes on teachers and firefighters.<br><br>Fifty-five&nbsp;<s>percent</s>&nbsp;of the largest corporations paid net zero in federal taxes in 2020 on $40&nbsp;<s>million</s>&nbsp;[billion] profits.<br><br>It just isn’t right.&nbsp; That’s why I’ve proposed a minimum tax for corporations.<br><br>Their plan would also raise taxes on 82 percent of small-business owners making less than $50,000 a year.&nbsp; But it would do nothing to help &#8212; to &#8212; to hold big co- &#8212; big corporations and companies accountable.&nbsp; Think about it.<br><br>Republicans in Congress are so deeply committed to protecting big corporations and CEOs that they would rather see taxes on working American families and try to depress their wages to take on inflation.<br><br>Never mind the fact that many of these companies are recording record profit margins, even as &#8212; as prices &#8212; as they raise prices records amounts.<br><br>Look, you’ve heard me say it before: I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; I’m not out to punish anybody.&nbsp; I have no problem with companies getting and generating reasonable profits.&nbsp; But in this moment of peril, with a war overseas and inflation surging around the world, the last thing we should be thinking about is rewarding companies for exploiting this situation.<br><br>While families struggle to pay their bills, some corporate &#8212; corporate executives are on earnings calls with investors on Wall Street, cheering their record profits and explaining how they’re using this period of inflation to cover the rise in prices far beyond what they need to do to cover their costs.&nbsp; And all this time, they’re not even paying for a fair share of taxes in the first place.<br><br>You want to bring down inflation?&nbsp; Let’s make sure the wealthiest corporations pay their fair share.<br><br>My plan asks those companies to pay their fair share in taxes.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The congressional Republican plan?&nbsp; Let them off scot-free.<br><br>And if&nbsp;<s>you</s>&nbsp;[it] weren’t extreme enough &#8212; the congressional Republican agenda &#8212; they put it in writing &#8212; it also calls on Congress to put special &#8212; excuse me &#8212; put Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid on the chopping block every five years.<br><br>Now, if I hadn’t seen it in writing, I’d think somebody is making this up.</p>



<p>But their proposal is: Every five years, all those programs would cease unless they’re re-voted &#8212; that the Congress comes along and says, “Yeah, we want to keep these plans,” affirmatively voting for them.</p>



<p>Well, imagine what &#8212; the changes that are going to take place then, man.&nbsp; Imagine all the bargaining that’s going to take place.&nbsp; “You Democrats want to maintain Social Security? &nbsp;You got give up such and such.”<br><br>Look, I want to give Medicare the power to negotiate drug prices, to make it stronger and lower your costs.<br><br>Republicans in&nbsp;Conre- [sic]&nbsp;want to make &#8212; in Congress want to put Medicare’s very existence up for a vote over and over again, along with Social Security and Medicaid.<br><br>Really, ask yourself: How well are we going to sleep at night knowing that every five years, MAGA Republicans &#8212; if they’re still the Republican &#8212; as I said, this is not your father’s Republican Party &#8212; if we’re going to have to vote on whether you will have Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid, and what amounts you’ll have in each of those programs?<br><br>You know what they’re likely to do?&nbsp; Use them as hostages every five years to get their way on other things.&nbsp; Think about it: “Give us another tax cut for billionaires, or Social Security gets it.”&nbsp; “Stop investing in clean energy, or you’re going to &#8212; or you’re going to &#8212; we’re going to kiss your Medicare goodbye.”&nbsp; It’s outrageous.&nbsp; It’s outrageous.<br><br>I can’t believe that the majority of Republicans buy on to Scott’s plan.&nbsp; But that’s a plan in writing, and he’s in the leadership.</p>



<p>Finally, let’s do one more comparison.&nbsp; Let’s compare our two&nbsp;plans when it comes to the deficit.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Republicans love to attack me as a big spender, as if that’s the reason why inflation has gone up.&nbsp; Let’s compare the facts.<br><br>Under my predecessor, the deficit exploded, raising &#8212; rising every single year under the Republicans.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Under my plan, we’re on track to cut the federal deficit by $1.5 trillion this year.&nbsp; Let me say it again: $1.5 trillion by the end of this fiscal year.&nbsp; The biggest one-year decline in all of history for America.&nbsp; And that’s in addition to last year we cut the budget $350 billion &#8212; the deficit, not the budget.&nbsp; The deficit: $350 billion.<br><br>My Treasury Department is planning to pay down the national debt this quarter, which never happened under my predecessor.&nbsp; Not once.&nbsp; Not once.<br><br>Because unlike my predecessor, the deficit has gone down both years I’ve been here.&nbsp; That is not an abstraction.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; It matters to families, because reducing the deficit is one of the main ways we can ease inflationary pressures.<br><br>Look, the bottom line is this: Americans have a choice right now between two paths, reflecting two very different sets of values.<br><br>My plan attacks inflation and grows the economy by lowering costs for working families, giving workers well-deserved raises, reducing the deficit by historic levels, and making big corporations and the very wealthiest Americans pay their fair share.<br><br>The other path is the ultra-MAGA plan put forward by congressional Republicans to raise taxes on working families; lower the incomes of American workers; threaten the sacred programs Americans count on like Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid; and give break after break to big corporations and billionaires &#8212; just like they did the last time they held power when their top priority was a reckless $2 trillion tax cut going &#8212; the majority of that going to the very wealthiest Americans, which ballooned the deficit, and not a penny of it was paid for.<br><br>Look, I know you’ve got to be frustrated.&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; I can taste it.&nbsp; Frustrated by high prices, by gridlock in Congress, by the time it takes to get anything done.<br><br>Believe me, I understand the frustration.&nbsp; But the fact is congressional Republicans &#8212; not all of them, but the MAGA Republicans &#8212; are counting on you to be as frustrated by the pace of progress, which they have everything &#8212; they’ve done everything they can to slow down &#8212; that you’re going to &#8212; will hand power over to them and enact &#8212; so they can enact their extreme agenda.<br><br>Look at their agenda.&nbsp; They put up on a webpage somewhere &#8212; I think I can do this &#8212; the “Scott Plan,” and it’s in writing.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We need a government focused on what families actually need.&nbsp; So I urge all Americans to think about the path I’ve laid forward.&nbsp; We’re going to have to do more beyond what I laid forward.&nbsp; But then, think about what the Republicans in Congress are actually proposing.&nbsp; Which path is right for you and your family and, quite frankly, for America?<br><br>Let’s build on the extraordinary process and progress we’ve made instead of tearing it down.&nbsp; Let’s focus on what matters.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>It &#8212; this really matters to average Americans.<br><br>I want to thank you all.&nbsp; God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; China tariffs?<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If you’re going to ask me about what I spoke about, I’ll try to &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, I have a question on tariffs.<br><br>Q &nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, why do you believe so many Americans believe that your administration is not doing enough to combat inflation?&nbsp; And do you believe that you and your administration bear some measure of responsibility for the inflation that we’re seeing across the country?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The first is, we’re in power.&nbsp; That’s the first thing.&nbsp; And you &#8212; justifiably right, we control all three branches of government.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Well, we don’t really.&nbsp; We have 50/50 in the Senate.&nbsp; You need 60 votes to get major things done.&nbsp; I’ve been pushing the things I’ve been proposing here, as you’ve heard me speak to today, since I got in office.&nbsp; And I have &#8212; I need to get 60 votes to be able to even pass them.&nbsp; Number one.<br><br>Number two, I think that, you know, it’s &#8212; they’re not focused.&nbsp; They’re &#8212; all they’re focused on, understandably, is the problem they’re facing.&nbsp; They get a 5 and a half percent raise &#8212; an average raise in their salaries, and yet inflation exceeds that.&nbsp; And they look around the world, and they know that a lot of it is extremely complicated.&nbsp; And so, they’re frustrated.&nbsp; And I don’t blame them.&nbsp; I really don’t blame them.<br><br>There’s a lot we have to do.&nbsp; And but &#8212; you know as well &#8212; I shouldn’t say “you.”&nbsp; I think what I have to do is explain in simple, straightforward language what’s going on.<br><br>Like, the reason why 30 percent of the inflation last year is because automobiles cost more.&nbsp; Why did they cost more?&nbsp; They couldn’t get the computer chips to make them.&nbsp; People are making a lot more money.&nbsp; They wanted to buy the automobiles.&nbsp; They couldn’t buy them because the costs went up so high because there were so few of them.&nbsp; The same way this year.&nbsp; The same way this year &#8212; the reason why prices are up.&nbsp;<br><br>They understand, but they don&#8217;t &#8212; they&#8217;re &#8212; look, most people &#8212; the vast majority of Americans are hoping that their government just takes care of the problem and they don&#8217;t have to think about it in detail at the kitchen table or at the dinner table.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s understandable no matter what their background.&nbsp;<br><br>But right now, it&#8217;s confusing.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a war in Ukraine.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re scratching their heads like, “What the heck is Russia doing?&nbsp; Should we be helping?”&nbsp; They think we should be helping the innocent Ukrainians.&nbsp; But what impact does that have?&nbsp; Do you think the average person, whether they have a PhD or they are &#8212; have any other job, sits and thinks, “Wow, there&#8217;s thousands of tons of grain in elevators in Ukraine that can&#8217;t get out”?&nbsp; And Ukraine is one of the biggest producers of corn and wheat.&nbsp; “Huh, I wonder whether that&#8217;s the reason my prices are up.”<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you take any responsibility for the inflation in this country?&nbsp; Do you take any responsibility &#8212; your policies?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think our policies help, not hurt.&nbsp; Think about what they say.&nbsp; The vast majority of the &#8212; of the &#8212; of the economists think that this is going to be a real tough problem to solve.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s not because of spending. &nbsp;We brought down the deficit.&nbsp;<br><br>The bottom line is: How much does America owe?&nbsp; How much in the hole are we going?&nbsp; We&#8217;re reducing that.&nbsp; So &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, today you have retail gasoline prices and diesel prices at record highs &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; yet you have yet to ask Americans to consume less.&nbsp; You&#8217;re a train guy.&nbsp; Have you ever thought of your administration asking Americans to drive less, to take public transport?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, if you ever raised a family like mine, you don&#8217;t have to tell them.&nbsp; They&#8217;re doing everything in their power to figure out how not to have to show up at the gas pump.&nbsp;<br><br>The vast &#8212; and that&#8217;s why &#8212; for example, one of the things that’s going to help a lot, which is going to take time, is our infrastructure bill.&nbsp; The truth is they don&#8217;t have that many options, in terms of transportation, around the country right now.&nbsp;<br><br>If you live in the Northeast Corridor you do.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re driving back and forth between Baltimore or Washington, New York, et cetera.&nbsp; But you don&#8217;t have many choices.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t have a whole lot of choices to deal with other aspects of transportation in terms of local transportation.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, what happens is &#8212; and unless they&#8217;re electric, we find theirselves &#8212; the cost of flying &#8212; getting &#8212; buying a ticket on a plane costs more because of gas prices.&nbsp;<br><br>So this is a process, but it&#8217;s a process that I&#8217;ve been consistent about: wanting to lower prices for &#8212; and shift to renewable energy so we&#8217;re not as dependent.&nbsp;<br><br>I have conversations almost every &#8212; well, that’s not &#8212; that’s an exaggeration &#8212; at least twice a week with one of my European counterparts, heads of state, on what &#8212; how can we help them, in fact, wean themselves off of Russian oil, because they&#8217;re so totally dependent.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we&#8217;re liken [sic] like &#8212; we’re working like the devil to help them transition.&nbsp; Because as long as Russia is able to make money selling oil, they&#8217;re going to continue to be able to do the bad things they&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;<br><br>So, there&#8217;s a lot.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really complicated.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not suggesting the American people can’t understand it.&nbsp; They understand it, but they have &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re working 8, 10 hours a day just to put food on the table.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I think what&#8217;s happened is we have &#8212; in a sense, I never expected &#8212; let me say &#8212; let me say this carefully: I never expected the Ultra-MAGA Republicans, who seem to control the Republican Party now, to have been able to control the Republican Party.&nbsp; I &#8212; I never anticipated that happening.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, a year ago, the administration was saying that inflation was transitory.&nbsp; That’s obviously not the case now.&nbsp; How long do you think it will be until we see prices coming down?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to predict that.&nbsp; It ranges depending on which economists you&#8217;re talking to. &nbsp;By the end of this year, and some say it’s going to be &#8212; it&#8217;s going to increase next year.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s others who say by the end of this year you&#8217;re going to see it come down &#8212; by the calendar year.&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t know, but I know what we have to do to make sure that we can bring it down.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you support any restrictions on abortion?&nbsp; Or what limits do you believe there should be, as the Senate is taking that up?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;I&#8217;m not going to respond to anything because I don&#8217;t want &#8212; I want this story to be about inflation.&nbsp; And I’ll talk about that &#8212;<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You called out Rick Scott &#8212; you called out Rick Scott a little while ago in your remarks.&nbsp; Earlier today, anticipating your remarks, he said &#8212; and I&#8217;m just quoting here &#8212; that the best thing &#8212; “the most effective thing Joe Biden can do to solve the inflation crisis he created is resign.&nbsp; He&#8217;s the problem.”&nbsp;&nbsp; The senator added later &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Resign?&nbsp; That’s a good idea.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The senator added later, “Joe Biden is unwell.&nbsp; He’s unfit for office.&nbsp; He’s incoherent, incapacitated, and confused.”&nbsp; These are his words.&nbsp; I&#8217;m offering you a chance to respond to that.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think the man has a problem.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you drop former President Trump’s China tariffs?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We&#8217;re discussing that right now.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking at what would have the most positive impact.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To lower them or to erase them?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I didn&#8217;t say that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m asking.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m telling you we&#8217;re discussing it, and no decision has been made on it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all very much.&nbsp; Appreciate it. &nbsp;Thank you.<br><br>12:28 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: S. 1226 and S.&#160;2126</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/05/10/bills-signed-s-1226-and-s-2126/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52867</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, May 10, 2022, the President signed into law: S. 1226, which designates the United States Courthouse located at 1501 North 6th Street in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, as the Sylvia H. Rambo United States Courthouse. Thank you to Senators Casey and Toomey and Representatives Perry, Wild, Fitzpatrick, Cartwright, Keller, and Reschenthaler for their leadership. S.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, May 10, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>S. 1226, which designates the United States Courthouse located at 1501 North 6th Street in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, as the Sylvia H. Rambo United States Courthouse.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Casey and Toomey and Representatives Perry, Wild, Fitzpatrick, Cartwright, Keller, and Reschenthaler for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 2126, which designates the Federal Office Building located at 308 W. 21st Street in Cheyenne, Wyoming, as the Louisa Swain Federal Office Building.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Lummis, Van Hollen, Cardin, and Barrasso for their leadership</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Media Advisory: Second COVID-&#8288;19&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/media-advisory-second-covid-19-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States as first COVID Summit Chair, Belize, as CARICOM Chair; Germany, holding the G7 Presidency; Indonesia, holding the G20 Presidency; and Senegal as African Union Chair, will co-host the second Global COVID-19 Summit, which will be held virtually on Thursday, May 12, 2022. We will be joined by countries, other partners, non-governmental organizations,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States as first COVID Summit Chair, Belize, as CARICOM Chair; Germany, holding the G7 Presidency; Indonesia, holding the G20 Presidency; and Senegal as African Union Chair, will co-host the second Global COVID-19 Summit, which will be held virtually on Thursday, May 12, 2022.<br><br>We will be joined by countries, other partners, non-governmental organizations, and private sector companies who have made financial or policy commitments. Some of those will include South Africa; Canada; Japan; India; Colombia; Republic of Korea; Italy; New Zealand; European Commission; Spain, Nigeria; Norway; Palau; Tanzania; Rwanda; Wellcome; Google; FIND, the global alliance for diagnostics; Rotary International; the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations; Clinton Health Access Initiative; Open Society Foundations; the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation; Gavi, The Vaccine Alliance; and the Mastercard Foundation. In addition, international and regional organizations will participate, such as the World Health Organization, World Bank Group; the World Trade Organization; the African Centres for Disease Control and Prevention; and the Caribbean Public Health Agency. We will share more about additional participants closer to the Summit. <br><br>Together, the Summit will redouble our efforts made at the first COVID Summit and will focus on four key objectives: </p>



<ul><li><strong>Recommitting Intensity to Global Response.</strong> The pandemic is not over, and now is the time to prepare for the next one.  The Summit will focus on securing new resources and policy commitments to control COVID-19 in 2022. </li><li><strong>Vaccinating the World. </strong>Vaccination remains the most important lifesaving tool in this pandemic. It is also the most effective means to fight emerging variants. This is true for the broad population, and particularly true for the most vulnerable. And it means focusing on both the quantity of vaccinations, but also the quality – including providing effective boosters.</li><li><strong>Protecting the Most Vulnerable.  </strong>The Summit will focus on getting vaccines, tests, and treatments to those at highest risk, like the elderly, the immunocompromised and frontline and health workers.</li><li><strong>Preventing future catastrophes.  </strong>By investing <em>now</em> to secure political commitment for pandemic preparedness globally.  The Summit will focus on expanding and financing country capacity, health workers, disease surveillance, and medical countermeasures, including through the new pandemic preparedness and global health security fund at the World Bank. </li></ul>



<p>President Biden and fellow heads of state from the co-host nations will kick off the Summit with remarks on how fighting COVID-19 must remain an international priority. The Summit will then feature three sessions focused on getting shots in arms, expanding access to tests and treatments, and advancing health security and preventing future catastrophes.&nbsp;&nbsp;Ahead of the Summit, the U.S. called on the leaders of governments, civil society, businesses, and philanthropies to make significant new commitments.<br>To date, President has committed to sharing 1.2 billion doses of safe, effective vaccines with the world, and the U.S. has made good on that commitment. The U.S. has shipped over 530 million doses of vaccine to 115 countries around the world, over four times more than our next closest donor. And the U.S. has sent them for free with no strings attached.</p>



<p>The Summit builds the U.S.’s steadfast leadership in the global COVID-19 response and our efforts to engage with the world to do their part to end this acute phase of the pandemic and prepare for future threats. It also reflects the Biden-Harris Administration’s work to continue to push the global response forward, including by securing funding from Congress, because the virus is not waiting for Congress to act. It’s critical for Congress to act with the urgency that a once-in-a-generation pandemic warrants.  </p>



<p>The U.S. and the co-host nations look forward to another successful Summit to accelerate the international response to combat COVID-19 and to advance global pandemic preparedness.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">You can join us for the Second COVID-19 Summit by tuning in here starting at 9 AM ET: WH.GOV/Live</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
