<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:42:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by Senior Advisor and Chief Spokesperson Symone Sanders on Vice President Kamala Harris’s Calls with Foreign Leaders on the Global Allocation Plan for the First 25 Million Doses of COVID-19 Vaccines</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-senior-advisor-and-chief-spokesperson-symone-sanders-on-vice-president-kamala-harriss-calls-with-foreign-leaders-on-the-global-allocation-plan-for-the-first-25-million-doses-of-c/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala D. Harris spoke this morning to President Andres Manuel López Obrador of Mexico, President Alejandro Giammattei of Guatemala, Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India, and Prime Minister Keith Rowley, Chairman of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM). In four separate calls, the Vice President notified each of the leaders that the Biden-Harris Administration will begin&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala D. Harris spoke this morning to President Andres Manuel López Obrador of Mexico, President Alejandro Giammattei of Guatemala, Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India, and Prime Minister Keith Rowley, Chairman of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM). In four separate calls, the Vice President notified each of the leaders that the Biden-Harris Administration will begin sharing the first 25 million doses of COVID vaccines to their respective countries and others, as part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s framework for sharing at least 80 million vaccines globally by the end of June.<br><br>The Vice President reiterated that the Administration’s efforts are focused on achieving broad global coverage, responding to surges and other urgent situations and public health needs, and helping as many countries as possible who requested vaccines. The four leaders thanked the Vice President, and they agreed to continue working together to address COVID-19 and advance our mutual interests around the world.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on Addressing the Threat from Securities Investments that Finance Certain Companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-addressing-the-threat-from-securities-investments-that-finance-certain-companies-of-the-peoples-republic-of-c/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC). I have determined that additional steps are necessary to address the national emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC).<br><br>I have determined that additional steps are necessary to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 of November 12, 2020 (Addressing the Threat From Securities Investments That Finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), including the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the PRC and its involvement in military, intelligence, and security research and development programs, and weapons and related equipment production under the PRC&#8217;s Military-Civil Fusion strategy.  In addition, I find that the use of Chinese surveillance technology outside the PRC and the development or use of Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuse, constitute unusual and extraordinary threats, which have their source in whole or substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States, and I hereby expand the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 to address those threats. <br><br>I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.<br>    </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">     Sincerely,<br><br>                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Addressing the Threat from Securities Investments that Finance Certain Companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/03/executive-order-on-addressing-the-threat-from-securities-investments-that-finance-certain-companies-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.) (NEA), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq</em>.) (NEA), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code,</p>



<p>I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, find that additional steps are necessary to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 of November 12, 2020 (Addressing the Threat From Securities Investments That Finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), including the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC) and its involvement in military, intelligence, and security research and development programs, and weapons and related equipment production under the PRC&#8217;s Military-Civil Fusion strategy. &nbsp;In addition, I find that the use of Chinese surveillance technology outside the PRC and the development or use of Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuse constitute unusual and extraordinary threats, which have their source in whole or substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States, and I hereby expand the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 to address those threats.</p>



<p>Accordingly, I hereby order as follows:</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">1.</span>  Sections 1 through 5 of Executive Order 13959, as amended by Executive Order 13974 of January 13, 2021 (Amending Executive Order 13959 &#8212; Addressing the Threat From Securities Investments That Finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), are hereby replaced and superseded in their entirety to read as follows:</p>



<p>&#8220;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Section</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">1.</span> (a) The following activities by a United States person are prohibited: the purchase or sale of any publicly traded securities, or any publicly traded securities that are derivative of such securities or are designed to provide investment exposure to such securities, of any person listed in the Annex to this order or of any person determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and, as the Secretary of the Treasury deems appropriate, the Secretary of Defense:<br>          (i)   to operate or have operated in the defense and related materiel sector or the surveillance technology sector of the economy of the PRC; or<br>          (ii) to own or control, or to be owned or controlled by, directly or indirectly, a person who operates or has operated in any sector described in subsection (a)(i) of this section, or a person who is listed in the Annex to this order or who has otherwise been determined to be subject to the prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section.<br>     (b)  The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section shall take effect:<br>          (i)   beginning at 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 2, 2021, with respect to any person listed in the Annex to this order; <br>or<br>          (ii)  beginning at 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on the date that is 60 days after the date of the determination in subsection (a) of this section with respect to any person not listed in the Annex to this order.<br>     (c)  The purchase or sale of publicly traded securities described in subsection (a) of this section made solely to effect the divestment, in whole or in part, of such securities by a United States person is permitted prior to:<br>          (i)   12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 3, 2022, with respect to any person listed in the Annex to this order; or<br>          (ii)  12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on the date that is 365 days after the date of the determination in subsection (a) of this section with respect to any person not listed in the Annex to this order.<br>     (d)  The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or any license or permit granted before the date of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">2.</span>  (a)  Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.<br>     (b)  Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">3.</span>  For the purposes of this order:<br>     (a)  the term &#8220;entity&#8221; means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;<br>     (b)  the term &#8220;person&#8221; means an individual or entity;<br>     (c)  the term &#8220;publicly traded securities&#8221; includes any &#8220;security,&#8221; as defined in section 3(a)(10) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, Public Law 73–291 (as codified as amended at 15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(10)), denominated in any currency that trades on a securities exchange or through the method of trading that is commonly referred to as &#8220;over-the-counter,&#8221; in any jurisdiction; and<br>     (d)  the term &#8220;United States person&#8221; means any United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">4.</span>  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order.  The Secretary of the Treasury may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury.  All executive departments and agencies (agencies) of the United States shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to carry out the provisions of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">5.</span>  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to submit recurring and final reports to the Congress on the national emergency declared in this order, consistent with section 401(c) of the NEA (50 U.S.C. 1641(c)) and section 204(c) of IEEPA (50 U.S.C. 1703(c)).</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">6.</span>  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and, as the Secretary of the Treasury deems appropriate, the Secretary of Defense, is hereby authorized to determine that circumstances no longer warrant the application of the prohibitions in section 1(a) of this order with respect to a person listed in the Annex to this order, and to take necessary action to give effect to that determination.&#8221;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">2.</span>  The Annex to Executive Order 13959 is replaced and superseded in its entirety by the Annex to this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">3.</span>  Section 6 of Executive Order 13959 is amended to replace &#8220;Sec. 6.&#8221; with &#8220;Sec. 7.&#8221;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">4.</span>  Executive Order 13974 is hereby revoked in its entirety.  The Secretary of the Treasury and the heads of agencies shall take all necessary steps to rescind any orders or prohibitions issued prior to the date of this order implementing or enforcing Executive Order 13974 or the versions of sections 1 through 5 of Executive Order 13959 replaced and superseded by section 1 of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">5.</span>  (a)  Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>     (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>     (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>          (b)  This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>          (c)  This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">  <br>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>   June 3, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><span style="text-decoration: underline">Annex</span><br>AERO ENGINE CORPORATION OF CHINA<br><br>AEROSPACE CH UAV CO., LTD<br><br>AEROSPACE COMMUNICATIONS HOLDINGS GROUP COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AEROSUN CORPORATION<br><br>ANHUI GREATWALL MILITARY INDUSTRY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIATION INDUSTRY CORPORATION OF CHINA, LTD.<br><br>AVIC AVIATION HIGH-TECHNOLOGY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIC HEAVY MACHINERY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIC JONHON OPTRONIC TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>AVIC SHENYANG AIRCRAFT COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIC XI&#8217;AN AIRCRAFT INDUSTRY GROUP COMPANY LTD.<br><br>CHANGSHA JINGJIA MICROELECTRONICS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA ACADEMY OF LAUNCH VEHICLE TECHNOLOGY<br><br>CHINA AEROSPACE SCIENCE AND INDUSTRY CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA AEROSPACE SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA AEROSPACE TIMES ELECTRONICS CO., LTD<br><br>CHINA AVIONICS SYSTEMS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA COMMUNICATIONS CONSTRUCTION COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA COMMUNICATIONS CONSTRUCTION GROUP (LIMITED)<br><br>CHINA ELECTRONICS CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA ELECTRONICS TECHNOLOGY GROUP CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA GENERAL NUCLEAR POWER CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA MARINE INFORMATION ELECTRONICS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>CHINA MOBILE LIMITED<br><br>CHINA NATIONAL NUCLEAR CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA NATIONAL OFFSHORE OIL CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA NORTH INDUSTRIES GROUP CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA NUCLEAR ENGINEERING CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA RAILWAY CONSTRUCTION CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA SATELLITE COMMUNICATIONS CO., LTD.<br><br>CHINA SHIPBUILDING INDUSTRY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA SHIPBUILDING INDUSTRY GROUP POWER COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA SOUTH INDUSTRIES GROUP CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA SPACESAT CO., LTD.<br><br>CHINA STATE SHIPBUILDING CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA TELECOM CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA TELECOMMUNICATIONS CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA UNICOM (HONG KONG) LIMITED<br><br>CHINA UNITED NETWORK COMMUNICATIONS GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>CNOOC LIMITED<br><br>COSTAR GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>CSSC OFFSHORE &amp; MARINE ENGINEERING (GROUP) COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>FUJIAN TORCH ELECTRON TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>GUIZHOU SPACE APPLIANCE CO., LTD<br><br>HANGZHOU HIKVISION DIGITAL TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>HUAWEI INVESTMENT &amp; HOLDING CO., LTD.<br><br>HUAWEI TECHNOLOGIES CO., LTD.<br><br>INNER MONGOLIA FIRST MACHINERY GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>INSPUR GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>JIANGXI HONGDU AVIATION INDUSTRY CO., LTD.<br><br>NANJING PANDA ELECTRONICS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>NORTH NAVIGATION CONTROL TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>PANDA ELECTRONICS GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>PROVEN GLORY CAPITAL LIMITED<br><br>PROVEN HONOUR CAPITAL LIMITED<br><br>SEMICONDUCTOR MANUFACTURING INTERNATIONAL CORPORATION<br><br>SHAANXI ZHONGTIAN ROCKET TECHNOLOGY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>ZHONGHANG ELECTRONIC MEASURING INSTRUMENTS COMPANY LIMITED</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Executive Order Addressing the Threat from Securities Investments that Finance Certain Companies of the People’s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/fact-sheet-executive-order-addressing-the-threat-from-securities-investments-that-finance-certain-companies-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 17:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to further address the ongoing national emergency declared in E.O. 13959 of November 12, 2020 with respect to the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the People’s Republic of China (PRC). President Biden also expanded the scope of this national emergency by finding that the use&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to further address the ongoing national emergency declared in E.O. 13959 of November 12, 2020 with respect to the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the People’s Republic of China (PRC). President Biden also expanded the scope of this national emergency by finding that the use of Chinese surveillance technology outside the PRC, as well as the development or use of Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuses, constitute unusual and extraordinary threats. This E.O. allows the United States to prohibit – in a targeted and scoped manner – U.S. investments in Chinese companies that undermine the security or democratic values of the United States and our allies.<br><br>Specifically, the E.O. the President is signing today will:<br><br><strong>Solidify and strengthen a previous E.O to prohibit U.S. investments in the military-industrial complex of the People’s Republic of China:&nbsp;</strong>This E.O. will amend E.O. 13959 by creating a sustainable and strengthened framework for imposing prohibitions on investments in Chinese defense and surveillance technology firms. The E.O. prohibits United States persons from engaging in the purchase or sale of any publicly traded securities of any person listed in the Annex to the E.O. or determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and, as the Secretary of the Treasury deems appropriate, the Secretary of Defense:</p>



<ul><li>To operate or have operated in the defense and related materiel sector or the surveillance technology sector of the economy of the PRC; or</li><li>To own or control, or to be owned or controlled by, directly or indirectly, a person who operates or has operated in any sector described above, or a person who is listed in the Annex to this E.O. or who has otherwise been determined to be subject to the prohibitions in this E.O.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ensure that U.S. investments are not supporting Chinese companies that undermine the security or values of the United States and our allies</strong>: This E.O. prevents U.S. investment from supporting the Chinese defense sector, while also expanding the U.S. Government’s ability to address the threat of Chinese surveillance technology firms that contribute — both inside and outside China — to the surveillance of religious or ethnic minorities or otherwise facilitate repression and serious human rights abuses. It signals that the Administration will not hesitate to prevent U.S. capital from flowing into the PRC’s defense and related materiel sector, including companies that support the PRC’s military, intelligence, and other security research and development programs; or into Chinese companies that develop or use Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuse.&nbsp; Tackling these challenges head-on is consistent with the Biden Administration’s commitment to protecting core U.S. national security interests and democratic values, and the Administration will continue to update the list of PRC entities as appropriate.&nbsp; At the same time, the E.O.’s prohibitions are intentionally targeted and scoped.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>The President listed the following 59 entities as subject to the E.O.’s prohibitions. </strong>The prohibitions against the entities listed in the Annex to this E.O. shall take effect beginning at 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 2, 2021. The U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) will also list these 59 entities on its new Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List (NS-CMIC List).<br><br><strong><em><u>Defense and Related Materiel Sector of the Economy of the PRC</u></em></strong><strong><em>:</em></strong><br>Aero Engine Corporation of China; Aerospace CH UAV Co., Ltd; Aerospace Communications Holdings Group Company Limited; Aerosun Corporation; Anhui Greatwall Military Industry Company Limited; Aviation Industry Corporation of China, Ltd.; AVIC Aviation High-Technology Company Limited; AVIC Heavy Machinery Company Limited; AVIC Jonhon Optronic Technology Co., Ltd.; AVIC Shenyang Aircraft Company Limited; AVIC Xi’An Aircraft Industry Group Company Ltd.; Changsha Jingjia Microelectronics Company Limited China Academy of Launch Vehicle Technology; China Aerospace Science and Industry Corporation Limited; China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation; China Aerospace Times Electronics Co., Ltd; China Avionics Systems Company Limited; China Communications Construction Company Limited; China Electronics Technology Group Corporation; China General Nuclear Power Corporation; China Marine Information Electronics Company Limited; China Mobile Communications Group Co., Ltd.; China National Nuclear Corporation; China National Offshore Oil Corporation; China North Industries Group Corporation Limited; China Nuclear Engineering Corporation Limited; China Railway Construction Corporation Limited; China Satellite Communications Co., Ltd.; China Shipbuilding Industry Company Limited; China Shipbuilding Industry Group Power Company Limited; China South Industries Group Corporation; China Spacesat Co., Ltd.; China State Shipbuilding Corporation Limited; China Telecommunications Corporation; China United Network Communications Group Co., Ltd.; Costar Group Co., Ltd.; CSSC Offshore &amp; Marine Engineering (Group) Company Limited; Fujian Torch Electron Technology Co., Ltd.; Guizhou Space Appliance Co., Ltd; Hangzhou Hikvision Digital Technology Co., Ltd.; Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd.; Inner Mongolia First Machinery Group Co., Ltd.; Inspur Group Co., Ltd.; Jiangxi Hongdu Aviation Industry Co., Ltd.; Nanjing Panda Electronics Company Limited; North Navigation Control Technology Co., Ltd.; Panda Electronics Group Co., Ltd.; Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corporation; Shaanxi Zhongtian Rocket Technology Company Limited; and Zhonghang Electronic Measuring Instruments Company Limited.&nbsp;<br><br><strong><em><u>Surveillance Technology Sector of the Economy of the PRC</u></em></strong><strong><em>:</em></strong><br>Hangzhou Hikvision Digital Technology Co., Ltd. and Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd.<br><br><strong><em><u>Own or Control, or Owned or Controlled by, Directly or Indirectly, a Person Who Operates or Has Operated in at Least One of These Two Sectors of the PRC Economy, or a Person Who Is Listed in the Annex to the E.O.:</u></em></strong><br>China Communications Construction Group (Limited); China Electronics Corporation; China Mobile Limited; China Telecom Corporation Limited; China Unicom (Hong Kong) Limited; CNOOC Limited; Huawei Investment &amp; Holding Co., Ltd.; Panda Electronics Group Co., Ltd.; Proven Glory Capital Limited; and Proven Honour Capital Limited.<br><br>For information concerning the process for seeking removal from any OFAC list, including the NS-CMIC List, please refer to OFAC’s Frequently Asked Question 897 at <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/faqs/897">https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/faqs/897</a>.&nbsp; Additional information regarding sanctions programs administered by OFAC can be found at <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/sanctions-programs-and-country-information">https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/sanctions-programs-and-country-information</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Israeli Minister of Defense Benjamin Gantz</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-israeli-minister-of-defense-benjamin-gantz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Israeli Minister of Defense Benjamin “Benny” Gantz to discuss recent developments in the region and continue the consultations between the United States and Israel on regional security issues. Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s right to defend itself and commitment to strengthening all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Israeli Minister of Defense Benjamin “Benny” Gantz to discuss recent developments in the region and continue the consultations between the United States and Israel on regional security issues. Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s right to defend itself and commitment to strengthening all aspects of the U.S.-Israel security partnership, including support for the Iron Dome System. They exchanged views on the current situation in Gaza and Mr. Sullivan highlighted the importance of ensuring that immediate humanitarian aid is able to reach the people of Gaza. They also discussed their common interest in steps to enhance stability, peace, and security not just for Israelis and Palestinians, but across the entire region. They shared their concerns about the threat posed by Iran’s aggressive behavior in the Middle East and expressed their determination to counter these threats. They agreed that the United States and Israel would remain closely engaged in the weeks ahead to advance their strategic priorities in the region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Fight Against Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/03/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-fight-against-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 8:47 A.M. EDT&#160;MODERATOR: Good morning, everyone, from the National Security Council at the White House. I would like to welcome our participants to an on-background conference call to discuss a forthcoming announcement by the White House related to the fight against corruption.&#160;Today we are joined by [senior administration official], as well as [senior&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>8:47 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR: Good morning, everyone, from the National Security Council at the White House. I would like to welcome our participants to an on-background conference call to discuss a forthcoming announcement by the White House related to the fight against corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today we are joined by [senior administration official], as well as [senior administration official]. We will begin with remarks from [senior administration official], and then we&#8217;ll open it up for a question-and-answer session.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a reminder, today&#8217;s briefing is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.” And the call content and the factsheet that we have not circulated yet but we will circulate at the conclusion of the call will be embargoed until they&#8217;re released by the White House later today.<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I will turn it over to our senior administration official for introductory remarks.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Great. Thanks. Hi, everybody. Good morning and thanks for joining the call today. I am really excited to be speaking to all of you about the President&#8217;s anti-corruption agenda in advance of our rollout later this morning of a national security study memorandum &#8212; that&#8217;s NSSM &#8212; on the fight against corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s worth noting that this is the first national security study memorandum of the administration, so it&#8217;ll come out as “NSM-1.” I don&#8217;t want to get hung up on the bureaucratic language of all of that, but the point is the memorandum is important because it&#8217;ll serve as formal and public direction from President Biden that he expects all relevant federal departments and agencies to up their anti-corruption game in very specific ways. And when you see the NSSM yourselves, you&#8217;ll see the specificity in the document itself.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, with the memorandum, President Biden is formally establishing the fight against corruption as a core national security interest of the United States. That was a commitment that he made during the campaign. And his pledge was that he would prioritize anti-corruption efforts and bring additional transparency to the U.S. and international financial systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that&#8217;s what we are embarked on, and the memorandum also speaks to our focus on delivering a foreign policy that benefits the American people, and particularly the middle class.<br>&nbsp;<br>So what the NSSM does is it directs the U.S. government to review and send to President Biden a report and recommendations in 200 days on how the government and its partners can modernize, coordinate, and further resource efforts to better fight corruption, tackle illicit finance, hold corrupt actors accountable, and build international partnerships. So it&#8217;s really the broadest span of what each of our federal departments and agencies does on anti-corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re really confident that implementation of this directive is going to lead to new and bold and decisive actions to combat corruption around the world. It, of course, builds upon much that we&#8217;re already doing &#8212; and I&#8217;m happy to speak to some of that agenda right now &#8212; but this is very much going to accelerate and prioritize that agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, with that, why don&#8217;t I leave it there and we&#8217;ll take a few questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Hi, guys. Thank you for doing this. I just &#8212; my first question is simply, you know, can you talk a little bit about some of the existing efforts under the Biden administration at the various agencies to make corruption a priority? Because I know this has sort of been in the works for a while, so it&#8217;s not like they&#8217;re starting from scratch.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah, thanks for that. So, that’s exactly right. We are very much hitting the ground running on this agenda, so let me just kind of give a few wave tops in terms what different departments and agencies are already doing that we expect to elevate with the NSSM today.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, some on the line may be familiar with the Corporate Transparency Act &#8212; that’s the law that Congress passed in last year’s National Defense Authorization Act that directs the Treasury Department to establish what’s called a “beneficial ownership registry” that effectively bars illicit assets from hiding the proceedings of corruption behind anonymous shell companies. So, Treasury is moving out on making that registry a reality. It&#8217;s a massive undertaking.<br>&nbsp;<br>And among other things, in his budget request, the President asked Congress to increase funding for this work by roughly 50 percent &#8212; 60-odd million dollars above what was enacted last year. So that really gave an early preview of how we&#8217;re looking to transform what Treasury does in terms of making sure that law enforcement is able to view the proceeds of corruption such that illicit actors can&#8217;t hide behind anonymity.<br>&nbsp;<br>Likewise, Treasury is building off of what&#8217;s already been done to limit the ability of illicit actors to hide behind anonymity. In terms of residential real estate, we have seen several instances over past years in which the proceeds of corruption have been funneled through shell companies and wound up in major metropolitan areas in the United States to offshore those ill-gotten gains, and so we&#8217;re going to be taking additional steps to make sure that that doesn&#8217;t happen in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>And across the board, we&#8217;re looking at analyzing the need for additional reforms to close loopholes in the entire regulatory regime that deals with corruption and illicit finance.<br>&nbsp;<br>On the Department of Justice side, some may be familiar with their Kleptocracy Asset Recovery Initiative. This initiative has really helped to make the United States a global leader in terms of recovery and return of stolen assets. In the &#8212; in the past two years, since 2019 alone, these asset recovery efforts have led to the transfer of more than $1.5 billion to countries that have been harmed by corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, on the State and USAID side, I think you&#8217;ve already seen significant statements by Secretary Blinken and Administrator Power on increasing their anti-corruption work. Stay tuned. I think there are going to be more announcements out of USAID soon, but we&#8217;re looking across the board to elevate our anti-corruption work in all of our bilateral context, as well as in multilateral fora, such as the G7 and United Nations.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that’s a little taste of, across departments, what we expect to be working on or accelerating ongoing work in the months to come.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you for taking the time. You know, the previous administration took something of a hands-off approach with corruption or with &#8212; would have them &#8212; you know, a transactional relationship, where they would essentially say, “We won’t worry about what&#8217;s going on in your country if you will work with us on these things that we need to work on.” And I&#8217;m wondering if, in any sense, this is meant to send a signal to the world that the U.S. does care about corruption again. Is there any, sort of, like, response to the past in this?<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, ahead of Vice President Harris&#8217;s trip to Latin America, are there any corruption measures associated with that, or any, sort of, additional push related to that?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: I&#8217;m not going to characterize the views of the prior administration, but I would say, to your point: The essence of the memorandum we&#8217;re going to release today is that the U.S. government is placing the anti-corruption plight at the center of its foreign policy, so we very much want to prioritize this work across the board.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the Vice President&#8217;s trip, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any announcements that are going to be made on the trip, but I can say that anti-corruption in the region is a major focus for the administration and will be a focus of all of her conversations while she&#8217;s traveling.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for doing this. As you know, anti-corruption activists periodically urge the U.S. government to use its various assets and capabilities, including the intelligence community, to expose specific cases of corruption overseas, to name and shame corrupt officials &#8212; and the arguments they make are familiar &#8212; but also include not only, you know, a deterrent to corruption, but also a possible contribution to the promotion of democracy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Does the does the memorandum &#8212; does the program include any component that connects with that?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;What I can say on that front is that the memorandum includes components of the intelligence community. So, the work on that front, in part, remains to be seen, but they are included &#8212; the Director of National Intelligence and Central Intelligence Agency.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so we&#8217;re just going to be looking at all of the tools in our disposal to make sure that we identify corruption where it&#8217;s happening and take appropriate policy responses.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;ll take the opportunity to mention that we&#8217;re also going to be using this effort to think about what more we can do to bolster other actors that are out in the world exposing corruption and bringing it to light.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, of course, the U.S. government has its own internal methods, but, largely, the way that corruption is exposed is through the work of investigative journalists and investigative NGOs.<br>&nbsp;<br>The U.S. government &#8212; to my point earlier, in terms of the support we&#8217;re already providing &#8212; in some instances provides support to these actors. And we&#8217;ll be looking at what more we can do on that front as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does the word “support” mean in that context?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Well, sometimes it boils down to foreign assistance. There are lines of assistance that have jumpstarted investigatory journalism organizations. What comes to my mind most immediately is OCCRP, as well as foreign assistance that goes to NGOs, ultimately, that do investigative work on anti-corruption, as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, good morning. Thank you for doing this. My question is to ask you: How are you going to engage with international allies to combat the impact of corruption coming from Latin American countries into the United States? For example, Venezuela or the Northern Triangle, as my colleague mentioned before. Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;So, as I mentioned earlier, the anti-corruption agenda will be front and center in the Vice President&#8217;s upcoming trip. And, across the board, we are engaging through every relevant multilateral body on this agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>And much of that &#8212; again, we&#8217;re not we&#8217;re not necessarily creating any of that work from scratch, but we are hoping to accelerate and elevate it, and that includes in the Western Hemisphere. But maybe [senior administration official] wants to jump in and say a little bit more on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thanks. You know, I think the general &#8212; underscoring what [senior administration official] just said &#8212; you know, working closely with our allies and partners includes engaging with civil society and investigative journalists, but also through our multinational and multilateral partnerships in the G7 and G20.<br>&nbsp;<br>This has been a big focus as well for the UK during their G7 presidency, to focus on working together on combating corruption. And so we have started those processes already, and I think you will see a lot more, particularly in our own backyard in the Western Hemisphere.<br>&nbsp;<br>A big indication is the Vice President&#8217;s trip &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s her first international trip. She&#8217;ll be going out there and discussing these issues. And as [senior administration official] mentioned earlier, anticorruption will be a key part of her trip there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi. So, [senior administration official], in your intro and in a couple of answers, you’ve referred to “illicit finance” and the danger of people profiting from corruption and being able to hide those profits through anonymity. Are you talking here about cryptocurrency? And if so, is this part of a larger discussion?<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, we&#8217;ve seen the use of cryptocurrency, the risk of cryptocurrency for illicit purposes in the ransomware attacks, for example. And there are certainly growing calls now for the administration to crack down on cryptocurrency and its use in illegal means. Is that what you meant to refer to, and is that where this is going?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah, thanks. We&#8217;ll certainly be looking at the impact of cryptocurrency as a means of illicit finance, but by no means was &#8212; were my remarks limited to crypto. We&#8217;ve seen, over many years, how corruption oversea- &#8212; the proceeds of corruption overseas make their way into the U.S. and international financial systems through anonymity.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this isn&#8217;t in any way limited to new technologies like crypto, but certainly as we think about the regulatory regime &#8212; the Bank Secrecy Act that governs much of this agenda, in terms of illicit finance &#8212; we will be asking for ideas around how we might want to modernize that regime to deal with issues like crypto, certainly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good morning and thanks for doing this. I want –- I think, as you mentioned, this is the first memorandum that we saw before sanctions against corruption yesterday. And there were sanctions against Bulgarian individuals. But also, we know that bad actors were able to survive despite sanctions everywhere, whether they are U.S. sanctions or, let’s say, international sanctions. Now, what tools are you planning to use? And let’s say you are using sanctions again &#8212; how you would use the sanctions as a tool without affecting an entire (inaudible) population? Let&#8217;s say, I give you an example here: Lebanon, let’s say.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Sure, thanks for that. So, this effort is really going to be across the board. And so, thinking about how we can better use sanctions to address corruption is definitely going to be part of the toolkit that we seek to emphasize. But sanctions are not the only tool in our toolkit.<br>&nbsp;<br>As I&#8217;ve been speaking to, we&#8217;re looking to make significant systemic changes to the regulatory structure that governs illicit finance. We&#8217;re looking to increase the use of law enforcement tools to go after corrupt actors. We&#8217;re looking to improve upon U.S. foreign assistance as a tool and increase the role that anticorruption plays in our day-to-day diplomatic work in bilateral engagements, in multilateral fora.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thinking about how sanctions are going to impact our anti-corruption agenda will be part of this conversation, but in no way will it be limited to sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>9:07 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Global Vaccine Distribution</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-global-vaccine-distribution/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 15:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the United States continues our efforts to get every eligible American vaccinated and fight COVID-19 here at home, we also recognize that ending this pandemic means ending it everywhere. As long as this pandemic is raging anywhere in the world, the American people will still be vulnerable. And the United States is committed to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As the United States continues our efforts to get every eligible American vaccinated and fight COVID-19 here at home, we also recognize that ending this pandemic means ending it everywhere. As long as this pandemic is raging anywhere in the world, the American people will still be vulnerable. And the United States is committed to bringing the same urgency to international vaccination efforts that we have demonstrated at home.<br><br>Already the United States has committed $4 billion to support COVAX, and we have launched partnerships to boost global capacity to manufacture more vaccines. My administration supports efforts to temporarily waive intellectual property rights for COVID-19 vaccines because, over time, we need more companies producing life-saving doses of proven vaccines that are shared equitably. We have already shared more than 4 million doses of vaccine with Canada and Mexico, and last month, I announced that, by the end of June, the United States will share 80 million doses of our vaccine supply with the world.<br><br>Today, we’re providing more detail on how we will allocate the first 25 million of those vaccines to lay the ground for increased global coverage and to address real and potential surges, high burdens of disease, and the needs of the most vulnerable countries. At least 75 percent of these doses—nearly 19 million—will be shared through COVAX, including approximately 6 million doses for Latin America and the Caribbean, approximately 7 million for South and Southeast Asia, and approximately 5 million for Africa, working in coordination with the African Union and the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention. The remaining doses, just over 6 million, will be shared directly with countries experiencing surges, those in crisis, and other partners and neighbors, including Canada, Mexico, India, and the Republic of Korea.<br><br>We are sharing these doses not to secure favors or extract concessions. We are sharing these vaccines to save lives and to lead the world in bringing an end to the pandemic, with the power of our example and with our values. And we will continue to follow the science and to work in close cooperation with our democratic partners to coordinate a multilateral effort, including through the G7.&nbsp;<br><br>Strong American leadership is essential to ending this pandemic now, and to strengthening global health security for tomorrow—to better prevent, detect, and respond to the next threat. The United States will be the world’s arsenal of vaccines in our shared fight against this virus. In the days to come, as we draw on the experience of distributing the vaccine doses announced today, we will have more details to provide about how future doses will be shared. And we will continue to do all we can to build a world that is safer and more secure against the threat of infectious disease.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Unveils Strategy for Global Vaccine Sharing, Announcing Allocation Plan for the First 25 Million Doses to be Shared Globally</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-unveils-strategy-for-global-vaccine-sharing-announcing-allocation-plan-for-the-first-25-million-doses-to-be-shared-globally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 15:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we continue to fight the COVID-19 pandemic at home and work to end the pandemic worldwide, President Biden has promised that the United States will be an arsenal of vaccines for the world. To do that, the Administration will pursue several additional measures beyond our robust funding for COVAX: Donating from the U.S. vaccine&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As we continue to fight the COVID-19 pandemic at home and work to end the pandemic worldwide, President Biden has promised that the United States will be an arsenal of vaccines for the world. To do that, the Administration will pursue several additional measures beyond our robust funding for COVAX: Donating from the U.S. vaccine supply to the world and encouraging other nations to do the same, working with U.S. manufacturers to increase vaccine production for the rest of the world, and helping more countries expand their own capacity to produce vaccines including through support for global supply chains. This vaccine strategy is a vital component of our overall global strategy to lead the world in the fight to defeat COVID-19, including emergency public health assistance and aid to stop the spread and building global public health capacity and readiness to beat not just this pandemic, but the next one.<br><br>Today, the Administration announced its framework for sharing at least 80 million U.S. vaccine doses globally by the end of June and the plan for the first 25 million doses.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Specifically, the Administration announced that: &nbsp;<br><br><strong><u>The United States will share vaccines in service of ending the pandemic globally</u></strong>. Today, the Administration announced its framework for sharing these 80 million U.S. vaccine doses worldwide. Specifically, the United States will:<br><br><strong><em>Share 75% of these vaccines through COVAX</em></strong>. The United States will share at least three-quarters of its donated doses through COVAX, supplying U.S. doses to countries in need. This will maximize the number of vaccines available equitably for the greatest number of countries and for those most at-risk within countries. &nbsp;For doses shared through COVAX, the United States will prioritize Latin America and the Caribbean, South and Southeast Asia, and Africa, in coordination with the African Union.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><strong><em>Share 25% for immediate needs and to help with surges around the world.</em></strong> The United States has received requests for vaccines from countries all over the world.&nbsp; The U.S. will share up to one-quarter of its donated doses directly with countries in need, those experiencing surges, immediate neighbors, and other countries that have requested immediate U.S. assistance. Specifically, we will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Set the stage for increased global coverage.</strong>&nbsp; The allocation of this first tranche of donated doses reflects the desire of the United States to respond to all regions and lay the ground for increased supply and access throughout the world.<br></li><li><strong>Prepare for surges and prioritize healthcare workers and other vulnerable populations </strong>based on public health data and acknowledged best practice. We will share with countries in urgent need, with a priority on vaccinating frontline workers. The United States will not use its vaccines to secure favors from other countries.&nbsp; The U.S. will work with partners who are both ready and in need.&nbsp; And, our donations will prioritize countries with vaccine readiness plans that prioritize individuals at highest risk of severe disease and those working to help care for them, like health care workers.<br></li><li><strong>Help countries in need and our neighbors.</strong> The United States will share vaccines in our region and across our borders. We first made doses available to our closest neighbors – Canada and Mexico.&nbsp; Our dose sharing approach prioritizes Latin American and the Caribbean on a <em>per capita </em>basis.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>The U.S. announced the proposed allocation plan for the first 25 Million doses.</u></strong> Based on the framework above and pending legal and regulatory approvals, the United States plans to send our first tranche of 25 million doses:</p>



<ul><li>Nearly 19 million will be shared through COVAX, with the following allocations:<ul><li>Approximately 6 million for South and Central America to the following countries: Brazil, Argentina, Colombia, Costa Rica, Peru, Ecuador, Paraguay, Bolivia, Guatemala, El Salvador, Honduras, Panama, Haiti, and other Caribbean Community (CARICOM) countries, as well as the Dominican Republic.</li><li>Approximately 7 million for Asia to the following countries and entities:  India, Nepal, Bangladesh, Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Afghanistan, Maldives, Malaysia, Philippines, Vietnam, Indonesia, Thailand, Laos, Papua New Guinea, Taiwan, and the Pacific Islands. </li><li>Approximately 5 million for Africa to be shared with countries that will be selected in coordination with the African Union. <br></li></ul></li><li>Approximately 6 million will be targeted toward regional priorities and partner recipients, including Mexico, Canada, and the Republic of Korea, West Bank and Gaza, Ukraine, Kosovo, Haiti, Georgia, Egypt, Jordan, India, Iraq, and Yemen, as well as for United Nations frontline workers.  </li></ul>



<p>The sharing of millions of U.S. vaccines with other countries signals a major commitment by the U.S. government.&nbsp; Just like in the United States, we will move as expeditiously as possible, while abiding by U.S. and host country regulatory and legal requirements, to facilitate the safe and secure transport of vaccines across international borders.&nbsp; This will take time, but the President has directed the Administration to use all the levers of the U.S. government to protect individuals from this virus as quickly as possible.&nbsp; The specific vaccines and amounts will be determined and shared as the Administration works through the logistical, regulatory and other parameters particular to each region and country.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Establishing the Fight Against Corruption as a Core U.S. National Security Interest</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/fact-sheet-establishing-the-fight-against-corruption-as-a-core-u-s-national-security-interest/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to tackling corruption as an economic and national security priority, and has pledged to lead international efforts to bring transparency to the global financial system and close loopholes that undermine democracy.  As the Interim National Security Strategic Guidance states:  “We will take special aim at confronting corruption, which rots democracy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to tackling corruption as an economic and national security priority, and has pledged to lead international efforts to bring transparency to the global financial system and close loopholes that undermine democracy.  As the Interim National Security Strategic Guidance states:</p>



<p><br> “We will take special aim at confronting corruption, which rots democracy from the inside and is increasingly weaponized by authoritarian states to undermine democratic institutions…We will crack down on tax havens and illicit financing that contribute to income inequality, fund terrorism, and generate pernicious foreign influence.” </p>



<p><br>Today, in line with this commitment, President Biden is releasing a National Security Study Memorandum (NSSM) that establishes the fight against corruption as a core national security interest of the United States. The NSSM directs a 200-day interagency review that will culminate in a report and recommendations on how the U.S. government and its partners can:<br><br><strong>Modernize, Coordinate, and Resource Efforts to Better Fight Corruption. </strong>Corruption threatens U.S. national security by eroding citizens’ faith in government, distorting economies, and enabling authoritarians to weaken democratic institutions. The NSSM therefore directs departments and agencies to identify and where appropriate establish new structures and staffing, improve intelligence collection and analysis, and increase resources aimed at confronting corruption at home and abroad.<br><br><strong>Curb Illicit Finance. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration has pledged to lead efforts internationally to bring transparency to the U.S. and international financial systems, including by reducing offshore financial secrecy, seizing stolen assets, and making it more difficult for those who steal to hide behind anonymity. The NSSM therefore directs departments and agencies to combat all forms of illicit finance, including through accelerating ongoing efforts to establish a “beneficial ownership” registry, so that illicit actors can’t hide the proceeds of corruption behind anonymous shell companies; limiting the ability of illicit actors to hide behind anonymity to buy residential real estate; and closing loopholes in existing regulatory regimes.   <br><br><strong>Hold Corrupt Actors Accountable. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to taking new steps to hold accountable corrupt individuals, transnational criminal organizations, and other actors engaged in illicit activity. This includes strengthening and building upon targeted anticorruption sanctions under the Global Magnitsky Act and similar authorities; and bolstering criminal or civil enforcement actions, such as under the Department of Justice’s Kleptocracy Asset Recovery Initiative. It also means increasing support to grow the capacity of civil society, the media, state and local bodies, international partners, and other oversight and accountability actors.<br><br><strong>Build International Partnerships. </strong>As part of its commitment to strengthening America’s alliances and partnerships, the NSSM directs departments and agencies to work with like-minded international partners through the UN, G7, Financial Action Task Force (FATF), and similar bodies to counteract strategic corruption emanating from autocratic and kleptocratic governments, foreign state-owned or affiliated enterprises, and transnational criminal organizations. This work will include closing loopholes exploited by those actors in order to mask the proceeds of corruption or interfere in democratic processes. <br><br><strong>Improve Foreign Assistance. </strong>The United States partners with foreign governments and civil society to enhance the capacity of their domestic institutions to implement transparency, oversight, and accountability measures. The NSSM therefore directs departments and agencies to focus on anticorruption best practices and improve enforcement measures in the implementation of foreign assistance programs and security cooperation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on the National Security Study Memorandum on the Fight Against Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-the-national-security-study-memorandum-on-the-fight-against-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Strengthening the resilience of rights-respecting democracies is one of the defining challenges of our era.  Corruption eats away at the foundations of democratic societies. It makes government less effective, wastes public resources, and exacerbates inequalities in access to services, making it harder for families to provide for their loved ones.  Corruption attacks the foundations of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Strengthening the resilience of rights-respecting democracies is one of the defining challenges of our era.  Corruption eats away at the foundations of democratic societies. It makes government less effective, wastes public resources, and exacerbates inequalities in access to services, making it harder for families to provide for their loved ones.  Corruption attacks the foundations of democratic institutions, drives and intensifies extremism, and makes it easier for authoritarian regimes to corrode democratic governance.<br><br>Corruption is a risk to our national security, and we must recognize it as such.  <br><br>Today, I am issuing a National Security Study Memorandum on the Fight Against Corruption to establish combatting corruption as a core U.S. national security interest. With this Memorandum, I am directing departments and agencies to make recommendations that will significantly bolster the ability of the U.S. government to combat corruption.<br><br>The United States will lead by example and in partnership with allies, civil society, and the private sector to fight the scourge of corruption. But this is a mission for the entire the world. And, we must all stand in support of courageous citizens around the globe who are demanding honest, transparent governance.<br><br>Fighting corruption is not just good governance.  It is self-defense.  It is patriotism, and it’s essential to the preservation of our democracy and our future.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
