<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 21:20:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden On the Passing of Former Secretary of State Madeleine&#160;Albright</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/23/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-former-secretary-of-state-madeleine-albright/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 21:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Madeleine Albright was a force. Hers were the hands that turned the tide of history. As a young girl, she found a home in the United States—after her family fled their home country of Czechoslovakia during World War II, and the Iron Curtain came down across Central and Eastern Europe. Her father, a diplomat, was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Madeleine Albright was a force.<br><br>Hers were the hands that turned the tide of history.<br><br>As a young girl, she found a home in the United States—after her family fled their home country of Czechoslovakia during World War II, and the Iron Curtain came down across Central and Eastern Europe. Her father, a diplomat, was marked for death by the Soviet regime. She spent the rest of her days defending freedom around the world and lifting up those who suffered under repression.<br><br>She was an immigrant fleeing persecution. A refugee in need of safe haven. And like so many before her—and after—she was proudly American.<br><br>To make this country that she loved even better—she defied convention and broke barriers again and again.&nbsp; As the devoted mother of three beloved daughters, she worked tirelessly raising them while earned her doctorate degree and started her career.&nbsp; She took her talents first to the Senate as a staffer for Senator Edmund Muskie, followed by the National Security Council under President Carter. And then to the United Nations where she served as U.S. Ambassador, and ultimately, made history as our first woman Secretary of State, appointed by President Clinton.<br><br>A scholar, teacher, bestselling author, and later accomplished businesswoman, Secretary Albright continued to advise presidents and members of Congress with matchless skill and diplomatic acumen.&nbsp; In every role, she used her fierce intellect and sharp wit—and often her unmatched collection of pins—to advance America’s national security and promote peace around the world. America had no more committed champion of democracy and human rights than Secretary Albright, who knew personally and wrote powerfully of the perils of autocracy.<br><br>Working with Secretary Albright during the 1990s was among the highlights of my career in the United States Senate during my tenure on the Foreign Relations Committee. As the world redefined itself in the wake of the Cold War, we were partners and friends working to welcome newly liberated democracies into NATO and confront the horrors of genocide in the Balkans.<br><br>When I think of Madeleine, I will always remember her fervent faith that “America is the indispensable nation.”<br><br>In the years after she left government, Secretary Albright never stepped away from that belief. &nbsp;As the Chairman of the National Democratic Institute for over two decades, and through other organizations she advised, she continued to champion democratic principles as vitally important to America’s interests in freedom, prosperity and security.<br><br>She continued to mentor and nurture new generations of foreign policy experts at Georgetown University, the Korbel Center for International Studies at the University of Denver, named after her father, and beyond.&nbsp; As always, she shared her insight and wisdom widely, but she was especially dedicated to supporting the next generation of women leaders, including through the establishment of the Albright Institute for Global Affairs at Wellesley College.<br><br>Madeleine was always a force for goodness, grace, and decency—and for freedom.<br><br>Jill and I will miss her dearly and send our love and prayers to her daughters, Alice, Anne and Katie, her sister Kathy, her brother John, her six grandchildren, and her nephews and grandniece.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Idaho Law Restricting Women’s Access to Health&#160;Care</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/23/statement-from-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-idaho-law-restricting-womens-access-to-health-care/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We knew that when Texas passed SB8, its extreme law that blatantly violates the constitutional right reaffirmed by Roe v. Wade, it would invite other states to follow.  Today, Idaho became the first state to adopt a similar law – a six-week restriction relying on private citizens to enforce the law.  This development is devastating for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We knew that when Texas passed SB8, its extreme law that blatantly violates the constitutional right reaffirmed by <em>Roe v. Wade</em>, it would invite other states to follow.  Today, Idaho became the first state to adopt a similar law – a six-week restriction relying on private citizens to enforce the law.  This development is devastating for women in Idaho, as it will further impede women’s access to health care, especially those on low incomes and living in rural communities. <br><br>Over the last six months, Texas’s SB8 has had profoundly negative effects–with women forced to travel hundreds of miles to access care, and clinics in neighboring states seeing a significant increase in demand since the law went into effect.  This is unacceptable, which is why President Biden directed a whole of government response to protect women’s rights that are currently under attack.<br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration will continue to stand with women and support their right to make their own health care decisions, a constitutional right that <em>Roe v. Wade</em> reaffirmed nearly five decades ago. And the President again calls on Congress to act and send a bill to his desk to shut down these radical steps.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Appointments to Federal Salary&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/23/president-biden-announces-appointments-to-federal-salary-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles: Stephen Emerson Condrey, Member and Chair, Federal Salary Council Jared James Llorens, Member, Federal Salary Council Janice Rachel Lachance, Member, Federal Salary Council The Federal Salary Council is an advisory body of the executive branch that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Stephen Emerson Condrey, Member and Chair, Federal Salary Council</li><li>Jared James Llorens, Member, Federal Salary Council</li><li>Janice Rachel Lachance, Member, Federal Salary Council</li></ul>



<p>The Federal Salary Council is an advisory body of the executive branch that provides recommendations on pay differentials for federal employees.&nbsp;The Council submits recommendations to the Secretary of Labor, Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</p>



<p><strong><u>Stephen Emerson Condrey, Member and Chair</u></strong><strong><br></strong>Stephen Emerson Condrey is President of Condrey and Associates, Inc., a human resources consulting firm specializing in compensation systems for state and local governments. In his forty years of experience, Condrey has consulted with over 800 organizations nationally and internationally and served as President Obama’s Federal Salary Council Chair from 2010 to 2017. He has authored or co-authored numerous scholarly articles and is the editor of the Handbook of Human Resource Management in Government (3<sup>rd</sup> edition) as well as the co-editor of Public Administration in Post-Communist Countries. He has degrees from the University of Montevallo (BS), the University of Tennessee (MPA), and the University of Georgia (PhD).&nbsp; After losing his sight in 2015, he received Assistive Technology training from the Birmingham Regional Center of the Alabama Institute for the Deaf and Blind. Condrey served as President of the American Society for Public Administration (2013-2014) and is a Fellow of the National Academy of Public Administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Jared James Llorens, Member</u></strong><strong><br></strong>Jared J. Llorens is Dean of Louisiana State University’s E. J. Ourso College of Business. An expert in the areas of public sector compensation and recruitment, Llorens launched his academic career in 2007 as an Assistant Professor of Public Administration at the University of Kansas. He accepted a faculty position with Louisiana State University’s Department of Public Administration in 2009 and was named chair of the Department in 2015. Llorens began his service as the college’s ninth Dean on November 1, 2020.</p>



<p>In 2020, Llorens was named a Fellow of the National Academy of Public Administration. He is the former editor-in-chief of Public Personnel Management and his research has been widely published in various academic outlets. He is also a co-author of the widely adopted textbook Public Personnel Management: Context and Strategies 6th &amp; 7th editions. Before beginning his academic career, Llorens served as a human resources analyst with the U.S. Office of Personnel Management and the U.S. Department of Labor in Dallas and Washington, D.C. A Baton Rouge native, Llorens received his BA in English from Loyola University of New Orleans, his MPAff from the LBJ School of Public Affairs at The University of Texas at Austin, and his PhD in Public Administration from the University of Georgia’s School of Public and International Affairs.</p>



<p><strong><u>Janice Rachel Lachance, Member</u></strong><strong><br></strong>Janice Lachance is the Executive Vice President for Strategic Leadership and Global Outreach at the American Geophysical Union (AGU), a scientific society supporting more than 130,000 Earth and space scientists in 140 countries. Her work at AGU includes the renovation of the organization’s headquarters into a net-zero energy consumption building – the first renovation of its kind in Washington, D.C. Beyond this innovative project, Janice’s duties include: leadership of AGU’s global partnerships and initiatives; positioning and message development across the range of climate, environmental, and science policy issues, discoveries, and solutions; and global government relations and public policy, membership and career services, and association governance.</p>



<p>Prior to her work in the nonprofit sector, Lachance was nominated by President Clinton and unanimously confirmed by the U.S. Senate to serve as the Director of the U.S. Office of Personnel Management (OPM), where she was responsible for policy and programmatic leadership of the nation’s 2.1-million-member civil service. Leading up to this role, she served as OPM’s Director of Communications, Chief of Staff, and Deputy Director. Janice received the American Society for Public Administration (ASPA) 2020 Elmer B. Staats Lifetime Achievement Award. She is a member of ASPA’s Endowment Board and was its president in 2017-2018. She also has been named a Fellow of the National Academy of Public Administration and the American Society of Association Executives. Born and raised in Biddeford, Maine, and the first in her extended family to attend college, Lachance graduated from Manhattanville College and earned her law degree from Tulane University.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Appointments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/23/president-biden-announces-key-appointments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles on the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &#38; Nutrition, the Commission of Fine Arts, and the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science: José Andrés, Co-Chair, the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &#38; Nutrition Elena Delle&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles on the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &amp; Nutrition, the Commission of Fine Arts, and the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science:</p>



<ul><li>José Andrés, Co-Chair, the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &amp; Nutrition</li><li>Elena Delle Donne, Co-Chair, the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &amp; Nutrition</li><li>Lisa E. Delplace, Member, the Commission of Fine Arts</li><li>May Berenbaum, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Rafael Bras, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Joan Ferrini-Mundy, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Erika Gonzalez, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Juan Maldacena, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Cora Bagley Marrett, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Valerie Montgomery Rice, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Craig Partridge, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Padma Raghavan, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Pedro A. Sanchez, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Robert Sellers, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Cherese Winstead, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>The President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &amp; Nutrition</u></strong></p>



<p>The President’s Council on Sports, Fitness &amp; Nutrition (PCSFN) is a federal advisory committee that aims to promote healthy, accessible eating and physical activity for all Americans, regardless of background or ability. President Biden issues Executive Order 14048, renewing the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness &amp; Nutrition. This Executive Order allows for continued promotion of the National Youth Sports Strategy, and provides for the work of the Council to include a focus on expanding national awareness of the importance of mental health as it pertains to physical fitness and nutrition.</p>



<p><strong>José Andrés as Co-Chair</strong></p>



<p>José Andrés is an internationally recognized culinary innovator, New York Times bestselling author, educator, and humanitarian. He was named one of Time Magazine’s “100 Most Influential People” in both 2012 and 2018, and awarded the 2015 National Humanities Medal from President Barack Obama. As the chef/owner of the award-winning ThinkFoodGroup restaurant collective, Andrés has been a pioneer of Spanish tapas in the United States and is also known for his groundbreaking avant-garde cuisine. In 2010, Andrés formed World Central Kitchen, a non-profit which uses the power of food to nourish communities and strengthen economies in times of crisis. His team served over 3.6 million meals to the people of Puerto Rico following Hurricane María. Since then, WCK has activated on six continents, serving tens of millions of fresh meals in the aftermath of both natural and manmade disasters. In response to the COVID-19 pandemic, the organization partnered with thousands of restaurants, farmers, and community leaders around the country to combat food and nutrition insecurity, laying the groundwork for smarter national food policy—one which builds longer tables in the US and around the world.&nbsp; Currently, Andrés and World Central Kitchen are working in Ukraine and four neighboring countries, feeding refugees who have fled their homes. Andrés currently serves as co-Chair of the Bipartisan Policy Center’s Food and Nutrition Security Task Force, was named Washington Business Journal’s CEO of the Year in 2020 for his leadership and impact on the global business community during the COVID-19 pandemic, and was awarded the Princesa de Asturias Foundation’s 2021 Concordia Prize for World Central Kitchen’s humanitarian work. As a naturalized citizen originally from Spain, Andrés has also been a tireless advocate for immigration reform.</p>



<p><strong>Elena Delle Donne as Co-Chair</strong></p>



<p>Elena Delle Donne is one of the most dominant players in the WNBA. The Washington Mystics star is a Top 25 WNBA player of all time, two-time WNBA MVP (2015, 2019), WNBA Champion (2019), six-time WNBA All-Star honor, and four-time All-WNBA First Team selection. Delle Donne is also the first WNBA player to join the 50-40-90 club, a group of elite sharp shooters comprised of only eight other NBA players. A member of Team USA, Delle Donne took home a gold medal during the 2016 Olympics and was the WNBA scoring champion in 2015. The 2013 WNBA Rookie of the Year, the Delaware native was drafted second overall in the WNBA draft. Prior to her WNBA career, Delle Donne attended the University of Delaware to remain close to her tight-knit family. While at Delaware, Delle Donne led her team to its first ever NCAA Sweet Sixteen her senior year, was a consensus first team All-American, and finished as CAA Conference Player of the Year three times. Off the court, Delle Donne is the author of a middle-grade series, Hoops, and released her memoir <em>My Shot: Balancing it All and Standing Tall</em>. Additionally, Delle Donne and her wife, Amanda, turned their passion for woodworking and design into their own business, Deldon, creating custom pieces like cutting boards, wall art and basketball hoops. In 2017, she founded the Elena Delle Donne Foundation to raise funds and awareness of Lyme disease research, special needs programs and animal welfare work.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>The Commission of Fine Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>The Commission of Fine Arts is an independent federal agency charged with giving expert advice to the President, the Congress and the federal and District of Columbia governments on matters of design and aesthetics, as they affect the federal interest and preserve the dignity of the nation’s capital. The Commission is composed of seven presidentially appointed experts in relevant disciplines including art, architecture, landscape architecture, and urban design.</p>



<p><strong>Lisa E. Delplace as Member</strong></p>



<p>Lisa E. Delplace, FASLA, is a landscape architect and Chief Executive Officer Emeritus of Washington, DC-based OEHME, VAN SWEDEN | OvS. In a career that spans four decades, Lisa has demonstrated comprehensive knowledge of ecological processes and a commitment to their artistic execution. Her diverse body of work ranges from bucolic sculpture parks to urban redevelopments and reflects a compelling sculptural relationship between architecture and landscape. Lisa holds a Master of Landscape Architecture from the University of Michigan and is a member of the American Society of Landscape Architects’ Council of Fellows. She serves as a visiting critic and lecturer for universities and professional organizations and has international experience in Europe, the Middle East, and service as a U.S. Peace Corps Volunteer in Kenya, East Africa.</p>



<p><strong><u>The President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</u></strong></p>



<p>The President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science evaluates nominees for the National Medal of Science, a Presidential Award to recognize individuals for their outstanding contributions to knowledge in the physical, biological, mathematical, engineering, social, and behavioral sciences. Since its establishment, the National Medal of Science has been awarded to 506 distinguished scientists and engineers whose careers spanned decades of research and development.</p>



<p><strong>May Berenbaum as Member</strong></p>



<p>May Berenbaum has been on the faculty of the Department of Entomology at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign for more than 40 years, serving as head since 1992 and as Swanlund Chair of Entomology since 1996. A member of the National Academy of Sciences, she has chaired two National Research Council study committees, including Status of Pollinators in North America, testifying before Congress on the study&#8217;s findings. Since January 2019, she has served as Editor-in-Chief of the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. She is a Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, the Ecological Society of America, and the Entomological Society of America. In 2011, she was awarded the Tyler Prize for Environmental Achievement, and, in 2014, she received the National Medal of Science from President Obama.</p>



<p><strong>Rafael Bras as Member</strong></p>



<p>A native of Puerto Rico, Rafael L. Bras is a professor in the School of Earth and Atmospheric Sciences and the School of Civil and Environmental Engineering at the Georgia Institute of Technology. He holds the K. Harrison Brown Family Chair. Dr. Bras works in the field of hydrology with particular interest on land-atmosphere-biosphere interactions. He was Provost and Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs at the Georgia Institute of Technology. He was also Distinguished Professor and Dean of the Henry Samueli School of Engineering of the University of California, Irvine and spent 32 years as a professor in the departments of Civil and Environmental Engineering and of Earth, Atmospheric, and Planetary Sciences at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Dr. Bras is an elected member of the U.S. National Academy of Engineering and the Academy of Arts and Sciences of Puerto Rico.</p>



<p><strong>Joan Ferrini-Mundy as Member</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Joan Ferrini-Mundy was appointed the 21<sup>st</sup> president of the University of Maine and its regional campus in Machias in 2018. She was also named Vice Chancellor for Research and Innovation for the University of Maine System and is a professor in the Department of Mathematics and Statistics. Ferrini-Mundy came to Maine following her service as the chief operating officer of the National Science Foundation. Prior to that role, she headed the National Science Foundation’s Directorate for Education and Human Resources for six years. She also has been a faculty member and administrator at her alma mater, the University of New Hampshire, and at Michigan State University. President Ferrini-Mundy’s awards and recognitions include the U.S. Senior Executive Service Presidential Rank Award of Distinguished Executive, Michigan State University Distinguished Professorship, election as a fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science and of the American Mathematical Society, and the 2020 Seaman A. Knapp Award for leadership and contributions to food and agricultural sciences.</p>



<p><strong>Erika Gonzalez as Member</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Erika Gonzalez is the CEO &amp; President of both South Texas Allergy &amp; Asthma Medical Professionals (STAAMP) and STAAMP Clinical Research. She previously served as the Chief of the Allergy, Immunology &amp; Rheumatology division at the Children’s Hospital of San Antonio and was an Associate Professor of Clinical Pediatrics at Baylor College of Medicine. She serves on the Board of Directors for Central Catholic High School, Girls Inc. San Antonio, and the San Antonio Economic Development Foundation. She is an Advisor to the Dean of Science Engineering &amp; Technology at St. Mary’s University, on the Stock Epinephrine Committee with the Texas Department of State Health Services, and Co-Chair for the Small Business for America’s Future. Dr. Gonzalez recently founded the nonprofit Con Corazon SA to address health inequities and emergency preparedness. She is a native of San Antonio and served 10 years of Active Duty Service as a Medical Officer in the U. S. Air Force. She was selected as a 2019 Presidential Leadership Scholar.</p>



<p><strong>Juan Maldacena as Member</strong></p>



<p>Juan Maldacena was born in 1968 in Argentina, where he obtained his college degree. He moved to the U.S. for his physics Ph.D., completed in 1996 at Princeton University. He has been a professor at the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton since 2001 and currently holds the Carl P. Feinberg chair. His research interests include quantum field theory, quantum gravity, string theory, and cosmology. He is a member of the National Academy of Sciences and the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. His awards include the Dannie Heineman Prize, the Einstein Medal, the Mac Arthur Fellowship, and the Breakthrough Prize in Physics.</p>



<p><strong>Cora Bagley Marrett as Member</strong></p>



<p>Cora Bagley Marrett is Professor Emerita of Sociology at the University of Wisconsin-Madison. She has held posts at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill; Western Michigan University; the University of Wisconsin System; and the University of Massachusetts-Amherst. At the University of Massachusetts-Amherst, she was Provost and Vice Chancellor for Academic Affairs. For eleven years, she served as an administrator at the National Science Foundation and was appointed Deputy Director of the National Science Foundation by President Obama. Throughout her career, she has served on governing or advisory boards with the Social Science Research Council, the Russell Sage Foundation, the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering and Medicine, and the Office of Naval Research. President Carter appointed her to the Commission on the Accident at Three Mile Island, which examined the nuclear power incident in Pennsylvania. She holds honorary degrees from Virginia Union University, the University of Wisconsin-Madison, and Wake Forest University.</p>



<p><strong>Valerie Montgomery Rice as Member</strong></p>



<p>Valerie Montgomery Rice, MD, FACOG, is the sixth President and CEO of Morehouse School of Medicine and the first woman to lead the free-standing medical institution. Prior to joining Morehouse School of Medicine, Montgomery Rice was the founding director of the Center for Women’s Health Research at Meharry Medical College, one of the nation’s first research centers devoted to studying diseases that disproportionately impact women of color. She currently serves on the Georgia Commission on Women, chairs the Georgia Department of Public Health’s Covid-19 Health Equity Council, and is a member of the National Academy of Medicine. A Georgia native, Montgomery Rice holds a bachelor’s degree in chemistry from the Georgia Institute of Technology, a medical degree from Harvard Medical School, an honorary degree from the University of Massachusetts Medical School, and a Doctor of Humane Letters honorary degree from Rush University.</p>



<p><strong>Craig Partridge as Member</strong></p>



<p>Professor Craig Partridge is the chair of the department of Computer Science at Colorado State University. Previously, he was Chief Scientist at Raytheon BBN Technologies. Partridge is a member of the Internet Hall of Fame and a Fellow of the Association for Computing Machinery and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers. Partridge is a member of the Computer Science and Telecommunications Board of the National Academies. He is a former chair of ACM&#8217;s Special Interest Group on Data Communication and a former member of the National Science Foundation&#8217;s Computer and Information Science and Engineering Advisory Committee. Partridge received his A.B., M.Sc., and Ph.D. degrees from Harvard University.</p>



<p><strong>Padma Raghavan</strong><strong> as Member</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Padma Raghavan is the inaugural Vice Provost for Research and Professor of Computer Science at Vanderbilt University. Prior to joining Vanderbilt in 2016, Raghavan served as the Associate Vice President for Research and Strategic Initiatives, the founding Director of the Institute for Computational and Data Sciences, and Distinguished Professor of Computer Science and Engineering at the Pennsylvania State University. Raghavan was named a fellow of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers in 2013 in recognition of her contributions to the development of energy-efficient supercomputing. She also serves on editorial boards of the Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics and the Advisory Boards of the Computing and Information Science and Engineering Directorate and the Office of Advanced Cyberinfrastructure of the National Science Foundation. Raghavan also serves on multiple committees of the National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine, including Technical Advisory Boards for the Army Research Laboratory on Computational Science and Information Sciences.</p>



<p><strong>Pedro A. Sanchez</strong><strong> as Member</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Pedro Sanchez was born and raised in Cuba, where he worked on his family’s farm. He has spent 50 years alternating between American universities and CGIAR&#8217;s international research centers. He has been faculty at North Carolina State University, the University of California Berkeley, Colombia University, and the University of Florida, where he is currently a research professor of tropical soils and core faculty member of the Food Systems Institute. Cambridge University Press published Sanchez’s book “Properties and Management of Soils in the Tropics” in 2019 and its translation into Spanish in 2021. Sanchez has received honorary Doctor of Science degrees from the Catholic University of Leuven, Guelph University in Canada, the Ohio State University, and North Carolina State University. He won the World Food Prize in 2002, became a MacArthur Foundation Fellow in 2004, and was elected to the U.S. National Academy of Sciences in 2012. In 2016, President Obama appointed him to the President´s Committee on the National Medal of Science.</p>



<p><strong>Robert Sellers as Member</strong></p>



<p>Robert M. Sellers is the Vice Provost for Equity and Inclusion, Chief Diversity Officer, and the Charles D. Moody Collegiate Professor of Psychology and Education at the University of Michigan. Prior to joining the Provost’s Office, Dr. Sellers was chair of the University of Michigan Department of Psychology. His research interests include ethnicity, racial and ethnic identity, personality and health, athletic participation, and personality. He has received the Theodore Millon Mid-Career Award in Personality Psychology from the American Psychological Foundation, the American Psychological Association Minority Fellowship Program Research Achievement Award, and the APAGS Kenneth &amp; Mamie Clark Award for Outstanding Contribution to the Professional Development of Ethnic Minority Graduate Students. Sellers received his B.S. in Psychology from Howard University and his doctorate in personality psychology from the University of Michigan.</p>



<p><strong>Cherese Winstead as Member</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Cherese Winstead is ranked as Full Professor in the Department of Chemistry at Delaware State University and currently serves as Dean of the College of Agriculture, Science &amp; Technology. She previously served as the Department Chair of Chemistry at Delaware State University for over eight years. She is a member of Delaware NASA Space Grant, Delaware Comprehensive Sickle Cell Research Center, Materials Research Society, American Chemical Society, and the Delaware Science Coalition. Dr. Winstead is Founder and President of the Young Chemists Society, a non-profit organization dedicated to the early education of underrepresented students in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. Dr. Winstead obtained her Ph.D. from The Virginia Polytechnic Institute &amp; State University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Marine One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/23/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 15:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 8:45 A.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, what would you like to say to European partners?&#160; What would you like to say to European partners? &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MR. PRESIDENT:&#160; I&#8217;m going to say that to their face.&#160; I&#8217;m going to say &#8212; all I have to say, I&#8217;m going to say when I get&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>8:45 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what would you like to say to European partners?&nbsp; What would you like to say to European partners?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to say that to their face.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to say &#8212; all I have to say, I&#8217;m going to say when I get there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll be happy to talk to you guys when I get back or &#8212;&nbsp; how many &#8212; are you coming?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They&#8217;re there.&nbsp; They&#8217;re there.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I know.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how concerned &#8212; how concerned are you about the threat of chemical warfare right now, that Russia will use chemical weapons?&nbsp; How high is that threat?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s a real threat.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p> 8:46 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the 12th Anniversary of the Affordable Care&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/23/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-12th-anniversary-of-the-affordable-care-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49502</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twelve years ago, I proudly stood beside President Barack Obama as he signed into law the most consequential expansion of health care in generations: the Affordable Care Act. With the stroke of a pen — after decades of tireless efforts — millions of Americans gained peace of mind. And because of my Administration’s efforts, including&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Twelve years ago, I proudly stood beside President Barack Obama as he signed into law the most consequential expansion of health care in generations: the Affordable Care Act. With the stroke of a pen — after decades of tireless efforts — millions of Americans gained peace of mind. And because of my Administration’s efforts, including passing the landmark American Rescue Plan, we have lowered health care costs and made coverage more accessible than ever before — even amid a global pandemic.</p>



<p>The ACA delivered quality, affordable health coverage to more than 30 million Americans — giving families the freedom and confidence to pursue their dreams without the fear that one accident or illness would bankrupt them. This law is the reason we have protections for pre-existing conditions in America. It is why women can no longer be charged more simply because they are women. It reduced prescription drug costs for nearly 12 million seniors. It allows millions of Americans to get free preventive screenings, so they can catch cancer or heart disease early — saving countless lives. And it is the reason why parents can keep children on their insurance plans until they turn 26.</p>



<p>When I ran for President, I promised I would protect and build on Obamacare — and that’s exactly what my Administration has done. Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, ACA premiums are at an all-time low, while enrollment is at an all-time high. Four out of five Americans can find quality coverage for under $10 a month, and families are saving an average of $2,400 on their annual premiums — that’s $200 in savings every month that families can spend on gas, groceries, and other necessities. We lowered costs and increased enrollment to a record high 14.5 million Americans gaining quality health coverage last year — including nearly 6 million who enrolled for the first time — with an additional 18.7 million low-income Americans now covered by Medicaid expansion. We’ve also reached communities that have historically been left behind, with the HealthCare.gov enrollment rate increasing by 26 percent for Hispanic Americans and 35 percent for Black Americans.</p>



<p>We’ve made tremendous progress, but our work is far from over. Over the last 12 years, Republicans in Congress have voted more than 70 times to repeal the ACA, with no real plan to replace it. Just this year, a Republican senator shared his plan to repeal the ACA, strip protections from the 100 million Americans with pre-existing conditions, and jack up premiums. As Republicans try to raise health care costs for the middle class, Congressional Democrats and I will do everything in our power to protect and build on Obamacare’s landmark achievements.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Releases Action Plan to Address Racial and Ethnic Bias in Home&#160;Valuations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-action-plan-to-address-racial-and-ethnic-bias-in-home-valuations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris Announces Release of Plan During White House Event with Secretary Marcia L. Fudge, White House Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, and Americans Impacted by Bias in the Appraisal Process On June 1, 2021—the centennial of the Tulsa Race Massacre—President Biden announced the creation of the Interagency Task Force on Property Appraisal&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Kamala Harris Announces Release of Plan During White House Event with Secretary Marcia L. Fudge, White House Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, and Americans Impacted by Bias in the Appraisal Process</em></p>



<p>On June 1, 2021—the centennial of the Tulsa Race Massacre—President Biden announced the creation of the Interagency Task Force on Property Appraisal and Valuation Equity (PAVE) to develop a transformative set of actions to root out racial and ethnic bias in home valuations. Today, the Task Force is releasing the <a href="https://pave.hud.gov/">PAVE Action Plan</a> which, when enacted, represents the most wide-ranging set of reforms ever put forward to advance equity in the home appraisal process. The Task Force is co-chaired by U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development Secretary Marcia L. Fudge and Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice.</p>



<p>A home appraisal is a critical element of the homebuying and lending process, intended to provide an independent, fair, and objective estimate of the market value of a property so that lenders can accurately evaluate risk. &nbsp;Homeownership is the primary contributor to wealth building for Black and brown households and continues to hold promise for building multigenerational wealth and housing stability for households of color. But, bias in home valuations limits the ability of Black and brown families to enjoy the financial returns associated with homeownership, thereby contributing to the already sprawling racial wealth gap. Today, the median white family holds eight times the wealth of the typical Black family and five times the wealth of the typical Latino family. According to a recent <a href="http://racialwealthaudit.org/downloads/RacialWealthGap.pdf">study</a>, eliminating racial disparities in the amount of wealth families gain from owning a home would narrow the wealth gap by an additional 16 percent between Black and white households and by an additional 41 percent between Latino and white households.</p>



<p>Just since the Task Force was launched, there have been numerous reports of Black homeowners receiving higher appraisals only after taking down family photos and having white families represent them in their stead. &nbsp;New research shows that mis-valuation in communities of color can be widespread. A recent report from <a href="https://www.freddiemac.com/research/insight/20210920-home-appraisals">Freddie Mac</a> found that appraisals for home purchases in majority-Black and majority-Latino neighborhoods were roughly twice as likely to result in a value below the actual contract price (the amount a buyer is willing to pay for the property), compared to appraisals in predominantly white neighborhoods. Similarly, a recent study from <a href="https://www.fanniemae.com/research-and-insights/publications/appraising-the-appraisal">Fannie Mae</a> examining refinance transactions found that white-owned homes are much more likely than Black-owned homes to be appraised at values that exceed algorithmic predictions.</p>



<p><strong>PAVE Action Plan</strong></p>



<p>The Action Plan details a set of commitments and actions, most of which can be taken using existing federal authorities, that will help every American to have a chance to build generational wealth through homeownership. You can read the full action plan at PAVE.HUD.gov.</p>



<p>Member agencies will take the following actions:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Make the appraisal industry more accountable.</strong> The Action Plan lays out steps to enhance oversight and accountability of the appraisal industry, which has long operated in a relatively closed and self-regulated framework and has not been effective at addressing deep-rooted inequities. Specifically, it commits federal agencies to create a legislative proposal to modernize the governance structure of the appraisal industry, and improves coordination and collaboration between federal enforcement agencies to better identify and redress discrimination in appraisals.</li><li><strong>Empower consumers with information and assistance.</strong> The Action Plan includes concrete efforts to empower homeowners and homebuyers on effective steps they can take when they receive a valuation that is lower than expected. For example, federal agencies commit to issue guidance and implement new policies to improve the process by which a valuation may be reconsidered.</li><li><strong>Prevent algorithmic bias in home valuation</strong><strong>.</strong> Federal agencies that regulate mortgage financing commit to including a nondiscrimination quality control standard as part of a forthcoming proposed rule establishing quality control standards on AVMs (Automated Valuation Models). This will ensure AVMs do not rely upon biased data that could replicate past discrimination.</li><li><strong>Cultivate an appraiser profession that is well-trained and looks like the communities it serves.</strong><em> </em>According to the Department of Labor’s Bureau of Labor Statistics, the appraiser/assessor profession is roughly 97 percent white, making it one of the least diverse professions in the country. The Action Plan lays out a series of actions to remove unnecessary educational and experience requirements that make it difficult for underrepresented groups to access the profession and to strengthen anti-bias, fair housing, and fair lending training of existing appraisers.</li><li><strong>Leverage federal data and expertise to inform policy, practice, and research on appraisal bias.</strong> The Action Plan proposes the development of an aggregated database of federal appraisal data to better study, understand, and address appraisal bias, complemented by a working group composed of subject matter experts from stakeholder agencies to develop a research agenda on appraisal bias.</li></ul>



<p>The PAVE Task Force has already made significant progress, and its commitment is ongoing. The Task Force identified several additional policy initiatives that may have the potential to make a significant difference in ensuring fair and accurate home valuations for all communities. These policy ideas require in-depth evaluation and research, greater input from stakeholders, and further exploration. The Task Force is committed to doing this work. As the Task Force transitions into the next phase of its work to advance equity in home appraisals, it will continue seeking opportunities to collaborate with lending institutions, philanthropy groups, academia, civil rights groups, advocates, and industry associations to create a coordinated approach in tackling this issue.</p>



<p>To read the full report and stay up to date on the work of the Task Force, you can visit PAVE.hud.gov.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Deputy Press Secretary Chris Meagher and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, March 22,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/22/press-briefing-by-deputy-press-secretary-chris-meagher-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-march-22-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 22:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:48 P.M. EDT MR. MEAGHER:&#160; Hello, everyone. Good afternoon.&#160; As you can see things are changing and moving pretty rapidly around here today. Obviously, we&#8217;ve had some last-minute adju- &#8212; adjustments to the briefing, which is why I&#8217;m up here today.&#160; I know folks might have some questions after&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:48 P.M. EDT<br><br>MR. MEAGHER:&nbsp; Hello, everyone. Good afternoon.&nbsp; As you can see things are changing and moving pretty rapidly around here today.<br><br>Obviously, we&#8217;ve had some last-minute adju- &#8212; adjustments to the briefing, which is why I&#8217;m up here today.&nbsp; I know folks might have some questions after the statement that we just released from Jen.&nbsp; And we in the Press Office are going to strive throughout the rest of the day to get you the answers to the questions you might have.<br><br>A few additions beyond Jen&#8217;s statement that I can provide right now.&nbsp; No members of the press who attended the briefing yesterday are considered to be close contacts.&nbsp; We are considering con- &#8212; or we are currently conducting contact tracing, and any member of the press who is considered to be a close contact will be contacted.&nbsp; But if a close contact is determined, it would &#8212; it would not be through yesterday&#8217;s briefing.&nbsp; So, we just wanted to be clear about that.<br><br>I&#8217;m going to speak briefly about the first day and a half of Judge Jackson&#8217;s committee hearing, and then I&#8217;m going to pass it over to National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, who will make some remarks at the top and then he&#8217;s happy to take some questions on the trip.&nbsp; And he has a hard out where &#8212; I&#8217;ll call it.<br><br>And then again, please let us know if you have any follow ups after the briefing.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll strive to get you answers, and we appreciate everybody&#8217;s flexibility today.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, just a couple of things from the first day and a half of Judge Jackson&#8217;s committee hearing.&nbsp; The President watched portions of Judge Jackson&#8217;s hearing yesterday and today and is proud of the way she is showcasing her extraordinary qualifications, her experience, and her even-handedness.&nbsp; Her dedication to following the facts, the law, and our Constitution as an independent judge is clear.<br><br>He was also moved by the grace and dignity she has shown, the deference to senators, and the level of detail she is offering, reinforcing the value of her experience, her intellect, and the strength of her character.&nbsp;<br><br>The President was particularly struck when, reacting to Senator Leahy raising the broad support she&#8217;d received from the law enforcement community, Judge Jackson spoke about her family members who have served as police officers, saying, &#8220;I know what it&#8217;s like to have loved ones who go off to protect and to serve, and the fear of not knowing whether or not they&#8217;re going to come home again because of crime in the community.&nbsp; Those are not abstract concepts or political slogans to me.&#8221;<br><br>As a former Chairman of the Judiciary Committee, President Biden also appreciated her respect for the intent of lawmakers and the text of the law.&nbsp; He appreciated Judge Jackson&#8217;s commitment to stay in the lane of judges prescribed by the Constitution and her highlighting the importance of precedent.<br><br>He was also struck by how she swiftly dismantled conspiracy theories put forward in bad faith.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been debunked by numerous fact checks, experts, and the record itself.<br><br>In selecting Judge Jackson, President Biden sought the opinions of Republicans and Democrats, who made clear they wanted someone have deep experience in the mold of Justice Breyer.<br><br>Today&#8217;s testimony and Judge Jackson&#8217;s endorsements by leading conservative jurists and some of the biggest law enforcement organizations in our country make clear she is indeed in Justice Breyer&#8217;s mold.&nbsp;<br><br>And with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to Jake, who has a topper for you, and then he&#8217;ll take some questions.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll make a few comments, and then, as Chris said, I&#8217;d be happy to take your questions.<br><br>The President is heading to Europe tomorrow to reinforce the incredible unity we built with Allies and partners in response to Russia&#8217;s brutal invasion of Ukraine and to consult on next steps.<br><br>Let me take a moment to set the context for this trip. Russia intended to accomplish three basic objectives in launching its unprovoked attack against Ukraine: first, to subjugate Ukraine; second, to enhance Russian power and prestige; and third, to divide and weaken the West.<br><br>Russia has thus far manifestly failed to accomplish all three objectives.&nbsp; In fact, it has thus far achieved the opposite.<br><br>On the first, the brave citizens of Ukraine are refusing to submit.&nbsp; They&#8217;re fighting back.&nbsp; They&#8217;re defending their homes.&nbsp; They&#8217;re defending their cities.&nbsp; And although Russia may take more territory in these brutal military operations, it will never take the country away from the Ukrainian people.<br><br>On the second, Russian power and prestige has been badly depleted.&nbsp; The Russian military has dramatically underperformed.&nbsp; The Russian economy has been rocked by powerful sanctions.&nbsp; The Russian high-tech and defense sectors are being choked off from key inputs.&nbsp; And Russia is a pariah in the international community.<br><br>On the third, the nations of the free world are more united, more determined, and more purposeful than at any point in recent memory.<br><br>For our part, since President Biden and the United States began warning the world of impending Russian aggression back in November, we have clearly and consistently pursued three lines of effort: first, help Ukraine defend itself by supplying weapons and military equipment; second, impose severe and escalating economic costs on Russia through the application of unprecedented sanctions in close coordination with Allies and partners in Europe, the Indo-Pacific, and other parts of the world; and third, fortify NATO and the Western Alliance by enhancing our force posture on the eastern flank and making our allies more resilient against other forms of Russian aggression.<br><br>We&#8217;ve made decisive moves on all three fronts, and President Biden&#8217;s trip will involve further actions on each of these three fronts.<br><br>He will attend an emergency NATO Summit, joined by the leaders of the other 29 NATO Allies.&nbsp; He will join the G7 leaders.&nbsp; And he will address the 27 leaders of the European Union at a session of the European Council.&nbsp; He will have the opportunity to coordinate on the next phase of military assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>He will join our partners in imposing further sanctions on Russia and tightening the existing sanctions to crack down on evasion and to ensure robust enforcement.&nbsp;<br><br>He will work with Allies on longer-term adjustments to NATO force posture on the eastern flank.&nbsp; He will announce joint action on enhancing European energy security and reducing Europe’s dependence on Russian gas at long last.&nbsp;<br><br>He will announce further American contributions to a coordinated humanitarian response to ease the suffering of civilians inside Ukraine and to respond to the growing flow of refugees.<br><br>From Brussels, President Biden will travel to Poland, where he will engage with U.S. troops who are now helping to defend NATO territory, and he will meet with experts involved in the humanitarian response.<br><br>He will also hold a bilateral meeting with President Duda of Poland.<br><br>I&#8217;ll leave further details on the schedule and program for each of these aspects of the trip to our trusty Communications and Press team.<br><br>Let me close with this: There will be hard days ahead in Ukraine &#8212; hardest for the Ukrainian troops on the frontlines and the civilians under Russian bombardment.&nbsp; This war will not end easily or rapidly.<br><br>For the past few months, the West has been united.&nbsp; The President is traveling to Europe to ensure we stay united, to cement our collective resolve, to send a powerful message that we are prepared and committed to this for as long as it takes, and to advance our response on all three critical fronts that I&#8217;ve described: helping the Ukrainian people defend themselves, imposing and increasing costs on Russia, and reinforcing the Western alliance.<br><br>And with that, I&#8217;d be happy to take your questions.<br><br>Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jake.&nbsp; The Russians and the Hungarians seem to be reluctant on imposing a ban on importing Russian oil and gas.&nbsp; Will this weaken the sanctions?&nbsp;<br><br>And would you call on the groups that the President is going to meet to exclude Russia from the G20, of course, group?&nbsp;<br><br>And do you think that an agreement with Iran could be reached without Russia?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, when the President announced that the United States was going to ban the import of Russian oil and gas, he was very clear.&nbsp; He said that the United States is uniquely positioned: We are an energy producer.&nbsp; We can do this.&nbsp; We can take this step of banning the import of Russian oil and gas and coal and be able to withstand it, have resilience against it.&nbsp;<br><br>But he also recognized quite explicitly in that statement that some of our European Allies and partners would not be able to follow suit, and he was not going to pressure them to do so.&nbsp;<br><br>From his perspective, what we have achieved with our European partners &#8212; in terms of financial sanctions, export controls, and other measures to hit the Russian economy hard &#8212; have had unprecedented impact on a large economy at a scale we have never seen before.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, he believes that that is in fact increasing the costs on Russia; it is sharpening the choice for Russia.&nbsp; And he feels very good about where things stand today in terms of the unity and resolve of the Western alliance on sanctions.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And as I mentioned in my opener, we will have more to say on sanctions in the coming days.<br><br>On the question of the G20, I will just say this: We believe that it cannot be business as usual for Russia in international institutions and in the international community.&nbsp; But as for particular institutions and particular decisions, we&#8217;d like to consult with our Allies, consult with our partners in those institutions before making any further pronouncements.<br><br>Finally, we believe that if there is an Iran nuclear deal that meets the standards the President has set to verifiably block the pathway of Iran to get to a nuclear weapon and put this program back in the box after President Trump let it out of the box when he left the deal back in 2018, we will do that deal because we believe it is in the American national security interest to do so.&nbsp; But we will not do that deal until it meets those objectives.<br><br>Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, thank you very much.&nbsp; If you can tell us anything more about the sanctions &#8212; you did just say “further sanctions” &#8212; anything more about what areas that could be in, that would be great.&nbsp;<br><br>And the other thing is, there was a report out that British troops are basically secretly training Ukrainians to use this very sophisticated anti-aircraft weapons &#8212; the “Star,&#8221; I think, or “Start” or something like that.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there any U.S. troops in Eastern Europe or anywhere else currently training Ukrainians (inaudible)?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, as for the first question, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of an announcement which will be rolled out in conjunction with our Allies on Thursday when the President has the opportunity to speak with them.&nbsp; That&#8217;s on a further package of sanctions.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>What I will say is that one of the key elements of that announcement will focus not just on adding new sanctions, but on ensuring that there is joint effort to crack down on inva- &#8212; evasion, on sanctions busting, on any attempt by any country to help Russia basically undermine, weaken, or get around the sanctions.&nbsp; That is an important part of this next phase.<br><br>We have applied an enormous amount of economic pressure.&nbsp; And in order to sustain and escalate that pressure over time, part of that is about new designations, new targets, but a big part of it is about effective enforcement and evasion &#8212; applying the lessons that we&#8217;ve learned from other circumstances where we have, in fact, imposed sanctions on countries.&nbsp; So, stay tuned for that.<br><br>On the question of U.S. troops, we do not have U.S. troops currently training Ukrainians.&nbsp; We do not have U.S. troops on the territory of Ukraine.&nbsp; We do, of course, have U.S. troops defending NATO territory, providing reassurance to our Allies, deterring Russian aggression.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And, of course, the United States is playing a key role not just in the direct provision of military equipment to Ukraine but in the facilitation of military equipment provided by many of our Allies as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, sir.&nbsp; Two questions, quickly.&nbsp; Moments ago, you said at the beginning that Russia would never take Ukraine.&nbsp; But does the President believe that Ukraine can win a military victory here?&nbsp; And if so, why haven&#8217;t we heard that from him thus far?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And then my second question is: With regards to Russia and partnership with the United States and certain institutions, what does the President hope that Russia can bring to the Iran nuclear deal?&nbsp; What do they have to bring to the table after they have rightfully been made a pariah on the world stage?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I can describe to you what happened with the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action back in 2015.&nbsp;<br><br>One of the key roles that Russia played in the implementation of that deal was that Russia actually accepted the enriched uranium from Iran so that Iran’s stockpile &#8212; stockpile stayed below 300 kilograms total, meaning that stockpile was so small that Iran could not swiftly break out to a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; That is a key part of how we ensured that Iran&#8217;s nuclear program was in a box.<br><br>Now, we don&#8217;t have to rely on any given country for any particular element of the deal, but that is a role that Russia played in the past &#8212; a practical role that didn&#8217;t have necessarily political significance but did have that practical significance.&nbsp;<br><br>What I said was that Russia is never going to take Ukraine away from the Ukrainian people &#8212; never going to be able to subjugate the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; That was not a statement about particular slice of territory that a Russian advance could occupy for a period of time or about a particular battle that some Russian element could win.&nbsp;<br><br>I would refer you over to the Pentagon in terms of the best military analysis for how particular battles in particular fronts will play out.&nbsp;<br><br>But what &#8212; I will say this: Whether Russia takes a city or takes a town or takes more territory, they are never going to be able to achieve the purpose that they set out, which was to subjugate this country, to bring this country to heel, because the Ukrainian people have made very clear that they will not be subjugated, no matter what it takes.&nbsp;<br><br>Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, thank you for being here.&nbsp; But to follow up on that question, is it the policy of this government that Ukraine should win this, it should reject Russia and regain its sovereignty and its freedom?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve said from the outset that we are unwavering in our commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within the internationally recognized borders of Ukraine.&nbsp; We remain committed to that as our proposition for this.&nbsp;<br><br>But in the immediate day-to-day of this conflict, our focus is on ensuring that Ukraine has the tools that it needs to defend itself and to be able to effectively ensure that Russia cannot achieve its objectives in Ukraine.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re focused on right now.&nbsp;<br><br>But on the basic proposition of Russia&#8217;s &#8212; of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, from day one of the Biden administration, we have not wavered an inch on that.<br><br>Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me follow up on one thing, Jake &#8212; on Article 5 and any cyberattack that comes now.&nbsp; Obviously, Russians have done it before; it wasn&#8217;t an Article 5 issue then.&nbsp; Does something in Ukraine now change the contour of a cyberattack against any member nation of a &#8212; of NATO become an Article 5 issue &#8212;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, in the June summit last &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; having the President raise that just yesterday as dramatically as he did?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, last June, when the NATO leaders gathered for the NATO Summit, President Biden &#8212; consulting with them, we put out a statement that spoke to cyberattacks and their relationship to Article 5.&nbsp; And we could see circumstances in which a collective response by the Alliance to a cyberattack would be called by an Ally.&nbsp; That is absolutely something where we and other countries could bring capabilities to bear to help a country both defend itself and respond to a particular cyberattack.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, that&#8217;s not necessarily the same thing as a military response.&nbsp; That response could take many different forms.&nbsp; But we have made clear through NATO documents now &#8212; not just last year, but going back years &#8212; that cybersecurity is an Alliance issue, is &#8212; it is an issue where, collectively, NATO is prepared to pull together both to enhance resilience, enhance defenses, and, if necessary, use the appropriate tools to respond.<br><br>Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; It’s been just over a week since you met with your Chinese counterpart, a couple of days since the President spoke with President Xi.&nbsp; Have you seen any indications that China will or will not provide assistance to Russia?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t make predictions going forward.&nbsp; What I can tell you is we have not seen since those meetings or since the President&#8217;s conversation with Xi the provision of military equipment by China to Russia.&nbsp; But, of course, this is something we are monitoring closely.&nbsp; We will continue to monitor it.&nbsp; And the President made clear to President Xi the implications and consequences of any such provision of equipment, and they very well understand one another.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And where does this fall on the agenda at the NATO Summit?&nbsp; Will there be an effort to try to put specific concrete steps in place if China does provide that assistance?<br><br>MR.&nbsp; SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President will certainly consult on the question of China&#8217;s potential participation in the conflict of Ukraine while he&#8217;s in Brussels &#8212; he&#8217;ll do so with NATO.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll also do so when he addresses the 27 leaders of the European Union, because, on April 1st, the European Union is having a summit with China.&nbsp; And so, this will be an opportunity &#8212; Thursday &#8212; for the United States and our European partners to coordinate closely on what our message is.&nbsp; We believe we&#8217;re very much on the same page with our European partners, and we will be speaking with one voice on this issue.<br><br>Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, I just wanted to follow up on your comment about shoring up the eastern flank of NATO.&nbsp; Are you &#8212; do you anticipate additional U.S. troop deployments to Europe?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I think there are two issues that are important to lay out.&nbsp; One is: What&#8217;s required in the immediate term?&nbsp; And right now, Secretary of Defense, the Supreme Allied Commander of Europe believe that they have effective posture today for what&#8217;s necessary today.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But, of course, that could evolve in the coming days and weeks, depending on Russia&#8217;s actions and depending on the overall threat picture.<br><br>The second is: What is the longer-term force posture &#8212; not just for this contingency, this emergency, this invasion, but over the course of time?&nbsp; That is something the President will discuss with his Allies at the NATO Summit on Thursday.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And if I might ask a quick follow-up on Russian troop casualties &#8212; a Russian media report that the outlet blamed on hackers and withdrew suggested that suggested that almost 10,000 Russian servicemen had been killed and 16,000 had been wounded in Ukraine.&nbsp; Does that &#8212; is your assessment that that number is realistic?&nbsp; Or how bad do you think the casualty situation is for Russia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’d refer you to the Pentagon for precise casualty figures.&nbsp; We do believe it numbers in the thousands.&nbsp; But it is a necessarily imprecise analysis from our part to be able to get, you know, that number down to the precise figure.&nbsp; So, I would refer you over to the Pentagon for that.</p>



<p>Yeah?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The President said yesterday, Jake, that cyberwarfare is a capability Putin has but has decided to not use yet in this iteration of this war, but administration sources have told us the Russians have this multi-phase plan to target critical infrastructure that is already underway.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ll give you a couple of specifics: Two weeks prior to the invasion, 21 U.S. energy companies targeted by hackers; they’re involved with LNG production.&nbsp;<br><br>March 9th, CISA and the FBI began working with an unnamed American pharmaceutical company whose top execs were targeted with malicious phishing attacks.&nbsp; Internally, the administration has attributed that to Russian intelligence.</p>



<p>I have a list of stuff that goes on and on here.&nbsp; Suffice it to say, this &#8212; how did these acts not constitute cyberwarfare so far already?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, the President put out a statement yesterday &#8212; a very strong, clearly worded statement &#8212; in which he said, based on evolving intelligence, we believe that attacks could occur.</p>



<p>Now, the Russians have spent years preparing the ground for attacks &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But do you &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; trying to get inside systems.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; is the position that they are not already underway?&nbsp; Just want to clarify.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; what I think we would distinguish between is gaining access to a system, which could be used for a variety of purposes &#8212; intelligence collection or mere preparation for a future attack &#8212; and the actual disruptive, destructive type of attack of the kind you saw that shut down the Colonial Pipeline last year, for example, or attack JBS Foods.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s really that latter thing that we have not yet seen.</p>



<p>But how one defines cyberwarefare [sic] &#8212; warfare or cyberattacks, of course, is going to differ across individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The distinction the President was making was the distinction between all of that preparatory work, which has been ongoing for years and has, in fact, intensified, and the type of destruction or disruption &#8212; the launch of a particular form of malware, for example &#8212; that would result in the kinds of physical effects we&#8217;ve seen in past attacks.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So no successful attacks yet?&nbsp; Just want to clar- &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about talk &#8212; concerns about the use of nuclear weapons, including possibly smaller nuclear weapons.&nbsp; Can you just address those concerns and talk about how that might come up on this trip?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, President Putin, in the early days of the conflict, actually raised the specter of the potential use of nuclear weapons.&nbsp; It is something that we do have to be concerned about.&nbsp; Based on our current analysis, we have not changed our nuclear posture to date.&nbsp; But we are constantly monitoring for that potential contingency.&nbsp; And of course, we take it as seriously as one could possibly take it.</p>



<p>We will be consulting with Allies and partners on that potential contingency, among a range of others, and discussing what our potential responses are.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to speak to that from this podium today.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to let the President have the opportunity to speak with his fellow colleagues on what is a very weighty matter.</p>



<p>Yeah?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen was asked yesterday &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are Vladimir Putin’s days numbered, Jake?&nbsp; Are Vladimir Putin’s days in power numbered?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; From our perspective, what happens with respect to the Russian political system is something that will be worked out inside Russia.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we can do is put forward our basic three lines of effort.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing: helping the Ukrainians defend themselves, fortifying the NATO Alliance, and imposing costs and consequences.</p>



<p>MR. MEAGHER:&nbsp; We’ve got time for one more.&nbsp; We’ve got time for one more.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have two questions on Russia and North Korea and China.&nbsp; There is a report today that the North Korea’s cyber-hacking organization is related to Russians&#8217; cyber-criminal organization.&nbsp; Do you have any information on that?</p>



<p>And I follow up next.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m sorry, can you just repeat the question?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; North Korea’s cyber-hacking organization is related to Russian’s cyber-criminal organization.&nbsp; Do you have any information on this?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; All I can say, generally, is that North Korea’s cyber capabilities have &#8212; have been manifest in the world and they work with all kinds of cyber criminals around the world, including Russian cyber criminals.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got nothing further for you on that today.</p>



<p>Yeah, I’ll take one more.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jake.&nbsp; Do have any expectation &#8212; do you have any specific comments or expectations on the meeting between &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What specifically does &#8212; what specifically &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; between President Xi and President Zelenskyy that&#8217;s scheduled to happen soon?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sorry, I told her &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, I’m sorry.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; that I would call on her &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jake.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; so I&#8217;ve got to &#8212; I&#8217;ve got to let her ask the question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What specifically does the President hope to accomplish when he&#8217;s in Poland?&nbsp; And why did he feel that it would be helpful for him to go to Warsaw at this time, particularly when the Vice President was there less than two weeks ago?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, Poland has taken the brunt of the humanitarian impact outside of Ukraine in terms of the refugee flows.&nbsp; Poland is where the United States has surged a significant number of forces to be able to help defend and shore up the eastern flank.&nbsp; Poland has to contend not just with the war in Ukraine but with Russia&#8217;s military deployments to Belarus, which have fundamentally changed the security equation there.</p>



<p>And so, for all of those reasons, we feel that it is the right place for him to go to be able to see troops, to be able to see humanitarian experts, and to be able to meet with a frontline and very vulnerable ally.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I’ll &#8212; I&#8217;ll leave it at that, guys.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>MR. MEAGHER:&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, is he meeting with refugees?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>(Mr. Sullivan returns to the podium to retrieve his facemask.)</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Oh, sorry.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he meeting with refugees, Jake?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We’ll &#8212; we’ll &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I thought you said &#8212; Psaki said that you&#8217;d tell us &#8212; you &#8212; you might be able to tell us today.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I think I said at the outset that we’ll go through the precise details of the schedule (inaudible).<br><br>2:12 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/22/statement-from-press-secretary-jen-psaki-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 17:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, in preparation for travel to Europe, I took a PCR test this morning. That test came back positive, which means I will be adhering to CDC guidance and no longer be traveling on the President’s trip to Europe. I had two socially-distanced meetings with the President yesterday, and the President is not considered a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, in preparation for travel to Europe, I took a PCR test this morning. That test came back positive, which means I will be adhering to CDC guidance and no longer be traveling on the President’s trip to Europe.</p>



<p>I had two socially-distanced meetings with the President yesterday, and the President is not considered a close contact as defined by CDC guidance. I am sharing the news of my positive test today out of an abundance of transparency.</p>



<p>The President tested negative today via PCR test.</p>



<p>Thanks to the vaccine, I have only experienced mild symptoms. In alignment with White House COVID-19 protocols, I will work from home and plan to return to work in person at the conclusion of a five-day isolation period and a negative test.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Business Roundtable&#8217;s CEO Quarterly&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/21/remarks-by-president-biden-before-business-roundtables-ceo-quarterly-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 02:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Business Roundtable OfficeWashington, D.C. 6:10 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; My name is Joe Biden, and I come from Delaware which has more corporations incorporated than all of the rest of the country combined.&#160; (Laughter.) And I know the Business Roundtable because in the days when I first ran for office &#8212; (clears throat)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Business Roundtable Office<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>6:10 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; My name is Joe Biden, and I come from Delaware which has more corporations incorporated than all of the rest of the country combined.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And I know the Business Roundtable because in the days when I first ran for office &#8212; (clears throat) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; in 1972, for the United States Senate, the DuPont company was the eighth-largest corporation in America.&nbsp; As they say in Delaware, they were the good old days.&nbsp; But all kidding aside, thank you for having me.&nbsp; You&#8217;re a hell of an organization.&nbsp; I appreciate it.</p>



<p>And I want to thank you, Josh.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve known each other a long, long time.&nbsp; And, you know, I&#8217;ve hosted CEO roundtables, you know, in the White House, including with many of you over the years.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve worked together on the American Rescue Plan, on COVID, on infrastructure, supply chains, innovation, on climate and clean energy, reducing costs and a whole lot more.</p>



<p>And our strategy has worked, I believe, and I think it’s still working.&nbsp; 6.7 million jobs last year –- the most ever created in one year; more than 7 million now.&nbsp; 678,000 created just last month, in one month.&nbsp; Unemployment down to 3.8 percent.&nbsp; Our economy grew at 5.7 percent last year, and the strongest in nearly 40 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we reduced the deficit, we reduced the deficit &#8212; I want to say it again: We reduced the deficit by $360 billion last year, notwithstanding all that I hear on some channels when I turn them on.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re on track to reduce it by over $1 trillion this year.</p>



<p>And that groundwork has positioned our economy to deal with &#8212; with the global problem of inflation, which is real &#8212; a lot of people are being hurt by it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it’s underscored that America is a great place to invest.</p>



<p>Intel is investing $20 million &#8212; billion in a semiconductor campus in Ohio.&nbsp; I think &#8212; Mary, I think GM is investing about $7 billion in new plant and equipment.&nbsp; And, Ford, I think you&#8217;re doing $11 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The point is: These are &#8212; these are hi- &#8212; these are history-making investments to build electric vehicles here at home.</p>



<p>We’ve seen record electric vehicle sales, along with records in solar, wind, and battery storage as well.</p>



<p>In sector after sector, we’re making it in America again.&nbsp; And that’s what my overwhelming objective is: to make it in America.</p>



<p>With the Infrastructure Law, we’re going to keep &#8212; we&#8217;re going to keep building millions of good-paying jobs, and they&#8217;re real jobs.</p>



<p>And to build on progress, the Senate and House need to work on the Innovation Bill and send it to my desk.&nbsp; It’s important for our economy and, I would argue, for our national security as well.</p>



<p>And we’re also leading on the global stage because of you all.&nbsp; I’m pleased to see American companies stepping up and doing their part.&nbsp; And what you&#8217;re doing in terms of donating to Ukraine and winding down your operations without anybody requesting it.&nbsp; I want to make that clear: You&#8217;re on your own on winding down operations in Russia.&nbsp; Not all, but many have.&nbsp; Not only you, but around the world.</p>



<p>And for the first time &#8212; on that subject, let me say this &#8212; for the first time that Putin began amassing troops along the Ukrainian border, I called for an emergency meeting of NATO in Europe to make the case that we had to be united.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The one thing I&#8217;m confident, knowing Putin fairly well &#8212; as well as, I guess, another leader could know one another &#8212; is that he was counting on being able to split NATO.&nbsp; He never thought NATO would stay resolved &#8212; stay totally, thoroughly united. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And I can assure you: NATO has never been stronger or more united in its entire history than it is today, in large part because of Vladimir Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but, you know, in response to his aggression, there has been &#8212; we presented a united front throughout NATO and in the Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Quad is &#8212; with the possible exception of India being somewhat shaky on some of this.&nbsp; But Japan has been extremely strong, so has Australia, in terms of dealing with Putin&#8217;s aggression.&nbsp; We presented a united front throughout NATO and the Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you did a hell of a lot to help us impose sanctions and incur costs &#8212; real costs on the Russian economy.&nbsp; And we’re seeing now that it mattered.&nbsp; It was really important what you all did.&nbsp; Not every one of you, but &#8212; I&#8217;m not suggesting you all had to &#8212; but those of you who did step up, it made a big &#8212; made a big difference.&nbsp; And I’m personally, as President, grateful for that.</p>



<p>But because our response &#8212; because our response is working, because the Ukrainians are fighting so valiantly and using the equipment we’ve given them &#8212; and the United States alone has committed over $2 billion to NATO.&nbsp; The idea that they don’t have enough sophisticated equipment is just simply not accurate.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to take the time to go into all of the detail here, but the point is: They have every &#8212; every equipment &#8212; every piece of equipment that makes rational sense, based on our military and NATO&#8217;s military, for them to be able to do what they&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re wreaking havoc on the &#8212; on the Russian military, whether it&#8217;s their tanks or their helicopters or their aircraft.</p>



<p>And, if you notice, they&#8217;ve just launched a &#8212; their hypersonic missile, because it&#8217;s the only thing that they can get through with absolute certainty.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; as you all know, it&#8217;s a consequential weapon.&nbsp; And &#8212; but &#8212; with the same warhead on it as a &#8212; as any other launched missile.&nbsp; It doesn’t make that much difference, except it&#8217;s almost impossible to stop it.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a reason they&#8217;re using it.</p>



<p>And now Putin’s back is against the wall.&nbsp; He wasn’t anticipating the extent or the strength of our unity.&nbsp; And the more his back is against the wall, the greater the severity of the tactics he may employ.</p>



<p>We’ve seen it before.&nbsp; He&#8217;s run a lot of false-flag operations.&nbsp; Whenever he starts talking about something he thinks NATO, Ukraine, or the United States is about to do, it means he&#8217;s getting ready to do it.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You may recall &#8212; I said this to a few of you this morning that I was able to declassify a whole range of operations that they were about to engage in without sacrificing sources and methods.&nbsp; And it was able to give everybody clear notice what was about to come.&nbsp; And it convinced a lot of our friends around the world that we know what they&#8217;re about to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, his back is against the wall.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s &#8212; now he&#8217;s talking about new false flags he&#8217;s setting up, including he&#8217;s asserting that, we, in America, have biological as well as chemical weapons in Europe &#8212; simply not true.&nbsp; I guarantee you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They&#8217;re also suggesting that Ukraine has biological and chemical weapons in Ukraine.&nbsp; That’s a clear sign he is considering using both of those.&nbsp; He&#8217;s already used chemical weapons in the past, and we should be careful of what about &#8212; of what&#8217;s about to come.&nbsp; He knows there&#8217;ll be severe consequences because of the united NATO front, but the point is: It&#8217;s real.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what I want to mention very much &#8212; very quickly with you all is: One of the tools he’s most likely to use, in my view, in our view, is cyber &#8212; cyberattacks.&nbsp; They have a very sophisticated cyber capability.</p>



<p>I’ve had, as they say in southern Delaware, where they &#8212; where they are very religious: We&#8217;ve had an &#8220;altar call,&#8221; he and I, on this issue.&nbsp; We’ve had a long conversation about, if he uses it, what would be the consequence.</p>



<p>But the point is that he has a capability; he hasn&#8217;t used it yet.&nbsp; And &#8212; but it’s part of his playbook.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve warned about the potential for Russian conduct to maliciously &#8212; malicious cyber activity in response to the cost we’d impose, with our Allies and partners, on the world.</p>



<p>But, look, today my administration has issued renewed warnings that, based on evolving intelligence, Russia may be planning a cyberattack against us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I&#8217;ve said, the magnitude of Russia&#8217;s cyber capacity is fairly consequential, and it&#8217;s coming.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The federal government is doing its part to get ready.&nbsp; But under U.S. law, as you all remember, the private sector, all of you, largely decides the protections that we will or will not take in order to protect your sources.</p>



<p>But let me be absolutely clear about something: It&#8217;s not just in your interests that are at stake with their potential use of cybersecurity, it is in &#8212; the national interest is at stake.</p>



<p>&nbsp; And I would respectfully suggest it&#8217;s a patriotic obligation for you to invest as much as you can in making sure &#8212; and we will urge &#8212; we&#8217;ll help in any way that you have built up your technological capacity to deal with cyber capa- &#8212; with cyberattacks: first, to protect your own companies; second, that provides critical &#8212; as providers of critical services that Americans rely on, from power to clean water; and finally, your role you can play in helping secure every American and every American’s privacy.</p>



<p>For example, banks can turn on cybersecurity by default for every customer so America&#8217;s financial data is safe.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re prepared to help you, as I said, with any tools and expertise we possess if you&#8217;re ready to do that.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s your decision as to the steps you&#8217;ll take and your responsibility to take them, not ours.</p>



<p>Now we need to do what&#8217;s necessary to support Ukraine, but we also need to step up for the families here at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In 2019, your organizations realized &#8212; or, excuse me, released a statement with a signature of almost everyone in this room.&nbsp; And it says, quote, “America deserves an economy that allows each person to succeed through hard work and creativity, and to lead a life of meaning and dignity.”&nbsp; And it expressed a commitment from you to invest in your workforce and support local communities.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t a do-gooder statement; it was a capitalist statement.&nbsp; We’re all capitalists in this room.&nbsp;&nbsp;And you did the right thing, in my view, in the assertion of that statement.</p>



<p>This was your view about how to run strong, profitable companies over the long term.&nbsp; And this commitment of consequence and pear- &#8212; for &#8212; prepare for the free world is vital that you reaffirm that commitment, in my humble opinion.</p>



<p>We can’t afford to prioritize shareholders at the expense of your stakeholders, the environment, your workers, your customers, your communities where they live and work.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re not doing that, but I think the inclination &#8212; would be inclined to do that on some occasions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Instead, now&#8217;s the time to invest in your people.&nbsp; You can hire and retain the best workforce &#8212; best-trained workforce in the entire world, which you&#8217;ve been doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To invest in innovation so you can &#8212; we can deliver better and more affordable products and services from &#8212; to more Americans.</p>



<p>To innovate with and for diversity, as you said in your statement, as you &#8212; as you committed to earlier this year.</p>



<p>Cultivating tools of artificial intelligence and advanced [to advance] dignity and opportunity for all Americans is what you’ve been doing, many of you, and it really matters.</p>



<p>And to invest in America itself in manufacturing; created over 450,000 manufacturing jobs because of you all, and it really matters.&nbsp; It hadn’t happened in a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As one of my colleagues from the Midwest said: We&#8217;re not going to talk about the Rust Belt anymore; we&#8217;re going to talk about new, expanded manufacturing capacity in the Middle &#8212; in the Middle Atlantics &#8212; excuse me, in the Midwest.</p>



<p>And to invest in America itself &#8212; in manufacturing, climate resilience, clean energy &#8212; so America can win the competition in the 21st century.</p>



<p>And it won&#8217;t hurt your bottom lines or the economy.&nbsp; It helps continue us &#8212; it’ll help us grow while lowering costs and lowering the deficit.</p>



<p>So, I want to thank you again for &#8212; there’s much more to say, but I&#8217;ve already probably taken too much time &#8212; of your time right now.</p>



<p>But I&#8217;m happy &#8212; I&#8217;m told I&#8217;m &#8212; we’re going to take some questions, Mary.&nbsp; Is that right?&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m happy to start taking questions.</p>



<p>But thank you for all you&#8217;ve been doing.</p>



<p>I think &#8212; you know, my mother had an expression: &#8220;Out of everything terrible, something good will come if you look hard enough for it.&#8221;</p>



<p>I think this presents us with some significant opportunities to make some real changes.&nbsp; You know, we are at an inflection point, I believe, in the world economy &#8212; not just the world economy, in the world.&nbsp; It occurs every three or four generations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As one of &#8212; as one of the top military people said to me in a secure meeting the other day, 60 &#8212; 60 million people died between 1900 and 1946.&nbsp; And since then, we’ve established a liberal world order, and that hadn’t happened in a long while.&nbsp; A lot of people dying, but nowhere near the chaos.</p>



<p>And now is a time when things are shifting.&nbsp; We’re going to &#8212; there’s going to be a new world order out there, and we’ve got to lead it.&nbsp; And we’ve got to unite the rest of the free world in doing it.</p>



<p>So, anyway, I’m going to hush up.&nbsp; Mary, fire away.</p>



<p>(The press departs.)</p>



<p>6:25 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
