<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 16:27:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on Actions to Expand Infant&#160;Formula</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/17/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-actions-to-expand-infant-formula/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 15:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (May 16, 2022) 7:34 P.M. EDT MR. MUNOZ:&#160; All right, good evening.&#160; Happy Monday, everybody.&#160; Thank you for joining us on this call tonight to discuss some updates from the administration on efforts to increase the availability of safe infant formula supply across the United States. As a reminder, this call will be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(May 16, 2022)</p>



<p>7:34 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, good evening.&nbsp; Happy Monday, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us on this call tonight to discuss some updates from the administration on efforts to increase the availability of safe infant formula supply across the United States.</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; It will be embargoed until the conclusion of the call.</p>



<p>At the beginning, we have a few brief remarks and then we can just get into a couple of questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Joining us on the call is [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].&nbsp; And with that, I will kick it to [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, Kevin.&nbsp; As you know, getting more safe infant formula onto shelves across the country is one of the President’s top priorities.&nbsp; We understand how stressful it is for parents trying to feed their children &#8212; I say that as someone expecting my second child in June &#8212; and that’s why this administration has been working for weeks to address the infant formula shortage.</p>



<p>It’s important to remember that this shortage exists because one manufacturer, Abbott Nutrition, closed a facility in Michigan due to safety concerns from the FDA.&nbsp; That facility was a major producer of formula that families in this country rely on.&nbsp; And you have heard from us about our ongoing, 24/7 work to tackle the issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to provide an update tonight on just a couple of very recent developments.&nbsp; First, today, FDA and Abbott agreed on next steps to reopen the Michigan plant that is currently closed.&nbsp; This is a critical step in resolving the shortages that are impacting families across the country today.</p>



<p>Abbott and the federal government signed a formal consent decree that outlines the steps to get the facility reopened and produce &#8212; and producing formula again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The consent decree requires that Abbott retain an independent expert to review the facility’s operation and ensure compliance with the law.&nbsp; It includes requirements for testing products and for promptly notifying the FDA should any contamination be detected.</p>



<p>And the consent decree also requires the implementation of a detailed sanitation plan, an environmental monitoring plan, a new employee training program.&nbsp; So a robust document outlining a key series of basic steps that the parties have agreed to.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, also today, we took another important step with the FDA releasing guidance under which major formula manufacturers can ask to safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market.</p>



<p>Companies will need to apply with the FDA, and FDA is prepared to review applications quickly and respond to them rapidly.&nbsp; FDA will prioritize review of applications that are most likely to be successful and will get the most formula to U.S. shelves as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>FDA is going to be closely evaluating quality and safety and safety history to ensure that only safe product will come to American shelves.</p>



<p>At the White House, we have alerted embassies and retailers and manufacturers to identify potential companies that could make use of the new importation process.&nbsp; And we’ll continue working with folks as we get this process moving.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, I want to highlight that throughout the weekend we’ve been working closely with manufacturers and retailers that are today producing formula for the U.S. market to identify transportation and logistical needs to increase the amount and speed of approved formula that’s being shipped into the country, and to ensure that formula that is being produced here or coming in from abroad is quickly moving from factories to retailers.&nbsp; And we’ve offered logistical support, and we’ll be, you know, continuing to conduct that outreach and identify ways to be helpful.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fourth, we’ve also continued to engage with pediatricians and parents’ groups and other stakeholders to hear from them and to share information about resources and (inaudible) during this time.</p>



<p>So, taken together, the steps we&#8217;re announcing today should continue to make a difference for families.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be working overtime to get more formula on shelves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, back to you, Kevin.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Don&#8217;t be shy &#8212; if you have questions, we have some time.&nbsp; First let&#8217;s go to Spencer Kimball at CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for doing the call.&nbsp; So the FDA said that, you know, it streamlined the process at ports, and imports have increased 300 percent since last year.&nbsp; Can you just say where exactly are the imports coming from &#8212; what companies, what countries?&nbsp; How long does the administration expect the situation to take until supply is kind of normalized?</p>



<p>And then also, in the consent decree, the Justice Department said that products were adulterated.&nbsp; Abbott has denied that.&nbsp; So did the FDA find contaminated baby powder at the facility?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], you want to take the first part of that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So I can take the piece on the consent decree.&nbsp; So, you know, I don&#8217;t want to get into a, like, huge back-and-forth on exactly the findings of facts between the agencies or between the parties here.</p>



<p>The consent decree reflects that there was a history of, you know, product disposal at the facility because of concerns about contamination, and so it&#8217;s consistent with that.&nbsp; But I would refer you to DOJ and to Abbott for, you know, specifics on the terms of the consent decree.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], if you can jump in.&nbsp; I think you&#8217;re best positioned to weigh in on where are you seeing imports are coming from.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And if not, I will (inaudible).</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, it&#8217;s working now.&nbsp; I had trouble unmuting my line, so apologies for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, when we look at our trade data, the sources of imports for formula currently include Ireland, Chile, the Netherlands.&nbsp; You know, as we look at the kind of countries that have health and safety inspection systems similar to our own, may be able to meet that quantity and labeling and nutritional guidance standards that [senior administration official] laid out, we can imagine Australia, New Zealand, the UK also being countries that, you know, product could be imported from.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Alex Alper at Reuters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Can you hear me okay?</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We can.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; I guess &#8212; you know, you mentioned the importance of facilitating transportation.&nbsp; And I was wondering if you could say, you know, what specific transportation help has the White House offered to the companies involved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, just to follow up on something that was mentioned I think late last week, which was the possibility of invoking the DPA.&nbsp; And I wondered if that was still under consideration and how specifically it could help increase production.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; On the &#8212; I can take those questions.</p>



<p>On the transportation side, you know, we&#8217;ve talked to the retailers, we&#8217;ve talked to the manufacturers.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve told them, “Let us know if you&#8217;re having some specific transportation, logistical challenges somewhere in your supply chain where we could offer some help.”&nbsp; Thus far, we&#8217;re still working through those requests, and I have no specific update to report on that side.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we have seen generally during this supply chain crisis &#8212; because we have a Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force that the administration has been running &#8212; that, in some instances, we’re able to help improve communication between all the firms and the logistics industry, and between suppliers and their customers to help speed up the movement of goods through the supply chain.</p>



<p>On the question of the Defense Production Act, here we are continuing to focus on actions we can take to get more supply available as quickly as possible.&nbsp; That is, like, our primary goal.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to look at every option that is on the table there.&nbsp; No additional specific updates to offer you on the DPA there, but I will point you again to the work that the FDA has done today with their new importation guidance.&nbsp; It’s is a really critical and crucial step to quickly increasing supply in the country.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Let’s go to MJ Lee at CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp; Sorry about that.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Hey.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I was wondering if you all could share or know when the last time was that the FDA inspected the Michigan facility that&#8217;s opening up again.&nbsp; And will FDA officials be there throughout the reopening process?&nbsp; And just if you could walk us through how that would work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then just on the new guidance you mentioned for applying to import formula, you said that you hope to go through some of these applications pretty quickly.&nbsp; Do you have a sense of a general timeline for that?&nbsp; Are we talking about days or weeks for approval?&nbsp; And also just what the quantity is that you are estimating.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so on the first question, I would refer you to the FDA.&nbsp; As you know, they&#8217;re an independent scientific entity that conducts, you know, independent inspections and enforcement activities.&nbsp; So I would refer you to them for details on what they can share about when they have been on site and, you know, the schedule there.</p>



<p>On the timing for reviewing applications, FDA, you know, has asked companies to provide them with information that they can review.&nbsp; FDA has made clear that they will prioritize applications that stand a good chance of being successful, that indicate, sort of, clear quality and safety and nutritional adequacy and all of that, and that have potential to move significant products into the United States quickly.</p>



<p>You know, we expect &#8212; well, the process has been designed to move rapidly so that FDA, again, can evaluate those applications that have a clearer chance of success and move forward on those on those quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t have a specific timeline or number of days to give you tonight.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Next question, let&#8217;s go to Alyssa Rosenberg, The Washington Post.</p>



<p>All right, Alyssa, we will come back to you.&nbsp;<br><br>Ben Gittleson, ABC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Along the same lines, I was wondering how soon you expect imports could be actually seen on shelves.&nbsp; I know the previous question was about the application process, but as you&#8217;re planning for supply to become available, if you could give an estimate for parents how long it would take for the imports to actually appear on shelves.&nbsp;<br><br>And then also, the White House had said earlier today that the administration had been contacting suppliers for infant formula manufacturers to let them know that their materials were critical for boosting production, and encouraging them to prioritize the production and delivery.&nbsp; I was wondering if you could provide a little bit more specific detail.&nbsp; Like, what does that actually look like?&nbsp; Are these suppliers within the U.S.?&nbsp; What type of impact will this make and how quickly?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, sure.&nbsp; On the first question, the FDA commissioner said this morning that we are talking about getting products to the shelves in, you know, a matter of weeks.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re talking just a couple of weeks to &#8212; you know, for &#8212; to get some of that imported product into the country and available in U.S. stores.<br><br>I’ll turn to [senior administration official] on the second piece.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, on the second one, you know, I can tell you broadly: You can imagine that a manufacturer of infant formula needs to assemble a range of inputs, whether it&#8217;s specific ingredients, it’s labeling, it’s packaging materials.&nbsp; And so, you know, in a few instances, they identified how it would be helpful to get some of those supplies in quicker, and we were able to contact the suppliers and let them know.&nbsp; And they were &#8212; it was a helpful flag because they were not aware of what that downstream customer was producing and were eager to help make sure that those orders were being sent quickly.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go back to Alyssa.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, sorry about that.&nbsp; So, I &#8212; you know, I just hopped off the FDA call.&nbsp; I&#8217;m hearing from you guys, from them that it&#8217;s going to be a couple of weeks.&nbsp; And what efforts are underway to connect families who can&#8217;t get formula now with the formula they need?&nbsp; Because, clearly, there are families who can&#8217;t wait a couple of weeks.<br><br>I know that, you know, the guidance has referenced trying to identify areas where out-of-stock rates are particularly high and expedite getting formula to retailers there.&nbsp; But can you talk about any resources and efforts that are helping families bridge that couple-of-weeks gap, especially because it could be longer?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, I mean, as you know, we are carefully monitoring data across the country and improving, you know, our ability to understand regional and other variations every minute.&nbsp; As we relayed last week and remains true, we do know that today there is more infant formula coming off of production lines in the U.S. than there was prior to the recall.&nbsp; And similarly, overall sales of infant formula are up 13 percent compared to the pre-recall period.&nbsp;<br><br>So there is infant formula available.&nbsp; At the same time, we are absolutely mindful of how challenging this is, and I think we have a couple of key messages for families.<br><br>One is we want families to talk to their pediatrician and have confidence that it is &#8212; it is generally safe to switch your baby between infant formula products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If there is a brand available in the store &#8212; even if it&#8217;s not your normal product or, you know, a slightly different formulation or a different brand or, you know, powder versus liquid or, you know, any of those differences &#8212; it is &#8212; the formula on U.S. shelves is safe, and it is safe to move your baby between products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We recognize that that&#8217;s scary and can be challenging, but families should have confidence buying whatever is available and providing that to their family.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time, you know, it is not &#8212; it is not safe to provide &#8212; to water down formula or to make your own infant formula at home.&nbsp; And so, we think it is important that families hear those messages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:  All right.  Last question, let&#8217;s go to Meredith Lee.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Can you hear me?</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you could just clarify the timeline for when FDA notified the White House about infant formula shortages at the Michigan plant and potential market disruptions from that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know Karine said today that the administration has been working on this 24/7 since February, but Politico reported that a whistleblower last October flagged food safety concerns to senior FDA officials.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m wondering when the FDA notified the White House about any issues at the Michigan plant and potential shortages stemming from that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not in a position to comment on any internal communication.&nbsp; The recall became public on February 17th.&nbsp; And, you know, we certainly have been very public about our activity in this space since then.&nbsp; But again, I am &#8212; I am not in a position to comment on internal communications that were &#8212; you know, that would have happened prior to that.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Well, thank you, everybody.&nbsp; As a reminder, the call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and the embargo lifts after this.&nbsp; So, thank you for joining tonight.</p>



<p>7:52 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call By Senior Administration Officials On New Cuba&#160;Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/17/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-new-cuba-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 15:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (May 16, 2022) 6:36 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; Thank you so much for calling in this evening.&#160; I know it&#8217;s late, so I won&#8217;t delay and get us started.&#160; Of note, this is a call that&#8217;s on background.&#160; So for just your own edification, we have [senior administration official], who is [redacted].&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(May 16, 2022)</p>



<p>6:36 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you so much for calling in this evening.&nbsp; I know it&#8217;s late, so I won&#8217;t delay and get us started.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of note, this is a call that&#8217;s on background.&nbsp; So for just your own edification, we have [senior administration official], who is [redacted].&nbsp; And we also have [senior administration official] &#8212; and I apologize if I misspelled her name.&nbsp; And she is also joining us for this call.&nbsp; For both of them, please use a “senior administration official” when you refer to them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This call is embargoed until &#8212; at its conclusion, and I will let you know at the end of the call.&nbsp; If you don&#8217;t get a question, but you want to answer one after the fact, feel free to contact me or State Department and we will assist you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I will turn it over to you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [moderator].&nbsp; So good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; And thanks again for jumping on the line.</p>



<p>Today we&#8217;re &#8212; the United States announced a series of measures to increase support for the Cuban people and safeguard our national security interests. </p>



<p>I&#8217;ll say that this is the result of work we&#8217;ve been doing over the last year as a part of the policy review of our Cuba policy.&nbsp; It continues to center on human rights and empowering the Cuban people to determine their own future, and we continue to call on the Cuban government to release all political prisoners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before jumping in, I want to just very quickly review some of the actions that we&#8217;ve been taking since the large-scale protests that took place last July.&nbsp; The President met with the Cuban American community and directed us &#8212; following that meeting &#8212; to take action in two primary areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first is to promote accountability for human rights abuses, for which we have announced several rounds of sanctions targeting those individuals and entities with direct ties to human rights abuses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, he directed us to explore meaningful ways to support the Cuban people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, since then, we&#8217;ve prioritized facil- &#8212; prioritized and facilitated the export of privately sourced or donated goods to the Cuban people, focusing specifically on agricultural and medical exports; facilitated U.S. private sector faith-based organizations and other NGOs to provide humanitarian support; provided guidance to individuals and entities seeking to export to Cuba for the first time; also increased our support for the families of those who were detained; and increased, by $5 million, our support for censorship circumvention technology to support the ability of the Cuban people to communicate to, from, and among each other. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the measures today, again, are practical steps that we&#8217;re taking to address the humanitarian situation and to respond to the needs of the Cuban people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden is also fulfilling his commitment to the Cuban American community and their family members in Cuba by announcing measures in four key areas, which we plan to implement in the coming weeks &#8212; these measures &#8212; willing to support greater freedom and expand economic opportunities for the Cuban people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, diving in, the four areas are: First, we&#8217;re going to reinstate the Cuba Family Reunification Parole Program and continue to increase the capacity for consular services.&nbsp; So as you all saw, we began &#8212; resumed limited immigrant visa processing in early May and are looking to make sure that we staff up so that we can begin processing the full 20,000 immigrant visas out of Havana as quickly as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, we will &#8212; we&#8217;re strengthening family ties and facilitating educational connections for American and Cuban people by expanding authorized travel.&nbsp; And on that, I’ll say specifically authorizing commercial and charter flights to locations beyond Havana.&nbsp; We are reinstating group people-to-people educational travel under a general license, among a number of other measures.&nbsp; We are not reinstating individual people-to-people educational travel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, we are increasing support for independent Cuban entrepreneurs.&nbsp; That includes encouraging commercial opportunities outside the state sector by using their access &#8212; independent Cuban entrepreneurs’ access to the Internet, cloud technology, programming interfaces, e-commerce platforms, and a number of other measures, including access to microfinance and training.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then lastly, we will ensure that remittances flow more freely to the Cuban people while not enriching those who perpetrate human rights abuses.&nbsp; And by that, I mean we are removing the limit on family remittances of $1,000 per quarter per sender/receiver pair.&nbsp; And we’ll authorize donative remittances, which will support Cuban families and independent Cuban entrepreneurs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Donative remittances will particularly be crucial in supporting the Afro-Cuban community on the island.&nbsp; And I will note that right now only one of six Afro-Cubans receives family remittances.&nbsp; We will not remove entities from the Cuba restricted list, so remittances through FINCIMEX will remain prohibited.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Most importantly, we&#8217;re going to continue to elevate the matter of human rights, the treatment of political prisoners, and in particular, we’re going to elevate the issue of labor rights in Cuba as something that &#8212; the issue of labor rights, in general, is something that is a core priority for the Biden-Harris administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, I will now defer to my colleague, who is a versed expert on all the details here, to add additional points.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Nothing for me at the top, but I&#8217;m happy to answer questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I do have a &#8212; I just have a quick question about Senator Menendez, who just released a statement saying that the announcement today “risks sending the wrong message.”&nbsp; And he says he&#8217;s dismayed to learn that the administration will authorize group travel to Cuba.&nbsp; Do you have any reaction?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I mean, what I&#8217;ll say &#8212; and I&#8217;ll allow my colleague to weigh in on this &#8212; is that, certainly, the senator’s concerns about establishing the group people-to-people travel under general license opens the door to tourism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; I think one thing to underscore is that the Treasury Department has the authority to audit groups that are organizing travel.&nbsp; And we will ensure that that travel is purposeful and in accordance with U.S. law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], I don&#8217;t know if there&#8217;s anything else you want to add to that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; We’ll certainly ensure travel is purposeful and in accordance with U.S. law.&nbsp; And we’ll note something that President Biden had said often, which is his belief that Americans are the best ambassadors for democratic values.&nbsp; And facilitating group people-to-people travel will allow for greater engagement between the American people and the promotion of their democratic values.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I wonder if you&#8217;ve reached a decision yet about the Summit of the Americas and whether Cuba will be invited.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So what I&#8217;ll say on that is &#8212; Karen &#8212; is we&#8217;ve not made &#8212; invitations have not gone out, so there&#8217;s not been a decision on that.&nbsp; This &#8212; and these policy measures, as I mentioned, have been long in the works, as you well know, and are seen as completely separate from the conversation of who attends and does not attend the summit.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, thank you very much.&nbsp; I think that &#8212; that was my &#8212; my question was the relationship between this process and the Summit of the Americas, and whether &#8212; for the countries that have expressed concern about attending the summit in the absence of a Cuban invitation, whether that timing is in any way related to the announcement you&#8217;re making today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;&nbsp; No, so the &#8212; I mean, this was always planned for what we&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; It’s a coincidence.&nbsp; But I would say that in the conversations we&#8217;ve had with other leaders, we have laid out also just the level of ambition of the summit agenda as really where the focus should be.&nbsp; And I think the large majority of interlocutors &#8212; and something where Senator Chris Dodd, as special advisor for the summit, has been very active &#8212; I think agree that we should be focusing on addressing a whole host of shared challenges in the region and not blow up the summit over who shows up and who doesn&#8217;t.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; My question goes back to the question before.&nbsp; Why are these changes being announced now?&nbsp; I mean, you say this it’s coincidental, but are these concessions to the Cuban government for the boycott on the Summit of the America?&nbsp; That’s something that people on Capitol Hill actually say right now.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I don’t &#8212; I don’t know what “on the Hill” you’re referring to.&nbsp; But, again, these are actions that we see as in the national interest of the United States.&nbsp; They are focused, they’re practical steps we are taking to find ways to expand support for the Cuban people and to do what all Cuban Americans have been asking for, which is for us to reestablish immigrant visa processing in Havana.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t know if, [senior administration official], if there&#8217;s anything else you want to add?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a time of concerning &#8212; the humanitarian situation in Cuba right now is very concerning.&nbsp; And as the President directed us to find ways to meaningfully support the Cuban people, we assessed that these measures do take steps to do so at a particularly concerning time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you very much for this.&nbsp; I really appreciate it.&nbsp; We know that on the campaign trail President Biden had referred to Trump&#8217;s policies as “failed” and wanted to reverse them.&nbsp; Is this going in the step of reversing what many have seen as a maximum-pressure-style campaign against Cuba?&nbsp; And can we expect more measures such as closer &#8212; closer relations in terms of normalization of relations?&nbsp; Could this move forward based on the reaction from the Cuban side and their attitude moving forward?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, look, I &#8212; thanks for that question.&nbsp; Again, these &#8212; these are steps that, as my colleague mentioned, are intended to help alleviate the humanitarian suffering that prompts out (inaudible) migration from Cuba and also to advance our interest in supporting the Cuban people and ensuring that Cuban Americans and Americans in general are also the best advanced ambassadors for U.S. policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, measures are ones that are a complement to what has been an active effort since July of last year to increase the pressure on human rights abuses in Cuba and to find ways to provide more direct humanitarian support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, the President&#8217;s direction has been to find ways to hold the regime accountable and to support the Cuban people.&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been what has informed this policy outcome.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you very much for doing this.&nbsp; I have actually two questions.&nbsp; The first is: Why keep Guyana processing the visas?&nbsp; Why not change everything coming back to Havana?&nbsp; What is impeding you &#8212; impeaching you to do so?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the second question is: Do you have any plans to change the five-year visa that was before, during the administration &#8212; during the Obama administration?&nbsp; I understand now it&#8217;s only one way.&nbsp; Before that, it was multiple ways for five years.&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to take that?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; At this time, we plan to process immigrant visas &#8212; many immigrant visas out of Georgetown, Guyana, while we are standing up limited immigrant visa processing in Havana.&nbsp; We intend to resume in short order the Cuban Family Reunification Parole Program out of Havana as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the reason we are continuing to process visas out of Guyana is to maximize capacity.&nbsp; We are slowly ramping up capacity in Havana.&nbsp; And as we do so, we do not want to diminish the overall numbers of interviews that we can conduct, and so we&#8217;ll keep the Georgetown option open.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with respect to the question on visa validity for B visas, I do not have anything to share at this time.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; Thanks very much for doing this.&nbsp; In 2017, the Trump administration scaled back our presence in Havana.&nbsp; And as you just said, we&#8217;re going to be increasing our presence.&nbsp; We scaled it back because of concerns about Havana Syndrome.&nbsp; And I was curious what exactly has changed that makes you feel confident that you could put more people in the embassy there.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], you want to take that?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; The President directed us to increase staff at Embassy Havana &#8212; at U.S. Embassy Havana and to do so with an appropriate security posture.&nbsp;<br><br>We have been working over the course of the last several months to put in place a plan to be able to do so.&nbsp; As you know, the top priority of the U.S. government, and Secretary Blinken has said this several times, is the safety and security of U.S. personnel overseas.&nbsp; And we are working closely with all the relevant bureaus in the Department of State and across the interagency as well on plans to investigate and get to the bottom of the anomalous health incidents.&nbsp; And then as we do so, we working to increase staff as an appropriate security posture at U.S. Embassy Havana.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp; Two quick questions.&nbsp; First, just following up on that last one: While you haven&#8217;t come to a conclusion about Havana Syndrome, are you now persuaded that the Cuban government was not responsible?&nbsp;<br><br>And more to the question of the sanctions relief here: Take us a little bit into the logic of not going back to the kind of sanctions relief that the Obama administration, or I should say Obama-Biden administration, had in place at the end of their time in office.&nbsp; And what are you getting from the leverage of holding back on some of the sanctions relief?</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, look, I&#8217;ll answer the second part and then defer to my colleague on the first part.&nbsp; Look, I think, fundamentally, these policies are ones that are designed to advance our own national interests and U.S. national security policy, specifically expanding the ability to process visas outside Havana.&nbsp; And the other is very specific steps and &#8212; specific and practical steps to create bridges to the Cuban people.<br><br>I think that what we&#8217;re going to be doing over the next several months is focusing on implementing these steps and which &#8212; you know, some of which are going to take place faster than others.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to monitor the situation in Cuba and the effects of our actions.&nbsp;<br><br>But I&#8217;ll say that the crackdown by the Cuban regime after the July 11th protests were there for, I think, the world to see.&nbsp; And the sentences that were imposed on people that were just singing in the streets and asking for food and to have a greater say in the future of their country really shows the situation &#8212; the lack of respect for human rights on the island.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something that is at the core of President Biden&#8217;s approach to the Americas and, frankly, the world.<br><br>But these are steps that we thought were designed to get specifically to the Cuban people and that were in our unilateral interest.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And with respect to your question about the anomalous health incidents, I&#8217;ll say that we are working across the interagency and State Department and with allies around the world as well to get to the bottom of the anomalous health incidents.&nbsp; And at this moment, we do not have a conclusion as to the attribution.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) much for doing this.&nbsp; I was hoping you could say when do you anticipate the invites for the summit to go out.&nbsp; And while I&#8217;m just considering this is one of the few times we&#8217;ll probably get to ask you questions about this &#8212; you know, this &#8212; you know, on this (inaudible) &#8212; can you talk any &#8212; a little bit about what goes into making the decisions of who to invite; you know, what are the factors that are being considered?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, I guess the plan is to send the invitations soon.&nbsp; And the &#8212; I guess the rationale is, look, the host has wide discretion.&nbsp; And we’ll &#8212; but we start by looking at the Inter-American Democratic Charter and the criteria that it established for inviting leaders from democratically elected governments.</p>



<p>I think the question of expanding that is one where we consult with our partners in the region.&nbsp; We have these debates about who to invite, but ultimately it is the prerogative of the host to make that decision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, good afternoon.&nbsp; So I have specific questions on the measures.&nbsp; First, do you have a timeline for when you expect the embassy in Havana to be working at full capacity where you think you&#8217;ll be meeting the 20,000 visa quota agreed with the Cuban government?&nbsp; That&#8217;s one.</p>



<p>The other: You say the authorizing of commercial and charter flights.&nbsp; So you expect that the frequencies that were available before the sanctions will be available again?&nbsp; And you said cities different from Havana.</p>



<p>And on the remittances: So you&#8217;re lifting their limit on 1,000 percent [sic] per quarter, but you&#8217;re not excluding the Cuban entity.&nbsp; So how are people going to send the money?&nbsp; And how will this specific measure benefit Afro-Cubans?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Would you like to take to the first question?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And forgive me, can you repeat the first question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How quickly are we going to get up to 20,000 in Havana?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, perfect.&nbsp; I do not have a timeframe at this time, unfortunately.&nbsp; We are working with our colleagues in the State Department and also Department of Homeland Security, which manages the Cuban Family Reunification Parole Program, to determine the pace at which we can increase capacity and visa issuance and parole practicing.</p>



<p>We aim to, and have every intent to, be in compliance with the migration accords.&nbsp; And the recent migration talks that were held last month between the United States and Cuba sought to bring both countries into compliance with their commitments for safe, legal, and orderly migration as enshrined in the migration accords.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On your second question is &#8212; so the implementation of these measures, I think we&#8217;re going to be working to move very quickly to execute on them over the course of weeks and months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when it comes to the question of visa (inaudible) or of remittance processing, certainly providing reassurance to third, kind of, electronic payment companies that there is bipartisan support for electronic payments &#8212; that is something that&#8217;s going to take time but it&#8217;s something we&#8217;re going to focus a lot on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On not removing FINCIMEX from the Cuba restricted list: Cuba is unique in the world at having the military play a role in remittance processing.&nbsp; If they were &#8212; you know, and we&#8217;ve engaged with them to underscore that if there was a civilian entity that could do the processing, that that would be something that would be acceptable, recognizing that what we want to work toward is having electronic payments expand to the extent that that&#8217;s possible.</p>



<p>So the decisions &#8212; the ball is in their court to decide.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, everybody.&nbsp; Well, that was the last question.&nbsp; Thank you so much for attending again.&nbsp; Remember, this is a call on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; And the embargo is now lifted.</p>



<p>Thank you so much.</p>



<p>7:01 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on International Day Against Homophobia, Transphobia and&#160;Biphobia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-international-day-against-homophobia-transphobia-and-biphobia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the International Day Against Homophobia, Transphobia and Biphobia, Jill and I stand in support and solidarity with lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex, (LGBTQI+) people in the United States and around the world. And we join with Americans across the country to reaffirm our commitment to the ongoing work of upholding human dignity&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On the International Day Against Homophobia, Transphobia and Biphobia, Jill and I stand in support and solidarity with lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex, (LGBTQI+) people in the United States and around the world. And we join with Americans across the country to reaffirm our commitment to the ongoing work of upholding human dignity for all people and advancing equality globally.</p>



<p>On this day in 1990, the World Health Organization took the long overdue step of declassifying ‘homosexuality’ as a mental disorder. Since that time, there has been much progress. But we continue to witness disturbing setbacks and rising hate and violence targeting LGBTQI+ people in the United States and around the world. This is wrong. LGBTQI+ people are entitled to all the rights, opportunities, and protections that belong to every human on this planet. LGBTQI+ people are an essential part of families and communities—teachers, first responders, public officials, doctors, lawyers, front-line workers, and friends who enrich and strengthen every single country.</p>



<p>And make no mistake: hateful legislative attacks against members of our own LGBTQI+ community cannot be tolerated in America or anywhere else. They spur discrimination and can stoke violence. And they are rooted in the same ignorance and intolerance that we see around the world. Hate is hate—and all of us have a responsibility to speak out against hate wherever we find it.</p>



<p>The United States leads the world not only by the example of our power, but by the power of our example. That means making commitments— and following through with action, transparency, and accountability. That’s why, last month, we released the first-ever public progress <a href="https://www.state.gov/lgbtqi-human-rights/">report</a> on my Administration’s whole-of-government approach to advance the human rights of LGBTQI+ people globally, from supporting local civil society organizations to standing up for LGBTQI+ human rights at the United Nations, and in our engagement with repressive governments.</p>



<p>By openly reporting on our own progress, the United States hopes to inspire other governments to take similar action to address the needs of their LGBTQI+ communities.</p>



<p>Strong and healthy democracies must ensure LGBTQI+ people can enjoy full participation in society and access all the benefits available to a nation’s citizens. At the first Summit for Democracy, the United States committed to facilitating the participation and leadership of LGBTQI+ community members in democratic institutions, a process we will continue to support.</p>



<p>To the LGBTQI+ community, my administration sees you. We stand with you. And we will continue to defend human rights and dignity, at home and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on the Meeting Between President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Andersson of Sweden and President Niinistö of&#160;Finland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-meeting-between-president-biden-and-prime-minister-andersson-of-sweden-and-president-niinisto-of-finland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Magdalena Andersson of Sweden and President Sauli Niinistö of Finland to the White House.  The leaders will discuss Finland’s and Sweden’s NATO applications and European security, as well as strengthening our close partnerships across a range of global issues and support for Ukraine. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Magdalena Andersson of Sweden and President Sauli Niinistö of Finland to the White House.  The leaders will discuss Finland’s and Sweden’s NATO applications and European security, as well as strengthening our close partnerships across a range of global issues and support for Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: The Biden Administration Announces Americans Can Order Additional Free At-Home, Rapid COVID-&#8288;19 Tests at&#160;COVIDTests.gov</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-announces-americans-can-order-additional-free-at-home-rapid-covid-19-tests-at-covidtests-gov/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden Administration is announcing that COVIDTests.gov is now open for a third round of ordering. U.S. households are now be able to order an additional eight free at-home tests at COVIDTests.gov—bringing the total number of free tests available to each household since the start of the program to 16. As the highly transmissible&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden Administration is announcing that COVIDTests.gov is now open for a third round of ordering. U.S. households are now be able to order an additional eight free at-home tests at COVIDTests.gov—bringing the total number of free tests available to each household since the start of the program to 16. As the highly transmissible subvariants of Omicron drive a rise in cases in parts of the country, free and accessible tests will help slow the spread of the virus.</p>



<p>In January 2022, President Biden committed to making one billion at-home tests available to the American people for free, including half-a-billion available for ordering at COVIDTests.gov. Since then, over 70 million households have visited COVIDTests.gov to order at-home tests to be mailed directly to them. To date, the Administration has delivered approximately 350 million free tests to mailboxes and doorsteps across the country, in U.S. territories, and at overseas military bases, with most tests delivered by the U.S. Postal Service within 48 hours of shipping. The third round of tests available were purchased by the federal government earlier this year with funding from the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>People who have difficulty accessing the internet or need additional support placing an order can call 1-800-232-0233 (TTY 1-888-720-7489) to get help in English, Spanish, and more than 150 other languages—8am to midnight ET, 7 days a week. For more information, people can visit: <a href="https://www.covid.gov/tests/faq">https://www.covid.gov/tests/faq</a>.</p>



<p>Since January 2021, the Biden Administration has taken significant action and invested resources provided by Congress to dramatically increase domestic COVID-19 testing manufacturing, the number of tests authorized for use in the U.S., and the number of places where Americans can get a test, as well as to decrease costs for consumers and increase access to free tests.</p>



<p>COVID-19 testing is a critical tool to help mitigate the spread of the virus, which is why maintaining domestic testing capacity is an essential component of the President’s National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan.</p>



<p>Due to Congress’s failure to provide additional funding for the nation’s COVID-19 response, the Administration cannot continue making the types of federal investments needed to sustain domestic testing manufacturing capacity, and this may jeopardize the federal government’s ability to provide free tests moving forward. Today’s announcement underscores the Administration’s commitment to doing everything in our power to ensure the American people have the lifesaving tools they need—so they are prepared for whatever comes. Congress must step up and act as well.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President Biden, First Lady Jill Biden, and Prime Minister Mitsotakis Of Greece at a Reception Honoring Greek American Relations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/16/remarks-by-president-biden-first-lady-jill-biden-and-prime-minister-mitsotakis-of-greece-at-a-reception-honoring-greek-american-relations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 03:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 5:22 P.M. EDT FIRST LADY BIDEN:&#160; Thank you, everyone.&#160; Please sit down.&#160; And thank you,&#160;Your Eminence, for your kind words.&#160; Thank you. And welcome, finally, to the Bicentennial Celebration and the very in &#8212; first in-person Greek Heritage event of our administration.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; And it’s &#8212; it’s so wonderful to see so many&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>5:22 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>FIRST LADY BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp; Please sit down.&nbsp; And thank you,&nbsp;Your Eminence, for your kind words.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>And welcome, finally, to the Bicentennial Celebration and the very in &#8212; first in-person Greek Heritage event of our administration.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And it’s &#8212; it’s so wonderful to see so many friends with us today.</p>



<p>I’m told that there’s a Greek proverb that says, “A society becomes great when its elder[s] plant trees whose” &#8212; “plant trees whose shade they know they will never enjoy.”</p>



<p>From democracy and philosophy, to astronomy and medicine, to art and literature, the legacy of Greece touches every corner of our culture.&nbsp; We all enjoy the shades of its branches.</p>



<p>And I’ve had the chance to visit Greece many times over the years.&nbsp; And I’ve stood in awe at the history of Athens and the beauty of the islands.&nbsp; And each time, I’ve been welcomed with open arms.</p>



<p>So it’s my pleasure to be able to return that welcome to you, our Greek and Greek American friends.</p>



<p>And I’m especially honored to welcome Prime Minister Mitas- &#8212; Mitsotakis and his wife.&nbsp; And we spent a couple minutes getting to know one another, and it was so nice to get to know you and Sofia and Dafni.&nbsp; You want to stand up and say hello?&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Your work is so inspiring, and I hope that we can continue to deepen our friendship.<br><br>The story of America is the story of all of you.&nbsp; You are a part of our beautiful and rich history.&nbsp; You help write our future every day.&nbsp; And the trees you plant will continue to cover our world.&nbsp; So thank you very much.<br><br>And now, as all of you know, this community has been a true partner to my husband throughout the years, and you mean so much to him.</p>



<p>So please welcome your President, my husband, Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Your Eminence, I’ve been hanging around with the Greek American community for so long, as a Roman Catholic, I bless myself the wrong way.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I find myself going right. &nbsp;I don’t know.&nbsp; I &#8212; the Pope is not real crazy about my change.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Welcome to the White House.&nbsp; It’s a welco- &#8212; it’s wonderful to be able to host this reception again in person and to welcome the Prime Minister to Washington.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We’ve had good conversations.&nbsp; And I’m delighted to welcome your wife and daughters today as well, because when it comes to Greek American relations, it’s all about family in my experience.&nbsp; As we &#8212; my grandfather Finnegan would say, “That’s the Irish of it.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But I want to welcome Speaker Pelosi.&nbsp; Where are you, Nancy?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And Paul Pelosi, her husband.<br><br>And to the members of Congress that are here today, including a great many proud Greek Americans that are here with us today.&nbsp;<br><br>And if you will excuse a point of personal privilege, I’d like to introduce John Sarbanes.&nbsp; I want you to know how much we all are thinking about and missing your dad today.&nbsp; Every day.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; His dad was an enormous influence on me and educated me a lot when I got here as a 30-year-old kid in the United States &#8212;<br><br>FIRST LADY BIDEN:&nbsp; And his mom.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Oh, his mom is there.<br><br>FIRST LADY BIDEN:&nbsp; No &#8212; and missing his mom, too.&nbsp;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Oh, yes.&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp; And missing your mom as well.&nbsp; But your dad really took me school, and I appreciate it.<br><br>And, Your Eminence, it’s great to get to honor and see you again.&nbsp; What an honor it is.&nbsp; And I want to thank you for your moral leadership and all of the work the Greek Archdiocese of America is doing to shine a light in the world.&nbsp;<br><br>And last year, we had to commemorate the bicentennial of independence virtually because of the pandemic.<br><br>And, by the way, I want to thank the proud Greek Americans who are on the forefront of the fight against COVID-19 and our efforts to vaccinate the world.<br><br>Last year, we celebrated two hundred &#8212; this year, we celebrate 201 years, the end of a year of bicentennial celebrations.&nbsp; And it’s an opportunity to honor the history of our two nations and peoples and how we share so much together &#8212; a chance to look to the future that we’re going to build together.<br><br>I’m incredibly proud the first year of my presidency was able to be the first year of the next 100 years of relations between Greece and the United States of America.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)<br><br>It’s no exaggeration to say that today our friendship and partnership and our alliance is closer and stronger than it has ever been.&nbsp; We had a great conversation.&nbsp; and the dangerous part for you all is we like one another a lot.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Our two nations are working together across the board on climate and energy, on trade and investment, on defense and disaster response, and so much more.<br><br>And our new Ambassador to Greece, George Tsunis, a proud Greek American, is with us today.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I’m not sure if I was prouder to be elected president or George to be named ambassador, which he was.&nbsp; But George &#8212; thank you, pal &#8212; has just taken up his post in Athens to continue carrying forward this important work.<br><br>And, Prime Minister, I think there is no area as vital for Greece and the United States to stand together than in the defense of our shared and diplomatic principles and our democratic systems.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The United States and the world owe a debt to the ancient Greek ideas that first taught us that “we the people” and the “demos,” our democracy, can control our own destiny.&nbsp; And you made us believe it.&nbsp; And the idea that has endured for a millennia.&nbsp; But it’s also an idea that every generation has had to fight to uphold.<br><br>Every generation has had to defeat democracy’s mortal foes.&nbsp;&nbsp; Because in our imperfect world, the appetites and ambitions of the few forever seek to dominate the lives and liberties of the many.<br><br>And, sadly, we have both discussed, including at the Summit for Democracies last year, that democracy is more under assault today than &#8212; including in the United States &#8212; than any time in the recent past.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But the Greek people know, just as the American people do, that freedom and democracy are worth sacrificing for.&nbsp; Just as the ideals of the ancient Athenians inspired America’s founders, the American Revolution, I’m presumptuous to say, helped inspire Greek patriots to fight for their own independence over 201 years ago.&nbsp;<br><br>And Greece remembers that when dictators and strongmen seek to dominate their neighbors, there is only one answer:<em>Oxi!&nbsp; Oxi!</em>&nbsp; No!&nbsp; No!&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>During World War Two, when the Axis forces of fascism were sweeping across Europe, Greece said “no,” inspiring the world through its resistance.<br><br>Today, the war and wisdom and the wanton disinformation have returned to Europe with Russia’s brutal and unprovoked attack on its neighbor, Ukraine.<br><br>We’re seeing horrific atrocities and war crimes, children being buried in mass graves, millions of refugees fleeing Putin’s war, and Greece and the United States standing as one to support the people of Ukraine and impose severe economic costs on Russia to hold Putin accountable.<br><br>And I want to thank you, Mr. Prime Minister, for the moral courage &#8212; and I mean it &#8212; the moral courage and clarity you have shown from the very beginning of this crisis: speaking out immediately to condemn Russia’s aggression, welcoming Ukrainian refugees, being a bulwark of security for NATO’s eastern and southeastern Europe and the Mediterranean.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Together, we’re showing the power and the capacity of democracies to be able to act in unison.&nbsp; And we’re helping Ukrainians say “no” to Russian aggression.&nbsp; And we’re saying “no” to tyranny and to the idea that autocracies will outpace democracies in the 21st century, because that’s what is at stake here in my view.&nbsp;<br><br>On a personal note, it’s wonderful to see so many friends here today.&nbsp; Friends like Andy and Mike Manatos &#8212; where are you guys?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Go back a long way.&nbsp; Who’ve helped with these events over the years since I was a senator and Vice President.&nbsp;<br><br>And Father Alex, who can’t be here today &#8212; I wanted him to know that he’s the reason I bless myself the wrong way.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And my friend from the University of Delaware, President Dennis Assanis.&nbsp; Where are you, Dennis?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; The President of the university and his sons, Nicholas and Dimitris.&nbsp; Welcome, gentlemen.&nbsp; It’s great to have you both here.&nbsp;<br><br>I like to joke about being known as “Joe Bidenopolous” in my Greek American community in Delaware.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I only own by 3,100 votes when I ran as a United States senator.&nbsp; And I think we got 92 percent of the Greek vote in Delaware &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and the nickname stuck.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Small population.&nbsp;<br><br>But the truth is, I’ve been blessed with lifelong friendships and political mentors in the Greek American community.<br><br>I’ve found inspiration in the courage and principled leadership of the Greek Orthodox Archdiocese of America, who fought for social justice and from the days &#8212; all the back to the days of Martin Luther King and right through George Floyd.&nbsp; And I thank you.&nbsp; I thank the church.&nbsp;<br><br>As a proud Irish American, I’ve felt a great kinship with the Greek American community.&nbsp; The same values define the way we grew up: courage, decency, honor, treating people with dignity as well as an immense pride in the heart and the heritage of our ancestors that they brought with them to America.<br><br>This is an incredible resilience among Greek Americans.&nbsp; A determination &#8212; a determination to keep going, to keep fighting, no matter the odds &#8212; no matter what.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And there’s no greater symbol of the faithfulness and perseverance of the community than seeing Greek Americans proudly celebrate the reconstitution and re-consecration of the Saint Nicholas Greek Orthodox Church and National Shrine last November in Manhattan.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The original structure was destroyed more than 20 years ago during the 9/11 terrorist attacks in our &#8212; on our country.&nbsp; And in rebuilding that sacred home of the Greek Orthodox Church and the Greek American community, reaffirmed that even in the deepest, darkest days we always have hope for the future.&nbsp; Always.&nbsp;<br><br>And today, let us tap into that same spirit and rededicate ourselves to all the hard work that lies ahead: to defend democracy in Greece, in the United States, and in all the places where it is under threat today; to stand up to the &#8212; for the dignity and rights of all people.<br><br>My dad used to have expression that everyone, no matter what &#8212; everyone &#8212; and this is not a joke; he would say it all the time &#8212; is entitled to be treated with dignity.&nbsp; Dignity.<br><br>And to renew our commitment to leave our children a world that is more peaceful and more secure and more just than we found it.&nbsp;<br><br>So I want to thank you again, Mr. Prime Minster, for making the trip and for the el- &#8212; the excellent discussions we had today.<br><br>And I look forward to see you again at the NATO Summit very soon in Spain and continuing our close cooperation on behalf of our two nations and all of our shared values.<br><br>But really, Jill and I are looking forward to seeing in Greece as well.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; The floor is yours.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER MITSOTAKIS:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you all so much.</p>



<p>Thank you, Mr. President, Dr. Biden.&nbsp; Ladies and gentlemen, it is really a great privilege to be here with you at this bicentennial celebration.&nbsp; My wife, my daughters, my team, myself are tremendously grateful for the warm reception you have offered us.</p>



<p>And honorable guests, ladies and gentlemen, thank you for joining us here tonight.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know this is a very special moment for you, Mr. President.&nbsp; I’m sure you see lots of very good friends amongst this gathering.&nbsp; But this visit, as you pointed out, has very strong historical connotations.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Modern Greece, like America before it, was forged in the hands of dreamers, of revolutionaries fighting for freedom, fighting for justice.&nbsp; And it was the story of your independence struggle and its eventual success, coming as it did decades before ours, that inspired the oppressed Greeks to fight against all odds for their own freedom.</p>



<p>The leaders of the Greek revolution drew inspiration from what was achieved on this soil.&nbsp; Our ancestors did not just dream of freedom and self-determination; they fought for democracy, Mr. President &#8212; that elusive government of the people, by the people, for the people, which was invented in ancient Greece 25 centuries ago.</p>



<p>And in his annual message on the 3rd of December, 1822, President James Monroe remarked: “The mention of Greece fills the mind with the most exalted sentiments and arouses in our bosoms the best feelings of which nature is susceptible.”&nbsp; “A strong hope,” he said, “is entertained that these people will recover their independence and resume their equal station among the nations of the earth.”</p>



<p>And it is this shared history of struggle, this shared history of sacrifice that binds our two nations together.&nbsp; It places upon us, as you said, a solemn responsibility to protect and defend the values that our forefathers risked so much to pass on to the next generations.</p>



<p>And today, this duty is more relevant than ever.&nbsp; The war in Ukraine, the invasion of Russia is a chilling reminder that what we took for granted in Europe &#8212; that maps cannot be redrawn by force &#8212; is unfortunately no longer the case.</p>



<p>As you know, Mr. President, we supported Ukraine from the very beginning with humanitarian aid but also with military assistance.</p>



<p>We did so for reasons of principle, which should be painfully obvious, but we did so also to protect a world order that is based on the premise of respect for international law &#8212; what you like to call a “rules-based” international order.</p>



<p>Neo-imperial fantasies belong to other centuries.&nbsp; They must not succeed.&nbsp; And they must not succeed not only for the sake of Ukraine, but to send a very clear signal to other authoritarian leaders that any violation of sovereignty will be met by a unified and a forceful response.</p>



<p>And this is why it is so important that Europe and the United States stand shoulder to shoulder in this fight.&nbsp; After all, what we are protecting are the values which lie at the foundations of our liberal democracies.</p>



<p>And as a Prime Minister of Greece but also as a member of the European Council, I would like to thank you again, Mr. President, for your leadership.</p>



<p>The sanctions we have imposed on Russia are crushing, and rightfully so.&nbsp; But as we discussed, we must not lose sight of the fact that our societies are paying a heavy price in terms of energy prices.&nbsp; And in this respect, there is so much more we can do together, the European Union and the United States, to bring down the prices of energy and, in particular, the price of gas.</p>



<p>And as we reduce our dependence on Russian hydrocarbons, we also need to use our market power as larger purchases of gas to deliver short-term relief to our households and our businesses.</p>



<p>Mr. President, I really mean it when I say that the relationship between Greece and the United States is today at an all-time high.</p>



<p>Last Thursday, our parliament ratified the new defense and cooperation agreement between our two countries.&nbsp; And this new cooperation manifests itself not just in the naval base at Souda Bay, on Crete, which I hope you will have an opportunity to visit.&nbsp; It has been described by many as the jewel in the crown of our fantastic military relationship.&nbsp; But it also manifests itself in the port city of Alexandroupolis in northeastern Greece, just 500 miles from the Ukrainian border.</p>



<p>And apart from its military importance for NATO, Alexandroupoli, as we discussed, is rapidly becoming a regional energy hub, an entry point for liquefied natural gas into the Balkans and Eastern Europe.&nbsp;<br><br>And Greece plans to play an important role as a gateway for electricity produced from cheap, renewable sources, primarily sun, in the Middle East, in Africa.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re very happy, Mr. President, that the U.S. has provided its unequivocal support for these projects.&nbsp;<br><br>A quick word about our region, Mr. President.&nbsp; You are extremely knowledgeable about the Cyprus issue.&nbsp; And please, use all your influence to put the negotiation process back on track in accordance with the U.N. Security Council resolutions.&nbsp; No one &#8212; no one can or will accept a two-state solution in Cyprus.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>The Balkans are also still quite fragile.&nbsp; We must keep the European perspective alive and tangible.&nbsp;<br><br>Greece is a pillar for regional prosperity and security, and we will always seek peaceful ways to resolve our differences with our neighbors.&nbsp; I’m convinced that we can achieve that.<br><br>We gre- &#8212; we place great emphasis on the 3+1 scheme &#8212; a framework that connects the U.S. with Greece, with Cyprus, and with Israel.&nbsp; And at the same time, Mr. President, we will continue to invest in our armed forces and make it very clear that we will not accept any violations of our sovereignty and our sovereign rights.&nbsp; And after all, we&#8217;re doing so in order not just to strengthen Greece, but also in order to strengthen NATO’s southeastern flank.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We will continue our longstanding cooperation between our defense industries.&nbsp; We will launch the process for the acquisition of a squadron of F-35 aircraft, and we do hope to be able to add this fantastic plane to the Greek Air Force before the end of this decade.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;m happy that on Friday, Lockheed Martin officially expressed its interest in investing in Hellenic aerospace.&nbsp; Of course, the bonds that connect us &#8212; the bonds between America and Greece reach far beyond our shared history, security and defense, and across the board from trade to tourism and technology and cultural exchanges.&nbsp; There is so much, ladies and gentlemen, to be mutually gained.&nbsp;<br><br>As you know, Greece has come through severe adversity.&nbsp; The recent economic crisis was extremely painful for our people.&nbsp; But Greeks have proven their resilience.&nbsp; Democracy in Greece has proven its resilience.&nbsp; And today, Greece bears no comparison to the Greece that became the poster boy of European financial crisis a decade ago.&nbsp;<br><br>Our economy is strong.&nbsp; Earlier this year, we paid off Greece&#8217;s outstanding debt to the IMF two years ahead of schedule.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>We are creating jobs and investing in new industries, such as digital and clean tech.&nbsp; Many European companies, wary of their dependence on China, are bringing back manufacturing jobs to the European continent, and Greece is an obvious candidate to welcome them.&nbsp;<br><br>And many American companies are investing in Greece for the first time &#8212; companies such as Microsoft, Pfizer.&nbsp; They&#8217;re doing so because they see a country that has an advantageous geographic position, that is both a member of NATO and the European Union, a country with a stable government that is welcoming foreign investors.&nbsp;<br><br>Because Greece, Mr. President, is back and a promising future lies ahead of us.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Let me conclude, Mr. President, by saying that you recognize many Greek American friends amongst this gathering tonight.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve mentioned several of them by name.&nbsp; They call you “Bidenopolous” &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; for a reason, although I suggested that maybe you should be called “Bidenakis.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It would rhyme well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m sure everyone in this audience is particularly proud today.&nbsp; I’m equally proud about what Greek Americans have achieved in the United States.&nbsp; Let me especially acknowledge the presence of your new ambassador to Greece, George Tsunis.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I met him at my office a few days ago.&nbsp; The first thing he told me was a story of his parents leaving a small village in western Greece called Platanos.&nbsp; We&#8217;re honored to welcome George back to his second homeland.</p>



<p>And, Mr. President, marking this bicentennial, albeit with a year&#8217;s delay due to COVID, matters deeply to the Greek people and to me personally.</p>



<p>Recent events make this celebration that much more pertinent.&nbsp; The fight of democracies against autocracies is a defining battle of our generation.&nbsp; And the proumo- &#8212; the proud moments from the history of our two nations give us confidence in what we can achieve in the future.</p>



<p>We should never lose sight of what our ancestors fought for and that which we must now defend.&nbsp; All of us should draw great strength from their example.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m hugely grateful to you, Mr. President, and Dr. Biden for hosting this magnificent gathering.&nbsp; And I took your word very seriously that you do intend to visit Greece &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; to reciprocate this visit.</p>



<p>Thank you again, all, very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>FIRST LADY BIDEN:&nbsp; You know, my husband has always told me that all politics is personal.&nbsp; And I think that you can see that in the relationship that Joe has with the Prime Minister.&nbsp; And Mareva and I are already making plans to see how we can work together.</p>



<p>And talking about, you know, personal relationships, I want to thank each and every one of you for the relationships that we’ve formed with all of you and the support that you’ve given us.</p>



<p>So, please enjoy the People’s House with food and drink and music.&nbsp; So, we look forward to saying hello.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>5:50 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Mitsotakis of&#160;Greece</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/16/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-mitsotakis-of-greece/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 02:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis of Greece.  The President congratulated the Prime Minister on 201 years of Greek independence. The leaders underscored that the relationship between the United States and Greece is stronger than ever, and noted the enduring people-to-people bonds that have helped define our bilateral ties&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis of Greece.  The President congratulated the Prime Minister on 201 years of Greek independence. The leaders underscored that the relationship between the United States and Greece is stronger than ever, and noted the enduring people-to-people bonds that have helped define our bilateral ties for more than two centuries. They reviewed our strong and growing defense partnership, our shared democratic values, and our commitment to further expand bilateral trade and investment. They discussed developments in Ukraine, including our strong support for efforts to impose costs on Russia for its unprovoked aggression, and pledged to continue backing the people and government of Ukraine. They also discussed developments in the eastern Mediterranean, as well as our common efforts to confront global challenges, including energy security, climate change, and threats to democracy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the Democratic Republic of Timor-Leste to Attend the Inauguration of His Excellency José Ramos-Horta and to Attend Ceremonies Commemorating the Twentieth Anniversary of the Restoration of&#160;Independence</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/16/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-democratic-republic-of-timor-leste-to-attend-the-inauguration-of-his-excellency-jose-ramos-horta-and-to-attend-ceremonies-commemorating-the-twe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53394</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Democratic Republic of Timor-Leste to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency José Ramos-Horta on May 19, 2022 and to attend ceremonies commemorating the Twentieth Anniversary of the Restoration of Independence on May 20, 2022 in Dili. The Honorable Alice P.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Democratic Republic of Timor-Leste to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency José Ramos-Horta on May 19, 2022 and to attend ceremonies commemorating the Twentieth Anniversary of the Restoration of Independence on May 20, 2022 in Dili.</p>



<p><a></a><a></a>The Honorable Alice P. Albright, Chief Executive Officer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation, will lead the delegation.</p>



<p><strong><u>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</u></strong></p>



<p>Mr. Thomas Daley, Charge d’ Affaires a.i., U.S. Embassy Timor-Leste</p>



<p>The Honorable Paloma Adams-Allen, Deputy Administrator, United States Agency for International Development</p>



<p>The Honorable Curtis Ried, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Multilateral Affairs, National Security Council</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre,&#160;May 16, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/16/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-may-16-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 23:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room   3:08 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Hello.&#160; I know that was a long two minutes.&#160; I apologize. Okay, let’s get started.&#160; So, before we start the briefing, I want to take a moment to recognize the lives lost and forever changed in Buffalo. Former Buffalo Police Lieutenant&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>  3:08 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; I know that was a long two minutes.&nbsp; I apologize.</p>



<p>Okay, let’s get started.&nbsp; So, before we start the briefing, I want to take a moment to recognize the lives lost and forever changed in Buffalo.</p>



<p>Former Buffalo Police Lieutenant Aaron Salter, 55, is a hero &#8212; a security guard who engaged the suspect to save lives and was killed in the process.</p>



<p>Ruth Whitfield, 86, was mother of Buffalo&#8217;s Retired Fire Commissioner Garnell W. Whitfield.&nbsp; Ruth was the rock of the family, devoting her life to taking care of her four children and husband.&nbsp; Ruth was visiting the former commissioner&#8217;s father in a nursing home, as she did each day, and she stopped at the supermarket to buy some groceries.</p>



<p>Katherine Massey, 72, was a well-known community figure who wrote for her local newspapers, assisted in elections, and dressed up in costume as “Mr. Broccoli” to teach local school children to eat &#8212; to “eat right.”</p>



<p>Pearl Young, 77, was a substitute teacher and a “true pillar in the community,” who volunteered at a church food pantry every Saturday.</p>



<p>Heyward Patterson, 68, a driver and church volunteer.&nbsp; Hayward worked as a driver who gave rides to residents to and from the grocery store and would help with their groceries when he was killed.</p>



<p>Celestine Chaney, 65, a grandmother to six.&nbsp; Celestine had been visiting her sister, and they went to the supermarket because she wanted to get strawberries to make shortcakes, which she loved.&nbsp; Celestine prized her role as a grandmother, survived cancer, and was a regular churchgoer.</p>



<p><s>Robert</s> [Roberta] Drury, 32, a resident of the Syracuse area.&nbsp; She was at the supermarket to get food for dinner while in town visiting her brother.&nbsp; “She always was the center of attention and made [the] whole room smile and laugh,” her sister said.</p>



<p>Geraldine Talley, 62, was doing her regular grocery shopping with her fiancé on Saturday when she was shot and killed.&nbsp; According to her niece Lakesha Chapman, “She was the person who always put our family reunion together…and mother of two beautiful children”.</p>



<p>Andre Mackneil, 53.&nbsp; Andre was going to the supermarket to get a birthday cake for <s>her</s> [his] son when <s>she</s> [he] was killed.&nbsp; Jahon Smith, Mackniel’s cousin, said he was a loving father and <s>grandmother</s> [grandfather] who used to check in on everyone.</p>



<p>Margus D. Morrison, 52.&nbsp; Margus was a father of three and a Buffalo resident.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We recon- &#8212; we recognize their lives today and those lost and affected by gun violence this weekend in Houston, in southern California, Milwaukee, and communities across the country.</p>



<p>And we honor the bravery of those in law enforcement who responded quickly and with professionalism in Buffalo, and who risk their lives every day to protect and serve their communities.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, as you all know, the President and the First Lady will travel to Buffalo to meet with families of the victims, first responders, and community leaders.&nbsp; They will comfort the families of the 10 people whose lives were senselessly taken in this horrific shooting.&nbsp; And they will express gratitude for the bravery of members of law enforcement and other first responders who took immediate action to try to protect and save lives.</p>



<p>A couple more toppers for you here &#8212; items for the top &#8212; at the top.</p>



<p>In just under an hour, the President will host Prime Minister of Greece and a senior delegation, including their Minister for fair- &#8212; Foreign Affairs and Minister of National Defense, for a bilateral meeting.&nbsp; The two leaders will discuss the U.S.-Greece bilateral relationship, which both our governments agree is at a historical high point.</p>



<p>The President and the Prime Minister will discuss our defense partnership, efforts to bolster energy security while also combatting climate change, our shared commitment to democratic values, and efforts to provide Ukraine with the support it needs to defend itself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The two leaders will also discuss ways to further expand the bilateral trade relationship and U.S. investment in Greece, where several U.S. tech and renewable energy companies have made significant investments.</p>



<p>The President and the First Lady, Jill Biden, will then host the Prime Minister and &#8212; and his wife for a reception honoring the conclusion of the Greece &#8212; Greece’s bicentennial year of March &#8212; on March &#8212; March 25th.</p>



<p>Also today, the administration announced an Action Plan to Ease the Burden of Housing Costs, taking a series of actions to address one of the largest items in a typical family’s budget and one of the largest drivers of inflation in our economy.</p>



<p>As President, Biden has said tackling inflation is his top economic priority.&nbsp; The best thing we can do to ease the burden of housing costs is to boost the supply of quality housing, including building more new homes and preserving existing federal support and market-rate affordable housing.</p>



<p>Today’s action plan includes legislative and administration &#8212; administrative actions that will help close America’s housing supply shortfalls in five years, starting with creation &#8212; the creation of preservation of hundreds of thousands of affordable housing units in the next three years.</p>



<p>This is the most comprehensive all-of-government effort to close the housing supply shortfall in history when aligned with other policies that the President has proposed to reduce housing costs and ensure affordability, such as rental assistance and down payment assistance.&nbsp; Closing the gap will mean more affordable rents and more attainable hone- &#8212; homeownership for Americans in every community.</p>



<p>Also today &#8212; we have a lot &#8212; we have a lot.&nbsp; Today marks six months since President Biden signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; Since then, the team has hit the ground running to deliver results for communities across the country.&nbsp; In six months, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law has already begun helping fight climate change, advancing environmental justice, boosting domestic manufacturing, strengthening critical links in our supply chain, and lowering costs for working families.</p>



<p>To date, the Biden-Harris administration has announced over $110 billion to rebuild roads and bridges, modernize ports and airports, replace lead pipes to deliver clean water, and high &#8212; and expand high-speed Internet.</p>



<p>This includes funding for &#8212; for over 4,300 specific projects touching over 3,200 communities across all 50 states, D.C., and Puerto Rico as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fifty-three states and territories have appointed state infrastructure coordinators, responding to the call from Infrastructure Coordinator Landrieu to appoint an individual to coordinate efforts in a state &#8212; in a state, along with serving as a single point of contact for the White House Infrastructure implema- &#8212; Implementation Team.</p>



<p>The President, Vice President, and Cabinet have traveled on more than 125 trips to over 40 states, as well as D.C. and Puerto Rico, to demonstrate how the President is delivering on this once-in-a-generation opportunity.</p>



<p> </p>



<p>The last thing &#8212; I promise &#8212; and then we’ll go to your questions.&nbsp; But before I do that, I just want to say a few words about how honored I am to be here with all of you today in this role, in this room, standing behind this podium.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I am obviously acutely aware that my presence at this podium represents a few firsts.&nbsp; I am a Black, gay, immigrant woman, the first of all three of those to hold this position.</p>



<p>I would not be here today if it were not for generations of barriers &#8212; barrier-breaking people before me.&nbsp; I stand on their shoulders.&nbsp; If it were not for generations of barrier-breaking people before me, I would not be here.</p>



<p>But I benefit from their sacrifices.&nbsp; I have learned from their ex- &#8212; excellence, and I am forever grateful to them.&nbsp; Representation does matter.&nbsp; You hear us &#8212; you hear us say this often in this administration.&nbsp; And no one understands this better than President Biden, which is why his administration is not only the most diverse in history, it is filled with barrier-breaking women and men, from the Vice President, to the Cabinet Secretaries, to his Supreme Court nominee, to senior staff throughout this administration.</p>



<p>When I did my first briefing as Principal Deputy</p>



<p>Press Secretary last year, almost a year ago, I said at this podium that this podium, this room, this building belong to the American people.&nbsp; We work for them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about me.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about them.&nbsp; It was true then, and it is very true indeed today.</p>



<p>On Jen&#8217;s first briefing, she made clear that the President&#8217;s and her priority was to bring truth and transparency back to this briefing room.&nbsp; Jen did a great job at that.&nbsp; And I will work every day to continue to ensure we are meeting the President&#8217;s high expectation of truth, honesty, and transparency.</p>



<p>I also have tremendous respect for the work that you all do, which I know it&#8217;s not easy.&nbsp; The press plays a vital role in our democracy, and we need a strong and independent press now more than ever.</p>



<p>We might not see eye to eye here in this room all the time, which is okay.&nbsp; That give-and-take is so incredibly healthy and it&#8217;s a part of our democracy.&nbsp; And I look forward to engaging with all of you on that.</p>



<p>With that, please kick us off.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; And congratulations.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; While you’ve been here before, it’s your first as Press Secretary, so on that &#8212; in that vein, I just want to ask you: Do you view your primary role here as speaking for the President and promoting his interests?&nbsp; Or are you &#8212; you know, or are you committed to providing the unvarnished truth to the American people so that they know what their government is doing on their behalf?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I actually think that&#8217;s hand in hand.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s &#8212; that there is any separation to that.</p>



<p>As I said at the end of my opening here, the President believes in truth and transparency.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what he expects from us.&nbsp; Clearly, we are here to talk about his platform and what he is doing to deliver for the American people.&nbsp; But he wants to make sure we&#8217;re doing this trans- &#8212; in a transparent way, in a truthful way, and an honest way.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on a housekeeping note, I know the pool has to gather at 3:30 for the event, but I’m hoping you might be able to stay here to take questions from more folks.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Absolutely.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on a substantive note, this weekend’s attack in Buffalo &#8212; the shooter professed ideology, echoed in some ways the hate &#8212; the hateful rhetoric espoused by the Charlottesville white supremacist protesters almost five years ago that motivated the President to run for this office back then, as he’s often talked about.</p>



<p>What more does the President believe he has to do and the country has to do to combat that sort of hatred?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So let me just say we still need to learn more about the motivation for the shooting as law enforcement do &#8212; does their work.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t &#8212; we don&#8217;t need anything else to stay &#8212; to state a clear moral truth &#8212; right? &#8212; which is: A racially motivated hate crime is abhorrent to the very fabric of this nation.&nbsp; Hate must not have a safe harbor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is something that the President says very often, especially in these horrific incidents that we have seen time and time again.&nbsp; We must do everything in our power to end hate-fueled domestic terrorism.&nbsp; And we must reject hatred and extres- &#8212; extremism ideologies that seek to divide Americans, whenever we find it in our society.&nbsp; It is antithetical to who we are as a country and fuels &#8212; and fuels violence as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Congratulations also.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In that vein, there&#8217;s polling that shows one in three Americans believe in some element of “replacement theory.”&nbsp; You just spoke in very broad brushstrokes there.&nbsp; Are there specifics that this White House is willing to do, willing to take in order to stop this form of thinking from further seeping out of the fringe and into the mainstream?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, we&#8217;re going to continue to call this out.&nbsp; As we have talked about many times, the President, at every chance he&#8217;s had &#8212; when we&#8217;ve seen a violent attack like this that is &#8212; that is &#8212; as we, you know, say “with hatred and racially motivated” &#8212; he calls it out and calls it what it is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, one thing I do want to touch on is, like, domestic terrorism a little bit, which kind of hopefully touches on your question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we have been working to implement the government-wide national strategy to counter domestic terrorism, which President Biden directed his natiol [sic] &#8212; national security team to develop on his first full day in office, recognizing that has &#8212; that has evolved into the most urgent terrorism threat the United States faces today.</p>



<p>That work includes improving information sharing throughout federal, state, and local law enforcement on domestic terrorism threats and analysis; adding resources to prevent domestic terrorism’s recruitment and mobilization to violence, including online by increasing information sharing with the technology sector; increasing our support for federal, state, and local law enforcement in addressing domestic terrorism nationwide; confronting long-term contributors to domestic terrorism and rooting out hate and bigotry.</p>



<p>This weekend’s terrible events in Buffalo are just another vivid reminder of the urgency of that work and continuing to move towards that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But on this notion that immigrants and others are believed to be, by some, taking over and pushing white people out of positions of authority in this country, which is at the heart of so much of this terror that is being spewed online, does the White House believe these views are being amplified by Tucker Carlson?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, you know, like I said, we are still figuring out the motivation of all of this.&nbsp; And we are very clear &#8212; look, you know, as you all know, watching what happened in Charlottesville was a major factor in the President deciding to run &#8212; right? &#8212; and back in 2017.&nbsp; You know, many of those dark voices still exist today, and the President is &#8212; is determined, as he was back then.&nbsp; And he is determined today to make sure that we fight back against those forces of hate and evil and of &#8212; and violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to keep doing.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to continue to call out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we reject hatred and extremism ideologies.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But just in the interest of &#8212; I apologize.&nbsp; In the interest of time &#8212; I know you’ve got to go &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but are there elected officials that this administration views as threatening in this way?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, it&#8217;s the &#8212; what we&#8217;re going to continue to do &#8212; anyone &#8212; any one person &#8212; right? &#8212; doesn&#8217;t matter who they are, who spews this type of hate &#8212; hatred, we are going to &#8212; we&#8217;re going to call out.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to condemn that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to speak or call out any individual names.&nbsp; I&#8217;m saying that this is something that we need to call out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so this is what the President has been doing and will continue to do that.&nbsp; You saw him say that in his statement over the weekend.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s &#8212; you know, now he&#8217;s going to go to Buffalo and visit with the victims that were affected by this violence that we saw on Saturday.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; And congratulations.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Putin said today that Russia has no objections to Finland and Sweden joining NATO, which seems to be a shift in policy for them.&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s reaction to that?&nbsp; And can you give us an update on U.S. efforts to help bridge the gap between Turkey and Finland and Sweden over NATO?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on the Turkey part &#8212; I&#8217;ll take that first &#8212; I know that there was a question about how they were feeling or what they &#8212; what the Turkey government &#8212; Turkish government said about Finland and Sweden.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Secretary spoke to this again, as I just said, yesterday during his press conference in Berlin &#8212; a meeting with his counterparts in NATO.&nbsp; And so, what he said is, we are “confident…we will reach consensus” as an Alliance on an entry process should they decide to apply.&nbsp; That was what Secretary Blinken said yesterday.</p>



<p>I cannot speak for the Kremlin.&nbsp; You know, this is &#8212; this &#8212; we believe &#8212; when it &#8212; we believe in NATO&#8217;s open-door policies and the right of each country to decide its own future &#8212; foreign policy and security arrangements.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we believe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we welcome the recent statements from governments of Finland and Sweden on their intention to seek NATO membership.&nbsp; We will strongly support these applications when they are formally presented in Brussels.&nbsp; Both Finland and Sweden are close and valued defense partners of the United States and of NATO.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secondly, when and why did the President decide to have additional troops sent to Somalia?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, I know that was just announced I believe today &#8212; earlier today.</p>



<p>So the President has approved a request from the Secretary of Defense to reestablish a persistent U.S. military presence in Somalia to enable a more effective fight against al-Shabaab, which has increased in strength and poses a heightened threat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a repositioning of forces already in theater who have traveled in and out of Somalia on an episodic basis since the previous administration made the decision to withdraw.&nbsp; That was back in January of 2021, as you might recall.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we&#8217;ve emphasized throughout his administration, we&#8217;re approaching counterterrorism in a manner tailored to the particular terrorist threats that we see emerging from particular countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today in Somalia, we face al Qaeda’s largest and wealthiest global affiliate, and one that holds substantial territorial safe haven.&nbsp; The decision to reintroduce a small but persistent presence was made, first and foremost, to maximize the safety and effectiveness of our force and enable them to provide better support of our partners.</p>



<p>Additionally, our partners can benefit from our more consistent support and engagement in addressing the threat posed by al-Shabaab by having a small but persistent U.S. military presence.&nbsp; And while there is risk, it is manageable.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the way that we are seeing this approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DOD is working to elevate local conditions, including those following the Somalia presidential election yesterday, and is engaging partners in the region, including the Somali government, to determine the best way forward.</p>



<p>Go ahead, MJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Two questions for you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One, there are some elected officials and media figures who are publicly espousing xenophobic, racist, and extremist views that may be helping to spread white nationalism.&nbsp; You just told my colleague here that you don&#8217;t want to call out any names.&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t you want to do that?&nbsp; Does that come from the President himself?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I think because it doesn&#8217;t matter who it is.&nbsp; What &#8212; if a person espouses hatred, we need to call that out.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into a back-and-forth on names and who said what.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re just saying: If someone does that, if there&#8217;s an individual that is espousing hate, xenophobia, you know, has &#8212; you know, has just white supremacy-type of extremism, we need to call that out.&nbsp; And this President has done that.&nbsp; He&#8217;s done that at every &#8212; at every unfortunate &#8212; every unfortunate, violent event that we have seen.</p>



<p>As we know, Charlottesville, as I just mentioned, was the reason that he decided to jump in, into this election, back in 2020 &#8212; 2019.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more thing &#8212; I’ll just wait a second.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Press pool departs for the President’s bilateral meeting with the Prime Minister of Greece.]</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we just explain for people who are watching: The pool is departing.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp; For folks who are watching, the pool is departing.&nbsp; They&#8217;re &#8212; the President is getting ready to have his event.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We don’t want anybody to think they’re walking out on you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; It’s okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re not walking out on you, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, you know &#8212; you know, that would be a great &#8212; that would be a great first day, one for the books: The press gets up and walks away.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But they did.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; They &#8212; well, for &#8212; yeah.&nbsp; They &#8212; they &#8212; the President is much more important than I am, for sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And those of us who stayed will be rewarded, correct?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I will &#8212; you guys all deserve rewards.&nbsp; How about that?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Go ahead, Nancy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have to leave.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m so sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, MJ. I&#8217;m so sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On a separate topic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President told my colleague Jeremy Diamond on Friday, when he asked if the administration should have acted sooner on baby formula shortage: “If we&#8217;d been better mind readers, I guess we could have.”&nbsp; This doesn&#8217;t seem like a situation that would have required mindreading.&nbsp; As you know, the recalls date back to February.&nbsp; I believe Politico reported months ago that the FDA was first warned about the suspected bacteria issue as early as September.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Are there any specific actions that this administration took &#8212; meetings, phone calls, briefings &#8212; in February or any earlier to begin addressing this potential shortage?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, you&#8217;ve heard us talk about this. You&#8217;ve seen my colleagues on your networks talking about what we have done.&nbsp; Since &#8212; you know, since February, we&#8217;ve been working aro- &#8212; on this 24/7.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I do want to give you a little bit of an update of where we are: So, getting more safe infant formula onto shelves across the country is one of the President&#8217;s top priorities.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; This is something that he is focusing on very acutely.&nbsp; And again, I said 24/7 we have been working on this since we have &#8212; since we learned about this back in February.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s important to remember this shortage exists because Abbott closed the facility &#8212; closed a facility because of safety concerns from the FDA.&nbsp; The FDA is working closely with Abbott to bring the facility back online safely.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the key here: safely.&nbsp; We want to make sure that this is done in a safe way.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re very &#8212; we are very close to having a path forward to safely reopening the facility.&nbsp; We can &#8212; you can expect a &#8212; an announcement from FDA later today on that that will go into more details.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also moving as quickly as possible to safely bring in additional product from other countries.&nbsp; As soon as today as well, we will be able to make an announcement on the expedited process to bring additional safe condu- &#8212; product to the American stores shel- &#8212; to American store shelves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And throughout the weekend, we&#8217;ve been working closely with manufacturers and retailers to identify transportation and logistical needs to increase the amount and spread of FDA-approved formula being shipped into the country and ensure that formula is quickly moving from factories to retailers.</p>



<p>The President understands.&nbsp; He gets this.&nbsp; He gets how stressful it is for parents trying to feed their children, which is why we&#8217;re leaving no stone unturned to make more safe formula available.</p>



<p>If parents need help finding formula, I encourage them to consult their pediatrician or visit HHS.gov/formula.&nbsp; But we have been working on this from the &#8212; from February &#8212; our administration has been.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As &#8212; we were just curious whether there are specific meetings, briefings, you know, phone calls that you can point us to.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything specific for you to point to.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m happy to go back and &#8212; and get that &#8212; you know, make sure that we are fully transparent on what we&#8217;ve been doing.</p>



<p>But this has been &#8212; this is an important, you know, this is an important priority, a top priority for the President.&nbsp; He is &#8212; his team has been working overtime to make sure that we get formula back on the shelves.&nbsp; And we want to do this in a safe way.</p>



<p>And again, we cannot forget how we got here.&nbsp; Abbott closed the facility because of safety concerns from the FDA.&nbsp; The FDA wanted to make sure that we &#8212; formula was going out in a safe way.&nbsp; And that is the job of the FDA, and that is the job of this administration as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just very quickly, on Abbott: Secretary Becerra said today, in terms of when things would be back to normal, that, “Abbott is the one that could tell you the timeline…We don&#8217;t run their plants.”&nbsp; Do you know if anyone from the federal government is currently at the plant or has visited the plant to get a sense of where things stand?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any information about if anyone is on the plant.&nbsp; Again, I can go back to our team and figure that out more specifically, but there are a lot of &#8212; what I can say is there are a lot of dates floating around out there.&nbsp; But at the end of the day, the infant formula market is tight because the Michigan Abbott facility is offline currently, which is what we&#8217;re trying to do &#8212; this is the &#8212; the announcement that you guys will hear from FDA later today on how we&#8217;re helping them to do that.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re taking a range of steps to get more supply onto shelves from domestic and international locations, and offering a suit &#8212; a suite of resources to move supply onto the market.</p>



<p>As the Secretary said, Abbott can speak on it &#8212; to an exact timeline for reopening, but FDA is and will be prepared to effectively and quickly certify moving out safe products onto shelf, as it is obligated to.&nbsp; And so that is going to be our focus.&nbsp; FDA is going to work closely with Abbott and make sure that we get them running again.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Nancy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Congratulations.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When you talk about bringing &#8212; importing more product imminently, what is the criteria going to be for which formula can be imported?&nbsp; Will the administration allow formula that was not produced in FDA-approved factories overseas to be imported or European brands, for example, that aren&#8217;t currently sold in the U.S.?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, as Dr. Califf was on &#8212; on various networks today, the FDA have said that it will release guidance as soon as today on how major formula manufacturers can bring in product that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market, as you&#8217;re alluding to there, Nancy, and to your question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Companies will need to apply with the FDA, and FDA is prepared to review applications quickly and respond to them rapidly.&nbsp; FDA will prioritize review of applications that are most likely to be successful and will get the most formula to U.S. shelves as quickly as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All companies will meet the FDA’s gold standard for quality control, and only safe products will come to America’s shelves as &#8212; as the FDA Commissioner said and explained in detail this morning.</p>



<p>At the White House, what are our &#8212; our role, what we&#8217;ll be doing, is we will have alerted embassies, retailers, and manufacturers to identify potential companies that would make use of the new FDA import- &#8212; importation process.</p>



<p>Once FDA has finalized its rules, we will be ready to provide information to the public on using the new system quickly and safely and bring new supply to the market.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And New York Senator Kirsten Gillibrand says the President should be invoking the Defense Production Act to increase supply more quickly.&nbsp; Is the President still considering that?&nbsp; And if not, why not?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;re pretty much where we were before on the DPA.&nbsp; We&#8217;re leaving no stone unturned and every option is on the table, as we have been saying for the past several days.</p>



<p>I have no update on the DPA and where we are.&nbsp; But what we&#8217;re &#8212; what we&#8217;re taking action is to make more supplies available as soon as possible, as you&#8217;ve been hearing me say. That is our prior- &#8212; our priority, our main goal.&nbsp; That&#8217;s happening by increasing imports, as I just laid out how we&#8217;re going to do that process, and working closely with manufacturers to help them quickly ramp up production.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s going to be our focus.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then finally, when you say that you&#8217;re offering these retailers and producers more assistance, what kind of assistance are you talking about?&nbsp; What kind of assistance can the White House or the administration provide to get supply to store shelves more quickly?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, we&#8217;re talking about logistical needs and &#8212; and any technical help is what we were talking about.&nbsp; But since the President calls on Thursday to manufacturers and retailers, which we &#8212; which we read out, the White House has been in close communication to follow up on those conversations.</p>



<p>The White House is having ongoing conversations with the four major infant formula to work with them to identify transportation, logistical, and supplier hurdles to increasing production of formula at their U.S. and FDA-approved facilities to expand the amount and speed of FDA-approved formula being shipped into the country and ensure that formula is quickly moving to retailers from factories.</p>



<p>We are also in ongoing communications, as we talk about retailers here as well, with Target and Amazon and Walmart and other leading retailers for baby formula to identify parts of the country that may be at risk of critically low supply of infant formula, and have offered to work with manufacturers and retailers to bring more formula to those parts of the country, including the U.S. government transportation and logistical support.</p>



<p>Last, we are also contacting suppliers to infant formula manufacturers to inform them that their materials are critical for boosting U.S. infant formula production and they should prioritize their production and delivery.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, essentially, in short, we want them to know we&#8217;re standing ready to provide the resources or support needed to move safely to get &#8212; to get this to the shelves as soon as possible.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; COVID cases are up 61 percent in the last two weeks.&nbsp; Hospitalizations are up almost 25 percent.&nbsp; Is the White House concerned that the pandemic has not moved on from us?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, you know, Dr. Jha was here not too long ago.&nbsp; I think he &#8212; very, very early in his &#8212; in his tenure, he stopped by and answered all of your questions.&nbsp; And he said this is a &#8212; this is tricky &#8212; right? &#8212; when it comes to COVID.</p>



<p>And the thing that we have to remember and we keep saying from here is that people have to get vaccinated; they have to get boosted.&nbsp; That is the way to really start moving forward from &#8212; from COVID.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been the President&#8217;s focus in putting together a comprehensive strategy to make sure that that is happening.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why you&#8217;ve seen that success of more than 200 million people who have been vaccinated.</p>



<p>And so we&#8217;re going to continue to have that message.&nbsp; Again, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s a &#8212; COVID is tricky, right?&nbsp; This is a once-in-a-generation pandemic, you know.&nbsp; And so &#8212; but what we&#8217;re going to continue to do is do the job of the federal government and make sure that we &#8212; you know, we keep the American public as safe as possible and communicating on what we need to do to move forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just in terms of that communication, Dr. Jha did come here but it was a while ago, and the regular COVID briefings with the CDC director and other health advisors have fallen off a cliff.&nbsp; What is your view on whether these briefings should be happening?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think they will be happening.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; any update for you on that.&nbsp; Dr. Jha is happy to come back.&nbsp; I think he&#8217;s asked to come back to the briefing to speak directly to you &#8212; to all of you.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m sure that they will be having a briefing pretty soon.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; any list in front of me to read out to you.</p>



<p>But yes, it is important to continue to communicate to the American public.&nbsp; And we’re going to continue to do that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of questions on Buffalo.&nbsp; We understand that the shooter did purchase his guns legally, but he did have a history of mental health issues and was held for an evaluation last year.&nbsp; So does the White House believe he should have been prevented from owning a gun because of that history?&nbsp; And how does the administration propose doing so in the future?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So just me a second, because I &#8212; I really want to touch on this.&nbsp; It’s really important.<br><br>Our nation is facing a mental health crisis, so it’s important to call it that &#8212; one that is worsened by acts of violence, like the one we saw in Buffalo, that can traumatize communities, especially communities of color.<br><br>And anyone seeking support in the wake of shootings like this should contact Disaster Distress Helpline at 1-800-985-5990.&nbsp; Help is available 24/7, 365 days a week &#8212; day of the year, I should say &#8212; for people who are experiencing emotional distress related to any natural or &#8212; or human-caused disaster.</p>



<p>We are committed to expanding access to mental health for all Americans.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan made historic investment in mental health and substance use &#8212; substance use care.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, in his first State of the Union, the President unveiled his vision for transforming mental health in the United States.<br><br>His comprehensive strategy focuses on building a system that works for everyone by increasing the supply and diversity of the mental health workforce, connecting more people to care by lowering costs and other barriers, and creating environments that help prevent mental health problems and support recovery.</p>



<p>While we are committed to this work, I want to also underscore that the overwhelming majority of individuals with mental health problems do not commit acts of violence.<br><br>And so, comments that make this about mental health only further stigma- &#8212; stigmatizing mental health issues and detract from the other issues, like gun violence, that must con- &#8212; that must be confronted in our society.<br><br>So, just want to make that clear that we are not stigmatizing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But should he have been prevented from owning a gun?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, this is &#8212; this goes back to making sure that, you know, we have gun reform.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; This goes back to making sure that we &#8212; we &#8212; you know, the President is going to continue to call on Congress to make that happen.<br><br>And so, you know, when it comes &#8212; I just wanted to make sure when we talk about mental health, we talk about it in its fullness.&nbsp; And like I said, not every &#8212; it&#8217;s not &#8212; it &#8212; you know, not every individual that has a mental health problem commits &#8212; commits acts of violence.&nbsp; So, I just want to make sure that we don’t stigmatize it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a quick &#8212; another one.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would the President support the death penalty for the shooter if he’s eventually convicted?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, this is being &#8212; this is being investigated by &#8212; by the Department of Justice.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have &#8212; it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not my place from here &#8212; this podium &#8212; to go be- &#8212; to go beyond that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Regarding gun violence, does the President plan to use his remarks tomorrow in Buffalo to push for gun control and gun reform?&nbsp; And will that be a key part of what his message is tomorrow in Buffalo?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the President, you know, is going to go &#8212; you know, he really wanted to go to Buffalo.&nbsp; He made it sure that &#8212; that he went there before he &#8212; he went to Asia.&nbsp; He wants to go there and comfort the people who are &#8212; who &#8212; who went through this violence on Saturday, and wanted to offer &#8212; you know, offer some comfort and listen to them, talk to them, see how they&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; And so that is going to be his priority with the First Lady.<br><br>I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of what he&#8217;s going to say.&nbsp; I will let the President speak for himself when we get there tomorrow.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he plan to use this moment, though, to call on Congress to pass gun reform measures, or is there recognition that that&#8217;s just not something that&#8217;s possible right now in Congress?&nbsp; He&#8217;s obviously pushed for these things here in the past, during his first term in office.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I think the President, as he&#8217;s done for this past year, is going to continue to call for gun reform.&nbsp; That is not going to &#8212; you know, that&#8217;s not going to change.&nbsp; That is something that &#8212; that he has done this past year every time we have heard of this gun violence.<br><br>You know, our country is facing an epidemic on gun violence that is costing lives every day.&nbsp; We saw that in Buffalo, as we&#8217;re talking about, and in examples every day that might not make the news but tear up families and communities.&nbsp; This is a top priority for the President, and it&#8217;s been through- &#8212; has been throughout his career.<br><br>I do want to say that, you know, what we saw in the country this weekend are an urgent reminder of how important it is to have confirmed leadership at <s>AFT</s> [ATF].&nbsp; So I want to &#8212; do take that moment to say <s>AFT</s> [ATF] agents are playing a key role in the investigation in Buffalo, and they are risking their lives every day to combat domestic terrorism and crack down on gun traffickers to keep our streets safe from violent crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If the Senate wants to get their &#8212; get their back, and &#8212; they should confirm Steve Dettelbach to lead the agency.&nbsp; Dettelbach is a career prosecutor who has confirmed &#8212; who was confirmed uni- &#8212; unanimously last time he was before the Senate.&nbsp; He was the support of former federal prosecution &#8212; he has the support of former prosecutors from both parties, including the team that prosecuted the deadly Oklahoma City bombing domestic terrorism case.&nbsp; He has the backing of major law enforcement groups, including one that represents many of the rank-and-file ATF agents he&#8217;s going to lead as ATF director.<br><br>So, that is something that is really important that we make sure that we get that done, and we&#8217;re calling on Congress to do that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, congratulations.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Nice to see you up there.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President’s Twitter account posted the other day, “You want to bring down inflation?&nbsp; Let&#8217;s make sure the wealthiest corporations pay their fair share.”&nbsp; How does raising taxes on corporations reduce inflation?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, are you talking about a specific tweet?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He tweeted, “You want to bring down inflation?&nbsp; Let&#8217;s make sure the wealthiest corporations pay their fair share?”<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, you know, we have talked about &#8212; we have talked about this this past year, about making sure that the wealthiest among us are paying their fair share.&nbsp; And that is important to do.&nbsp; And that is something that, you know, the President has been, you know, working on every day when we talk about inflation and lowering costs.</p>



<p>And so it&#8217;s very important that, you know, as we&#8217;re seeing costs rise, as we&#8217;re talking about how to, you know &#8212; you know, build an America that is safe, that&#8217;s equal for everyone, and doesn&#8217;t leave anyone behind, that is an important part of that as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But how does raising taxes on corporations lower the cost of gas, the cost of a used car, the cost of food for everyday Americans?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, I think we encourage those who have done very well &#8212; right? &#8212; especially those who care about climate change, to support a fairer tax &#8212; tax code that doesn&#8217;t change &#8212; that doesn&#8217;t charge manufacturers’ workers, cops, builders a higher percentage of their earnings; that the most fortunate people in our nation &#8212; and not let the &#8212; that stand in the way of reducing energy costs and fighting this existential problem, if you think about that as an example, and to support basic collective bargaining rights as well.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; That&#8217;s also important.<br><br>But look, it is &#8212; you know, by not &#8212; if &#8212; without having a fairer tax code, which is what I&#8217;m talking about, then all &#8212; every &#8212; like manufacturing workers, cops &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s not fair for them to have to pay higher taxes than the folks that &#8212; who are &#8212; who are &#8212; who are not paying taxes at all or barely have.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But was does that have to do with inflation?&nbsp; The President said, “You want to bring down inflation?&nbsp; Let&#8217;s make sure the wealthiest corporations pay their fair share.”<br><br>Jeff Bezos came out and tweeted about that.&nbsp; He said, “The newly created disinformation board should review this tweet.”&nbsp; Would you be okay with that?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, it&#8217;s not a huge mystery why one of the wealthiest individuals on Earth &#8212; right? &#8212; opposes an economic agenda that is for the middle class, that cuts some of the biggest costs families face, fights inflation for the long haul &#8212; right? &#8212; and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re talking about; that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re talking about lowering inflation here &#8212; and adds to the historic deficit reduction the President is achieving by asking the richest taxpayers and corporations to pay their fair share.&nbsp; That is what we&#8217;re talking about.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then just one on the trip tomorrow: How come the President is visiting Buffalo after a senseless tragedy there, but he couldn&#8217;t visit Waukesha after 6 were killed and 61 injured in an attack on a Christmas parade there?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, he’s visited many communities.&nbsp; Buffalo &#8212; he was &#8212; we &#8212; you know, he was &#8212; he’s able to go tomorrow to Buffalo before the trip.&nbsp; That is something that was important for him to do.&nbsp; But he has visited many &#8212; many other communities.&nbsp; This is not &#8212; Buffalo is not the first community, sadly, that he has to go up to because of a violent attack.&nbsp; So, you know, that&#8217;s not &#8212; that&#8217;s not the first one.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s been to many others, sadly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You outlined some steps that the administration has taken related to baby formula.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any sense of the timeline for the imports that the FDA is considering?&nbsp; Obviously, for parents, this is a hour-by-hour, day-by-day concern.&nbsp; And is the President expressing any worry about how quickly this can be resolved, since parents are dealing with this on an urgent basis?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Like I said, this is something that &#8212; this is incredibly important to the President.&nbsp; We want this to happen as soon as possible, as quickly as possible.&nbsp; That is why we&#8217;re working with manufacturers and retailers, as I just laid out.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why FDA is working with Abbott to open up that facility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we want to get this done as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why our &#8212; we&#8217;ve been working 24/7 to make that happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a sense of the timeline when FDA announces?&nbsp; Does that mean the production will be up and running in a matter of days?&nbsp; Do you know when imports would be approved?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, I don&#8217;t have a timeline on that.&nbsp; I know, again, we want to make this happen quickly.&nbsp; FDA, again, is going to be working with the Abbott facility.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to have an announcement later on how that&#8217;s going to happen.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to work closely with them to make sure that we do it as quickly as possible.&nbsp; We know how urgent and important this is to parents who need to make sure that they have safe formula for their babies and infants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To the back?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Two questions, please.&nbsp; Does the President see any link to the white supremacist theories that &#8212; like the replacement theory &#8212; and what he started calling “ultra-MAGA” or sometimes he just refers to as “extreme Republican” politics?&nbsp; Does he see that as part of it?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, I think what the President believes and has done is call it out.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; I think, you know, this is &#8212; this is not about politics.&nbsp; This is about people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we saw on Saturday and many times &#8212; you think about El Paso in Texas, you think about the Tree of Life in Pittsburgh, you think about the Pulse nightclub in Florida, the Mother Emanuel in South Carolina.&nbsp; These are events that are very &#8212; that have been led by some dark for- &#8212; forces that still exist today.&nbsp; And so, it is important to call that out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We understand that there is still a lot of work to do.&nbsp; And so that is &#8212; when you talk about people&#8217;s lives in this way, it&#8217;s not about politics.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about making sure that we&#8217;re doing everything that we can, you know, to uproot this evil that we&#8217;re seeing, this hatred that we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what the pers- &#8212; the President is going to continue to do to make sure that we&#8217;re working &#8212; we&#8217;re working towards that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, but when he talks about “ultra-MAGA,” as he has started to a lot, is he &#8212; would he include that in the bundle of what he considers “ultra-MAGA”?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, again, this is about the lives of people who were taken in a violent way, in an abhorrent way.&nbsp; And so, the focus for the President is to make sure that, you know, we call this out &#8212; we call out white supremacy, we call out hatred.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I&#8217;ve said before, this is still being investigated.&nbsp; This is still being looked at.&nbsp; But the moralness &#8212; right? &#8212; the moral center of this should be called out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s going to be the focus.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what you&#8217;re going to see the President do tomorrow.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to meet with the victims.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to have conversations.&nbsp; He’s going to offer them comfort.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to listen to them and hear what is it that they want to share with him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he&#8217;s going to continue to work with Congress and call on Congress to call for &#8212; to work on gun reform, which is really important here as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, sorry, I had a second question.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A very quick one, I promise.&nbsp; Is there any update on whether Cuba, Nicaragua, or Venezuela will be invited to the Americas Summit?&nbsp; And, generally, when are you going to be announcing invitations?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any update for you on that &#8212; on invitations or when we&#8217;re going to announce invitations or who’s been invited.&nbsp; As soon as I &#8212; as soon as we have that, we’ll promise to share.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, congratulations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions on internal policy review or internal government reviews that have actually fallen out of the headlines.&nbsp; The first is on the investigation of Border Patrol agents that &#8212; in the &#8212; I guess it was September of last year &#8212; who were there for the Del Rio arrival of thousands of Haitian migrants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s been eight months at this point, and we don&#8217;t have a conclusion of that review.&nbsp; The President had wanted accountability; he demanded it at the time.&nbsp; Secretary Mayorkas said that there would be a conclusion to that review within weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So why is it taking so long?&nbsp; And is there any urgency, given the fact that you&#8217;re going to &#8212; you&#8217;re &#8212; the administration is now preparing for the arrival of potentially new surges of migrants?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a very good question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update on that.&nbsp; The Department of Homeland Security &#8212; that&#8217;s where &#8212; you mentioned Secretary Mayorkas &#8212; that&#8217;s where that review sits.&nbsp; And as soon as we have an update, I promise to share that, or we &#8212; or they will share that.&nbsp; That won&#8217;t &#8212; that would not come from here.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have an update.&nbsp; But I &#8212; I understand the question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the second review that hasn&#8217;t concluded, it appears: The administration said that after the terrorist attack in Fort Worth at a synagogue, they were going to review how an individual that was a British-born citizen, who had been on a watchlist 10 years prior, somehow was able to enter the United States, and that they were going to look at lessons learned.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You mentioned how there are increased threats of foreign-born terrorism as well as domestic-born terrorism.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Where is that review?&nbsp; What lessons have been learned?&nbsp; And is that a priority for the administration?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don’t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have an update on that.&nbsp; I will have to check in with our team to see if we have something to share on &#8212; on that particular review.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;ll do that; I&#8217;ll check in with the team.&nbsp; And you should reach out to us afterwards and see what we can do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Hey, Jenny.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Two on the economy.&nbsp; China&#8217;s industrial output and consumer spending came in at the worst level since the pandemic began.&nbsp; Are you worried that this will cause a global recession, and including here?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Can you say that again?&nbsp; What &#8212; what came back?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; China&#8217;s industrial output &#8212; which, of course, has an impact on the global economy and the U.S. economy &#8212; came in at the worst level since the pandemic began.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m worried &#8212; wondering if you&#8217;re worried about a global recession.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, I &#8212; the one thing I can tell you is that I know that there&#8217;s always a question about the economic strategy around China.&nbsp; I can give you that update.</p>



<p>I have not seen that specific data that you&#8217;re speaking of.&nbsp; But the United States has strong economic trade ties in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And so &#8212; but we agree it is essential for us to stop &#8212; to step up economically in the region and to do it fast.</p>



<p>We need a new model of economic engagement and trade when &#8212; as we&#8217;re talking about that region specifically.&nbsp; The past couple of years have highlighted real gaps in global economy, like vulnerable supply chains and corruption and tax havens and lack of innovation and creative &#8212; creativity holding us back.</p>



<p>The old models did nothing to address these issues that underpin our growth.&nbsp; And we will &#8212; and will define the coming decades and our ability to deliver for our people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re working intensely on develop &#8212; developing an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve gotten a lot of interest from countries in the region.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also spent months engaging Congress and labor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as it relates to our economic framework, it&#8217;s going to focus on building agreements with Indo-Pacific partners and, one, developing &#8212; one, developing a modern digital economy, including opening the door for small and medium businesses; reducing &#8212; two, reducing supply chain vulnerabilities and diversifying our supply chains to drive investment that will create good jobs for people at home and Indo-Pacific; three, treating climate change like the economy issue it is by investing together in the green economy; and also, building a fairer economy with tax and anti-corruption practices that level in the playing field not just for workers, but also for businesses too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s kind of our strategy &#8212; economic strategy in the region.&nbsp; That particular data I have not seen yet, so I would need to check in with our team.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more, overall on the economy.&nbsp; The dollar is very strong right now, and all indications are that it&#8217;s damaging the domestic and global economy.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m worri- &#8212; wondering if you share that view and if it&#8217;s time for the Biden administration to address this.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, that &#8212; I would just &#8212; going to have to check with our team.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve not seen that report, but I&#8217;ll check in with our team on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And quickly, the follow-up on the economic strategy in the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President expected to lay that out on his trip there?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new to share or preview for you on his trip.&nbsp; As you know, Jake is going to be here &#8212; Jake Sullivan, National Security Advisor &#8212; the President&#8217;s National Security Advisor is going to be here on Wednesday.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll talk more and give a little bit more depth on what&#8217;s happening and what we&#8217;re going to be doing &#8212; the messaging and the goals in Asia.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll also have calls.&nbsp; As you know, we tend to do these background calls leading up to the trip.&nbsp; And those background calls will give you a little bit more information on Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; Kind of &#8212; you know, what we’re &#8212; the goals and de- &#8212; what we&#8217;re delivering, I don&#8217;t have anything specific on that.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Steven.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick one.&nbsp; Probably a good question for Jake, but I’ll ask you because it’s timely.&nbsp; Does the White House have a response to the Indian move over the weekend to block wheat exports?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything for you on that.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, yes.&nbsp; On the &#8212; several civil rights groups are calling for a forum, a summit on hate crimes.&nbsp; Is that something you all are considering?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, we&#8217;ve heard &#8212; we&#8217;ve heard of this &#8212; of the summit.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything for you to preview or to confirm on if we&#8217;re going to have that summit here at the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Clearly, we&#8217;re constantly talking to organizations and leaders in the communities and having constant dialogue, but I just don&#8217;t have anything new on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more quickly.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This morning, the Supreme Court ruled against a man who immigrated from India.&nbsp; And he &#8212; they ruled that he was deportable essentially because he checked the wrong box on his driver&#8217;s license application.&nbsp; Is that a case that the Biden administration might try and intervene on?&nbsp; Or what do you think of that decision?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; my guess is it&#8217;s going to go to &#8212; that would be a Department of Justice for it to decide, not for us to decide on.&nbsp; And so, I would refer you to DOJ.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And congratulations.&nbsp; I was hoping you could offer a little more of an explanation about something you said earlier, where you said that they were &#8212; did not want to call out by name individuals who had been espousing racist theories that could be fueling violence.&nbsp; I guess my question is: Why not, particularly if they&#8217;re individuals who have very large platforms and theoretically carry a lot of influence?&nbsp; This would be &#8212; people accused of doing so include the number three Republican in the House and the host of the number one cable news show on television.&nbsp; Why not call them out by name?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, what we saw on Saturday was devastating and horrific.&nbsp; You know, it is &#8212; what we want to do is making sure that we send a very clear message that hate must have no safe harbor.&nbsp; And we must do everything in our power to end hate-fueled domestic terrorism.&nbsp; And we must reject hatred and extreme &#8212; extreme ideologies that seek to divide Americans, wherever we find it in society; it is antithetical to who we are as a country.&nbsp; And that is what we want to make sure that we&#8217;re doing.</p>



<p>It doesn&#8217;t matter who it is.&nbsp; This &#8212; this is something, like, morally &#8212; like, mor- &#8212; the moral truth of this is that, you know, it is a racial-motivated hate crime, and it&#8217;s a &#8212; abhorrent.</p>



<p>And so, that&#8217;s what we need to call out.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t matter who that is.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re trying to make clear here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to get into politics here about this.&nbsp; We want to make sure that we&#8217;re calling out what we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; These are people&#8217;s lives.</p>



<p>At the top of this &#8212; of the briefing &#8212; I talked about 10 people &#8212; 10 people who are doing what many of us might be doing on a Saturday &#8212; is going shopping.&nbsp; You know, I know I go to the supermarket with my &#8212; with my seven-year-old very often.&nbsp; If it&#8217;s not on a Saturday, it&#8217;s on a Sunday, before the week starts, to get the needs &#8212; to get what we need for the week.</p>



<p>I mean, this is what happened to everyday people, from 20 years old to 86 years old.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we saw on Saturday.&nbsp; And so, we need to call that out and do everything that we can to really deal with this issue.</p>



<p>And we know we have a lot of work to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you know it matters to some, right?&nbsp; It does matter to some people who it is that’s calling it out.&nbsp; And when you don&#8217;t call the &#8212; when you don&#8217;t call out the individual, they feel as if you&#8217;re backing away from the issue.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, but we’re not.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) to the point.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, we’re not backing.&nbsp; How are we backing away from the issue?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, because you won’t name who it is.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But here’s the thing: We&#8217;re calling out what is happening.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to the heart of the issue, the hatred of the issue.&nbsp; Why &#8212; but I guess my point is, you know, we are &#8212; this is a President &#8212; right? &#8212; who decided to run because of what he saw in Charlottesville &#8212; right? &#8212; and he talked about the soul of the nation.&nbsp; And it was something that propelled him to jump into the 2020 primary &#8212; because of what this showed, because it was, again, against who we are as a country, as he believed it to be.</p>



<p>And so, you know, it is something that is important to remember.&nbsp; And this is a President that calls it out every time we see this horrific violence.</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s not about &#8212; once you get into calling out people&#8217;s names, then you move away from that issue, right?&nbsp; You move away from that issue.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s why I&#8217;m not going to do that from here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to focus on &#8212; as I did when I started &#8212; the 10 lives that were murdered.&nbsp; Everyday people doing everyday things.&nbsp; And that is why the President is going to Buffalo tomorrow.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, April.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, first of all, congratulations.&nbsp; Two polar opposite questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, boy.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One on the issue, Saturday.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m going to take it in another vein, which you just mentioned.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President ran on the issue of the soul of this nation.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Charlottesville.&nbsp; He speaks now of equity and inclusion.&nbsp; He has strengthened civil rights in DOJ.&nbsp; He’s strengthened civil rights in other departments in this White House.&nbsp; But where are the teeth when it comes to changing this hate that has been plaguing this nation since the inception of this nation?&nbsp; Where&#8217;s the teeth for the President people are expecting when it comes to these issues?</p>



<p>And on the summit issue, is the White House looking at what Bill Clinton did &#8212; the precedent of having the Race Initiative, which brought people from all walks of life together to discuss issues of race &#8212; the browning of America?&nbsp; Is the President looking at that as well?</p>



<p>And then I have another question.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; You stopped there.&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>You know, now, this is a President that has been very clear about race in this country.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>When he walked in, he talked about the multiple crises that were facing us as a country.&nbsp; He talked about COVID, the economy, climate, and where we are with &#8212; with race.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s called it a crisis.</p>



<p>And he made it a point in his administration &#8212; what he can do on the federal level &#8212; to really deal with that in a way that we&#8217;ve not seen before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, one of the first things that he signed when he walked into the &#8212; this presidency is an executive order to make sure that there&#8217;s fairness, equality, and representation in &#8212; in the federal government and federal agencies.&nbsp; And that is something that Susan Rice and her team, the Domestic Policy Council, has taken on, and they&#8217;ve made that a priority.</p>



<p>Look, I know, April &#8212; and we all know &#8212; there&#8217;s still so much work to be done.&nbsp; This President is committed to that work, and he has not shied away from it.&nbsp; He has called out the hatred that we have seen, the violence that we have seen when it comes to racially motivated attacks.&nbsp; He has been very, very clear on that.</p>



<p>Is there more work to be done?&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; It is our &#8212; is the team here looking to see what else we can do?&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re just going to continue to do that work.</p>



<p>But I do want to say, you know, tomorrow &#8212; again, tomorrow, you know, the President wants to go to a community, he wants to grieve with them, and he wants to send a message to the entire country that we stand behind them and with them.&nbsp; And that is so important, as well as the President.&nbsp; He will try to bring some comfort to the community, particularly to those who lost loved ones.&nbsp; And, you know &#8212; you know, we hear him discuss some of things he said Saturday about “hate must have no safe harbor.”&nbsp; You heard me say that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s probably the third time I&#8217;ve said this in this briefing.&nbsp; And it really does &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t in this country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so any &#8212; any racially motivated hate crime is abhorrent to the very fabric of this nation.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what you&#8217;re going to see him do.&nbsp; And that is going to be the focus tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the second other opposite of the question.&nbsp; You&#8217;re making history &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on so many levels.&nbsp; So many communities are so proud of you, and we&#8217;re hearing it on social media everywhere.&nbsp; You&#8217;re the first.&nbsp; What does that mean for the broader community, particularly Washington &#8212; white male-dominated still, even though we had the first Black president &#8212; and the broader society that is &#8212; majority does not look like you?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does this say?&nbsp; Because it&#8217;s not window dressing; it&#8217;s more than that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a very good question, April.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to answer it in a &#8212; in a kind of a personal way, if that&#8217;s okay, since you asked it in a personal way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I have not read a lot of the things that have been written about me because I wanted to focus on the work at hand.&nbsp; And I do believe it&#8217;s not about me, it&#8217;s about this place.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about what &#8212; the work that I have to do every day, that we all have to do as a team to make sure that we communicate with you and communicate with the broader &#8212; the broader public.</p>



<p>But there was something that moved me, and I think this speaks to &#8212; to what you&#8217;re asking, which is: There was a story about my elementary school.&nbsp; I went to Franklin Middle School &#8212; Elementary School in Hampstead, New York.&nbsp; And they did a story, and they went to the class &#8212; I think I was in sixth grade when I went there; I went for one year &#8212; and they talked to the students about me and this moment &#8212; and this administration too, which is very important, because I don&#8217;t think I would be here &#8212; yes, I stand &#8212; I stood on so many shoulders, but it does matter who sits in the Oval Office as well.&nbsp; That is very, very real.</p>



<p>And these kids wrote me a letter.&nbsp; And in the letter, they talked about how they can dream bigger because of me standing behind this podium.&nbsp; And that matters.&nbsp; You know, as I started out at the beginning: Representation matters.&nbsp; And not just for girls, but also for boys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, what I hope is that young people get to dream big and dream bigger than they have before by seeing me stand here and answer all of your questions, you know, and have a healthy dialogue, as I discussed.</p>



<p>And so I think it is important, and so I appreciate the question.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have to follow that, unfortunately, with some questions about Somalia and Ukraine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, first, happy first day.&nbsp; Let me just ask you &#8212; (laughter).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And now &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And now &#8212; (laughs).&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s a bit of hard left, sorry.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, it’s okay.&nbsp; That’s what this is all about.&nbsp; It’s okay.&nbsp; It’s okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has President Biden spoken to Somalia&#8217;s new leader?&nbsp; Did he or does he plan to congratulate him?&nbsp; And has there been any leader-to-leader discussion about the new troop deployment?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say this &#8212; and I think I said earlier that, you know, having &#8212; making sure that we&#8217;re work- &#8212; that we&#8217;re working, we&#8217;re having &#8212; engaging with partners in the region, including the Somalia &#8212; the Somali government.&nbsp; So, I did say that about the announcement about what &#8212; what you&#8217;re asking me here.</p>



<p>But on the election &#8212; I want to get back to that &#8212; we congratulate the Somali people and their new president who was sworn in last evening, as you know.&nbsp; Somalia now has an opportunity to focus on the political, economic, and security reforms necessary to advance the interests of the people of Somalia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We encourage their new president and all the Somalian leaders to prioritize strengthening democratic governance and institutions, developing security forces to defeat terrorism, enacting economic reforms, and facilitating the delivery of humanitarian aid to the millions of Somalia&#8217;s &#8212; Somalis suffering from devastating drought.</p>



<p>We look forward to the timely formation of a new government and to partnering with the Somalis &#8212; with Somalia&#8217;s leaders to achieve our shared goal to a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous Somalia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Before I move on to Ukraine, so have the two presidents spoken yet?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a conversation or call to preview for you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine, the President has said he wants to go to Ukraine for a visit.&nbsp; Any movement on that issue?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I know that &#8212; to your point, he wants to &#8212; to visit Ukraine, clearly in the future.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s no plans to go at that &#8212; at all at this &#8212; at this time, I should say.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He sent Secretary Blinken and Secretary Austin to Kyiv to demonstrate an &#8212; our unwavering commitment to Ukraine.&nbsp; And the First Lady, as you all know, went for Mother&#8217;s Day to send an important message that the American people stand with the people of Ukraine.</p>



<p>You know, the President, as you &#8212; as you guys know, because we&#8217;ve read out some of these calls &#8212; speaks to President Zelenskyy and leaders around the world regularly as we organize the world&#8217;s response to Russia&#8217;s invasion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; Thank you so much, guys.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll see you on Wednesday, if you &#8212; and hopefully I&#8217;ll see some folks in Buffalo, and we&#8217;ll do this again.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) congratulations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Welcome to the soup.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Thanks, guys.</p>



<p> 4:12 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;BidenAnd Prime Minister Mitsotakis of GreeceBefore Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/16/remarks-by-president-bidenand-prime-minister-mitsotakis-of-greecebefore-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 22:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 3:39 P.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, Mr. Prime Minister, welcome.&#160; It&#8217;s great to have you here.&#160; And later this afternoon, we&#8217;re going to celebrate 201 years &#8212; 201 years of Greek independence and strong ties of family and shared democratic values with the United States, and a burgeoning personal friendship between you and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>3:39 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, Mr. Prime Minister, welcome.&nbsp; It&#8217;s great to have you here.&nbsp; And later this afternoon, we&#8217;re going to celebrate 201 years &#8212; 201 years of Greek independence and strong ties of family and shared democratic values with the United States, and a burgeoning personal friendship between you and I.&nbsp; You’ve been wonderful.</p>



<p>The democratic ideals that we so cherish originated in Greece, as we all know, inspired by our founders who were students of Greece, and for centuries has empowered &#8212;</p>



<p>(A cell phone interrupts.)&nbsp; Someone is playing music.&nbsp; Anybody want to make that phone call?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; It happens all the time.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t worry about it.</p>



<p>Sadly, Russia’s brutal attack on Ukraine is also about a threat to democracy from autocrats who want to bear down on rules-tested orders and &#8212; rules-based orders.</p>



<p>I want to thank you, Mr. Prime Minister, for Greeks’ moral leadership here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not easy, I know.&nbsp; But thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have much to discuss today on our ongoing support for Ukraine, our deepening defense and trade partnerships, energy security, climate change, and so much more.</p>



<p>Today, the friendship and partnership between our countries, between Greek &#8212; the Greeks and Americans is, I think, more important than ever.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m honored to celebrate that partnership with you because you&#8217;ve been a good friend.&nbsp; So, welcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The floor is yours.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER MITSOTAKIS:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you very much, Mr. President, for these kind words.&nbsp; It is indeed a privilege for me to be here in the United States to celebrate with you 201 years since the beginning of our War of Independence.</p>



<p>As you know, your founding fathers were inspired by the ideals of Athenian democracy, and our founding fathers were inspired by the struggle for independence on these &#8212; on these lands.&nbsp; And over the past two centuries, our two countries have always been on the right side of history.&nbsp; We fought in wars together.&nbsp; And, of course, we are now facing, united, the challenge of Russia&#8217;s invasion into Ukraine.</p>



<p>At the same time, this visit is an opportunity to reassess the status of our relationship.&nbsp; I honestly believe it is at an all-time high.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not just speaking about the defense component of the relationship, but I&#8217;m also speaking about trade investment &#8212; Greece&#8217;s role as a reliable partner in the eastern Mediterranean, as a country that overcame the financial crisis with a booming economy, and as a pillar of stability both in the Balkans and in the broader region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, when we talk about issues such as energy security, there&#8217;s so much more we can &#8212; we can do together.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m very, very happy to be here with you to discuss these important topics and, later, to be able to address also your many Greek-American friends.&nbsp; And I know how close your ties are to Greeks and Greek Americans.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a privilege to have them here at the White House.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Well, I’m delighted you’re here.  Thank you.  And I look forward to our discussion.</p>



<p>3:43 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
