<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 13:09:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Senior Officials from the Federal Republic of&#160;Nigeria</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-senior-officials-from-the-federal-republic-of-nigeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 13:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met yesterday with Nigerian Presidential Chief of Staff Professor Ibrahim Gambari and Nigerian National Security Advisor Babagana Monguno at the White House.  Mr. Sullivan affirmed the Administration’s commitment to collaborate with Nigeria to tackle shared global challenges, including ending the COVID-19 pandemic, building a more inclusive global economy, and combatting&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met yesterday with Nigerian Presidential Chief of Staff Professor Ibrahim Gambari and Nigerian National Security Advisor Babagana Monguno at the White House.  Mr. Sullivan affirmed the Administration’s commitment to collaborate with Nigeria to tackle shared global challenges, including ending the COVID-19 pandemic, building a more inclusive global economy, and combatting the climate crisis.  The leaders discussed shared concerns about democratic backsliding and political instability in West Africa and the importance of ongoing efforts by the Economic Community of West African States to reverse military seizures of power and restore constitutional order in Burkina Faso, Guinea, and Mali.  Mr. Sullivan conveyed U.S. support for Nigeria’s important preparations to hold free and fair elections in 2023 and counter violent extremists and terrorist groups.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 8,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/08/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-8-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:41 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160;&#160;Okay.&#160;&#160;Well, happy Tuesday, everyone.&#160;&#160;As you all know &#8212; just a couple of announcements for all of you at the top.&#160;&#160;As you all know, the pandemic-induced global supply chain backlog has strained our transportation industry and created a critical shortage of truck drivers.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Almost two&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:41 P.M. EST<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Okay.&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, happy Tuesday, everyone.&nbsp;&nbsp;As you all know &#8212; just a couple of announcements for all of you at the top.&nbsp;&nbsp;As you all know, the pandemic-induced global supply chain backlog has strained our transportation industry and created a critical shortage of truck drivers.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Almost two months ago, the Biden-Harris administration launched a Trucking Action Plan to strengthen America&#8217;s workforce.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A key element of this plan is encouraging the trucking industry to recruit and retain well-trained drivers by creating a safe, welcoming, and stable career path with good-paying jobs and family-sustaining wages.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We can think of few Americans better prepared to take on this challenge than our nation&#8217;s veterans, since many have military trucking experience, are familiar with safety culture, and have maintenance skills.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Friday, the administration met with veteran service organizations representing nearly 4 million veterans to discuss ways that we and the industry could attract, train, place, and retain veterans in trucking jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And today, we&#8217;re pleased to announce the Departments of Labor, Transportation, Defense, Veterans Affairs, and the Small Business Administration will be raising awareness about 16 different federal programs that can &#8212; that can connect transitioning military personnel and veterans to rewarding careers in the trucking industry.&nbsp; A highlight of these efforts is the Department of Labor&#8217;s Registered Apprenticeship Program.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we see this as a win-win-win &#8212; getting more veterans to work, addressing the shortages in the trucking industry.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also wanted to note that, as you&#8217;ve heard the President talk about a fair amount, he&#8217;s committed to using every tool at his disposal to bring down prices.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re going to hear him talk and the administration talk a lot about this as the &#8212; as the week proceeds.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re working to ease supply chain bottlenecks and give consumers more choices.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we continue to push for legislation like Build Back Better and a competitiveness bill that will make our economy stronger, lower the costs of essentials, bring more manufacturing to the United States, and strengthen our supply chains.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This week, the President is also going to be meeting with business leaders and traveling in the country &#8212; to Virginia, as you know &#8212; to highlight his plan to address prices.&nbsp; While we&#8217;re made &#8212; we&#8217;ve made remarkable strides with the fastest economic growth since 1984 and the most jobs created in one year ever, he knows there&#8217;s more work to do to keep prices down.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He will al- &#8212; he also talked this afternoon, as you just all heard him do, about how we can build more in America, bring down costs through making more in America, and rebuilding our supply chains.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as I noted, tomorrow he&#8217;ll be hosting CEOs at the White House to talk about how Build Back Better can lower energy costs.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you know, he&#8217;s going to Virginia on Thursday to talk about lowering the price of prescription drugs.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With that, Colleen, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, a couple things.&nbsp; Do you have any information about a possible security threat at Dunbar High School where the Second Gentleman was?&nbsp; I think he was just taken from the event and it was postponed, but we don&#8217;t know &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates on this.&nbsp; We will venture to see if we can get to anything, even if it&#8217;s during the briefing.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It just happened, yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Excellent.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, second, the remaining Child Tax Credit is &#8212; you know, the Biden administration is encouraging people to use what&#8217;s left of the remaining tax credit.&nbsp; So, to what extent do you hope that you can show the benefits of the program to overcome skepticism about the program, kind of by getting this last bunch of money out there?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more thing after.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, one of the steps we&#8217;re trying to take here, which is &#8212; which is showcased by the fact that today the Vice President, Secretary Yellen, and Gene Sperling are hosting a Day of Action with over 100 nonprofits and community-based organizations to encourage all Americans to take advantage of critical tax credits, including the expanded Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit when they file their taxes this year.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Part of the reason we&#8217;re doing that is because we know how effective it is.&nbsp; We know that it helped cut child poverty by 40 percent last year.&nbsp; We know it helped give many families some extra breathing room at a time where the economy was still recovering.&nbsp; And studies show that the Child Tax Credit also helps working families with development &#8212; with developments and opportunities for their children.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s important to remember &#8212; and this one of the things they&#8217;ll be talking about today &#8212; that Americans that qualify for the extended Child Tax Credit will still receive half of the entire benefit when they file their taxes this year.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And yesterday, we launched a new version of ChildTaxCredit.gov to help Americans get the full Child Tax Credit as tax filing season begins.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, part of our effort here is to continue to talking about &#8212; continue talking about the benefits: how they&#8217;re helping working families; how they&#8217;re helping many women who need &#8212; who need an extra hand to cover childcare costs; and how they&#8217;re helping give people a little extra breathing room.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then lastly, if Dr. Lander &#8212; the President accepted his resignation last night, I think.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Or this morning.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Last night.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last night.&nbsp; I mean, not to go back to yesterday&#8217;s discussion, but should he have just fired him to begin with, if he was just going to offer his resignation anyway, and spare all of the criticism from yesterday?&nbsp; I mean, I don&#8217;t know, should there have been things done differently, I guess?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me reiterate something I said yesterday, because I think it&#8217;s important for people to hear that, from the outset, Dr. Lander&#8217;s behavior was unacceptable.&nbsp; Senior White House officials conveyed that to him directly at the conclusion of the investigation.&nbsp; And, of course, we talked about that yesterday.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what happened here is we took &#8212; we &#8212; as a part of the implementation of the Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy &#8212; something that we implemented and announced last May, or put out there last May &#8212; we implemented a process &#8212; including an investigation, including a meeting that Dr. Lander had with senior White House officials &#8212; to convey the severity of his actions and what steps he was expected to take and the fact that there would be complia- &#8212; he would be expected to be compliant.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you saw, we released Dr. Lander&#8217;s note last night to all of you &#8212; or his letter of resignation, I should say.&nbsp; It was made clear to him &#8212; through the course of the day yesterday, I suppose &#8212; that he could no longer lead OSTP effectively.&nbsp; And he conveyed that in his letter.&nbsp; The President accepted his resignation.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I think we&#8217;re now focused on looking forward.&nbsp; There&#8217;s obviously a lot of important work that OSTP will do, continue to do, and continue to lead on moving forward.&nbsp; And the President is eager to continue working with them.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A couple on Ukraine.&nbsp; President Macron says that he believes that he achieved this objective of preventing an escalation after his day with Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; What have the French shared with the White House about that meeting?&nbsp; And does the White House believe that we are, today, closer to seeing de-escalation as a result of this meeting than we were yesterday?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the meeting and the press conference, as you may have seen, ended very late last night.&nbsp; So, obviously, we are &#8212; will continue to be in very close contact with our French counterparts at a range of levels.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has spoken with &#8212; with President Macron twice in the last week.&nbsp; I expect he&#8217;ll be engaged with him soon, which we will, of course &#8212; to go back to Kelly&#8217;s question yesterday &#8212; make you all aware of.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would just say we encourage and we&#8217;re encouraged by any efforts at diplomacy.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t &#8212; we still don&#8217;t have any prediction of what President Putin will do.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t control what Russia will do next.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What we can do and what I think President Macron played a role in doing yesterday is making clear with our Allies and partners that there will be massive consequences should Putin choose to further invade Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But in terms of an assessment, we don&#8217;t have any new information or new prediction about where President Putin&#8217;s head is.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the White House not received a readout from the French on this?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We &#8212; we are &#8212; we remain in close touch with our counterparts, but I don&#8217;t have an update on any specifics of behind-the-scenes diplomatic talks.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more one Ukraine.&nbsp; We heard the President and the Chancellor yesterday emphasize this united front.&nbsp; We did not hear the Chancellor mention the phrase &#8220;Nord Stream 2.&#8221;&nbsp; What assurances did this White House get from Germany &#8212; the German government &#8212; about Nord Stream 2 and the future of that pipeline if Russia invades?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you heard the President very definitively say yesterday at the press conference: If Russia further invades Ukraine, there will no longer be a Nord Stream 2 and we will bring an end to it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You heard the German Chancellor also convey yesterday that we are working in lockstep and that we are very coordinated in our efforts.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of the specifics, we’ll let those conversations happen through diplomatic channels.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I would also reiterate that Nord Stream 2 is not currently operational.&nbsp; We agree that it is a point of leverage with President Putin and the Russians.&nbsp; German regulators have suspended certification of the pipeline.&nbsp; And we have been very clear privately, as we have been publicly, about the fact that it would not continue should Russia invade.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I have just one last one.&nbsp; Your reaction to the RNC declaring what happened on January 6th as &#8220;legitimate political discourse&#8221;?&nbsp; And Democrats on the Hill today are being very vocal about this.&nbsp; Hakeem Jeffries says the &#8220;C&#8221; in &#8220;RNC&#8221; stands for &#8220;cult.&#8221;&nbsp; Does the White House agree with that?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it’s clear to Americans that what happened on January 6th was not &#8220;legitimate political discourse.&#8221;&nbsp; Storming the Capitol in an attempt to halt the peaceful transition of power is not legitimate discourse, neither is attacking and injuring over 140 police officers, smashing windows, and defiling offices.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s telling to all of us that some leading Republicans have rejected that characterization, including the former President’s National Security Advisor and the Chief of Staff to the former Vice President, who, as he put it, had a front-row seat that day, including as rioters chanted for the former Vice President to be hanged.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, we certainly reject the notion that that was &#8220;legitimate political discourse,&#8221; as we think very &#8212; a large number of Americans would as well.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I want to ask you about this Army after-action investigation into the Afghanistan withdrawal that was obtained by the Washington Post.&nbsp; First of all, is this is a report that the White House has had an opportunity to review and absorb?&nbsp; And if so, were there any lessons that were learned from it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know, obviously, our national security team, as we said at the time, was going to conduct after-action reports as they would as it relates to the end of any conflict or any engagement of that sort.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, we have always believed that the end of a 20-year war was always going to have significant challenges.&nbsp; We &#8212; as you know and we talked about at the time, through the summer, we were pressing our system hard on whether we were meeting previously established tripwires that would require us to adjust operations at Embassy Kabul.&nbsp; That’s how we looked at it and evaluated it at the time.&nbsp;<br><br>The NSC led that process and convened regular interagency discussions.&nbsp; And, of course, earlier in the summer, we prepositioned U.S. forces in the region to be ready to facilitate a NEO in preparation of exactly that scenario.<br><br>I know I &#8212; I reiterate all of that because I know we haven’t talked about this in great detail in some time, so I just wanted to lay it all out there.<br><br>All that work, of course, took months of planning.&nbsp; But we always look at and assess &#8212; that’s why after-action reports are so important and so essential.&nbsp; In terms of additional reports out of any of these findings, I don’t have anything to report from here.&nbsp; I’d really point you to the Department of Defense.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But has the White House had an opportunity to review this particular report?&nbsp; (Inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, internal &#8212; internal discussions and internal reviews of any &#8212; of any after-action reports, I don’t have any updates on or assessments from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Among the criticisms from military commanders in the document is that, as late as early August of last year, the NSC, quote, &#8220;appeared to lack a sense of urgency&#8221; about planning for an evacuation because &#8220;it would signal [that] ‘we have failed.’&#8221;&nbsp; What’s your reaction to that criticism?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, again, earlier in the summer, we prepositioned U.S. forces to be ready to facilitate a NEO if needed &#8212; meaning an evacuation, if needed, of our embassy there.&nbsp; That is fact in terms of what was planning, what was done at the time.&nbsp;<br><br>And that &#8212; in advance of that, that required months of planning to ensure there were a range of contingencies planned for, as we always do, through the national security team and through the military team.<br><br>And as we prepared in the early summer to leave Afghanistan, we prepositioned military assets in the region that enabled us to execute one of the largest airlifts in history.<br><br>So, I would just say, if you look back at the specific planning steps we took, we did plan for a range of contingencies even while, as we talked about at the time, there wasn&#8217;t an anticipation that &#8212; that the Afghan National Security Forces would fall as they did or as quickly as they did.&nbsp; And that was not anticipated by anyone.&nbsp; But we still had done a range of contingency planning.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, broadly then, do you reject the assertion that was made by various military commanders in this report that they were trying to convince members of the administration of the urgency of planning for the evacuation, but that they were rebuffed?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, there was a range of contingency planning that was done in close coordination by all of the players on the national security team at the time to prepare for a range of options and a range of outcomes.&nbsp;<br><br>No one predicted, as we know and as we talked about a lot during the period of August and September, that the Afghan National Security Forces would fall at the pace they fell.&nbsp; But if you look back at the history of what we actually did and what planning was done, there was a range of planning &#8212; including positioning military forces, including ensuring that we had a plan for a NEO operation for evacuation at the time should that be needed.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we always look back and assess, but I would say the facts of what was planned for at the time show that we were preparing for a range of contingencies.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up real quick on this last exchange.&nbsp; That report did paint a pretty damning picture of the NSC and the State Department pretty much having blinders on while generals sounded the alarm over Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br><br>But we&#8217;re hearing sort of the same bleak, blunt assessments right now from the Pentagon about Ukraine.&nbsp; So, is there &#8212; I guess, any &#8212; is there any closer relationship between the White House and Pentagon &#8212; are the generals being listened to differently now &#8212; post Afghanistan, post this report?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s really important to separate the two.&nbsp; Because, first, we are not in a 20-year war with U.S. troops in Ukraine.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a very different circumstance.&nbsp; I would say that we believe and we continue to view our relationship &#8212; both from the White House, from the diplomatic team, and from the Defense Department &#8212; as one where we are closely coordinating, where there are healthy disagreements as there can be, and the President certainly welcomes them.<br><br>And the after-action reports are very important because you can look at and make assessments about anything you would change moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>But Ukraine and the circumstance &#8212; the situation on the border of Ukraine with Russian troops building up is not the same as ending a 20-year war.&nbsp; That is something the President had talked about for some time, where we were spending an enormous amount of not just money but blood of American service members for the &#8212; over the course of decades.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a different circumstance.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on this meeting between Putin and Macron yesterday, it sounds like the White House does not have a clear idea yet about whether there was in fact a deal or not for Russia to de-escalate or pledge, rather, not to go &#8212; give any further escalation.&nbsp; Obviously, the Kremlin denied reports that the French put out about having struck a deal.<br><br>If the U.S. is not aware of where things stand, doesn&#8217;t that signal that there&#8217;s a separate negotiating track happening between the Europeans and Russia right now that could put the U.S. at risk of being sort of shut out from that discussion?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not in any way.&nbsp; I completely disagree with what you just conveyed.&nbsp;<br><br>First of all, there are a range of diplomatic conversations happening all the time.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been the case for many weeks.&nbsp; The United States is a key player in the vast majority of those negotiations.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, there are important formats, whether it is bilateral leader-to-leader engagement, which President Macron was a part of yesterday; or the Normandy Format, which is something we fully support, which is the format that the Minsk agreement would be discussed through, which includes Ukraine, Russia,&nbsp;<s>Georgia</s>&nbsp;[Germany], and France.&nbsp; That&#8217;s another format that we fully support.<br><br>Those are conversations that have been happening.&nbsp; And typically, through a diplomatic process, there are a range of conversations that are happening at the same time.<br><br>Again, as I noted a little bit earlier, the President spoke with President Macron twice over the last week &#8212; including on Sunday, the day before he spoke with President Putin.&nbsp; And I expect to speak with him soon again.<br><br>But it&#8217;s also important to note that there are others &#8212; German &#8212; the German Chancellor, who was just here yesterday, is also meeting with President Putin tomorrow.&nbsp; And certainly, if there is diplomatic progress, we would welcome that.&nbsp; But we will believe it when we see it with our own eyes at the border.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the warships that moved into the Black Sea, there are some people who are fearing that this is another invasion force potentially targeting the city of Odesa.&nbsp; Obviously, the Kremlin is saying it&#8217;s just exercises.&nbsp; But is there a concern in the White House that, you know, while we&#8217;re buying time for this diplomatic push, that Putin is just bolstering his forces, building his forces while we&#8217;re all talking?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I know that my colleague, John Kirby, has spoken to this from the Pentagon, so I’d point you to his comments.&nbsp; But I would say that we are not &#8212; we are always going to leave the door to diplomacy open because we think as long as we don’t know what President Putin is going to do &#8212; and we don’t; and he has not invaded Ukraine at this point &#8212; then it is important to always keep that door open because that’s always the preferred path.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, we are not just talking; we have built, through 200 engagements &#8212; talking is engaged in part- &#8212; is an important part of it, I guess.&nbsp; But to build a &#8212; an agreement with our partners and allies in Europe about putting together a severe set of economic consequences should they decide to invade.&nbsp;<br><br>We have provided an enormous amount of security assistance to Ukraine to make sure they are prepared.&nbsp; So, we are working on a number of paths, as you should do, but diplomacy is always going to be the preferred path.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last one on masks.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When are we going to hear from the CDC on this guidance?&nbsp; California yesterday changed their guidance.&nbsp; Randi Weingarten &#8212; teachers union &#8212; is vocally asking for the White House and the CDC to weigh in.&nbsp; So when are we going to hear from the CDC about updating the guidance on masks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You’ll have to ask the CDC.&nbsp; The CDC moves at the pace of data and science.&nbsp; I would note that our goal remains continuing to ensure that there is guidance that helps school districts stay open.&nbsp; That’s our goal.&nbsp; We want kids to be in school.&nbsp; Ninety-eight percent of schools are open.&nbsp; That’s a very &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me finish.&nbsp; That’s a very good sign.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We know what works.&nbsp; The CDC is always going to be reviewing their guidance, including mask guidance.&nbsp; But in terms of when they will provide additional new guidance, that is up to them.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Do you believe then that the Democratic- led states who are breaking with the CDC on this guidance, that they&#8217;re not &#8212; that they&#8217;re throwing science away and that the CDC is &#8212; has access to different science somehow?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;We don’t look at it through that prism.&nbsp;&nbsp;These states, I think it’s important to note, they still allow for decisions to be made by local school districts.&nbsp;<br><br>Where we come up with concern &#8212; where we have great concern is if a kid or a parent chooses to wear a mask or a school district decides they should keep mask guidance in place and there are leaders who are preventing them from doing that.&nbsp;&nbsp;That is the place [case] in some other states.<br><br>But our hope is that states, leaders will look at the science and data about what&#8217;s going on, they’ll make decisions about local school districts.&nbsp;&nbsp;Local school districts have always made these decisions.&nbsp;&nbsp;That remains the case.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask about Supreme Court process.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About three weeks left before the President’s &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Who’s counting?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has any of this process moved to a point where you are requesting documents, background materials directly from those women who are among the potential choices?&nbsp;<br><br>And also, how are you facilitating the President in getting advice from allies and so forth, on the outside, who may want to pitch their favorite contenders?&nbsp; We&#8217;re certainly seeing lawmakers and others speaking publicly.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a little different than speaking directly to the President.&nbsp; How is that information getting to him?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me start with the second part, and then I&#8217;ll come back to the first, to the best of my ability.<br><br>So you all have seen that the President has met with, very publicly, both Chairman Durmin [sic] &#8212; Durbin and Ranking Member Grassley.&nbsp; The Chairman and the President and Vice President have also spoken with a number of members to engage with them, get their feedback.&nbsp;<br><br>I had also noted, I think yesterday, that the President has also spoken with a wide range of outside legal experts, as he&#8217;s seeking to consult and to get feedback and advice from them.&nbsp;<br><br>So, he is receiving and engaging with a range of people as he considers this process.&nbsp; I would note also that as he&#8217;s looking at the process, he&#8217;s reviewing not just bios, but he&#8217;s also reviewing cases.&nbsp; And he is looking at binders of cases because he is very &#8212; taking this approach very seriously.&nbsp; He&#8217;s taking a very thorough approach to it.<br><br>In terms of the process, that is &#8212; that is a part of the process, as you know, from covering these, Kelly &#8212; vetting documents &#8212; and that requires engagement with individuals.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics about where that sits.&nbsp; What I would reiterate from the &#8212; and those of you who’ve covered this know this well &#8212; is that we &#8212; later in the process &#8212; the very end of the process is typically when the President would interview candidates.<br><br>We remain &#8212; we remain on track to announce a nominee by the end of the month.&nbsp; But that is typically the very end of the process.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say that the field has narrowed a bit from the dozen or so that we were originally talking about?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is a natural part of the process, but I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics of the numbers.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Going back to the after-action report on the Abbey Gate investigation: It’s incredible what is in this report.&nbsp; Some of the military officials say things such as, “[The Department of State] did not get one message right to the Afghans during the NEO.”&nbsp; “Marines at Abbey Gate were forced to play God by identifying who would be allowed into the airfield.”<br><br>One of the reasons you do an after-action report, as you said, is to go back and assess.&nbsp; But isn’t it also to allow for accountability?&nbsp; Does he President intend to seek any accountability?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we’re going to allow a discussion internally to continue about any after-action report.&nbsp; I have no predictions beyond that at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaking of accountability &#8212; last night, accepting the resignation of Dr. Lander.&nbsp; It’s been postulated here in town that perhaps Dr. Lander would still be working for this administration if POLITICO hadn’t reported the story yesterday morning and if reporters in this room hadn’t asked about it yesterday.&nbsp; Is that a fair assessment?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, again, given that Dr. Lander made the decision himself to submit his resignation, that would be a question best posed to him.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the President was not involved?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, he was not.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And he did not seek Dr. Lander’s resignation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He did not.&nbsp; He made that decision himself.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Frontier has announced plans to buy Spirit Airlines.&nbsp; Is there any concern in this administration about reduced competition?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, broadly speaking, we always have a concern about reduced competition.&nbsp; But in terms of this potential merger, I don’t have any specific comment from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it under discussion, at least?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, you know, that would be reviewed by the Department of Justice and not from here.&nbsp; So I don’t have any additional comment from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; China, as has been widely reported, has largely missed its phase one purchase commitments.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been talk about administration officials voicing, this week, its disappointment over that and frustration.&nbsp; What is the President prepared to do on that front?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first that &#8212; hold on, I have some update on this.&nbsp; Let me just make sure I have the most up-to-date information.&nbsp; One moment.&nbsp; Thanks for your patience.&nbsp;<br><br>So, as you know and have been following this closely, Alex, the USTR has been in conversations with China about its performance regarding purchase commitments under phase one, which they did not meet in 2020 and did not meet in 2021.&nbsp;<br><br>And they have conveyed &#8212; and I would just reiterate on their behalf, the USTR officials &#8212; it is on China to show up and follow through on its commitment.<br><br>So, our &#8212; again, this is under the purview, as you know, of Ambassador Tai.&nbsp; We have expressed our concerns; we have them.&nbsp; In terms of specifically what the President would be prepared to do, we&#8217;re going to continue to engage with Ambassador Tai and the trade team to determine next steps.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, just to be clear, what is the President prepared to do though?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, the USTR, our &#8212; Ambassador Tai is the one who runs point on this.&nbsp; And I would point you to her for any additional comment on the current status.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Finally, there&#8217;s some talk on Capitol Hill about congressional staffers unionizing.&nbsp; Does the President support that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He does.&nbsp; He supports the right of any individual to seek to join a union, to collective bargain.&nbsp; And of course, Capitol Hill staffers are certainly individuals who are pursuing that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the staff been in touch with those folks?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our staff &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; been in touch with them?&nbsp; I would really point you to congressional leadership.&nbsp; I know Speaker Pelosi and her team have spoken to this as well.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So, truckers in Canada last night shut down the Ambassador Bridge, which carries about a quarter of U.S.-Canada trading goods.&nbsp; So what&#8217;s the administration&#8217;s response to this action?&nbsp; And what steps are being taken to ensure the free flow of goods?&nbsp; And also, any preventative steps being taken to address a possible blockade on the Michigan side of that bridge?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first start by saying: I know there&#8217;s been some suggestion &#8212; not by reporters necessarily at all &#8212; but that this congestion is related to the vaccine requirements.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not.&nbsp; I mean, I &#8212; I&#8217;m saying &#8212; I&#8217;m going to get to the protests.&nbsp; But the protests going on across Canada, which have spread to a bridge, are leading to sporadic congestion and blockages.&nbsp;<br><br>I would &#8212; just to go back to my point I was trying to make is that across &#8212; what we&#8217;ve seen with these requirements is, across indus- &#8212; a range of industries, vaccine &#8212; vaccination requirements have been implemented with no disruptions, have helped increase vaccinations.<br><br>These requirements help protect more people from COVID.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s been zero indication across these industries that they would lead to disruptions, including on this policy.&nbsp;<br><br>We, of course, support, as you know, the right to freedom of speech and protest.&nbsp; But we &#8212; and while we do see some of these congestions due to protests, this is clear that these disruptions have broadened in scope beyond the vaccine requirement implementation.&nbsp;<br><br>We &#8212; beyond that, we are, of course, in touch with our Canadian counterparts, but I don&#8217;t have any updates in terms of specific steps.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Ukraine: So, yesterday &#8212; in yesterday&#8217;s briefing, you mentioned that the Minsk Agreements would possibly be a part of these Macron and Putin talks.&nbsp; And now that it’s over, is the U.S. discussing directly with any of the parties the use of the Minsk Agreement as a possible way out of the conflict, as President Zelenskyy has suggested?&nbsp; Do you see that as, sort of, a fruitful pathway toward a diplomatic agreement?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we see the Minsk Agreements &#8212; which are discussed through the Normandy Format, which I was talking about a little bit earlier &#8212; as certainly a format to move things forward.&nbsp; And we stand ready to support these sincere efforts.&nbsp; And, again, we welcome calls for a diplomatic resolution to the conflict in eastern Ukraine, and the Minsk Agreement is a format that those could take place through.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I guess, you know, there’s been some suggestions that the Minsk Agreement would be unfavorable toward Ukraine if implemented in the way that the Russians want it implemented.&nbsp; So, is the U.S. coming down in any way on one side or the other?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are not.&nbsp; We just seem them as a format through which there could be discussion and continued engagement.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, lastly, quickly on competition.&nbsp; You know, Tyson Foods’ stock went up very high yesterday &#8212; I think its highest in about two years &#8212; on the back of record profits on rising meat pri- &#8212; partially on rising meat prices.&nbsp; So how is that posing a challenge to your administration’s efforts to address competition in that industry?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, just four large conglomerates control the majority of the market for beef, pork, and poultry products.&nbsp; And the data shows &#8212; and I think their record profits are evidence of this &#8212; that there have been increases in meat prices while the companies have generated recent record profits.&nbsp; And that’s a good example of it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I would just note, just if you look at historical precedent here: Fifty years ago, ranchers got over 60 cents for every dollar a family spent on beef; today, they get about 39 cents.&nbsp; Fifty years ago, hog farmers got 40 to 60 cents for each dollar they spent; today, it’s about 19 cents.&nbsp; And the big companies are still making major profits.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It certainly shouldn’t work that way.&nbsp; And as the President has said many times: Capitalism without competition isn&#8217;t capitalism, it’s exploitation.&nbsp; And we have continued concern about the lack of competition in these industries.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Mara.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I have a Lander and Ukraine question.&nbsp; First of all, will Rachel Wallace get her job back?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will have to check and see in the internal HR process.&nbsp; I’m happy to do that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, since you’ve made it clear that he was &#8212; he resigned, he was not fired, how does this comport with President Biden’s pledge to fire you, quote, “on the spot” if he found about any kind of mistreatment of employees?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, what we did early in the administration, after he made those comments &#8212; which I think that were the first or second day in office &#8212; was: Our team &#8212; our HR team, our legal team, others &#8212; worked to put in place a Safe And Respectful Workplace Policy.&nbsp;<br><br>And that policy, which is about a six-page document &#8212; I think we made it available to all of you, and we&#8217;re happy to reshare it if useful &#8212; that was the process through which there was an investigation into these allegations.&nbsp; There was a conclusion of that investigation.&nbsp; At the conclusion of that, Eric Lander &#8212; Dr. Eric Lander met with senior members of our officials who made clear what steps needed to be taken and that he would be required to be compliant with those.<br><br>So that was actually an implementation of the President&#8217;s commitment and in an effort to create a process for a large administration to maintain a healthy work environment and create a channel to address issues as they come up.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, “on the spot” meant “on the spot after an investigation&#8221;?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think in any workplace and one where &#8212; like the White House, you need to have a process and a process through which employees can present any concerns they have, any allegations they have, and that there&#8217;s a process that those can be seen through.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what happened in this case.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine, if you could explain to ordinary Americans who find the domestic politics of other countries very mystifying, why couldn&#8217;t Chancellor Scholz say the words “Nord Stream pipeline”?&nbsp; He was asked numerous times, not just in the press conference yesterday, but also later in interviews.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Why can&#8217;t spit out the words that President Biden said?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s what I can speak for, which is the U.S. government, of course, and President Biden and our commitment and agreement that if Russia invades, Nord Stream 2 will not move forward.&nbsp; It is still not operational at this point in time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; We know your position.&nbsp; I’m just asking if you can give us any insights into why Germany can&#8217;t say that.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I &#8212; you are a very industrious reporter, Mara, and I&#8217;m sure you can pose that question to the Germans as well.&nbsp; But I can only speak for our government, and I can &#8212; you heard the President say and reiterate many times yesterday how, you know, strong our relationship and our alliance is; how Germany is one of the most important alliances &#8212; allies we have in the world; how we have full confidence and faith in their commitment to implementing a strong outcome &#8212; or strong consequences should Russia invade.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; If I heard you correctly, earlier you were saying that President Biden was not involved in directly seeking Dr. Lander’s resignation.&nbsp; But can you clarify if he accepted the resignation because of the investigation or because of the public outcry around it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, if you go back to the letter that Dr. Lander submitted &#8212; this is very small type; I don&#8217;t know if this means I&#8217;m getting older &#8212; but, you know, what he conveyed in that letter was that he did not feel that it was possible to continue effectively in his role.&nbsp; He conveyed that, and he felt &#8212; and he also conveyed that he felt the office &#8211;the work of his office was too important.&nbsp;<br><br>And the President &#8212; that was &#8212; was that the result of the public response or the response of his team?&nbsp; You&#8217;d have to ask Dr. Lander that question.&nbsp; But the President accepted the resignation letter he submitted last night.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it sounds like the investigation was completed in December.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Actually, it was it was completed &#8212; the full process was completed at the very end of January.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, why was it &#8212; why did it not occur that there was any repercussions until after it became public?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there was an entire process that was &#8212; went &#8212; was underway, including a meeting with Dr. Lander conveying exactly what steps he would take, would be required to take, that he would be expected to be compliant with those requirements, and that his actions were absolutely unacceptable and would not be tolerated in this White House, and we wanted to prevent them from happening again.<br><br>So that process had under &#8212; had been undergone.&nbsp; It’s standard.&nbsp; And, of course, these things are reported sometimes, as they were &#8212; but to keep HR processes private, in part because you&#8217;re protecting the range of officials who came forward.&nbsp; And that is &#8212; that is the standard process.&nbsp; Sometimes officials speak publicly, as they did in this case, and that&#8217;s their prerogative.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, can you say when the President learned of the internal investigation and if he was briefed on it before this became a more public subject yesterday?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He was made aware in advance of the &#8212; after the conclusion of the investigation.&nbsp; But beyond that, I don&#8217;t have any updates on the timeline.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just one more.&nbsp; A few weeks ago, the President had talked about in his press conference about the desire to get out of Washington.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since then &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He’s still trying.&nbsp; He’s trying to get on that plane.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s my question, I guess.&nbsp; He’s had a trip to Pittsburgh.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He’s had a trip to New York.&nbsp; As you alluded earlier, he&#8217;s going to Virginia.&nbsp; Is this the robust kind of schedule that he&#8217;s looking for?&nbsp; Or is there something that&#8217;s keeping him in Washington?&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think there are a couple things that, obviously, every president juggles, and including this president is juggling right now.&nbsp; If he could spend every day on the road, he probably would do that.&nbsp; And, you know, any &#8212; when you&#8217;re traveling as president, you know, the world comes with you a bit.&nbsp;<br><br>But there&#8217;s certainly an open Supreme Court spot that he needs to fill and he takes very seriously.&nbsp; He wants to approach that very thorough &#8212; with a thorough approach.<br><br>Of course, he&#8217;s getting regular updates on Russia, Ukraine, from his &#8212; Russia and Ukraine and the buildup of troops on the border.<br><br>So there are a number of, of course, important priorities that, at times, can keep a president here and are &#8212; maybe are keeping the President here.<br><br>However, I think we&#8217;ll be getting out there more; he&#8217;ll be getting out there more in the country.&nbsp; Otherwise, maybe he&#8217;ll fire one of us &#8212; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s eager to do that.&nbsp; He wants to be out in the country.<br><br>And I think as we get to the period of time post State of the Union, I think you&#8217;ll see more of that.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just a quick follow-up on Kelly.&nbsp; Has the President spoken with Congressman Clyburn about his advocacy that has been very prominent for Judge J. Michelle Childs for the Supreme Court?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have any updates on specific members he’s engaged with beyond the ones I’ve &#8212; we’ve read out or you’ve seen publicly, though I would say members of our Supreme Court team &#8212; you’re very familiar with &#8212; have been engaged with a range of members, including Mr. Clyburn.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And back on Ukraine: What was the President’s response to this U.S. assessment that a Russian invasion of Ukraine could kill 25- to 50,000 civilians and cause a humanitarian crisis that would end up with 5 million refugees?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say we’re &#8212; I’m not going to get into intelligence assessments from here, obviously.&nbsp; But we, certainly, prepare for a range of contingencies and work and engage with our European partners and counterparts to prepare for them.&nbsp; And that relates to the potential for refugees; it relates to the potential for natural gas or oil shortages.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And those are part of the discussions the President is a part of, our Secretary of State is a part of, and that is why we are doing so much engagement at this point.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Nord Stream 2: The President was pretty confident yesterday that it would not go forward if Russia invaded Ukraine, even though the German Chancellor would not say that.&nbsp; So, I guess, logistically speaking, how would the President ensure that that would not happen?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m just not going to get into more specifics from here.&nbsp; But I can assure you that that is a commitment and one we will deliver on.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But would that include sanctions on anyone or any company that does business with the pipeline?&nbsp; What does that look like?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand why you’re asking, I just don’t have more details I can outline from here at this point.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In hindsight, does he regret waving sanctions on the company behind Nord Stream 2, as the administration did last year?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Nord Stream 2 is not operational at this point in time.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But does he &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And it remains a point of leverage.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it could quickly become operational.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it’s not &#8212; the German regulators have not approved it.&nbsp; So, it’s not operational.&nbsp; It hasn’t been.&nbsp; So, I don’t think we’re looking in the rearview mirror; I think we’re looking at it as a point of leverage with the Russians.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I guess the question is that Putin has been quite aggressive in his stance with Ukraine.&nbsp; He’s amassed over 100,000 troops on their border.&nbsp; He clearly is seeking to use leverage over them.&nbsp; So why let the pipeline go forward at all, regardless of invasion, given the tactics that he’s been using?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I would say that we &#8212; there’s a disagreement &#8212; I’m not sure this is what you’re asking, but &#8212; between us and some in Congress who suggest that sanctioning Nord Stream 2 now would be effective.&nbsp; We don’t agree.&nbsp; We believe that it is a point of leverage and that making clear it will not proceed if Russia invades is a point of leverage.&nbsp; And that’s why we’re proceeding on the path we are.&nbsp; We don’t think that approach would work.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s been some reporting that President Biden has kind of refused to mention Tesla when he’s talking about electric vehicles.&nbsp; There’s kind of been some reporting around that.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, he mentioned Tesla when he was talking about electric vehicles.&nbsp; Anything noteworthy there?&nbsp; Any change in how he approaches this?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would just note: I think we all know that Tesla is a major producer of electric vehicles; I think that’s fair to say, factually.&nbsp; And, certainly, the electric vehicle industry is one that we feel is a huge opportunity for the United States to move towards our clean energy goals and objectives, and a range of auto- &#8212; of automobile makers are a part of the effort.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; The House version of the China competition bill includes a measure that would require a broad screening process of outbound international investments into China &#8212; not in the Senate one.&nbsp; Does the White House support that particular measure?&nbsp; I know National Security Advisor Sullivan has discussed that in general.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, so, right now, as you know, they’re in conference, or they’re discussing.&nbsp; And we are looking at the impact of outbound U.S. investment flows that could circumvent the spirit of export controls or otherwise enhance the technological capacity of our competitors, which is something I think our National Security Advisor has touched on, in ways that would harm our national security, which we would certainly be concerned by.<br>We are in touch with Congress about the proposal and also our efforts broadly in this regard.&nbsp; But again, we’re going to keep working that through Congress, and that’s with leaders there.&nbsp; And that’s where the focus is at, at this point.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Does the climate of high oil gas prices influence how the White House, the administration approaches sanctions on Iran and Venezuela with an eye at getting more supplies into the market?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me just outline for you &#8212; and I know &#8212; I don’t know if Edward is here.&nbsp; Oh, there you are.&nbsp; He asked me this question yesterday, and I just wanted more detail, so I’m just coming back to it a little bit.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, the President is focused on doing everything we can to address the squeeze that we know gas prices can have on families.&nbsp; As he has said, supply of oil around the world should be keeping up with the demand as we’re exiting the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, there’s a couple of areas that we are focused on, and you’re familiar with them, but let me just outline them from here.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re engaging, one, internationally, both with oil-producing and oil-consuming countries.&nbsp; These discussions are happening right now; they’re ongoing.&nbsp; With oil-producing countries, we’re talking about prod- &#8212; proposed production increases.&nbsp; With oil-consuming countries, we’re talking about releases from strategic reserves.&nbsp; Of course, we’re not going to outline every conversation, but that’s largely how we’re approaching it.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two, the President is going to continue to use every tool at his disposal to reduce prices.&nbsp; We’ve already announced a historic release from the strategic petroleum reserve last fall 40 &#8212; of 50 million barrels.&nbsp; Forty million barrels of those barrels are contracted for delivery, including a num- &#8212; thirteen million that we just released in January.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, as you &#8212; this is not &#8212; it wasn’t that 50 million released at once; they’re continuing to be released.&nbsp; We saw a drop in prices, which fell more than 10 cents a gallon in the course of the holiday season after some of that initial release.&nbsp; And all options remain on the table.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Third, we’re focused on protecting consumers from abuse.&nbsp; We know markets have been volatile.&nbsp; Often, firms exploit market volatility to extract excess profits from consumers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re looking at every legal and regulatory authority we have available to ensure consumers are protected.&nbsp; That means responding to any sign of manipulation in the oil commodities markets or&nbsp;<s>gauging</s>&nbsp;[gouging] at the pump.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, we are looking at it.&nbsp; We are approaching it through all of those forums.&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s overarching view on prices, of course, is that he wants to address the squeeze on consumers; is that nobody &#8212; now that we &#8212; that even with barrels &#8212; even with those barrels released, prices are rising, and that&#8217;s because supply is not keeping up with the demand.&nbsp; We know that is the issue &#8212; the core issue.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Nobody should hold back supply at the expense of the American consumer, particularly as the recovery from the pandemic continues, and oil producers around the world have the capacity to produce at levels that match demand and reduce the high prices.&nbsp; That is what we are going to continue to convey.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one real quick point of clarification?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You announced that the &#8212; the cooperative releases are ready.&nbsp; And in a statement, you suggested that maybe those conversations are ongoing.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we assume then there may be future cooperative releases then?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All options remain on the table, but I don’t have anything to preview at this point in time.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, Jen, following up on the trucker question from earlier.&nbsp; Inspired by the so-called &#8220;Freedom Convoy&#8221; in Canada, a group of U.S. truckers say they&#8217;re planning a similar protest in Washington, D.C., possibly for March 1st, to oppose COVID vaccine mandates.&nbsp; That date is obviously &#8212; would coincide with President Biden&#8217;s State of the Union Address.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you know, the trucker convoy in Ottawa has been very disruptive and paralyzed parts of the city&#8217;s downtown.&nbsp; Is the administration making preparations to be ready for an upcoming &#8220;Freedom Convoy&#8221; planned for D.C.?&nbsp; And does the White House have any concerns about this similar &#8212; a similar protest happening here in the nation&#8217;s capital?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And do you mean, by &#8220;preparations,&#8221; like security preparations?&nbsp; Or do you mean &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, security preparations.&nbsp; Or is it on your radar?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;d have to check with our team on security preparations.&nbsp; I think what I would just reiterate here is that we know that requirements work.&nbsp; We have not seen a disruption as it relates to requirements to the industry.&nbsp; Where we have seen disruptions has been related to these convoys and protests.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now, everybody can peacefully protest; we fully support that.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s important to note where the disruption is occurring.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, on a different topic &#8212; and forgive me if I missed this earlier &#8212; does the White House plan to fill Dr. Lander&#8217;s position?&nbsp; How quickly would you want to nominate somebody?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We do.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update on the timing.&nbsp; But certainly, the President is confident in the expertise of the OSTP team and their ability to move forward on key components of the agenda they are responsible for.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my final topic: The White House has recently held kind of local ECD announcements here &#8212; with the Intel project two weeks ago in Ohio, today with the electric vehicle station facility in Lebanon, Tennessee.&nbsp; And so I&#8217;m trying to &#8212; I&#8217;m curious, what is the federal government&#8217;s role been in these sorts of announcements versus the governors of these two states, in terms of getting these projects?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;So, just so I understand your question, what are we &#8212; in terms of how do we get them the mon- &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, these are traditionally the kind of projects you might expect the governor to announce.&nbsp; Instead, we&#8217;re seeing them here in the White House.&nbsp; What kind of role is the Biden administration have &#8212; I mean, are you working in tandem with these governors?&nbsp; Or is it &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Typically &#8212; yes, exactly.&nbsp; And if the governor can attend, we typically invite them.&nbsp; And sometimes they&#8217;ve taken place in states.&nbsp; And, you know, I think it&#8217;s important &#8212; the President believes it&#8217;s important to lift up the ingenuity of American businesses and companies, and especially companies that are creating jobs here in the United States and putting people back to work. &nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Katie.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; As most people in this room have asked about, the President said yesterday that he would shut down Nord Stream 2 if there was a military invasion.&nbsp; He kind of defined it traditionally as &#8220;tanks on the ground.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>So if Putin attacks but doesn&#8217;t send massive forces over the border, perhaps through cyberattacks or through paramilitary forces, does the President feel the Western alliance could still present a united front, given his conversation with the Chancellor yesterday?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, we have a range of contingency.&nbsp; I certainly understand your question, but I don&#8217;t have anything more to detail here.&nbsp; Obviously, we don&#8217;t think Nord Stream 2 is a good deal or a good project; we&#8217;ve been very clear about that.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think, right now, what we&#8217;re focused on is what we think the right diplomatic tactic is, as it relates to deterrence, which is part of approach.&nbsp; And that includes making clear that Nord Stream 2 will not proceed, given, of course, President Putin and the Russians want it to proceed.&nbsp;<br><br>But we have a range of contingencies should Putin invade, should he take other additional steps, and we&#8217;re going to continue to work to be lockstep with our partners.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to clarify: So, if it&#8217;s a cyberattack or paramilitary or anything besides tanks, would he pull &#8212; well, I know it&#8217;s not operational, but would he stop Nord Stream from going forward?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t have anything more to update you on.&nbsp; We have a range of contingencies, depending on &#8212; if any steps that President Putin takes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then would he still keep the science advisor post &#8212; would that still be Cabinet level?&nbsp; I know that was a first &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; with him.&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The President said yesterday he believes President Putin still has a diplomatic off ramp &#8212; that de-escalation is still possible.&nbsp; But last month at the press conference, less than three weeks ago, the President said, about Putin, &#8220;My guess is he will move in.&nbsp; He has to do something.&#8221;&nbsp; Does he no longer believe that President Putin has to do something?&nbsp; And if that&#8217;s the case, what has changed in those couple of weeks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I mean, he either has to de-escalate or invade.&nbsp; Obviously, our preference is that he de-escalates.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m not sure &#8212; I think that&#8217;s what the President likely meant in the time.&nbsp; We still &#8212; we didn&#8217;t at the time, nor do we now have an assessment of him making a decision.&nbsp; Our &#8212; and we can&#8217;t control what Russia will do next.&nbsp;<br><br>What we can do is we can prepare.&nbsp; And we can prepare for a range of contingencies, and we can stay coordinated with our partners and Allies.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what our focus has been.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned at the top that the Thursday event in Virginia is prescription drugs.&nbsp; Can you tell us more about that?&nbsp; Where he&#8217;s going?&nbsp; Why Virginia?&nbsp; And will we have an announcement on prescription drugs?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I expect we&#8217;ll have more tomorrow as we get a little bit closer, but he&#8217;s going outside of Richmond to Congresswoman Abigail Spanberger&#8217;s district.&nbsp; I think she&#8217;s &#8212; she will be at the event as well, as I understand it.&nbsp; And certainly talking about the need to &#8212; to reduce the cost of prescription drugs, something that is bearing a lot of weight on seniors, on families across the country.&nbsp; It’s something that is still a initiative &#8212; a priority that we still have more work to get done.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On that Thursday trip, has the President invited the Republican Governor of Virginia to join him?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me check and see if we have more details on the specifics.&nbsp; It&#8217;s still all final &#8212; getting finalized.&nbsp; And I expect we’ll have more as we get closer to tomorrow, but I&#8217;ll see if we have any more we can get you after the briefing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if so, would he plan to talk to him about their, sort of, differences in opinion on masking at schools?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me just see who&#8217;s been invited to the event and who&#8217;s planning to attend.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll get you more details from there.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Another one on Ukraine.&nbsp; Yesterday, after meeting Putin, President Macron said that one of the options for Ukraine would be to get a status like the one Finland had during the Cold War &#8212; a status of strict neutrality.&nbsp; Is that also an action the President would consider?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I saw that President Macron said this morning that was not a formulation he used and that ending NATO&#8217;s “open door policy” would be a problem.&nbsp; We agree with that.&nbsp; And as we&#8217;ve said previously, we&#8217;re committed to the right of sovereign nations to make their own decisions about their security.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And maybe &#8212; we see there is a very intense diplomatic battle going on around Moscow.&nbsp; And does the President believe that it is really helpful or maybe that it creates, like, uncertainties around the situation and could ultimately benefit the Russians?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean President Putin engaging in diplomatic conversations?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In a lot of diplomatic conversations.&nbsp; And after every encounter, there is a press conference and there are new questions about “are the Allies really aligned?” &nbsp;Is there maybe concern that there is maybe too much going on?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think what you hear from the Allies time and time again is that we are aligned and we &#8212; there will be severe consequences.&nbsp; And that does not mean that consequences will be identical from every country.&nbsp; It means we agree that invading Ukraine, a sovereign country, is &#8212; violates global norms.&nbsp; And we have worked hard, through more than 200 engagements, to &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t happen by accident, I guess is my point &#8212; to ensure that we remain coordinated and closely working together.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Two topics.&nbsp; The first one is going to be the truckers and then Russia, but first the Canadian &#8212; the movement in Canada &#8212; the truckers.&nbsp; So, the Ottawa mayor has asked for 1,800 additional police officers to quell what he called the “insurrection.”&nbsp; You know that it&#8217;s been a rallying cry for the far right &#8212; this movement.&nbsp; And Prime Minister Trudeau yesterday accused the protestors to &#8212; of trying to blockade Canada&#8217;s economy and democracy.&nbsp; Does the White House share this perspective on the movement?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not how we&#8217;ve described it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you &#8212; you said yesterday, just again, that the CBP was not impacted by the movement at the moment.&nbsp; Now with what happened at the bridge, it has had an impact.&nbsp; Isn’t that &#8212; considering that now trade is concerned, shouldn&#8217;t the White House give more emphasis &#8212; put more emphasis on what&#8217;s going on on the other side of the border?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;ve ever deemphasized.&nbsp; I just think I was trying to convey that while there was kind of a view by some that it was related to vaccine requirements, it wasn&#8217;t; it was related to congestion created by the protests, which I think is for &#8212; important for people to understand.<br><br>In terms of what&#8217;s being done, of course we&#8217;re closely engaged.&nbsp; The Department of Homeland Security would be the right entity to talk to.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just the last question on Russia.&nbsp; Sorry.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Russian President yesterday with Emmanuel Macron commented, and I quote, “They’re trying” &#8212; “they” being the West, the U.S., NATO &#8212; “trying to calm us down with assurances that NATO is a peaceful and defensive organization.”&nbsp; But then he cited Iraq, Libya, Belgrade as counterexamples.&nbsp; What do you say to that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; NATO has always been a defensive alliance.&nbsp; It is Russia that is &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In Libya &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me finish my answer.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is Russia that is building up tens of thousands of troops &#8212; troops at the border, not NATO.&nbsp; We are working to plus-up support for our partners.&nbsp; They have the ability to deescalate, and we certainly hope they do that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Jen.&nbsp; This afternoon, the White House issued a statement criticizing Florida legislation that would restrict classroom discussion of sexual orientation or gender identity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s relatively rare for the White House to weigh in on state-level legislation.&nbsp; So can you speak about the decision to weigh in on this particular bill and why this issue rose to the level that the White House wanted to put something out there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, for those of you who weren&#8217;t following this &#8212; maybe all of you were &#8212; but let me first say that every parent, as one myself too, hopes that our leaders will ensure their children&#8217;s safety, protection, and freedom.&nbsp; And today, conservative politicians in Florida rejected those basic values by advancing legislation that is designed to target and attack the kids who need the support &#8212; support the most: kids from the LGBTQI+ community who are already vulnerable to bullying &#8212; and we&#8217;ve seen that in study after study &#8212; and violence, just for being themselves and just for being who they are.&nbsp;<br><br>Make no mistake: This is not an isolated action in Florida.&nbsp; Across the country, we&#8217;re seeing Republican leaders taking action to regulate what students can or cannot read, what they can or cannot learn, and most troubling, who they can or cannot be.&nbsp; This is who these kids are.&nbsp; And these &#8212; these legislators are trying to make it harder for them to be who they are.<br><br>So, we felt it was important to speak out against this action and speak really &#8212; and felt it was important to do that today.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House reaction to the Supreme Court, late yesterday, restoring an Alabama voting map that a lower court ruled was discriminatory?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; This is a very important story.&nbsp; So I would say that we need to make sure, as you&#8217;ve heard the President say, that our sacred voting rights are fully protected.&nbsp; We should be moving forward, not backward.&nbsp; That is always the view of the President, the Vice President, and this White House.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That means ensuring fair election maps that protect the rights of Black voters to have an equitable and meaningful opportunity to elect candidates of their choice as the Voting Rights Act and Supreme Court precedent have guaranteed for decades.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is deeply disturbing to us that the Supreme Court gave Alabama a free pass to use a map that &#8212; in 2022 &#8212; that three federal judges found to discriminate against Black voters.&nbsp; This is exactly what the Voting Rights Act is in place to prevent and what &#8212; and one of the reasons it’s so important to pass a reauthorization into law.&nbsp; Without &#8212; and they did this without the Supreme Court finding any reason to doubt that conclusion.&nbsp; That is concerning to us.&nbsp;<br><br>And certainly protecting people’s rights &#8212; not taking steps backward &#8212; is our objective.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The administration, as you know, through the Justice Department took legal action against Texas.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They challenged those maps perceived as being discriminatory.&nbsp; Given that voting rights legislation here in Washington has basically been put on pause for a number of reasons, has the White House considered any sort of unilateral or preemptive actions against states that might try to take similar steps as Texas and Alabama did?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I understand the question.&nbsp; I would point you to the Department of Justice.&nbsp; As you know, but for others, we’re not a party to this lawsuit, but I would point you to the Department of Justice.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; A couple on Dr. Lander.&nbsp; I want to be precise, first, I guess on his resignation, because you said it became clear to him yesterday.&nbsp; Was &#8212; did the President or anybody else in the White House encourage him to resign, or was this 100 percent totally voluntary?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This was a decision made by Dr. Lander.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And what does it say to the staff, I guess, in the administration that the President appeared happy to keep him in his role until essentially this became public and became untenable, at least in Dr. Lander’s mind?&nbsp; What does that say to the staff?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wouldn’t say that’s an accurate depiction of how the President feels or we feel.&nbsp; And so, I appreciate the opportunity to restate that Dr. Lander’s behavior was not acceptable at all, and the President did not view it as acceptable either.&nbsp;<br><br>There was a full process that was undergone; that was an implementation of the policies put in place last spring &#8212; the Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy.&nbsp; That included a thorough investigation.&nbsp; It included a meeting of Dr. Lander with individual &#8212; senior officials from the White House team.&nbsp; And it included specific steps he had to take to prevent this from happening ever again.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think what people should be assured of in the White House is that the President is committed to maintaining a healthy work environment, to creating a channel also to address any issues that come up, and that channel was created through this policy last May.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, are there any other senior White House staff or Cabinet members who have been subject to investigations like this?&nbsp; And can the White House commit to making them public in the future, given that it was a public scrutiny here that ended up in a resignation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I certainly understand the question, and we want to create an environment here that’s safe and people feel comfortable and they also the know the channel where they can express concerns as they have them.<br><br>But this is an HR process, and an internal process because of that, and we typically keep those processes private to respect the individuals &#8212; the privacy of the individuals who come forward, if individuals come forward.&nbsp; And that’s how we would proceed moving forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you can’t say “yes” or “no” whether there are other investigations similar to this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, those are private processes and HR processes.&nbsp; And if individuals choose to speak publicly, that, of course, is their prerogative.&nbsp; But as is true of any HR process in any company, we would certainly keep that process private as a policy.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any reevaluation of the workplace policies and goals here, given this &#8212; given everything that’s happened, I guess, here?&nbsp; Is there any feeling needing to go back and revisit whether those are effective and not effective?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, again, our objective is to prevent this behavior &#8212; unacceptable behavior from ever happening again.&nbsp;<br><br>And the Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy, which was implemented in this case, provides a channel for any individual to come forward if they have concerns, where their concerns can be addresses through a thorough process.&nbsp; And hopefully people know that.&nbsp; And it is part of an effort to maintain a healthy work environment.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Immigration reform seems like a nonstarter in the current Congress.&nbsp; But today, freshman Republican Congresswoman Maria Elvira Salazar presented an immigration reform bill that would legalize millions of undocumented.&nbsp; And she’s calling it a starting point.&nbsp; She’s got Republican backing.&nbsp; Will the President agree to invite her to the White House, listen to her ideas and incorporate them somehow?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President proposed an immigration bill on his first day in office, and certainly he’s eager to work with anybody who wants to put in place compr- &#8212; immigration reform policies that would create a safer system, a more effective system, a more humane system at the border.&nbsp; I’m not familiar with all of the specific details, but certainly we engage with a range of members about their policies.<br><br>Let me just do one last one here.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to ask for an update on how many COVID-19 rapid tests you’ve received from the President’s pledge to provide free testing.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Have been sent out?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Received to you and then sent out to Americans.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh.&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I know there’s a COVID briefing, I think tomorrow or Thursday.&nbsp; Let me check with them and see.&nbsp; I don’t have the numbers in front of me, but I can see if they’re in a position to provide an update on that.<br><br>Okay, everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Olympics &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; I think we’ve got to wrap up, but more tomorrow.&nbsp; Let’s do this again.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you finally take a question on Africa?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m often answering questions on Africa.&nbsp; I’m happy to do some more tomorrow.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We didn’t (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll look forward to talking to all of you tomorrow.&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>3:40 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Economists on the Benefits of Infrastructure&#160;Investment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-economists-on-the-benefits-of-infrastructure-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President and members of his economic team today met with Dr. Edward Glaeser and Dr. Janet Currie to discuss the economics of infrastructure investment.  The historic investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law are a key component of the President’s plan to build on the historic economic recovery and boost the capacity of the economy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President and members of his economic team today met with Dr. Edward Glaeser and Dr. Janet Currie to discuss the economics of infrastructure investment.  The historic investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law are a key component of the President’s plan to build on the historic economic recovery and boost the capacity of the economy in order to promote growth, expand economic opportunity, and reduce costs for families. Dr. Glaeser, who is the Fred and Eleanor Glimp Professor of Economics and Chair of the Department of Economics at Harvard University, briefed the President on the economic benefits of investments in infrastructure and the importance of project selection and efficient implementation of infrastructure investment. Dr. Currie, the Henry Putman Professor of Economics and Public Affairs at Princeton University, briefed the President on the effect of lead exposure on a range of outcomes for children. Both the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and the President’s Build Back Better plan include historic investments to reduce lead exposure. In the months ahead, the President will continue to meet with experts and leaders in a range of fields, as he continues to execute on an economic strategy that delivers for the American people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Honors 117 Individuals and Organizations with Highest U.S. Award for Science and Mathematics Teachers and&#160;Mentors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/president-biden-honors-117-individuals-and-organizations-with-highest-u-s-award-for-science-and-mathematics-teachers-and-mentors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden named 117 teachers, mentors, and mentoring organizations as recipients of the Presidential Awards for Excellence in Mathematics and Science Teaching (PAEMST) and Presidential Awards for Excellence in Science, Mathematics and Engineering Mentoring (PAESMEM). These awards honor the dedication, hard work, and important role that America’s teachers and mentors play in supporting&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden named 117 teachers, mentors, and mentoring organizations as recipients of the Presidential Awards for Excellence in Mathematics and Science Teaching (PAEMST) and Presidential Awards for Excellence in Science, Mathematics and Engineering Mentoring (PAESMEM). These awards honor the dedication, hard work, and important role that America’s teachers and mentors play in supporting learners who will be future STEM professionals, including climate scientists, mathematicians, innovators, space explorers, and engineers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I am deeply appreciative of the inspiration that America’s teachers and mentors provide every day to support the next generation of STEM professionals,” <strong>President Biden said.</strong> “The dedication these individuals and organizations have demonstrated to prepare students for careers in STEM fields, during what has been a difficult time for teachers, students, and families, plays a huge role in American innovation and competitiveness.&nbsp; The work that teachers and mentors do ensures that our Nation’s children are able to unlock &#8212; for themselves and all of us – a world of possibilities.”</p>



<p>The benefits of a quality STEM education fail to reach every learner in this country often due to racial, gender, economic, and geographic disparities. STEM teachers and mentors serve as powerful catalysts for developing the vast potential of our Nation’s learners. PAEMST honors STEM teachers for the commitment they bring to the classroom and for their efforts to meet the learning needs of all their students. PAESMEM recognizes mentors for their efforts to inspire and encourage individuals from underserved and underrepresented communities in STEM and their efforts to ensure that all Americans can fully participate in science, mathematics and technology regardless of gender, race, resources or geography.</p>



<p><strong>Presidential Awards for Excellence in Mathematics and Science Teaching (PAEMST)</strong></p>



<p>Established in 1983, PAEMST is the highest award kindergarten through 12th grade mathematics and science (including computer science) teachers can receive from the U.S. government. Each year, the award criteria alternates years between kindergarten through sixth grade and seventh through 12th grade teachers. This year, kindergarten through sixth grade teachers will receive Presidential Awards for Excellence in Mathematics and Science Teaching (PAEMST).</p>



<p>Award recipients over the years represent schools and organizations from all 50 states, Washington D.C., Puerto Rico, Department of Defense Education Activity (DODEA) schools, and the U.S. territories (American Samoa, Guam, Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and U.S. Virgin Islands).</p>



<p>Nominees complete a rigorous application process that allows them to demonstrate deep content knowledge and their ability to adapt to a broad range of learners and teaching environments.</p>



<p>A panel of distinguished mathematicians, scientists and educators at the state and national levels assess the applications before recommending nominees to the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP). Teachers are selected based on their distinction in the classroom and dedication to improving STEM education.</p>



<p><strong>Presidential Awards for Excellence in Science, Mathematics and Engineering Mentoring (PAESMEM)</strong></p>



<p>PAESMEM recognizes the critical roles mentors play outside the traditional classroom in the academic and professional development of the future STEM workforce.</p>



<p>Colleagues, administrators, and students nominate individuals and organizations for exemplary mentoring sustained over a minimum of five years. Since 1995, PAESMEM has honored the hard work and dedication mentors exhibit in broadening participation in STEM pathways.</p>



<p>Mentors support learners from the kindergarten through collegiate levels, as well as those who recently have started their careers in STEM. They share their expertise and guidance with learners, sometimes through formal mentoring programs. Learners are often from underrepresented and underserved communities in STEM.</p>



<p>The National Science Foundation (NSF), which manages PAEMST and PAESMEM on behalf of the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), provides each recipient $10,000.&nbsp; Award recipients also receive a certificate signed by the President. For more information, please visit<a> </a><a href="http://www.paemst.org">PAEMST</a>&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.paemst.org">www.paemst.org</a>) and&nbsp;<a href="/Users/NHHuntOwens/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/WKSQ4ON8/www.paesmem.net">PAESMEM</a> (<a href="http://www.paesmem.net">www.paesmem.net</a>).</p>



<p><strong>Recipients of the Presidential Award for Excellence in Mathematics and Science Teaching (PAEMST) are listed below with their award category in parentheses:</strong></p>



<p><strong>ALABAMA</strong></p>



<p>Elizabeth Baranov, Hutchens Elementary School, Mobile (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Jennifer Kennedy, SPARK Academy at Cowart Elementary School, Athens, Alabama (Science)</p>



<p><strong>ALASKA</strong><br>Cori Ferenczy, Airport Heights Elementary School, Anchorage, Alaska (Mathematics)<br></p>



<p>Jason Daniels, Kalifornsky Beach Elementary School, Soldotna, Alaska (Science)</p>



<p><strong>ARIZONA</strong></p>



<p>Agnus Post, Tucson County Day School, Tucson, Arizona (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Robyn Yewell, Harelson Elementary School, Tucson, Arizona (Science)</p>



<p><strong>ARKANSAS</strong></p>



<p>Lindsay Hall, Bernice Young Elementary School, Springdale, Arkansas (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Lisa Taylor, Willis D. Shaw Elementary School, Springdale, Arkansas (Science)</p>



<p><strong>CALIFORNIA</strong></p>



<p>Khamphet Pease, Wilson Middle School, San Diego, California (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Marlys Williamson, Wolf Canyon Elementary School, Chula Vista, California (Science)</p>



<p><strong>COLORADO</strong></p>



<p>Michelle Dillard, Twain Elementary School, Centennial, Colorado (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Stephanie Basile, STEM Lab, Northglenn, Colorado (Science)</p>



<p><strong>CONNECTICUT</strong></p>



<p>Mallory Emmons, The Peck Place School, Orange, Connecticut (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Lori Durocher, Norfeldt Elementary School, West Hartford, Connecticut (Science)</p>



<p><strong>DELAWARE</strong></p>



<p>Brandi Luloff, Townsend Elementary School, Townsend, Delaware (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Leona Williams, Forwood Elementary School, Wilmington, Delaware (Science)</p>



<p><strong>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</strong></p>



<p>Sarah Werstuik, Brent Elementary School, Washington, D.C. (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Sheri Frierson-Chenier, Kimball Elementary School, Washington, D.C. (Science)</p>



<p><strong>DODEA</strong></p>



<p>Lachanda Garrison, Bahrain Elementary School, FPO AE DoDEA (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Antoine Sharpe, Humphreys Middle School, APO, AP, DoDEA (Mathematics)</p>



<p><strong>FLORIDA</strong></p>



<p>Lori Price, The Webster School, St. Augustine, Florida (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Katrina Madok, Gerald Adams Elementary School, Key West, Florida (Science)</p>



<p><strong>GEORGIA</strong></p>



<p>Dyanna Motes, Kemp Elementary School, Powder Springs, Georgia (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Duane Doblar, R. D. Head Elementary School, Lilburn, Georgia (Science)</p>



<p><strong>HAWAII</strong></p>



<p>Wrayna Fairchild, Voyager Public Charter School, Honolulu, Hawaii (Science)</p>



<p>Crystal Doi, Nu’uanu Elementary School, Honolulu, Hawaii (Science)</p>



<p><strong>IDAHO</strong></p>



<p>Leigh Wilson, Potlatch Elementary School, Potlatch, Idaho (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Courtney Greene, Bryan Elementary, Coeur d’Alene, Idaho (Science)</p>



<p><strong>ILLINOIS</strong></p>



<p>Brandy Hempen, Germantown Elementary School, Germantown, Illinois (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Carla Shortino, Catherine Cook School, Chicago, Illinois (Science)</p>



<p><strong>INDIANA</strong></p>



<p>Amanda Fox, Prairie Vista Elementary School, Granger, Indiana (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Sara Hoover, Beiger Elementary School, Mishawaka, Indiana (Science)</p>



<p><strong>IOWA</strong></p>



<p>Angela Bonthuis, Gilbert Elementary School, Gilbert, Iowa (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Sarah Borzo, South Middle School, Waukee, Iowa (Science)</p>



<p><strong>KANSAS</strong></p>



<p>Callie Harris, Maize Elementary School, Maize, Kansas (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Zerrin Oelze, McLean Science &amp; Technology Magnet Elementary School, Wichita, Kansas (Science)</p>



<p><strong>KENTUCKY</strong></p>



<p>Kaysin Higgins, North Calloway Elementary School, Murray, Kentucky (Mathematics)</p>



<p>David McDowell, Mason County Middle School, Maysville, Kentucky (Science)</p>



<p><strong>LOUISIANA</strong></p>



<p>Stephanie Gullage, R. K. Smith Middle School, Luling, Louisiana (Mathematics)</p>



<p>James Evans, Sterlington Middle School, Sterlington, Louisiana (Science)</p>



<p><strong>MAINE</strong></p>



<p>Michele Flores, Deer Isle-Stonington Elementary School, Deer Isle, Maine (Science)</p>



<p>Cindy Soule, Gerald E. Talbot Community School, Portland, Maine (Science)</p>



<p><strong>MARYLAND</strong></p>



<p>Joanie Gulden, Glen Burnie Park Elementary School, Glen Burnie, Maryland (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Melissa Thompson, Arlington Elementary School #234, Baltimore, Maryland (Science)</p>



<p><strong>MASSACHUSETTS</strong></p>



<p>Laura Richardson, Edith C. Baker School, Chestnut Hill, Massachusetts (Science)</p>



<p>Daniel Adler, UP Academy Leonard, Lawrence, Massachusetts (Science)</p>



<p><strong>MICHIGAN</strong></p>



<p>Stephanie Giroux Phillips, Murphy Elementary School, Metamora, Michigan (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Bridget Zahradnik, Parkview Elementary School, Novi, Michigan (Science)</p>



<p><strong>MINNESOTA</strong></p>



<p>Abram Schwartz, Bemidji Middle School, Bemidji, Minnesota (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Brian Hare, E-STEM Middle School, Woodbury, Minnesota (Science)</p>



<p><strong>MISSISSIPPI</strong></p>



<p>Millicent Gunter, Bayou View Elementary School, Gulfport, Mississippi (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Laura Bivins, Ann Smith Elementary School, Ridgeland, Mississippi (Mathematics)</p>



<p><strong>MISSOURI</strong></p>



<p>Cassidy Urie, Jefferson Middle School, Columbia, Missouri (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Stacy Sharp-Adamson, Bell Prairie Elementary School, Kansas City, Missouri (Science)</p>



<p><strong>MONTANA</strong></p>



<p>Shianne Schmidt, Olney-Bissell School, Whitefish, Montana (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Christina Pavlovich, East Side Intermediate School, Livingston, Montana (Science)</p>



<p><strong>NEBRASKA</strong></p>



<p>Leah Litz, Bancroft Elementary School, Omaha, Nebraska (Science)</p>



<p><strong>NEVADA</strong></p>



<p>Amie Braik, Nick Poulakidas Elementary School, Reno, Nevada (Science)</p>



<p><strong>NEW HAMPSHIRE</strong></p>



<p>Tristan Bowen, Riddle Brook School, Bedford, New Hampshire (Science)</p>



<p><strong>NEW JERSEY</strong></p>



<p>Bruce Williams, Hedgepeth-Williams Middle School of the Arts, Trenton, New Jersey (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Helen Corveleyn, Hopewell Elementary School, Hopewell, New Jersey (Science)</p>



<p><strong>NEW MEXICO</strong></p>



<p>Silvia Miranda, Mesa Elementary School, Clovis, New Mexico (Mathematics)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hope Cahill, El Dorado Community School, Santa Fe, New Mexico (Science) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>NEW YORK</strong></p>



<p>Lynda Brennan, RP Connor Elementary School, Suffern, New York (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Leslie Anson, Millbrook Middle School, Millbrook, New York (Mathematics)</p>



<p><strong>NORTH CAROLINA</strong></p>



<p>Sarah Remery, Trindale Elementary School, Archdale, North Carolina (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Rolie Webb, Forest Hills Global Elementary School, Wilmington North Carolina (Science)</p>



<p><strong>OHIO</strong></p>



<p>Krystina Pratt, New Albany Primary School, New Albany, Ohio (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Stephanie Nowak, Fairfax Elementary School, Mentor, Ohio (Science)</p>



<p><strong>OKLAHOMA</strong></p>



<p>Jennifer Donwerth, Centennial Elementary School, Edmund, Oklahoma (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Karla White, Science, Earl Harris Elementary School, Bethany, Oklahoma (Science)</p>



<p><strong>OREGON</strong></p>



<p>Amber Linn, North Star Elementary School, Bend, Oregon (Mathematics)</p>



<p><strong>PENNSYLVANIA</strong></p>



<p>Jessica Tilli, William M. Meredith School, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Kristin Joivell, Juniata Valley Elementary School, Alexandria, Pennsylvania (Science)</p>



<p><strong>PUERTO RICO</strong></p>



<p><strong>Audha Ramirez, Colegio Sagrado Corazon de Jesus, San Juan, Puerto Rico (Mathematics)</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><strong>Janine Hidalgo, Academia San Ignacio de Loyola, San Juan, Puerto Rico (Science)</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><strong>RHODE ISLAND</strong></p>



<p>Nicolle Greene, Holliman Elementary School, Warwick, Rhode Island (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Nicole Lemire, Samuel Slater Middle School, Pawtucket, Rhode Island (Science)</p>



<p><strong>SOUTH CAROLINA</strong></p>



<p>Kimberly Rothberg, Carolina Forest Elementary School, Myrtle Beach, South Carolina (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Michelle Traynum, Homeland Park Primary School, Anderson, South Carolina (Science</p>



<p><strong>SOUTH DAKOTA</strong></p>



<p>Darcy Vincent, Camelot Intermediate School, Brookings, South Dakota (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Merideth Wald, Black Hawk Elementary School, Black Hawk, South Dakota (Mathematics)</p>



<p><strong>TENNESSEE</strong></p>



<p>Laura Koch, Richland Elementary School, Memphis, Tennessee (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Charles Hayes, Highland Oaks Elementary School, Memphis, Tennessee (Science)</p>



<p><strong>TEXAS</strong></p>



<p>Kristen Butler, Medlin Middle School, Trophy Club, Texas (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Lori Garrett, Cactus Elementary School, Cactus, Texas (Science)</p>



<p><strong>U.S. JURISDICTIONS</strong></p>



<p>Michelle De Guzman, Guam, Juan M. Guerrero Elementary School, Dededo, Guam (Science)</p>



<p>Zahra O’Reilly-Bates, Virgin Islands, Ricardo Richards Elementary School, Kingshill, Virgin Islands (Mathematics)</p>



<p><strong>UTAH</strong></p>



<p>Heidi Boogert, Highland Park Elementary School, Salt Lake City, Utah (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Jennifer Carver-Hunter, Mountain View Elementary School, Salt Lake City, Utah (Science)</p>



<p><strong>VERMONT</strong></p>



<p>Glenda Allen, Barre Town Middle and Elementary School, Barre, Vermont (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Susan Koch, Union Elementary School, Montpelier, Vermont (Science)</p>



<p><strong>VIRGINIA&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Tracey Curcio, Elizabeth Scott Elementary School, Chester, Virginia (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Cathleen Drake-McGarvey, Stony Mill Elementary School, Danville, Virginia (Science)</p>



<p><strong>WASHINGTON</strong></p>



<p>Julie Fry, Roosevelt Elementary School, Yakima, Washington (Science)</p>



<p>Allison Greenberg, Woodside Elementary School, Bothell, Washington (Science)</p>



<p><strong>WEST VIRGINIA</strong></p>



<p>Joni Jones, Suncrest Elementary, Morgantown, West Virginia (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Tiffany Pace, Weberwood Elementary, Charleston, West Virginia (Science)</p>



<p><strong>WISCONSIN</strong></p>



<p>Lois Womack, Marvin E. Pratt Elementary School, Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Leigh Kohlmann, Rock River Intermediate School, Waupun, Wisconsin (Science)</p>



<p><strong>WYOMING</strong></p>



<p>Willis Williams, Buffalo Ridge Elementary School, Cheyenne, Wyoming (Mathematics)</p>



<p>Katie McCue, Eastside Elementary School, Cody, Wyoming (Mathematics)</p>



<p><strong>Individual Recipients of the Presidential Award for Excellence in Science, Mathematics and Engineering Mentoring (PAESMEM) are listed below:</strong></p>



<p>Mohammad Qazi, Tuskegee University, Tuskegee, Alabama</p>



<p>Winny Dong, California State Polytechnic University-Pomona, Pomona, California</p>



<p>Enrico Ramirez-Ruiz, University of California-Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, California</p>



<p>Ansley Abraham, Southern Regional Education Board, Atlanta, Georgia</p>



<p>Junior Bernadin, The Ron Clark Academy, Atlanta, Georgia</p>



<p>Karen Burg, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia,</p>



<p>Mohsen Mosleh, Howard University, Washington D.C.</p>



<p>Cheryl Knobloch, Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>Margaret Baguio, University of Texas at Austin, NASA Texas Space Grant Consortium, Austin, Texas</p>



<p>Minerva Cordero, The University of Texas at Arlington, Arlington, Texas</p>



<p>Carri LeRoy, The Evergreen State College, Olympia, Washington</p>



<p>Joyce Yen, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington</p>



<p><strong>Organizational Recipients of the Presidential Award for Excellence in Science, Mathematics and Engineering Mentoring (PAESMEM) are listed below:</strong></p>



<p>California Academy of Sciences, San Francisco, California</p>



<p>Hawaii Academy of Science, Honolulu, Hawaii</p>



<p>National GEM Consortium, Alexandria, Virginia</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with NATO Secretary General Jens&#160;Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 21:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46937</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg. They discussed their shared concern about Russia’s build-up of forces along Ukraine’s border, and underscored their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. They discussed the readiness of the U.S. and NATO to continue engaging in dialogue with Russia to find a diplomatic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg. They discussed their shared concern about Russia’s build-up of forces along Ukraine’s border, and underscored their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. They discussed the readiness of the U.S. and NATO to continue engaging in dialogue with Russia to find a diplomatic path toward de-escalation. They also underscored the readiness of Allies to defend against any threat to NATO Allies’ territory, including by reinforcing the eastern flank in response to potential Russian aggression.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Rebuilding Our Manufacturing to Make More in&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/remarks-by-president-biden-on-rebuilding-our-manufacturing-to-make-more-in-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 21:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46925</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium Eisenhower Executive Office Building 2:22 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Jane, thank you.&#160; Thank you very, very much.&#160; I want to thank Secretary Granholm and Buttigieg, and Gina McCarthy, for being here today. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; And Congressman Jim Cooper, an old friend who did an awful lot to get this to &#8212; get&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>2:22 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Jane, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you very, very much.&nbsp; I want to thank Secretary Granholm and Buttigieg, and Gina McCarthy, for being here today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Congressman Jim Cooper, an old friend who did an awful lot to get this to &#8212; get this to go in Tennessee, who’s here today.&nbsp; And Governor Bill Lee of Tennessee &#8212; he deserves credit as well.&nbsp; He wasn’t able to be here today, but he worked hard to help make this happen.&nbsp; Another example of what America can achieve when we come together &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; to get things done.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The new manufacturing facility Tritium is &#8212; that it’s announced today is more than just great news for Tennessee.&nbsp; Yes, it’s going to create more than 500 good-paying jobs in Tennessee, but it’s going to deliver greater dignity and a little more breathing room to workers and their families.&nbsp; And it’s going to have a ripple effect beyond &#8212; and far beyond one state.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is great news for workers across the country, for an economy, and, frankly, for the planet.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When we wrote the &#8212; and passed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we included $7.5 billion for electric vehicle chargers, like the one Jane brought along today.&nbsp; It’s a little thing.&nbsp; You can see.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But all kidding aside, Secretaries Granholm and Buttigieg have been helping lead this effort from our administration.&nbsp; And later this week, we’re going to announce a state-by-state allocation for $5 billion of the funding for these chargers.&nbsp; So states can start making plans to build out what will become a national network of electric vehicle chargers.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tritium’s new facility is going to produce up to 30,000 of these chargers every year.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They’ll use American parts, American iron, American steel.&nbsp; And they’ll be installed up and down the highways and corridors in our communities all across the country by union workers from the IBEW and the electric work- &#8212; and the electrical workers union.&nbsp; So, the benefits you’re going to &#8212; ripple thousands of miles away in every direction.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And these jobs will multiply in steel mills, small parts suppliers, construction sites all over the country in the years to come.&nbsp; And it’s going to help ensure that the American &#8212; America leads the world in electric vehicles.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; China has been the &#8212; leading that race up to now.&nbsp; But this is about to change, because America is building convenient, reliable, equitable, national public charging networks.&nbsp; So wherever you live, charging an electric vehicle will be quick and easy.&nbsp; And the foundation will help build &#8212; help American automakers set the pace for electric vehicles, which means even more good-paying jobs producing batteries, materials, and parts.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s also going to help save hundreds of billions of gallons of gasoline over time, serving &#8212; saving an average driver who chooses an electric vehicle up to $1,000 every year on fuel; making our country more economically competitive, lowering air pollution, and keeping families healthier as we tackle climate &#8212; the climate crisis.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Here’s the &#8212; here’s the key point.&nbsp; Announcements like this don’t happen by accident.&nbsp; They require a vision and a commitment to build a future that’s made in America.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I made it clear from day one: When the federal government spends taxpayers’ dollars, we’re going to buy American: American products made in America, including American component parts.&nbsp; That’s why I established a Made in America Office at the White House led by Celeste Drake.&nbsp; She’s here on the stage.&nbsp; Where is Celeste?&nbsp; There is she is.&nbsp; Celeste Drake.&nbsp; To ensure that the trillion dollars we’re investing in infrastructure is spent on American workers and American manufacturing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the way over here, by the way, I was talking with Gina.&nbsp; We were talking about &#8212; we have how many vehicles in a fleet, Gina, roughly?</p>



<p>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; Six hundred thousand.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:  We have 600,000 federal vehicles that we &#8212; the federal government owns.  They’re going to all end up being electric vehicles &#8212; electric vehicles.  That’s what it means to finally make Buy in America a reality and not an empty promise.</p>



<p>     It means bringing manufacturing jobs back and building supply chains here at home so we have better jobs <s>at</s> [and] lower prices.  And it means a federal government that just doesn’t give lip service to Buy American but actually takes action, investing in innovation and manufacturing, which powers up companies like Tritium to do what they do best: create great products and good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s been my approach from day one.&nbsp; And now we’re seeing the results &#8212; beginning to see the results.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In my first full year as President, the economy created 6.6 million new jobs.&nbsp; 6.6 million.&nbsp; That’s never happened before in American history.&nbsp; And that includes 375,000 manufacturing jobs.&nbsp;&nbsp; 2021 saw the highest increase in U.S. manufacturing jobs in nearly 30 years.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And let me give you one example.&nbsp; A few weeks ago, the CEO of Intel, Pat Gelsinger, came to the White House to announce a new $20 billion semiconductor factory that they&#8217;re going to &#8212; they call it a “campus” &#8212; outside of Columbus, Ohio.&nbsp; I had the two senators from Ohio here standing with me &#8212; one Republican, one Democrat.&nbsp; Creating 7,000 construction jobs at that facility and 3,000 permanent jobs running the facility with an average salary &#8212; running the facility at $135,000 a year.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Those semiconductors, microchips power virtually everything in our everyday lives: cellphones, automobiles, refrigerators, the Internet, the electric grid.&nbsp; Without semiconductors, those things are not &#8212; cannot fully function.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the spin-off of this is that we’re going to create thousands of additional jobs helping build America’s products here in America, manufacturing automobiles, appliances, and so much more.&nbsp; And it’s going to help ease inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the reasons automobiles cost so much is &#8212; they’re responsible for one-fifth of the recent inflation &#8212; is because they lack semiconductors.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not able to build them quick enough so the price goes up higher because there’s fewer to sell.</p>



<p>     Intel’s announcement helps us fix that problem.  And Intel isn’t alone.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since 2021, companies have announced investments totaling more than $200 billion in domestic manufacturing here in America, from iconic companies like GM and Ford building out new electric vehicle production; to Tesla, our nation’s largest electric vehicle manufacturer; to innovative younger companies like Rivian, building electric trucks, or Proterra, building electric buses, which I saw at a virtual tour last year when I met with the CEO virtually.&nbsp; And they really impressed me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; These companies joining Intel, bringing microchip manufacturing back to America after decades of decay &#8212; from Texas Instruments to Samsung in Texas, to TSMC in Arizona.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re seeing the beginnings of an American manufacturing comeback.&nbsp; This is not hyperbole.&nbsp; This is real.&nbsp; This is genuine.&nbsp; This is real.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’ve heard me say all along when I was running and since I&#8217;ve gotten here: Amer- &#8212; the world is at an inflection point.&nbsp; Things are going to change in big ways.&nbsp; And this is one of those transition moments.</p>



<p>Two weeks ago, I went to Pittsburgh, where the Union Pacific Railroad announced the largest purchase of American-made battery ec- &#8212; battery ele- &#8212; batter &#8212; excuse me, electric-battery locomotives in history, built by American workers in Erie, Pennsylvania.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And these locomotives aren’t only going to be sold here in America and take a hell of a lot of &#8212; heck of a lot of pollution out of the air.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be sold in countries around the world that are going to be buying them, just like they’re going to buy American-made electric cars.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just like we heard last week when Boeing announced $20 billion &#8212; a $20 billion bill &#8212; $20 billion deal right here in the White House to sell American-made aircraft to one of the major airlines in the Middle East, Qatar Airways, supporting tens of thousands of good-paying American manufacturing jobs.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, we’re seeing the same thing in planes, trains, and automobiles.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Other countries recognize what’s happening here.&nbsp; They want to buy American as well.&nbsp; They’re ready to bet on America and American workers &#8212; workers who built the middle class, earning good pay and benefits and the right to organize.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today’s announcement is part of the drumbeat of jobs resurgence like anything &#8212; more than anything we’ve seen before.</p>



<p>     And, by the way, the House of Representatives passed a bill on Friday providing over $90 billion for research and development, manufacturing, and all those elements of the supply chain needed to produce end products right here in America.  We can keep delivering more announcements like this one.  And the House and Senate are working to deliver a final bill to my desk.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The bottom line is the United States is in a position to outcompete the world once again.&nbsp; And I look forward to working with governors &#8212; Republican and Democrat &#8212; to keep that drumbeat going.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, let’s keep coming together to invest in the backbone of America, in American manufacturing, and the workers who make it run, because when we do, there’s no limit to what we can achieve.&nbsp; None.</p>



<p>     Thank you.  And may God protect our troops.  We&#8217;ve got a lot to look forward to.  Thank you very much. <br></p>



<p>2:31 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Encouraging All Americans to Take Advantage of Critical Tax&#160;Credits</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/08/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-encouraging-all-americans-to-take-advantage-of-critical-tax-credits/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium 9:50 A.M. EST THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Sharron, for that very meaningful introduction.  And Sharron and I were talking earlier.  You know, there&#8217;s so much about the Child Tax Credit that is about the &#8212; the impact &#8212; the intergenerational impact.  And Sharron was sharing with me that her grandfather actually worked&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>South Court Auditorium</em></p>



<p>9:50 A.M. EST<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Sharron, for that very meaningful introduction.  And Sharron and I were talking earlier.  You know, there&#8217;s so much about the Child Tax Credit that is about the &#8212; the impact &#8212; the intergenerational impact. <br> <br>And Sharron was sharing with me that her grandfather actually worked with President Kennedy.  And we were talking about the fact that, obviously, her family has a long, strong, and deep commitment to public service and this good work.  So, thank you, Sharron, for that introduction. <br> <br>It is good to be here with two of the most energetic champions of our nation&#8217;s working families: Secretary Janet Yellen and Gene Sperling. <br> <br>And as many of you know, Secretary Yellen and I are working on a number of things. <br> <br>Gene, I heard your introduction about the conspiracy.  It&#8217;s not a conspiracy; it&#8217;s just a collaboration to do very important work to lift people up with one of the &#8212; the leaders in the world on how we do that in terms of economic empowerment. <br> <br>So, Secretary Yellen, thank you.  Gene Sperling, thank you for your years of hard work.  You really are the backbone of what we, as an administration, have been doing with the Child Tax Credit. <br> <br>So, on this day of action, there are so many individuals and organizations who are dedicated to action: the United Way, AARP, and Code for America.  And I want to thank all of you for the work you do every day and for joining us today. <br> <br>So, our message today is simple: If you are eligible for the Child Tax Credit and the Earned Income Tax Credit, we want you to get those credits.  And you know why: Working families deserve a break.<br> <br>Last month, I received a letter from a mother in Pennsylvania.  She and her husband have four children.  They both work 50-hour weeks.  They coordinate their schedules to minimize the cost of childcare, and their family is still barely holding on.  They just need a little help, and that&#8217;s what she told me in her note &#8212; a hand up, not a handout.  A hand up. <br> <br>And I receive letters like this all the time.  The truth is, there are people across our nation who work hard every day and still struggle to get by.  And it should not be this way in our country &#8212; in the United States of America.<br> <br>And the President and I firmly believe that we have to do better.  And that is why we fought to expand the Child Tax Credit and the Earned Income Tax Credit as part of the American Rescue Plan: to give families and working people a little help. <br> <br>The American Rescue Plan increased the Child Tax Credit<br>and extended it to millions more families.<br> <br>And the American Rescue Plan also nearly tripled the maximum Earned Income Tax Credit and made it available to workers between 19 and 24 years of age, as well as to workers 65 years old and above.<br> <br>These tax credits are already making a difference.  In fact, thanks to the Child Tax Credit, we are on a path to cut child poverty in America by 40 percent.  That bears repeating: We are on a path to cut child poverty by 40 percent.<br> <br>This is historic and, as I said earlier, will have a generational impact.<br> <br>Millions of families have used their monthly Child Tax Credit &#8212; CTC &#8212; check to put food on the table, to save for college, to cover daily expenses, and to pay down debt.  That is why this Day of Action is so important.<br> <br>If you are eligible for either of these credits or even if you think you might be eligible, please go to the following website: ChildTaxCredit.gov.  ChildTaxCredit.gov. <br> <br>It is a quick and easy way to check whether you qualify.  And if you qualify, all you need to do to receive benefits is to file your taxes.<br> <br>Now, one more important note: If you are one of the more than 30 million families who have already received the Child Tax Credit, you still need to file your taxes.  So that is the only way to receive the second half of what you are owed.  So, remember: You are owed more, but you still need to file your taxes.<br> <br>Everyone here knows it will take a hands-on-deck approach to get people signed up for these credits.  So, we need help.  We need state and local governments to send out texts to remind folks of what they entitled to receive.  We need faith-based organizations to spread the word at houses of worship.  We need community groups to get people the help they need to file their taxes.  And we need everyone to spread the word &#8212; be it at Sunday dinner, at the barbershop, at work, at school, and at home.<br> <br>And I believe and I know our work will be worth it, because every family we lift up, when we do that, we lift up our entire nation.<br> <br>And that&#8217;s why the President and I will keep fighting to extend these measures for years to come.<br> <br>And I’ll close today where I began: with that mother from Pennsylvania.  In her letter, she wrote that, earlier this year, her family started receiving the monthly Child Tax Credit.  And with the money, she described that they bought food, they paid their daily expenses, and they supported local businesses in the process.  She wrote, “Nothing fancy.”  Just making a difference.<br> <br>So, it’s enough to make a difference.  And that’s why we are here today: to make a difference for working families across our nation, to offer just a little help.<br> <br>So, thank you all for what you have done and will continue to do.  Let’s keep getting the word out, and be well and take care. <br> <br>Thank you. <br> <br>               END                 9:57 A.M. EST<br> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Ensuring Future is Made in&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-ensuring-future-is-made-in-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tritium Announces EV Charger Manufacturing Facility in Tennessee; To Produce Up To 30,000 Buy America-Compliant Chargers Per Year, Create 500 Jobs Since his first day in office, President Biden relentlessly focused on an industrial strategy to revitalize our manufacturing base, strengthen critical supply chains, drive down prices, and position U.S. workers and businesses to compete&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Tritium Announces EV Charger Manufacturing Facility in Tennessee; To Produce Up To 30,000 Buy America-Compliant Chargers Per Year, Create 500 Jobs</em></p>



<p>Since his first day in office, President Biden relentlessly focused on an industrial strategy to revitalize our manufacturing base, strengthen critical supply chains, drive down prices, and position U.S. workers and businesses to compete and lead globally in the 21<sup>st</sup> century. This whole-of-government effort is leading to a historic recovery in domestic manufacturing. During President Biden’s first year in office, the economy added <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/MANEMP">367,000 manufacturing jobs</a> – the most in nearly 30 years. The U.S. economy grew at the fastest pace in nearly 40 years in 2021, and manufacturing as a share of U.S. GDP has <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/VAPGDPMA#0">returned to pre-pandemic levels</a>. Manufacturing activity has seen a <a href="https://www.ismworld.org/supply-management-news-and-reports/reports/ism-report-on-business/pmi/december/">significant</a> <a href="https://www.markiteconomics.com/Public/Home/PressRelease/51d060f7a3314d1b8bb8d948e035d4c7">expansion</a> every month that President Biden has been in office, consistently above pre-pandemic levels.</p>



<p>The Build America, Buy America Act in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law expands on the Biden-Harris Administration’s work to ensure that the future is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/25/president-biden-to-sign-executive-order-strengthening-buy-american-provisions-ensuring-future-of-america-is-made-in-america-by-all-of-americas-workers/">made in America</a> by American workers by strengthening and expanding Buy America rules to all taxpayer-funded infrastructure and public works projects.</p>



<p><strong>Today, President Biden and Jane Hunter, CEO of Tritium, will announce that Tritium will break ground on its first U.S. manufacturing facility in Lebanon, Tennessee.</strong> This facility will house six production lines that will produce up to 30,000 Buy America-compliant DC Fast Chargers per year at peak production and create 500 local jobs.</p>



<p>This is the latest of announcements in recent weeks by major companies announcing investments in U.S. manufacturing and jobs, including <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-bringing-semiconductor-manufacturing-back-to-america/">Intel</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/25/statement-by-president-biden-on-general-motors-investment-in-michigan/">General Motors</a>, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/31/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-amir-sheikh-tamim-bin-hamad-al-thani-of-qatar/">Boeing</a>, and more than $200 billion in investments in domestic manufacturing of semiconductors, electric vehicles, aircraft, and batteries announced since 2021.</p>



<p>In addition to Tritium, EV charging manufacturers large and small are investing and expanding U.S. operations, driven by the Administration’s economic strategy, Made in America policies, and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Siemens</strong>, which is investing and expanding its U.S. manufacturing operations to support electric vehicle infrastructure in America, will produce 1 million EV chargers by 2025. This investment, spurred by the passage of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, is the latest in the company’s strategic plan to meet accelerating electric vehicle charging demand, and expand its U.S. manufacturing capabilities.<br><br></li><li><strong>ABB</strong>, which currently manufactures Buy America-compliant transit bus chargers in the U.S., will expand its US EV charging manufacturing operations, including Level 2 and DC Fast Chargers, over the coming five years, employing hundreds of Americans and producing thousands of EV chargers each year.<br><br></li><li><strong>FreeWire Technologies, </strong>based in Oakland, California, currently manufactures Buy America-compliant battery-integrated EV charging equipment, and recently announced groundbreaking on a research, manufacturing, and testing facility in Newark, California. FreeWire currently employs and plans to add more than 200 jobs in electrification and clean energy in and around disadvantaged communities this year.<br><br></li><li><strong>Dunamis Clean Energy Partners, </strong>a Black- and woman-owned EV charger manufacturer based in Detroit, Michigan, will manufacture Level 2 EV chargers and charging connectors in a new production facility in Detroit beginning this summer. Dunamis’ training and workforce development efforts will focus on underrepresented, economically disadvantaged communities most impacted by greenhouse gas emissions.</li></ul>



<p>The future of the auto industry is electric, and America can own that future by building more here at home, creating good-paying jobs in the process. In August, President Biden set an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-steps-to-drive-american-leadership-forward-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/">ambitious target</a> and roadmap to get to 50% of electric vehicle (EV) sale shares in the U.S. by 2030. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law included a down payment on the EV future, with more than $7 billion in funding to secure an American EV supply chain, from materials processing to battery manufacturing and recycling, along with $7.5 billion to build out the first-ever nationwide public EV charging network.</p>



<p>This charging network will provide a convenient, reliable, affordable and equitable charging experience, with a focus on serving national highway corridors, rural areas, and underserved communities. It will also accelerate the adoption of electric vehicles, fight the climate crisis, and support domestic manufacturing jobs.</p>



<p>Later this week, Department of Transportation Secretary Buttigieg and Department of Energy Secretary Granholm will announce the state allocations and guidance for the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s National Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Formula Program, which will provide $5 billion over five years to help states create a network of EV charging stations along designated Alternative Fuel Corridors on the Interstate Highway System.</p>



<p><strong>The Biden-Harris Administration has already taken action to prepare for the build-out of the nationwide public EV charging network.</strong></p>



<ul><li>In December, Vice President Harris announced the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-electric-vehicle-charging-action-plan/">EV Charging Action Plan</a> to outline the steps the Administration is taking to accelerate the EV charging investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br><br></li><li>In December, the Department of Energy and the Department of Transportation announced the creation of the <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-and-dot-launch-joint-effort-build-out-nationwide-electric-vehicle-charging-network">Joint Office of Energy and Transportation</a>, which will support and accelerate deployment of the national EV charging network, including by providing technical assistance to states as they develop their comprehensive EV charging plans. This week, the Joint Office launched <a href="https://driveelectric.gov/">DriveElectric.gov</a> to support the states in their planning.<br><br></li><li>Last week, the Department of Transportation released an <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/rural/ev/toolkit">EV Rural Charging Toolkit</a>, a one-stop resource for rural communities to plan and implement EV charging infrastructure projects.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris Leads Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Day of Action to Ensure Americans Get the Tax Credits They&#160;Deserve</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/fact-sheet-vice-president-kamala-harris-leads-biden-harris-administration-day-of-action-to-ensure-americans-get-the-tax-credits-they-deserve/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46867</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris and Secretary Yellen Headline Day of Action Event Alongside White House ARP Coordinator Gene Sperling, Mayors and Major Non-Profits to Encourage Americans to Sign Up for the Expanded Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit The American Rescue Plan Made Significant Changes to Two Critical Tax Relief Programs. Expanded the Child&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Harris and Secretary Yellen Headline Day of Action Event Alongside White House ARP Coordinator Gene Sperling, Mayors and Major Non-Profits to Encourage Americans to Sign Up for the Expanded Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit</em></p>



<p><strong>The American Rescue Plan Made Significant Changes to Two Critical Tax Relief Programs.</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expanded the Child Tax Credit</strong> from $2,000 per child to $3,600 for children under 6 and $3,000 for children between 6 and 17.</li><li><strong>Nearly Tripled the Earned Income Tax Credit for workers without dependent children</strong> – from ~$540 to up to $1,500 for 17 million workers without dependent children and made previously ineligible younger workers (19-24) who are not half-time or full-time students, and older workers (65+) newly eligible for the expanded Earned Income Tax Credit.</li></ul>



<p><strong>February 8<sup>th</sup> is a Day of Action to Ensure All Eligible Americans Sign Up for These American Rescue Plan Tax Cuts.</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Families must file a tax return in 2022 to receive the second half of the Child Tax Credit. </strong>While the families of 61 million children received advance monthly payments between July and December 2021, families need to file a tax return to receive the second half.</li><li><strong>By filing a tax return, families that did not receive the advance payments in 2021 can still get the full Child Tax Credit, as well as the up to $1,400-per-person Economic Impact Payment that they might have missed.</strong> Some taxpayers with qualifying children – like those who welcomed a new baby in 2021 or those who haven’t filed taxes in recent years and did not use the non-filer portal – can get their full Child Tax Credit by filing their tax returns. Eligible families that did not receive the up to $1,400 per person Economic Impact Payment included in the American Rescue Plan can claim those payments by filing a tax return this year.</li><li><strong>Many families who are eligible for the Child Tax Credit are also eligible for the Earned Income Tax Credit and can get thousands of dollars in additional tax relief by filing their tax return this year. </strong>In addition, the American Rescue Plan nearly tripled the EITC for workers without dependent children to $1,500 and made millions more Americans eligible.</li></ul>



<p><strong>New Government Website – ChildTaxCredit.Gov – Directs Americans to Tax-Filing Assistance.</strong><br>The Day of Action coincides with the recent re-launch of the new and improved ChildTaxCredit.gov. The revamped website has several new features to help taxpayers file their taxes and access the remainder of the expanded Child Tax Credit, the full amount of the Child Tax Credit, and/or the Earned Income Tax Credit as tax filing season begins.<br><br><strong>To help Americans navigate tax filing season, the website features a new tool that directs taxpayers to free assisted filing options that suit them based on answers to a handful of simple questions.</strong> These options include both virtual and in-person support in multiple languages. Many of the organizations who have answered the Administration’s call to action are leveraging the new ChildTaxCredit.gov for assistance.<br><br><strong>Congressional Champions Join the Day of Action.<br></strong>U.S. Senators Michael Bennet (D-Colo.), Sherrod Brown (D-Ohio), Cory Booker (D-N.J.), and Reverend Raphael Warnock (D-Ga.) and U.S. Representatives Rosa DeLauro (D-Conn.) and Suzan DelBene (D-Wash.) will headline a press call on the Day of Action encouraging all Americans to file their taxes to access the Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit.<br><br><strong>Hundreds of Non-Profits and Community-Based Organizations Are Taking Action to Reach Families Across the Country.</strong><br>Hundreds of non-profits, community-based organizations, religious organizations, veterans’ organizations, youth organizations, disability organizations, seniors’ organizations, health and medical organizations, foster care organizations, and more made commitments to take a wide range of actions, today and throughout the tax filing seasons.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Events in all 50 states and Puerto Rico throughout tax filing season to encourage families to file their taxes and connect them with tax filing assistance</strong>. Major non-profits and faith-based organizations including AARP, UnidosUS, United Way Worldwide, the Partnership for America’s Children, Coalition on Human Needs, the Arc of the United States, the National Community Action Partnership, NETWORK Catholic Lobby for Social Justice, Friends Committee on National Legislation, Salvation Army, National Association of Evangelicals, National Council of Jewish Women, the Jewish Federations of North America, Catholic Charities USA, and more have committed to host community events to ensure Americans receive the tax credits they are eligible for.</li><li><strong>Texting campaigns to direct families to tax filing assistance. </strong>Organizations including but not limited to the National Urban League, the Hispanic Federation, Think of Us, the Shah Family Foundation and FindYourFunds, the Community Child Care Council (4Cs) of Alameda County, and Common Sense Media will launch direct texting campaigns.</li><li><strong>Trainings for frontline workers and service providers</strong> <strong>to ensure they encourage clients to file their taxes and direct them to assistance. </strong>Groups including Children at Risk and the Texas Family Leadership Council, Children’s Action Alliance, Partnership for America’s Children, Lutheran Services of America, UnidosUS, American Public Human Services Association, and Hunger Free America will train hundreds of frontline workers to help families navigate tax filing.</li><li><strong>Hosting Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) sites to connect people with in-person tax preparation assistance</strong>, including those run by StreetCred at Boston Medical Center, Lincoln VITA, Educational Alliance, United Way, and AARP.</li><li><strong>Developing and providing free tax preparation online services </strong>including United Way’s My Free Taxes, AARP’s Tax Counseling for the Elderly, and Code for America’s Get Your Refund.</li><li><strong>Sharing information on the Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit through social media channels, with a reach totaling 16.7 million people</strong> including campaigns led by MomsRising, Prosperity Now, National Council of Jewish Women, and dozens of other organizations.</li></ul>



<p><strong>State and Local Governments Commit to Action Throughout Tax Filing Season.</strong><br>During tax filing season, state and local leaders will take action on CTC/EITC enrollment, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>California</strong> will continue ongoing awareness activities through a variety of NGO and local government channels, including outreach and education to support prioritizing uptake of financial supports through a public-private partnership investing $30 million in community-based organizations to reach people where they live, work and play.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Illinois </strong>through its “Ladder Up” program, will continue supporting tax prep for residents with incomes below 200% of the poverty level and rely on a network of professional tax prep staff and volunteers.</li><li><strong>New York </strong>will continue encouraging New Yorkers to take advantage of Free File software, which can help millions of taxpayers claim valuable tax credits without the cost of hiring a paid tax preparer.</li><li><strong>Oregon </strong>Department of Human Services will work with several other state agencies and community organizations to spread the word to “file your taxes.” Agencies and partners can “take turns” reinforcing the main message to encourage Oregonians to find a tax filing assister near them.</li><li><strong>National Community Action Partnership </strong>the 200 Community Action Agencies that are units of local governments will do CTC/EITC outreach, with a number of them directly operating VITA sites.</li><li><strong>Chicago, IL </strong>will launch a series of webinars and trainings in partnership with elected officials as well as conduct a Tax-a-Thon event at Olive-Harvey College through VITA partners and Ladder Up Chicago.</li><li><strong>Kansas City, MO </strong>will continue leveraging its Emergency Rental Assistance hub to assist residents with applying for and obtaining the CTC/EITC, and promoting information on platforms and channels including the City’s quarterly news magazine.</li><li><strong>Newark, NJ </strong>will launch a virtual kick-off event with Mayor Baraka and New Jersey Citizen Action to promote their free tax preparation services.</li><li><strong>Detroit, MI</strong> will kick off “Ten Days of Action” including a United Way for Southeast Michigan Town Hall, and email and text message campaigns to city subscribers, public school community district subscribers, and state social services recipients.</li><li><strong>Hartford, CT </strong>will launch an SMS campaign sending direct text messages to residents, as well as radio, and media&nbsp;campaigns. Hartford has also trained local librarians to serve as navigators for individuals who need tax filing assistance.</li><li><strong>Houston, TX </strong>will amplify CTC/EITC on official channels and to their Employee News communication platform which services 22,000+ city employees.</li><li><strong>Lansing, MI: </strong>will continue partnering with Capital Area United Way to promote CTC/EITC to targeted households and conduct outreach at events such as their utility assistance events.</li><li><strong>Los Angeles County</strong><strong>, CA </strong>will continue a text-message campaign in partnership with the United Ways of California, and ensuring county residents are connected to VITA resources.</li><li><strong>Louisville, KY</strong> will continue their Tax Time Connect initiative with VITA and Bank On Louisville to promote banking access and CTC/EITC, expand VITA capacity, and partner with the Louisville Urban League in-person support.</li><li><strong>Miami Dade County</strong><strong>, CA </strong>will partner across county departments to promote local free income tax preparation services through VITA as well as conduct outreach at existing resource fairs, canvassing, radio, info cards.</li><li><strong>N</strong><strong>ew York, NY </strong>will lead press and outreach events in targeted neighborhoods with local elected officials at VITA sites, canvas at local food pantries, issue postcard mailers to 250,000 EITC eligible households, launch outdoor advertising on bus shelters and send an email to the more than 420,000 City of New York employees about CTC and EITC.</li><li><strong>Philadelphia, PA</strong> will launch “Claim Your Money PHL,” and run targeted print and digital ads, bus ads, and deploy street team outreach in addition to providing resources to our local non-profit tax preparation partners.</li><li><strong>San Antonio, TX </strong>will place VITA program information in the City’s “on-hold phone message,” host community events, and continue cross-enrollment promotion through COVID-19 emergency programs. As Chair of the Texas Big City Mayors coalition, Mayor Nirenberg will encourage statewide enrollment throughout Texas’ largest municipalities, representing over 8 million Texans.</li><li><strong>South Bend, IN </strong>will train staff at local assistance programs, canvas targeted neighborhoods, and partner with local public health workers, librarians, and other nonprofit organizations to organize sign-up events.</li><li><strong>St. Paul, MN</strong> will deploy their Office of Financial Empowerment and other departments and community partners to provide free tax prep and VITA support, and continue to amplifying their multi-language website and messaging on digital and social platforms.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Continued Biden-Harris Administration Whole-of-Government Effort On CTC/EITC Enrollment.</strong><br>Agencies across the federal government have heeded the call to reach as many families as possible.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The Treasury Department </strong>will push out information on CTC and EITC on social media during the Day of Action and in the weeks that follow and will co-lead trainings with the White House reaching external and intergovernmental CTC/EITC navigators. In addition, IRS, through its Volunteers Income Tax Assistance (VITA) and Tax Counseling for the Elderly (TCE) sites, assist taxpayers in free tax return preparation and electronically filing tax returns, including those claiming the CTC and EITC credits. Last year, in local communities, over 8,800 volunteer sites filed nearly two million tax returns at no cost. For information on a local site, visit <a href="https://www.irs.gov/individuals/free-tax-return-preparation-for-qualifying-taxpayers">https://www.irs.gov/individuals/free-tax-return-preparation-for-qualifying-taxpayers</a>.</li><li><strong>Social Security Administration </strong>will build off of their 2021 successful five-week national marketing campaign, which included web banners, digital search ads, radio ads, and billboards, to reach low-income individuals, including people who receive SSI and Social Security benefits. SSA also released guidance to 27,000 employees in over 1,200 field offices nationwide on how to educate families applying for or receiving SSI about the CTC and the advanced CTC payments and reiterated that CTC should not affect SSI benefits. SSA will build upon their successful 2021 efforts by updating instructional material to frontline technicians that explains the impact of the CTC and EITC with persons filing for SSI and SSI recipients who have a child or children. In addition, will release a blog post on the importance of the CTC and EITC.</li><li><strong>The Department of Housing and Urban Development </strong>will mobilize on-the-ground staff and stakeholders to help HUD-assisted households file taxes. Through targeted communications and promotion at conferences, HUD will provide information on the CTC and EITC, and connect VITA centers to public housing authorities, multifamily housing property managers, resident services providers, housing counselors, Continuums of Care, HIV/AIDS service organizations, victim service providers and tribal organizations. These efforts will reach staff at the more than 3,000 Public Housing Authorities (PHAs), the nearly 2,000 PHA-based service providers, 2,000 tribal housing partners, nearly 400 Continuums of Care, and the roughly 16,000 housing counselors, as well as nearly 14,000 Multifamily property managers and resident service providers. HUD will also partner with VITA centers across the country and continue our ongoing collaboration with AmeriCorps to mobilize more than 200 HUD-VISTA Volunteers to assist HUD families’ tax filing. Building on the ten stakeholder CTC trainings HUD held in the fall, HUD will coordinate with Treasury to hold targeted navigator trainings for HUD stakeholders on the CTC and EITC.</li><li><strong>The Administration for Children and Families at the Department of Health and Human Services </strong>will partner with local VITA sites with tax specialists, focusing on immigrant communities, young teen parents, parents in recovery and parents with mental health. They will also share videos of parents and grandparents who are trusted messengers who share their stories on how signing up for the tax credits made a significant impact on their lives.</li><li><strong>AmeriCorps </strong>will host a roundtable during the week of 2/14 with an AmeriCorps Seniors VITA center grantee in Baltimore. AmeriCorps is also a member of the Colorado Economic Mobility Partnership, a joint effort between Colorado Governor Jared Polis’ administration, the Colorado State Service Commission, Serve Colorado, Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment and AmeriCorps. The partnership kicked off on January 14, 2022, which was declared by Governor Polis as &lt;a href=&quot;#:~:text=Governor%20Primavera%20have%20announced%20January,%E2%80%9CAmeriCorps%20Economic%20Mobility%20Day.%E2%80%9D“AmeriCorps Economic Mobility Day</a>” and marked the initial deployment of two AmeriCorps NCCC teams focused on VITA service activities. AmeriCorps NCCC is a fulltime service program that supports young adults to serve on a team and make a positive impact in communities across the country while gaining valuable leadership skills. AmeriCorps NCCC has six additional projects identified to deploy its volunteers on tax preparation efforts, including the additional CTC follow-up work. All of the projects will include VITA tax prep for low-income individuals and will include a focus on CTC and Earned Income Tax Credit, as well as other rebates available for low-income individuals.</li><li><strong>The United States Department of Agriculture Food and Nutrition Services </strong>will inform and engage FNS stakeholders through email, traditional mailed and digital lifting up and reinforcing CTC outreach opportunities and supporting materials available by Treasury.&nbsp; FNS expects to reach more than 100,000 program operators, community organizations, and interested individuals directly through our collective platforms, with an even broader reach as FNS encourages the resharing of information.</li><li><strong>The Department of Education </strong>will share information on the Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit to grantees and organizations that primarily serve disadvantaged students. The Department will ask that these grantees and organizations share information with their communities.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Philanthropic Support of Tax Benefits Access.</strong><br>Dozens of philanthropic investors have made significant investments to help families access tax relief in 2022, coordinated by the CTC and EITC funders networks. <strong>The Annie E. Casey Foundation, the AARP Foundation, Doris Duke Charitable Foundation, The Gates Foundation, The David and Lucile Packard Foundation, The Rockefeller Foundation, Charles and Lynn Schusterman Family Philanthropies, and others have contributed </strong>more than $25 million in new investments into communities to support CTC and EITC. Investments area include:<br><br><strong><em>Testing New Models for Effective Outreach.</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>EITC Funders Network</strong>, in partnership with Community Foundation Opportunity Network <strong>(</strong>CFON) and CFLeads, is managing the <strong>Community Outreach and Opportunity Fund (CO-OP Fund)</strong>. The fund partners with 24 community foundations across the country to work with their local partners testing a range of innovative outreach and engagement strategies. The purpose of the CO-OP Fund is to engage community foundations and their strongly connected local community partners to ensure that as many families as possible receive the full Child Tax Credit (CTC) and Earned Income tax Credit (EITC) benefits they have earned, as quickly and easily as possible.</li><li>Funding the <strong>American Public Human Services Association </strong>to work with state human services agencies to connect with potential eligible families and assist families in filing taxes and getting their tax refunds.</li><li>Providing resources for organizations to help gather and widely disseminate outreach materials in multiple languages, conduct non-filer focus groups, and create customized messages to new filers for the EITC and CTC.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Commitments to Focus on Newly Eligible EITC Populations (Older and younger Workers).&nbsp;</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>The <strong>AARP Foundation</strong> is redoubling its outreach effort, developing a specialized toolkit, flyers, and postcards to let newly eligible older workers know about the EITC. They are investing deeply in three communities to build capacity and test effective models of outreach and engagement.</li><li>The <strong>Annie E. Casey and Rockefeller Foundations</strong> are initiating an aggressive social media campaign to reach young adults also newly eligible for the EITC.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Specific Funding for Puerto Rico’s CTC and EITC Eligible Populations.</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Funders are investing resources in leading organizations, such as <strong>Espacios Abiertos </strong>and <strong>Instituto del Desarrollo de la Joventud, </strong>in Puerto Rico to ensure that newly eligible populations are filing for the CTC and EITC.</li><li>This effort includes investments from the Rockefeller Foundation, the EITC Funder Network Pooled Fund and Hispanic Federation, who are providing support to Puerto Rican organizations to undertake and expand outreach and enrollment for the tax credits over the next two years.</li></ul>



<p><strong>About the Child Tax Credit: Tax Cuts for Families with Children.</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Largest-ever Child Tax Credit: </strong>The American Rescue Plan dramatically expanded the Child Tax Credit – providing by far the largest credit ever. For families with children under 17, the American Rescue Plan increased the Child Tax Credit from $2,000 per child to $3,000 per child for children over the age of six and from $2,000 to $3,600 for children under the age of six. It also raised the age limit from 16 to 17, providing families of older children up to an additional $3,000 in Child Tax Credit.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>First-ever monthly tax payments to the families of 61 million children: </strong>In July, just four months after President Biden signed the American Rescue Plan, Treasury began distributing advance monthly Child Tax Credit payments to the overwhelming majority of families with children. Advance payments went out each month from July to December 2021 – providing most families with the first half of their Child Tax Credit.</li><li><strong>Payments were delivered on the same day – the 15<sup>th</sup> – of each month from July to December</strong>: Close to 90% of families enrolled in advance payments received their Child Tax Credit payments with direct deposit – on the 15th of every month (or earlier if the 15<sup>th</sup> fell on a weekend or a holiday), listed under “CHILDCTC”.</li><li><strong>Helping middle class families cover the costs of raising their children and dramatically reducing child poverty:</strong> The Child Tax Credit is helping middle income families cover the costs of raising their children, from paying for <a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2021/10/nearly-a-third-of-parents-spent-child-tax-credit-on-school-expenses.html">childcare</a> to making their mortgage and car payments, to <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/up-front/2021/09/24/the-new-child-tax-credit-does-more-than-just-cut-poverty/">helping</a> build a college fund. The Child Tax Credit is also a critical tool to cut child poverty. Treasury estimates that the families of over 26 million lower-income children will receive the full credit for 2021 who would have previously gotten a partial credit or no credit because they had too little in income. Monthly Child Tax Credit payments had an immediate impact – <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w29285/w29285.pdf">reducing</a> food insufficiency among lower-income families by 25 percent. Experts estimate that expanded Child Tax Credit and other critical policies in the American Rescue Plan will have brought child poverty to its lowest levels on record.</li><li><strong>729,000 children in non-filing families received advance payments automatically: </strong>The Biden-Harris administration automatically enrolled the families of 729,000 children – whose parents or guardians had signed up for a previous Economic Impact Payment.</li><li><strong>First-ever simplified filing tools Child Tax Credit</strong>: The Biden-Harris Administration launched the first-ever non-filer tools for the Child Tax Credit in 2021, including a portal that was mobile friendly and available in Spanish.</li></ul>



<p><strong>About the Earned Income Tax Credit: Over 17 Million Americans to Benefit from Expansion of EITC for Workers Without Dependent Children.</strong><br>The American Rescue Plan expanded the Earned Income Tax Credit to include more people, more families, and more money by nearly tripling the credit for workers without dependent children and including younger (19-24) and older workers (65+) who were previously excluded.<br></p>



<ul><li><strong>Nearly tripled EITC to $1500 for workers without dependent children – benefitting 17 million Americans: </strong>The American Rescue Plan nearly tripled the Earned Income Tax Credit for workers without dependent children from about $540 to $1,500. The Center on Budget and Policy Priorities <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/american-rescue-plan-act-includes-critical-expansions-of-child-tax-credit-and">estimates</a> that this expansion has the potential to benefit <em><u>over 17 million Americans</u>.</em></li><li><strong>First increase to EITC for workers without dependent children since 1993: </strong>While the Earned Income Tax Credit provides thousands of dollars of critical relief to families with children, workers without dependent children, including younger workers, and workers with adult children, have not seen a meaningful increase in their Earned Income Tax Credit since 1993.</li><li><strong>Younger and older workers <em><u>Are</u> </em>eligible: </strong>Before the American Rescue Plan, people under 25 or 65 and over were ineligible for the Earned Income Tax Credit for workers without dependent children. The American Rescue Plan changed that. Younger workers (19-24) who are not half-time or full-time students, and older workers (65+) are newly eligible for the Earned Income Tax Credit for workers without dependent children. In addition – the American Rescue Plan increased the cap at which someone’s income made them ineligible for a benefit – from about $16,000 to over $21,000 for a single filer and from about $21,000 to more than $27,000 for a married couple.</li></ul>



<p><strong>APPENDIX: FULL LIST OF COMMITMENTS FROM NON-PROFITS AND COMMUNITY-BASED ORGANIZATIONS</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>AARP </strong>will host VITA sites, offer free tax assistance through their Tax Counseling for the Elderly program, and will host events to raise awareness about CTC and EITC in all 50 states.</li><li><strong>Afterschool Alliance</strong> will host a webinar that will be recorded and can be re-watched at any time.</li><li><strong>Agudath Israel of America </strong>will enlist accountants and other experts to educate and assist individuals and families in the community to obtain the CTC/EITC and will assist populations within their community that require language assistance (e.g. in Yiddish, Hebrew or Russian) to learn about the CTC/EITC.</li><li><strong>Alliance to End Hunger </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>American Children’s Campaign</strong> will distribute social media materials to their large network of organizational partners to share with their followers and lists.</li><li><strong>Americans for Tax Fairness </strong>will distribute flyers on the CTC and EITC and will promote the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>American Muslim Health Professionals </strong>will share information about CTC, its impact on child health, and ChildTaxCredit.gov on social media, email lists and newsletters.</li><li><strong>American Public Health Services Association </strong>will provide technical assistance and resources to state and local governments to support outreach efforts and increase awareness of benefits for family economic mobility through the Earned Income Tax Credit and the Child Tax Credit. APSHA will support development of targeted resources for state and local human service agencies to use in customer communications by text and web, as well as in-person resources. These efforts will include effective parent-led campaigns to raise awareness to these important benefit for all families.</li><li><strong>Association of American Medical Colleges </strong>will ask affiliates to share information with the communities they serve.</li><li><strong>Blue Future </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>Boston Medical Center </strong>will share information about the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America </strong>will share information about free tax prep resources on Childtaxcredit.gov with their Boys &amp; Girls Clubs affiliates that serve 4.3 million youth at over 4,700 Club sites in a typical year.</li><li><strong>Building Back Together </strong>will share information about the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Care Income Now </strong>will host a press conference with community partners. They will distribute flyers on the CTC and EITC and will promote the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Catholic Charities USA </strong>and their local affiliates will continue to host trainings and share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>Center on Budget and Policy Priorities </strong>will host a learning series on EITC/CTC outreach called Tax Time Thursdays every other week throughout the tax season. Presentation topics will include peer-to-peer outreach, reaching foster and homeless youth, reaching older adults, and reaching immigrants.</li><li><strong>Center for the Study of Social Policy </strong>will create and circulate flyers specific to their networks.</li><li><strong>Change Machine</strong> will reach out to 5,000 people, primarily nonprofit practitioners offering direct services to build financial security.</li><li><strong>CHILDREN AT RISK, the Texas Family Leadership Council, the Coalition on Human Needs, and the Partnership for America’s Children </strong>will co-host a training for Texas service providers on February 16.</li><li><strong>Children Now </strong>will distribute flyers on the CTC and EITC and will promote the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Children’s Action Alliance, Partnership for America’s Children, and the Coalition on Human Needs </strong>will co-host a training for Arizona service providers and other organizations in early March.</li><li><strong>Children’s Advocacy Alliance </strong>will distribute flyers on the CTC and EITC and will promote the CTC and EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Children’s Defense Fund </strong>published FAQs about tax filing on their website and will discuss the CTC and EITC on media. They will send information and flyers on CTC/EITC to their email networks.</li><li><strong>Children’s HealthWatch </strong>will host a virtual event on how to assist families with accessing the CTC/EITC.</li><li><strong>Children’s Home &amp; Aid Society of Illinois </strong>will provide information and training to frontline staff to help families access the CTC/EITC. They will also post information on social media.</li><li><strong>Citizens’ Committee for New York, Inc. </strong>will host a training for frontline staff and will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>CityGate Network </strong>will distribute a 12-page publication to their 300 affiliates with information on the tax credits and how to access them.</li><li><strong>Coalition on Human Needs </strong>will host webinars for community health networks across the country. They will also partner with <strong>Lutheran Services in America</strong> and the <strong>Partnership for America’s</strong> <strong>Children</strong> on a training on February 17<sup>th</sup>. Coalition on Human Needs will also partner with <strong>UnidosUS</strong> and the <strong>Partnership for America’s Children</strong> on trainings for families in Spanish.</li><li><strong>Code for America’s </strong>GetYourRefund tool will continue to help tens of thousands of Americans with free, simple tax filing assistance.</li><li><strong>Common Sense Media</strong> will launch a direct texting campaign to eligible families and will host a press conference with community partners.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Community Catalyst </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Community Child Care Council (4Cs) of Alameda County </strong>will launch a direct texting campaign to eligible families.</li><li><strong>Community Economic Development of Michigan </strong>and its member organizations will host more than a dozen “Show Me The Money Days” &#8212; local financial empowerment and community resource fairs for lower-income families that will highlight free tax prep and state and federal tax credits including the CTC and EITC.</li><li><strong>Community Legal Aid Society, Inc. (Delaware) </strong>will post a training for community members on social media.</li><li><strong>Community Legal Services of Philadelphia </strong>will be hosting a Claim Your Cash Party in Philadelphia to help young people ages 18-25 learn about the tax credits and refunds they can get, including the Earned Income Tax Credit and the Child Tax Credit, if they are parents. Many low-income youth must support themselves and their families, but aren’t required to file taxes, and might not be getting all of the income support they are entitled to. CLS’s party will help youth engage in the process so they can claim their refunds and credits, which will help them support themselves and their families.</li><li><strong>Connecticut Association for Human Services </strong>will host pop up events, including a “Super Refund Saturday” on February 26 to help people with tax filing. They will also distribute information through social media, text campaigns, and other communications.</li><li><strong>Economic Security Project</strong>&nbsp;is spreading the word about the Day of Action to their network of 100+ advocacy and nonprofit groups with reach on the ground who can amplify the message and distribute it directly to impacted people and is working with Members of Congress to lift up.</li><li><strong>Educare Learning Network</strong> will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Education Alliance </strong>will host a VITA site and distribute their own translated materials.</li><li><strong>Espacios Abiertos Puerto Rico </strong>will launch an EITC/CTC data visualization map that shows the economic impact in dollars, number of families and children that will benefit from the credits and how it all relates to poverty levels island-wide and for each one of the 78 municipalities in Puerto Rico. This platform will serve as the compass for a strategic multi-sector collaborative effort across the island for a tax filing campaign and free tax preparation services.</li><li><strong>Evangelical Lutheran Church in America </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Family Equality </strong>will share information about childtaxcredit.gov on their LGBTQ+ family Facebook page and other on-line groups and will circulate a one-pager.</li><li><strong>Family Healthcare of St. George, Utah </strong>will share information on social media, and on their website news page.</li><li><strong>Feeding America </strong>will share materials on CTC/EITC and tax prep assistance with their 199 local affiliates and will host nation-wide webinars. They will also encourage further sharing of resources with over 60,000 faith-based and charitable food distribution partners. Feeding America will also invite network members engaging in SNAP application assistance to help with outreach. Additional actions include: adding new content on tax prep service to their website, sending text messages to their listserv, posting content on social media, post links to free tax prep services on the “thank you” pages displayed to neighbors upon electronic submission of an online referral form for SNAP application assistance.</li><li><strong>First Choice Primary Care </strong>will share CTC/EITC information with their staff and their community on their social media platform as well as at outreach events.</li><li><strong>First Focus on Children </strong>will host a virtual event in April.</li><li><strong>Food Research &amp; Action Center</strong> will host a training for frontline staff.</li><li><strong>Georgia Budget and Policy Institute </strong>will issue a press release and share a toolkit on CTC and EITC with partners.</li><li><strong>Get My Payment Illinois </strong>is working with a number of organizations on outreach and press, including a press release.</li><li><strong>Goodwill Industries International, Inc. </strong>will Goodwill share resources with our network of local Goodwill organizations and share information via social media channels.</li><li><strong>Hispanic Federation </strong>is committing $600,000 to support affiliate community-based organizations in Puerto Rico for tax prep assistance by way of Mobile Assistance Centers [“Tax Prep Mobile Labs”] deployed to low-income communities, mainly rural. In coordination with the Youth Development Institute (IDJ), they will also be supporting an outreach and strategic communications campaign to reach these families with resources to help them file federal tax returns in order to claim their Child Tax Credit.</li><li><strong>Hunger Free America </strong>will print and distribute a bilingual one pager on CTC/EITC in combination with our ongoing food benefits and vaccine outreach work in low-income neighborhoods in NYC, share information about CTC/EITC on social media and their website, and prepare their frontline staff – including those who answer calls for the USDA Hunger Hotline – with basic facts to share on CTC/EITC.</li><li><strong>Institute on Taxation and Economic Policy </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Jewish Federations of North America </strong>will share toolkits and information via weekly emails to 146 Jewish Federations during filing season and participate in a joint webinar with many other faith organizations for early March with human service providers, faith leaders, educators, and other groups that work with or encounter families.</li><li><strong>Lincoln VITA </strong>will host VITA free tax clinics at 11 sites in Lincoln, NE and will facilitate a virtual free tax preparation site.</li><li><strong>MAZON </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Minority Veterans of America </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>Missouri Budget Project </strong>will share information on social media and will share the information with direct service organizations and tax assistance partners in Missouri.</li><li><strong>MomsRising </strong>will launch a bilingual social media campaign.</li><li><strong>Montessori Public Policy Initiative </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Mother’s Outreach Network/DC Guaranteed Income Coalition </strong>will print and distribute information on CTC/EITC and how to get help with free filing, share information about CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists and newsletters, and on their websites, and incorporate CTC/EITC information into existing communications streams, including text outreach to low-income populations.</li><li><strong>National Association of Hispanic Nurses </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media and with their email lists.</li><li><strong>National Association of Social Workers </strong>will co-host a webinar with the Coalition on Human Needs and will share information about CTC/EITC on social media.</li><li><strong>National Black Justice Coalition </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists and newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>National Center for Lesbian Rights </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC with LGBTQ parents via social media.</li><li><strong>National Community Action Partnership </strong>will host 5-10 virtual events that walk people through how to get their CTC/EITC by utilizing ChildTaxCredit.gov. They will also distirbute CTC/EITC flyers to frontline staff who can distribute them to families enrolled in Head Start and other programs such as LIHEAP, weatherization, case management, and emergency food assistance. National Community Action Partnership will also produce bilingual graphics and social media content for easy use and dissemination and will host office hour sessions with tax specialists to respond to specific tax credit inquiries from frontline staff helping families across their network. The 200 Community Action Agencies that are units of local go</li><li><strong>National Military Family Association </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists and newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>National Urban League </strong>will print and distribute information on CTC/EITC and how to get help with free filing, share information about CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists and newsletters, and on their websites, and incorporate CTC/EITC information into existing communications streams, including text outreach to low-income populations.</li><li><strong>National Women’s Law Center </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Network Lobby for Catholic Social Justice </strong>will host a webinar with faith communities in early March and will integrate CTC/EITC into planned communications throughout tax season.</li><li><strong>NN4Y </strong>will share info on social media and will provide very practical resources to their youth homelessness service providers about EITC for homeless and foster youth.</li><li><strong>ParentsTogether Action</strong> will host online events for members to walk them through the tax filing process and share information.</li><li><strong>PFLAG </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>Philabundance </strong>will hold a training to reach partner agencies and members of their network.</li><li>Propel, a mission-driven financial technology company, will provide information via the Providers app to connect more than 5 million low-income families to information and partners to help them file taxes to receive the EITC and CTC.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Prosperity Now </strong>will include PSAs about CTC/EITC at all external and learning events and will send emails to their list of over 20,000 people.</li><li><strong>Religious Action Center of Reform Judaism </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>Religious Organizations including Friends Committee on National Legislation, Salvation Army, National Association of Evangelicals, Bread for the World, National Council of Jewish Women </strong>will host a joint webinar.</li><li><strong>RESULTS </strong>will embed messages about CTC/EITC and ChildTaxCredit.gov in letters to the editor generated by RESULTS volunteers in local newspapers.</li><li><strong>Robinson Elementary Community Hub </strong>will share information about CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists and newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>Save the Children </strong>and their local affiliates will share materials in English and Spanish with individuals and families they serve and also amplify CTC/EITC information through their social media channels.</li><li><strong>SaverLife </strong>will share their one-stop guide which highlights CTC/EITC with their networks.</li><li><strong>Shah Family Foundation/FindYourFunds </strong>will work with the Massachusetts Department of Transitional Assistance to send texts messages to 1 in 7 Massachusetts families and will host a statewide webinar with over 200 providers on February 16. They will also host Facebook Live Events with key groups representing immigrant leaders in Portuguese and Spanish.</li><li><strong>Skagit Legal Aid </strong>will leverage recently received funding from the Washington Department of Commerce and the Skagit County Commissioners to conduct outreach to historically disadvantaged communities in Skagit County while also resolving unmet civil legal needs that have prevented them from not regularly filing tax returns. The project will aim to serve the following communities: Single Parents with Young Children; Individuals Living with a Disability; Low-Income Seniors; Rural Black, Indigenous, and People of Color (BIPOC), emphasizing those who identify as Hispanic, Latinx, or Indigenous; Immigrants, emphasizing Mixteco and Triqui speaking farmworkers; and Tribal Members, emphasizing the Swinomish Indian Tribal Community, Upper Skagit Tribe, Samish Indian Nation, and the Sauk-Suiattle Indian Tribe.</li><li><strong>Southern Economic Advancement Project </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Start Early </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>StreetCred at Boston Medical Center</strong> will run a VITA site at Boston Medical Center and distribute their own VITA tax site information in English, Spanish, Haitian Creole, and Portuguese.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Student PIRGs </strong>will distribute a flyer to staff and administrators on campuses that work with graduate students &amp; non-traditional students and will send it out to their student e-mail lists.</li><li><strong>Student Veterans of America </strong>share information about the CTC/EITC on social media and through their newsletter.</li><li><strong>The Arc of the United States </strong>will host events on CTC/EITC which will reach hundreds of people with disabilities, their families, and the direct care workforce.</li><li><strong>Think Babies NC Alliance </strong>will share information on social media.</li><li><strong>Think of Us </strong>will directly contacting 22,000 young people to make sure they are aware that they may be eligible for the ETIC. In addition, they will provide marketing support to 44 states foster care systems.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>TransLatin@ </strong>will share information about the CTC/EITC on social media, with their email lists, through newsletters, and on their website.</li><li><strong>UnidosUS </strong>will deploy a tax credits campaign to promote the CTC/EITC which will include: distributing resources to nearly 300 affiliates, hosting townhalls and navigator trainings, supporting efforts to promote CTC/EITC in Puerto Rico, sharing content on social media accounts.</li><li><strong>United State of Women </strong>will work with local partner organizations on the ground in communities to refer and send information on the free tax prep services to their memberships.</li><li><strong>United Way of Puerto Rico </strong>has implemented five Facilitated Self-Service Centers (FSA-Facilitated Self Assistance), in the municipalities of San Juan, Ponce, Mayagüez, Arecibo, Canóvanas and remote centers and is operating a 2-1-1 call center offering information and referral on CTC, VITA Centers, Facilitated Self-Service Centers. They will help schedule appointments to fill out the digital 1040-PR form at the UWPR FSA Centers, register volunteers, and collaborate with organizations in Puerto Rico to expand these services.</li><li><strong>United Way Worldwide </strong>will host more than 300 VITA sites through their local affiliates. United Way Worldwide will also offer tax preparation support through MyFreeTaxes. In addition, they will host a webinar for local partners around the country to update them on what’s new this year with CTC/EITC and tools/resources available to them to help individuals file their taxes (e.g., VITA, MyFreeTaxes, ChildTaxCredit.gov, tool kits etc.). The webinar will be presented in partnership with <strong>Prosperity Now</strong> and <strong>The Jewish Federation</strong> during the first two weeks of March.</li><li><strong>Virginia Campaign for a Family Friendly Economy </strong>will share information on social media and on their website.</li><li><strong>Vote Common Good </strong>will dedicate a podcast to CTC/EITC awareness and outreach.</li><li><strong>We Got Us </strong>will provide information about CTC/EITC during community outreach events in the coming months.</li><li><strong>Women of Color in the Global Women’s Strike</strong> will continue to organize and participate in community-based events in low income communities with information on how people can get their CTC/EITC.</li><li><strong>Youth Development Institute/Instituto del Desarrollo de la Juventud (IDJ) </strong>will encourage national and local partners to become VITA volunteers and/or allocate funds for CTC tax assistance efforts, post on their social media accounts stories addressing frequently asked questions about CTC in Puerto Rico and informing about free tax prep services, and activate local CTC champions (journalist and influencer for mothers with children, “Milly Méndez”) to re-share social media posts.</li><li><strong>YMCA </strong>will encourage local YMCAs to post information about free tax prep services in highly visible, highly trafficked physical spaces and will post to social media.</li><li><strong>YWCA USA </strong>will distribute materials to their associations throughout the country.</li><li><strong>ZERO TO THREE </strong>will share information on social media.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Chancellor Scholz of the Federal Republic of Germany at Press&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/07/remarks-by-president-biden-and-chancellor-scholz-of-the-federal-republic-of-germany-at-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 3:40 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Please, sit down.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; I’d like to start by thanking Chancellor Scholz for making this visit to Washington.&#160; We had an opportunity to have a very productive meeting.&#160; I think our staffs wondered whether we were going to let them in at all.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>3:40 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Please, sit down.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’d like to start by thanking Chancellor Scholz for making this visit to Washington.&nbsp; We had an opportunity to have a very productive meeting.&nbsp; I think our staffs wondered whether we were going to let them in at all.&nbsp; We spent the first half hour or more talking together, and &#8212; and it’s been a very, very useful meeting.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One of the things that struck me was the shared values, and &#8212; that shape how each of us approaches leadership, among them the foundational commitment to the dignity of workers and the need to treat all people with respect.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I enjoyed speaking with you, Olaf.&nbsp; And I know, working together, we’ll continue to strengthen and deepen our alliance and the extensive partnership between Germany and the United States.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Of course, at the top of our agenda today was our united approach to deterring Russia&#8217;s threats against Ukraine and the longstanding principles of rule-based international order.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we spent most of our time talking about.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Germany and the United States, together with our Allies and partners, are working closely together to pursue diplomatic resolutions of this situation.&nbsp; And diplomacy is the very best way forward for all sides, we both agree, including best for Russia, in our view.&nbsp; And we have made it very clear we&#8217;re ready to continue talks in good faith with Russia.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Germany has also been a leader in pushing de-escalation of tensions and encouraging dialogue through the Normandy Format.&nbsp; But if Russia makes the choice to further invade Ukraine, we are jointly ready and all of NATO is ready.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, the Chancellor and I discussed our close cooperation and developed a strong package of sanctions that are going to clearly demonstrate international resolve and impose swift and severe consequences if Russia violates Ukraine&#8217;s sovereignty and its territorial integrity.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to thank Germany and our &#8212; and all of our other partners in Eastern Europe &#8212; in the European Union for their work in this united effort.&nbsp; We are in agreement that it cannot be business as usual if Russia further invades.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also discussed our shared commitment to NATO&#8217;s Article 5 responsibilities and reassurance of our eastern flank allies.&nbsp; We’re united in that as well.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Already, the United States is sending troops to reinforce the Alliance, and I want to thank the Chancellor of Germany for hosting additional U.S. forces and for the longstanding hospitality to our women and men in uniform.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also discussed the challenges we&#8217;re facing to the international order from China, along with Russia and other competitors that are pursuing more illiberal futures.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve agreed that Germany and the United States will continue to work together to ensure that the rules and principles governing emerging technologies are geared to advance freedom of opportunity, not repression or authoritarianism.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also reaffirmed our commitment to completing the work of integrating the Western Balkans into the European institutions and to finally realize a Europe that is whole, free, and at peace.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With Germany holding the presidency of the G7, we also talked about how that form can harness the world&#8217;s leading democracies to advance a robust agenda of global &#8212; on global challenges, from ending the pandemic to addressing climate change.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the bottom line is this: Whether as Allies in NATO, partners through the European Union, as leaders of the G7 and G20, or through our strong bilateral relationship, Germany and the United States are close friends and reliable partners, and we can count on one another.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There is no issue of global importance where Germany and the United States are not working together strength-to-strength and applying and amplifying our efforts together.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I want to thank you, Olaf, for making the journey today.&nbsp; And I look forward to being the first of many opportunities we can spend together, beginning this meeting and throughout the rest of the year and the rest of our terms.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, thank you and welcome.&nbsp; The floor is yours, sir.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Good afternoon from my side as well.&nbsp; I&#8217;m very grateful that we had the opportunity to talk in much detail today, and that I was able to make my first official visit here and that we also could talk about the important questions that we&#8217;re dealing with today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are in a very difficult situation, and it is a good thing that Joe and I were able to discuss what we need to do in this difficult context.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Of course, there is a military threat in Ukraine &#8212; against Ukraine, and we cannot remain silent on that.&nbsp; We see the number of Russian troops along the Ukrainian border, and that is a serious threat to European security.&nbsp; And this is why it is important that we act together, that we stand together, and that we do what is necessary together.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is important that all allies &#8212; the U.S. and Germany, the transatlantic partnership between the U.S. and Europe, NATO &#8212; say the same thing, speak with one voice, and do things together.&nbsp; And we made it very clear: If there was a military aggression against Ukraine, this will entail severe consequences that we agreed upon together, severe sanctions that we have worked on together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there will be a high price for Russia.&nbsp; This is a very clear message; everybody has understood it.&nbsp; And I think this message has been made clear again and again so that even Russia has understood the message now.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is important is that we also intensively worked on preparing possible sanctions together.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t want to start once there is a military aggression against Ukraine; we have prepared a reaction that will help us to react swiftly if needed, and we will do that.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the same time, it is important to use all diplomatic means we have.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m very glad about your great willingness to move forward together, especially the bilateral talks between the U.S. and Russia, and, of course, the talks that we have agreed upon within the NATO-Russia format.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is also important, also because Russia needs to understand that NATO stands together and that NATO is prepared.&nbsp; After so many years, there have not been any talks in this format.&nbsp; So, it is a good sign that they are happening now.&nbsp; Of course, we have controversial debates there, but it is important that we talk.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the same is true for the OSCE where we need to discuss about security in Europe.&nbsp; This is also a progress, as tiresome as it may be.&nbsp; And we have not yet reached any very substantial conclusions yet, but it is good to see that this format plays a role now.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the same is true for the talks between Ukraine, Russia, France, and Germany &#8212; the Normandy Format.&nbsp; We have this format, but we haven&#8217;t been able to really use it in a productive way over the last few years, so now we have come back to that format.&nbsp; We&#8217;re having tough discussions in that format, and that shows that there are ways that will lead us out of this difficult situation.</p>



<p>And this dual-track approach of clear announcements with regard to sanctions that will be taken if there is a military aggression and, at the same time, keeping all dialogue formats open &#8212; I think this is the most promising strategy one can have.&nbsp; And that is what we&#8217;re doing together, and we stand side by side in this approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also talked about many other topics that are important for us today, especially when it comes to the G7 presidency of the Federal Republic of Germany.&nbsp; We will work closely as strong economies, strong democracies.&nbsp; And we also therefore have a special mandate to contribute to cohesion worldwide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And part of this is that we continue to do everything we can to make sure that the citizens of the world can be vaccinated not only in our rich countries, but also in countries where people would love to have the vaccine but don&#8217;t have access yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And these are initiatives that we have carried out together and that are of utmost importance worldwide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The same is true for fighting manmade climate change &#8212; a big topic that keeps us all busy.&nbsp; Even though it is obvious that only a global solution can be successful, because climate is a global thing.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t stop at national borders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As an industrialized nation, we have an important contribution to make.&nbsp; We have technological opportunities, economic opportunities, and have to use them in order to prepare a situation where we and others can enjoy prosperity without harming the climate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is the big challenge that we see and that is of great importance to us.&nbsp; So, this is why we want to work together on this strategy and use a climate club of likeminded people and partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These are some of the topics we discussed.&nbsp; And once again, the personal discussion we had illustrates the excellent cooperation between our countries, the strong bond we have within our transatlantic partnership, and the fact that both countries can rely on each other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll now take a couple questions to each &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reuters.&nbsp; Andra- &#8212; Andrea.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve got the first question.</p>



<p>Q    Thank you, Mr.  President.  And thank you, Chancellor Scholz.  Mr.  President, I have wanted to ask you about this Nord Stream project that you&#8217;ve long opposed.  You didn&#8217;t mention it just now by name, nor did Chancellor Scholz.  Did you receive assurances from Chancellor Scholz today that Germany will, in fact, pull the plug on this project if Russia invades Ukraine?  And did you discuss what the definition of &#8220;invasion&#8221; could be?</p>



<p>And then, Chancellor Scholz:</p>



<p>(Speaks German.) (As interpreted.)&nbsp; If I may ask you, Chancellor Scholz &#8212; you said there was some strategic ambiguity that was needed in terms of sanctions.&nbsp; I just wanted to know whether the sanctions you are envisaging and the EU is working on &#8212; and the U.S. as well &#8212; are already finished, finalized, or is there still work ongoing?</p>



<p>And you&#8217;re not really saying what the details are.&nbsp; Is that just an excuse for Germany, maybe, to not support the SWIFT measures?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; The first question first.&nbsp; If Germany &#8212; if Russia invades &#8212; that means tanks or troops crossing the &#8212; the border of Ukraine again &#8212; then there will be &#8212; we &#8212; there will be no longer a Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; We will bring an end to it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But how will you &#8212; how will you do that exactly, since the project and control of the project is within Germany&#8217;s control?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We will &#8212; I promise you, we&#8217;ll be able to do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you very much for your question.&nbsp; I want to be absolutely clear: We have intensively prepared everything to be ready with the necessary sanctions if there is a military aggression against Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is necessary.&nbsp; It is necessary that we do this in advance so that Russia can clearly understand that these are far-reaching, severe measures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is part of this process that we do not spell out everything in public because Russia could understand that there might be even more to come.&nbsp; And, at the same time, it is very clear we are well prepared with far-reaching measures.&nbsp; We will take these measures together with our Allies, with our partners, with the U.S., and we will take all necessary steps.&nbsp; You can be sure that there won&#8217;t be any measures in which we have a differing approach.&nbsp; We will act together jointly.</p>



<p>(Speaks in English.) And possibly this is a good idea to say to our American friends: We will be united, we will act together, and we will take all the necessary steps.&nbsp; And all the necessary steps will be done by all of us together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And will you commit today &#8212; will you commit today to turning off and pulling the plug on Nord Stream 2?&nbsp; You didn&#8217;t mention it, and you haven&#8217;t mentioned it.</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; As I&#8217;ve already said, we are acting together, we are absolutely united, and we will not be taking different steps.&nbsp; We will do the same steps, and they will be very, very hard to Russia, and they should understand.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; You can recognize someone now, Chancellor.</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; Herr Fischer.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Michael Fischer, DPA.&nbsp; Mr.&nbsp; President, one question to you: The U.S., over the last few years, have exported heavy weapons to Ukraine, and Germany excludes that &#8212; has only delivered 5,000 helmets to Ukraine.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t you think that NATO should act unanimously in this respect and Germany, as the strongest European NATO partner, should also deliver heavy weapons to Ukraine?&nbsp; And Ukraine has asked Germany to do so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on Nord Stream 2, I would also like to ask: Don&#8217;t you think, with regards to the threat posed by Russia, Germany should already rethink its position on Nord Stream 2?</p>



<p>And the third question, if I may: Over the last few days and weeks, there has been severe criticism from the U.S. media and from Congress as well vis-à-vis Germany about the reliability of Germany as an ally.&nbsp; This has been called into question.&nbsp; Do you understand this criticism?&nbsp; Is Germany a reliable partner, from your point of view?</p>



<p>And, Mr. Chancellor, also a question to you: Nord Stream 2 &#8212; you said all options around the table.&nbsp; You&#8217;re not mentioning Nord Stream 2 by name.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t you think if you were to spell this out, you could win back trust as a strong ally here for the U.S.?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; There&#8217;s no need to win back trust.&nbsp; He has the complete trust of the United States.&nbsp; Germany is our &#8212; one of our most important allies in the world.&nbsp; There is no doubt about Germany&#8217;s partnership with the United States.&nbsp; None.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With regard to helping Ukraine, one of the largest contributors financially to Ukraine has been Germany.&nbsp; Germany has been in the forefront of making sure &#8212; providing economic assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You also asked the question &#8212; you asked so many I can&#8217;t remember them all.&nbsp; But in terms of the U.S. media saying Germany is not reliable, Germany is completely reliable &#8212; completely, totally, thoroughly reliable.&nbsp; I have no doubt about Germany at all.</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; We are united.&nbsp; And the transatlantic partnership between Germany and the U.S. is one of the permanent pillars of German policy, and it will be relevant in the future as well &#8212; just as relevant.&nbsp; And this will be one of our top priorities always.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On behalf of NATO, we are the country in continental Europe that is doing &#8212; making the largest contribution: financial means and also military power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we are the country that contributes a great share &#8212; we&#8217;re not fully &#8212; we don&#8217;t fully agree with you as who pays the biggest part of financial support to Ukraine.&nbsp; So, since 2014, about 2 billion U.S. dollars direct bilateral support and, within the EU, an additional 3.8 billion that is made available.&nbsp; So a substantial financial means to stabilize the Ukraine economy, and we are willing to continue with that sort of contribution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is the very strong and unbreakable friendship between our two countries.&nbsp; Part of this is that with regard to the difficult situation at the Ukrainian border due to the Russian troops, we have made it very clear we will unanimously act in terms of sanctions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Mr. President, once again, a question with regard to arms exports.&nbsp; Do you think it is okay that NATO partners have different approaches here?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on Nord Stream 2, once again, do you think the current positioning of Germany with regard to the Russian threat is okay?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Look, there is no doubt in America&#8217;s mind that Germany is an incredibly reliable Ally and one of the leading physical powers in NATO, number one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, the notion that Nord Stream T [sic] would go &#8212; Nord Stream 2 would go forward with an invasion by the Russians &#8212; it’s just not going to happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, Wall Street Journal, Sabrina.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Based on everything you know now, do you think that President Putin will authorize an invasion of Ukraine before the end of the winter?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what is your message to the roughly 30,000 Americans who are currently in Ukraine?&nbsp; Do you think that they should leave the country?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ve had discussions &#8212; numerous discussions with the &#8212; with the Russians and particularly with Putin.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that he&#8217;s even made a &#8212; I don&#8217;t know that he knows what he&#8217;s going to do.&nbsp; And I think he has to realize that it would be a gigantic mistake for him to move on Ukraine.&nbsp; The impact on Europe and the rest of the world would be devastating, and he would pay a heavy price.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have been very, very straightforward and blunt with President Putin, both on the phone and in person.&nbsp; We will impose the most severe sanctions that have ever been imposed &#8212; economic sanctions &#8212; and there&#8217;ll be a lot to pay for that down the road.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It will affect others as well.&nbsp; It will affect us somewhat.&nbsp; It will affect Europeans.&nbsp; But it will have profound impact on his economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I &#8212; I &#8212; but I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; I know that he&#8217;s in a position now to be able to invade almost &#8212; assuming that the ground is frozen above Kyiv.&nbsp; He has the capacity to do that.&nbsp; What he&#8217;s going to do, I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think anybody knows but him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is your message to the Americans who are currently in Ukraine &#8212; should they leave the country?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;d be wise to leave the country.&nbsp; Not &#8212; I don&#8217;t mean our &#8212; I don&#8217;t mean &#8212; I&#8217;m not talking about our diplomatic corps; I&#8217;m talking about Americans who are there.&nbsp; I’d hate to see them get caught in a crossfire if in fact they did invade.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no need for that.&nbsp; And I &#8212; if I were they &#8212; if I had anyone there, I&#8217;d say leave.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to Chancellor Scholz: Can you outline specific steps that Germany is taking to reduce its energy dependence on Russia?&nbsp; And what do you say to those who suggest that German reliance on Russian gas is limiting Europe&#8217;s options for how to respond to the crisis in Ukraine?</p>



<p>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you very much for raising that question because it gives me the opportunity to address a topic that&#8217;s important to me.&nbsp; One good news, maybe, within its strategy on fighting manmade climate change, Germany has decided at very short &#8212; in a very short period of time to phase out of the use of oil and gas by &#8212; very soon.&nbsp; And by 2045, Germany will have a carbon neutral economy as one of the strongest economies of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with regard to these energies &#8212; we often think about heating at home and driving a car, but we&#8217;re talking about industrial production: producing steel, chemical substances, cement.&nbsp; And changing these industrial processes and reorganizing such systems is what we have planned.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this year, we will continue to take far-reaching decisions that will help us to use more wind energy &#8212; offshore wind energy, onshore wind energy &#8212; and solar energy; and expand the capacities, expand the grids; and have a strategy for Germany but also worldwide on the use of hydrogen, which is a central element for us to change our industrial processes that are using oil and gas right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The industry is willing to be on board.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing this together with them, but it will probably be the biggest industrial modernization project in Germany in 100 years, with very good prospects that we will develop new technologies that other partners in the world can use as well, and this will help us fight climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, the energy mix today, we are talking about one quarter of our energy that is linked to gas.&nbsp; And only part of that gas comes from Russia; a big part comes from Norway or the Netherlands.&nbsp; And, of course, it is very important to us that we develop an infrastructure that will give us the opportunity to have all options available and react if needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you don&#8217;t have to be concerned.&nbsp; There are some who should be concerned who see themselves maybe too much as a deliverer of such resources.&nbsp; Because we are focusing on renewable energies, we will go down that path and make sure that this is the profitable future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. Rinke.<br><br>     Q    (As interpreted.)  Mr. President, I would like to ask you a question about LNG.  Germany and Europe are much more dependent on Russian gas than other regions of the world, and you promised European allies to help with LNG.  But this resource is more expensive; it&#8217;s not available in the volumes that might be needed to replace Russian gas.  And I would like to know from you how you would help Europeans in case of a conflict with Russia.  Is this an empty promise, or what can you really do?  What can you offer?<br><br>     And, in addition, the U.S. are buying oil from Russia worth billions of dollars.  And I would like to know whether these transfers are also part of the sanctions package against Russia. </p>



<p><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, Mr. Chancellor &#8212; liquefied natural gas.&nbsp; There is a big controversy in Germany about fracking gas and how far is LNG even a real replacement, or is it also with a view to the climate collab you intend to found.&nbsp; Is it really an alternative to Russian pipeline gas?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Let me respond.&nbsp; First of all, we are looking at opportunities to make up for lost gas &#8212; LNG &#8212; from Russia.&nbsp; We&#8217;re underway of trying to see what we can do to do that and dealing with our friends around the world, as well.&nbsp; We think we could make up a significant portion of it that would be lost.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, you know, what everybody forgets here is Russia needs to be able to sell that gas and sell that oil.&nbsp; Russia relies &#8212; a significant part of Russia&#8217;s budget &#8212; it&#8217;s the only thing they really have to export.&nbsp; And if, in fact, it&#8217;s cut off, then they&#8217;re going to be hurt very badly, as well.&nbsp; And it’s of consequence to them as well.&nbsp; This is not just a one-way street.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, we are looking at what we could do to help compensate for loss of &#8212; immediate loss of gas in Europe if it occurs.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve been working on for some time now.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; I can confirm that we work closely with the United States of America, and Joe Biden and I are working closely together as well.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are prepared for all kinds of situation.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s part of what we do when we say we prepare sanctions.&nbsp; That means we need to be able to react at any time, and this is happening.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With regard to the use of LNG, I can say that the biggest volume of LNG used across the world is gas, and that is part of the debate.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Concerning a long-term perspective, I already outlined what this is about.&nbsp; We will modernize our economy.&nbsp; And where gas is being used, we will switch to hydrogen.&nbsp; This will be a process that will happen faster than many might imagine today, and that will create a bright future for all of us.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on de-escalation, sir.&nbsp; Do you still believe there’s an off-ramp for Vladimir Putin here?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, do you believe there’s still an off-ramp for him &#8212; that de-escalation is an actual possibility, given that there are 100,000 troops at the border?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; The answer is “yes.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">4:08 P.M. EST<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
