<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 22:43:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris on the Anniversary of the Voting Rights Act of&#160;1965</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/06/statement-by-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-the-anniversary-of-the-voting-rights-act-of-1965/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 22:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fifty-six years ago today &#8211; surrounded by Democrats and Republicans, activists and leaders including Dr. Martin Luther King, John Lewis, and Rosa Parks &#8211; President Lyndon Baines Johnson signed the Voting Rights Act of 1965 into law. The Voting Rights Act remains one of the most important pieces of legislation in our nation&#8217;s history. It&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Fifty-six years ago today &#8211; surrounded by Democrats and Republicans, activists and leaders including Dr. Martin Luther King, John Lewis, and Rosa Parks &#8211; President Lyndon Baines Johnson signed the Voting Rights Act of 1965 into law. The Voting Rights Act remains one of the most important pieces of legislation in our nation&#8217;s history. It is estimated that in the five years after passage, almost as many Black Americans registered to vote in some southern states as in the 100 years prior to 1965. <br><br>On the anniversary of its signing, we honor the generations of Americans who marched, organized, and sacrificed, and we commit to continuing the fight. Today, voting rights are once again under attack. Over the past decade, the Voting Rights Act has been gutted by Supreme Court decisions. As a result, states have passed anti-voter legislation. Just this year, 18 states have passed 30 laws that make it more difficult for Americans to vote, including by limiting vote-by-mail, early voting, and other restrictive measures. We must fight back, and we are.<br><br>There are two landmark pieces of federal legislation moving through Congress now that our Administration fully supports—the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act. Just as leaders recognized 56 years ago, we are in a critical moment, and that is why we must pass these bills.<br><br>It will not be easy. But the struggle over voting rights has never been easy. Each generation has fought to expand voting rights, and we owe it to the next generation to fight for every American’s right to vote and have their vote counted.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the Second Meeting of the White&#160;House Council on Native American&#160;Affairs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/06/readout-of-the-second-meeting-of-the-white-house-council-on-native-american-affairs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 22:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland and Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice convened&#160;the second&#160;meeting of the White House Council on Native American Affairs&#160;(WHCNAA).&#160;&#160;They were joined by eleven Cabinet Secretaries and senior administration officials in a discussion focused on bolstering the government-to-government relationship and advancing self-determination and self-government of Tribal Nations.&#160;&#160;During the meeting, the Domestic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland and Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice convened&nbsp;the second&nbsp;meeting of the White House Council on Native American Affairs&nbsp;(WHCNAA).&nbsp;&nbsp;They were joined by eleven Cabinet Secretaries and senior administration officials in a discussion focused on bolstering the government-to-government relationship and advancing self-determination and self-government of Tribal Nations.&nbsp;&nbsp;During the meeting, the Domestic Policy Council, White House American Rescue Plan Implementation Team, and Department of Interior committed to lead an interagency process to support Tribal Nations’ use of the historic infusion of federal funding dedicated to tribal needs. The WHCNAA Health Committee also announced it will host a Nation-to-Nation dialogue on COVID-19 and improving health systems in Indian Country this fall. This will be an opportunity for Tribal engagement with Administration leadership on federal emergency management programs and resources and to share the latest data. The Health Committee will develop a workplan informed by this dialogue to strengthen inter-agency federal emergency response efforts.<br><br>The Council will&nbsp;continue to&nbsp;coordinate with Tribal Nations as it advances work on key issues such as climate change, Tribal homelands and treaties; economic development, energy and infrastructure; health; education; public safety and justice; and international Indigenous issues.&nbsp;<br><br>Members of the Council on Native American Affairs include:</p>



<ul><li>Department of the Interior&nbsp;</li><li>Domestic Policy Council&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Agriculture&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Commerce&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Defense&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Education&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Energy&nbsp;</li><li>Environmental Protection Agency&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Health and Human Services&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Homeland Security&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Justice&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Labor&nbsp;</li><li>Office of Management and Budget&nbsp;</li><li>Office of Personnel Management&nbsp;</li><li>Office of Management and Budget&nbsp;</li><li>Small Business Administration&nbsp;</li><li>Social Security Administration&nbsp;</li><li>Department of State&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Transportation&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Treasury&nbsp;</li><li>Department of Veterans Affairs&nbsp;</li><li>US Ambassador to the United Nations&nbsp;</li><li>US Trade Representative&nbsp;</li><li>Advisory Council on Historic Preservation&nbsp;</li><li>Denali Commission&nbsp;</li><li>Gender Policy Council&nbsp;</li><li>Office of Science and Technology Policy&nbsp;</li><li>National Climate Advisor&nbsp;</li><li>Office of Intergovernmental Affairs&nbsp;</li><li>Council on Environmental Quality&nbsp;</li><li>White House&nbsp;Cabinet Affairs&nbsp;</li><li>White House COVID Response Team</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, August 6,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/08/06/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-august-6-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 22:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:42 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI: &#160;Hi, everyone. &#160;Happy Friday. &#160;Okay. &#160;A couple of items for you at the top.&#160;Are you &#8212; Zeke, are you married?&#160;Q &#160; &#160;Yes.&#160;MS. PSAKI: &#160;Welcome back. &#160;Congratulations. &#160;(Applause.)&#160;Q &#160; &#160;Thank you.&#160;MS. PSAKI: &#160;You know, he&#8217;s got some bling on his finger. &#160;Okay. &#160;Most important decision you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:42 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Hi, everyone. &nbsp;Happy Friday. &nbsp;Okay. &nbsp;A couple of items for you at the top.<br>&nbsp;<br>Are you &#8212; Zeke, are you married?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Welcome back. &nbsp;Congratulations. &nbsp;(Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;You know, he&#8217;s got some bling on his finger. &nbsp;Okay. &nbsp;Most important decision you make in your life. &nbsp;(Laughter.) &nbsp;Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today’s numbers &#8212; on the jobs numbers; obviously, it&#8217;s Jobs Day &#8212; today&#8217;s numbers are further proof that President Biden’s economy is booming. &nbsp;Jobs are up, growth is up, and unemployment is down as Americans get back to work.<br>&nbsp;<br>We see that clearly in today’s data. &nbsp;This is the fastest monthly job growth in almost a year. &nbsp;Labor force participation also ticked up as more Americans got back to work. &nbsp;Since January, more than 1 million Americans have re-entered the labor force. &nbsp;Unemployment also fell sharply, from 5.9 to 5.4 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>See how we enjoy charts here? &nbsp;I will note the comparison.<br>&nbsp;<br>In total, we’ve created over 4 million new jobs &#8212; 832,000 on average for the last three months, with revisions upwards for the last two months. &nbsp;And over the first six months, we’ve created almost 700,000 per month on average. &nbsp;That’s more jobs created faster than any other President’s first six months in history.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In comparison, the previous administration only created 1.1 million jobs in their first six months.<br>&nbsp;<br>And just last week, new GDP figures showed the U.S. economy has now made up the las- &#8212; the losses of the last 18 months and surpassed the pre-pandemic peak.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will note, as always, there may be ups and downs. &nbsp;But thanks to the strong foundation from the American Rescue Plan and the tools it gives us, as well as our vaccination program, positions &#8212; positions us to weather any challenges without going backwards or shutting down our schools or our economy.&nbsp;<br> <br>I also wanted to note &#8212; (a cellphone ring) &#8212; that&#8217;s an exciting ringtone &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; okay &#8212; that, yesterday, President Biden released a statement on progress we’ve made expanding access to quality, affordable healthcare &#8212; a huge priority for him &#8212; with the expansion of the Special Enrollment Period, which goes through August 15th.<br>&nbsp;<br>In February, we announced &#8212; opened a Special Enrollment period to provide all Americans the opportunity to sign up for health insurance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In March, President Biden signed the American Rescue Plan into law, lowering premiums and saving families an average of $50 per person per month. And later in March, we extended the enrollment deadline to August 15th.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Five months later, the results are clear: more than 2 million Americans have signed up for health coverage. &nbsp;That&#8217;s exciting.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we also launched a “Summer Sprint to Coverage” campaign earlier this summer, leveraging robust paid media, increased community outreach, and more to get Americans signed up.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, for those who don&#8217;t have healthcare, go to HealthCare.gov and you can sign up there and get more information.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also wanted to provide you all an update on COVID. &nbsp;Today, we&#8217;ve recorded &#8212; we recorded 821,000 total vaccinations. This is the second day in a row we have got more than 800,000 total shots &#8212; the first time we’ve done this since June &#8212; since June 30th and July 1st.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Overall, more than 3.2 million Americans have gotten newly vaccinated over the past seven days. &nbsp;And importantly, as we&#8217;ve seen as a trend over the last few weeks, states with the highest case rates are seeing their vaccination rates grow the fastest.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as we’ve said from the start, that’s exactly what it’s going to take to get us out of this pandemic: more Americans stepping up and doing their part to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to encouraging trends on the vaccination front, we’re seeing &#8212; with the pace of vaccinations, we&#8217;re seeing growing momentum on requirements. &nbsp;And we&#8217;ve seen a number of announcements out this morning. &nbsp;We expect that, certainly, to continue.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as you know, last week, the President announced new requirements for federal employees and contractors, and asked the private and public sectors, universities, and healthcare systems, state and local governments, and other institutions to take steps, and many of them are answering his call to action.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this week, one of the largest nursing home chains announced they’d require vaccinations for employees. &nbsp;Massachusetts will require vaccination for nursing home staff. &nbsp;And Maryland and Virginia announced vaccination requirements for state employees. &nbsp;And I&#8217;d note: Two of those three states are led by Republican governors.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just today, United Airlines announced it will require all of its roughly 85,000 employees to be vaccinated by the end of September.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the message &#8212; our message is simple: We support these vaccination requirements to protect workers, communities, and our country. &nbsp;And we hope to see even more action from the public and private sector over the coming weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last piece for all of you &#8212; lots going on here, as you all know. &nbsp;This week, we &#8212; the administration &#8212; administration officials held virtual listening sessions with groups representing landlords and tenant advocates to discuss state and local disbursement of Emergency Rental Assistance funds and ways to protect renters from evictions. &nbsp;This is part of our ongoing outreach and ongoing effort to get money out in states and localities.<br>&nbsp;<br>Landlords offered ideas on how grantees might speed delivery and increase access to rental assistance, and tenant advocates expressed challenges renters are facing in accessing Emergency Rental Assistance funds &#8212; both issues we want to work to address.<br>&nbsp;<br>In both meetings, administration officials reiterated the commitment made by President Biden that our administration will not rest &#8212; nor should state and local governments &#8212; until Emergency Rental Assistance dollars reach Americans in need.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as we know, given the rising urgency of containing the spread of the Delta variant, the President’s overriding goal is, of course, keeping people &#8212; the American people safe and, ideally, in their homes.<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of this effort, the CDC has used the legal authority that Congress provided, and developed the requisite record for a new, targeted, and dynamic eviction moratorium focused on counties with high or substantial case rates to protect renters and help to stop the spread of this new and more transmissible COVID variant.<br>&nbsp;<br>The administration believes that this is a proper use of a lawful authority to protect the public health, and the Supreme Court has not ruled otherwise.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Ultimately, we hope that these combined efforts will keep as many Americans safe and housed as possible.<br>&nbsp;<br>I usually have a week ahead. &nbsp;I will note for all of you that the President &#8212; we expect the President to be here for a few days early next week.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, the Senate also is expected to be, and we will keep you updated as we know more specific details about his travel plans.<br>&nbsp;<br>Zeke.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you, Jen. &nbsp;First, on COVID: some developments in the states this morning. &nbsp;In Arkansas, a judge there blocked the state from enforcing its ban on schools enforcing mask mandates. &nbsp;I was wondering if the White House had any reaction to that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, similarly, in Florida, where the legislature there was passing a &#8212; essentially a voucher program to allow parents to pull their kids out of school if there were &#8212; if there were mask requirement they didn&#8217;t like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What&#8217;s the level of White House engagement right now with all of these different state governments? &nbsp;And for folks who are sort of, you know, puzzled by the &#8212; all these &#8212; you know, federal guidance, state guidance, what&#8217;s the advice from the White House to parents worried about their kids in school?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, since you reminded me, I also want to &#8212; &nbsp; for anyone who doesn&#8217;t know Kevin Munoz, he&#8217;s one of the amazing people on the press team who does COVID &#8212; so just reminded me. &nbsp;We call him &#8220;Dr. Munoz,&#8221; because he&#8217;s such a specialist in this area. &nbsp; So, I pulled him out here with me today. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I would say, Zeke, that we do have a concern, of course, about restrictions that are being put in place in a handful of states &#8212; or have been put in place around the country that make it more difficult for localities, for schools, for businesses in some places to implement public health guidelines.<br>&nbsp;<br>And our message continues to be that if you don&#8217;t want to abide by public health guidelines &#8212; don&#8217;t want to use your role as leaders, elected officials &#8212; then you should get out of the way and let public health officials guide localities, schools, universities to do the &#8212; or local schools as well &#8212; to do exactly the right thing.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think you heard yesterday &#8212; or those of you who were here heard Secretary Cardona convey, as it relates to schools specifically, that we do have information from our public health experts, from the CDC, on how we can open up 100 percent of schools and keep them open in the fall. &nbsp; That&#8217;s our objective. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The only prevention &#8212; the only thing preventing that would be if officials in different states and localities put in place restrictions that make that challenging or impossible. &nbsp;And that is certainly concerning to us. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And I got another COVID one for you. &nbsp;The President, a few minutes ago, said that additional vaccination penalties &#8212; for lack of a better term &#8212; or burdens for those who are not vaccinated are likely to come in the coming days. &nbsp;I was hoping you might be able to address what some of those are likely to stand as the new policy here at White House, in addition to across the federal government, as well, in terms of forms people have to fill out under potential criminal or civil penalty. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, you know, is the White House looking at requiring vaccinations for all nursing home workers nationwide or for people flying on domestic airlines (inaudible)? &nbsp;Is domestic travel vaccination requirements something that&#8217;s under consideration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I know there was also, in addition to the President&#8217;s comments, some reporting overnight as well that a number of you have asked us about, understandably.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would say that that and the President&#8217;s comments certainly reflect what we always do in this administration, which is discuss policy options about how we can continue to mount a wartime response against the virus.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, what he was conveying and I think if &#8212; for those of you who have asked us about reporting overnight: Yes, there are early conversations, early discussions about a range of options. &nbsp; Those are all early-stage, they&#8217;re pre-decisional, and I would not &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any policy decisions to preview for you because we&#8217;re not at that point in the process.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know you didn&#8217;t ask me about this, but since others have, I would also note that there has been some reporting around discussions about &#8212; around cruises and universities, and that would not be accurate. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And just, from a broader, 30,000-foot standpoint, why is the administration sort of taking &#8212; you know, acting sort of slowly here? &nbsp;You&#8217;re highlighting all the different efforts, you know, businesses and some states are taking on this vaccination front. &nbsp;Shouldn&#8217;t the White House sort of lead at the front here to sort of try to really increase the &#8212; sort of, maybe, hold that &#8212; wield that stick a little bit more for people who are still waiting on the sidelines and not rolling up their sleeves?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, Zeke, I would say that the President led, eight days ago, by delivering a speech where he conveyed that the federal government would be taking actions, conveyed that there would be requirements for federal government employees and contractors, and also asked the public and private sector to take actions on their own. &nbsp;And we&#8217;re seeing that happening.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we are going to consider a range of options. &nbsp;There are factors, as I think you all know, as you consider these policy options &#8212; pros and cons. &nbsp;We&#8217;re making all decisions through the prism of what is in the interest of public health, but we&#8217;re going to let that policy process see itself through. &nbsp;And certainly, we want to make decisions as expeditiously as possible. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thanks, Jen. &nbsp;Given the strength of today&#8217;s jobs numbers, has the President decided that he&#8217;s not going to seek to renew the beefed-up unemployment benefits when they expire next month?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know, earlier this summer, he said that it would make sense to let them lapse, but that was before the Delta variant really took hold.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;There has not been any decision about this at this point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;He&#8217;s still deciding whether to ask to renew them &#8212; whether to seek to renew them or not?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Correct. &nbsp;At this point, they&#8217;re expiring at the beginning of September. &nbsp;Nothing has changed on that front, but a final decision has not been made.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And then, on Afghanistan, the Taliban has made big gains this week. &nbsp;They&#8217;re surrounding a number of cities. &nbsp;They&#8217;ve taken control of a provincial capital. &nbsp;They assassinated government officials. &nbsp;Has all of that caused any reflection, second thoughts on the part of the White House when it comes to the Afghanistan policy or any changes in the strategy there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, first, let me strongly condemn &#8212; on behalf of the government, of course &#8212; the assassination of Dawa Khan Menapal, the Director of the Afghan Governmental Information Media Center. &nbsp;His murder follows the bombing attack in Kabul earlier this week that targeted the Acting Afghan Defense Minister.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Taliban has claimed responsibility for this later attack, and there&#8217;s no reason to doubt reports they are responsible.<br>&nbsp;<br>Additionally, there are credible reports, as you&#8217;ve touched on, of atrocities and retaliation against civilians in other Taliban-controlled areas, which, of course, we are closely tracking and concerned about. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If the Taliban &#8212; our view is that the &#8212; if the Taliban claim to want international legitimacy, these actions are not going to get them the legitimacy they seek. &nbsp;They do not have to stay on this trajectory. &nbsp;They could choose to devote the same energy to the peace process as they are to their military campaign. &nbsp;We strongly urge them to do so. &nbsp;This is what the Afghan people so urgently need, deserve after decades of war. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it&#8217;s very much in Afghanistan&#8217;s neighbors&#8217; interest to invest renewed energy into a peace process that promotes a peaceful Afghanistan and stable region.<br>&nbsp;<br>As it relates to the decision, the &#8212; we knew from the beginning &#8212; and the President would be the first to say this &#8212; that there are difficult choices a Commander-in-Chief needs to make on behalf of the American people. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He made clear &#8212; the President made clear: After 20 years at war, it&#8217;s time for American troops to come home. &nbsp;And as he said at the time, the status quo was not an option. &nbsp;The Taliban was prepared to attack U.S. and NATO troops after May 1st, which was the deadline for our departure. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also feels and has stated that the Afghan government and the Afghan National Defense Forces have the training, equipment, and numbers to prevail, and now is the moment for the leadership and the will in the face of the Taliban&#8217;s aggression and violence. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And then a follow-up question about Afghanistan, please?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you very much, Jen. &nbsp;As she asked about the senior journalist that has been killed today, Afghan government &#8212; Afghan leaders like President Ghani and the &#8212; all leaders in Afghanistan now, they said that Pakistan is behind all of the Taliban activity &#8212; activity &#8212; very systematically there, in general. &nbsp;Now, Afghan people do not understand that Pakistan is our enemy or our neighbor, our friend. &nbsp;What do you think? &nbsp;Part of the &#8212; which route Pakistan should play to bring Taliban &#8212; the peace process?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Our view continues to be: It&#8217;s in the interest of all countries in the region for there to be a political process, peace, and stability in the region. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Could you describe a little bit about what the overarching ask is within the federal government to look at things like what levers do you have to further spur vaccination?<br>&nbsp;<br>On the nursing home piece, is it using Medicare dollars and linking back to nursing homes? &nbsp;Is it regulatory action? &nbsp;What sorts of things can you help us to understand where that policy might go?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I certainly understand your question. &nbsp;I&#8217;m not going to be able to lay out too many details of internal conversations. &nbsp;I will note that, certainly, we have applauded the steps taken by a number of states as it relates to requirements of nursing home employees and health providers to get vaccinated. &nbsp;We&#8217;ve seen states do that. &nbsp;We&#8217;ve seen some health providers do that. &nbsp;That&#8217;s a positive step. &nbsp;And as noted in some of the reporting, that&#8217;s an area of early discussion &#8212; but again, early pre-decisional discussion. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to make decisions from the federal government that we believe will save lives and we believe will protect the most vulnerable populations, that will incentivize more people getting vaccinated and bring an end to the virus. &nbsp;There are pros and cons to many of these policies; that&#8217;s part of the discussion as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Does it extend to other &#8212; we&#8217;ve talked nursing homes. &nbsp;Is it affecting travel? &nbsp;Is it affecting other types of businesses? &nbsp;Could you just broaden it there for us to understand &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;There are obviously a number of private sector companies that have taken their own steps. &nbsp;We certainly applaud that. &nbsp;And there are a range of topics and industries under discussion internally.<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, the best step that that can happen out there is for Americans going out and getting vaccinated. &nbsp;And there are private sector companies that are in the lead and continue to be in the lead on moving this forward. &nbsp;That&#8217;s a positive step. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But there are ongoing internal discussions. &nbsp;I&#8217;m not going to be able to preview those too much &#8212; too extensively from here. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;First, on the jobs report: If the economy is so great and you guys are celebrating jobs being created at a historic &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Wouldn&#8217;t you say over 900,000 jobs created is pretty good?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;So, this is my question: Why then is the President still pushing for big relief packages &#8212; pandemic-era relief packages like the eviction moratorium?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, first, I would say: One of the biggest pieces of legislation he&#8217;s pushing for, as we know, is the infrastructure package, and also the Build Back Better agenda. &nbsp;A lot of &#8212; most of the components in those packages are long-term investments. &nbsp;They&#8217;re out &#8212; they&#8217;re overdue. &nbsp;They&#8217;re meant to modernize our infrastructure, put people back to work over the long term, and make us more competitive over the long term. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is still a reality, even with a good jobs number this month and even with 4 million jobs created over six months, that there are still people out of work. &nbsp;There are still people who don&#8217;t have enough money to make ends meet. &nbsp;That&#8217;s one of the reasons why we designed the American Rescue Plan to have a long-term, spread-out impact &#8212; whether it&#8217;s the Child Tax Credit or benefits that are going to schools that are spread out over the course of a year &#8212; because we are still in a recovery. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Back-to-school question: Florida&#8217;s Governor DeSantis says that he may start withholding funds from school districts that don&#8217;t let parents opt out of policies that require masks in the classroom. &nbsp;Does the President think that parents should have that kind of power? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I think I&#8217;ve spoken to this a few times, but I will say, as a parent myself of two young children, that I want public health officials to make decisions about how to keep my kids safe, not politicians. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And not only is Governor DeSantis not abiding by public health decisions, he&#8217;s fundraising off of this. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, my view is that &#8212; and our view, as an administration, is that teacher &#8212; parents in Florida, parents across the country should have the ability and the knowledge that their kids are going to school and they&#8217;re in safe environments. &nbsp;That shouldn&#8217;t be too much to ask. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;He says that his concern is about harmful, emotional, academic, and psychological effects of putting kindergarteners in masks for hours at a time. &nbsp;Is there any concern from officials that you guys talked to in your early pre-decisional discussions about that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;No, there&#8217;s not. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I will tell you from personal experience, my rising kindergartener told me, two days ago, she could wear a mask all day, and she&#8217;s just happy to go to camp and go to school. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the objective from all of our public health officials have &#8212; has been clearly &#8212; and our Secretary of Education &#8212; kids need to be in school. &nbsp;We know there&#8217;s a mental health impact of them not being in school, and we should take the mitigation measures needed in order for them to be in school and in the classroom, including masking and including allowing that to be part of a reality in these schools to keep the community safe. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;On the infrastructure bill, there&#8217;s a cryptocurrency tax provision in the bill. &nbsp;And some bipartisan lawmakers have suggested an alternative to the White House-backed cryptocurrency. &nbsp;Are you &#8212; is the White House asking for those lawmakers &#8212; it&#8217;s Wyden, Toomey, and Lummis &#8212; to withdraw their crypto amendment? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, first we are pleased with the progress that has yielded a compromise sponsored by Senators Warner, Portman, and Sinema to advance the bipartisan infrastructure package and clarify the measure to reduce tax evasion in the cryptocurrency market, which, of course, is the objective &#8212; or was the initial objective. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We believe this provision will strengthen tax compliance in this emerging area of finance and ensure that high-income taxpayers are contributing what they owe under the law, which is part of our objective. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are also very grateful to Chairman Wyden and other leaders in the Senate in pushing the Senate to address this issue. &nbsp;But we believe that the alternative amendment put forward by Senators Warner, Portman, and Sinema strikes the right balance and makes an important step forward in promoting tax compliance. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;So, sticking with that one, would you &#8212; would the White House prefer that Wyden withdraw his amendment then?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;We&#8217;ll leave the mechanics up to Leader Schumer. &nbsp;But certainly, we see this amendment as an option that helps address the concerns. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thanks. &nbsp;And you&#8217;ve seen that he has talked about how the White House-backed proposal &#8212; that Sinema proposal &#8212; wouldn&#8217;t be good for climate because it pushes &#8212; it undermines some parts of crypto that use less energy. &nbsp;So his argument is that there&#8217;s a climate, environment argument there. &nbsp;Do you have any reaction to that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, again, we&#8217;re very grateful to his leadership. &nbsp;He&#8217;s been a key partner to us in this effort to move this initiative forward. &nbsp;I would just go back to the overarching objective here, which is reducing tax evasion in the cryptocurrency market. &nbsp;And we feel that the compromise sponsored by Senators Warner, Portman, and Sinema is a good option moving forward. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;9/11 families are saying today that President Biden should not participate in any memorial events unless there&#8217;s information declassified that could show some link with Saudi Arabia to the attacks. &nbsp;Is he going to follow through with that and release that information?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, our hearts are with the families who lost loved ones on 9/11, especially in these days preceding the 20th anniversary of the attacks coming up just next month. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know you didn&#8217;t ask this, but I just want to share that the White House Office of Public Engagement and the National Security Council staff have had several meetings with groups representing the families of those who perished on 9/11 regarding their document requests and to hear their thoughts on policy priorities. &nbsp;That will continue to be a priority.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a candidate &#8212; which you may be aware of, Alex &#8212; President Biden made a commitment to 9/11 families to ask the Department of Justice to work constructively on resolving issues relating to the previous administration&#8217;s invocation of the state secrets privilege, including adhering to guidance issued in the Obama-Biden administration, that the invocation of such a privilege be narrowly tailored and not be undertaken to prevent embarrassment to a person or organization. &nbsp;He remains committed to that pledge he made during the campaign.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, any steps would be taken by the Department of Justice. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And, secondly, I want to ask if the President supports a redo in the Amazon union matter. &nbsp;Does he &#8212; is he calling for another vote on that? &nbsp;Is he going to publicly advocate for workers on that front?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, it&#8217;s certainly &#8212; the President is a strong supporter of collective bargaining rights and the rights of workers, and has been for decades throughout his career. &nbsp;It would be up for the workers to make that decision. &nbsp;And certainly, we would leave that process to move forward accordingly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Asma.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Yeah, there&#8217;s been some reporting in the Wall Street Journal about a number of business groups calling on the administration to lift or cut these tariffs with China (inaudible). &nbsp;Can you give us any guidance on the stage of your review and what is going on with the China tariffs?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yes, well, we are always going to use &#8212; the President is always going to use every tool in his toolbox, including tarrists [sic] &#8212; tariffs to fight against unfair trade practices that hurt American workers, businesses, and farmers. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he&#8217;s been very clear that he thinks that a go-it-alone strategy is a losing one. &nbsp;We&#8217;re stronger when we work with our allies and unite the world&#8217;s GDP. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know we&#8217;ve talked about an ongoing review, including tariffs; I don&#8217;t have any preview for you or timeline for that conclusion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Jen, with respect to the government exercising its federal authority around vaccines, you said that the conversations are &#8220;pre-decisional.&#8221; &nbsp;What is the timeline for getting to decisional? &nbsp;Like, are we talking days, weeks, months? &nbsp;Do you guys have a sense on when you&#8217;ll have a determination on some of these discussions? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you. &nbsp;And when we say &#8220;early&#8221; and &#8220;pre-decisional,&#8221; often that means it&#8217;s just at the staff level and they&#8217;re discussing a broad range of options, many of which never may even be presented up beyond that. &nbsp;But there are a broad range of discussions happening &#8212; early stages. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And obviously, no decisions have been made, but clearly COVID is our number-one priority, and they&#8217;ll continue to work towards what they think the best options are. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And you said that the schedule is a little bit in flux for next week. &nbsp;Does President Biden intend to take a summer vacation? &nbsp;And if not, is that attributed to COVID numbers? &nbsp;Is that attributed to the Senate infrastructure talks? &nbsp;Like &#8212; what are &#8212; what are &#8212; why are the plans in flux?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, every President is always working, no matter where they are. &nbsp;Right? &nbsp;That&#8217;s always how it works. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I was referring to the fact that we know the Senate is going to be here early next week. &nbsp;That wasn&#8217;t always the intention, as you all know. &nbsp;And so I just wanted to give you all a heads up about your own plans that we expect him to be here early days next week.<br>&nbsp;<br>Even as he goes to Delaware or Camp David, he will of course still be working. &nbsp;But we will, of course, provide&nbsp;<br>finalized details to you as soon as they’re made available.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Katie.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thanks. &nbsp;The number of migrant children arriving alone at the border continues to remain high each day. &nbsp;And they&#8217;re telling attorneys and advocates that they can wait as long as a month at least to talk to the sponsor or somebody in the United States or a family member. &nbsp;So is a month-long stay in detention acceptable to the President, given the ongoing pandemic and the spread of the variants?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, the &#8212; if the President were standing here today, he would tell you he always wants to shorten the length of time that unaccompanied children are waiting to go to sponsor homes or be connected with family members. &nbsp;And we have made a great deal of progress on reducing the number of hours, as you know, that children are in Border Patrol facilities, most importantly, and also reducing the amount of time and days they are in HHS facilities, where they do have access to educational resources, health resources, et cetera. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re always working to reduce that time. &nbsp;There is also another factor, which is vetting and ensuring that these children are going to homes that are safe and have gone through a review process. &nbsp;And certainly, we don&#8217;t want to expedite that over the point of where they would go &#8212; be going to harmful homes &#8212; not that you&#8217;re suggesting that, but that&#8217;s the factor. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, he&#8217;s always going to say he wants it to be faster. &nbsp;And he&#8217;s always pushing the system to ensure that&#8217;s the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And some of these children are also saying that at that these facilities they&#8217;ve gotten food poisoning and have had to wash their clothes in sinks. &nbsp;Is the President satisfied with the level of care they&#8217;re receiving at these facilities? &nbsp;Are there discussions to expand capacity, open new shelters, improve conditions? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I don&#8217;t know &#8212; are you referring to a specific facility? &nbsp;And I only ask that because there&#8217;s been an IG review over at Fort Bliss.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Pecos, Texas.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Okay, well, I would say that there has been &#8212; I&#8217;m not sure if that&#8217;s exactly the location, but there has been a review of Fort Bliss by the Inspector General, one that we&#8217;ve &#8212; our team at HHS has been participating in. &nbsp;And certainly, as conditions &#8212; as our HHS team is made aware of conditions that are problematic or concerning, we&#8217;ve &#8212; they have taken steps to address them, whether that is providing additional personnel, additional resources. &nbsp;That has been the ongoing case throughout the last several months, but we can see if there&#8217;s more details on that particular facility. &nbsp;Go ahead. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Just to follow up on Nancy’s question: You said no final decision has been made on the UI expiration, so that means that it’s a possibility that perhaps the President would ask for an extension at some point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, it&#8217;s planning to end &#8212; it&#8217;s supposed to end, at this point, at the beginning of September. &nbsp;So, he hasn&#8217;t made a decision to extend it; he also hasn&#8217;t made a decision not to. &nbsp;So, I suppose that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s correct. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Well, it gets to the question I actually wanted to ask, which &#8212; you guys have been really aggressive on the public health front. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;The President laid out today, I think, a series of six measures that kind of foamed the runway on the economic front &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;&#8212; as Delta has resurged. &nbsp;Is your economic team, right now, looking at perhaps new short-term measures to implement if the Delta variant drives the economy in the wrong direction?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, some of these factors we have been tracking and watching for some time, which is the supply &#8212; one of them is the supply chain impact. &nbsp;That&#8217;s on a domestic issue. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;ve seen, for example, in Malaysia and Vietnam, the rise of Delta in countries like Malaysia and Vietnam has impacted the supply chain, which of course impacts some industries here in the United States, including the car industry. &nbsp;That has been expedited by Delta but predates Delta to some degree as well. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We haven&#8217;t seen, to date, a direct impact on the economy from Delta, but we anticipate supply chain impacts and certainly know those would be factors.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will say that, as the President talked about earlier today, one of the &#8212; the way that we designed the American Rescue Plan and our economic recovery plans was to plan for the potential for ups and downs because we knew an economic recovery would include them. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I referenced earlier the Child Tax Credit benefits, which will go monthly through the course of this calendar year, but then additional benefits next year, which will help tens of millions of people. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, the assistance that&#8217;s going to schools &#8212; that goes out through the course of next year. &nbsp;So there are a number of benefits that don&#8217;t expire right now and weren&#8217;t meant to that will continue. &nbsp;But, of course, we will continue to monitor any impacts we see.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And then one more. &nbsp;A couple days ago, there was a U.S. bombing campaign in support in Afghanistan. &nbsp;Is it the administration&#8217;s intent that U.S. air support, as it pertains to helping the Afghan National Security Forces, will end at the end of this month? &nbsp;Or is there a possibility that short-term micro-campaigns like that will continue beyond?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;It&#8217;s a great question, Phil, and I would point you to the Department of Defense.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Jeff.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;I’m going to kick off with an international question as well. &nbsp;How closely, Jen, is the President and the White House following the war in Ethiopia? &nbsp;And are you concerned about the threats to a World Heritage site, which has just been taken over by forces from Tigray, not to mention the lives of the people there?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;We are, Jeff, following it quite closely. &nbsp;And, of course, the President is kept abreast of a range of global events happening during his PDB and by updates through his national security team. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, the State Department would be most closely engaged on the ground through our embassy and other officials, as we watch closely. &nbsp;But we are concerned about threats to the Heritage site and, of course, the threat to the people in Ethiopia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;All right. &nbsp;And one domestic one as well. &nbsp;The President said a few months ago, a few weeks ago &#8212; time is &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;It’s all running together.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;&#8212; that he wanted to have both the reconciliation bill and the infrastructure bill done at the same time. &nbsp;Then he walked that back a little bit. &nbsp;Speaker Pelosi is saying that she wants both votes to happen at the same time. &nbsp;What is your view of the timetable on those two votes? &nbsp;And are you concerned that one may thwart the other? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;We certainly trust the leadership of Speaker Pelosi and Leader Schumer. &nbsp;And we&#8217;ve seen Leader Schumer deliver on exactly what he promised to do, which was to move these forward during the summer session here. &nbsp;And the President intends to sign each of them into law. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thanks, Jen. &nbsp;The jobs report is getting a lot of praise today. &nbsp;But with the Delta variant surging, should Americans expect an economic slowdown? &nbsp;What&#8217;s the message from the White House to ordinary Americans who might be a little nervous moving forward?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I think, first, the message is: This is not March 2020 or even January 2021. &nbsp;We&#8217;re not going to lock down our economy or our schools because our country is in a much stronger place than when we took office, thanks to the President&#8217;s leadership in vaccinating the American people and getting economic relief to those who need it. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would say, yes, the topline number is very encouraging. &nbsp;But there are also very encouraging trends we saw in the numbers and encouraging number &#8212; encouraging data, including wages going up. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So there were a number of pieces of data in there that were positive. &nbsp;But we are not going back. &nbsp;We are not turning back the clock. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as I noted earlier, the other message is: We&#8217;ve been preparing like Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts for this moment and the potential that there would be ups and downs in our recovery, there would be ups and downs as we fight the virus. &nbsp;And that&#8217;s why a number of the programs were designed to extend for several months beyond this summer. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And one more on infrastructure: Do you expect the infrastructure plan to pass this weekend? &nbsp;And what role is the President playing in the process in this final stretch in the Senate?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, the President is always happy to pick up the phone, make calls, even when they&#8217;re not on his schedule. &nbsp;He usually does it on a, you know, moment&#8217;s notice, typically. &nbsp;He was in the Senate for 36 years, so quite comfortable for him. &nbsp;And he&#8217;s prepared to do that. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He will receive updates from his team on the progress. &nbsp;As you know, a number of members of the Senate are currently attending former Senator Enzi’s funeral today. &nbsp;But we expect things to proceed and look forward to getting updates of progress over the weekend. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Fran- &#8212; go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Oh, me?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Sorry. &nbsp;Sorry. &nbsp;Thank you so much. &nbsp;The White House recently asserted in a memo that swing voters want bipartisan infrastructure deal, and Democrats, as you know, have an extremely tight margin in the House. &nbsp;So why does the White House think that the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill will help lawmakers in the Democratic Party keep their seats in battleground congressional districts in the midterm elections?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, because the poll showed that 87 percent of battleground voters surveyed said they would be more likely to vote for a candidate who supports investing in our country&#8217;s infrastructure, helping grow our economy, and securing our supply chain, investing in American manufacturing. &nbsp;That&#8217;s exactly what the President&#8217;s agenda is, what the Build Back Better agenda is, what the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill is. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s also reflective of the fact that, for most people, the economy, making sure they have a good job, they&#8217;re getting through the pandemic is front and center. &nbsp;But that was reflected in the D-triple-C’s own poll. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And while the President may not be taking a vacation, he is in Delaware, and it&#8217;s a place that he goes often on the weekends. &nbsp;Why is it important for the President to visit his Delaware residence so frequently?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Because it&#8217;s his home. &nbsp;You like going home, right? &nbsp;So, does the President. &nbsp;He&#8217;s human too.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;In April, Ron Klain said the Education Department was reviewing whether the President could forgive student debt. &nbsp;He told us that it would be done in a few weeks. &nbsp;When can we expect that? &nbsp;We’re past &#8220;weeks.&#8221; &nbsp;We’re in August, and, just next month, the pause is going to end, as you know.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I don&#8217;t have an update on that. &nbsp;I will say that &#8212; and I &#8212; somebody asked this &#8212; it may have been you, but I don&#8217;t think it was &#8212; about also student loan forbearance, which is expected to expire at the end of September &#8212; slightly different but also hugely impactful. &nbsp;I expect we&#8217;ll have more on that soon as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And there are some insurance companies experts signaling that we may see vaccination status kind of be held against people when it comes to their insurance. &nbsp;Basically, if you chose not to get vaccinated, the leniency provided over the pandemic so far on costs, co-pays might go away. &nbsp;I&#8217;m curious if the administration has been talking to insurance companies about this and what your reaction is.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yeah, it&#8217;s an interesting question. &nbsp;I&#8217;d have to talk to our health team about that specifically. &nbsp;I haven&#8217;t had a chance to do that yet. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thanks, Jen. &nbsp;You just mentioned wages are going up in this jobs report. &nbsp;At what point do you worry that there might be inflation that is here for the longer term versus just in the short term right now?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, clearly, the inflation is the purview of the Federal Reserve. &nbsp;And we refer to their projections. &nbsp;As you know, they continued to project, and haven&#8217;t changed this, that while there will be an increase in inflation this year, they expect it to be transitory, and they expect it to come back to normal levels next year. &nbsp;That has not changed. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we knew that as the economy turned back on that could be a reality. &nbsp;But we rely on those projections, and we take it seriously and monitor it closely.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And just to follow up on the federal unemployment benefits: Is the White House willing to acknowledge that that might be a reason now that more workers are returning to the workforce after they&#8217;ve been expired now for a month and a half in some places?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;We don&#8217;t see any evidence in the available data that some states ending unemployment benefits early had any impact on today&#8217;s incredibly strong numbers. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are seeing strength across the economy and across states and regions, of course. &nbsp;But that&#8217;s thanks to a number of investments that have helped get people through this difficult time and get them back to work. &nbsp;We know there&#8217;s more that needs to happen, but we haven&#8217;t seen evidence of that data to date.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;What do you see as the main reason for this strengthened number today then?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Vaccinations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;With vaccine doses expiring in places like Alabama &#8212; tens of thousands have recently expired &#8212; what are the administration&#8217;s plans for continuing the push for vaccines while ensuring that places with low vaccination rates don&#8217;t have vaccine doses that go to waste?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, first, I would say that the number of doses that have gone to waste is only about 2.5 percent. &nbsp;Now, we don&#8217;t want any doses to go to waste, but that is a very low number. &nbsp;And we made some changes several weeks ago &#8212; even &#8212; maybe even more than that &#8212; where states and governors can order the number of doses they think they need. &nbsp;We also work with states and localities to ensure they are following best practices in order to get them out to communities to reduce the potential for any wastage.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But those efforts will continue, and certainly we want to do everything we can to reduce the wasting of doses.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, in the back. &nbsp;Go ahead. &nbsp;Go ahead, Patsy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you, Jen. &nbsp;I have a question on Iran and then a question on vaccinations. &nbsp;So, a CENTCOM investigation has concluded that the drone used in the Mercer Street tanker attack was produced in Iran. &nbsp;There&#8217;s a U.N. Security Council meeting on this today. &nbsp;What is the U.S. position? &nbsp;And what steps are you willing to take to hold Iran accountable? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, I have a different question on vaccines.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Okay. &nbsp;Well, this morning, U.S. Central Command issued a statement on the investigation into the July 30th unmanned aerial vehicle attack on the motor tanker Mercer Street. &nbsp;We concluded that &#8212; and it was noted in the statement, I should say &#8212; based on evidence, that this UAV was produced in Iran.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This comes as the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States, and the high representative of the European Union issued a statement standing united in our commitment to maritime security and the protection of commercial shipping. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As outlined in the statement, we condemn the unlawful attack committed on a merchant vessel off the coast of Oman on the 29th of July, which killed a British and Romanian national. &nbsp;This was a deliberate and targeted attack, and a clear violation of international law. &nbsp;We call on Iran to stop all activities inconsistent with relevant U.N. Security Council resolutions. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We know, as you noted, there is going to be some conversation up there. &nbsp;We call on all parties to play a constructive role in fostering regional stability and peace.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of any action, I would &#8212; I&#8217;m not in a position to preview that. &nbsp;Obviously, there&#8217;s discussion with the G7, with the U.N. Security Council, and others.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Okay. &nbsp;And a question on the vaccine: You&#8217;ve addressed &#8212; a couple of days ago &#8212; on the question on WHO urging wealthy countries to not provide booster shots &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;&#8212; until lower-income countries have had more vaccinations. &nbsp;And you said that the U.S. can do both. &nbsp;We can provide booster shots as well as help the world vaccinate its people.<br>&nbsp;<br>My follow-up to that is: In the determination of whether or not booster shots are needed, would the FDA include research or modeling on what is the more effective method to stop the emergence of new variants, whether it&#8217;s providing booster shots or maybe it&#8217;s better to &#8212; if we ship those vaccine doses to countries who need it, including like the 2.5 percent of the wasted doses that you just mentioned?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I&#8217;d certainly send you to the FDA, but I don&#8217;t think they look at things through that prism. &nbsp;But they&#8217;re evaluating whether there are portions of the population who may need the &#8212; a booster shot in order to be safely protected. &nbsp;They&#8217;re scientists, right? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I know that Dr. Fauci has obviously also referred recently &#8212; or maybe yesterday, today; it&#8217;s all running together &#8212; to that potential need as well. &nbsp;We&#8217;ll see what they decide for immunocompromised individuals, but that&#8217;s the recommendation that they will be making. &nbsp;<br>Go ahead, behind you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;No, no. &nbsp;Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;So, the last time we talked about debt and deficits, you noted that the President has proposed a way to pay for his proposals and that he cares about the future of the next generation. &nbsp;I&#8217;m wondering what the White House reaction is to a recent analysis by the Congressional Budget Office that predicts that the bipartisan infrastructure bill would add a quarter trillion dollars to the deficit over the next 10 years.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, the CBO analysis I assume you&#8217;re &#8212; you&#8217;re referring to?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Yes, ma&#8217;am. &nbsp;Yes, ma’am. &nbsp;Sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;No, no, of course. &nbsp;I thought &#8212; I thought I understood where you were coming from. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The CBO score, which projects a $30 billion deficit a year for eight years, does not count real savings agreed to on a bipartisan basis. &nbsp;That includes over $200 billion in lower costs for emergency programs, like paid leave, over the last year than CBO had originally estimated, and over $60 billion in higher spectrum revenue from a February auction than CBO had anticipated. &nbsp;Also, it doesn&#8217;t include the positive effects of the economic growth this package will drive on the budget.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, there&#8217;s strong evidence from a number of economists, including Moody&#8217;s, that infrastructure investment like this can in fact help pay for itself over the course of time and over the long run. &nbsp;And that&#8217;s something a number of leaders in the Senate are referring to.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And then, one more quick one. &nbsp;Yesterday, Secretary Cardona noted that the administration is working closely with teacher unions as they prepare for school openings this fall. &nbsp;I&#8217;m wondering: Are there any specific parent organizations that the administration is also partnering with?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;To help ensure schools opening? &nbsp;You know, that would &#8212; that is something certainly the Department of Education &#8212; they are working with a range of organizations to make sure they are educated, they have the information they need, they know what the mitigation measures are. &nbsp;I can certainly ask Secretary Cardona if there any specifics or get you in touch with the Department of Education. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Jen, I&#8217;d like to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;&#8212; follow up on that &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;&#8212; on the mask issue. &nbsp;With Secretary Cardona yesterday, he &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;&#8212; mentioned that, with Governor DeSantis, they were &#8212; he was concerned about the EO he did regarding public schools on masks. &nbsp;And he said, “We know what works.” &nbsp;But the &#8212; one of the President&#8217;s top COVID advisors, Michael Osterholm, just this &#8212; recently &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Who&#8217;s not a current advisor to the President, but &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Not a current, but &#8212; but was. &nbsp;So, notable, right?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Okay. &nbsp;Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;He said, in a television interview this week, regarding mask wearing &#8212; specifically the cloth masks, like so many of us are wearing here and what the kids are wearing in school &#8212; right? &#8212; largely. &nbsp;He said it&#8217;s a &#8212; that the scientific community has been doing a disservice to the public on face coverings. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He said that cloth masks like these have very &#8220;limited&#8221; impact on the amount of virus that you inhale or you exhale out. &nbsp;And he also said that he&#8217;s really disappointed in his colleagues for not making that more clear to the public. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s sort of in line with the study that Governor DeSantis is citing as the basis for his executive order. &nbsp;So how do you respond to that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I think you&#8217;re confusing a few things there. &nbsp;But let me first say that Osterholm is not an advisor to the President, to the administration, to the White House. &nbsp;He doesn&#8217;t work here. &nbsp;He&#8217;s a private citizen and a medical ex- &#8212; a public health expert. &nbsp;But a lot of public health experts are out there speaking, and good for them. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will say that we are going to continue to rely on the advice of medical experts in the federal government on what kind of masks we all should wear, what kind of masks kids should wear. &nbsp;And if they change that advice, then the Department of Education will be working with schools to make sure that&#8217;s implemented as a mitigation measure.<br>&nbsp;<br>The issue we have taken with the guidance of Governor DeSantis &#8212; which he, of course, is fundraising off of, I think we should note &#8212; is that he is preventing schools and teachers and others from protecting themselves and the students in their classroom. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as a mother myself, that&#8217;s concerning. &nbsp;And I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s concerning to mothers in Florida. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Now I want to &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I think we&#8217;re going to have to continue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;I have a &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;I have a follow-up on vaccine &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I think we’ve got to continue. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Everybody else got one. &nbsp;I have one more.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;You had a very long question. &nbsp;We&#8217;ve got to continue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;No, I have one more &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;&#8212; on vaccinations.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I’m sorry. &nbsp;I’m sorry. &nbsp;Emerald, we’re going to continue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;On the vaccine grants for India, what&#8217;s your understanding on why the jabs haven&#8217;t gotten into the arms in India? &nbsp;And is this failure only because of the indemnity that&#8217;s involved? &nbsp;Or is there a timeline that you can sketch out for us?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;As why more people are not vaccinated in &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Why haven’t the vaccines reached India? &nbsp;The U.S. &#8212; the grant that was announced. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I would say, first, that we have seen in some places that there are legal &#8212; legal issues or regulatory issues that need to be worked out country by country as we are delivering vaccines. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The holdup is not on this end, but we are eager to get vaccines and continued assistance to the people of India and want to continue to be a part of the arsenal of solving the pandemic.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And is there a timeline that has come out in the discussions when Secretary Blinken was in India?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yeah, it&#8217;s a great question. &nbsp;I would point you to the government of India and see if they have more updates. &nbsp;But we are eager to continue to be partners with them, to continue to provide assistance, including in the form of vaccines.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Raquel, go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you so much, Jen. &nbsp;Yesterday, the National Security Advisor met with the Brazilian President. &nbsp;And I want to know how &#8212; if you have more information about this meeting. &nbsp;What was the message that President Biden wants to convey with the Brazilian President with this meeting?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yeah, so National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and a delegation are in travel right now to Argentina. &nbsp;They concluded their trip to Brazil just yesterday. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And Mr. Sullivan did meet with President Bolsonaro. &nbsp;He reiterated that the U.S.-Brazil partnership is one of our most important relationships in the hemisphere. &nbsp;As the hemisphere&#8217;s two largest democracies, the United States and Brazil have a stake in each other&#8217;s successes &#8212; success, and we should be working together to advance ambitious climate goals, successfully combat the COVID-19 pandemic, and build back better in the region.<br>&nbsp;<br>And certainly, this, as the National Security Advisor&#8217;s first trip there, shows how important our relationship with Brazil and Argentina is.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Did he pressure President Bolsonaro on climate change, on deforestation? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And also, there are many investigations right now on the Brazilian President, including about his claims that there will be &#8212; be a fraud in the next Brazilian election next year. &nbsp;Did the White House also discuss this? &nbsp;Is this something that concerns this administration that puts democracy on the center of foreign policy as well? &nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, certainly, in any meeting, the National Security Advisor and any high-level representatives from the United States would advocate for democracy, for free elections &#8212; for free and fair elections around the world. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note, on climate change, as one of the &#8212; another one of the world&#8217;s &#8212; as are we &#8212; biggest emitters, certainly climate change, deforestation are always a part of the topics of conversation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I can see, Raquel, if there&#8217;s any more specifics that we can provide to you directly as well. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Shelby.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you, Jen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thanks, Jen. &nbsp;I wanted to ask &#8212; a little bit ago, it was reported that the emergency compound setup for COVID-positive migrants in McAllen expanded overnight, and there&#8217;s only the City of McAllen resources and manpower being used. &nbsp;So has the administration been in contact with officials in McAllen, Texas, on this &#8212; regarding the situation? &nbsp;And is the administration going to be helping provide relief?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I think part of &#8212; one, certainly, I believe, we have been in touch through the Department of Homeland Security. &nbsp;And the setup of this facility is meant to ensure we are taking steps to isolate and mitigate any spread of COVID. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we have measures in place that we maintain: Any migrant who is picked up by the Border Patrol is given PPE. &nbsp;They&#8217;re required to wear a mask. &nbsp;If they show any signs of illness, they are referred to local health systems for proper, appropriate testing.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that is part of what our &#8212; as a government &#8212; steps we are certainly taking. &nbsp;I can check and see, or I would point you to the Department of Homeland Security on any &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Is there &#8212; but is there anything additional?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;The Department of Homeland Security would be the best entity to talk to about any additional assistance or any new assistance that we&#8217;re providing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;I wanted to bring it back to cryptocurrency. &nbsp;So, some in the industry have said that the Portman-Warner-Sinema amendment includes language that could favor Bitcoin over other cryptocurrencies. &nbsp;Could you maybe address that?<br>&nbsp;<br>And if it came down to it, would the administration be willing to accept the Wyden amendment to move the broader package?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I think we &#8212; our objective here is to support and pass an infrastructure package into law. &nbsp;We have &#8212; we feel these negotiations and discussions about this issue and others have been done in good faith. &nbsp;And we are very grateful to Chairman Wyden for his leadership in pushing the Senate to address this issue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I noted a little earlier, we were pleased with the progress that has yielded a compromise, sponsored by Senators Warner, Portman, and Sinema, to advance the bipartisan infrastructure package and clarify the measure to reduce tax evasion. &nbsp;We will, of course, be closely monitoring and closely in touch as discussions continue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Josh, is that you?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;It is.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;How are you?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Very well. &nbsp;Very well.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;You didn’t raise your hand, but I haven’t seen you in here yet, so I&#8217;m just &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Well &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;It’s a Friday. &nbsp;Do you have a question?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Sure, why not. &nbsp;So, the administration is having the Justice Department defend the new eviction moratorium. &nbsp;Given that the President pretty openly mused about the fact that he wasn&#8217;t even sure whether this passed the constitutional muster and that a number of, you know, leading experts he&#8217;s consulted with feel it does not, isn&#8217;t he putting them in a pretty awkward position to be asking the Justice Department to defend something the President himself doesn&#8217;t necessarily believe is legal?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, the President would not have supported moving forward with this modified moratorium if he did not feel comfortable and confident in the legal backing. &nbsp;We believe that this is proper use of a lawful authority to protect the public health, and the Supreme Court has not ruled otherwise.<br>&nbsp;<br>We obviously don&#8217;t control the courts, but he asked &#8212; we asked our &#8212; our legal team, I should say, asked the CDC, the Department of Justice, and others to look into what options there would be. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is different from the national moratorium because it is more limited, it is focused on the areas that are most highly hit by COVID, and it is a short-term extension. &nbsp;Understand there&#8217;s going to be work happening in courts, but we certainly support and stand by the extension. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, all the way in the back &#8212; Yahoo.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Jen &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I&#8217;m just going to keep calling you &#8220;Yahoo.&#8221; &nbsp;Go ahead. &nbsp;(Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;That would be fine.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve spoken a lot about Ron DeSantis and Greg Abbott this week. &nbsp;Who are the two or three Republican governors who are getting things right, in the view of the White House, right now,<br>on COVID?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;There are a number. &nbsp;We&#8217;ve ca- &#8212; talked about Asa Hutchinson, who’s taken a number of steps. &nbsp;We&#8217;ve also talked about Governor Hogan in Maryland; I talked about him earlier today. &nbsp;I&#8217;ve talked about the governor of Massachusetts. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;ve said several times: The vast majority of governors &#8212; Republican governors are doing exactly the right thing. &nbsp;They&#8217;re putting public health, they&#8217;re putting policies first, and they&#8217;re saving lives in the process. &nbsp;And we&#8217;ve seen in a number of these states where they&#8217;ve taken these steps, the rates actually come down because it&#8217;s having an impact. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So that&#8217;s a positive sign. &nbsp;This is not political to us. &nbsp;We are going to continue to take steps to work with governors, leaders of all political stripes in order to prevent &#8212; end the pandemic. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Thanks, everyone. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Jen. &nbsp;Jen. &nbsp;Jen. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Jen, there&#8217;s &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Oh, I have one more person. &nbsp;I&#8217;m sorry. &nbsp;Go ahead, hello.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Hi, Jen. &nbsp;It’s Vanessa Tyler from the Black Information Network. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Hi, Vanessa.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;I wanted to ask you about voting rights. &nbsp;That&#8217;s a big concern for the listeners of the Black Information Network. &nbsp;Will the President make voting rights one of those filibuster exceptions? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And also, I wanted to know: What is his message to people who are really tired of waiting? &nbsp;Their patience is running out for many items on the agenda, like voting rights, like the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I would say his message, first, is: He&#8217;s with you, and that he is also tired of waiting. &nbsp;He believes voting rights is a fundamental right. &nbsp;It will be a fight of his presidency. &nbsp;And he would love to sign legislation on voting rights and the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act into law. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He is also, I would say, not waiting for that to happen in order to take action. &nbsp;He signed a historic executive order into law, during his first few weeks in office, to put in place additional protections.<br>&nbsp;<br>His Department of Justice has redoubled funding and efforts to ensure they&#8217;re supporting litigation across the country, and we&#8217;ve already seen them take action. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he has continued &#8212; and he has asked the Vice President to lead this effort. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the fight is continuing, it’s ongoing, and it is &#8212; certainly remains a priority for him and of his presidency.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you so &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;May I follow up and ask for &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Oh, go ahead. &nbsp;You have a follow-up. &nbsp;Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Will he push to make it a &#8212; one of those filidu- &#8212; filibuster-proofed exceptions &#8212; voting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, the filibuster is, of course, a Senate legislative tool, not a tool controlled by the President. &nbsp;He has not changed his position on that, but he is eager to sign a piece of legislation into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s ongoing discussions about that. &nbsp;We&#8217;re hopeful there&#8217;ll be progress. &nbsp;And he&#8217;s going to continue to use the White House, the bully pulpit. &nbsp;And, of course, the Vice President will be leading this effort moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;And (inaudible) &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Thanks so much. &nbsp;Very nice to meet you. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;All right. &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Thanks. &nbsp;Thanks, everyone. &nbsp;I&#8217;m sorry. &nbsp;We&#8217;ve got to wrap it up. &nbsp;Have a wonderful weekend.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>2:33 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden Extending the Pause on Student Loan&#160;Repayment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/06/statement-by-president-joe-biden-extending-the-pause-on-student-loan-repayment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 21:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On my first day in office in January, I directed the Department of Education to pause federal student loan repayments for millions of Americans through September. The pause has been a critical lifeline so they don’t have to choose between paying for basic necessities or their student loan during the pandemic that upended their lives.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On my first day in office in January, I directed the Department of Education to pause federal student loan repayments for millions of Americans through September. The pause has been a critical lifeline so they don’t have to choose between paying for basic necessities or their student loan during the pandemic that upended their lives.</p>



<p>As today’s jobs numbers show, we have the tools that will allow us to beat COVID-19 and keep our economy recovering at a record rate. But we know there is more work to do and the road will still be long for many people – especially for the one in six adults and one in three young people who have federal student loans.</p>



<p>That’s why today, my administration is extending the pause on federal student loan repayments one final time until January 31, 2022. This will give the Department of Education and borrowers more time and more certainty as they prepare to restart student loan payments. It will also ensure a smoother transition that minimizes loan defaults and delinquencies that hurt families and undermine our economic recovery.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the July Jobs&#160;Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/06/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-july-jobs-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 11:22 A.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning.&#160; What a good morning.&#160;&#160;Yesterday, the United States Senate took the additional step toward passing the bipartisan infrastructure bill.&#160; It’s a bill that would end years of gridlock in Washington, and create millions of good-paying jobs, and put America on a new path to win the race for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>11:22 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; What a good morning.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Yesterday, the United States Senate took the additional step toward passing the bipartisan infrastructure bill.&nbsp; It’s a bill that would end years of gridlock in Washington, and create millions of good-paying jobs, and put America on a new path to win the race for the economy in the 21st century<br>&nbsp;<br>A historic investment in roads and rail, in transit and bridges, in clean energy and clean water.&nbsp; It will enable us to not only build back, but build back better than before the economic crisis hit.<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank the bipartisan group of senators for working together and the committee chairs for raising their ideas and concerns with me and Vice President Harris and members of our Cabinet.<br>&nbsp;<br>As we did with the Transcontinental Railroad and the Interstate Highway System, we&#8217;ll soon, once again, transform America and propel us into the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>This bill makes key investments to put people to work all across the country &#8212; in cities, in towns, in rural communities, small towns, big towns, coastal &#8212; along the coastlines, and on plains.&nbsp; It covers the nation.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to put America to work in good-paying union jobs, building and repairing our roads, bridges, ports, airports.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, once this bill passes the Senate, I know that body will move toward establishing a framework for the remainder of my Build Back Better agenda &#8212; giving tax cuts to the middle class by investing in childcare and home care for seniors, critical investments to combat climate change and to build a clean energy future &#8212; vital steps needed to bring down the cost of healthcare and so much more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’re going to do it without raising taxes by even one cent on people making less than $400,000 a year.<br>&nbsp;<br>And here’s another important part of the bill: Ninety percent of the jobs created by this legislation will not require a college degree.&nbsp; Ninety percent.&nbsp; It’s a blue-collar blueprint to rebuild America.<br>&nbsp;<br>Which brings me to another piece of good news this morning:&nbsp; We learned that the economy created 943,000 new jobs in July &#8212; 943,000.&nbsp; And the unemployment rate fell by a half a percent to 5.4 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, while our economy is far from complete and while we have &#8212; doubtlessly we&#8217;ll have ups and downs along the way as we continue to battle the Delta surge of COVID, what is indisputable now is this: The Biden plan is working, the Biden plan produces results, and the Biden plan is moving the country forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re now the first administration in history to add jobs every single month in our first six months in office, and the only one in history to add more than 4 million jobs during the first six months.<br>&nbsp;<br>Economic growth is the fastest in 40 years.&nbsp; Jobs are up.&nbsp; The unemployment rate is the lowest since the pandemic hit.&nbsp; Black unemployment is down as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Why?&nbsp; Because we put in place the necessary tools early in my presidency &#8212; the COVID vaccine &#8212; the COVID-19 vaccine plan, the American Rescue Plan &#8212; to fight the virus and fight the economic mess we inherited.&nbsp; As a result, we’ve been able to make progress on both fronts against grave challenges.&nbsp; And we have &#8212; we put in place the tools to prevent this Delta variant wave of COVID-19 from shutting down our small businesses, our schools, and our society.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, when we first got to office, the COVID-19 crisis and economic crisis were unrelenting and devastating for people.&nbsp; And as a nation, we didn’t have to the tools to deal with either.&nbsp; Nearly 4,000 Americans were dying each and every day to the virus.&nbsp; Four thousand a day.&nbsp; The economy had been wiped out.&nbsp; We were down 10 million jobs from where we were before the pandemic.&nbsp; We were in a dark winter with real concerns about what spring would bring.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But then we got to work.&nbsp; We passed the American Rescue Plan shortly after I was sworn in.&nbsp; That gave us the tools to fight the pandemic and rebuild our economy, and it produced results.<br>&nbsp;<br>To beat the pandemic, we ramped up testing and protective equipment.&nbsp; And we bought it &#8212; we brought &#8212; we actually went out and bought enough vaccine so that every single, solitary American could be vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And because of the help of everyone, from the military to civilian efforts, we carried out one of the most difficult logistical challenges in our nation’s history to get 220 million shots into people’s arms in first 100 days in office.&nbsp; Two hundred and twenty million.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Over the past seven months, we&#8217;ve cut COVID-19 deaths by 90 percent.&nbsp; As of today, 193 million Americans have gotten at least one vaccination shot, including over 70 percent of adults over the age of 18.&nbsp; A hundred and sixty-five million Americans are now fully vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Because of our success with the vaccination effort, this new Delta variant wave of COVID-19 will be very different &#8212; be able to deal with than the one that under- &#8212; that we under- &#8212; was underway when I took office.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, yes, cases are going to go up before they come back down.&nbsp;&nbsp;It&#8217;s a pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp;&nbsp;I know I&#8217;ve said that constantly, and others have as well. &nbsp;The vaccation [sic] of the unvaccinated.&nbsp;&nbsp;You know, and it&#8217;s needless &#8212; taking a needless toll on our country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, we have, roughly, 350 million people vaccinated [doses administered] in the United States and billions around the world, and virtually no one has died because of that vaccinations.&nbsp;&nbsp;But even so, the impact is going to be very different than what happened last January.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, about 400 people will die because of the Delta variant in this country &#8212; a tragedy because virtually all of these deaths were preventable if people had gotten vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But seven months ago today, almost 4,000 people died on that very day from COVID-19.&nbsp; Four thousand versus four hundred.&nbsp; That shows how much our vaccination progress has already done to protect us from the worst of the new Delta COVID-19 wave.<br>&nbsp;<br>Likewise, the American Rescue Plan has given us the economic tools we need to protect our recovery against the worst impacts of the Delta virus: 1,400 checks into pockets &#8212; $1,400 checks into the pockets of millions of American; help to keep folks in their homes; help to put food on the table.<br>&nbsp;<br>Remember those long lines we used to talk about?&nbsp; People lined up in their cars for hours just to get a box of food put in their trunk.<br>&nbsp;<br>Help to small businesses so they could keep the lights on, their doors open, and their employees on the job.&nbsp; Because states were losing revenue.&nbsp; They were having to lay off essential workers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, the aid to states and cities and counties and Tribes, it kept essential workers going &#8212; police officers, firefighters, educators on the job.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Funding for schools to reopen, and ventilation systems, sanitation services, protective equipment to keep students and staff safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as we vaccinated America, we developed our economic tools to help our economy recover.&nbsp;&nbsp; As a result, in the past three months, we’ve created, on average, 832,000 new jobs per month since sworn in.&nbsp; That’s compared to five thou- &#8212; 50,000 jobs in the last three months of the previous administration.<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, even so, my message today is not one of celebration.&nbsp; It’s one to remind us we got a lot of hard work left to be done, both to beat the Delta variant and to continue our advance of economic recovery.&nbsp; We all know what it starts with.&nbsp; As I’ve said again and again, this is a pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; So we have to get more people vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>I said well over &#8212; what’s the number again? &nbsp;I have to remind myself &#8212; 350 million Americans have already been vaccinated [doses have been administered]. &nbsp;They’re doing fine.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’m pleased to report that, the past week, we’ve seen the first-time vaccinations in America go up by 4 million people getting vac- &#8212; 4 million shots.&nbsp; That’s more than we’ve seen in a long time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank the governors.&nbsp; I listened to the governor of Maryland today on the &#8212; on the television.&nbsp; He’s doing a heck of a job.&nbsp; Democratic governors as well, Republican governors &#8212; they’re getting the word out.</p>



<p>Look, as you all know, I’ve put in place new incentives and requirements to encourage vaccinations.&nbsp; For example, federal workers will be asked to attest to their vaccination status.&nbsp; Anyone who does not attest or is not vaccinated will be required to wear a mask no matter where they work, test one or two times a week, socially distance, and generally will not be allowed to travel for work.<br>&nbsp;<br>There will be more to come in the days ahead.&nbsp; And once again, I want to thank the local leaders and the private sector leaders who are imposing vaccine requirements.<br>&nbsp;<br>America can beat the Delta variant, just as we beat the original COVID-19.&nbsp; We can do this.&nbsp; So wear a mask where recommended.&nbsp; Get vaccinated today.&nbsp; All of that will save lives, and it means we’re not going to have the same kind of economic damage we’ve seen when COVID-19 began.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we aren’t stopping there.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan was built knowing the recovery would take time and that there’d be ups and downs.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, let me outline today six specific actions people will see over the next few weeks to make sure that we fight the Delta variant and wait for the new vaccinations to be finished and keep our economy strong.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, thanks to the latest middle-class tax cut in a long time, the next monthly check &#8212; that is the Child Tax Credit &#8212; in the next month &#8212; next nine days, checks are going &#8212; all going out to almost 40 million families with children &#8212; in nine days, beginning next month &#8212; the middle of this month, I should say.<br>&nbsp;<br>On August 15th, for example, a family with two young kids under the age of seven is going to get a check for $600 paid immediately.&nbsp; And they’ll get a check next week &#8212; next month for $600, et cetera.&nbsp; If you’re a family with two kids between the ages of 7 and 17, you’re getting a check for $500 &#8212; $250 per child.&nbsp; And that will continue month after month.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, I’ve looked ahead &#8212; we’ve looked ahead, and now schools have the resources they need to safely re-open as the schoolyear starts again so that every child can be in school full time, safe, in this year.<br>&nbsp;<br>Third, we provided, months ago, states and localities with $45 billion in their coffers &#8212; the state and localities &#8212; to help renters and landlords to keep people in their homes and keep their local economy strong.&nbsp; That money has to get out now.&nbsp; I’m urging all local (inaudible) to get that money out.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’re going to send more help to small businesses on Main Street so the Delta variant doesn’t cause them to lay off employees and shutter their doors.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There’s something called the Paycheck Protection Program.&nbsp; It’s a loan program &#8212; forgivable if a small business kept their employees on the job and their doors open.&nbsp; We’re now in the process to forgive those loans for small businesses who are doing the right thing, putting them in a better position to keep their businesses going.<br>&nbsp;<br>Fifth, if anyone is worried about getting health insurance during the pandemic, there’s help today.&nbsp; For those who get their health insurance through the Affordable Care Act, we’re covering more people with more extensive benefits, with premiums that average 40 percent lower.&nbsp; If you don’t have insurance, you can still sign up under the Affordable Care Act through August the 15th.&nbsp; Just go to HealthCare.gov today.<br>&nbsp;<br>And sixth, we’re going to lower the prices on everything from prescription drugs to hearing aids by allowing businesses to compete, which will give them more choices at lower costs.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example: You’re not going to have to go to a doctor to get a prescription to get a hearing aid.&nbsp; You’re going to go right to the counter of the store and buy it over the counter.<br>&nbsp;<br>The bottom line is this: What we are doing is working.&nbsp; But don’t take my word for it.&nbsp; Forecasters on Wall Street project: Over the next 10 years, our economy will expand by trillions of dollars and will create 2 million more jobs a year &#8212; good-paying jobs.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we just have to keep going.&nbsp; And it’s simple.&nbsp; That means: Get vaccinated, please.&nbsp; It’s safe.&nbsp; It works.&nbsp; It will save lives and maybe save your life.&nbsp; As I’ve said before, this is a pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; So, please, get vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>We can get this done.&nbsp; We just have to stay the course.&nbsp; And we just have to remember who we are.&nbsp; You’ve heard me say it before: We’re the United States of America.&nbsp; There’s not a single thing &#8212; nothing &#8212; beyond our capacity when we do it together.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; And have a good weekend.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>11:37 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces 10 Key&#160;Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/06/president-biden-announces-10-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 10 individuals to serve in key roles: David R. Gilmour, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Equatorial Guinea Scott Miller, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Swiss Confederation and to the Principality of Liechtenstein Marc R.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 10 individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>David R. Gilmour, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Equatorial Guinea</li><li>Scott Miller, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Swiss Confederation and to the Principality of Liechtenstein</li><li>Marc R. Stanley, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Argentine Republic</li><li>Sam Bagenstos, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Melissa Dalton, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Homeland Defense and Global Security Affairs, Department of Defense</li><li>Alexia Latortue, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for International Markets, Department of the Treasury</li><li>Brent Neiman, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary / Designated Assistant Secretary for International Finance and Development, Department of the Treasury</li><li>Alice Albright, Nominee for Chief Executive Officer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation</li><li>Todd Harper, Nominee for Chairman of the National Credit Union Administration</li><li>Owen Herrnstadt, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors, Export-Import Bank</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>David R. Gilmour, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Equatorial Guinea</u></strong></p>



<p>David R. Gilmour, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the Chargé d’Affaires a.i. at the U.S. Embassy in N’Djamena, Chad.&nbsp; He is a former U.S. Ambassador to the Togolese Republic.&nbsp; He has served in the Bureau of African Affairs at the Department of State as Deputy Assistant Secretary for Central Africa, Director of East African Affairs, and Director of Public Diplomacy for Africa.&nbsp; He was Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. embassies in Panama and Malawi, and Counselor for Public Affairs at the U.S. Mission in Geneva.&nbsp; Other overseas assignments include Australia, Costa Rica, South Africa and Cameroon.&nbsp; He is the recipient of numerous awards, including Partnership Excellence Award from the Secretary of State’s Office of Global Partnerships.&nbsp; Gilmour received a B.A. from Saginaw Valley State University in Michigan, and an M.A. from the University of Texas at Austin.&nbsp; He speaks French and Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Scott Miller, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Swiss Confederation and to the Principality of Liechtenstein</u></strong></p>



<p>Scott Miller is an LGBTQ rights activist and philanthropist.&nbsp; As co-chair of the Gill Foundation’s board of directors, Miller directs the foundation’s national giving strategy to advance LGBTQ equality, including public education campaigns to ban conversion therapy and end discrimination against LGBTQ Americans.&nbsp; At the foundation, Miller also oversees local efforts to ensure equal opportunity for all Coloradans, including generous support for K-12 STEM education at numerous Colorado public schools.&nbsp; During the pandemic, Miller led efforts to provide over 5.6 million meals to tens of thousands of his fellow Coloradans to alleviate food insecurity.&nbsp; Together Miller and his husband, Tim Gill, are among the top contributors to LGBTQ equality issues in the United States.&nbsp; Previously, Miller served as an account vice president at UBS Wealth Management in Denver, Colorado.&nbsp; Miller earned a Bachelor of Science degree with honors in business administration from the University of Colorado Boulder.&nbsp; Upon graduation, he started his career as a management consultant for Accenture, followed by work as an event planner for global clientele.</p>



<p><strong><u>Marc R. Stanley, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Argentine Republic</u></strong></p>



<p>Marc R. Stanley is President of the Stanley Law Group and a board-certified civil trial lawyer in Dallas, Texas.&nbsp; A former president of the Texas Trial Lawyers Association and the Dallas Trial Lawyers Association, Stanley has served in leadership positions in dozens of local and national charitable and civic organizations throughout his career.&nbsp; He was a Council Member of the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum in Washington, D.C. and a Member of the Board of Visitors at the United States Air Force Air University at Maxwell Air Force Base in Montgomery, Alabama.&nbsp;&nbsp; He served for four years as Chairman of the Texas Public Finance Authority and was Co-Chair of the Mayor’s Complete Count Outreach Committee for the U.S Census (City of Dallas).&nbsp; Stanley earned a B.B.A. at George Washington University, and a J.D. at the University of Texas-Austin.&nbsp; He is the recipient of numerous awards, including the Tikkun Olam Award by the Jewish Council for Public Affairs.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sam Bagenstos, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of Health and Human Services</u></strong></p>



<p>Samuel R. Bagenstos currently serves as General Counsel to the Office of Management and Budget.&nbsp; He is on leave from his position as the Frank G. Millard Professor of Law at the University of Michigan Law School.&nbsp; From 2009 to 2011, Bagenstos served as a political appointee in the Obama-Biden Administration&#8217;s Department of Justice, where he was Principal Deputy Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights.&nbsp; Pursuant to an appointment by Governor Gretchen Whitmer, he chaired the Michigan Employment Relations Commission from 2019 to 2021.&nbsp; An expert in civil rights law, Bagenstos wrote the leading law school casebook on disability rights law and has engaged with state Medicaid systems as a lawyer, advocate, and consultant to promote community-based services for individuals with disabilities.&nbsp; He has argued four cases in the Supreme Court of the United States, including key matters under the Americans with Disabilities Act as well as Young v. UPS, a case that established new protections for pregnant workers.&nbsp; A graduate of the University of North Carolina and the Harvard Law School, Bagenstos clerked for Judge Stephen Reinhardt on the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit and Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg on the Supreme Court of the United States.</p>



<p><strong><u>Melissa Dalton, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Homeland Defense and Global Security Affairs, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Melissa G. Dalton is currently the Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Strategy, Plans, and Capabilities at the U.S. Department of Defense. She is responsible for advising the Secretary of Defense and other senior defense leaders on national security and defense strategy; the forces, contingency plans, and associated posture necessary to implement the defense strategy; nuclear deterrence and missile defense policy; and security cooperation plans and policies. Prior to her appointment to the Biden-Harris Administration in January 2021, Ms. Dalton was a senior fellow and deputy director of the Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) International Security Program and director of the Cooperative Defense Project. Her CSIS research focused on reinforcing the principled foundations of U.S. defense strategy and military operations, including the responsible role of the U.S. military in Defense Support of Civil Authorities. Prior to joining CSIS in 2014, Ms. Dalton served for a decade as a career civil servant in the Bush and Obama Administrations at DoD. Her assignments included senior advisor for force planning, special assistant to the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy, policy adviser to the commander of the International Security Assistance Force in Kabul, Afghanistan, and country director for Lebanon and Syria in the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy. She also served as an intelligence analyst at the Defense Intelligence Agency.</p>



<p><strong><u>Alexia Latortue, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for International Markets, Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Alexia Latortue is Deputy Chief Executive Offer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation where she helps shape MCC’s strategic vision, oversees the agency’s operations to deliver on programmatic priorities and leads the team. Ms. Latortue has over 20 years of experience in international development, with a focus on development finance, policy and making markets work for all people. Her work has covered private sector development, financial systems development, climate, infrastructure and economic inclusion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ms. Latortue was previously Managing Director for Corporate Strategy and a member of the Executive Committee of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD). Prior to joining the EBRD, she served as the Obama-Biden Administration as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for International Development Policy at the Department of the Treasury, advancing inclusive growth and poverty reduction internationally through the multilateral development banks. Previously, Ms. Latortue spent 10 years with the World Bank where her last assignment was Deputy CEO of CGAP, a unit dedicated to advancing financial inclusion. She began her career with Development Alternatives, Inc.</p>



<p>Ms. Latortue earned a M.A. from the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy at Tufts University and a B.S. from Georgetown University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Brent Neiman, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary / Designated Assistant Secretary for International Finance and Development, Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Brent Neiman is the Edward Eagle Brown Professor of Economics at the University of Chicago’s Booth School of Business. His teaching and research focus on international macroeconomics, finance, and trade. He is a co-founder of the Global Capital Allocation Project and serves as the director of the Initiative on International Economics at the Becker Friedman Institute and a co-director of the Initiative for Global Markets at Chicago Booth. He is a research associate at the National Bureau of Economic Research, a research fellow at the Center for Economic Policy Research, and is an associate editor of The American Economic Review, The Quarterly Journal of Economics, and The Journal of International Economics.</p>



<p>Neiman previously served as the staff economist for international finance on the White House Council of Economic Advisers and has worked at the Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago, at McKinsey and Company, and at the McKinsey Global Institute. He earned a Bachelor of Science in Economics and a Bachelor of Applied Science from the University of Pennsylvania. He earned a master’s degree in mathematical modelling from Oxford University, where he was a Thouron Scholar, and received his PhD in economics from Harvard University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Alice Albright, Nominee for Chief Executive Officer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation</u></strong></p>



<p>Alice Albright serves as the Chief Executive Officer of the Global Partnership for Education, a multilateral partnership and fund dedicated to improving education outcomes for the most marginalized children in low income countries. Before joining GPE, Ms. Albright served in the Obama-Biden Administration from 2009 to 2013 as the Executive Vice President &amp; Chief Operating Officer of the Export-Import Bank of the United States. From 2001 to 2009, Ms. Albright served as the Chief Financial and Investment Officer for the Global Alliance for Vaccines and Immunization. While there, Ms. Albright led GAVI&#8217;s innovative finance efforts, including the launch the International Finance Facility for Immunization, a program to enhance GAVI&#8217;s ability to finance the purchase of vaccines. Previously, Ms. Albright worked as a banker with a focus on emerging markets and held a variety of positions at Citicorp, Bankers Trust Company, JP Morgan, and the Carlyle Group.</p>



<p>Ms. Albright has served on a number of boards and working groups in the development, education, and gender arenas. Currently, she serves on the UK’s G7 Gender Equality Advisory Council, the Board of Williams College, and the UNESCO Institute of Statistics. She is a member of the Council on Foreign Relations. She has been decorated as an Officier de L’Order de L’Etalon by President Kabore and a Commandeur, Ordre National du Lion by President Macky Sall.</p>



<p>Ms. Albright graduated from Williams College with a BA in History, with honors, and received an MIA from Columbia University&#8217;s School of International and Public Affairs. She is also a Chartered Financial Analyst.</p>



<p><strong><u>Todd Harper, Nominee for Chairman of the National Credit Union Administration</u></strong></p>



<p>Todd Harper has specialized in financial services policy during his more than 25 years of government service and has led the NCUA Board as Chairman since January 2021. He also chairs the interagency Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council. Mr. Harper joined the NCUA Board in April 2019 and is the first NCUA staffer to become a Board Member and Chairman. From 2011 to 2017, he led the agency’s Office of Public and Congressional Affairs and served as the chief policy advisor to two NCUA Chairmen. Previously, as staff director for the Subcommittee on Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises in the U.S. House of Representatives, Mr. Harper contributed to the efforts after the financial crisis to enact the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act. As legislative director to former Congressman Paul E. Kanjorski of Pennsylvania, he also worked on bipartisan legislation concerning credit union capital rules, terrorism risk insurance, auditing standards and subprime mortgage lending. A member of the LGBTQ community, Mr. Harper earned an M.P.P. from Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Government and a B.S. with high distinction in business analysis from Indiana University’s Kelley School of Business.</p>



<p><strong><u>Owen Herrnstadt, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors, Export-Import Bank</u></strong></p>



<p>Owen Herrnstadt is the Chief of Staff to the International President and Director of Trade and Globalization at the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers. As Chief of Staff, he assists in running one of the largest manufacturing and transportation unions in the United States. As Director of Trade and Globalization, he develops policy for international trade, economic investment, international labor standards, and human rights matters. He also teaches employment and labor law at the Georgetown University Law Center and has taught international employment and labor at American University’s Washington College of Law.</p>



<p>Mr. Herrnstadt is a member of the Council on Foreign Relations, Independent Mexico Labor Expert Board, U.S. Export-Import Bank Federal Advisory Committee, and the U.S. State Department Federal Advisory Committee on International Economics. He also served as Co-Chair of the State Department’s Stakeholder Advisory Board on OECD Guidelines and  as Chair of the Board of Directors of the Baltimore Branch of the Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond. He has testified, written articles and made presentations on labor and employment law, international employment and labor law, corporate social responsibility, trade, manufacturing policy, human rights, and industrial relations in the U.S. and abroad.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Export Control&#160;Regulations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/08/06/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-export-control-regulations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice, stating that the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13222 of August&nbsp;17, 2001, in light of the expiration of the Export Administration Act of 1979, is to continue in effect for 1 year beyond August 17, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Export Control&#160;Regulations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/08/06/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-export-control-regulations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On August 17, 2001, the President issued Executive Order&#160;13222 pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.).&#160; In that order, the President declared a national emergency with respect to the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States related to the expiration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On August 17, 2001, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13222 pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.)</em>.&nbsp; In that order, the President declared a national emergency with respect to the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States related to the expiration of the Export Administration Act of 1979, as amended.&nbsp; Because the implementation of certain sanctions authorities, including sections 11A, 11B, and 11C of such Export Administration Act of 1979, consistent with section 1766(b) of Public Law 115-232, the Export Control Reform Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 4601 note), is to be carried out under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, the national emergency declared on August 17, 2001, must continue in effect beyond August 17, 2021.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13222, as amended by Executive Order 13637 of March 8, 2013.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>August 6, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Bills Signed: H.R. 208, H.R. 264, H.R. 772, H.R.&#160;1002</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/06/press-release-bills-signed-h-r-208-h-r-264-h-r-772-h-r-1002/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 16:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26441</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, August 6, 2021, the President signed into law: H.R. 208, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 500 West Main Street, Suite 102 in Tupelo, Mississippi, as the Colonel Carlyle &#8220;Smitty&#8221; Harris Post Office; H.R. 264, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 1101&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, August 6, 2021, the President signed into law:<br><br>H.R. 208, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 500 West Main Street, Suite 102 in Tupelo, Mississippi, as the Colonel Carlyle &#8220;Smitty&#8221; Harris Post Office;<br><br>H.R. 264, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 1101 Charlotte Street in Georgetown, South Carolina, as the Joseph Hayne Rainey Memorial Post Office Building;<br><br>H.R. 772, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 229 Minnetonka Avenue South in Wayzata, Minnesota, as the Jim Ramstad Post Office; and<br><br>H.R. 1002, the &#8220;Debarment Enforcement of Bad Actor Registrants Act of 2021 or the DEBAR Act of 2021,&#8221; which authorizes the Attorney General to issue an order to prohibit any person from being registered to manufacture, distribute, or dispense controlled substances under certain circumstances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meetings with Landlords and Tenant&#160;Advocates</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/06/readout-of-white-house-meetings-with-landlords-and-tenant-advocates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 13:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling and Special Assistant to the President for Housing and Urban Policy Erika Poethig, along with other Biden-Harris Administration officials, held virtual listening sessions with groups representing landlords and tenant advocates to discuss state and local disbursement of emergency rental assistance funds and ways to protect&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling and Special Assistant to the President for Housing and Urban Policy Erika Poethig, along with other Biden-Harris Administration officials, held virtual listening sessions with groups representing landlords and tenant advocates to discuss state and local disbursement of emergency rental assistance funds and ways to protect renters from eviction.</p>



<p>Administration officials communicated the need for landlords to accept rental assistance before pursuing evictions. They also received feedback on strengths and weaknesses of state and local rental assistance programs as well as ways the Administration can work with governors and mayors to expedite the release of rental assistance funds. Landlords also offered their feedback on how grantees might speed delivery and increase access to rental assistance.&nbsp; In their discussions with tenant advocates, Administration officials also heard about the challenges renters are facing in accessing emergency rental assistance funds. They also shared examples of where evictions are proceeding and ways to promote eviction diversion strategies.</p>



<p>In both meetings, Administration officials reiterated the commitment made by President Biden that his Administration will not rest—nor should state and local governments—until emergency rental assistance dollars reach Americans in need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The meetings with these groups are part of continued engagement by the Administration to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/fact-sheet-companies-non-profits-government-agencies-answer-biden-harris-call-make-combined-commitment-to-alert-tens-of-millions-of-americans-to-emergency-rental-assistance/">raise awareness among tenants and landlords</a> on available resources and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initiatives-to-promote-housing-stability-by-supporting-vulnerable-tenants-and-preventing-foreclosures/">increase the pace of distribution</a> of the billions in emergency rental assistance that is available to state and local governments to prevent evictions and make landlords whole.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
