<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 19:07:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meetings with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy and Diplomatic Advisor to the Prime Minister Luigi&#160;Mattiolo</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meetings-with-prime-minister-mario-draghi-of-italy-and-diplomatic-advisor-to-the-prime-minister-luigi-mattiolo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 19:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On March 15, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met in Rome with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy to discuss international cooperation in response to Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. This followed Mr. Sullivan’s meeting with Luigi Mattiolo, Diplomatic Advisor to the Prime Minister. The two senior officials discussed continued measures, including in coordination with the G7&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On March 15, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met in Rome with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy to discuss international cooperation in response to Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. This followed Mr. Sullivan’s meeting with Luigi Mattiolo, Diplomatic Advisor to the Prime Minister. The two senior officials discussed continued measures, including in coordination with the G7 and EU, to impose costs on Russia for its war on Ukraine and to provide humanitarian assistance to those fleeing the conflict. They also talked about U.S. support for European efforts to establish alternative energy sources.  In addition, the two sides discussed Transatlantic approaches to the People’s Republic of China, as well as further enhancement of the US-Italian relations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the President’s Travel to&#160;Belgium</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-presidents-travel-to-belgium/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 18:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to Brussels, Belgium later this month. President Biden will join an extraordinary NATO summit on March 24 to discuss ongoing deterrence and defense efforts in response to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack on Ukraine as well as to reaffirm our ironclad commitment to our NATO Allies. President Biden&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to Brussels, Belgium later this month. President Biden will join an extraordinary NATO summit on March 24 to discuss ongoing deterrence and defense efforts in response to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack on Ukraine as well as to reaffirm our ironclad commitment to our NATO Allies. President Biden will also join a scheduled European Council Summit to discuss our shared concerns about Ukraine, including transatlantic efforts to impose economic costs on Russia, provide humanitarian support to those affected by the violence, and address other challenges related to the conflict.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on COVID Response and Funding&#160;Needs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/15/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-covid-response-and-funding-needs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:36 A.M. EDT      MR. MUNOZ:  Hey, everybody.  Thanks you for joining us &#8212; Happy Tuesday &#8212; for this press call today.  We are going to outline the consequences that a lack of COVID-19 response funding will have on the United States if Congress fails to act.      The call and the accompanying&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>10:36 A.M. EDT<br><br>     MR. MUNOZ:  Hey, everybody.  Thanks you for joining us &#8212; Happy Tuesday &#8212; for this press call today.  We are going to outline the consequences that a lack of COVID-19 response funding will have on the United States if Congress fails to act.<br><br>     The call and the accompanying factsheet that you all just received before this will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and embargoed until 11:30 a.m. Eastern.<br><br>     On today’s call, we have [senior administration officials].<br><br>     With that, I will kick it to [senior administration official] for some opening remarks.<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Kevin.  Good morning, everyone.  Thanks for joining us.<br><br>Today, we want to cover the consequences of a lack of additional funding for the nation’s COVID response.<br><br>I’ll discuss the near-term impacts, and then I’ll turn to [senior administration official] to discuss the impacts on our longer-term preparedness.<br><br>First, I want to step back and provide some context on how we view this moment in the pandemic.<br><br>Over the past 14 months, the country has made critical investments, using resources that Congress provided on a bipartisan basis, to make sure the American people have access to free and widely available tools: vaccines, boosters, treatments, tests, and high-quality masks.<br><br>As a result, the U.S. has made tremendous progress: Cases are down 95 percent since the peak of Omicron.  Hospitalizations are down 85 percent.  Over 215 million Americans are fully vaccinated, and over 95 million Americans have received a booster shot.<br><br>But as the President said in the State of the Union, we still have more work to do.<br><br>Our scientific and medical experts have been clear that in the next couple of months we could see COVID cases increase here in the U.S., just as we’re seeing cases rising abroad right now.<br><br>That’s why we remain laser-focused on fighting COVID and preparing for the future.<br><br>The President has laid out a comprehensive National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan to continue the progress we’ve made and to ensure we keep the country moving forward safely.<br><br>We asked for immediate funding needed to start to implement that plan.<br><br>In fact, for months, we’ve made clear to Congress, on a bipartisan basis, that the funding for tests, treatments, and vaccines was drying up and that additional funds would be needed.<br><br>In January, we notified the Hill that funding would be needed after the Omicron surge.  In February, we briefed appropriators and authorizers about the status of funds and the consequences if there were no additional funds.<br><br>We sent a formal request of $22.5 billion to the Hill, again being clear of what we could not do without more funding.<br><br>The President called for additional funding in his State of the Union address; outlined in a 96-page plan, made clear that more funding is needed. <br><br>And our team has held more than two dozen calls and meetings with members of Congress about this emergency funding request. <br><br>We have been clear: We hoped Congress would provide these resources, as lawmakers have done multiple times on a bipartisan basis under the prior administration.<br><br>Further inaction will set us back; leave us unprepared &#8212; less prepared; and cost us more lives.<br><br>We need Congress to provide the $22.5 billion in emergency immediate funding.<br><br>Now, let me walk through some of the immediate consequences of a lack of funding.<br><br>First, on vaccines: Without additional funding, we do not have the adequate resources to purchase enough booster shots for all Americans if an additional shot is needed.<br><br>Keep in mind, when Congress passed the supplemental bill in December of 2020 and the American Rescue Plan, the mRNA vaccines were envisioned as a two-shot vaccine.  We’ve now administered nearly 100 million booster shots, and four shots are now recommended and available for immunocompromised people.<br><br>To ensure enough fourth doses for all Americans or a variant-specific vaccine should we ever need them, we must have funding in hand.<br><br>Vaccines are our most effective tool.  We cannot be caught without the ability to move quickly to get more of the most effective vaccines available as soon as we are able.<br><br>Next, on treatments: To date, we have shipped over 7 million courses of treatments to the American people.  And in many cases, we have sent federal medical personnel to states to help administer those treatments.  When Omicron hit, the federal government stepped in to ramp up delivery of the last remaining treatment that worked.<br><br>These efforts have saved lives in every state in the country.<br><br>We have planned &#8212; we had planned to purchase additional monoclonals as soon as next week.  Without additional funding, we are cancelling those plans.  And as we will make clear to governors later this morning, we also need to cut the number of monoclonal antibody treatments we send to states by 30 percent starting next week.<br><br>Even with these cuts, we anticipate that our supply of monoclonal antibody treatments will run out as soon as late May.<br><br>Next, on the preventative treatments for immunocompromised Americans: We have purchased 1.7 million doses of AstraZeneca’s Evusheld &#8212; all that they could produce to date.<br><br>AstraZeneca recently told us that they will be &#8212; they will have additional supply that will be available for delivery starting in September.  These are doses we had planned to purchase as soon as the end of March.<br><br>Without more funding, the federal government will now be forced to scale back on that purchase.  So, we’ll likely run out of treatments for our most vulnerable Americans by the end of the year, if not sooner.<br><br>The bottom line on treatments is this: Without additional funding soon, thousands of patients could lose access to treatments, and these companies will have little incentive to continue investing in the development and manufacturing of these treatments.<br><br>Next, on the uninsured fund: <s>The Office of Management and Budget</s> [The Administration] notified Congress in February that this fund that reimburses doctors and other medical providers for caring for uninsured individuals was running out of money and would have to stop taking new claims in March.<br><br>Unfortunately, we’re now having to take that action.<br><br>HHS will begin to scale back this program starting next week and end it completely in early April.<br><br>This means doctors, nurses, pharmacists, labs, and other healthcare providers will no longer be reimbursed for tests, treatments, and vaccinations for people without health insurance.<br><br>And finally, in addition to all of these impacts to our domestic response, the lack of funding greatly impacts our global response.<br><br>Without more funding, USAID and our interagency partners will have to cut short efforts to turn vaccines into vaccinations around the world.<br><br>In fact, the administration won’t be able to extend surge support to over 20 additional under-vaccinated countries that will need intensive support this year to get shots in arms.<br><br>This will devastate our ability to ensure these countries can effectively deploy safe and effective vaccines.  And leaving large unvaccinated populations worldwide will increase the risk of new deadly emerging &#8212; of variants emerging that could evade our current vaccines and treatments. <br><br>Without additional funding, USAID will also be unable to provide lifesaving supplies, tests, therapeutics, oxygen, and other humanitarian aid to countries still struggling to manage a continued COVID disease burden.<br><br>Now, I’ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to discuss some of the long-term preparedness efforts at risk.  [Senior administration official]?<br><br>One second.<br><br>[Senior administration official], can you unmute?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  [Senior administration official], do you have me now?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  I got you.  Go for it.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Oh, my goodness.  Okay, sorry about that.<br><br>All right.  So, thanks, [senior administration official].  Thanks, everybody.  Let me also start with vaccines.<br><br>Without additional support from Congress, NIH and BARDA will lack the funding needed to accelerate research and development of next-generation vaccines that provide broader and more durable protection, including a vaccine that protects against a range of variants.<br><br>We’ll face a similar challenge on treatments.  The current antivirals require multiple pills over several days.  We think it’s possible to get treatment courses down to one or two pills, but that requires additional research and funding.<br><br>And when a new vaccine or treatment becomes available, it’s important for us to have the funding to secure enough doses for the American people.<br><br>Over the past 14 months, we’ve put the massive purchasing power of the federal government to use, making sure America is first in line for promising treatments.<br><br>That’s the reason we’ve been able to secure more Pfizer antiviral pills than anyone else in the world.  These pills cut the risk of hospitalization and death by 90 percent.<br><br>Without additional funding, we lack the resources needed to get behind promising new treatments, meaning less supply available to the American people.<br><br>So the failure to invest in the research and the advanced purchase of lifesaving treatments and new vaccines now will leave the nation vulnerable in the face of a new variant or a new surge.<br><br>Finally, on testing: We have significantly increased our testing capacity in this country through targeted federal investments.<br><br>Without additional funding, we do not have the ability to maintain our domestic testing capacity beyond June.<br><br>So, after spending the last year building up our testing capacity, Congress now risks squandering that capacity heading into the second half of this year. <br><br>And because it takes months of ramp-up to rebuild capacity, failure to invest now will leave us less prepared for any potential future surges.  So providing funding only when cases rise is far too late to make a difference.<br><br>Bottom line: We need funding now so we’re prepared for whatever comes next.<br><br>With that, back over to you, [senior administration official].<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, [senior administration official].  Let me just close with a few thoughts here.<br><br>We have been clear-eyed and we are clear-eyed moving forward about how unpredictable this virus has been and can be moving forward.<br><br>Omicron was the most contagious variant we’ve ever seen.  It led to an unprecedented increase in cases.  But because we had the resources, we were able to surge support to Americans that needed it.<br><br>We sent tests to homes, masks to pharmacies, over 2,500 federal personnel to states, more treatments to providers.  We kept our businesses open and almost all of our kids learning in person. <br><br>That was because we had resources at our disposal to act and to act quickly. <br><br>We have a plan to keep it that way, but we need the resources to execute that plan. <br><br>The failure to provide additional resources soon will have severe consequences in the near term, as I’ve outlined: fewer monoclonal antibodies treatments, fewer tests, fewer treatments for the immunocompromised, and a risk of running short on vaccines.<br><br>We want to be clear: Waiting to provide funding until we’re in a worse spot with the virus will be too late.<br><br>Importantly, when you consider the cost of all these investments compared to the cost of what we will prevent &#8212; in terms of hospitalizations, deaths, and damage to our healthcare system and our economy &#8212; it is not a close call.<br><br>With that. let&#8217;s open up for questions. <br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Thanks.  We have time for a few questions.  First, let&#8217;s go to Josh Wingrove at Bloomberg. <br><br>Q    Hi there.  Thank you.  Can you tell us a little bit more about the monoclonal order in terms of the scale?  Like how many were you planning to order?  If you don&#8217;t order it now, do you lose your spot in line?  And, you know, if new funding came in the following weeks, would you still be able to place that order?<br><br>And, more broadly, you mentioned, on fourth shots &#8212; can you specify: Right now, you think you have enough for immunocompromised people that are currently eligible, but without new funding, you might not have enough in the event that the broader population would need a fourth shot or be given the option to get a fourth shot? <br><br>Thank you. <br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Josh.  I&#8217;ll start, and maybe, [senior administration official], you can add.<br><br>On your first question on monoclonals, the purchase was likely to be in the hundreds of thousands of more doses.  We had planned to place that order next week on March 25th. <br><br>I can&#8217;t say whether those &#8212; you&#8217;d have to ask the company whether those would be available to us if we purchased at a later date.  That was the plan.  And as we know, these are &#8212; these are treatments that are highly sought after not just in this country but in other countries. <br><br>And so, we have to end that purchase and we have to reduce the allocations to our states by 30 percent but that we&#8217;re stretching out the supply as long as we possibly can. <br><br>On the fourth shot, we have enough now for immunocompromised individuals who need to seek a fourth shot.  What we don&#8217;t have the funding for is if all Americans were needed to get an additional dose, we would need additional funding from Congress. <br><br>And importantly, Josh, I would add that if we need a variant-specific testing, which heretofore we have been lucky enough not to need, but we want to be ready for that.  And if we need a new vaccine, we have &#8212; our gap in resources is even more severe if we need a variant-specific vaccine. <br><br>{Senior administration official}, anything you would add?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Sure, [senior administration official].  Thank you.  I think you said it exactly right. <br><br>The other thing I would just add is we have to make these purchases now so the product is available in the coming months.  It requires several months for some of the manufacturing to take place.  So, to secure our place in line, we have to make the purchases now to bring these doses forward in the coming weeks to months. <br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Thanks.  Next question.  Let&#8217;s go to Jeremy Diamond at CNN. <br><br>Q    Hey, thanks very much for doing this.  Just searching for some more concrete numbers on the testing front.  What are we at now in terms of tests per month?  And how would that number be impacted after June?<br><br>And then secondly, if there were to be a game-changing variant spreading wildly in the U.S., you know, say, tomorrow, is the U.S. prepared for that?<br><br>And after which point in time would we not be prepared without additional funding?<br><br>Thanks. <br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Jeremy.  It&#8217;s a good question. <br><br>On tests per month, we&#8217;re in the hundreds of millions of tests per month now.  That&#8217;s because of the investments over the last 14 months in getting to that point. <br><br>We don&#8217;t know, after June, if we can maintain the domestic manufacturing capabilities that we have today.  In fact, we were told by the domestic test manufacturers that they cannot.  We&#8217;ve made investments to get us to June.  We need additional funding from Congress to not lose the gains that we&#8217;ve made over the last 14 months in the domestic testing manufacturing. <br><br>So, it&#8217;s vitally important that we continue that manufacturing so we don&#8217;t lose everything that we&#8217;ve done in over-the-counter testing in the last year. <br><br>On variants, look, what I can say, Jeremy, is we will &#8212; we are well less prepared without additional funding than we would be otherwise.  We laid out an entire plan in 96 pages of detail for how we want to be prepared moving forward and to be prepared.  We were clear in that plan, we were clear in the State of the Union, and we&#8217;ve been clear with Congress for the past few months that we need additional funding to do that. <br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Let&#8217;s go to Rachel Roubein at the Washington Post. <br><br>Q    Hi, thanks for taking my question.  I was wondering: Have you guys had any conversations in the past few days with Congress about lowering the funding number at all from 15.6 billion? <br><br>And then, also, have you talked with lawmakers in recent days on additional pay-fors out of existing funds to replace the state and local aid pay-for that was taken out of the bill?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Rachel.  On your first question on the conversations with Congress to reduce the funding, the answer is no.  We need &#8212; we&#8217;ve submitted emergency requests for $22.5 billion, and we stand by that request.<br><br>On the pay-fors, you know, we&#8217;ll leave it to Congress the details of how they get this over the finish line in Congress.  But I think there&#8217;s bipartisan recognition that we need this money.  There&#8217;s recognition of the money they provided over a year ago has been well spent.  And we defer to Congress on the specific legislative approach. <br><br>But I will say that there is precedence, including in the prior administration multiple times, to provide direct COVID response funding on a bipartisan basis without offsets.<br><br>And so, we hope and expect that we&#8217;ll be able to rely on that precedent moving forward. <br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Let&#8217;s go to Tamara Keith at NPR. <br><br>Q    Apologies.  Two years in, I can&#8217;t figure out mute. <br><br>Thank you for taking my question.  I&#8217;m hoping that you can sort of explain the mechanics of the markets for these various things, like why the government still needs to be involved in making these large purchases; why, you know, large hospital groups couldn&#8217;t be buying the vaccines or buying the monoclonal antibodies; like, why &#8212; why it is all so contingent on federal funds.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah.  Tamara, it’s a good question.<br><br>Look, in our preparedness plan, we outlined that we want to explore in the future the ability to transition some of COVID treatments and potentially other tools to insurance-based market, like other healthcare. <br><br>But I think our priority from the beginning is to make sure that in a once-in-a-generation pandemic that has killed over 960,000 Americans, that we&#8217;re taking the measures that are necessary to make those widely available, free, and accessible to all Americans. <br><br>That&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve done with monoclonal antibody.  That&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve done with the Pfizer pills and the Merck pills.  That’s what we’ve done with testing.  And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve done with, obviously, vaccines.<br><br>We think it&#8217;s the right thing at this moment to continue to move forward with that. <br><br>And I&#8217;d say most important, when we have a variant that strikes like we had with Omicron, our ability as the federal government to use our purchasing power as a government to purchase all of those things, all of those tools, and get them available to all Americans on an equitable basis saves lives.  And it was fundamental in Omicron, and I would &#8212; we would argue it&#8217;s fundamental if a variant were to come in the next few months.<br><br>So, yes, we want to explore over the long term a safe, a smooth transition.  But right now, we have immediate needs, and we need Congress to act.<br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Let’s go to Sheryl Stolberg at the New York Times.<br><br>Sheryl?  All right, Sheryl, we&#8217;ll come back to you.<br><br>Let&#8217;s go to Zeke Miller at the AP.<br><br>Q    Hey.  Thanks for doing this.  Just to follow up on Tam&#8217;s question there: So, why not, if &#8212; you know, if the need is immediate and Congress right now shows no sign of budging, aren&#8217;t you exploring those alternate avenues?  You know, you just required private insurers to cover the cost of at-home tests.  Why not have them cover the cost of vaccines and Paxlovid and other things like that? <br><br>Why does the government still need to be the middleman there, given the current rate of COVID-impacted society and mortality?  I mean, how is that different than, you know, cancer or heart disease, other things where insurance is &#8212; the private insurance market is already effective there?<br><br>And then, separately, lawmakers on Capitol Hill have been, you know, complaining about that lack of outreach over the last several week &#8212; several weeks from the White House.  Why did it take until, you know, just the last couple of months for the White House to sort of sound the alarm here?  Shouldn’t this have been something that you all raised the alarm on last year as this &#8212; as these funds were being rapidly depleted?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Zeke.  So, on your first question, I&#8217;d say, look, we are exploring those alternatives.  We made that clear in the &#8212; in the Preparedness Plan that we released a few weeks ago.  But it takes time, as you know, to move to that &#8212; to such a system.  We &#8212; it needs to be an orderly, smooth transition.  So we&#8217;re working through that. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;d also say, though, especially for things like vaccines, but in fact for all of our tools, the United States competes against other countries to get access &#8212; preferential access, as much as we can, to those tools.&nbsp; So we shouldn&#8217;t be fooled that if we move to this market that we would still be able to provide Americans the early access to the tools that we have worked really hard for the last 14 months to be able to provide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So if you think about a scenario where we had another variant or if we need a variant-specific vaccine, if the U.S. government sees our responsibility to provide and purchase those, you know, insurance companies would be competing against other countries to provide those, to try to purchase those, as opposed to the U.S. government stepping in and making sure that all Americans have easy, free access to something that can save their life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So it&#8217;s certainly something we’re exploring.&nbsp; But it needs to be a smooth transition, an orderly transition, and there are certain places where we want to make sure that we are able to step in as the federal government and provide that access where we think it is merited.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To your second question on outreach: You know, we have been clear with Congress since mid-January that funds in our existing balances were low.&nbsp; We briefed appropriators and authorizers in February on our immediate needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also in February, we sent a document to the Hill clearly outlining the near-term consequences of no funding, which included specifically saying things like the uninsured fund would have to stop taking claims in March &#8212; we are now in March; monoclonals would stock out in May if we didn&#8217;t have funds by March; that AstraZeneca for immunocompromised would stock out this summer if we didn&#8217;t have funds in March.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We then &#8212; the Acting Director of OMB, Shalanda Young, sent a letter to Congress in March &#8212; early March asking for the $22.5 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve been clear with Congress on how funds were dwindling in these accounts and that there were &#8212; there were going to be immediate consequences of that.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re making that &#8212; those consequences clear again today.</p>



<p>     MR. MUNOZ:  Next question, let’s go to Jeff Mason at Reuters.<br><br>Q    Thanks very much.  Two questions.  One, can you &#8212; I know, [senior administration official], that you said you would leave the mechanics of how Congress did this to Congress, but can you just outline what the options are at this point?  Do you expect that Democrats would have to put this into a separate bill or the reconciliation bill?  Or what is your expectation at least for options on how on how to get this across the finish line?<br><br>And secondly, I saw that Punchbowl wrote a story this morning about a letter that you&#8217;ve written to Congress about this.  Can you get us that letter or confirm that that was written?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, Jeff.  So, [senior administration official] on mechanics, and I welcome [senior administration official] to jump in here after I talk if they want to add. <br><br>But, you know, I think, as I mentioned, there are many avenues that Congress can do to move to move this funding forward.  The &#8212; what we see is past precedent under the prior administration for bipartisan support for funds for direct COVID response to save lives that were provided multiple times without offsets.  So we think there&#8217;s clearly a precedent for that.  We&#8217;re asking for $22.5 billion for immediate funding, and we think Congress should move on that.<br><br>I say on reconciliation &#8212; again, I defer to Congress, but we need this money now.  These are immediate, near-term consequences, some of which we&#8217;re having to act on this week, next week, and the first week of April.  So, time is not on our side; we need we need the funding immediately.<br><br>And then on the letter to Congress that&#8217;s being sent today &#8212; and we&#8217;ll make sure that folks have access to that.<br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  Last question, let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett at ABC News.<br><br>Q    Thank you.  Hi, guys.  So, I wanted to clarify on testing: Is capacity declining this month, as we previously heard in March, or do you have enough on that front to get through June unscathed, [senior administration official], as you said, just a bit ago?<br><br>And then on Test to Treat: Can that new program still go on?  Are there enough antivirals to support that or is that going to have to be scaled back?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks.  On testing capacity, [senior administration official], I don&#8217;t know if you want to add here, but we have domestic manufacturing capability to sustain our domestic manufacturing capability until June.  And at that point, it will greatly diminish.<br><br>[Senior administration official], anything you’d add on testing?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Well, I think that&#8217;s exactly right.  Due to federal support, we&#8217;ve been able to maintain this manufacturing capacity, even though as [senior administration official] mentioned, we are hearing from our domestic manufacturers that demand from other places is starting to crater. <br><br>So, it&#8217;s very important that we have this federal funding to support that manufacturing.  And we anticipate we can keep it going through June.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks.  And then, Cheyenne, just on your second question: We do have the pills to do Test to Treat.  We do not, however, have funding &#8212; and this is clear in the materials we put out &#8212; to make any additional purchases of Pfizer pills beyond the ones that we&#8217;ve made.<br><br>MR. MUNOZ:  All right.  Well, thank you, everybody, for joining today.<br><br>As a reminder, this call is embargoed until 11:30 and attributable to “senior administration officials.”<br><br>Let me know if you have any other questions, and have a good day.<br><br>11:03 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The White&#160;House Announces 2022 Public&#160;Tours</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/the-white-house-announces-2022-public-tours/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is pleased to announce public tours of the White House will begin on Friday, April 15, 2022.&#160; Public tours will initially be available from 8:00 AM to 12:30 PM on Fridays and Saturdays, excluding Federal holidays or unless otherwise noted. All White House tours are free of charge. The White House&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is pleased to announce public tours of the White House will begin on Friday, April 15, 2022.&nbsp; Public tours will initially be available from 8:00 AM to 12:30 PM on Fridays and Saturdays, excluding Federal holidays or unless otherwise noted. All White House tours are free of charge. The White House tour schedule is subject to change based on inclement weather or official use.</p>



<p><strong>PUBLIC WHITE HOUSE TOUR REQUESTS</strong></p>



<p>Public tour requests are scheduled on a first come, first served basis and must be submitted through a Member of Congress and their Congressional Tour Coordinator. Constituents may reach your Member of Congress and Congressional Tour Coordinator through the U.S. House of Representative’s Switchboard at 202-225-3121, the U.S. Senate Switchboard at 202-224-3121, or online at <a href="http://www.congress.gov/members">www.congress.gov/members</a>.</p>



<p>Consistent with prior practices, public White House tour requests must be submitted a minimum of 21 days in advance and no more than 90 days in advance of the requested tour date(s). Reservations cannot be accepted for tour dates outside this 21 – 90-day window. Congressional Tour Coordinators will be able to submit tour requests beginning Monday, March 21, 2022.&nbsp; <a></a></p>



<p>The White House will continue to closely monitor the COVID-19 situation with guidance based on recommendations from the CDC, and other public health officials and medical experts, and reserves the right to adjust availability of the public tours as necessary to adhere to the latest health guidance. Within the 10 days prior to the public tour, anyone who has tested positive for COVID-19, has had any COVID-19 symptoms, or been in close contact with someone confirmed or suspected to have COVID-19, should stay home. Face masks will be available when entering the White House complex for those who choose to wear them.</p>



<p><em>Information regarding additional springtime events at the White House, including the Spring Garden Tours and the White House Easter Egg Roll, will be released in the coming days.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Consequences of Lack of Funding for Efforts to Combat COVID-&#8288;19 if Congress Does Not&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/fact-sheet-consequences-of-lack-of-funding-for-efforts-to-combat-covid-19-if-congress-does-not-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. has made tremendous progress in our fight against COVID-19. Over the past 14 months, the Biden Administration has made vital investments – using resources Congress provided on a bipartisan basis – to make sure the American people have free and widely available access to lifesaving tools: vaccines, booster shots, treatments, tests, and high-quality&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The U.S. has made tremendous progress in our fight against COVID-19. Over the past 14 months, the Biden Administration has made vital investments – using resources Congress provided on a bipartisan basis – to make sure the American people have free and widely available access to lifesaving tools: vaccines, booster shots, treatments, tests, and high-quality masks. As we enter a new moment in the pandemic, Congress has not provided us with the funding we need to continue the COVID-19 response and minimize the pandemic’s impact to the Nation and our economy. With cases rising abroad, scientific and medical experts have been clear that in the next couple of months there could be increasing cases of COVID-19 here in the U.S as well. As the Administration has warned, failure to fund these efforts now will have severe consequences as we will not be equipped to deal with a future surge. Waiting to provide funding once we’re in a surge will be too late.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without funding, the United States will not have enough additional boosters or variant specific vaccines, if needed, for all Americans. The federal government is unable to purchase additional life-saving monoclonal antibody treatments and will run out of supply to send to states as soon as late May. The federal government cannot purchase sufficient quantities of treatments for immunocompromised individuals. And, the federal government will be unable to sustain the testing capacity we built over the last 14 months, as we head into the second half of the year.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, President Biden laid out a comprehensive plan to ensure that the country can continue to move forward safely and remain prepared to fight new variants and future surges of the virus. And the Administration has been clear that we need Congress to provide additional resources, including $22.5 billion in immediate emergency funding. Inaction will set us back in this fight, leave us less prepared, and cost us more lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Consequences of lack of critical funding include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Inability to Secure Sufficient Booster Doses and Variant Specific Vaccines, If Needed: </strong>The federal government does not have adequate resources to purchase enough booster vaccine doses for all Americans, if additional doses are needed. The shortages will be even more acute if we need a variant-specific booster vaccine, since we will not have any existing supply.<strong></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Providers No Longer Able to Submit Claims for Testing, Treating, and Vaccinating the Uninsured:&nbsp;</strong> The fund that reimburses doctors and other medical providers for caring for uninsured individuals will start to be scaled back this month and end completely in early April.&nbsp;&nbsp; Specifically, one week from today – March 22 &#8212; the Uninsured Program will stop accepting new claims for testing and treatment due to lack of sufficient funds. Providers will no longer be able to submit claims for providing these services to uninsured individuals, forcing providers to either absorb the cost or turn away people who are uninsured, increasing the disparity in access to critically needed health care and putting additional burdens on safety net providers. Three weeks from today—April 5—the Uninsured Program will also stop accepting vaccination claims due to a lack of sufficient funds.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ending the Purchase of Monoclonal Antibody Treatments, Scaling Back State/Territory Allocations:</strong> The federal government has no more funding f0r additional monoclonals, including a planned order for March 25. To date, the federal government has been able to provide these life-saving treatments free of charge to Americans and work with states to make sure they get to as many people as possible who need them. In order to keep these treatments free and available to the American people for as long as possible, the Administration will now have to stretch our current supply and, starting next week, will be forced to cut state allocations of our limited existing supply of life-saving monoclonal antibody treatments by more than 30%.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Halting Critical Testing, Vaccine, Treatment Efforts</strong>: The President’s National Preparedness Plan was clear that the federal government must invest in next-generation vaccines and treatments and maintain our testing capacity in order to fight COVID-19 in the future. Now, without additional funding, we do not have the ability to:<ul><li><em>Purchase additional oral antiviral pills beyond the 20 million already secured.</em></li></ul><ul><li><em>Pre-purchase promising new antivirals</em>. The reason why the Administration has been able to secure more oral antiviral pills than any other country is because we committed to purchasing them early, even prior to an Emergency Use Authorization (EUA). As even more effective pills potentially become available, the federal government is no longer able to make advance purchase commitments to ensure America is one of the first countries in line.&nbsp;</li></ul><ul><li><em>Accelerate the creation of a next-generation, pan-COVID vaccine that would provide broad protection against a range of variants</em>. Vaccines are the most effective tool to prevent COVID-19, and the Administration does not have the funding for necessary investments in research and to support the development of promising new vaccine candidates.&nbsp; Such next-generation vaccines hold potential to broaden protection against known and future variants, reduce dosing through single-dose primary regimens with extended duration of protection (i.e., longer interval between boosters or possible elimination of boosters altogether), and reduce costs by increasing manufacturing yields and extending shelf life.</li></ul><ul><li><em>Maintain our domestic testing capacity beyond June.</em> After spending the last year building up our testing capacity, that progress will be squandered, the Administration will be unable to help keep domestic manufacturers online starting in June. That means, heading into the second half of the year, there will be significantly diminished domestic testing capacity and we may be unprepared for surges.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Scaling Back Planned Purchases of Preventive Treatments for Immunocompromised:</strong> The federal government has been planning to move forward with a purchase of preventative treatments for the immunocompromised as soon as March 31 that would begin delivery in September, once the treatments are manufactured. &nbsp;However, absent additional funding the federal government will now be forced to scale back that purchase of treatments for our most vulnerable. Because these treatments take more than 6 months to manufacture, the United States will likely not have enough of these treatments by the end of the year. &nbsp;And being unable to make additional purchase commitments now likely means that fewer treatments will be available next year as well. &nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Reducing Ability to Rapidly Identify and Assess Emerging Variants.&nbsp; </strong>Robust surveillance and research are critical to identify, understand and monitor emerging variants.&nbsp; With reduced capability to perform adequate surveillance, the country will be prone to being “blindsided” by future variants. In the absence of funding to immediately assess lab-based efficacy and real-world effectiveness of existing vaccines and treatments as new variants emerge, health care professionals will be forced to make insufficiently informed treatment decisions. The Administration will need to wind down some COVID surveillance investments, leaving us less able to detect the next variant.<strong></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Damage to Global Vaccination and COVID-19 Treatment Efforts:  </strong>Without additional funding to support getting shots into arms, USAID and interagency partners will have to cut short efforts to turn vaccines into vaccinations across the globe.  Leaving large unvaccinated populations worldwide will increase the risk of new deadly variants emerging that could evade our current vaccines and treatments.  Without additional funds, the Administration would be unable to extend Global VAX surge support to 20+ additional under-vaccinated countries that will need intensive support this year to get shots in arms. This will devastate our ability to ensure those countries can effectively deploy safe and effective vaccines. USAID will also be unable to provide life-saving supplies, tests, therapeutics, oxygen, and humanitarian aid to countries still struggling to manage a continuing COVID disease burden. </li></ul>



<p>In addition to the immediate need for funding, in order to facilitate a smooth transition to insurance coverage of life-savings COVID treatments the Administration is requesting that Congress provides authority to ensure seamless access to Medicare and insurance coverage for treatments under an Emergency Use Authorization (EUA).</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the March National Climate Task Force&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/readout-of-the-march-national-climate-task-force-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 15:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Task Force discussed ways to lower prices at the pump and secure true energy independence Yesterday, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the tenth meeting of the National Climate Task Force with Cabinet members and senior leadership from across the Biden-Harris Administration. The Task Force focused on how agencies can continue supporting the President’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>National Task Force discussed ways to lower prices at the pump and secure true energy independence</em></p>



<p>Yesterday, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the tenth meeting of the National Climate Task Force with Cabinet members and senior leadership from across the Biden-Harris Administration. The Task Force focused on how agencies can continue supporting the President’s commitment to addressing Putin’s Price Hike from his unprovoked war against Ukraine, minimizing pain at the pump here at home, continue rapidly deploying clean energy, and keep reducing emissions that cause climate change.</p>



<p>The Task Force echoed the President’s belief that this moment underscores the need to accelerate – not slow down – our transition to a clean energy future that will strengthen U.S. energy independence. They noted when electric cars are powered by clean energy, homes run on clean electricity, and our grid is more resilient and reliable, autocrats like Putin won’t be able to weaponize fossil fuels against other nations. Officials discussed building a clean energy future by furthering the Task Force’s work every day and advancing the President’s legislative agenda that provides tax credits to save families money, lower energy bills, boost U.S. manufacturing jobs, and promote competition.</p>



<p>Task Force members also discussed progress across government to achieve the President’s ambitious climate goals. A new Climate-Smart Infrastructure Working Group outlined efforts to ensure Bipartisan Infrastructure Law investments are resilient to future climate impacts and utilize low-carbon and carbon-free materials. Energy Secretary Granholm previewed upcoming work to make schools more energy efficient and cleaner for our children. Interior Secretary Haaland discussed how the Department of the Interior is leveraging Bipartisan Infrastructure Law investments to reclaim abandoned mines and plug orphan oil and gas wells across the country. Lastly, the Council on Environmental Quality highlighted the Administration’s continued commitment to environmental justice and their progress deploying the Climate and Economic Justice Screening Tool.</p>



<p>As outlined by President Biden’s January 27&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/executive-order-on-tackling-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad/">Executive Order on Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad</a>, the Task Force is chaired by the National Climate Advisor and includes Cabinet-level leaders from 21 federal agencies and senior White House officials to mobilize the Biden-Harris Administration’s implementation of a whole-of-government approach.</p>



<p>Task Force membership is comprised of the following government officials:</p>



<ul><li>National Climate Advisor (Chair)</li><li>Secretary of the Treasury</li><li>Secretary of Defense</li><li>Attorney General</li><li>Secretary of the Interior</li><li>Secretary of Agriculture</li><li>Secretary of Commerce</li><li>Secretary of Education</li><li>Secretary of Labor</li><li>Secretary of Health and Human Services</li><li>Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Secretary of Transportation</li><li>Secretary of Energy</li><li>Secretary of Homeland Security</li><li>Administrator of General Services</li><li>Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality</li><li>Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration</li><li>Director of the Office of Management and Budget</li><li>Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs</li><li>Assistant to the President for Homeland Security and Counterterrorism</li><li>Assistant to the President for Economic Policy</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: S. 1543, S. 1662, S.&#160;3706</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/03/15/bills-signed-s-1543-s-1662-s-3706/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 15:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, March 15, 2022, the President signed into law:&#160;S. 1543, the &#8220;Suicide Training and Awareness Nationally Delivered for Universal Prevention Act of 2021&#8221; or the &#8220;STANDUP Act of 2021,&#8221; which prioritizes in certain grant programs, educational agencies that implement suicide awareness and prevention training policies, and to provide best practices for such training policies.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, March 15, 2022, the President signed into law:<br>&nbsp;<br>S. 1543, the &#8220;Suicide Training and Awareness Nationally Delivered for Universal Prevention Act of 2021&#8221; or the &#8220;STANDUP Act of 2021,&#8221; which prioritizes in certain grant programs, educational agencies that implement suicide awareness and prevention training policies, and to provide best practices for such training policies.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Hassan and Ernst and Representatives Peters and Bilirakis for their leadership.<br>&nbsp;<br>S. 1662, the &#8220;Supporting the Foundation for the National Institutes of Health and the Reagan-Udall Foundation for the Food and Drug Administration Act,&#8221; which increases the set-aside for the Foundation for the National Institutes of Health and the Reagan-Udall Foundation for the Food and Drug Administration.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Lujan, Romney, and Collins and Representatives Hudson and Eshoo for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 3706, which makes technical amendments to the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Crapo, Risch, Merkley, Wyden, Wicker, and Manchin and Representatives McMorris Rodgers and Neguse for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Harris Administration Announces Commitments to Advance Pay Equity and Support Women’s Economic&#160;Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-commitments-to-advance-pay-equity-and-support-womens-economic-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 14:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This&#160;Equal Pay Day, the White House&#160;is&#160;announcing&#160;critical steps that&#160;the&#160;Biden-Harris Administration is taking to advance pay equity&#160;and promote women’s&#160;economic security. President Biden and Vice President Harris have long championed equal pay as a cornerstone of their commitment to ensuring all people have a fair and equal opportunity to get ahead. Closing gender and racial wage gaps is essential to building&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><em>This&nbsp;Equal Pay Day, the White House&nbsp;is&nbsp;announcing&nbsp;critical steps that&nbsp;the&nbsp;Biden-Harris Administration is taking to advance pay equity&nbsp;and promote women’s&nbsp;economic security.</em></p>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris have long championed equal pay as a cornerstone of their commitment to ensuring all people have a fair and equal opportunity to get ahead. Closing gender and racial wage gaps is essential to building an equitable economy and addressing the barriers that have long hampered women from fully participating in the labor force. There is growing recognition that reliance on past salary and a lack of pay transparency can contribute to arbitrary and potentially discriminatory pay that then follows women and workers of color from job to job, entrenching gender and racial pay gaps over time. But we still have work to do. In 2020, the average woman working full-time, year-round earned 83 cents for every dollar paid to their average male counterpart.  Compared with the average man working full-time, year-round, disparities are even greater for Black women, Native American women, and Latinas, as well as certain subpopulations of Asian women.</p>



<p>This Equal Pay Day,&nbsp;the Vice President&nbsp;is&nbsp;hosting&nbsp;a&nbsp;virtual summit,&nbsp;bringing together&nbsp;partners across&nbsp;the country who are taking critical steps to&nbsp;tackle pay discrimination,&nbsp;create&nbsp;good-paying jobs, and&nbsp;support families’ access to care.</p>



<p>Today,&nbsp;the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new actions to promote women’s employment and support working families across the country.&nbsp;These actions will:</p>



<p>• <strong>Advance pay equity for the Federal workforce.</strong>  The Office of Personnel Management announced that they anticipate issuing a proposed regulation that will address the use of prior salary history in the hiring and pay-setting process for Federal employees, consistent with the President’s Executive Order on Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility in the Federal Workforce.  </p>



<p> • <strong>Promote efforts to achieve pay equity for job applicants and employees of Federal contractors.</strong> President Biden signed an Executive Order directing the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to consider enhancing pay equity and transparency, including by limiting or prohibiting federal contractors from seeking and considering information about job applicants&#8217; and employees&#8217; existing or past compensation when making employment decisions, and appropriate accountability measures.  The Department of Labor will consult with the FAR Council on the efficiency, economy, and effectiveness in Federal contracting that would be promoted by potential regulatory changes, and the most effective implementation strategy for any subsequent rulemaking.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;<strong>Strengthen pay equity audits by Federal contractors.</strong>&nbsp;The Department of Labor’s Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs issued a new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ofccp/directives/2022-01">directive</a>&nbsp;clarifying federal contractors’ annual obligation to analyze their compensation practices. &nbsp;Conducting these pay equity audits helps address and prevent pay disparities based on gender, race, or ethnicity.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;<strong>Ensure equitable access to good-paying jobs.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Labor issued a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/WB/media/BearingTheCostReport.pdf">report</a>&nbsp;analyzing the impact that&nbsp;women’s concentration in low-wage sectors – and their relative underrepresentation in many good-paying occupations – has on their&nbsp;overall&nbsp;economic security&nbsp;and gender and racial wage gaps.&nbsp;The report finds that, in 2019, Black women lost $39.3 billion and Hispanic women lost $46.7 billion in wages compared to white men due to differences in industry and occupation.&nbsp;This segregation intensified the COVID-19 pandemic’s disproportionate impact on women, in part due to the overrepresentation&nbsp;of women&nbsp;in hard-hit industries such as hospitality. &nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;<strong>Address discrimination against caregivers.&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>Yesterday, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission&nbsp;<a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/laws/guidance/covid-19-pandemic-and-caregiver-discrimination-under-federal-employment">published technical assistance</a>&nbsp;on caregiver discrimination, addressing the circumstances under which discrimination against applicants and employees based on pandemic-related caregiving responsibilities may violate federal employment discrimination laws.</p>



<p>The actions announced today&nbsp;build on&nbsp;steps the Administration has taken to advance pay equity, including:</p>



<p>•&nbsp;<strong>Provided immediate relief through the&nbsp;American Rescue Plan (ARP)&nbsp;to millions of women who have borne the brunt of the pandemic.&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;This work includes: standing up a historic vaccination program that has fully vaccinated more than 215 million Americans; reopening schools; providing direct payments to individuals; expanding nutrition programs for families; providing paid leave tax credits for small and midsize employers; distributing the majority of emergency rental assistance to female-headed households; and expanding&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-whole-of-government-effort-to-ensure-child-tax-credit-reaches-all-eligible-families/">Child Tax Credit</a>, which last year helped reduce child poverty to its&nbsp;estimated&nbsp;lowest level&nbsp;in&nbsp;recorded&nbsp;American history.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;<strong>Helped keep child care providers open&nbsp;and boosted&nbsp;pay&nbsp;for child care workers.</strong>&nbsp;States have&nbsp;already delivered American Rescue Plan&nbsp;stabilization grants to more than 150,000 child care providers serving more than 5 million children and their families.&nbsp;One&nbsp;<a href="https://www.naeyc.org/sites/default/files/wysiwyg/user-98/naeyc_ece_field_survey_february2022.pdf">survey</a>&nbsp;finds that 92% of providers receiving funds&nbsp;relied on&nbsp;them to&nbsp;help&nbsp;stay open and nearly half used them to repay debt incurred during the pandemic.&nbsp;Many states&nbsp;also&nbsp;used funds to help boost compensation of the&nbsp;child care&nbsp;workforce.&nbsp;For example, Minnesota&nbsp;is requiring providers to increase compensation, while North Carolina and Connecticut offered bonus payments to providers who increased compensation of the workforce.&nbsp;Increasing compensation&nbsp;for child care workershelps narrow gender and racial pay gaps, as&nbsp;more than&nbsp;nine in ten are women and&nbsp;more than&nbsp;four in ten are women of color.&nbsp;While ARP funds allowed child care programs to provide&nbsp;temporary&nbsp;bonuses,&nbsp;they need long-term funding&nbsp;asthe President has proposed to sustainably increase wages.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;<strong>Provided tax relief to help families with child care costs during the pandemic&nbsp;by delivering a historic increase in the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit (CDCTC) to support millions of working families this tax season.</strong>&nbsp;The ARP increased&nbsp;the&nbsp;maximum CDCTC&nbsp;for a median income family with two children under age 13&nbsp;by more than&nbsp;sixtimes—providing&nbsp;up to $8,000 towards child care expenses in 2021.&nbsp;It will reimburse&nbsp;most families for up to half of their child care expenses.&nbsp;And the ARP CDCTC is fully-refundable, helping lower-income parents fully benefit regardless of&nbsp;their&nbsp;tax&nbsp;liability.&nbsp;Even before the pandemic, families struggled to afford child care,&nbsp;forcing&nbsp;parents and especially mothers&nbsp;to&nbsp;forego higher paying jobs, work fewer hours, or&nbsp;take time out of the workforce,&nbsp;leading to lower pay over their career.&nbsp;The President has urged Congress to pass his plan&nbsp;for child care, which could&nbsp;lower child care costs for nine in ten families with young children.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;<strong>Increased the&nbsp;minimum&nbsp;wage to $15 per hour for Federal&nbsp;workers and&nbsp;contractors,&nbsp;benefiting manywomen and people of color.&nbsp;</strong>The President issued&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/27/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-issues-an-executive-order-to-raise-the-minimum-wage-to-15-for-federal-contractors/">Executive Orders</a>&nbsp;directing the Administration to work toward ensuring that employees working on federal contracts and federal employees earned a $15 per hour minimum wage.&nbsp;Those directives went into effect in January, raising the wages of about 370,000 federal employees and employees of federal contractors.&nbsp;In addition to helping the government do its work&nbsp;more efficiently, these directives take a step towards narrowing racial and gender disparities in income, as many low-wage workers are women and people of color.&nbsp;The order also eliminates the subminimum wage for&nbsp;workers with disabilities.&nbsp;The President has called on Congress&nbsp;to raise the federal minimum wage to $15 an hour, so that American workers can have a job that delivers dignity, and to make greater strides towards pay equity.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;<strong>Signed into law the Bipartisan&nbsp;Infrastructure Law. &nbsp;</strong>Administration investments through this law&nbsp;will increase access to good-paying jobs, including for women, people of color, and members of other communities who are currently underrepresented in the sectors where these jobs will be created, such as transportation, clean energy, and broadband.<strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>The&nbsp;Department of Transportation and the Department of Labor&nbsp;signed a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/OPA/newsreleases/2022/03/OSEC20220210.pdf">memorandum of understanding</a>&nbsp;to promote the creation of good infrastructure and transportation jobs with a focus on equitable workforce development using funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;<strong>Issued an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/25/executive-order-on-diversity-equity-inclusion-and-accessibility-in-the-federal-workforce/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;to promote&nbsp;diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility&nbsp;across the federal government – the nation’s largest employer</strong>&nbsp;–&nbsp;including by prioritizing efforts to close gender and racial wage gaps, address workplace safety and harassment, including in our national security workforce, and advance equity for LGBTQI+ public servants.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;<strong>Issued&nbsp;an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;on Promoting Competition in the American Economy.&nbsp;</strong>This&nbsp;established the Administration’s policy of addressing&nbsp;<a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/State-of-Labor-Market-Competition-2022.pdf">anticompetitive behavior</a>&nbsp;in labor markets, which can fall heavily on women and workers of color.&nbsp;The Order includes specific initiatives to promote competition in labor markets, including encouraging the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to ban or limit non-compete agreements, and&nbsp;encouraging the&nbsp;FTC and&nbsp;the Department of Justice to&nbsp;strengthen antitrust guidance to prevent employers from collaborating to suppress wages or reduce benefits by sharing wage and benefit information with one another.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces New Initiative to Improve Supply Chain Data&#160;Flow</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-new-initiative-to-improve-supply-chain-data-flow/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Freight Logistics Optimization Works (FLOW) Will Speed Up Delivery Times and Reduce Consumer Costs White House to Host Launch Event Today with Key Industry Stakeholders Since taking office, the Biden-Harris Administration has been focused on addressing supply chain vulnerabilities and congestion, working to speed up the movement of goods, and lower costs for families. Last&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Freight Logistics Optimization Works (FLOW) Will Speed Up Delivery Times and Reduce Consumer Costs</em><br><br><em>White House to Host Launch Event Today with Key Industry Stakeholders</em></p>



<p>Since taking office, the Biden-Harris Administration has been focused on addressing supply chain vulnerabilities and congestion, working to speed up the movement of goods, and lower costs for families. Last year, the ports and the private sector moved a historic amount of goods with record holiday sales and delivery times below pre-pandemic levels. Currently, real retail inventories excluding autos are six percent higher than at the end of 2019 and products at grocery and drug stores are 90 percent in stock, just 1 percentage point below pre-pandemic levels.</p>



<p>The Administration is also focused on addressing the longer-term weaknesses in our nation’s supply chains, the result of decades of underinvestment, outsourcing, and offshoring instead of investment in long-term security, sustainability, and resilience. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law (BIL) is now making a generational investment in our ports, highways, and other parts of our physical infrastructure, which will help speed up the movement of goods and lower costs. But we can further strengthen our goods movement supply chains by making a similarly bold improvement in a <em>digital</em> infrastructure to connect the supply chain.</p>



<p><strong>To take the first step toward addressing this challenge, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing the launch of Freight Logistics Optimization Works (FLOW), an information sharing initiative to pilot key freight information exchange between parts of the goods movement supply chain. </strong>FLOW includes eighteen initial participants that represent diverse perspectives across the supply chain, including private businesses, trucking, warehousing, and logistics companies, ports, and more. &nbsp;These key stakeholders will work together with the Administration to develop a proof-of-concept information exchange to ease supply chain congestion, speed up the movement of goods, and ultimately cut costs for American consumers. DOT will lead this effort, playing the role of an honest broker and convener to bring supply chain stakeholders together to problem solve and overcome coordination challenges. This initial phase aims to produce a proof-of-concept freight information exchange by the end of the summer.<br><strong><br>A Novel Data Sharing Partnership<br></strong><br>Recent supply chain disruptions have raised national awareness of the need for improved information exchange. Supply chain stakeholders deserve reliable, predictable, and accurate information about goods movement and FLOW will test the idea that cooperation on foundational freight digital infrastructure is in the interest of both public and private parties. FLOW is designed to support businesses throughout the supply chain and improve accuracy of information from end-to-end for a more resilient supply chain.</p>



<p>Resiliency—the ability to recover from an unexpected shock—requires visibility, agility, and redundancy. The lack of digital infrastructure and transparency makes our supply chains brittle and unable to adapt when faced with a shock. The goods movement chain is almost entirely privately operated and spans shipping lines, ports, terminal operators, truckers, railroads, warehouses, and cargo owners such as retailers. These different actors have made great strides in digitizing their own internal operations, but they do not always exchange information with each other. This lack of information exchange can cause delays as cargo moves from one part of the supply chain to another, driving up costs and increasing goods movement fragility.</p>



<p>This effort shows a strong and deliberate response by the Administration to tackle this challenge head-on and set the country on the right trajectory for a resilient and globally competitive 21st century goods movement chain. The Biden-Harris Administration is laser focused and creative in identifying ways to speed up the movement of goods from ships to shelves and cut costs for American consumers. With FLOW, the Biden Administration will play a leadership role in bringing companies together to problem solve for the American people. Initial partners in FLOW include:</p>



<p><strong>Port Authorities:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Port of Long Beach</li><li>Port of Los Angeles</li><li>Georgia Ports Authority</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ocean Carriers:</strong></p>



<ul><li>CMA CGM</li><li>MSC</li></ul>



<p><strong>Terminal Operators:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Fenix Marine Terminal</li><li>Global Container Terminals</li></ul>



<p><strong>Business:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>Albertsons</li><li>Gemini Shippers</li><li>Land O’ Lakes</li><li>Target</li><li>True Value</li></ul>



<p><strong>Trucking</strong></p>



<ul><li>&nbsp;CH Robinson</li></ul>



<p><strong>Chassis:</strong></p>



<ul><li>DCLI</li><li>FlexiVan</li></ul>



<p><strong>Logistics and Warehousing:</strong></p>



<ul><li>FedEx</li><li>Prologis</li><li>UPS</li></ul>



<p>These first partners are committed to working with the Biden-Harris Administration to identify and operationalize a first information exchange that will support a more resilient and fluid supply chain. They represent stakeholders throughout the supply chain including large BCOs (beneficial cargo owners) like Target, small and medium size businesses represented by True Value and Gemini Shippers, as well as agricultural producers such as Land O’Lakes. FLOW will be able to address issues such as ensuring early return dates are consistent across partners, measuring more accurate chassis availability and understanding aggregate dwell time throughout the supply chain. The principles of the pilot include the following: it is a voluntary, secure national exchange for freight information, it is available to participants who share data, and it is sustained by supply chain operational improvement.<br><br><strong><u>For additional interested parties, the Biden-Harris Administration is launching a webpage to gauge additional stakeholder interest in supporting foundational freight infrastructure:<br></u></strong><br>While starting with a limited pilot, DOT wants to hear from others who are interested in engaging as part of FLOW as a participant as the initiative grows. Within one month of the FLOW launch, DOT will launch a web page to gauge industry interest in participation and data sharing for a potential long-term FLOW effort.</p>



<p><strong>Building on Ongoing Supply Chain Achievements<br></strong><br>The FLOW initiative builds on previous successes of the Biden-Harris Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force to ensure cargo is getting from ship to shelf, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Reduced Dwell Time in Los Angeles and Long Beach.</strong> At the beginning of November, with support from the Administration, the Ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach proposed charging the ocean carriers for cargo that dwelled on the docks for nine days or more, which led to about a 60 percent reduction in the number of long-dwelling import containers on the docks to date.<br></li><li><strong>Alleviated congestion at the Port of Savannah</strong> by funding the Georgia Port Authority pop-up container yards project. With this policy change, the Georgia Port Authority was able to reallocate more than $8 million to convert existing inland facilities into five pop-up container yards in both Georgia and North Carolina.  Since the temporary container yards opened in late November, the container yards have provided relief to about 5,000 containers over eight weeks and freed up more dock space, speeding goods flow in and out of the Port of Savannah.<br></li><li><strong>Secured commitments to move towards 24/7 operations </strong>via a Presidential call to action to encourage every link in the goods movement chain to move towards a 24/7 pace to increase the volume and pace of products flowing through the system. The Ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach and International Longshore and Warehouse Union (ILWU) workers joined together to make the first commitment. Some of the countries’ largest companies joined in as well—including Walmart, Target, FedEx, UPS, Home Depot, Best Buy, The Gap, and Samsung—committing to try a new solution.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Democratic National Committee&#160;Fundraiser</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/14/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-democratic-national-committee-fundraiser/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 03:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hotel WashingtonWashington, D.C. 7:59 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Happy to do that.&#160; First, let me begin by thanking you all for your commitment to the environment.&#160; I think maybe Mark is the only guy in here who knows that way back in the ‘80s, I wrote the first climate bill, and it didn&#8217;t go very&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Hotel Washington<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>7:59 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Happy to do that.&nbsp; First, let me begin by thanking you all for your commitment to the environment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think maybe Mark is the only guy in here who knows that way back in the ‘80s, I wrote the first climate bill, and it didn&#8217;t go very far.&nbsp; We &#8212; we had rai- &#8212; (coughs) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; raised consciousness, but it didn&#8217;t go very far.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And let me began by saying: It is the existential threat to humanity.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; And you got a chance to speak to my former &#8212; our former Secretary of State, John Kerry, who is as passionate about this as anybody in the world &#8212; for real.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been going around the world trying to make sure that we keep the kind of commitment that the G28 did.&nbsp; At any rate, we &#8212; there&#8217;s a long way to go, but we&#8217;re running into some obstacles that I&#8217;m going to need your help on in terms of individuals, as well as circumstances.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ll get to that a little bit later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, Lise, thank you for &#8212; for doing this.&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s great to be with this group again.&nbsp; An awful lot of you here supported the campaign throughout and been with me throughout the first year and a half or so of my administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The climate crisis is the existential threat.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not hyperbole; it&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp; If we don&#8217;t keep it to 1.5 degrees Celsius &#8212; no warmer than that &#8212; we&#8217;re going to have &#8212; our kids are going to &#8212; our grandchildren will never forgive us, and the world will change.&nbsp; I mean, literal sense it will change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And before we begin the discussion, I have three quick points.&nbsp; One, clean energy is a double-edged sword to deal with the climate crisis.&nbsp; Actually, it’s not even double-edged, it’s a triple-edged sword if we think of it in positive terms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I had &#8212; years ago, when I was taken to a hospital with an aneurysm, the doctors explained to me what was going through and whether it was environmental or whether it was congenital.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I said, “Doc, I don&#8217;t need to know.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be okay.”&nbsp; He was operating at me.&nbsp; And he looked at me, and he said, “Your problem, Senator, is you&#8217;re a congenital optimist.” Well, in this job, you have to be.&nbsp; I always used to kid Barack, “A country is never going to be more optimistic than its president.”&nbsp; And I am optimistic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there are three &#8212; three things we can deal with at the same time now: climate crisis, consumer costs, and national security.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re not at odds with one another if we look at it the right way; they&#8217;re compatible.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we have to pass the other provisions in my Better Back &#8212; Build Back America plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In advance of our aggressive climate goals, we’re going to cut costs for families &#8212; an average of $500 a year.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not something anybody at this table worries about, but as my dad used to say, when everything from the price of gasoline to heating your home goes up, it&#8217;s a subject at the &#8212; at the dinner table.&nbsp; It&#8217;s real.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and so, that&#8217;s why this &#8212; my proposal advances aggressive climate goals, tax credits to weatherize homes and businesses, doubling America&#8217;s solar wind and &#8212; and other energy, lowering the price of electric vehicles, and &#8212; and much more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in addition, the Russia and Ukraine is another reason why we have to get off our dependency on fossil fuels.&nbsp; Imagine where we&#8217;d be right now if, in fact, Europe was in fact energy- free of fossil fuels and was &#8212; we were in a situation where &#8212; (coughs) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; where &#8212; where we &#8212; it was all renewables.&nbsp; It&#8217;d be a different world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and so, we have to get off the dependency on fossil fuels &#8212; a subject matter I’ve spoken over, I don&#8217;t know, 75 to 100 times over the last four months; trying to keep NATO together and the EU.&nbsp; I mean, literally, not figuratively &#8212; meaning both here and there.&nbsp; And the dependence of Europe on fossil fuels is &#8212; way exceeds any dependence we have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, it&#8217;s not an immediate solution to the crisis, but it&#8217;s all about the future if we were to change the fossil fuel dependency.</p>



<p>Second thing: I&#8217;m going to continue to take executive actions where I can.&nbsp; The Court has overruled me a couple of times.&nbsp; But we created a climate office in the White House to carry out the whole-of-government effort to deal with climate.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve signed executive orders ranging from the most ambitious fuel economy standards for cars and trucks to taking on super-polluting hydrofluorocarbons.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to be aggressive on the executive front as well.</p>



<p>The third thing is we have to continue to catalyze private investment and bring everybody along, which you all know much more about that than the vast majority of Americans.</p>



<p>And the infrastructure law &#8212; it was going to take us a long way.&nbsp; For example, we’re going to provide 500,000 charging stations for electric vehicles; that is motivating both utilities, car companies, and states to invest their own money in deploying these chargers as well.</p>



<p>Ford, General Motors are making historic investments in electric vehicles.&nbsp; GM says they will be 100 percent electric vehicles by &#8212; maybe by 2035; Ford says, by 2030, 50 percent of all their vehicles.&nbsp; And this proves we can deal with climate and &#8212; crisis &#8212; and jobs.&nbsp; This creates a lot of jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the law also is going to help us build more climate resilience and deal with the record wildfires, floods, droughts, and other ways to get private sector into the game.</p>



<p>I have &#8212; I’ve gone to almost every major climate crisis we&#8217;ve had in the last year and a half.&nbsp; You know, you all know it, but more land has burned to the ground, including buildings and forest, than the entire square footage of New Jersey, in the West, and &#8212; primarily.</p>



<p>And, you know, we&#8217;ve had climate resilience to deal with the floods and droughts as well.&nbsp; I mean, now &#8212; you know, when the hurricane hit in Louisiana, the 170-mile-an-hour winds &#8212; 79-mile-an-hour winds &#8212; more people died in Queens from flooding than they died in that hurricane.&nbsp; Because when I went up there and visited &#8212; people went to their basements because of tornadoes and rain &#8212; 20 inches of rain.&nbsp; They &#8212; it flooded their basements; couldn&#8217;t get out, and died.</p>



<p>And so, you know, it&#8217;s another way to get the private sector into the game as well.&nbsp; Every place I go, the private sector is wanting to talk about what they can do and what they want to work with me to get done.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and, by the way, that brings everyone in: the labor unions; urban, rural and Tribal communities as well; and our young people &#8212; this is their generational cause.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s the coalition we need to put together &#8212; business, labor, and &#8212; and including Tribal communities, and just the whole generation of young people who are &#8212; for example, my wi- &#8212; my daughter is a social worker.&nbsp; She is &#8212; runs a lot of Boys &amp; Girls Clubs around the &#8212; anyway, I called her tonight to tell her I love her.&nbsp; And her father-in-law is ill.&nbsp; And she said, “Dad, you&#8217;re talking about climate, right?&nbsp; Talking about climate.”&nbsp; And dad is talking about climate.</p>



<p>So the coalition we need to bring &#8212; bring together &#8212; is going to need your help.&nbsp; And &#8212; and there&#8217;s a lot more to say.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But rather than that, since I have a call with a foreign leader &#8212; I must leave by 8:40 at the latest &#8212; I &#8212; why don&#8217;t we get on with what you want to do ne- &#8212; tell me how you want to proceed?</p>



<p>And so, I’m supposed to turn it over to Nat right now.&nbsp; They told me &#8212; that’s what I’m told.</p>



<p>(The press departs.)</p>



<p>8:09 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
