<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 17:31:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces Over $25 Billion in American Rescue Plan Funding to Help Ensure Every American Has Access to High Speed, Affordable&#160;Internet</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-over-25-billion-in-american-rescue-plan-funding-to-help-ensure-every-american-has-access-to-high-speed-affordable-internet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 17:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new investments from the American Rescue Plan to help provide every American with access to affordable, high-speed internet. The American Rescue Plan funding is in addition to the $65 billion investment in high-speed Internet access in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and recent announcements to lower the cost of high-speed internet&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new investments from the American Rescue Plan to help provide every American with access to affordable, high-speed internet. The American Rescue Plan funding is in addition to the $65 billion investment in high-speed Internet access in the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/bipartisan-infrastructure-law/#internetaccess">Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</a> and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/fact-sheet-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-reduce-high-speed-internet-costs-for-millions-of-americans/">recent announcements</a> to lower the cost of high-speed internet for tens of millions of American families. These investments will bring down costs for families, help small businesses, and boost education for America’s kids. Affordable, high-speed internet connects Americans to critical services and expands economic opportunities to every community. The American Rescue Plan has already spent or committed more than $25 billion to invest in affordable high-speed internet and connectivity.</p>



<ul><li><strong>$10 billion through the </strong><a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/coronavirus/assistance-for-state-local-and-tribal-governments/capital-projects-fund"><strong>Capital Projects Fund</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Today, the Treasury Department announced the first state awards of the Capital Projects Fund, which is providing resources, in addition to the State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds, to states, territories, and Tribal governments to deliver affordable, reliable, high-speed internet infrastructure and other connectivity projects<strong>.</strong><br><br></li><li><strong>$8 Billion Already Committed with American Rescue Plan </strong><a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/coronavirus/assistance-for-state-local-and-tribal-governments/state-and-local-fiscal-recovery-funds"><strong>State and Local Funds</strong></a>: Even without full reporting in, state and local governments have committed more than $8 billion in investments toward expanding affordable digital connectivity, through construction of affordable and high-speed broadband infrastructure and providing assistance to households for Internet access and digital literacy.<br><br></li><li><strong>$7 billion through the FCC&#8217;s </strong><a href="https://www.fcc.gov/emergency-connectivity-fund"><strong>Emergency Connectivity Fund</strong></a><strong> program to help schools and libraries close the “homework gap.” </strong>The American Rescue Plan’s Emergency Connectivity Fund has already helped over 12.6 million students and provided schools and libraries with 10.5 million connected devices and over 5 million internet connections.<br><br></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>First State Awards of the $10 Billion Capital Project Fund Announced to Provide Affordable, Reliable, High-Speed Internet to over 200,000 Homes and Small Businesses</u></strong><strong>: </strong>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is also announcing <strong>the first state awards of the American Rescue Plan’s $10 billion Capital Projects Fund for critical connectivity investments</strong>—like broadband infrastructure expansion—that enable work, education, and health monitoring. These first awards, <a>totaling more than a half a billion dollars, will make <strong>resources immediately available to support Louisiana, New Hampshire, Virginia, and West Virginia in deploying infrastructure to connect over 200,000 homes and businesses</strong> </a>to reliable internet service at download and upload speeds of at least 100 Mbps. Broadband infrastructure projects supported by Capital Project Funds must:<strong> Support delivery of reliable high-speed internet</strong> by requiring service that meets or exceeds speeds of 100 Mbps download and 100 Mbps upload symmetrical upon project completion wherever practicable; <strong>Prioritize connecting families and businesses with poor and inadequate service</strong>, particularly in rural and remote areas; and<strong> Ensure affordability</strong> by requiring all service providers to participate in the Federal Communications Commission’s new <a href="http://getinternet.gov">Affordable Connectivity Program (ACP)</a> to ensure that households can afford the broadband they need for work, school, healthcare, and more by providing a discount of up to $30 per month (up to $75/month on Tribal lands) and by encouraging states to further require that services provided by a Capital Projects Fund-funded Broadband Infrastructure Projects include at least one low-cost high-speed option. First four awards go to following states:<br><br></p>



<ul><li><strong>Louisiana ($177 million) will provide funding to connect nearly 88,500 homes and businesses</strong> currently lacking access to internet at speeds of 25/3 Mbps through the state’s new Granting Unserved Municipalities Broadband Opportunities (GUMBO) program—a multi-phase, broadband infrastructure competitive grant program. Louisiana estimates that Capital Projects Fund-supported projects will close the digital divide for approximately 25 percent of all locations lacking high-speed internet access in the state.<br><br></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Virginia ($220 million) will expand high-speed internet access to more than 76,800 homes and businesses</strong> through a competitive grant-making program, closing the digital divide for approximately 28% of locations that still lack access to high-quality broadband service.<br><br></li><li><strong>West Virginia ($136 million) will provide high-speed internet access to 20,000 homes and businesses</strong> through three separate grant programs that focus funding for last-mile connections to homes and businesses currently without access to internet at speeds of at least 25/3 Mbps, reaching approximately 10% of remaining locations that lack access to high-speed internet.<br><br></li><li><strong>New Hampshire ($50 million, 41% of their available allocation) will provide high-speed internet service to 15,000 homes and businesses</strong> through the state’s new Broadband Contract Program targeting the most underserved rural parts of the state, reaching approximately 50% of locations that still lack access to high-speed internet.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>State, local, and Tribal governments in over 40 states have already committed over $8 billion in State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds to provide critical support for broadband infrastructure and Internet access</u></strong>: In addition to the $10 billion Capital Projects Fund, the American Rescue Plan provided state, local, territorial, and Tribal governments with critical resources to support a response to and recovery from the COVID-19 public health emergency—including investments in broadband infrastructure needed to connect their communities to work, education, health care, and civic opportunities available online.</p>



<p>With Fiscal Recovery Funds resources already in hand, many communities have already started making progress towards significantly expanding access to reliable, high-speed internet. To date, <strong>more than 230 state, local, and Tribal governments have budgeted more than $8 billion in Fiscal Recovery Funds to expand last-mile and middle-mile networks in their communities—including in rural and other areas that have traditionally lagged in connectivity—or to provide families assistance in affordably accessing high-speed services</strong>.<br><br></p>



<p>Examples of eight states and eight localities committing Fiscal Recovery Funds to improve access to reliable, high-speed internet:<br><br></p>



<p><strong>State Examples</strong>:</p>



<ul><li>The <strong>State of California</strong> is investing over $500 million of Fiscal Recovery Funds as part of a larger initiative to fund grants for “last-mile” broadband infrastructure projects to provide affordable access to unserved households, anchor institutions and local governments.<br><br></li><li>The <strong>State of Georgia</strong> has announced preliminary awards of over $400 million from Fiscal Recovery Funds to support 49 projects across 70 counties that could potentially serve more than 130,000 currently unserved homes and businesses with faster and more reliable broadband.<br><br></li><li>The <strong>State of Montana </strong>has received applications for $266 million in available funding from Fiscal Recovery Funds to expand access to reliable broadband and close the digital divide throughout the state.<br><br></li><li>The <strong>State of North Carolina</strong> has committed over $660 million in Fiscal Recovery Funds to deploy crucial last-mile broadband infrastructure to serve remaining unserved and underserved areas in the state, and expects to begin awarding up to $350 million of those funds beginning in July of 2022.&nbsp;<br><br></li><li>The <strong>State of Washington</strong> has begun awarding $145 million in Fiscal Recovery Funds it has committed to help advance its goal of connecting all its residents to reliable, high-speed internet access by 2028.<br><br></li><li>The <strong>State of Wisconsin</strong> provided $100 million towards 83 projects in 40 counties and 3 tribal lands that will expand fiber broadband internet to more than 28,000 homes and nearly 1,500 business locations that were either unserved or underserved.<br><br></li><li>The <strong>State of Vermont</strong> has committed $150 million of Fiscal Recovery Funds to support and accelerate the state’s goal of achieving universal access to reliable, high-quality, affordable broadband.<br><br></li><li>The <strong>State of Virginia</strong> is awarding $479 million of Fiscal Recovery Funds along with state resources that will connect more than 200,000 households, businesses, and community anchor institutions to high-speed internet.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Local Examples</strong>:<br><br></p>



<ul><li><strong>Boone County, Kentucky</strong> leveraged over $10 million in Fiscal Recovery Funds to enter into agreement with an Internet service provider to construct fiber-to-the-premises high speed broadband infrastructure capable of delivering 1 gigabit speed service to every household in the county by roughly the end of 2023. The county will also address affordability with a strategic partnership with the incumbent service provider to authorize a discount on monthly service to individual subscribers.<br><br></li><li><strong>Yavapai County, Arizona</strong> is using $20 million in Fiscal Recovery Funds for the design, construction, implementation, and maintenance of telecommunications equipment and services providing &#8220;last mile&#8221; Internet access, with a focus on ensuring unserved or underserved households and businesses in unincorporated areas in Yavapai County receive high-speed broadband.<br><br></li><li><strong>Frederick County, Virginia</strong> will use $8.6 million to participate in a regional project to develop fiber-to-the-home broadband service, which includes eight localities. Broadband service will be made available to roughly 42,700 currently unserved locations in the region, including all locations in Frederick County that remain unserved by cable or fiber-to-the-home broadband. The project will leverage a partnership between the localities, the electric cooperatives, and a broadband provider.<br><br></li><li><strong>Florence County, South Carolina</strong> will use $4.5 million to bring new broadband service to more than 3,300 residential and business addresses that are unserved or underserved. Funds will support installation of a fiber-to-the-premises wireline broadband network capable of delivering 1 Gig speeds.<br><br></li><li><strong>Washtenaw County, Michigan </strong>is committing over $13 million in Fiscal Recovery Funds to expand affordable and equitable high-speed broadband infrastructure to unserved and underserved communities as part of a larger investment intended to connect every household in the County to high-speed broadband infrastructure.<br><br></li><li><strong>Brownsville, Texas</strong> is using $19.5 million in Fiscal Recovery Funds to build out 95 miles of &#8220;middle-mile&#8221; infrastructure, including connecting 32 anchor institutions, and will partner with private providers to bring high-speed internet to its most underserved communities.<br><br></li><li><strong>Bowling Green, Kentucky</strong> is leveraging $16.5 million in Fiscal Recovery funds to seek bids on a fiber to the premises network that would provide Gig speed fiber connections to all homes and businesses in the city.<br><br></li><li><strong>Detroit, Michigan</strong> will begin construction this summer, using $10 million in Fiscal Recovery Funds, to pilot a fiber-to-the-home connectivity project to approximately 2,000 homes in the Hope Village neighborhood with affordable 1 Gig service.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>The Emergency Connectivity Fund is helping over 10,000 schools, school districts, libraries, and consortia to close the homework gap and support off-campus learning, such as nightly homework, to ensure students across the country have the necessary support to keep up with their education<br><br></u></strong></p>



<p>The American Rescue Plan’s $7.2 billion Emergency Connectivity Fund is helping schools and libraries provide the tools and services their communities need for remote learning during the pandemic, helping millions of students and closing the Homework Gap for those students who lack necessary Internet access or the devices they need to connect to classrooms.<br><br></p>



<p>The Emergency Connectivity Fund provides funding to schools and libraries for the reasonable costs of eligible equipment and services that can be provided to students, teachers, and library patrons who lack connected devices, such as laptop or tablet computers, and/or lack broadband access during the pandemic.<br><br></p>



<p>The <strong>Emergency Connectivity Fund has already committed nearly $4.9 billion, helping over 12.6 million students and providing schools and libraries with 10.5 million connected devices and over 5 million broadband connections</strong>. In May of 2022, following the closure of the program’s final planned funding application window, the Federal Communication Commission announced that it would prioritize remaining funds to schools and libraries with the greatest need, with a preference for schools and libraries located in rural areas.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on Bipartisan Senate Vote to Advance Toxic Exposure&#160;Legislation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/statement-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-bipartisan-senate-vote-to-advance-toxic-exposure-legislation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 17:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s bipartisan Senate vote to advance the Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson Honoring Our PACT Act of 2022 is a critical step towards delivering health care and benefits to veterans and survivors impacted by toxic exposures. Veterans and advocates across the country have spoken out about the importance of this legislation, which represents one of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s bipartisan Senate vote to advance the <em>Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson Honoring Our PACT Act of 2022 </em>is a critical step towards delivering health care and benefits to veterans and survivors impacted by toxic exposures. Veterans and advocates across the country have spoken out about the importance of this legislation, which represents one of the most significant and substantive expansions of benefits and services in the Department of Veterans Affairs history. We also appreciate the Senate working across the aisle to address outstanding concerns and ensure that the Department has the support to effectively implement it.<br> <br>We owe it to our veterans and their families to address these consequences comprehensively. Unfortunately, it has taken decades to understand the dangerous effects of harmful environmental exposures—leaving too many veterans without the benefits and services they need and deserve.<br> <br>America’s veterans are the best of us. Delivering for our veterans is a key pillar of the Unity Agenda the President outlined at the State of the Union – because we can all unite around supporting veterans who have served our nation. President Biden looks forward to working with Congress to swiftly enact this legislation and continue to uphold our sacred obligation to support those who have served our nation, their families, caregivers, and survivors.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on Trade in Goods and&#160;Services</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/statement-from-president-biden-on-trade-in-goods-and-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 16:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we received additional news underscoring the strength of our economic recovery. U.S. goods exports hit a record in April, even after adjusting for inflation, which in turn narrowed the trade deficit. While monthly trade data can be volatile, this suggests American businesses and farmers are selling record numbers of their goods abroad, as we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we received additional news underscoring the strength of our economic recovery. U.S. goods exports hit a record in April, even after adjusting for inflation, which in turn narrowed the trade deficit. While monthly trade data can be volatile, this suggests American businesses and farmers are selling record numbers of their goods abroad, as we continue to make more in America.</p>



<p>In addition, one of the nation’s largest retailers announced that it will take swift action to lower prices for certain goods, as American families’ spending returns to more normal patterns. This is an additional indicator that our economy is beginning to transition from an historic recovery to steady, stable economic growth.</p>



<p>The economic progress we have made didn’t happen by accident—it is a direct result of my economic plan to grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out and to unsnarl supply chains so retailers can rebuild inventories and American goods can more smoothly move through our ports. There’s more work to do to build on our historic recovery and bring down costs for families, without giving up on the significant gains we’ve made in the last year. I’ll work with anyone serious about helping transition our economy to steady, stable economic growth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on the Vice President&#8217;s Engagements Regarding Root Causes of&#160;Migration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/07/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-the-vice-presidents-engagements-regarding-root-causes-of-migration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 09:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference&#160;(June 6, 2022) 5:19 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thanks, everyone, for joining us.&#160; This briefing is to preview the Vice President&#8217;s engagements tomorrow &#8212; Tuesday, June 7th &#8212; in Los Angeles related to her work addressing the root causes of migration.&#160; I would just note, as many of you are aware, there is another background&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>&nbsp;<br>(June 6, 2022)</p>



<p>5:19 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining us.&nbsp; This briefing is to preview the Vice President&#8217;s engagements tomorrow &#8212; Tuesday, June 7th &#8212; in Los Angeles related to her work addressing the root causes of migration.&nbsp;<br><br>I would just note, as many of you are aware, there is another background briefing at 6:00 p.m. Eastern Time, which will cover other issues related to the Summit of the Americas, which I know many are interested in.&nbsp; But again, this briefing is about the Vice President&#8217;s engagements regarding root causes.&nbsp;<br><br>This briefing is on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The contents will be embargoed until Tuesday, June 7th, 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time, 2:00 <s>p.m.</s> [a.m.] Pacific Time.&nbsp; And by joining this call, you&#8217;re agreeing to these ground rules.&nbsp;<br><br>Following the call, we&#8217;ll also be sending you some factsheets to support the announcements that the Vice President will be making.&nbsp; They are also embargoed until Tuesday, June 7th at 5:00 a.m. Eastern, 2:00 a.m. Pacific Time.&nbsp;<br><br>And for your awareness today, our speaker is [senior administration official], who will hereinafter be referred to as “senior administration official.”&nbsp;<br><br>And before I hand it over to him, I would just like to preview what we already put out publicly, but to recap the Vice President’s schedule for tomorrow, Tuesday, in Los Angeles.&nbsp;<br><br>First, she&#8217;ll deliver remarks at a women&#8217;s economic empowerment event hosted by the Chamber of Commerce and the Partnership for Central America.&nbsp;<br><br>She will host a roundtable with women leaders, including women business executives, entrepreneurs, and civil society.&nbsp;<br><br>And third, she will host a roundtable with business executives as part of her call to action in partnership with the private sector.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, I will turn it over to senior administration official number one.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [moderator].&nbsp; And thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp;<br><br>Before I dive into some of the specific announcements of this week, let me just take a step back and give you some context for the Vice President&#8217;s approach to this set of issues.&nbsp;<br><br>As you all know, the Vice President leads our administration&#8217;s implementation of the strategy to address root causes of migration from Central America &#8212; a strategy that we launched last summer.&nbsp; And this week is a real opportunity for her to continue to drive this process under her leadership.&nbsp;<br><br>The focus of that strategy is addressing endemic issues in the countries of El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras &#8212; issues such as poverty and corruption and gender-based violence, which are the causes of migration.&nbsp;<br><br>The Vice President&#8217;s theory of the case in approaching this and at the center of this strategy is that people don&#8217;t want to leave their homes.&nbsp;And&nbsp;if you can help provide them hope and opportunity, particularly economic opportunity, there&#8217;s a greater chance that they will remain there.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve acknowledged all along that the drivers of migration from Central America and elsewhere are long-term issues that can&#8217;t be resolved quickly.&nbsp; But we think that we have been tackling them and are seeing real progress in our efforts.&nbsp;<br><br>When the Vice President began her work on this issue, she recognized that governments were important, but we also had to engage the private sector and civil society.&nbsp; And she believes that governments can&#8217;t solve these problems alone.&nbsp;<br><br>So as part of that process, she launched the call to action in May 2021, in which she challenged and encouraged companies to invest in the region and help provide those economic opportunities and support the sort of long-term development in the region that would provide opportunity and hope for people to stay home.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s the context in which the call-to-action work she&#8217;s doing in Los Angeles this week takes place.&nbsp; And let me roll out some of what she is able to announce this week.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;ll remember last December, when the Vice President held a roundtable with some business executives, she announced that we had galvanized $1.2 billion of commitments for the region.&nbsp;<br><br>Tomorrow, we will announce &#8212; and you&#8217;ll get this factsheet &#8212; that the Vice President has galvanized a total of more than $3.2 billion of investments for the region from 40 different companies and organizations.&nbsp;<br><br>So, this total includes more than $1.9 billion in new investments that we&#8217;re going to announce tomorrow from 10 new companies.&nbsp; And I just underscore: These, we think, are pretty sizable direct investments in economies the size of the three countries in question, and they will be responsible for creating tens of thousands of jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, we&#8217;ll get you a factsheet and all of the details, but just to give you a sense of what I&#8217;m talking about, it includes $150 million from the Gap to increase its sourcing from Central America.&nbsp; Another apparel company, SanMar, will invest $500 million in the region, generating 4,000 additional jobs.&nbsp; There&#8217;s $700 million from Millicom, a telecommunications company that&#8217;s going to expand its mobile and broadband networks in the region, and $270 million from Visa to expand financial inclusion and digital infrastructure.&nbsp;<br><br>And I particularly stress in the context of these announcements &#8212; you know, the last two, which expand broadband and financial inclusion and banking opportunities for people, really help make this project part of creating an ecosystem of opportunity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just the direct jobs that are created by these investments, but jobs in areas that help people thrive and succeed economically.&nbsp;<br><br>The Vice President believes that we need to not just offer an individual a job but address the full spectrum of needs and support individuals in the different facets of their lives.&nbsp; And that’s what this project is all about: trying to help individuals move up the economic ladder and not just have a job but also have access to information technology, banking system, and infrastructure that creates that positive ecosystem.<br><br>So we feel like, in the call to action, we’ve created an innovative public partner &#8212; public-private partnership model where companies and organizations and governments can work together and build off of each other’s work.&nbsp; And that’s what the Vice President will be discussing in a number of roundtables with business executives and others throughout the week.<br><br>She’s also going to be discussing other elements of our strategy, which we think make the investment climate even more attractive to these companies.&nbsp; I’m talking about combating corruption, promoting rule of law, reducing violence, and, in particular, empowering women, about which I can say a little bit more now.<br><br>But I just want to underscore that we believe, and the strategy last summer articulates this comprehensively, that you need all of these pillars &#8212; better governance, anti-corruption, rule of law, reducing violence, empowering women &#8212; going hand-in-hand with the job creation to have the long-term effect that we’re looking for.<br><br>So, I mentioned some specific initiatives in the space of empowering women, which the Vice President feels strongly about.&nbsp; And tomorrow, she&#8217;ll announce further initiatives in this area.&nbsp; Again, we&#8217;ll send you a factsheet.<br><br>But she&#8217;ll be announcing new commitments from the United States government and the private sector to support women&#8217;s economic empowerment and reduce gender-based violence in the region.<br><br>Some of the companies involved in the call to action, who have all stressed the importance of women&#8217;s empowerment for economic reasons, among others, are coming together for a new initiative called “In Her Hands,” where companies and organizations are making commitments to empower, train, and protect women.<br><br>Taken together, these private sector commitments will connect more than 1.4 million women and their communities to the financial system and digital economy, accelerate women&#8217;s participation in the agro industry, train more than 500,000 women and girls in core job skills, promote gender parity, and elevate women within the companies across the region.<br><br>Additionally, she&#8217;ll be announcing some U.S. government initiatives and funding, including efforts to address gender-based violence, which goes hand-in-hand with their economic empowerment.<br><br>So, tomorrow, the Vice President will speak to these initiatives and their importance.&nbsp; She will make clear the case that when a woman has access to economic opportunities and is safe and secure, it&#8217;s not just good for the individual, it&#8217;s good for her children, her family, her community, and our entire hemisphere.<br><br>Her central message in all this is that when women succeed, all of society benefits.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what she has told the companies that we &#8212; and organizations we&#8217;ve been working with, and that&#8217;s what she&#8217;s heard from them as well.<br><br>She’s prioritized this work as part of the Root Causes Strategy, and we are really pleased to see so many organizations and companies join us in lifting up women in Central America.<br><br>Lastly, let me just mention that the Vice President will also launch an initiative called the Central American Service Corps.<br>This is a $50 million initiative that will be administered by USAID.&nbsp; We will provide young people in northern Central America with paid community service opportunities.&nbsp; They will engage on local priorities, such as education and tutoring, climate action, food security, health services, and violence prevention.&nbsp; This will help them with life and job skills and, we believe, further help address the root causes of migration.<br><br>This initiative began as a pilot project in response to the call to action by our private sector and philanthropic &#8212; philanthropic partners.&nbsp; And we are pleased that we are now able to dedicate U.S. government resources to scale it up.<br><br>It really is &#8212; and I&#8217;ll end with this &#8212; a good example of how the public and private sectors can go hand-in-hand and work together and create the sort of synergies we think we need to be successful in this area.<br><br>So thanks for listening to that, sort of, summary.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;ll be happy to take a couple of questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yeah, if our operator could re-up the instructions to get in the queue that would be great.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Given that the Vice President is focused on the Northern Triangle, I wanted to see if any Northern Triangle leaders are going to be going to the summit, and if not, what that says about her efforts to engage with them.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; What we can confirm is that the countries of what you&#8217;re calling the Northern Triangle, northern Central America &#8212; Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador &#8212; will be represented at the summit and will fully participate in the summit.&nbsp; They are sending delegations.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;ve heard from the leaders of those countries.&nbsp; And we’ll leave them to speak for themselves about whether their leaders themselves are going to come.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a call for them to make.&nbsp; Some of them have said that they aren&#8217;t going to come, but they also have confirmed that they will be sending delegations.&nbsp;<br><br>So we consider them the participants in the summit.&nbsp; Each of them had a different reason for the leader &#8212; him or herself &#8212; potentially not coming.&nbsp; But it doesn&#8217;t undermine any of what I wrote out in terms of our approach to the region.&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, we do work with and need to work with governments, and we do so where we can.&nbsp; But at the same time, we&#8217;re consistent with our principles.&nbsp;<br><br>I mentioned earlier how central anti-corruption and good governance was to making this effort work, and we&#8217;re not going to shy away from standing firm on those principles.&nbsp; And indeed, you know, he was standing firm on principles, such as inviting just democratic countries to participate in the summit and pursuing anti-corruption efforts, that may be the reason that particular leaders choose not to come.&nbsp; And we have nothing to apologize for in standing for those principles.&nbsp;<br><br>But going back to what I laid out in terms of our efforts to create economic opportunity (inaudible) hope, you&#8217;ll see that (inaudible) we&#8217;ve been, I think, remarkably successful in generating public-private partnership and private sector interest in these countries, and it&#8217;s having real results.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; I want to piggyback off of that last question for a second, because &#8212; so I know the President of Honduras, Castro &#8212; they announced on Saturday that they would be sending the Foreign Minister, but whether or not she&#8217;s attending, it&#8217;s still (inaudible).&nbsp;<br><br>I wonder if the Vice President is at all disappointed that you guys don&#8217;t know whether the President, Castro &#8212; who, you know, she obviously talked to in late May &#8212; is coming; whether you guys expect a phone call to happen in the next few days with either her or the Guatemalan President, since those are the two countries, out of the three, that Harris has talked to the most.&nbsp;<br><br>And as the President of Mexico is not coming, but we know that he&#8217;s going to be headed to the White House next month, can we expect any type of travel either on the Vice President’s side or on either of those two leaders’ sides to the U.S. in, kind of, the same fashion if they don&#8217;t make it?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Thanks for all of that.&nbsp; Just on the last thing: I don’t have any travel to announce, but I&#8217;m happy to address the three countries that you mentioned.<br><br>And I&#8217;m glad you started with Honduras.&nbsp; And I think the President of Honduras herself has said that she didn&#8217;t plan to come, and the reason that she &#8212; it was that she believes all countries in the region should be invited.&nbsp; And, you know, mainly that&#8217;s a reference to Cuba, which was not included.&nbsp;<br><br>The Vice President has a good relationship with the new President &#8212; I say “new”; it&#8217;s been over 100 days now &#8212; of Honduras.&nbsp; She went to her inauguration.&nbsp; She supports her efforts to support democracy and, indeed, fight anti-corruption &#8212; the issue I mentioned a minute ago. &nbsp;<br><br>But like I said, President Biden took a decision not to invite Cuban participation.&nbsp; This is a longstanding principle, in fact, of the Summit of the Americas which &#8212; and I think the third summit in 2001, in Canada, all of the countries participating made clear that democracy should be a core principle for this summit.&nbsp;<br><br>So we&#8217;re consistent with that collective decision, not just the U.S. one.&nbsp; And if that was the reason that &#8212; you know, as the President of Honduras, we respect her decision.&nbsp; If she wants to make a stand on that issue and feels differently, that&#8217;s obviously her sovereign right.&nbsp;<br><br>But my point on that is that it doesn&#8217;t interfere with our relationship with Honduras, with the Vice President&#8217;s personal relationship with President Castro, with Honduras&#8217;s participation in the summit &#8212; which you mentioned; they do plan to participate.&nbsp; The Foreign Minister will be here, and we look forward to fulsome engagement and follow-up.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to do all the private sector work that I described.&nbsp;<br><br>Guatemala is a different question.&nbsp; Again, I &#8212; you know, you can refer you to &#8212; I’ll refer you to the government of Guatemala for the reasons President Giammattei may not come.&nbsp;<br><br>I can only say on that: We&#8217;ve been consistent on the issue of principle as well.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve said that corruption is a core part of the Root Causes Strategy that President Biden put out an executive order on fighting corruption around the world, and we&#8217;ve been following up on that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been following up in terms of Guatemala.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m sure you saw last month we sanctioned and designated the newly re-appointed attorney general over issues of corruption.&nbsp; We set up an anti-corruption task force.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we&#8217;re just going to continue to be consistent and principled on the issues we think are important.<br><br>So, once again, it hasn’t prevented our work with the government of Guatemala or even the President of the Guatemala, for that matter, with whom we have engaged extensively.&nbsp; And it hasn’t stood in the way of the economic development that we&#8217;re trying to &#8212; and succeeding in delivering, or uplifting women and providing opportunity and empowering women in Guatemala and elsewhere.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s how I see the situation there.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, how are you?&nbsp; I wanted to ask you regarding this last question: How confident are you that these issues about root causes of migration can be addressed without talking to the government delegations?&nbsp; Because, you know, like &#8212; there is, like, civil society and other representatives, as you’ve said, that it will be interesting to talk about the bilaterals &#8212; if there are going to be any in which the Vice President is going to take part.<br><br>And another question is: Is the Vice President going to meet with the Spanish delegation with &#8212; regarding an announcement that was circulated last week about possibly both Spain and Canada &#8212; this was published by Axios &#8212; taking Central American refugees from the United States, from the border?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, first of all, on the first part, let me be clear: We are talking to and the Vice President is talking to the countries in question.&nbsp; I mentioned their representation will be here.&nbsp; Our government-to-government work goes on.&nbsp; We have diplomats in the field.&nbsp; There are lots of phone calls.<br><br>So, when you say, you know, &#8220;Can the root causes be addressed without dealing directly with the governments?” &#8212; no, we don&#8217;t think so.&nbsp; It&#8217;s very helpful to deal with the governments as we do and we will continue to do, even as we also engage civil society and the private sector.<br><br>And again, I want to be clear: All of the governments we&#8217;ve talked about will be represented here in Los Angeles and will have interactions with their American counterparts.<br><br>On the issue of Spain and Canada, let me just say: We&#8217;ll have further announcements in the course of the week about migration.&nbsp; It is one of the issues that this summit is tackling, and there&#8217;s been an in-depth conversation going on with all of the countries of the hemisphere but then also some external partners like Spain, which has been really helpful including, frankly, on the root causes in Central America issue, but also potentially on migration.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ll have more to say on that in the course of the week.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s definitely in-depth conversations going on about a regional approach to those issues.&nbsp; And the two countries you mentioned are a core part of that.<br><br>Maybe we&#8217;ll take one last question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for having this.&nbsp; Since my colleagues beat me to the attendance questions, I&#8217;ll ask about the investment.&nbsp; In terms of keeping the governments of the region up to date with your actions and your announcements, are these governments &#8212; are the governments of Giammattei and Castro, and I suppose Bukele not so much, part of these announcements?&nbsp; Are they informed ahead of time of these announcements like the Gap, Visa, and so on that you mentioned?&nbsp; Or are they just going to find out tomorrow when the embargo breaks?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The initiative that I&#8217;ve described is based in the Partnership for Central America, which is a non-governmental entity that was set up in the context of the Vice President&#8217;s call to action.&nbsp; And most of this private sector work and these discussions have been in that &#8212; in that context.<br><br>I think it goes without saying that major investments of the scale that I&#8217;ve been talking to also entail and involve contact with the government by the companies in question.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s not part of our process necessarily to engage the government as we discuss and encourage and work on these investments, but it&#8217;s also not in any way going on behind their backs.&nbsp;<br><br>They &#8212; in fact, they welcome it.&nbsp; I know President Giammattei has underscored his personal interest in making foreign direct investment a priority for his country.&nbsp; President Castro, the same thing.<br><br>So, in terms of driving this process, I think it&#8217;s fair to say, you know, we&#8217;re doing it transparently, we&#8217;re on the same page, and we have a common interest in increasing jobs and foreign direct investment.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you very much to our speaker and thank you, everyone, for joining us.<br><br>As a reminder, that was on background to a &#8220;senior administration official&#8221; and the contents are embargoed until Tuesday, June 7, 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time and 2:00 a.m. Pacific Time.<br><br>We will follow up with all of you on some supporting materials, and we look forward to tomorrow&#8217;s announcements.&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 5:42 P.M. EDT</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Vice President Harris Announces More Than $1.9 Billion in New Private Sector Commitments as Part of Call to Action for Northern Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-more-than-1-9-billion-in-new-private-sector-commitments-as-part-of-call-to-action-for-northern-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 09:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Vice President, U.S.&#160;Department of State, and&#160;the&#160;Partnership for Central America (PCA),&#160;come together to announce private sector commitments now total more than $3.2 billion Vice President Kamala Harris today announced more than $1.9 billion in new private sector commitments to create economic opportunity in northern Central America, more than doubling the value of initial private sector&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The Vice President, U.S.&nbsp;Department of State, and&nbsp;the&nbsp;Partnership for Central America (PCA),&nbsp;come together to announce private sector commitments now total more than $3.2 billion</em><br><br></p>



<p>Vice President Kamala Harris today announced more than $1.9 billion in new private sector commitments to create economic opportunity in northern Central America, more than doubling the value of initial private sector investments in response to her Call to Action.&nbsp; As part of her role addressing the root causes of migration from Central America, in May 2021, the Vice President <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/27/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-launches-a-call-to-action-to-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-the-northern-triangle/">launched</a> the Call to Action for businesses and social enterprises to make significant commitments to promote economic opportunity for people in the region. This is in support for the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Root-Causes-Strategy.pdf">U.S. Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration</a> which the Vice President launched in July 2021. A summary of progress in implementation of the Root Causes Strategy can be found <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/fact-sheet-update-on-the-u-s-strategy-for-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/">here</a>.<br>&nbsp;<br>The announcement today builds on the announcement the Vice President made in <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/vice-president-kamala-harris-announces-new-commitments-as-part-of-the-call-to-action-for-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-central-america-now-totaling-over-1-2-billion/">December 2021</a> of $1.2 billion in private sector commitments. &nbsp;Aggregate commitments under this initiative now total more than $3.2 billion.&nbsp; Taken together, these investments are creating an ecosystem of opportunity and helping to provide hope for people in the region to build safe and prosperous lives at home. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Biden-Harris Administration recognizes that long-term development in northern Central America requires more than just the resources of the U.S. Government. For this reason, Vice President Harris called upon the private sector to draw upon its resources and expertise to support inclusive economic growth in northern Central America. Over the course of the past year, the Vice President has convened CEOs and philanthropic leaders to advance this effort, and will do so again on the margins of the Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles at events hosted by the Partnership for Central America and Chamber of Commerce.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>New Commitments</u></strong><br><br>The following 10 companies and organizations announced major new commitments today, joining 30 companies that have already invested since the launch of the Call to Action in May 2021:<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Agroamerica</u></strong>:&nbsp; Agroamerica, a family-owned sustainable food and ingredients corporation, will invest more than $100 million in six new projects that will generate 1,000 permanent, living-wage jobs in northern Central America over the next 5 years.&nbsp; Future projects include a food ingredients refinery, a 600-hectares banana plantation,&nbsp;a large avocado plantation and processing plant,&nbsp;and the expansion of a Natural Ingredients Processing Plant. &nbsp;Agroamerica expects to drastically reduce food waste in the region while presenting an innovative business line for small and independent producers of raw ingredients and tropical fruits produced in Central America.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>COATL</u></strong>: COATL, a digital service firm, will invest $35 million in El Salvador to expand rural access to high-speed internet over the next 5 years by expanding and operating a highly reliable rural broadband network over existing high-power electricity lines. This work will allow equal access to a digital ecosystem in rural areas, enabling online education, financial inclusion, and e-services.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Fundación Terra</u></strong>:&nbsp; Fundación Terra, an independent foundation funded by contributions from Terra Inversiones, which works in the energy, petroleum, retail, and real-estate sectors, will invest $24.5 million in new programs over 5 years.&nbsp; These programs will support secondary education, digital access, entrepreneurship, and environmental conservation, including scholarships to tutor 40,000 students in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras in Math and Spanish, which will promote financial inclusion.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Gap Inc.</u></strong>: Gap Inc. is committed to sourcing in Central America, and their current production in Central America supports an estimated 8,200 manufacturing jobs in the region held primarily by women.&nbsp;Gap Inc. plans to increase its sourcing in Central America by approximately $50 million per year, for a total growth commitment of $150 million by 2025, as part of its strategy to increase supply chain resilience by nearshoring more production to the Western Hemisphere.&nbsp;These increased purchases from the region will support an estimated 5,000 additional jobs in Central America.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Millicom</u></strong><strong>:&nbsp; </strong>Millicom, a telecommunications company, will invest $700 million to expand and maintain its mobile and broadband networks in Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador over the next two years.&nbsp; This investment will advance Millicom’s efforts to accelerate economic growth in the region via increased connectivity as penetration rates for broadband in these markets are well below regional averages. &nbsp;In addition, Millicom’s investments will be made in line with the Race to Zero, the UN-backed campaign aimed at promoting a healthy, resilient, zero-carbon recovery.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Pantaleon</u></strong>:&nbsp; Pantaleon, a conglomerate including investments in agroindustry and real-estate, will invest $9.4 million to fund the initial phase of a 1,200-acre industrial park on Guatemala´s Southern Coast.&nbsp; Once completed, the park is expected to house a mix of manufacturing, logistics, and distribution businesses, among others.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>SanMar</u></strong>:&nbsp; SanMar, a U.S.-based apparel wholesaler, will increase its purchases of products manufactured in northern Central America by $500 million by 2025.&nbsp; These purchases will support the supply of products to SanMar’s over 60,000 customers, the overwhelming majority of which are American small businesses engaged in domestic light manufacturing.&nbsp; The increased capacity required for this growth will lead to the creation of 4,000 additional full-time jobs at Elcatex, a Honduras-based apparel manufacturer owned in part by SanMar.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Unifi</u></strong>:&nbsp; Unifi, a company that produces recycled and synthetic yarns, established its manufacturing and sales operation in El Salvador (Unifi Central America) in 2010 and has been invested in El Salvador and the region since then.&nbsp; Unifi is making significant investments in the footprint capacity and innovation of its El Salvadoran operation and has committed to investing $15 million over the next five years to expand capacity, improve efficiency, and reduce energy use.&nbsp; The investment includes new innovative texturing technology that will increase the company’s polyester yarn production in El Salvador by 40% and support continuous training and job growth in the region.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Visa</u></strong>:&nbsp; Visa will invest more than $270 million over the next five years to expand financial inclusion and digital infrastructure, with the goal of adding 6.5 million people and 1 million small and medium enterprises (SMEs) into the formal financial system in Guatemala, El Salvador, and Honduras. Visa will focus on helping the local financial sector deploy innovative payment technology, improving citizens’ financial capabilities while driving efficiencies in key areas of the economy including: agriculture, digital disbursement of government subsidies, and remittances, while also expanding financial education for citizens and SMEs, thus increasing acceptance of digital payments and bringing more people into the formal economy.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Yazaki</u></strong><strong>:&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>Yazaki North America, an automotive components producer, will invest an additional $110 million to hire over 14,000 new employees in Guatemala and El Salvador by the end of 2026.&nbsp; This builds upon a recent announcement to invest $10 million in a new factory in Guatemala, which is scheduled to start production with its first 1,000 employees in January 2023.&nbsp; Yazaki NA provides electrical wire harnesses for General Motors, Ford, Stellantis, and other global automakers.<br><br><strong><u>Updates on Previously Announced Commitments</u></strong><br>&nbsp;<br>Starting with just 12 companies and organizations, the Call to Action now includes 40 companies and organizations that have made commitments to invest in the region, representing financial services, textiles and apparel, agriculture, technology and telecommunications, and nonprofits.&nbsp; In addition, the&nbsp;Call to Action has generated new collaboration across participating companies, further boosting the initiative’s impact.<br><br>Highlights of progress to date include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Microsoft </strong>announced in December that they have expanded broadband internet access to nearly 2 million people. The company anticipates reaching 3 million individuals across the region by July 2022. Additionally, Microsoft expanded on its initial commitment and will provide digital skills training for 1 million individuals by 2025.</li><li><strong>Nespresso </strong>committed in May 2021 to support regional economies with a minimum of $150 million in investment by 2025. To date, Nespresso has signed over $100 million in contracts for coffee procurement, including the first-ever Nespresso coffee shipments from Honduras and El Salvador, which will increase incomes for thousands of farmers.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Accion</strong> through its work with partners in northern Central America, has brought over 140,000 people living in Guatemala — including 90,000 women — into the formal financial sector.</li><li><strong>Davivienda</strong> has brought over 201,000 individuals into the formal financial sector through expansion of digital services, signed a new Loan Portfolio Guarantee Agreement with the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), and extended over $100 million in low-cost loans for housing and small businesses.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>How to Respond to the Call</u></strong><br><br>The Call to Action is facilitated through a public-private partnership between the State Department and the independent organization the Partnership for Central America, in close coordination with USAID. &nbsp;The&nbsp;Call to Action’s six focus areas are intended to support long-term development of the region, including: promoting a reform agenda; digital and financial inclusion; food security and climate-smart agriculture; climate adaptation and clean energy; education and workforce development; and public health access. It serves as one component of the Biden-Harris Administration’s comprehensive Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration, which involves significant commitments of U.S. government resources to support the long-term development of the region—including by fostering economic opportunity, strengthening democratic governance, combatting corruption, and improving security. This approach will leverage commitments and resources from the governments in the region, as well as partnerships with multilateral development banks, international financial institutions, and other partner countries.<br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration looks forward to increased collaboration with private companies from around the world to build upon this&nbsp;Call to Action&nbsp;in the months and years to come. The Administration welcomes additional commitments to participate in this initiative and promote economic opportunity in northern Central America.&nbsp;Vice President Harris invites&nbsp;interested parties to visit the State Department’s website at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.state.gov/jointhecall">www.state.gov/jointhecall</a>, or contact the State Department at&nbsp;<a href="mailto:jointhecall@state.gov">jointhecall@state.gov</a>.<br><br>More information can also be found in the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/27/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-launches-a-call-to-action-to-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-the-northern-triangle/">initial Fact Sheet announcing the Call to Action on May 27</a>. More information about the Partnership for Central America can be found at www.centampartnership.org. The Partnership can be contacted at&nbsp;<a href="mailto:support@centampartnership.org">support@centampartnership.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Vice President Harris Announces the Central American Service Corps&#160;(CASC)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-the-central-american-service-corps-casc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 09:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris announced the Central American Service Corps (CASC).&#160; The CASC initiative was developed by public, private, and philanthropic partners in response to the Vice President’s Call to Action for northern Central America. CASC—a $50 million initiative, which will be administered by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)—will provide young people&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris announced the Central American Service Corps (CASC).&nbsp; The CASC initiative was developed by public, private, and philanthropic partners in response to the Vice President’s Call to Action for northern Central America. CASC—a $50 million initiative, which will be administered by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)—will provide young people in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras with paid community service opportunities, mentorship, and a path to future employment. Young people are looking for meaningful opportunities to build their futures and CASC is aimed at addressing the range of challenges youth face in the region. By supporting life and job skills, offering hope, and building confidence and a sense of belonging for youth, the CASC initiative will generate leadership potential and help foster optimism among youth in Central America that a better future is possible for themselves and for their communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>This initiative is in support of the U.S. Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration in northern Central America, which the Vice President launched in July 2021.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Central American Service Corps</u><br>&nbsp;</strong><br>Through CASC, youth will be offered opportunities to work in their own communities on local priorities such as educational support and tutoring, climate action, food security, green jobs, health education and services, violence prevention, and other civic-engagement activities.<br>&nbsp;<br>CASC will help address the drivers of irregular migration among those most likely to migrate by engaging youth in local driven service opportunities, providing a modest stipend, offering work and life skills acquisition, and enhancing young people’s sense of rootedness and commitment to their communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>Youth service programs harness the energy of young people to meet critical local development needs, while providing them a pathway to education, employment, and a sense of civic responsibility and belonging. &nbsp;Educated, healthy, employed, and civically engaged youth are critical for driving economic growth, democracy, and prosperity.<br>&nbsp;<br>CASC programs will be funded in part through FY 2022 appropriations, which included $50 million for the&nbsp; Central America Youth Empowerment Program.&nbsp; The&nbsp; initiative is a multi-sectoral effort that will benefit from technical and financial support provided by a wide range of stakeholders in the public, private, and philanthropic sectors.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Partnerships</u></strong><br>&nbsp;<br>USAID’s coordination of CASC will promote the development of a robust network of youth service corps programs in Central America. It builds on a collaboration between USAID, the Howard G. Buffett Foundation, and Salvadoran NGO Glasswing International on a youth service pilot program which launched in 2021 with $13.2 million provided exclusively by the Buffett Foundation.&nbsp; CASC also builds on a collaborative effort between the Partnership for Central America (PCA) and Glasswing International to implement a community service program for young adults in the region in response to the Vice President’s Call to Action.<br>&nbsp;<br>Further, Peace Corps will draw upon its experience in partnering with host countries Costa Rica, Paraguay, and Peru to help Glasswing and other partners establish this service initiative.&nbsp; The Inter-American Foundation will leverage its broad network of civil society grantees and partners in the region to support CASC.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, more than a dozen businesses affiliated with PCA that collectively employ tens of thousands of people across the region have committed to support CASC through such possible activities as matching participants to potential jobs, training and mentoring, facilitating financial inclusion efforts, and direct financial support.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Vice President Harris Announces New Commitments Supporting Women’s Economic Empowerment in Latin&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-new-commitments-supporting-womens-economic-empowerment-in-latin-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 09:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State, U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), and the Partnership for Central America (PCA), come together to announce programs supporting women’s economic empowerment in northern Central America and the broader Western Hemisphere Vice President Kamala Harris today announced new commitments from the U.S. government, private sector companies and organizations to support women’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>U.S. Department of State, U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), and the Partnership for Central America (PCA), come together to announce programs supporting women’s economic empowerment in northern Central America and the broader Western Hemisphere</em></p>



<p>Vice President Kamala Harris today announced new commitments from the U.S. government, private sector companies and organizations to support women’s economic empowerment in northern Central America and the Western Hemisphere more broadly. Accion, CARE International, Cargill, Mastercard, Microsoft, and PepsiCo—companies and organizations who have responded to the Vice President’s Call to Action—made additional commitments to remove barriers to women’s full economic participation and strengthen women’s access to quality employment, tools, resources, and networks for business development and growth—thereby promoting equitable economic recovery across the hemisphere. These commitments will also address gender-based violence in northern Central America—to help create safer, stronger, and more prosperous communities across the region.</p>



<p>These initiatives are committed in support of the U.S. Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration in northern Central America, which the Vice President launched in July 2021.</p>



<p><strong><u>Private Sector and Civil Society Commitments</u></strong></p>



<p>Today, the Vice President and the Partnership for Central America launched <a href="https://www.centampartnership.org/inherhands"><strong><em>In Her Hands</em></strong></a> as a private sector initiative to empower, train, and protect women in northern Central America and across the Western Hemisphere. Founding members are a coalition of companies and organizations who responded to Vice President Harris’s Call to Action, including CARE, Cargill, Mastercard, Microsoft, Millicom, Nespresso, PepsiCo, PriceSmart, and Pro Mujer.</p>



<p><strong>The integrated <em>In Her Hands</em> commitments will connect more than 1.4 million women and their communities to the financial system and digital economy, accelerate women’s participation in the agroindustry, train more than 500,000 women and girls in core job skills, promote gender parity, and elevate women within companies across the region.</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Establishing a Gender Equity Center</strong>: As a follow up to its December 2021 commitment in response to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/vice-president-kamala-harris-announces-new-commitments-as-part-of-the-call-to-action-for-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-central-america-now-totaling-over-1-2-billion/">the Vice President&#8217;s Call to Action</a> humanitarian organization CARE officially established the Center for Gender Equity in Central America. The Center is designed to empower 500,000 individual women and their families&#8211;providing benefits to a total of two million people to advance efforts to address the root causes of migration. The Center will leverage CARE’s gender and development expertise and deep connections to local partners and women&#8217;s organizations to support financial inclusion, women’s economic empowerment (including in the protection of labor rights and in supporting entrepreneurship), improved agricultural outcomes, prevention and reductions in gender-based violence.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Integrating Women into the Financial</strong><strong> Sector:</strong> Accion, with support from the Mastercard Center for Inclusive Growth, will partner with local institutions to connect over 300,000 Guatemalan women to the financial sector by 2025. In addition, PriceSmart, INCAE Business School, Mastercard, and Cargill will work with the Central American Institute of Business Administration to support 120 women-led small-and-medium enterprises (SMEs) in Honduras and Guatemala in increasing their access to markets and capital to grow their businesses and support job growth in areas of high-out migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting Female Agricultural Workers</strong><strong>:</strong> Cargill has committed to empowering women in northern Central America’s agriculture sector by allocating a portion of its $160 million commitment in commercial and charitable investments made in December 2021 to establish new programs that will support and accelerate women’s participation in the agroindustry.&nbsp; One of these programs, a partnership with the global development organization ACDI/VOCA and their Transforming Market Systems program will provide grants to women-owned small businesses in Honduras to create thousands of jobs. These programs will facilitate women’s access to financing, provide them with training, and connect them to new markets to grow their businesses. To help empower women and increase employment among female farmers, Nespresso will roll out programs in El Salvador and Honduras in 2022 that will train its agronomists on gender equity. Finally, PepsiCo Latin America will bring the Next Generation Agriculture Fund to Guatemala, in partnership with the Interamerican Development Bank and a local implementing partner.&nbsp; The program will accelerate women’s participation in the agroindustry and increase their incomes.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Digitizing Women-owned Businesses:</strong> &nbsp;Mastercard will digitize 300,000 women-owned and led businesses in Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador by 2025. This commitment will build on Mastercard’s May 2021 commitment to&nbsp;bring five million people in the region into the financial system and digitize&nbsp;one million micro and small businesses in the three countries by ensuring Mastercard’s efforts reach women across the region. &nbsp;Additionally, Accion will partner with key stakeholders in El Salvador and Honduras to expand digital services to over 700,000 people within the next five years. Microsoft will also work with local partners to launch high-tech digital community centers in 20 new communities across the region to provide women and girls with internet, digital skills, devices, educational experiences, and mentorship in rural and high-migration areas.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Training Women in Critical Job Skills</strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp; Microsoft will partner with Trust for the Americas to expand on its commitment to provide cybersecurity, coding, and artificial intelligence skills training to reach an additional 400,000 women, bringing the total number of beneficiaries to more than 500,000 women in Central America. Through a partnership with Pro Mujer, Microsoft will assist 146 organizations in the region to provide financial literacy and education programs to nearly 25,000 low-income women. Additionally, Mastercard will support 5,000 girls to pursue a future career in Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics through its award-winning Girls4Tech program. Millicom will also provide digital skills training for more than 8,000 adolescent girls and adult women in 2022—with a commitment to year-over-year increases—in the three countries of northern Central America through its <em>Conectadas </em>program. &nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Achieving Gender Parity: <a>&nbsp;</a></strong>PepsiCo will launch a fellowship program designed to elevate more women in PepsiCo with a goal to achieve equal representation at management levels in the company by 2025. &nbsp;Millicom similarly committed to achieve gender parity across its 22,000-employee organization by 2030.&nbsp; To ensure long-term sustainability of their gender commitments, anchor members of the Partnership for Central America, Mastercard, Microsoft, Nespresso, and Cargill will integrate CARE’s gender equity framework into their programming.&nbsp; This will build off examples from Nepal, Australia, France, Canada, and the United States to improve gender integration, strengthen capacity, and set new performance targets.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Elevating Women Within Companies:</strong>&nbsp; The World Economic Forum committed to launching a Gender&nbsp;Parity&nbsp;Accelerator&nbsp;focusing on economic empowerment in Central America. Building off the models deployed elsewhere in Latin America, the Accelerator will reskill women to prepare them for high-growth sectors, work to enhance work quality and pay standards, enhance social safety nets, and advance more women into management and leadership positions, with targets for women in leadership across government and business.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>U.S. Government Announcements</u></strong></p>



<p>Building off her leadership of collaborative public-private partnerships to address key challenges in the region, the Vice President announced the following U.S. government initiatives to complement private sector commitments to empower women and girls in the Latin American region:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Gender-Based Violence (“GBV”) Prevention, Protection, and Accountability Initiative:&nbsp;</strong>The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) announced new programs in northern Central America to end the scourge of GBV.&nbsp; In Guatemala, a new $6.5 million program will provide access to violence prevention interventions and services while increasing the capacity of local institutions and service providers.&nbsp; In Honduras, USAID will dedicate $2.7 million to strengthen access to security and justice for GBV survivors, as part of a broader investment in the judicial sector. The initiative will work with each country’s justice system to address crimes, especially those that are drivers of migration, such as GBV, homicide, extortion, and corruption, as well as human trafficking. This builds off a recently-announced program in El Salvador, the $35 million GBV Prevention, Protection, and Accountability Initiative, which will support prevention, protection for survivors, and increasing accountability for perpetrators.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>GBV Analysis and Roadmap:&nbsp; </strong>USAID’s new initiative will advance efforts to prevent sexual, gender-based, and domestic violence; hold perpetrators accountable; and protect and provide services for victims in northern Central America.&nbsp; Migration patterns and GBV are deeply intertwined, and individuals on migration pathways, especially irregular ones, are often at heightened risk of experiencing GBV due to their vulnerable status as undocumented migrants.&nbsp; This initiative will analyze gaps, drivers, and opportunities in preventing, mitigating, and responding to GBV in the context of migration, and offer a roadmap to inform U.S. government policies in support of the U.S. Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration.<strong><em><u></u></em></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Women’s Entrepreneurship and Labor Rights:</strong> To promote economic security for all, the Department of State will provide $4.5 million through the Gender Equity and Equality Action (GEEA) Fund to support the economic participation of women and girls across the region.<ul><li><strong>Empower Innovation Challenge: &nbsp;</strong>The State Department’s $3.5 million program will build the capacity of local civil society organizations and women-owned small businesses in Belize, Colombia, Costa Rica, Dominican Republic, Guatemala, Ecuador, El Salvador, Haiti, Honduras, Panama, and Peru. &nbsp;The initiative aims to empower women-owned micro-, small-, and medium-sized enterprises to scale their businesses through small grants, training, access to capital, networking, and partnership opportunities with local and international businesses. &nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Domestic Workers Rights Program:</strong>&nbsp;The State Department will expand&nbsp; its “Promoting the Rights of Domestic Workers in Mexico” program to protect labor rights of domestic workers and support their transition to the formal workforce. &nbsp;This $1 million project will also support exchanges between domestic worker organizations in Mexico and Guatemala.&nbsp; Program activities include national and international-level advocacy for the rights of domestic workers; training and mentorship to build the knowledge and capacity of domestic worker organizations; legal assistance for domestic workers; training domestic workers on a variety of topics related to labor rights, leadership, and professionalization; and education for employers to formalize relationships with domestic workers.&nbsp; </li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Women’s Digital Inclusion Initiative:&nbsp; </strong>The U.S. Mission to the Organization of American States (OAS), in partnership with the OAS Secretariat for Integral Development, will launch the $1.5 million “Economically Empowered Women for Equitable and Resilient Societies”&nbsp;project to increase the knowledge and capacity of women to effectively function in the digital economy, build sustainable livelihoods, and increase their participation in policymaking and leadership in their societies.&nbsp; The OAS Secretariat for Integral Development will implement the 36-month project, in partnership with Meta, which aims to build the capacity of women-led small and medium-sized enterprises to digitize, build an online presence, and access financial services and international markets.&nbsp; The initiative will benefit 18,000 women in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, as well as a select group of six Eastern Caribbean countries.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Dinner with Business Executives and Leadership of the Call to Action for Northern Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-dinner-with-business-executives-and-leadership-of-the-call-to-action-for-northern-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 03:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris tonight hosted a dinner in Los Angeles with business executives and leadership of the Call to Action for northern Central America, her effort to bring together the private sector and social enterprises to invest in and support the long-term development of the region. This dinner is part of a series of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">Vice President Kamala Harris tonight hosted a dinner in Los Angeles with business executives and leadership of the Call to Action for northern Central America, her effort to bring together the private sector and social enterprises to invest in and support the long-term development of the region. This dinner is part of a series of engagements in which the Vice President will participate on the margins of the Summit of the Americas to further her work addressing the root causes of migration from northern Central America. The Vice President believes that governments cannot solve these problems alone, which is why she has focused on bringing the private sector and civil society to the table.  In advance of roundtable meetings tomorrow, the Vice President and the business executives discussed how to further strengthen our collaboration and strategize on next steps as we continue to create economic opportunities for those in northern Central America. They also reviewed progress made thus far, including progress on the investments from 40 companies and organizations that have participated thus far in the Call to Action.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Meeting with Faith Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-faith-leaders-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 01:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris held a roundtable in Los Angeles, California with faith leaders to discuss some of the most urgent challenges facing our communities, including protecting reproductive rights and addressing the epidemic of hate that is gripping our nation. Attendees discussed the importance of protecting access to reproductive health care, preserving the right to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris held a roundtable in Los Angeles, California with faith leaders to discuss some of the most urgent challenges facing our communities, including protecting reproductive rights and addressing the epidemic of hate that is gripping our nation.<br> <br>Attendees discussed the importance of protecting access to reproductive health care, preserving the right to self-determination for individuals and families, and working together to chart the path forward. The Vice President affirmed the key role faith leaders play in bringing people together to move our country in the direction of justice, and she highlighted the constitutional rights affirmed in <em>Roe</em>, including the right to privacy, which protects the right to use contraception and the freedom to marry the person you love.<br> <br>Participants underscored the importance of ensuring that health care decisions are made by women without government interference, and the need to work together as a coalition to safeguard this right. The Vice President raised that the Louisiana legislature passed a bill that would ban abortion even in cases of rape and incest, saying the bill illustrates that there is a clear and imminent threat to the shared principle of allowing women to make decisions about their own bodies.<br> <br>During the conversation, the Vice President also raised the issue of gun violence that has been plaguing our nation. The Vice President thanked the faith leaders for the important role they play in working toward healing, hope, and unity in their congregations and communities.<br> <br>The Vice President affirmed that faith leaders are essential partners to the Administration and that she looks forward to continuing to work with them to build coalitions across faiths.<br><span style="text-decoration: underline"><br>Participants included:</span></p>



<ul><li><strong>Pastor Demetries Edwards</strong>, Pastor, 23rd Avenue Church of God (Oakland, CA)</li><li><strong>Rabbi Dara Frimmer</strong>, Senior Rabbi, Temple Isaiah (Los Angeles, CA)</li><li><strong>Rev. Edgar Boyd</strong>, Senior Minister, First AME Church (Los Angeles, CA)</li><li><strong>Nitasha Kaur Sawhney</strong>, Sikh civil rights advocate and lawyer (La Cañada, CA)</li><li><strong>Edina Lekovic</strong>, UCLA Community Scholar in Residence, Islamic Studies Program (Los Angeles, CA)</li><li><strong>Claire Lipschultz, </strong>VP of Board of Directors, National Council of Jewish Women (Sacramento, CA)</li><li><strong>Rev. Dr. Amos Brown, </strong>Pastor, Third Baptist Church (San Francisco, CA)</li><li><strong>Jackie Dupont Walker, </strong>Director, Social Action Commission, AME Church (Los Angeles, CA)</li><li><strong>Reverend Dr. Young Lee Hertig</strong>, Executive Director, Innovative Space for Asian American Christianity (Los Angeles, CA).</li><li><strong>Rev. Najuma Smith-Pollard</strong>, Assistant Director of Community and Public Engagement, USC Center for Religion and Civic Culture (Los Angeles, CA).</li></ul>



<p><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">The Vice President was also joined by:</span></p>



<ul><li><strong>Senator Alex Padilla</strong> (D-CA)</li><li><strong>Representative Jimmy Gomez</strong> (D-CA-34)</li><li><strong>Lieutenant Governor Eleni Kounalakis</strong></li><li><strong>Mayor Eric Garcetti</strong></li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before Roundtable with Faith Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Healthcare</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/06/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-roundtable-with-faith-leaders-on-reproductive-healthcare/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles County Federation of LaborLos Angeles, California THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  I want to thank these extraordinary leaders for being here today for a very important conversation that we will have about the challenges facing our nation, but our collective commitment to address these challenges in a way that inspires hope&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles County Federation of Labor<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  I want to thank these extraordinary leaders for being here today for a very important conversation that we will have about the challenges facing our nation, but our collective commitment to address these challenges in a way that inspires hope and optimism and grace and dignity and love.  And so, I&#8217;m looking forward to our conversation.<br> <br>I want to recognize and thank Senator Padilla for being here.  I watched your work in the halls of the United States Senate and you represent California in such an extraordinary way.<br> <br>Congressman Jimmy Gomez &#8212; just always fighting.  Fighting for your district and fighting for our state and for our country.  Thank you for that.<br> <br>Of course, Lieutenant Governor Eleni Kounalakis, thank you for your extraordinary leadership of our state and the work you do every day.<br> <br>And, of course, our mayor, Eric Garcetti.  Thank you.  Thank you.<br> <br>So, I think we all would agree that, in particular, these last few years have, in many ways, tested our faith &#8212; tested our ability to believe that everything will be okay, should be okay, can be okay.<br> <br>Over the last few years, we&#8217;ve experienced &#8212; as a community, as a society, as a country, as a world &#8212; so much loss, unpredictability. <br> <br>And, of course, one of the discussions that we will have today is about also what we&#8217;ve seen in terms of a rise in hate and misinformation.<br> <br>And so, I do believe &#8212; and I, my entire life, believed this &#8212; but I think we, collectively, know, in particular now: We need faith.  We need faith. <br> <br>I know that no matter the differences among us in a society, there&#8217;s so much more in common than what separates us.  And I think most people, regardless of who they are, would agree.<br> <br>We need faith in each other, in our nation, and in our future.  And so, that&#8217;s why we are coming together today with a goal of instilling in folks a belief that gives them a sense of hope and optimism in themselves, in their community and our future. <br> <br>So, the faith leaders who are gathered here today are representative of many different faiths, many different communities, but share a common purpose, which is to bring healing and hope and a sense of community to all people.<br> <br>So, our discussion today will focus on, I&#8217;m sure, a number of issues.  But in particular, there are two &#8212; which is, one, what I believe is something that requires all of the leaders at this table, which is what we have been experiencing in terms of what I call an &#8220;epidemic of hate,&#8221; where we have seen so many communities who are being targeted &#8212; individuals who are being targeted simply because of who they are. <br> <br>And we combine that then with what we have seen in terms of misinformation that now, because of this age that we are in and how quickly it can spread unchecked, how ubiquitous it is, what it does to fan the flames of hate, which, of course, has always and recently vividly manifested itself in violent acts targeting innocent people and their families and their community and our nation as a result of those acts.  So, we will talk about that. <br> <br>And also, I would like to talk with these faith leaders about the impending decision from the United States Supreme Court that we believe will undo the very principles and premise of the importance of the privacy, the right that Roe v. Wade stands for.  And so, we will talk a bit about that.<br> <br>And I will say that, on the first issue, a subset &#8212; but a very, very specific subset &#8212; that we must address is how hate manifests itself in violent acts, most of which are committed with the use of guns, and what, therefore, that requires in terms of sensible laws for any society that should be rules-based with a goal of being a civil society.  And so, we can talk a bit about that.<br> <br>And then, on the issue of Roe, it, of course &#8212; basically, the premise of Roe and the power of Roe is it is about saying that people should have the right to make decisions about their own bodies &#8212; that women should have that right and have unfettered access to reproductive healthcare.<br> <br>So, that conversation, of course, in my mind, is a conversation that requires us to also discuss whether we value the concept of self-determination &#8212; the ability of an individual to make decisions about their own life and the future of their life and the choices that will directly impact so many other choices.  The issue of self-determination.<br> <br>I do believe that when we look at the challenge that we will face when that decision comes down, a part of it will be that it will directly, if not indirectly, impact other privacy rights, including the right to have access to contraception and the right to marry the person you love. <br> <br>And how will we then &#8212; as those who are guided by our faith, who believe in the best of what we are and who we can be &#8212; how will we speak with and talk about the people who are going to be directly impacted by that decision and how we uplift them in a way that they do not feel alone and without options.<br> <br>And I think it is very important to say &#8212; and I&#8217;m going to close my comments in a moment &#8212; it&#8217;s very important, I think, for us to agree and it&#8217;s an important point to make that to support Roe v. Wade and all it stands for does not mean giving up core beliefs.  It is simply about agreeing that a woman should be able to make that decision with her faith leader, with her family, with her physician &#8212; and that the government should not be making that decision for her.<br> <br>And I can&#8217;t end my comments without mentioning that, today, Louisiana is on the path to pass a law &#8212; or passed a law that will take away this right with no exception for rape or incest.<br> <br>So, the threat to all of these principles and priorities is very clear and imminent. <br> <br>And with that, I will close by again saying that &#8212; that you all, as our faith leaders, have done extraordinary work, in particular of these last few years, to remind folks that they are not alone, that we are in this together, that there is a higher purpose, and that we should be guided by all that we know &#8212; that that gives us a chance of shining a light in the midst of dark moments and dark days.<br> <br>So, I look forward to our conversation and talking about how we&#8217;re going to build the coalition based on these shared principles and beliefs.<br> <br>And with that, I thank you all.  And I thank you.  We&#8217;re now going to thank the press for your attention, and we&#8217;re going to have a conversation.<br> <br>So, thank you, all.<br> <br>END<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
