<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 02:27:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official Previewing the Visit of Prime Minister Mustafa Al-Kadhimi of the Republic of Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/26/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-previewing-the-visit-of-prime-minister-mustafa-al-kadhimi-of-the-republic-of-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Hey, everyone.&#160; Again, thank you for participating in today&#8217;s call, which is on background and attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;&#160; The contents of the call are embargoed until Monday, July 26th, at 5:00 a.m.&#160; For awareness only, you&#8217;ll be speaking with [senior administration official].&#160; With that, I turn it over to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey, everyone.&nbsp; Again, thank you for participating in today&#8217;s call, which is on background and attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;&nbsp; The contents of the call are embargoed until Monday, July 26th, at 5:00 a.m.&nbsp; For awareness only, you&#8217;ll be speaking with [senior administration official].&nbsp;<br><br>With that, I turn it over to SAO-1.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks for joining me here on a Friday, late in the day.&nbsp; So, I think, as Jen &#8212; as Jen [Psaki] previewed from the podium earlier this week and today, President Biden looks forward to welcoming Prime Minister Mustafa Kadhimi of Iraq on Monday afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>And this visit will come in the middle of what&#8217;s really a week-long &#8212; starting middle of this week and heading into the middle of next week &#8212; events with the government of Iraq, which just demonstrates our commitment to strategic partnership under the strategic framework agreement we have with this important country.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I thought what I&#8217;d [do] for this background call is just give you some of the sense of the breadth of what&#8217;s happening and some of the initiatives that have already been announced and some that will be announced here over the coming days.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of the sequence of events, we had very senior-level meetings yesterday at the Pentagon with senior Iraqi commanders, and Secretary Austin joined that meeting.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, at the State Department, I was with Secretary Blinken for the Strategic Dialogue, in which Secretary Blinken and Iraqi Foreign Minister Fuad Hussein co-chaired a meeting of our higher coordinating committee, discussing a whole host of issues on the bilateral agenda.&nbsp; And then Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Hussein had a bilateral meeting.<br><br>And at the State Department &#8212; almost through the day, I think &#8212; still going on &#8212; are a number of breakout sessions with experts talking about various aspects of commerce, trade, education, culture, and energy, which I&#8217;ll talk about a little bit as we really move forward on these critical components of our agenda.&nbsp;<br><br>On Monday will be the meeting in the Oval Office with the Prime Minister.&nbsp; And the Prime Minister Kadhimi, of course, will have a number of events throughout the week, but there&#8217;ll be a number of counterpart meetings as well.&nbsp; Iraq&#8217;s Finance Minister Ali Allawi will be seeing Secretary Yellen, and so on and so forth.<br><br>In terms of just the &#8212; some of the &#8212; &#8220;deliverables&#8221; is a word we use for these trips &#8212; but the deliverables that we&#8217;ve been working on with the Iraqi government over the last four to five months that have &#8212; some of which have been announced and some of which will be.&nbsp; So let me just kind of roll them up so you get a sense of the breadth of what we&#8217;re talking about.&nbsp;<br><br>First, given that we&#8217;re all dealing with the COVID crisis, and particularly Iraq has been hard-hit by COVID, we are delivering 500,000 Pfizer vaccines through COVAX to Iraq.&nbsp; In addition, $155 million in humanitarian assistance to support over 1 million IDPs in Iraq, announced by the State Department.<br><br>Iraq has an election coming up in October, and there was a call by a number of very senior Iraqi leaders and also Grand Ayatollah Sistani, interestingly, also called for a significant U.N. role to help observe the election that&#8217;s coming up in October.&nbsp; And the United States led an effort in the U.N. Security Council and secured a unanimous U.N. Security Council resolution a few months ago to establish that mission.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re announcing today a $5.2 million contribution for that electoral monitoring mission.&nbsp; And again, that election is taking place in October.<br><br>We&#8217;re also contributing about $9.7 million for technical electoral assistance to Iraq&#8217;s independent High Electoral Commission through the U.N. mission in Iraq; about $1.2 million also from the State Department to restore Iraqi universities up in Ninewa Province, which are devastated by the campaign &#8212; in the occupation by ISIS and in the campaign to liberate Mosul from ISIS.&nbsp; This is part of an ongoing initiative.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been going on for a couple of years.&nbsp;<br><br>Similar to the &#8212; in the COVID bucket, about $800,000 towards facilitating high-consequence pathogen track-and-trace methodology.&nbsp;<br><br>In the climate agenda, we have a huge climate agenda with the Iraqis which I want to highlight.&nbsp; USAID funded technical assistance for renewable energy and climate adaptation with a figure &#8212; monetary figure I just can&#8217;t announce yet.&nbsp; But that is also something very much on the agenda.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll get to a couple other energy-related initiatives fairly soon.<br><br>Centers for Disease Control signing a new arrangement to work with Iraq&#8217;s public health sector to help improve their public health capacity is particularly important because Iraq has suffered from just a couple horrific hospital fires over the past few months that have just been devastating.&nbsp; And we want to help them as best we can through our expertise and technical advice to get a handle on that problem.&nbsp;<br><br>The Development Finance Corporation plans to invest about a billion dollars in Iraq to boost private-sector activity, create jobs, provide opportunities for Iraqis.<br><br>Some on the energy &#8212; on the energy front.&nbsp; King Abdullah, of course, was here this week.&nbsp; And we are in the process of finalizing arrangements for connecting the Jordanian electricity grid with the Iraqi electricity grid.&nbsp; This is a project that USAID is helping to fund on the Jordanian side and General Electric is helping to fund on the Iraqi side.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll help bring power to about a million Iraqis in southern Iraq and also some revenues to Jordan.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s a really major win-win initiative.&nbsp;<br><br>Also on the energy and climate side, if you follow these issues, Iraq flares gas from its oil exploration in southern Iraq.&nbsp; And they will be breaking ground later this fall on a &#8212; a really historic project that has been many years under discussion, and we were finally able to get it over the line.&nbsp; And it&#8217;ll be a gas capture project.&nbsp; Baker Hughes is a part of this project.&nbsp; But it&#8217;ll capture about 5.2 million cubic meters of flared gas every day.&nbsp;<br><br>And just why that&#8217;s so important not only for Iraq&#8217;s own energy needs, which are critical, but also these &#8212; this flared gas in southern Iraq contributes about 10 percent of flared emissions of greenhouse gases worldwide.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s a critical not only energy initiative, but also on the on the climate side, which is obviously central to our agenda here in the Biden administration.<br><br>So, that&#8217;s just, like, a peek of what is under discussion.&nbsp; It is truly an enormous agenda.<br><br>Of course, there have been talks, yesterday, at the Pentagon on the security side and military side.&nbsp; We are in Iraq at their invitation to help Iraq&#8217;s capacity Security Forces and Peshmerga in the campaign against ISIS.<br><br>We&#8217;ve &#8212; are completing the fourth Strategic Dialogue.&nbsp; There were two last year in 2020.&nbsp; And two &#8212; there was one in April.&nbsp; This will be the final one.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll talk about &#8212; still under discussion, but we&#8217;re talking about shifting to a new phase in the campaign in which we very much complete the combat mission against ISIS and shift to an advisory and training mission by the end of the year.<br><br>So, I know that has been in the news.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that is a part of the visit, but just one piece of this &#8212; of this, overall, just massive agenda between our two countries.<br><br>Of course, all of this will be discussed between the two leaders on Monday, and we&#8217;re very much looking forward to the meeting.&nbsp; And I am happy to answer any of your questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official], thanks for doing this.&nbsp; And thanks, [senior administration official], for making it happen.&nbsp; First, a housekeeping matter: Can you tell us what time the Oval meeting is and what you know of the &#8212; you know, sort of, like, will there be a pool spray?&nbsp; Are they doing a press conference?&nbsp; That kind of stuff, like the logistics.&nbsp; And then, I have a policy question after that.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I believe it&#8217;s at two o&#8217;clock and likely a pool spray at the top.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That is correct to both.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not a side by side, like two-and-two press conference?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That is correct.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think they&#8217;ll both &#8212; they&#8217;ll both make remarks in the Oval, similar to King Abdullah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, yeah.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, you just mentioned, a moment ago, the discussion at the Pentagon and the larger discussions that have been taking place before that toward ending the combat mission.&nbsp; Do you anticipate that the President will be able to announce &#8212; you know, put a period on the end of that sentence, basically, on Monday, and say, &#8220;We are ending combat operations this year…&#8221; on a certain day?&nbsp; You know, something like that.&nbsp; What would that look like?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, I&#8217;m confident of that.&nbsp; There will be a communiqué issued, probably at the end of the day on Monday.&nbsp; It will be a broad communiqué, kind of wrapping up many of these initiatives that I discussed, and similar to prior Strategic Dialogue communiqués.&nbsp; There have been <s>four</s> [three] of them, so you can go see those.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think something similar to that, and I think it will make very clear that this has been an evolution.&nbsp; So when the Strategic Dialogues began, I think there were about 9,000 U.S. forces in the country.&nbsp; Each Strategic Dialogue has resulted in an a &#8212; in a communiqué and an arrangement agreement about consolidation, redeployment of forces, and there has been a consolidation.<br><br>So, I defer to DOD, but I think we&#8217;re down (inaudible) 2,500 troops or so in the country doing a variety of things, really helping the Iraqis continue to build their capacity.<br><br>Iraq has also reached out to NATO &#8212; NATO training mission and other coalition partners to train and support Iraqi forces.&nbsp; And again, I think those are very important initiatives.<br><br>So, to put a period on your question about whether we&#8217;ll have a period on it: Yes, a statement, a communiqué will come out on Monday.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re excited about that.&nbsp; And that will wrap up, I think, the entire breadth of what I, kind of, conveyed up top.&nbsp; And there will be a security component in the communiqué as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you guys hear me?&nbsp; Hello?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, sorry about that.&nbsp; So &#8212; and to put a period at the end of that.&nbsp; Is that period that the combat mission will end at the end of 2021?&nbsp;<br><br>And secondly, just, I guess, more broadly, it seems like Iraqis want to be able to say there&#8217;ll be no combat troops, but the combat mission seems to have been done, for all intents and purposes, for some time now.&nbsp; So is this really more of something about semantics than actually a really great shift in what&#8217;s happening on the ground?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, no, I wouldn&#8217;t say that.&nbsp; I think if you, you know, look at the <s>four</s> [three] Strategic Dialogues and a significant evolution from our Presidents at the height of that until now, and then between now and the end of the year, I think you can anticipate additional adjustments.&nbsp;<br><br>But what the communiqué will also make clear and what the Iraqis have made clear and Prime Minister Kadhimi himself, I think, in an interview with The Washington Post has made clear is that, as this evolution continues, and as we formally end the combat mission and make clear that there are no American forces with a combat role in the country, Iraq has requested, and we very much agree, that they need continued training; support with logistics, intelligence, advisory capacity building &#8212; all of which will continue.<br><br>So, it’s far more than semantics.&nbsp; And if you look at what’s happened over the last <s>four</s> [three] Strategic Dialogues from where we were at that point to where we are now, and then between now and the end of the year &#8212; I don’t want to get into numbers or anything like that, and I think in none of the Strategic Dialogues were those types of details put out.&nbsp;<br><br>But no, it’s &#8212; you know, it’s a significant evolution and I think it’s something that we feel good about, just given the fact that we’ve trained about 250,000 Iraqi Security Forces and Peshmerga.&nbsp; They are, you know, battle-tested.&nbsp; They have proven very capable in protecting their country.<br><br>At the same time, ISIS remains a threat.&nbsp; And we saw a bombing in Baghdad just this week &#8212; the first one in some time, which, I think, just, kind of &#8212; just reinforces the need that we both understand and recognize that Iraq continues to need support in this kind of advisory training/capacity-building sense.&nbsp; And that’s something that will continue.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thank you.&nbsp; So, how many American forces will still be there after the 2,500 are gone &#8212; and they’ll be in this training role?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I’m not going to &#8212; I’m just not going to talk about numbers at all.&nbsp; So, I think right now we have about 2,500 in the country.&nbsp; Of course, we have a mission in Syria as well.&nbsp; But I think you’ll see a shift in roles and responsibilities, but I’m just not going to get into numbers or make predictions on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about &#8212; first, can you say: Will any U.S. troops be leaving?&nbsp; And can you define what you mean by “combat troops” and “combat forces”?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, again, I am not going to get into details of what capabilities are there, what capabilities we intend to have in the training/advisory role, for reasons I think you can understand.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, between now and the end of the year, I think a number of things will be happening &#8212; changes of command &#8212; you know, I think a number of things over the next five months.&nbsp; And I think it’s fair to anticipate adjustments as we shift to this new role.&nbsp; But I’m just not, from here, going to get into details on numbers or capabilities or anything.<br><br>But it is a significant evolution in the mission.&nbsp; I think, if you look to where we were when we had Apache helicopters in combat, when we had U.S. Special Forces doing regular operations.&nbsp; I mean, I remember those days.&nbsp; It’s a significant evolution.&nbsp; And just &#8212; so, by the end of the year, we think we’ll be in a good place to really formally move into an advisory and capacity-building role.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, yeah, sorry.&nbsp; I missed asking one last thing at the beginning, which is &#8212; I mean, you were just touching about this.&nbsp; You, maybe more than anybody in this &#8212; in government right now have been telling about what &#8212; the issue from the beginning.&nbsp; What does it look and feel like to you to be part of this, as you put it, &#8220;significant evolution&#8221; in the mission?&nbsp; I mean, it must be pretty different than thinking about those combat helicopters and the days that you were at the embassy.&nbsp; I mean, this is a long way from that, right?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, I think if you do reflect on the situation in 2014, when ISIS swept through Mosul and we had 40,000 foreign fighters pouring into Iraq and Syria, you had 50 suicide bombers a month going off in Iraq, and the Iraqi Security Forces, you know, almost collapsed, and you had a psychological collapse in the country.&nbsp;<br><br>And the Iraqis, at the time, asked for help.&nbsp; We built one of the largest international coalitions in history.&nbsp; And we began to help them claw back territory.&nbsp; And it was extremely, extremely difficult.&nbsp; I just don’t think we can under- &#8212; that can’t be understated.&nbsp;<br><br>Some of these battles in Mosul were extremely costly on the Iraqi side.&nbsp; And so, nobody ever wants to see something like that again.&nbsp; And we’re committed to making sure, as we always said from the beginning, nobody is going to declare “mission accomplished.”&nbsp;<br><br>The goal is the enduring defeat of ISIS.&nbsp; We recognize you have to keep pressure on these networks as they seek to reconstitute, but the role for U.S. forces and coalition forces can very much recede, you know, deep into the background where we are training, advising, sharing intelligence, helping with logistics.&nbsp; And that’s about where we are now.<br><br>I&#8217;d say, off the record, [redacted].<br><br>But back on background.&nbsp; So, yeah, it’s a good question.&nbsp; And I think it is a &#8212; it is an important moment to reflect on how far we’ve come &#8212; the sacrifices, particularly from Iraqis, from Syrians, the couple dozen American causalities in the campaign against ISIS.&nbsp;<br><br>And so it’s important.&nbsp; I think it’s poignant.&nbsp; And I think the fact that two leaders like President Biden and Prime Minister Kadhimi &#8212; two leaders who really believe in solving problems, in leading with diplomacy, and in working together.&nbsp; And that’s why this visit is so important.<br><br>And I just highlight there &#8212; I&#8217;m sure one of the topics in the Oval Office will be the orientation of this Iraqi government under Prime Minister Kadhimi’s leadership. &nbsp;He has worked extremely hard to kind of reintegrate Iraq into its neighborhood.<br><br>You saw &#8212; we just had King Abdullah here this week.&nbsp; And this was a topic when King Abdullah saw the President.&nbsp; King Abdullah was in Baghdad with President Sisi &#8212; a pretty historic summit.&nbsp; First visit of an Egyptian President to Baghdad since before the first Gulf War in 1991.&nbsp;<br><br>Iraq has restored its relations with Saudi Arabia and the entire GCC.&nbsp; The GCC, in fact &#8212; I mentioned the electricity connection from Jordan into Iraq.&nbsp; The GCC is also supporting and helping to finance electoral [sic] &#8212; electricity grid connection from the GCC through Kuwait into southern Iraq.&nbsp; That is a project that will take some time to get on line, but it is moving.&nbsp;<br><br>And Prime Minister Kadhimi has really kind of led these diplomatic initiatives.&nbsp; Again, just two more examples of that: Under his leadership and at his invitation, prote- &#8212; including with his &#8212; the President of Iraq, Barham Salih &#8212; the Pope visited Iraq for this historic, incredible visit to the land of Abraham in visiting Najaf; Baghdad, of course; but also Mosul and Ninewa, where all these atrocities from ISIS were committed.&nbsp;<br><br>And Iraq is also &#8212; Prime Minister Kadhimi has helped facilitate direct talks between Saudi Arabia and Iran in Baghdad.&nbsp; So a pretty extraordinary leader &#8212; diplomatically minded, pragmatic, focused on solving problems, and very similar, of course, to President Biden and our orientation here.<br><br>So, I think it&#8217;ll be a great meeting, an extraordinary meeting.&nbsp; And given the agenda that I laid up on top with everything we&#8217;re talking about, there&#8217;s a lot to talk about.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re excited about it.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I think you, a little bit, answered that &#8212; my question just there.&nbsp; But what &#8212; you&#8217;ve been &#8212; you&#8217;ve been there and you&#8217;ve seen so many of these Prime Ministers.&nbsp; What &#8212; what&#8217;s your measure and what&#8217;s the President&#8217;s measure of Kadhimi?&nbsp; And what &#8212; why is &#8212; why, I guess &#8212; and I&#8217;m making an assumption here &#8212; do you think that he has some staying power?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s different this time with this Prime Minister?&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, I think I just laid out, kind of, his outlook and what he&#8217;s working to do.&nbsp; He inherited, of course, an awful situation when he came into power earlier last year, following protests and Iraqi militias killing protesters and incredible heightened regional tensions.&nbsp; And he has worked very much to try to get a handle on that and deescalate things.<br><br>We hear now &#8212; what&#8217;s interesting &#8212; we hear now, from almost every country in the Middle East, one of their first agenda items is the importance of Iraq and the importance of supporting Iraq and the Iraqi government.&nbsp; I mean, that&#8217;s a sea change from even four or five years ago.&nbsp;<br><br>And, I think, again, that’s a testament to Prime Minister Kadhimi &#8212; just his &#8212; his orientation and pragmatism and trying to be a problem solver rather than someone who, you know, tries to use problems for his own political interests, which is something we&#8217;ve seen in the past.&nbsp;<br><br>So, you know, I don&#8217;t know if that answers your question.&nbsp; But he is, I think, a testament to his leadership is what we hear from so many other leaders in the region.&nbsp;<br><br>And again, just &#8212; you look at the visit of the Pope &#8212; that&#8217;s quite extraordinary; Iran and Saudi Arabia holding talks in Baghdad &#8212; that&#8217;s no small thing; a trilateral summit from the President of Egypt and the King of Jordan; and many other things.&nbsp; The initiatives with Saudi Arabia and the GCC and the electricity connections &#8212; the electricity connection to Jordan.&nbsp; And these are real things, and they&#8217;re things to build on.<br><br>Of course, Iraq will have an election in October, and that&#8217;s their process to sort through.&nbsp; But we have answered the call through the U.N. and with our leadership in the U.N. Security Council, which took a lot of diplomacy, for a unanimous U.N. Security Council resolution to provide the U.N. support for the election that Iraq requested.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s quite important.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s also something, I think, that we&#8217;ll highlight over the course of the week.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, two things.&nbsp; Has President Biden ever met with Prime Minister Kadhimi before, and when was that?&nbsp; And what &#8212; I know you&#8217;ve been trying to arrange a visit by the Israeli Prime Minister.&nbsp; Is that coming?&nbsp; What &#8212; give us an update on that.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, so, President Biden has met so many Iraqis, and I think this will be the first face-to-face between the President and Prime Minister Kadhimi.&nbsp; But I &#8212; they have spoken on the phone and developed a relationship. And so I think the face-to-face will be &#8212; they’ll be very familiar with each other, and I think we&#8217;re &#8212; it should be a great meeting.&nbsp;<br><br>On &#8212; I have nothing to announce on Prime Minister Bennett’s visit, but we will be looking forward to having him in Washington fairly soon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I wanted to just ask, related on Syria, that it&#8217;s a similar mission, as you know, to ISIS (inaudible) in Iraq.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you anticipate a similar kind of shift in mission.&nbsp; Or has that shift already been completed?&nbsp; Do you anticipate any change in the U.S. mission there?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t anticipate any changes right now to the mission or the footprint in Syria.&nbsp;<br><br>I would just add, as you know, just in Syria, we&#8217;re supporting Syrian Democratic Forces in their fight against ISIS.&nbsp; That&#8217;s been quite successful, and that&#8217;s something that we’ll continue.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And on that note, we will go ahead and wrap up.&nbsp; Thank you, again, for everyone for participating on a Friday evening.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, this call is on background and attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; The contents of this call will be embargoed until Monday, July 26th, at 5:00 a.m.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Bye.<br><br>END&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at Campaign Event for Virginia Gubernatorial Candidate Terry McAuliffe</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/24/remarks-by-president-biden-at-campaign-event-for-virginia-gubernatorial-candidate-terry-mcauliffe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lubber Run ParkArlington, Virginia (July 23, 2021) 8:01 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, Virginia!&#160; (Applause.)&#160; It’s so great to be back.&#160; First off, it goes without saying how much I appreciate your current governor, Ralph Northam, by the way.&#160; (Applause.) &#160;Because of the hard work of the American people, we’ve put ourselves in a position&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Lubber Run Park<br>Arlington, Virginia</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(July 23, 2021)</p>



<p>8:01 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, Virginia!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s so great to be back.&nbsp; First off, it goes without saying how much I appreciate your current governor, Ralph Northam, by the way.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;Because of the hard work of the American people, we’ve put ourselves in a position for us to control the virus instead of it controlling us.</p>



<p>Here in Virginia, COVID-19 deaths and hospitalizations are down 90 percent since January.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Fifty-four percent of your population has been fully vaccinated, eighty-two percent of your seniors &#8212; both of which are above the national average.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this pra- &#8212; this didn’t happen by itself.&nbsp; It’s due to the heroic vaccination program &#8212; one of the greatest and most complex operational challenges in American history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It happens when we all work together &#8212; the federal government, states, cities, the private sector, and all of Americans.</p>



<p>Look, it happens when you have governors like Ralph who’ve been a key partner, coordinating FEMA and the National Guard to move personnel and resources around the state to get shots in arms.&nbsp; It happens when you’re honest with people.</p>



<p>You know, I know folks are watching the number of cases rising again and are wondering what it means for them.&nbsp; Well, here’s the truth: If you&#8217;re fully vaccinated, you’re safer with a higher degree of protection.&nbsp; But if you’re not vaccinated, you are not protected.</p>



<p>And now &#8212; (applause) &#8212; what we have now is a pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; And, by the way &#8212; you know the old expression &#8212; you notice a lot of our very conservative friends have finally had an “altar call.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; They’ve seen the Lord, whether it’s on Fox News or whether it’s the most conservative commentators or governors.</p>



<p>Thank God the governor of Arkansas &#8212; excuse me, of &#8212; of Alabama &#8212; had one of the lowest vaccination rates in the country &#8212; is now &#8212; and I give &#8212; I&#8217;m genuinely complimenting her &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBERS:&nbsp; Stop line three!&nbsp; Stop line three! Stop line three!</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We love you, Joe!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all right.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all right.&nbsp; No, no, no, no.&nbsp; Let &#8212; let him talk.&nbsp; No, let &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; Look, this is not a Trump rally.&nbsp; Let them holler.&nbsp; No one is paying attention to them.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, here’s the point: Virtually all the COVID-19 deaths and hospitalizations are today among the unvaccinated people.&nbsp; And I know &#8212; I know this has gotten a bit politicized, but I hope it’s starting to change.&nbsp; It’s not about red states or blue states or guys like that hollering; it’s about life and it’s about death.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know Governor Northam is going to work like the devil to finish the job.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, Gov.</p>



<p>Look &#8212; and, of course, it’s great to be with another great friend that&#8217;s been around &#8212; I&#8217;ve been around a long time, and I&#8217;ve &#8212; seldom do I get to campaign for someone who I&#8217;ve agreed with more on basically everything. We go back all the way to roots in Syracuse, New York. (Applause.)</p>



<p>I&#8217;m talking about &#8212; and before that, I&#8217;m actually talking about Dorothy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Her roots don&#8217;t go there, but &#8212; look, she&#8217;s always been there for me and Jill when we&#8217;ve needed her most. &nbsp;She was an incredible First Lady of Virginia and she will be again.&nbsp; She is the very best.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, Dorothy, speaking of First Ladies, I&#8217;m Jill&#8217;s husband.&nbsp; Jill wanted to be here tonight.&nbsp; But if you turn on your &#8212; if you turn on the Olympics and watch Team USA, you&#8217;ll see Jill Biden standing there, cheering with them.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The Japanese Prime Minister, who was &#8212; I invited him to be the first person to come to the White House &#8212; head of state &#8212; he made it real clear: He didn&#8217;t want me, he wanted her to go.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; He is a man of incredible judgment.</p>



<p>Look, folks, now, of course, it&#8217;s great to be with my friend and your once and future governor, Terry McAuliffe.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I mean this &#8212; think about this &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Terry! &nbsp;Terry!&nbsp; Terry!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You got it.&nbsp; You’re not going to find anyone &#8212; I mean anyone &#8212; who knows how to get more done for Virginia than Terry.&nbsp; That’s a fact.&nbsp; You don’t have to wonder what kind of governor Terry will be; you know what kind of governor he was and what kind of governor he’ll be again.</p>



<p>He was a great governor of Virginia, and he’ll be even greater this time because he even has more going for him.&nbsp; And, Virginia, you got to elect him again.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You got to elect him again.</p>



<p>And I mean this: not just for Virginia, but for the country.&nbsp; The country is looking.&nbsp; These off-year elections, the country is looking.&nbsp; This is a big deal.</p>



<p>Terry and I share a lot in common.&nbsp; I ran against Donald Trump, and so is Terry.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; And I whipped Donald Trump in Virginia and so will Terry.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I tell you what, the guy Terry is running against is an acolyte of Donald Trump, for real.&nbsp; I mean, it’s just like &#8212; I don’t know where these guys come from.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I really mean it.</p>



<p>But above all, Terry and I &#8212; Terry, we share the same vision about delivering results and, maybe most importantly, why we got involved in politics in the first place.&nbsp; The very wealthy &#8212; and I respect anybody who makes a lot of money; you should be able to be a millionaire or billionaire, whatever you want, as long as you pay your fair share.&nbsp; But here’s the deal &#8212; (applause) &#8212; they don’t need me to protect them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I got involved in politics because the neighborhood I came from, the towns I came from &#8212; Scranton and Claymont, Delaware &#8212; little steel town &#8212; delivering results for hardworking people, who, if you just give them a chance &#8212; (applause) &#8212; just a chance, they never, never let the country down.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>You know &#8212; I really mean that.&nbsp; That’s not &#8212; that’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; Just, look &#8212; I’ve been in office now for six months, as of a couple days ago.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And I think &#8212; I think the administration has a lot to be proud of.</p>



<p>We’ve vaccinated over 160 million Americans.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’ve created over three million new jobs &#8212; more than any administration has in the first six months in entire presidential history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Never has it happened before.</p>



<p>We eliminated &#8212; what we’re on &#8212; we’re now estimated to be on track &#8212; the economy, not growing before the recession, before COVID, said the economy would grow &#8212; it would be three, three and a half percent.&nbsp; Now everything from the OECD to all Wall Street suggests that we’re going to grow this economy 7 percent just this year.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That is the highest growth in more than four decades in America.&nbsp; In fact, it’s the best job growth in the world right now.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And in just the past few weeks, one of the biggest tax cuts in the history for families in American with kids went into effect this last week.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ve been saying &#8212; I really mean this &#8212; it&#8217;s about time ordinary, hardworking people get a tax break.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Because that&#8217;s what it is.&nbsp; Parents should see that money going into their bank accounts right now.&nbsp; And let me tell you what it&#8217;s going to mean for Americans: We&#8217;re going to cut child poverty in half this year because of that.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, Terry and I share the same basic truth: Trickle-down economies never work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s time to build the economy from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where we are.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, by the way, the wealthy have never done poorly when the middle-class and the working-class people do well &#8212; they do well.</p>



<p>Look, Terry understands that it started with the American Rescue Plan that&#8217;s delivering immediate relief to the folks who needed it most &#8212; folks who were on the back of their &#8212; on heels, a lot of them knocked down.</p>



<p>Those rescue checks that went out to more than 80 percent of the adults and children in Virginia that provide a little extra breathing room for people.</p>



<p>My dad used to say &#8212; I really mean this &#8212; my dad used to say, &#8220;Joey, a job is about a lot more than a paycheck; it&#8217;s about your dignity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about respect.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about your place in the community.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about just having, Joey…&#8221; &#8212; and I mean this sincerely.&nbsp; When he left &#8212; lost everything in Scranton and we moved to Delaware, he said, &#8220;Joey, it&#8217;s about a little breathing room.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all people are asking for &#8212; just a little bit of breathing room, a little extra room.&#8221;</p>



<p>Look, aid for small businesses that helps them hire and reopen there doors.&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking &#8212; here it is.&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Aid to cities and counties to keep their police officers and firefighters and first responders on the job, educators on the job.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The American Rescue Plan lowered health insurance premiums for those buying into the Affordable Care Act by 40 percent on average, saving people $600 a year.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And Terry knows the work continues &#8212; that healthcare should be right, just not a privilege, folks.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And as I said when I was running, with Terry and Dorothy&#8217;s help, it&#8217;s not enough to build back.&nbsp; I mean this sincerely.&nbsp; America is the only nation in the world, when it&#8217;s faced a crisis, has come back stronger than before the crisis &#8212; the only one.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.</p>



<p>We have to build back and build back better.&nbsp; It&#8217;s amazing how that phrase has caught on around the world, isn&#8217;t it?&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>But Terry and I know, along with Mark Warner and Tim Kaine and Don Beyer and Abby Spanberger &#8212; (applause) &#8212; who are working on this in Congress.&nbsp; It means modernizing our physical infrastructure.</p>



<p>Folks, we used to invest more than any country in the world in research and development.&nbsp; We had the number-one infrastructure in the world &#8212; the best roads, highways, airports, ports.</p>



<p><br>Infrastructure is about rebuilding roads and bridges, replacing lead pipes that are poisoning our kids and the water system; delivering high-speed Internet to every single Virginian, rural and urban &#8212; (applause); making sure &#8220;Buy American&#8221; &#8212; so when we invest in the jobs, when we purchase all this, that American workers are doing the work.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not that complicated.&nbsp; It really isn&#8217;t if you fight for it.</p>



<p>Terry and I share the belief that building back better means investing also in our human infrastructure.&nbsp; You know, that&#8217;s my plan.&nbsp; It includes all the things Terry is fighting for.&nbsp; Terry and I believe that when we educate our children earlier, they do better.&nbsp; They do better.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No matter what &#8212; no matter what background they come from, all the studies at the great universities in this state and others have &#8212; in the last eight years &#8212; have pointed out that if a kid goes to &#8212; not daycare, but preschool, beginning at age three, they increase, by 58 percent, the possibility of going all the way through school and on to community college.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we support universal pre-K for three- and four-year-olds. (Applause.)&nbsp; And, Terry, if I get it done, you all aren&#8217;t going to have to pay for it here in Virginia.</p>



<p>And, look, we believe 12 years of education is not enough to compete in the 21st century economy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I want to make two-year community college available to every single American.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We can afford to do this.</p>



<p>I do have one concern.&nbsp; My wife Jill is teaching fulltime still as a community college professor and First Lady.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But Terry is going to be her boss again.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Because she teaches at Vir- &#8212; anyway &#8212; Northern Virginia Community College.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And, by the way, Terry, since the time she started working there, she&#8217;s never stopped teaching.&nbsp; When we got elected, she thought that she was going to continue to teach.&nbsp; She thought I might object.&nbsp; I strongly supported it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Teaching is not what my wife does; it&#8217;s who she is.</p>



<p>And, folks, look &#8212; look, the fact is that the idea that we are able to bring together people to give them great opportunities is totally within &#8212; you know, look &#8212; and we can afford to do this. We can afford to do this. If the very wealthy just start paying their fair share just a little bit. (Applause.)</p>



<p>Terry and I know &#8212; (applause) &#8212; how hard the pandemic has been on working families, especially women.&nbsp; About 2 million women are still unable to go back into the workforce during this pandemic due to things like not being able to afford childcare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, when I got elected to the United States Senate, I was 29 years old.&nbsp; Between the time I got elected and before I was sworn in, there was an automobile accident.&nbsp; My wife and daughter were killed and my two boys almost died.&nbsp; And, by the way, I thank all firefighters.&nbsp; It took the Jaws of Life three hours to get them out on top of their dead mom and dead sister.&nbsp; You saved their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I needed help.&nbsp; I was a senator making $42,000 a year.&nbsp; I could no longer afford daycare and someone to take care of my kids (inaudible).&nbsp; And thank God I had a sister who is my friend, who &#8212; she and her husband, without my asking, moved in and helped me raise my kids.&nbsp; My mom and my brother as well.&nbsp; I got lucky.</p>



<p>But, look, the idea, as a single mom or a single dad, working and having young children &#8212; it&#8217;s awful hard.&nbsp; That’s why Terry and I want to expand paid leave and childcare in this country.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, Terry, you and I have been talking about this for a long time.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been talking about high drug prices &#8212; how incredibly high they are and how we keep getting ripped off.&nbsp; You know, we pay more for our drugs than any major country in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here&#8217;s the deal.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a way to do it: Let Medicare negotiate drug prices.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; All of the prices are going to come down.&nbsp; And it will pay for itself.&nbsp; I promise you, I&#8217;m going to get that done.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look &#8212; and here&#8217;s the deal, Terry and I know this can be paid for.&nbsp; Look, we support asking the wealthiest 1 percent who got that $2 trillion tax cut that, in fact &#8212; in fact, not a single penny was paid for &#8212; the so-called &#8220;Trump tax cut.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And guess what?&nbsp; Just pay.&nbsp; Begin to pay their fair share.&nbsp; Corporate America &#8212; I come from the corporate capital of the world.&nbsp; More corporations are, in fact, registered in Delaware than every other state in the union combined.&nbsp; I got elected 36 years there because I was honest with them.</p>



<p>Look, fift- &#8212; right today, 50 of the biggest corporations in America of the Fortune 500 &#8212; 50 of them don’t pay &#8212; and this is not an exaggeration; check it out &#8212; not a single solitary penny in federal taxes.&nbsp; Not one.&nbsp; And they made over 40 &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, but &#8212; no, but I’m not doing this to get &#8212; I just want to make it clear to you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the deal: They made over $40 billion.&nbsp; If they just paid a minimum tax of 15 percent, they&#8217;d raise the dollars &#8212; all we need to do all this education we&#8217;re talking about here.</p>



<p>Look, you know &#8212; (applause) &#8212; when I was Vice President, the President asked me to check out what the major corporations needed the most.&nbsp; Along with the Secretary of Commerce, we interviewed three hundred and, I think it was, fifty-six &#8212; it could have been forty-six &#8212; but over three hundred and fifty CEOs and major corporations.</p>



<p>You know what they all said?&nbsp; &#8220;I need a better-educated workforce.&#8221;&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; They&#8217;re not spending any money to educate the workforce.</p>



<p>But if we want to make sure America succeeds and runs the world again &#8212; economically runs and &#8212; be the most powerful economy in the world, we should make sure that they have a chance.</p>



<p>These millionaires and billionaires &#8212; I&#8217;m not one of these guys that say you shouldn&#8217;t be able to be a millionaire or billionaire.&nbsp; But just pay your fair share.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, all told, experts in the World Bank &#8212; outfits like Wall Street like Moody&#8217;s estimate that my plan will grow the economy and create $2 million more jobs over the $16 million they said in 10 years we&#8217;d create &#8212; good-paying jobs.&nbsp; Good-paying jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>A significant amount of these jobs will pay the prevailing wage of 30, 40, 50 bucks an hour.&nbsp; Ninety percent of the jobs in our infrastructure plan go to people without a college degree.</p>



<p>Folks, we&#8217;re proposing a blue-collar blueprint to rebuild America &#8212; a once-in-a-generation investment in American jobs and families that&#8217;s going to position us to win the competition for the 21st century.</p>



<p>But we&#8217;ve got to get it done.&nbsp; And I need a partner like Terry who not only is respected in this state, but is respected by governors all across America, who knows how to get it done in the states.</p>



<p>Folks, on his watch as governor the last time, the Virginia economy boomed.&nbsp; Two hundred million &#8212; 200,000 jobs created.&nbsp; Unemployment went down in every single county, including rural Virginia, by nearly 50 percent.</p>



<p>He attracted major companies to this state.&nbsp; Look how your state grew.&nbsp; And by the way, any of you who are in the business know the first thing you try to attract a company to come to your city, your state, your town &#8212; the first thing they ask is, “What&#8217;s the highway system?&nbsp; Will I have access to interstate?&nbsp; Is the port available?&nbsp; Tell me whether or not I have broadband.&nbsp; Tell me whether or not…”&nbsp; All the things.&nbsp; All the things we’re going to build.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, look, Terry worked with Republicans to invest in education, transportation, and workforce development.&nbsp; And, by the way, Virginia has a whole bunch of veterans and active-duty military members &#8212; more than almost any state.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And guess what?&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan marked one of the biggest investments in veterans’ health in a long, long time.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It will upgrade VA hospitals that are 50 years old, reduce the shortages of doctors and nurses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>No veteran &#8212; from my son who passed away on &#8212; should pick up a phone and say, or have a wife or husband call and say, “I need help,” and say, “We can&#8217;t see you for a while.”&nbsp; We owe them immediate action.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Immediate.&nbsp; It’s a sacred obligation.</p>



<p>And I know no governor who stood up for our veterans and military families more than this guy, helping them apply their skills to good-paying civilian jobs &#8212; fields like cybersecurity and healthcare.</p>



<p>He also worked with the General Assembly to fund two new veteran care centers, including the first one in Hampton Roads region, which is hard to believe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Terry understands.&nbsp; He knows &#8212; he knows also about crime prevention as a top priority.</p>



<p>He understands how important it is funding &#8212; to find funding &#8212; from the American Rescue Plan to provide law enforcement personnel with more resources, not fewer resources.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, we need to help in a lot of ways.&nbsp; We need to do away with chokeholds and all those things.&nbsp; I agree, but (inaudible) side of this is we need them to have more social workers, more veterans, more psychological help, more psychologists.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And where it happens, it works.&nbsp; Personnel and resources, they keep communities safe.</p>



<p>And he has taken on the gun lobby to enact sensible gun safety measures without infringing on anybody’s Second Amendment right, including keeping guns out of the hands of domestic abusers.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Here’s what else: Terry is going to guarantee he&#8217;s going to move to get a $15 minimum wage.&nbsp; Think about it, folks.&nbsp; Just think about it.&nbsp; And you &#8212; maybe some of you, maybe you know people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anybody working 40 hours a week making less than $15 an hour is, in fact, living in poverty as defined by poverty in America.&nbsp; It should not happen, period.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>An amazing number of American people who are struggling have rental costs and housing costs that are at least 30 to 35 percent of their total income.&nbsp; How do you do that?&nbsp; How do you make it, especially if you have a child?&nbsp; Look, folks, housing that&#8217;s affordable &#8212; everybody is going to be in the plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, like me, when Terry thinks about the climate crisis, he thinks three things: jobs, jobs, jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It is the reason why we’re going to lead the world.</p>



<p>Let me close with this &#8212; and I’m sorry, I’m getting kind of wrapped up in this.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I need him.&nbsp; I need him.&nbsp; Look, in this election and in 2022, the question the American people are going to be asking is whether or not we’re helping them and their families &#8212; not giving them anything.&nbsp; Are we giving them a shot &#8212; just giving them an even shot?&nbsp; Do we understand what they’re going through?&nbsp; Can we deliver for them?</p>



<p>As Democrats, we have to show we do understand, and we’re delivering for them, and we’re keeping our promises.&nbsp; We just have to keep making the case &#8212; just as the Republican Party today offers nothing but fear, lies, and broken promises.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>No, listen &#8212; I mean, think about it &#8212; turning on the television every day and seeing a replay of what happened on January 6th and saying, “I was told there were a lot of peaceful, wonderful people.”</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; God &#8212; no, I really mean it.&nbsp; Think about it. &nbsp;It is bizarre.</p>



<p>We have to keep cutting through the Republican fog that government is the problem and show that &#8220;We the People&#8221; are the solution.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’re the most unique country &#8212; think about this &#8212; we’re the most unique country in the history of the world.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Every other country is put together based on race, religion, ethnicity, background, except the United States.</p>



<p>The United States is based on &#8212; the only country in the world based on the proposition that “We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all women and men are created equal.&nbsp; Endowed by their creator with certain unalienable rights.”&nbsp; Life, liberty, the pursuit of happiness.&nbsp; We’ve never met the test, but we’ve never walked away from it like the Republicans have.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have never walked away.&nbsp; And we keep &#8212; every administration, we keep moving that needle further and further.</p>



<p>Look, folks, we’re going to have to go out and win &#8212; win this thing, win races up and down the ticket.&nbsp; We got to protect your majority in the House of Delegates.&nbsp; (Applause)&nbsp; We got to re-elect Mark as Attorney General.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We got to re-elect Hala as your Lieutenant Governor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We got to elect Terry back as Governor. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp; He’s been here before.&nbsp; He knows what to do to.&nbsp; He knows how to get things done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Virginia, we did it in 2020.&nbsp; In the battle for the soul of America, the people voted.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Democracy prevailed.&nbsp; The Constitution held.&nbsp; We have to do this again.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I’ve said, time and again, no matter what, you can never stop the American people from voting.&nbsp; And they’re trying like hell.&nbsp; We have to decide.&nbsp; The power must always be with the people.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Fifty &#8212; I promise you this &#8212; fifty years from now &#8212; fifty years from now, our children and grandchildren will look back and know that it was at this moment America won the 21st century again.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And it starts now.&nbsp; Virginia, it starts with Terry.&nbsp; It starts with you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>8:28 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Call with President Ashraf Ghani of Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-president-ashraf-ghani-of-afghanistan-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 23:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Ashraf Ghani of Afghanistan.&#160; President Biden and President Ghani discussed the situation in Afghanistan and reaffirmed their commitment to an enduring bilateral partnership.&#160; President Biden emphasized continued U.S. support, including development and humanitarian aid, for the Afghan people, including women, girls, and minorities.&#160; President Biden and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Ashraf Ghani of Afghanistan.&nbsp; President Biden and President Ghani discussed the situation in Afghanistan and reaffirmed their commitment to an enduring bilateral partnership.&nbsp; President Biden emphasized continued U.S. support, including development and humanitarian aid, for the Afghan people, including women, girls, and minorities.&nbsp; President Biden and President Ghani agreed that the Taliban’s current offensive is in direct contradiction to the movement’s claim to support a negotiated settlement of the conflict. &nbsp;President Biden also reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to continue supporting the Afghan security forces to defend themselves. The FY2022 request to Congress for $3.3 billion for the Afghanistan Security Forces Fund prioritizes:</p>



<ol><li>$1 billion to ensure the Afghan Air Force and Special Mission Wing have the capabilities and maintenance to support ongoing combat operations, including by delivering additional aircraft, such as the three newly-refurbished UH-60 Blackhawk helicopters delivered to Kabul on July 16;</li><li>$1 billion to purchase and deliver key supplies for Afghan forces such as fuel, ammunition, and spare parts; and</li><li>$700 million to fund continued payment of salaries for Afghan soldiers.</li></ol>



<p>They deplored the loss of innocent Afghan lives, including through continued targeted killings, as well as displacement of the civilian population, looting and burning of buildings, destruction of vital infrastructure, and damage to communication networks.&nbsp;The United States recently announced more than $266 million in additional&nbsp;humanitarian assistance and released $300 million in development and other non-humanitarian assistance to help the Afghan people.&nbsp;The President has also requested an additional $364 million in development and other non-humanitarian assistance for the State Department and USAID for FY2022.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden urged continued work for unity among Afghan leaders on behalf of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan and the values on which it is based.&nbsp; The two leaders discussed the importance of Afghans coming together to support their common interest in security and peace, and President Biden underscored continued U.S. diplomatic engagement in support of a durable and just political settlement.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Roundtable with Transgender Women of Color Advocates</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-transgender-women-of-color-advocates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and Co-Chair of the Gender Policy Council Julissa Reynoso hosted a roundtable at the White House with transgender women of color advocates from around the country. This event was the first in a series of listening sessions that will be convened by the White House-led Interagency Working Group&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and Co-Chair of the Gender Policy Council Julissa Reynoso hosted a roundtable at the White House with transgender women of color advocates from around the country. This event was the first in a series of listening sessions that will be convened by the White House-led Interagency Working Group on Safety, Inclusion, and Opportunity for Transgender Individuals, which was <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-advances-equality-for-transgender-americans/">announced</a> by the White House in June.</p>



<p>Participants discussed the epidemic levels of violence and harassment faced by transgender women and girls of color. They noted that discrimination, homelessness, intimate partner violence, poverty, unemployment, immigration and other systemic barriers take a disproportionate toll on transgender women and girls of color and are drivers of the violence visited upon transgender women of color. Participants shared their policy recommendations for advancing economic justice, opportunity, health equity, and safety for transgender individuals. They also highlighted the strength, resilience, and hope that drive their advocacy and the importance of creating more opportunities to lift up diverse voices from the transgender community and support their leadership.</p>



<p>Ambassador Rice and Co-Chair Reynoso shared their appreciation for the advocacy and policy recommendations provided by the participants. They reiterated that the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to advancing justice, opportunity, and safety for transgender women of color and all LGBTQ+ people and families in America. They emphasized that the Domestic Policy Council and Gender Policy Council will take an intersectional approach to advancing gender equity and racial justice as they lead the Interagency Working Group on Safety, Inclusion, and Opportunity for Transgender Individuals.</p>



<p>Participants in today’s roundtable included:</p>



<ul><li>Tori Cooper, Director of Community Engagement for the Transgender Justice Initiative, Human Rights Campaign</li><li>Ruby Corado, Founder, Casa Ruby</li><li>Sage Dolan-Sandrino, youth advocate, National Black Justice Institute</li><li>Andrea “Andy” Marra, Executive Director, Transgender Legal Defense &amp; Education Fund</li><li>Bamby Salcedo, President and CEO, TransLatin@</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Iranian-American Journalist and Activist Masih Alinejad</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/readout-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-iranian-american-journalist-and-activist-masih-alinejad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Iranian-American journalist and activist Masih Alinejad and her husband Kambiz Foroohar. During the meeting, Mr. Sullivan expressed concern for Ms. Alinejad’s family and colleagues who are detained in Iran. He affirmed the U.S. Government’s strong continued support for Ms. Alinejad’s work to advance universal human rights, particularly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Iranian-American journalist and activist Masih Alinejad and her husband Kambiz Foroohar. During the meeting, Mr. Sullivan expressed concern for Ms. Alinejad’s family and colleagues who are detained in Iran. He affirmed the U.S. Government’s strong continued support for Ms. Alinejad’s work to advance universal human rights, particularly her tireless efforts on behalf of women, the Iranian people, and all those unjustly detained by the Iranian government. Mr. Sullivan noted with concern the growing practice of authoritarian regimes such as Iran targeting dissidents, activists, and journalists across international borders, including within the United States. The U.S. Government will continue to strenuously oppose these illegal actions, which violate human rights and threaten the rules-based international order.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Unexpected Urgent Refugee and Migration Needs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/memorandum-on-unexpected-urgent-refugee-and-migration-needs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Unexpected Urgent Refugee and Migration Needs By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 2(c)(1) of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 (22 U.S.C. 2601(c)(1)) (MRAA), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 2(c)(1) of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Unexpected Urgent Refugee and Migration Needs<br><br><br>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 2(c)(1) of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 (22 U.S.C. 2601(c)(1)) (MRAA), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 2(c)(1) of the MRAA, that it is important to furnish assistance under the MRAA in an amount of up to $100 million from the United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund for the purpose of meeting unexpected urgent refugee and migration needs, victims of conflict, and other persons at risk as a result of the situation in Afghanistan, including applicants for Special Immigrant Visas.  Such assistance may be provided on a bilateral or multilateral basis as appropriate, including through contributions to international organizations and through funding to other nongovernmental organizations, governments, and United States departments and agencies.<br><br>This determination supersedes Presidential Determination 2021-08 of June 11, 2021. <br><br>You are authorized and directed to submit this determination to the Congress, along with the accompanying Justification, and to publish this determination in the <em>Federal Register</em>.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum for the Secretary of State on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/23/memorandum-for-the-secretary-of-state-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a2-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;301 of title 3, United States Code, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section 652 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), and in order to provide assistance for refugees, victims of conflict,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;301 of title 3, United States Code, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section 652 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), and in order to provide assistance for refugees, victims of conflict, and other persons at risk as a result of the situation in Afghanistan, including applicants for Special Immigrant Visas, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(1) &nbsp;the authority under section 506(a)(2) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $200,000,000 in articles and services from the inventory and resources of any agency of the United States Government and military education and training from the Department of Defense for the purposes and under the authorities of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962;<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(2) &nbsp;the authority to make the determination under section&nbsp;506(a)(2) of the FAA to direct such drawdown; and<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(3) &nbsp;the authority under section 652 of the FAA to make, before any such drawdown, the required notifications to the&nbsp;Congress.<br><br>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 23, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/23/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-23-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:14 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:  Hi everyone.  Happy Friday.  Okay, a couple of notes for you at the top. Today, the Biden-Harris administration took additional steps to provide stability and relief to homeowners who are still feeling the economic effects of the COVID-19 pandemic. HUD, USDA, and the VA announced details to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:14 P.M. EDT<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Hi everyone.  Happy Friday.  Okay, a couple of notes for you at the top.<br> <br>Today, the Biden-Harris administration took additional steps to provide stability and relief to homeowners who are still feeling the economic effects of the COVID-19 pandemic.<br> <br>HUD, USDA, and the VA announced details to help people with government-backed mortgages stay in their homes through monthly payment reductions and potential loan modifications.<br> <br>Homeowners could see reductions in their monthly payments of roughly 20 to 25 percent, allowing them to remain in their homes and build long-term equity.<br> <br>We&#8217;re working hard to get the word out to Americans who may benefit from these new programs.  And thanks to the work of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau and today’s actions, most servicers of mortgages are required to provide borrowers information about these options.<br> <br>Homeowners can visit ConsumerFinance.gov/Housing for up-to-date information and more details.<br> <br>Also would note, on our delegation in Haiti, the presidential delegation is safe and accounted for in light of the reported shootings outside of the funeral.  They’re on their way back to the United States. <br> <br>We are deeply concerned about unrest in Haiti.  In this critical moment, Haiti’s leaders must come together to chart a united path that reflects the will of the Haitian people. <br> <br>We remain committed to supporting the people of Haiti in this challenging time.<br> <br>Also, a vaccine-sharing update for you:  We shipped a record number of doses to a record number of countries this week.  Twenty-two million doses went out to 23 countries, including Guatemala, Senegal, Zambia, Niger, Gambia, El Salvador, Honduras, the Central African Republic, Cameroon, Lesotho, Panama, Vietnam, Georgia, Pakistan, Tanzania, Mozambique, Benin, Morocco, Tajikistan, Colombia, Madagascar, Liberia, and Eswatini. <br> <br>Our teams across the government are working to get more and more doses out every day, but this was a record week for our efforts to provide supply to the global community.<br> <br>Finally, week ahead: On Monday, the President will host an event in the Rose Garden to celebrate the 31st anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act, which the President proudly cosponsored as a senator.  While we have much work to do to realize the full aspiration of the ADA, our country has made progress toward its goals of equality of opportunity, full participation, self-sufficiency, and respect for the 61 million Americans with disabilities.<br> <br>Also Monday, the President will welcome Prime Min- &#8212; the Prime Minister of Iraq to the White House.  The Prime Minister’s visit will highlight the strategic partnership between the United States and Iraq, and advance bilateral cooperation under a Strategic &#8212; the Strategic Framework Agreement. <br> <br>The visit will also focus on key areas of shared interest, including through education, health, cultural, economic, energy, and climate initiatives.  President Biden looks forward to strengthening bilateral cooperation with Iraq on political, economic, and security issues, including joint efforts to ensure the enduring defeat of ISIS.<br> <br>On Wednesday, the President will travel to Pennsylvania and Lehigh Valley &#8212; in the Lehigh Valley area, where he will emphasize the importance of American manufacturing, buying products made in America, and supporting good-paying jobs for American workers.<br> <br>We&#8217;ll have more details for you over the weekend as things get finalized.<br> <br>Josh, why don&#8217;t you kick us off.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Two subject areas.  First, an AP-NORC  survey found that 45 percent of the unvaccinated say they would definitely not get vaccinated.   Another 35 percent say they probably won&#8217;t get vaccinated.   Why does this opposition still exist after all the public outreach?  And should more governments and employers mandate vaccinations?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, Josh, I think &#8212; let&#8217;s take a step back first.   In December, before the President took office, the percentage of Americans willing to get a shot was in the 30s.   Today, over 68 percent of adult Americans have taken a shot.  <br> <br>So, what that shows you is that, in a relatively short period of time, we&#8217;ve been able to influence a whole lot of people to change their minds, taken ac- &#8212; take action, get a shot, save their lives and the lives of people around them.<br> <br>I&#8217;d also note that we&#8217;ve seen some encouraging data over the last couple of weeks.  The five states with the highest case rates &#8212; Arkansas, Florida, Louisiana, Missouri, and Nevada &#8212; had a higher rate of people getting newly vaccinated compared to the national average.   That is a good sign.  This is the second week in a row &#8212; I noted this last week.<br> <br>And finally, in the past 10 days, more than 5.2 million Americans have gotten a shot.  <br> <br>Now, there will be institutions, there will be private-sector companies, and others who make decisions about how to keep their communities safe.   That&#8217;s certainly appropriate, but I would just note that we&#8217;re going to continue our efforts to go community by community, case by case to convey the accurate information about the efficacy of vaccines.  <br> <br>Q    Gotcha.  Secondly, the Taliban has said that, as a condition for peace in Afghanistan, Ashraf Ghani has to be removed as President and a new negotiated government formed.  Does the administration believe that that&#8217;s in the best interest of the Afghan people and U.S. national security?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, the President and the administration supports the leadership of the Afghan people, including Ashraf Ghani.  The President was scheduled to speak with him today, I believe, and I don&#8217;t believe there&#8217;s a readout that&#8217;s come out about that call quite yet.  It may while we&#8217;re speaking here.  <br> <br>I would note that there are ongoing political negotiations and discussions that we certainly support between Afghan leaders, members of the Afghan government, and the Taliban.  And we believe a political solution is the only outcome to lasting peace in Afghanistan, but we will continue to provide support to the government in the form of humanitarian support, security support, training.  And we&#8217;ll also continue to encourage them to take a leading role in defending and protecting their own people.  <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Alabama&#8217;s Republican governor says it is &#8220;time to start blaming the unvaccinated folks&#8221; who &#8220;are letting us down.&#8221;   What do you think about that take?  Should the administration be taking a sharper tone against unvaccinated people for putting vaccinated people at risk?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I don&#8217;t think our role is to place blame, but what we can do is provide accurate information to people who are not yet vaccinated about the risks they are incurring not only among &#8212; on themselves, but also the people around them.  <br> <br>And while, if you are a young person, you may think you&#8217;re Superman or Superwoman and immune from the &#8212; from getting the virus, that is not true.   That is not accurate.   You can get very sick.  You can die from the virus.   You can also make your grandparents sick and your parents sick.  That is factual information.<br> <br>We&#8217;re not &#8212; but we&#8217;re not here to place blame or threats; we&#8217;re here to provide accurate information.<br> <br>Q    She says that she doesn&#8217;t know what else she can do at this point, that she&#8217;s hit a brick wall with trying to convince people to get vaccinated.  Is that a sign that perhaps the federal government should step in and issue mandates?  And if not, are you putting the needs of unvaccinated people ahead of the needs of vaccinated people?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think the question here &#8212; one, that&#8217;s not the role of the federal government; that is the role that institutions, private-sector entities, and others may take.  That certainly is appropriate.  Also, local communities are going to take steps they need to take in order to protect people in their communities.  <br> <br>I will say: We understand her frustration, and we understand the frustration of leaders out there and public voices who are trying to say the right thing, advocate for the efficacy of the virus, save people in their communities.<br> <br>What our role is and what we are going to continue to do is make the vaccine available.  We&#8217;re going to continue to work in partnership to fight misinformation.  And we&#8217;re going to continue to advocate and work in partnership with local officials and &#8212; and trusted voices to get the word out.<br> <br>Q    And is there something to be learned from our neighbors to the north &#8212; Canada?  They got a much slower start.  They didn&#8217;t have nearly as many vaccines as we did early on.  And yet, now they&#8217;ve shot past us, and 70 percent of their population is at least partially vaccinated.  What&#8217;s the difference between the two countries?  What can we learn from their experience?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I would say 162 million Americans are now vaccinated.  That certainly is a positive step.  We&#8217;re the first to say and we have long said that that&#8217;s not enough.  We need to ensure more people and more communities are vaccinated.  And it is now &#8212; we reached a point where there are some communities, even states, where there are 70 percent, 80 percent, or higher vaccination rates. <br> <br>Other communities where there&#8217;s 40 percent, 50 percent, or otherwise, that&#8217;s not just a health issue &#8212; it&#8217;s a huge health issue &#8212; it&#8217;s an economic issue.  We&#8217;ve seen how that can impact local communities, as it may lead to shutdowns of different businesses.  That can have &#8212; it&#8217;s an economic issue as well.<br> <br>So, of course, we work in close partnership with our neighbors, but we have 162 million Americans vaccinated.  We&#8217;re the world&#8217;s largest provider of vaccines to the global community.  That&#8217;s progress, in our view, even as we&#8217;ve said from the beginning there&#8217;s more work to be done.<br> <br>Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    Thank you.  About the economics of COVID that you just mentioned: Now that daily doses administered of the vaccine are down below 300,000 for the first time since December, we&#8217;ve heard talk about maybe updating the mask guidance.  Do you know if there&#8217;s been any talk here about updating guidance to start shutting businesses down in places that have very low vaccination rates?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  No.  There has not been, no.<br> <br>Q    Okay.  And then on crime, generally &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Can I note, though, two things &#8212;<br> <br>Q    Yeah.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  &#8212; just for your public information purposes?  One is that, while we have seen &#8212; while we don&#8217;t look at one week of data as an indication of &#8212; as you know, we talk about weekly averages &#8212; we did see larger numbers of unemployment claims in areas where there are lower vaccination rates.  We &#8212; it&#8217;s not enough data to draw a conclusion; I&#8217;m just noting it for all of you. <br> <br>I would also note that, on the American Rescue Plan, the way we designed that is for the impact and the assistance that we&#8217;re providing to communities across the country to be long-lasting &#8212; not to stop all in July or all in September.  It extends far beyond.  It was &#8212; that is a lesson learned from the past.  And so, there are different components of that package that&#8217;s providing assistance to businesses, to organizations, to communities that is going to be lasting for months to come.<br> <br>Q    Okay.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Proceed.<br> <br>Q    And then, on crime: The intersection in D.C. that was shot up last night, only about a mile and a half from here,  President Biden had lunch in that neighborhood this summer.  What is your message to innocent people who live in cities like this one who might start to get worried about getting caught in the crossfire?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I &#8212; the message is that the cornerstone of the President&#8217;s comprehensive plan to reduce gun violence is providing communities with the tools and resources they need to reduce gun crime, including in Washington, D.C.<br> <br>And there are a couple of steps specific to Washington D.C.  I mean, a lot of us live there or live in the neighboring communities, or know people who are on 14th street or in the neighboring areas.  And for people who are not &#8212; who are watching or hearing this who are not from those neighborhoods, there&#8217;s a lot of restaurants there, a lot of foot traffic.  This is a pretty popular part of &#8212; of the city many of us live in. <br> <br>It&#8217;s one of &#8212; D.C. is one of the five areas nationwide where DOJ launched gun trafficking strike forces just yesterday, which are going to for- &#8212; focus law enforcement resources across jurisdictions to keep guns out of the hands of criminals.<br> <br>D.C. is also a part of our 16 City Community Violence Intervention Collaborative, which is helping cities implement evidence-based strategies and which have been shown to reduce violence by as much as 60 percent.<br> <br>And Washington D.C. is also taking advantage of the historic funding that they&#8217;ve gotten through the Rescue Plan to bolster public safety.  So, Mayor Bowser&#8217;s budget proposal would invest $59 million from the Rescue Plan to reduce violent crime.  It would add 100 new slots to the cadet program and add $14 million for youth safety initiatives. <br> <br>So we&#8217;re certainly seeing this and feeling this, even in our community here, and it is one of the cities that DOJ is focused on.<br> <br>Q    And you just mentioned the White House is working with D.C. as part of this collaborative.  But just in the last week and a half or so since the mayor of D.C. was here, a six-year-old girl was shot and killed, a Nationals game had to be evacuated, and then there&#8217;s this incident last night where diners are diving for cover.  So, at what point would the President maybe reconsider his strategy?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say we&#8217;re just implementing our strategy, which is a multi-pronged effort to work in partnership with local leaders &#8212; including Mayor Bowser, who has been a great partner to us in this effort &#8212; to address gun violence that&#8217;s rising in cities across the country, including Washington.  And the events of the last week are just examples of that. <br> <br>Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Secretary Yellen just said, before you came to the podium, that the Treasury Department will need to take extraordinary measures if the debt limit isn&#8217;t raised by August.  And she indicated those could run out shortly after lawmakers return, possibly as soon as October.  So, does the White House &#8212; are you guys setting a deadline?  Before recess, do you want to see that debt limit raised?  And what is the White House doing to urge lawmakers to address the debt limit?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  This is like the Olympics for Bloomberg, these days.  (Laughter.)  So, I would say &#8212;<br> <br>Q    And Reuters.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  And Reuters, sorry.  And other financial outlets in the room. <br> <br>Let me give you just a little bit of context, for those of you who have not seen the letter that just went from Secretary Yellen to the Hill. <br> <br>So, this is a letter that’s standard practice for Treasury Secretaries when a debt limit is going to be reimposed, which there&#8217;s a timeline coming up at the end of this month.  That is diff- &#8212; I&#8217;m not saying you&#8217;re suggesting this &#8212; that is different from defaulting, which has never happened in the history of the United States and would clearly be a catastrophic event.  But it is a timeline for the debt limit to be &#8212; to be raised or extended.<br> <br>So, during the previous two administrations, the Treasury Secretary sent nearly 50 letters to the Hill on the debt limit, some of which were very similar in wording and asks and updates to this letter.  And raising or suspending the debt limit does not authorize new spending commitments; it simply enables the government to pay for obligations that Congresses and Presidents of both parties have already approved. <br> <br>And Congress &#8212; finally the last piece of history &#8212; has raised or suspended the debt limit approximately 80 times, which has happened under both Republican and Democratic Presidents &#8212; I will say, just for historical fact, more often under Republican Presidents.<br> <br>But it has happened under both, and it has been supported in a bipartisan way.  So, we expect Congress to act promptly to raise or suspend the debt limit and protect the full faith and credit of the United States.<br> <br>Now, it is not &#8212; I gave you all the context because it is not out of the ordinary, even though they&#8217;re called “extraordinary measures,” for Treasury Secretaries to present to Capitol Hill steps that they are going to take, even as this is being litigated on Capitol Hill.  That was the &#8212; this is what &#8212; that was what this update was to provide.<br> <br>In that letter, she also noted that the period of time that extraordinary measures may last is subject to considerable uncertainty due to a variety of factors, which are exacerbated this year by uncertainty related to the pandemic and calculations about inflows and outflows.<br> <br>So, the October timeline that she &#8212; was referenced in there &#8212; or the October 1st date, I should say, was referenced &#8212; was because there&#8217;s a very large reduction in the cash balance on October 1st &#8212; or we&#8217;re projecting that &#8212; due to outflows on that day to meet our obligations to the Department of Defense.<br> <br>So, she was giving a sense of what the timeline looks like, while not &#8212; while also conveying that we can&#8217;t give a sense, at this point, on the length of time for extraordinary measures.  We certainly expect Congress to act in a bipartisan manner, as they did three times under the prior administration, to raise the debt limit.<br> <br>Q    But given that uncertainty, is the White House communicating to congressional leaders that you&#8217;d like to see this debt limit extended before the recess for August?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m not here to set a new deadline.  I&#8217;m conveying to you the history and conveying to you that we think it&#8217;s clear Congress should act in a bipartisan manner to raise the debt limit as they have in the past.<br> <br>Q    And then just one more on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework.  Is the White House getting involved in this dispute between Democrats and Republicans over transit funding?  And are you recommending any solutions as to how that should be resolved?  Are you backing Democrats who say it should remain with the 80/20 highway transit split? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Oh, transit funding is obviously extremely important to the President &#8212; the “Amtrak President,” as we may call him.  And &#8212; but we believe that &#8212; that members can get this work done and can work through these issues quite quickly.  <br> <br>And as you know, the issue is about the balance of funding and how it would be allocated between different forms of infrastructure.  But we&#8217;re encouraged by their progress, they&#8217;re having conversations, and we believe they can work through any disagreement. <br> <br>I&#8217;m just going to go to the back because I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m not always good at that. <br> <br>Mike Memoli, do you have a question today?<br> <br>Q    Yes, Jen.  Thank you.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Okay.<br> <br>Q    We&#8217;ve talked a lot with &#8212; (laughter) &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  You didn&#8217;t raise your hand, but usually have a question.<br> <br>Q    I often do.  We&#8217;ve talked about &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;ll go to the back, back too.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>Q    Now everyone is into it.  We&#8217;ve talked a lot about this, this week &#8212; the protocols that are in place at the White House &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yep.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; to ensure the President&#8217;s safety in &#8212; with COVID-19.  But we&#8217;ve seen over the last few weeks the President has been traveling the country quite a bit.  He&#8217;s been engaging in more uncontrolled environments.  He went to an ice cream stop.  He was on a rope line for almost an hour in Philly last week.  He&#8217;s doing a campaign event today.  And we &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Best hour he&#8217;s spent probably in probably a while.<br> <br>Q    Given &#8212; I remember well how COVID changed the way he would campaign &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; last year, what &#8212; to what extent is the rise in cases that we&#8217;re seeing in this country leading any discussions behind the scenes about whether the President would continue to engage in this kind of activity in public settings where you can&#8217;t control for people&#8217;s vaccinations?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  Well, first, we&#8217;re always going to abide by public health guidelines.  And right now, the public health guidelines continue to be that if you&#8217;re vaccinated &#8212; and we expect them to continue to be &#8212; if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you&#8217;re very much protected from severe illness from the virus. <br> <br>And the President will continue to be a model in following those guidelines and also engaging with the public in a manner that, one, is his role as President of the United States and is certainly aligned with and appropriate according to those guidelines.<br> <br>As you all know, he has an event later this evening with Governor &#8212; future governor, maybe &#8212; former Governor Terry McAuliffe in Virginia, where he will be certainly engaging with people and &#8212; with people of Virginia who are making decisions about their future leadership.  But I expect he&#8217;ll be engaging as he did at events last week.<br> <br>So, nothing has changed about our approach or protocols over the past week or how you&#8217;ve seen him engage at the ice cream shop or at larger crowd events we&#8217;ve had.<br> <br>Q    And then a question about infrastructure.  With some key votes coming up, obviously, next week, again, we&#8217;ve seen the President not necessarily engaging in the kind of meetings at the White House with lawmakers on this specific set of proposals in the way we have earlier on in the process.  He&#8217;s been meeting more with outside stakeholders.  It seems like there&#8217;s an outside-in pressure campaign.  But can you give us an update on what his specific conversations might be with lawmakers involved in this process?  We haven&#8217;t really heard much about that.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He has had a range of conversations with lawmakers over the phone.  And he&#8217;s always conveyed to his team that if it would be helpful to bring members down here, as he has continued to do, he&#8217;s always happy to do that.  The door to the Oval Office is always open.  And he is available and will be through the course of the weekend, but also through the coming pivotal weeks as we work to get the infrastructure package across the finish line in the Senate and also the reconciliation bill moving forward.<br> <br>Okay, we&#8217;re going to go all the way to the very back.  Todd Gillman, I see you somewhere there. <br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  So, the Texas Democrats who broke quorum from the legislature have &#8212; they&#8217;re about halfway through their one-month quorum break.  They&#8217;ve been trying really hard to get into a meeting, even if it&#8217;s a Zoom meeting, with the President.  Is he going to meet with them?  Is he specifically not meeting with them because of fears that they are spreading COVID?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  No, he &#8212; the Vice President, who is leading our voting rights effort and our voting rights movement we&#8217;re building across the country, met with these lawmakers last week, as you all know.  And the President is very proud of their activism, their vocal support and advocacy for voting rights, but I don&#8217;t have any meetings scheduled for him. <br> <br>Q    And in a kind of similar vein regarding COVID: Will the First Lady be quarantined away from the President when she gets back from Japan? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  The First Lady will ca- &#8212; follow all public health guidelines.  I don&#8217;t believe that&#8217;s part of the protocols. <br> <br>All right, let&#8217;s go &#8212; let&#8217;s see &#8212; to the middle here.  I&#8217;m just jumping around today because, you know, trying better.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.   Does the White House have a reaction to Mississippi&#8217;s decision ask the Supreme Court to overturn Roe v. Wade? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, certainly, we are prominent sup- &#8212; or we are supporters &#8212; the President is a supporter of preserving Roe v. Wade.  That is our position.  In terms of a legisla- &#8212; or a legal reaction, I would point you to the Department of Justice.<br> <br>Let&#8217;s go to you, Patsy.  Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.   I have a question on China.  China just announced sanctions &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; against six individuals and an entity in the U.S. in retaliation of sanctions imposed by the Biden administration on Chinese officials over Hong Kong.  Do you think that this announcement will complicate or impact any plans for Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman&#8217;s visit to Tianjin?  And is the administration concerned on the escalating sanctions &#8212; a potential escalating sanctions war?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I&#8217;m not aware of any changes to her planned trip.  And certainly, we discussed not only areas where we agree, but areas where we disagree when we have engagements and diplomatic meetings.<br> <br>In terms of the sanctions, we are aware, of course, of the reports that the PRC has imposed sanctions on several individuals and NGOs, including at least one official from the previous administration.  We’re undeterred by these actions and we remain fully committed to implementing all relevant U.S. sanctions authorities. <br> <br>These actions are the latest examples of how Beijing punishes private citizens, companies, and civil society organizations as a way to send political signals and further illustrate the PRC’s deteriorating &#8212; deteriorating investment climate and rising political risk. <br> <br>These actions would follow the baseless sanctioning in March of two commissioners from the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom.  The PRC’s January sanctions on 21 &#8212; 28 U.S. officials and their July 2020 sanctions on U.S. officials and organizations promoting democracy and human rights around the world.<br> <br>Americans of both parties oppose these outrageous moves to target those who defend universal human rights and fundamental freedoms.  And Beijing&#8217;s attempt to intimidate and bully internationally respected NGOs only demonstrate its further isolation from the world.<br> <br>Q    I do have another question on vaccine sharing.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Let&#8217;s keep going &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to keep going around because &#8212; go ahead.  Go ahead, in the back.  I&#8217;m just going to keep going around so I get to more people.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  On vaccines.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah. <br> <br>Q    You’ve been asked about the travel restrictions for international travel before &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; but I&#8217;m going to try something different.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Okay.<br> <br>Q    Would the President drop those restrictions if airlines adopted vaccine passports or vaccine mandates?  I know you&#8217;ve, you know, sort of encouraged businesses to take steps to get everyone vaccinated that they possibly can. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I would say, first, that there are ongoing working groups that are having discussions about how to, hopefully, move forward to a point where there is international travel and is returning something we would all like to see &#8212; not just for tourism, but for families to be reunited. <br> <br>There are a range of topics in those discussions that are ongoing.  The President receives regular briefings on them, but we rely on public health and medical advice on when we&#8217;re going to determine changes to be made.<br> <br>Q    Has the President continued engaging with Chancellor Merkel on the subject?  I know they talked about that at the bilateral press conference the other week.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  That was raised.  He has not had another follow-up conversation with her since that point in time. <br> <br>Why don&#8217;t I go to the young man next to you.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  You know, a lot of parents are concerned about the upcoming school year.  What&#8217;s the White House doing to sort of make sure that we&#8217;re not &#8212; we&#8217;re not doing remote learning again nationwide? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, our plan and our objective and our desire and commitment is to push for and ensure 100 percent of schools are open across the country.  That&#8217;s also, of course, up to school districts to implement.<br> <br>But from the federal government, the role we have played is by work &#8212; advocating for funding in the American Rescue Plan that can help provide funding for mitigation measures for schools so that they can invest in social distancing opportunities or repairing vents that need to improve ventilation. <br> <br>We&#8217;re also &#8212; we&#8217;ve also put out public health guidance from the CDC that includes specific mitigation measures that schools can take. <br> <br>And our Secretary of Education has been focused on this issue from the first day he was sworn into office &#8212; working across school districts to share best practices and ensure we can work towards returning kids to in-school learning.<br> <br>Q    The Delta doesn&#8217;t change that, right?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Delta has not changed our public health guidelines, no. <br> <br>Okay, let&#8217;s go back to the front, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Just a quick follow-up on infrastructure.  On the transit spending &#8212; we know that&#8217;s important to the President &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; is that a red line for him?  If that is dropped from this package, would he still support it? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m not setting red lines here, but we are confident that they can work through the funding issues and that &#8212; the breakdown of funding issues between Democrats and Republicans over the coming days. <br> <br>Q    And then one other question just on Alabama, and then I have one on Hunter Biden. <br> <br>On Alabama, the big concern here &#8212; and the reason why these comments from the governor are so alarming is because of the low vaccination rates.  Right?  So, is there some concern from the White House?  And does the administration fear that some elected leaders may just get so frustrated and accept this fact that there are just some people in this country that just may not want to get vaccinated?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I didn&#8217;t hear those comments as accepting the fact.  I heard those comments as being frustrated that &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s an effort to protect the citizens in your state and trying to figure out what steps you can take to encourage people to get vaccinated and save their lives and the lives of their loved ones. <br> <br>We always knew it would be harder as more people got vaccinated.  That&#8217;s the stage we&#8217;re in now.  But we also believe that there is still opportunity through a range of approaches and tactics and partnerships with governors and leaders and civic leaders to get more people vaccinated. There a range of factors &#8212; you all &#8212; many of you have reported on &#8212; that are leading individuals in these five states with lower vaccination rates to get vaccinated. <br> <br>Some are &#8212; is the Delta variant; and reporting, frankly; and fears of the transmissibility of the Delta variant.  Some is, unfortunately, individuals are experiencing people in their communities, family members who are getting sick and getting hospitalized because of the transmissibility of the Delta variant. <br> <br>I don’t think we have com- &#8212; complex data quite yet to determine what is leading to the increase in vaccination rates in some of these states, but we think that&#8217;s an encouraging sign.  We know it&#8217;s frustrating.  We get it.  But we have to stay at it to save people&#8217;s lives.<br> <br>Q    And last, on Hunter Biden: You confirmed yesterday that he will be meeting with prospective buyers, but you also said that he&#8217;s not going to have any conversation related &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Not that he&#8217;s meeting with prospective buyers &#8212; that he is attending gallery events that had been prior me- &#8212; prior planned and announced.<br> <br>Q    There could be prospective buyers there.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He&#8217;s not &#8212; those discussions will be happening with the gallerist.  But that is different than meeting with prospective buyers.<br> <br>Q    If there are prospective buyers there, you said, yesterday, that he is not going to have any conversations related to the selling of art.  How can the administration guarantee that?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  The selling of his art will all happen through galler- &#8212; the gallerist, and the names and individuals will be kept confidential.  We will not be aware of, neither will he be aware of.<br> <br>Q    Is there anything stopping anyone from directly telling, though, Hunter Biden that they&#8217;re going to purchase his art?  And if they do, the American people won&#8217;t know who they are.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He will not know, we will not know who purchases his art.<br> <br>Go ahead, Jeff.<br> <br>Q    The President said yesterday that the 25-person COVID group is quote, &#8220;investigating every aspect of any change.&#8221;   What specifically are they doing or is he looking for them to do in regards to the Delta variant?  What information is he looking for them to bring back to him?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  You mean the CDC &#8212; or discussions with our public health experts? <br> <br>I think what he was conveying, Jeff, is that he gets regular weekly, if not more frequent, updates from his COVID team about what is happening with the virus, the rise of certain variants, including the Delta variant, and certainly steps that they suggest we take as a result.  That&#8217;s an ongoing process. That&#8217;s not new. <br> <br>So, I think he&#8217;s, of course, looking for their updates and guidance on what the spread is, where we&#8217;re seeing the spread, what impacts we&#8217;re having, and any mitigation measures they recommend we take from a public health and data-driven perspective.<br> <br>Q    On testing specifically, does the President believe that more testing should be done?  It&#8217;s fallen some 75 percent or so since November.  What specifically do you think should be done or does he think should be done on testing?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He relies on the guidance of his health and medical experts.  If they are advising that that is a factor, then certainly his role would be to advocate for expanding it if &#8212; in his role as President, but that they obviously provide recommendations publicly as well.<br> <br>Q    And final thing here: You said it&#8217;s not your role to place blame, but a President has a remarkable ability to use the bully pulpit, pick up the telephone.  It happens all the time with &#8212; with corporations and things.  What is he doing specifically with celebrities, perhaps, or with business leaders &#8212; like we saw the NFL this week &#8212; to use his power of the office to try and get some companies or groups to do mandates or make changes?  Is he doing anything himself &#8212; reaching out like this?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  You mean, aside from getting &#8212;<br> <br>Q    Aside from public speeches.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  &#8212; aside from getting enough vaccine to &#8212;<br> <br>Q    Right.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  &#8212; make sure every American is vaccinated; and donating more to the world than any other country; and ensuring we&#8217;re expanding accessibility to pharmacies, to community groups; and giving $3 billion to empower local voices to get into local communities to get people vaccinated?  I&#8217;d say that&#8217;s a fair amount that he&#8217;s done.<br> <br>Q    But you said, several times, that it&#8217;s not the role of the government to, essentially, you know, talk to private corporations.  But a President talks to corporations and leaders all the time, certainly during the Rescue Plan, when he was Vice President.  It happened all the time &#8212; talking to private corporations. <br> <br>If a corner is to be turned here on the hesitancy, is there anything that he believes that he personally can do among some different leaders &#8212; not giving a public speech, but that he can do?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I think, I referenced the $3 billion because the most powerful and impactful role we&#8217;ve seen across the country, from community to community, is engaging, educating, and empowering those trusted local voices.<br> <br>We know the President, the Vice President, Olivia Rodrigo, who we&#8217;re very grateful to, and others have been out there advocating for the efficacy of the vaccine, and we&#8217;re hopeful that&#8217;s effective.  And it can be.  And he&#8217;ll continue to do that, and we&#8217;ll continue to look to partner with more voices and more creative, you know, well-known individuals to elevate the issue of vaccine &#8212; of the effectiveness of the vaccine.<br> <br>But we&#8217;ve seen that’s &#8212; that, actually, local voices &#8212; people you may not know, who may not have a Twitter following &#8212; are actually the most powerful people in this fight, and we&#8217;ll continue to empower and fund those efforts.<br> <br>Go ahead.  Oh, Jeff, go ahead.  And then, I&#8217;ll go to Karen.<br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  Pfizer says the U.S. government is purchasing another 200 million doses of its vaccine &#8212; <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Mm-hmm.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; for children and for potential booster shots.  Can you confirm the purchase?  And can you say whether the thinking about the need for booster shots is crystallized within the administration?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  First, HHS has all the specifics, but, yes, we have made that purchase.  Here&#8217;s the bottom line: We&#8217;ve always prepared for every scenario.  The federal government is exercising an option in its contract with Pfizer to purchase these 200 million doses of the Pfizer vaccine to be delivered between the fall of 2021 and the spring of 2022 to prepare for future vaccination needs, including &#8212; as you referenced, Jeff &#8212; vaccines for children under 12 and possible booster shots, if studies show they are necessary.<br> <br>I will note, I have said from the podium many times that we were like Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts, and we were going to prepare for every contingency.  That&#8217;s the job of the federal government &#8212; right? &#8212; to ensure we have maximum flexibility.<br> <br>We don&#8217;t know if we&#8217;ll need a booster shot.  That&#8217;s going to be up to the research that&#8217;s ongoing with the FDA.  That&#8217;s not a recommendation that&#8217;s currently made. <br> <br>We also don&#8217;t know &#8212; we also can&#8217;t predict what the outcome will be of research on kids under 12.  We&#8217;re certainly hopeful.  And we don&#8217;t know which vaccine will be most effective, but we want to have maximum flexibility, so this is an effort to provide us with that.<br> <br>Q    All right.  And just one on infrastructure.  We understand that Senate negotiators are looking at repurposing COVID relief funds for hospitals and nursing homes to pay for the &#8212; parts of the bill.  Is that something the White House would support?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, there&#8217;s a range of final nitty-gritty discussions between both sides, but I&#8217;m not going to give feedback on each of the discussions from here.<br> <br>Okay, Asma, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Karen’s turn.<br> <br>Q    Karen, go.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Oh, Karen, sorry.  Go ahead, Karen.<br> <br>Q    Thank you.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Apologies.<br> <br>Q    Sort of keying off of what Jeff Zeleny was asking &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; the NFL is telling teams that they could potentially forfeit games for a COVID outbreak among unvaccinated players, and the players could lose their pay for any missed games.  Does the administration support a policy where players &#8212; or more broadly, employees &#8212; could lose pay if they are unvaccinated and cause a COVID outbreak at their place of work?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I&#8217;m not going to make a sweeping private-sector conclusion here.  What I will say is the NFL policy is making clear how they&#8217;re going to proceed with their season.  That&#8217;s their role to do.  Right?<br> <br>We certainly believe the biggest takeaway is that getting vaccinated is our ticket back to normal, and that vaccines are effective and allow all of us a high degree of protection, importantly, avoid hospitalization or death.  So, this provides &#8212; this is guidance they determined &#8212; the NFL &#8212; about how they&#8217;re going to proceed with their season.  That is their role to do.<br> <br>Q    And there&#8217;s a new model out from an organization that consults with the CDC, and it&#8217;s predicting that the current surge in cases right now could continue until a peak in mid-October.  The daily deaths potentially more than tripling where they are right now.  What can the President do right now to prepare Americans for that possibility?  He talked so much about the long winter last year.  What about a potentially long fall?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think the President&#8217;s role right now is to continue to encourage people to get vaccinated because it is incredibly effective in prodect [sic] &#8212; protecting them from serious illness, from death, from hospitalization from the virus.  That&#8217;s the most powerful role he can play at this point in time.<br> <br>George, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Hi, Jen.  This morning, the Cleveland Indians announced they&#8217;re changing their name to &#8220;Guardians,&#8221; and that&#8217;s already become an issue in the Ohio Senate race.  And the former President, just minutes ago, attacked it.  Any reaction by the President or the White House?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We certainly support their change of name.  We may be on the other side of the President &#8212; former President &#8212; on that front, I would guess.  I haven&#8217;t seen his tweet, or however he&#8217;s communicating these days.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Two questions on the vaccine.  First, you had mentioned yesterday that every individual at this White House has been, quote, &#8220;offered&#8221; a vaccine.  So, can you clarify, is the administration not mandating vaccines for White House staff?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  No, we have not mandated.<br> <br>Q    Okay.  And do you have a count or can you offer any confirmation to us on the percentage of employees who are vaccinated?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I’m not going to provide that.  I will see if there is more information to provide.<br> <br>Q    Can you offer any guidance then on how you&#8217;re confirming vaccination status of employees?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, they&#8217;re vaccinated here in the White House Medical Unit, for the most part.<br> <br>Go ahead.  Oh, Kelly, I&#8217;m sorry.  I&#8217;ll come to you next.<br> <br>Q    Two questions: One, this administration has long claimed that you&#8217;re trying to be the most transparent in history.  If that&#8217;s the case, why won&#8217;t you just release the number of breakthrough cases that you&#8217;ve had of vaccinated staffers?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think, first, we&#8217;re in a very different place than we were six to seven months ago as it relates to the virus.  And as many medical experts have said &#8212; inside and outside of the government &#8212; those who are vaccinated are protected from serious illness, most are asymptomatic &#8212; if they are individuals who are vaccinated who get the virus.  And, you know, we are in a different place in terms of the impact of individuals who may have, as you said, breakthrough cases.<br> <br>Q    But why not just provide the number?  Are you trying to hide something?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  No, but what is the &#8212; why do you need to have that information?<br> <br>Q    It&#8217;s a case of transparency, in the interest of the public, knowing &#8212; having a better understanding of how breakthrough cases work here in the White House.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, there are &#8212; the CDC tracks &#8212; and let me give you this information, too: The CDC tracks, across the country, of course, hospitalizations and deaths, as we have seen.  They also do a great deal of tracking in cohorts and ensure that &#8212; so, let me give you a little more information on this, which I think &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if it &#8212; hopefully, it&#8217;s of interest.<br> <br>So, the way that &#8212; because people have asked this before &#8212; so, the way the CDC is actively tracking breakthrough cases &#8212; there are tens of thousands of people across the country, in course, who are in what we are &#8212; what they call &#8220;cohort studies,&#8221; which the CDC is actively monitoring.<br> <br>For example, the CDC has a long-term care facility study where it is getting data from more than 14,000 long-term care facilities.  CDC has a healthcare worker study where they monitor vaccinated healthcare workers who got tested &#8212; who get tested with PCR tests every single week.  And CDC also collects what they call &#8220;passive surveillance,&#8221; which is where hospitals provide CDC with data when they identify someone who is hospitalized but has been vaccinated.<br> <br>So there&#8217;s a range of means our public health officials are tracking, across the country, across D.C., across any individuals here about who is vaccinated, who is getting the virus, getting hospitalized &#8212; hopefully not; it remains a small percentage.<br> <br>Q    And following up on the questions about Hunter Biden and his art shows.  Are there any specific procedures you can tell us that are being put in place to ensure that these conversations remain, as you say, not about the sales.  Will he get ethics training?  Will he have to report afterwards about the conversations?  Anything specific you can tell us about how you are monitoring this?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, again, I think it is certainly a commitment that has been made by all parties involved.  He is not involved in the sale or discussions about the sale of his art.  And he will not be informed of the sale &#8212; of the sale of his art and who is purchasing that art.  That is a commitment that&#8217;s been made, and we expect that all parties would abide by it.<br> <br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br> <br>Q    I wanted to ask about the CDC tracking &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; because &#8212; and you gave us some information just now, but &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; as of May 1st, they stopped tracking breakthrough cases that did not result in hospitalization or death, with the exception of those kinds of tests that you just described. Should there be a more broader net on breakthrough cases?  Would the President support that to get a better picture of breakthrough? <br> <br>And those White House employees, staff &#8212; EOP, on the campus in any capacity &#8212; who are not vaccinated, are they working here or are they working from home?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, any individual who has chosen not to be vaccinated, same as in the press corps, the public health guidance is to wear a mask.  That is the public health guidance that&#8217;s provided to employees as well.<br> <br>In terms of the &#8212; it is much more expensive than hospitalizations that &#8212; that was what I was trying to convey.  What the CDC does is they have these &#8212; they tra- &#8212; actively track breakthrough cases through these cohorts of individuals who are vulnerable populations, who are hi- &#8212; have high risks of exposure. And they, of course, incl- &#8212; as I noted &#8212; long-term care facilities, healthcare workers, and others who would be in those cohorts and categories.<br> <br>I would also note that because the vast majority of individuals who are vaccinated who get &#8212; test positive for COVID may be asymptomatic or have moderate or minimal cases, those are cases we may not know &#8212; we may not know about, right? <br> <br>Q    But they&#8217;re &#8212; the CDC says, as of May 1st, they stopped tracking breakthrough cases that don’t result in hospitalizations.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  They do track through these cohorts, which is a large swath of people who would be vulnerable or on the frontlines of exposure.<br> <br>Q    My periodic question: It’s now past &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; six months.  When can we expect to know about a physical exam for the President?  And what are the plans for that?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  There is &#8212; absolutely he will have a physical exam.  Absolutely you will know about the physical exam.  I don’t have a date for you at this point in time.  And I expect you will continue to ask, as you should.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Yeah, Jen, thank you.  This is sort of a rhetorical question &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Oh.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; following up on vaccinations.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Okay.<br> <br>Q    It is a shame that people have to get very sick and some people have to die in order to increase the vaccination rate in many parts of this country. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Mm-hmm.<br> <br>Q    But isn&#8217;t that, I guess, a logical order of how this would play out?  Or is there a political component to it, do you think? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m following your question.  Try again.  Or tell me more about what you&#8217;re looking for.<br> <br>Q    Well, wouldn&#8217;t it be standard practice that people, if more people are getting sick in a certain area, that the people in that area who are unvaccinated would say, “Gee, I really need to go get vaccinated.”  Isn&#8217;t that a logical order for this?  Or is there a political component, do you think, that has kept people away from being vaccinated? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Look, I think there are a range of reasons we&#8217;ve seen across the country why individuals have not yet been vaccinated.  Some of it is misinformation &#8212; a large amount, in our view.  Some of it is fear.  Some of it is, they may feel, time.  Some of it is they&#8217;re young, and they feel they&#8217;re Superman or Superwoman, and they&#8217;re not going to get sick. <br> <br>That shouldn&#8217;t be; we don&#8217;t want that to be the order of events.  It shouldn&#8217;t be that someone should have to know a neighbor who gets sick and hospitalized to motivate them to go to a hospital &#8212; I mean to go to get vaccinated.  We don&#8217;t want that to be the case. <br> <br>We have seen anecdotally and through some of your &#8212; all of your reporting that that has been the case in some communities.  But certainly, our objective is to communicate to people this is not a political issue, it is not a partisan issue; this is about protecting lives.  The virus does not discriminate between political party affiliation.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    The White House noted yesterday that 40 percent of cases are coming from three states with low vaccination rates: Florida, Texas, and Missouri. <br> <br>All three of those states have governors who, in recent weeks, have criticized the White House&#8217;s strategy.  One of them is even fundraising off of it, as you are probably aware. <br> <br>What&#8217;s being done to engage those governors, come up with a common message, common strategy to try and be one team with those governors in terms of fighting this virus? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say, first, our public health experts work with governors from across the country and work with local health officials from across the country in all of these states, especially the ones at this point in time where there are lower vaccination rates and we&#8217;re seeing the Delta variant spread. <br> <br>And this is one of the reasons we rely so much on &#8212; hold on, I’m going to sneeze.  Okay, hold on.  Okay, maybe it will come back.  (Laughter.)  This is wh- &#8212; sorry, (inaudible) &#8212;<br> <br>This is why we rely on local messengers and why we rely on trusted voices.  Because whether it&#8217;s the President of the United States or the governor, sometimes those aren&#8217;t the people you trust.   Sometimes that is too political or partisan for people.  We understand that. <br> <br>That&#8217;s why we rely on and we&#8217;re funding and empowering local, trusted voices who aren&#8217;t seen through a political prism.<br> <br>Q    And then on the West Coast right now, we’re seeing wildfires in Oregon and Northern California. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    What steps is the administration taking to combat the current fires and also prevent additional fires this summer?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I appreciate you asking about this because I know this has gotten a lot of attention across the country, and we just haven&#8217;t talked about it a lot.  There&#8217;s so much going on.<br> <br>One, the President receives regular reports on the wildfire situation; he&#8217;s quite focused on it.  As I think you&#8217;re probably aware but others may not be, the National Wild- &#8212; Wildland Fire Preparedness Level is at a five, which is the highest level due to significant fire activity. <br> <br>And as of today, 2.5 million acres have burned across the United States. In the past two weeks alone the number of large, uncontained fires across the United States has increased by nearly 90 percent. <br> <br>So, right now, what we&#8217;re doing: One, the President is very focused on this and wants regular updates.  He&#8217;s regularly met with Western governors, and I expect we&#8217;ll do that again soon. <br> <br>The FEMA Administrator is visiting Idaho, Oregon, and California this week to meet with state, federal, and Tribal partners and emergency groups about worsen &#8212; the worsening wildfire situation, to coordinate response efforts and discuss how the regions are addressing climate change and ongoing resilience work. <br> <br>We are also closely coordinating with officials on the frontlines to provide federal assistance as needed, including by recently approving Fire Management Assistance Grants for fire departments in Oregon, California, and Washington, which are where there&#8217;s the collective threat to homes and major communities. <br> <br>And we&#8217;re also continuing to monitor the &#8212; monitor these fires from here.  Again, the President receives regular updates and he&#8217;s quite focused on this. <br> <br>Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    On Cuba &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; Congresswoman Salazar says that the administration could turn the Internet back on for Cubans within minutes.  I guess there&#8217;s this technology to allow high-tech balloons to float over Cuba to act as towers.  What&#8217;s being done?  Or can you provide an update on restoring Internet services to Cuba? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I wish it was that easy.  We are exploring a range of options.  We are quite focused and interested in restoring Internet access to the people of Cuba, which we actually &#8212; which we absolutely believe, and agree, I would say, would provide information, would allow individuals to communicate.  And we feel if we can get it done, that would be a great step forward and beneficial to the people of Cuba.<br> <br>Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    Thank you, ma’am.  You mentioned at the top that  Republicans had also increased the debt ceiling and certainly, you know, spending has been bipartisan for many years.  I&#8217;m wondering what the President&#8217;s long-term view of the country&#8217;s balance sheets are, given that under current long-term CBO estimates, debt is never again expected to dip below 100 percent of gross domestic product, and then, within 30 years, it is projected to hit 202 percent of gross domestic product. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I would say the President has proposed a way to pay for his proposals, which is something that is a fiscally responsible step some of his predecessors &#8212; the most recent one &#8212; did not do when he worked and advocated to support the passing of $2 trillion in tax cuts that did not bear out the financial benefit he promised and also certainly added to the deficit.<br> <br>The President takes these issues seriously.  He is focused on being a President who cares about the future of our &#8212; the next generations.  And I think his actions have borne that out. <br> <br>Q    And then a quick follow-up:  There was a lot of discussion about masking the other day.  This administration has always followed CDC guidance. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    If the CDC was to say, “We need to return to masking,” would this administration follow suit?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We&#8217;re always going to follow the guidance of our health and medical experts. <br> <br>Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  On the vaccine immunity: Given that Pfizer&#8217;s now seeing waning immunity and separate from who is vaccinated and who is not, is the White House looking at models and projections that say, in the next year, as everyone who has been vaccinated could start to lose that immunity, what does that look like for hospitalizations and deaths, et cetera? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I would certainly point to our health and medical experts to answer questions about future projections about the impact of waning immunity.  I will say that as they look at this data and assess from our &#8212; from the CDC and other public health entities in the government, they certainly talked to private-sector companies like Pfizer, but that&#8217;s only one source of data and engagement.  They look at a range of data across the board as they make projections.  So we really rely on their broad data and projections as we assess what the future looks like. <br> <br>Q    Just a follow-up on Afghanistan as well: You mentioned continuing U.S. support.  Does that include continuing military support?  I mean, we&#8217;ve seen a number of airstrikes that the U.S. has launched on Taliban targets over the last 30 days.  Could that continue past the end of the military mission at the end of August?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have anything on that for you.  I&#8217;d certainly point to the Department of Defense.  But what I&#8217;m &#8212; what I was communicating about was, you know, over the coming weeks, we maintain our authorities, as you know, and we provide &#8212; we’ve provided a range of training and security assistance equipment to the Afghans and the leaders of Afghanistan as we transition to bringing our men and women home. <br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Thanks so much, everyone.  Have a great weekend.<br> <br>2:04 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 19:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Presidential Delegation to the funeral of President Moise is safe and accounted for, and those traveling from Washington, D.C. have arrived safely back in the United States.&#160; The United States remains deeply concerned about the situation on the ground in Haiti. We strongly urge all parties to express themselves peacefully, and call on Haiti’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Presidential Delegation to the funeral of President Moise is safe and accounted for, and those traveling from Washington, D.C. have arrived safely back in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States remains deeply concerned about the situation on the ground in Haiti. We strongly urge all parties to express themselves peacefully, and call on Haiti’s leaders to be clear that their supporters must refrain from violence. In this critical moment, Haiti’s leaders must work together and engage in a broad and inclusive dialogue that is reflective of the will of the Haitian people. The Presidential Delegation, led by Ambassador Linda Thomas-Greenfield, and joined by Representative Meeks and Representative Fortenberry, met with senior Haitian officials and civil society leaders and shared this message directly.<br><br>The United States will continue to provide requested assistance, including equipment and training, to the Haitian National Police and the Government of Haiti amid ongoing security challenges. Additionally, the Departments of Justice and Homeland Security are providing investigative assistance to the Haitian authorities at the request of the Government of Haiti, and will keep working closely with our international partners to support the Haitian government as it seeks to hold accountable those responsible for the assassination of President Moïse.<br><br>The United States stands with the people of Haiti in this challenging time.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How the Biden-Harris Administration Is Advancing Educational Equity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/fact-sheet-how-the-biden-harris-administration-is-advancing-educational-equity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As Schools Reopen, Vital PK-12 Investments Will Address Disparities, Build Back Our Schools on a Stronger and More Equitable Foundation, and Enable America to Compete Globally The last year and a half have been extraordinarily challenging for America’s students. As we prepare for the 2021-2022 school year, the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to helping every&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>As Schools Reopen, Vital PK-12 Investments Will Address Disparities, Build Back Our Schools on a Stronger and More Equitable Foundation, and Enable America to Compete Globally</em></p>



<p><br>The last year and a half have been extraordinarily challenging for America’s students. As we prepare for the 2021-2022 school year, the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to helping every school safely open for full-time, in-person instruction; accelerate academic achievement; and build school communities where all students feel they belong. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, President Biden understands that addressing the immediate impact of the pandemic is not enough. For too many Americans—including students of color, children with disabilities, English learners, LGBTQ+ students, students from low-income families, and other underserved students—the promise of a high-quality education has gone unfulfilled for generations. Studies show the <a href="https://www.future-ed.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Gormley_et_al-2017-Journal_of_Policy_Analysis_and_Management.pdf">remarkable benefits of preschool programs</a>, but such programs are too often <a href="https://s3-us-east-2.amazonaws.com/edtrustmain/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/05162154/Young-Learners-Missed-Opportunities.pdf">out of reach</a> for children of color and low-income children. <a href="https://edtrust.org/resource/funding-gaps-2018/">Dramatically unequal funding</a> between school districts means some children learn in gleaming new classrooms, while students just down the road navigate <a href="https://eric.ed.gov/?id=ED498100">unsafe and rundown facilities</a>. Amid a <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">nationwide teacher shortage</a>, high-poverty school districts struggle to attract certified staff and experienced educators. And students of color and children with disabilities face disproportionately high rates&nbsp;<a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/crdc-exclusionary-school-discipline.pdf">of school discipline</a> that removes them from the classroom, with lasting consequences.<br><br><a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/cge">With 53 percent of our public school students</a> now students of color, addressing these disparities is critical for not only all our children, but for our nation’s collective health, happiness, and economic security. Consistent with the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-advancing-racial-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through-the-federal-government/">Executive Order</a>, the Administration is committed to advancing educational equity for every child—so that schools and students not only recover from the pandemic, but Build Back Better. As First Lady Dr. Biden says, “Any country that out-educates us is going to outcompete us.” We will meet the challenges of the coming decades only by harnessing the full potential of every young person.<br><br>Taken together, the unprecedented investments already made in the American Rescue Plan—along with those proposed in the Build Back Better Agenda—will devote historic and vitally-needed resources that unlock opportunity for millions of Americans. These investments in evidence-based approaches will shore up schools struggling with the aftermath of COVID-19, tackle inter-generational educational disparities, address the holistic needs of children, and incentivize states to help our schools rebuild on a stronger and more equitable foundation.<br><br>To support the equitable education of every child at every step, the Administration will:</p>



<ul><li>Safely reopen schools and support students, particularly those disproportionately impacted by the pandemic;<br></li><li>Invest in high-quality early childhood education, including providing universal pre-school for all three and four-year-olds and access to affordable child care;<br></li><li>Address the national teacher shortage by improving teacher preparation, strengthening pipelines for underrepresented teachers, and supporting current teachers;<br></li><li>Upgrade and build new public schools and child care centers;<br></li><li>Expand college and career pathways for middle and high school students;<br></li><li>Make a historic $20 billion investment in high-poverty Title I schools;<br></li><li>Fund additional transformational investments to support the needs of the whole child, including community schools that provide wraparound services like afterschool programs, and hiring more counselors, social workers and school psychologists.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>ADVANCING EDUCATIONAL EQUITY IN THE AMERICAN RESCUE PLAN</u></strong><br><br>The President made clear on <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/21/executive-order-supporting-the-reopening-and-continuing-operation-of-schools-and-early-childhood-education-providers/">Day One of this Administration</a> that safely reopening schools was a national priority, signing an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/21/executive-order-supporting-the-reopening-and-continuing-operation-of-schools-and-early-childhood-education-providers/">Executive Order</a> that launched a comprehensive effort across the White House, Department of Education, and Department of Health and Human Services to safely reopen schools. The Department of Education has worked to support states and school districts in implementing CDC guidance for safe operations, and engaged education leaders across the country to collect and share best practices. The Administration has prioritized K-12 educator, staff, and child care vaccinations, and increased access to and awareness of vaccines among adolescents and their parents.<br><br>States, school districts, and schools are supported in this work by the American Rescue Plan’s historic and needed investment in our schools. This included $130 billion to support the safe reopening of schools and address the academic, social, emotional, and mental health needs of students—including $122 billion through the American Rescue Plan’s Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief Fund (ARP ESSER). This funding is being used to help schools safely operate, implement high-quality summer learning and enrichment programs, hire nurses and counselors, support the vaccination of students and staff, and invest in other measures to take care of students. Thanks to these efforts—combined with the Administration’s aggressive vaccination push and the hard work of state, district, school leaders, educators, and parents—the percentage of K-8 schools offering only remote instruction dropped from 23 percent in January to only 2 percent in May.<br><br>The American Rescue Plan recognizes and addresses <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/20210608-impacts-of-covid19.pdf">the disproportionate impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on underserved students</a>. Districts and states must spend a combined minimum of 24 percent of total ARP ESSER funds on evidence-based practices to address lost instructional time and the impact of the coronavirus on underserved students, such as summer learning and enrichment programs, comprehensive afterschool programs, and tutoring. School and district leaders must ensure that these efforts respond to students’ social and emotional needs as well. ARP ESSER includes a first-of-its-kind maintenance of equity requirement to ensure that high-poverty school districts and schools are protected from funding cuts. The American Rescue Plan also includes additional funding for students with disabilities, students experiencing homelessness, Tribal education, nutrition security, broadband access, and child care for low-income families.<br><br><strong><u>ADVANCING EDUCATIONAL EQUITY IN THE BUILD BACK BETTER AGENDA</u></strong><br><br>The resources in the American Rescue Plan, however, are not enough to address the deep educational inequities that have existed in our country since its founding. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda directly addresses longstanding educational inequities and will revitalize our education system so that students have the opportunities to learn and prepare for jobs in tomorrow’s economy, which includes ensuring the needs of the whole child are addressed.<br><br><strong><u>Make a historic investment to support students in high-poverty schools</u></strong>.<br>To ensure that every student—including those from underserved and under-resourced communities—can learn and thrive, the President’s discretionary budget request provides an additional $20 billion in funding for Title I schools. These investments will help address long-standing funding disparities between under-resourced school districts and wealthier districts:</p>



<ul><li><strong><em>Providing meaningful incentives to examine and address inequalities in school funding systems.</em></strong> There is a <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/overview/budget/budget22/justifications/a-ed.pdf">$23 billion annual funding gap</a> between white and nonwhite districts, and gaps between high- and low-poverty districts as well. A <a href="https://edtrust.org/resource/funding-gaps-2018/">2018 report from The Education Trust</a> found that the highest poverty districts receive 7 percent less per pupil in State and local funding than the lowest poverty districts.<br></li><li><strong><em>Promoting competitive teacher pay.</em></strong> In 2017, public school teachers <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/teacher-pay-gap-2018/">earned 18.7 percent less</a> in weekly wages than their peer group of college educated workers, up from only 1.8&nbsp;percent less in 1994. <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/education-k-12/reports/2014/07/23/94168/mid-and-late-career-teachers-struggle-with-paltry-incomes/">In many states, teachers with ten years of experience who head a household of four may qualify for public assistance.<br></a></li><li><strong><em>Increasing preparation for, access to, and success in rigorous coursework.</em></strong> Black and Native American students <a href="https://sites.ed.gov/underservedyouth/files/2017/01/MS3-Lead-Higher-Initiative-Finding-Americas-Missing-AP-and-IB-Students.pdf">participate in AP coursework at half</a> the national average<strong>.</strong> <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/crdc-course-access-report">While 87% of low-poverty schools provide calculus, only 45 percent of high-poverty schools do.</a> Lack of access to and preparation for success in mathematics and science coursework ultimately has a <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/education-k-12/news/2019/08/28/473876/advancing-racial-equity-career-technical-education-enrollment/">negative impact on the outcomes achieved by Black and Latino students in high-paying, in-demand STEM fields</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Boost early childhood care and education</u></strong><br>The President’s Build Back Better Agenda makes historic investments in our youngest learners, so that every child can succeed, paving the way for the best-educated generation in U.S. history.<br><br><strong><em>Establishing universal preschool</em></strong><br>Preschool is critical to ensuring that children start kindergarten with the skills and supports that set them up for success in school. However, <a href="https://s3-us-east-2.amazonaws.com/edtrustmain/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/05162154/Young-Learners-Missed-Opportunities.pdf">children of color are less likely to have access to high-quality preschool programs,</a><a href="https://nieer.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/NIEER-AchievementGaps-report.pdf%20with%20a%20furtherhttps:/nces.ed.gov/ecls/kindergarten2011.asp">resulting in disparate educational outcomes before students even enter kindergarten</a>. <a href="https://www.future-ed.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Gormley_et_al-2017-Journal_of_Policy_Analysis_and_Management.pdf">Research shows</a> that kids who attend preschool programs are more likely to take honors classes and less likely to repeat a grade, do better in <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/bpea-articles/the-impacts-of-expanding-access-to-high-quality-preschool-education/">math and reading</a>, <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w28756/w28756.pdf?utm_campaign=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_medium=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_source=PANTHEON_STRIPPED">and are more likely to graduate from high school and enroll in college</a>. Impacts are particularly strong for <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w23215/w23215.pdf">children from low-income families</a>, and children with disabilities benefit from inclusive, accessible preschool programs with their peers<a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w23215/w23215.pdf">.</a><br><br>President Biden’s plan would establish a national partnership with states to offer free, high-quality, accessible, and inclusive preschool for all three-and four-year-olds. This will benefit five million children, and save the average family $13,000 a year on preschool tuition. This historic investment in America’s future will prioritize high-need areas first, establishing universal programs in these communities, so that all students can access them, facilitating the creation of diverse classrooms that are best for all students. It will also enable communities and families to choose the setting that works best for them, whether that’s a preschool classroom in a public school, family child care provider or child care center, or a Head Start program. The President’s plan supports low student-to-teacher ratios, high quality standards, and inclusive classroom environments.<br><br><strong><em>Make high-quality child care affordable and accessible</em></strong><br>High-quality early care and education helps ensure that children can take full advantage of education and training opportunities later in life, especially for children from low-income families and children of color, who disproportionately <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/digest/d19/tables/dt19_202.30b.asp">lack access</a> to good child care options and who face <a href="https://rhyclearinghouse.acf.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/docs/18755-Disparities_in_Early_Learning_and_Development%5Bfull%5D.pdf">learning disparities</a> before they even can go to preschool. President Biden’s proposal will ensure that low- and middle-income families can access affordable, high-quality, child care. The most hard-pressed working families would pay nothing, and families earning 1.5 times their state’s median income would spend no more than 7 percent of their income on child care for their young children. The plan will also provide families with a range of inclusive and accessible options to choose from, from child care centers to family child care providers to Early Head Start programs. Child care providers will receive funding to support the true cost of quality early childhood education, which will allow them to provide care that is accessible and inclusive of children with disabilities.<br><br>The President’s investments in child care and preschool will also support early childhood educators, more <a href="https://nwlc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ChildCareWorkersFS.pdf">than nine in ten</a> of whom are women and more than <a href="https://nwlc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ChildCareWorkersFS.pdf">four in ten</a> of whom are women of color. <a href="https://cscce.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/ReportFINAL.pdf">One report found that nearly half</a> rely on public income support programs. The President’s plan establishes a $15 minimum wage for these educators and ensures those with similar qualifications as kindergarten teachers receive comparable compensation and benefits.<br><br>And the President’s proposal will extend the American Rescue Plan’s expanded Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit so that families can instead choose to get a credit for up to half of their child care expenses, saving up to $8,000 per year.<br><br><strong><u>Invest in our teachers.</u></strong> Few people have a bigger impact on a child’s life than a great teacher. Unfortunately, the U.S. faces a <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">large and growing teacher shortage</a>. Before the pandemic, <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">schools needed an estimated additional 100,000 certified teachers</a>, resulting in key positions going unfilled, the granting of emergency certifications, or teachers teaching out of their certification area. Shortages disproportionately impact <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">students of color </a>and rural communities. In schools with the highest percentage of students of color, the percentage of teachers who are uncertified is more than <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/understanding-teacher-shortages-interactive?gclid=EAIaIQobChMIlZbktfGP8AIVg-DICh10CQyXEAAYAiAAEgJgV_D_BwE">three times as large</a> as in schools with the lowest percentage of students of color. The percentage of teachers in their first or second year of teaching is <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/understanding-teacher-shortages-interactive?gclid=EAIaIQobChMIlZbktfGP8AIVg-DICh10CQyXEAAYAiAAEgJgV_D_BwE">70 percent higher</a>. While access to <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/Diversifying_Teaching_Profession_REPORT_0.pdf">teachers of color benefits all students and has a particularly strong impact on students of color</a>, only around <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat11.htm">one in five</a> teachers are people of color, compared to <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator_cge.asp">more than half</a> of public school students.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda will increase support for teacher preparation and invest in Grow Your Own programs and year-long, paid teacher residency programs. These programs have a significant impact on <a href="https://www.aft.org/sites/default/files/ae_spring2017guha_hyler_and_darling-hammond.pdf">student outcomes and teacher retention</a>, and <a href="https://www.aft.org/sites/default/files/ae_spring2017guha_hyler_and_darling-hammond.pdf">are more likely to enroll underrepresented teacher candidates, including candidates of color</a>. The plan would also invest in teacher preparation at Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and Minority-Serving Institutions. The President has also called for increased investments in certifications in high-demand areas like special education and bilingual education, and is urging Congress to invest in programs that leverage teachers as leaders, such as high-quality mentorship programs for new teachers. These investments will improve the quality of new teachers, increase retention rates, and grow the number of teachers of color—all of which will improve student outcomes like <a href="https://mrbartonmaths.com/resourcesnew/8.%20Research/Improving%20Teaching/Teaching%20Experience.pdf">academic achievement</a> and <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/Diversifying_Teaching_Profession_REPORT_0.pdf">high school graduation rates</a>, resulting in <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/Diversifying_Teaching_Profession_REPORT_0.pdf">higher long-term earnings, job creation, and a boost to the economy</a>. As more teachers stay in the profession, districts will <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/the-cost-of-teacher-turnover">save money</a> on recruiting and training, and can invest more in programs that directly impact students.<br><br><strong><u>Expand career pathways for middle and high school students.</u></strong><a href="https://ies.ed.gov/ncee/wwc/interventionreport/671">Strong dual enrollment programs</a> increase college enrollment, and graduation. High-quality career and technical education models have significant positive effects on <a href="https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED570132.pdf">high school graduation, increase college enrollment, and improve wages</a>. The President’s plan would provide more students with access to high-quality career and technical education programs that expand access to computer science; connect underrepresented students to careers in STEM and in in-demand, high-growth industry sectors; that include partnerships with institutions of higher education, employers, and other stakeholders; and that allow students to engage in quality work-based learning opportunities, earn a credential, and/or earn college credit.<br><br><strong><u>Eliminate inequitable school infrastructure conditions</u>. </strong>According to one national study, <a href="https://infrastructurereportcard.org/cat-item/schools/">there is a $38 billion gap</a> between the current infrastructure spending on schools and actual infrastructure needs. The <a href="https://infrastructurereportcard.org/cat-item/schools/">American Society of Civil Engineers gives American school infrastructure a grade of D+.</a><a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/letters/colleague-resourcecomp-201410.pdf">Students of color are more likely to attend schools with rundown and unsafe facilities</a>. <a href="https://ajph.aphapublications.org/doi/pdfplus/10.2105/AJPH.2009.165324">Poor physical school conditions are associated with increased rates of student absenteeism, with one study finding poor ventilation associated with a 10 to 20 percent increase in student absences</a>. While the American Rescue Plan provides critical resources for improving ventilation systems, it does not provide sufficient resources to address all health and safety needs, let alone long-overdue investments to increase energy efficiency, ensure our schools have the technology and labs to prepare students for jobs in tomorrow’s economy, or build new buildings where needed. President Biden’s plan supports investments to upgrade and build new public schools, ensuring that all our children have equal access to healthy learning environments that prepare them for success. It also invests in upgrading child care facilities and increasing the supply of child care in areas that need it most.<br><br><strong><u>Addressing lead in schools</u>. </strong>There is no safe level of lead exposure for children. Lead can slow development and cause learning, behavior, and hearing problems in children, as well as lasting kidney and brain damage. Communities of color are <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nceh/lead/prevention/populations.htm">at a higher risk</a> of lead exposure. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework would make significant investments towards the elimination of all lead pipes and service lines in the country, and reduce lead exposure in our schools and child care facilities, improving the health of our country’s children, including in communities of color.<br><br><strong><u>Increasing broadband access for students and families</u>. </strong>Broadband internet is critical to learning. Yet, by one definition, more than 30 million Americans live in areas where there is no broadband infrastructure that provides minimally acceptable speeds. <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/fact-sheet/internet-broadband/?menuItem=d5edf003-5858-4269-89c5-f2889ecf7951">In urban areas, there is a stark digital divide: a much higher percentage of white families report having a home broadband internet than Black, or Latino families</a>. <a href="https://aipi.asu.edu/sites/default/files/tribal_digital_divide_stimulus_bill_advocacy_04032020.pdf">Native families in their tribal communities also lack sufficient access to high-speed internet.</a><a href="https://msutoday.msu.edu/news/2020/poor-internet-connection-leaves-rural-students-behind"> One Michigan study</a> found that 47 percent of students who lived in rural areas had broadband access at home, compared to 77 percent of those in suburban areas. The last year made painfully clear the cost of these disparities, particularly for students who struggled to connect while learning remotely. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework would make historic investments in building “future proof” broadband infrastructure in unserved and underserved areas, so that we finally reach 100 percent high-speed broadband coverage.<br><br><strong><u>Electrifying school buses for safe student travel</u>. </strong><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4476560/">One study finds</a> that when children ride buses with clean air technologies, they experience lower exposures to air pollution, less pulmonary inflammation, and reduced absenteeism. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework would make a down payment on electrifying our yellow school bus fleet.<br><br><strong><u>Increase support for children with disabilities.</u></strong> All children, including those with disabilities, should be provided the services and support they need to thrive in school and graduate ready for college or a career. The discretionary request provides an historic $2.6 billion increase for Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) grants that support special education and related services for children with disabilities in grades preschool through 12. This funding would, for the first time in eight years, increase the federal share of the cost of providing services to children with disabilities, and is a significant first step toward fully funding IDEA. The discretionary request also includes an additional $250 million for IDEA Part C, which supports early intervention services for infants and toddlers with disabilities or delays, and funds services that have a proven track record of improving academic and developmental outcomes. This increase in funding would be paired with reforms to improve access to these vital services for underserved children, including children of color and children from low-income families.<br><br><strong><u>Prioritize the physical and mental well-being of students.</u></strong> The discretionary request provides $1 billion to increase the number of counselors, nurses, and mental health professionals in schools, prioritizing high-poverty schools.<br><br><strong><u>Support full-service community schools.</u></strong> Community schools play a critical role in providing comprehensive wrap-around services to students and their families, from afterschool to adult education opportunities to health and nutrition services. The discretionary request increases funding for these schools from $30 million to $443 million, an over ten-fold increase.<br><br><strong><u>Foster diverse schools.</u></strong> Schools play vital roles in bringing communities together. But, too many of the nation’s schools are <a href="https://cepa.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/wp19-06-v092019.pdf">still largely segregated by race and class</a>, mirroring their communities. The discretionary request includes $100 million for a new voluntary grant program to help communities develop and implement strategies to build more diverse student bodies. As part of their application, applicants would be required to demonstrate strong student, family, teacher, and community involvement in their plans. Applicants would have flexibility to develop and implement school diversity plans that reflect their individual needs and circumstances, and improve educational opportunities and outcomes for students.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
