<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 23:46:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, March 7th,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/07/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-march-7th-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 23:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:42 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; I have two items for all of you at the top. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; This week, we are marking one year &#8212; the one-year anniversary of the American Rescue Plan, which has been the key driver of our strong economic recovery, provided&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:42 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I have two items for all of you at the top.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This week, we are marking one year &#8212; the one-year anniversary of the American Rescue Plan, which has been the key driver of our strong economic recovery, provided us with the tools needed to fight the pandemic, and made long-term investments to revitalize the local economy in communities around the country.</p>



<p>Each day this week, we will focus on a different element of the hundreds of ARP &#8212; or American Rescue Plan &#8212; programs that have successfully delivered resources across the country over the past year.</p>



<p>Today, we&#8217;re focusing on ARP’s higher-ed investments in community colleges; HBCUs; TCCUs &#8212; Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities; and MSIs &#8212; Minority-Serving Institutions.</p>



<p>In a press call today with key members of Congress, Education Secretary Cardona will highlight the ARP’s Higher Education Emergency Relief Fund to serve students and ensure learning continues during the pandemic.</p>



<p>The ARP’s funding for Higher Education includes over $10 billion for community colleges and over $2.7 billion for HBCUs &#8212; one of the largest-ever federal investments in community colleges and HBCUs.</p>



<p>These funds are already having a significant impact on institutions and students.&nbsp; A recent survey of college presidents by the American Council on Education found that these ARP investments enabled 93 percent of colleges to provide direct financial support to students at risk of dropping out, 81 percent of colleges to keep students&#8217; net prices similar to pre-pandemic levels, and 70 percent of colleges to continue to employ faculty, staff, and other employees.</p>



<p>Today, we also have a new announcement from the President’s competition agenda.&nbsp; The Departments of Treasury, Justice, Labor, and the Federal Trade Commission investigated the effects of the lack of labor market competition on the U.S. economy.</p>



<p>This new report makes clear that there is more we can do so every worker can take advantage of our historically strong labor market recovery.</p>



<p>Corporate concentration and anti-competitive practices, like non-compete agreements and misclassification, have stifled wages for workers and reduced their power to bargain for dignity and respect in the workplace.</p>



<p>The costs to workers are substantial.&nbsp; Lack of competition causes workers’ wages to be 20 percent lower than what they’d otherwise earn.</p>



<p>The report also shows that diminished labor market competition holds back our entire economy, inhibiting innovation, increasing prices, and curbing economic growth.</p>



<p>And finally, I know some of you will be traveling with us to Fort Worth, Texas, tomorrow, so I wanted to give you a little bit of a preview of that.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, President Biden and Secretary of Veterans Affairs Denis McDonough will travel to Fort Worth, Texas, to speak with veterans, caregivers, and survivors about addressing the health effects of environmental exposures such as burn pits.&nbsp; This is obviously something the President talked about in his State of the Union Address a little less than a week ago.</p>



<p>They will visit the Fort Worth VA Clinic and receive a briefing from VA doctors and nurses on their primary care and specialty health services for veterans.&nbsp; They will also speak with veterans and patient advocates about different challenges facing the community.</p>



<p>Then they will deliver remarks at Tarrant County Resource Connection on expanding access to healthcare and benefits for veterans affected by exposure to harmful substances, toxins, and other environmental hazards, including those from burn pits, as part of the &#8220;Unity Agenda for the Nation.&#8221;</p>



<p>The President will discuss the administration’s actions to address these issues, including a new proposed rule to consider adding certain rare cancers to the list of those presumed to be service connected.&nbsp; And he will urge Congress to send him legislation that ensures we honor our commitment to veterans exposed to toxic substances.</p>



<p>President Biden believes we have a sacred obligation to care for our veterans and their families.&nbsp; And as a military family, the Bidens know firsthand the challenges that come from military service and deployment to combat zones.</p>



<p>With that, Josh, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Three questions. &nbsp;&nbsp;First: Administration officials are meeting with foreign counterparts in Venezuela. &nbsp;You&#8217;ve also talked to Iran and the Saudis.&nbsp; Is the supply of oil so important that it&#8217;s acceptable to cut deals in some cases with countries that may have engaged in unsavory actions in the past?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think it&#8217;s important to take each of those engagements separately, because there are a range of issues that are important in each of those &#8212; in each of those relationships.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One, as it relates to Saudi Arabia, we did talk a few weeks ago about how Brett McGurk and Amos Hochstein went to Saudi Arabia to discuss a range of issues &#8212; including the war in Yemen, including security in the region, and certainly including energy security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They had the discussion.&nbsp; It&#8217;s in everyone&#8217;s interests to &#8212; to reduce the impact on the global oil marketplace, and that was part of that discussion.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As it relates to Venezuela, the purpose of the trip that was taken by administration officials was to discuss a range of issues &#8212; including, certainly, energy security &#8212; but also to discuss the health and welfare of detained U.S. citizens.&nbsp; We&#8217;re never going to miss an opportunity to do exactly that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I will just note, in this scenario, that they are separate.&nbsp; They are separate paths and conversations, just as they are in the Iran negotiations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what was the third country you mentioned?&nbsp; Sorry.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, Venezuela, Iran, and Saudis.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, and Iran.&nbsp; The most vital reason &#8212; the most important reason why we are focused and have been focused on having these discussions with the Iranians and our P5+1 partners is to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That is why we&#8217;re in these &#8212; these negotiations.&nbsp; We are getting closer.&nbsp; There are still important components to work through.&nbsp; But certainly, the discussion of oil is a part of that, but the most important reason is to prevent them from acquiring a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I would just note &#8212; and I went through all of those purposefully, obviously, because these are all geopolitical issues that have a range of topics that are a part of the discussion in our engagements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secondly, House Speaker Nancy Pelosi has suggested that Russian oil imports should be banned.&nbsp; We&#8217;re already seeing that Russia is struggling to sell some of its oil, which suggests that supplies are destabilized.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given that fact, would President Biden sign a ban?&nbsp; And what would hold him back from doing so if not?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, no decision has been made at this point by the President about a ban on import &#8212; a ban on importing of oil from Russia, and those discussions are ongoing internally and also with our counterparts and partners in Europe and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would note that what the President is most focused on is ensuring we are continuing to take steps to deliver punishing economic consequences on Putin while taking all action necessary to limit the impact to prices at the gas pump.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as you noted, yes, it is true that there has obviously been an impact of the invasion on the level of import to the United States and to other parts of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would note as we&#8217;re having these conversations &#8212; and obviously, the President talked with his &#8212; a number of his European partners this morning about a range of issues; this was part of it.&nbsp; But if you look at Russian imports, they account for about a third currently of Europe&#8217;s oil imports.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, with the data we have that&#8217;s most &#8212; that we have available at this point in time is back to 2021, not that long ago.&nbsp; But just to give you a point of comparison: The amount that the United States was importing back in 2021 before the invasion was about 700,000 barrels per day of crude oil and petroleum.&nbsp; The Europeans import about 4.5 million barrels per day of oil.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, obviously, we are also very well aware as we&#8217;re having these conversations and as we&#8217;re consulting with our partners that there would be &#8212; we have different capacities and capabilities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, last, the Florida Surgeon General says that healthy children shouldn&#8217;t get COVID vaccines.&nbsp; Is that a good policy?</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp; Let me just note that we know the science, we know the data and what works and what is the most &#8212; what the most effective steps are in protecting people of a range of ages from hospitalization and even death.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The FDA and CDC have already weighed in in the safety &#8212; on the safety and efficacy of COVID-19 vaccines for those five and older.&nbsp; The recommendations are vetted transparently through a process for &#8212; with a purpose so that parents can have confidence, after consulting with their pediatricians or doctors if they would like, about the safety.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we also know through the data that unvaccinated teenagers are three times as likely to be hospitalized if they get COVID than vaccinated teenagers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s deeply disturbing that there are politicians peddling conspiracy theories out there and casting doubt on vaccinations when it is our best tool against the virus and the best tool to prevent even teenagers from being hospitalized.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to read to you &#8212; if I could, Jen &#8212; some comments from people we&#8217;ve met at gas stations today.&nbsp; One woman saying, &#8220;I just never imagined to see the cost of gas be this high.&#8221;&nbsp; Another said, &#8220;It&#8217;s a huge stressor to my financial situation, a huge stressor.&nbsp; It&#8217;s kind of like something I&#8217;m stressed about, like, during the day: Will I be able to afford gas?&nbsp; How much money do I have?&#8221;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the White House, what is the President&#8217;s message to Americans who are going to the gas station today and seeing prices so high?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President&#8217;s message is that he&#8217;s going to do everything we can, everything he can to reduce the impact on the American people, including the price of gas at the tank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is also true is that because of the actions of President Putin, because he invaded a sovereign country, that created instability in the markets.&nbsp; That is something the President talked about even before Russia and President Putin moved forward with their actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we have already taken steps, the President has already taken steps: historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve &#8212; one that’s done in a coordinated fashion.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, clearly, we will continue to have conversations with large oil producers and suppliers around the world about how to mitigate the impact and consider domestic options as well.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said, on Friday, the administration is looking at options it could take, quote, “right now…to cut U.S. consumption of Russian energy.”&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When is a decision on that going to be made?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a prediction of that for you at this point in time, but there is an active discussion.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to go back to one of the three countries that Josh mentioned: Venezuela.&nbsp; There was a U.S. team there this weekend talking to the Maduro regime.&nbsp; Sanctions have been in place since 2019, a lack of diplomatic engagement since then because of electoral fraud, because of all the things that that regime has done to the Venezuelan people.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I hear you say we&#8217;re doing everything we can to bring down the cost of gas, but is it really worth doing business with a despot like Nicolás Maduro to drive down gas prices?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think that&#8217;s leaping several stages ahead in any process.&nbsp; There was a discussion that was had by members of the administration over the course of the last several days.&nbsp; Those discussions are also ongoing.&nbsp; And part of our focus is also on the health and welfare of detained U.S. citizens &#8212; while a separate process, still that is part of our engagement with them.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, at this point in time, I don&#8217;t have anything to predict.&nbsp; It&#8217;s ongoing.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to convey at this point.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Americans who are not &#8212; or who are being detained: What&#8217;s being done about Brittney Griner, in Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we, of course, have seen the reports.&nbsp; Because we do not have a Privacy Act waiver, which I think you&#8217;re all familiar with, I can&#8217;t speak to that more specifically. &nbsp;Of course, we obviously do everything we can, when there are any reports of Americans who are detained, through the State Department and through diplomatic channels.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I would point you to the State Department for more.&nbsp; But given we don&#8217;t have a Privacy Act waiver, it&#8217;s unlikely we would say &#8212; to say more.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you’re not aware of any other Americans like her who have been detained in recent weeks under similar incidents?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I have nothing to report from here, Ed.&nbsp; I would say that the Privacy Act waiver, which is required for us to be able to speak to any instances.&nbsp; But given you asked me about the particular report, I wanted to speak to that.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; It sounds like you guys are blaming Putin for the increase in gas prices recently, but weren&#8217;t gas prices going up anyway because of post-pandemic supply chain issues?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think there&#8217;s no question that, as we have seen and outside analysts have conveyed this as well, the increase, and the anticipated continued increase &#8212; which is, I think, what some of your colleagues were asking about &#8212; that that is a direct result of the invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; And also, there was an anticipation of that that was &#8212; that was &#8212; it was factored in, as gas prices have gone up.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you say that you&#8217;re going to do everything that you can to reduce the impact that high gas prices have on Americans.&nbsp; We&#8217;re asking other countries to think about maybe pumping more oil.&nbsp; Why not just do it here?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, to be very clear, federal policies are not limiting the supplies of oil and gas.&nbsp; To the con- &#8212; let me finish &#8212; to the con- &#8212; let me finish &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden signed an executive order &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Peter.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; his first week &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Peter, I’m &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that halted new oil and gas leases &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me &#8212; let me give you &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on public lands.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me give you the facts here &#8212; and I know that can be inconvenient, but I think they&#8217;re important in this moment: To the contrary, we have &#8212; we have been clear that in the short term, supply must keep up with the demand we’re &#8212; we are &#8212; here and around the world, while we make the shift to secure a clear &#8212; clean energy future.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are one of the largest producers with a strong domestic oil and gas industry.&nbsp; We have actually produced more oil; it is at record numbers.&nbsp; And we will continue to produce more oil.&nbsp; There are 9,000 approved drilling permits that are not being used.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the suggestion that we are not let allowing companies to drill is inaccurate.&nbsp; The suggestion that that is what is hindering or preventing gas prices to come down is inaccurate.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would President Biden rescind his executive order that halts new oil and natural gas leases on public lands?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, 90 percent of them happen on private lands, as I&#8217;m sure you know.&nbsp; And there are 9,000 unused approved drilling permits.&nbsp; So I would suggest you ask the oil companies why they&#8217;re not using those if there&#8217;s a desire to drill more.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would President Biden ever undo his executive order that stopped the construction of the Keystone XL Pipeline?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Are you suggesting that would solve the gas prices issue?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, do you think that that would maybe affect prices faster than getting the whole country off of fossil fuels?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I actually don&#8217;t think it would.&nbsp; The Keystone was not an oilfield; it&#8217;s a pipeline.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Also, the oil is continuing to flow in, just through other means.&nbsp; So it actually would have nothing to do with the current supply imbalance.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, gas prices are approaching an all-time high per gallon.&nbsp; How high would they have to get before President Biden would say “I&#8217;m going to set aside my ambitious climate goals and just increase domestic oil production, get the producers to drill more here, and we can address the fossil fuel future later”?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, Peter, the U.S. produced more oil this past year than in President Trump&#8217;s first year.&nbsp; Next year, according to the Department of Energy, we will produce more oil than every &#8212; than ever before.&nbsp; Those are &#8212; those are the facts, in terms of oil production.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And again, right now there are 9,000 unused approved permits to drill on shore.&nbsp; So, I think you&#8217;re misidentifying what the actual issue is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if we&#8217;re looking to the future and what &#8212; how &#8212; what we can do to prevent this from being a challenge in future crises, the best thing we can do is reduce our dependence on fossil fuels and foreign oil, because that will help us have a reliable source of energy so that we&#8217;re not worried about gas prices going up because of the whims of a foreign dictator.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; And you guys think that asking Saudi Arabia or Venezuela or Iran is reducing our dependence on foreign oil?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s actually &#8212; I just outlined each of those specific scenarios and the range of discussions that we&#8217;re having with each of those countries.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think anybody is advocating for Iran to continue acquiring a nuclear weapon, perhaps except for the former president who pulled us out of the deal.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; President Zelenskyy spoke with ABC today.&nbsp; He says that he&#8217;s had a longstanding request in with allies to access these Soviet-era fighter jets.&nbsp; So I want to &#8212; I want to ask you about this backfilling &#8212; this possibility of backfilling these fighter jets.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He says President Biden can do more to make this happen.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your response to that, and what&#8217;s the holdup?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, just for clarity &#8212; I know everybody is following this very closely, but to catch others up &#8212; we&#8217;re talking about Polish planes &#8212; right? &#8212; these fighter jets that they are requesting.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working with Poland on this issue and consulting with the rest of our NATO Allies on it.&nbsp; This is Poland’s sovereign decision to make.&nbsp; We have in no way opposed Poland transferring planes to Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But to go to the source of your question here, I think, Cecilia, there are a number of challenging practical questions, including how the planes would actually be transferred from Poland to Ukraine.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So, are they going to fly?&nbsp; Where will they depart from?&nbsp; Where will they land?&nbsp; Those are all very important questions here.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, as it &#8212; as it relates to the backfill question, we are working through some pretty complicated logistics on that front as well, including how we would backfill, because procuring new planes and transferring serious weapon systems often takes years &#8212; take years to do from the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that is all &#8212; those are all two layers of dif- &#8212; of difficult logistical challenges here.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is it predominantly logistical challenges that is the holdup?&nbsp; Or is there a concern on the part of the President that supplying Poland these planes could exacerbate the conflict with Russia, Poland, and other Allied countries?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think there&#8217;s an important question here, as I touched on a little, about where they take off from and where they land, right? &nbsp;There is a airbase that is a NATO airbase in Poland.&nbsp; If you have plans &#8212; planes departing from there, that&#8217;s &#8212; that could be a challenging circumstance.&nbsp; Are there &#8212; what are the other options and where do they land?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So those are some of the logistical challenges.&nbsp; Obviously, the Department of Defense can speak to this more intensively.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re looking at all of those factors.&nbsp; But we are not, certainly, preventing or blocking or discouraging Poland.&nbsp; That is &#8212; they are a sovereign country.&nbsp; They make &#8212; they make their own decisions.&nbsp; But it is not as easy as just moving planes around.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And President Zelenskyy said that, in recent days, that “all the people who will die from this day, will die also because of you.”&nbsp; He’s essentially saying the West will have blood on its hands if it doesn&#8217;t do more.&nbsp; Is the President happy with &#8212; does he believe the cr- &#8212; the administration&#8217;s response so far to this crisis has been adequate?&nbsp; Is he okay?&nbsp; Does he consider this successful at this point?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I mean, Cecilia, I don&#8217;t think anybody watching this anywhere around the world feels happy.&nbsp; This is &#8212; this is &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But as it relates to the American side of this?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But let me finish.&nbsp; This is barbaric.&nbsp; It&#8217;s horrific to watch.&nbsp; I mean, you have 1.5 million, if not more, refugees crossing the border.&nbsp; You have mothers and children dead on the side of the road.&nbsp; This is heart wrenching to watch.&nbsp; And &#8212; ugh, sorry, it&#8217;s &#8212; it is.&nbsp; It&#8217;s heart wrenching to watch, you know?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think for us who are working in public service, you watch in these moments and there are &#8212; there are limitations in the sense that we are not going to send U.S. troops to fight in Ukraine against Russia.&nbsp; The President is not going to do that.&nbsp; That is what you have to weigh as President of the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we are doing and what he is doing is continuing to take every step to provide them security assistance &#8212; $1 billion of security assistance.&nbsp; That has been expedited.&nbsp; I know the Department of Defense gave an update on Friday about how much of that has arrived.&nbsp; A huge percentage has arrived and been expedited in a very short timeframe.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have also provided economic, humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; And I think any world leader would tell you that without the President&#8217;s leadership and without the United States rallying the world to hold Russia accountable, there would not be the kind of accountability, pressure on the financial system in Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we are doing everything that is in the interest of the United States, in the interest of our partners in NATO to put pressure on President Putin, to support the Ukrainians, and certainly doing that while we watch them fight bravely and courageously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think the last think I would say on this, Cecilia, is that it’s also important &#8212; and we’re very cognizant of this here &#8212; to be clear that this is going to be &#8212; continue to be a very, very difficult period of time.&nbsp; The Ukrainians are fighting bravely.&nbsp; We&#8217;re standing by them and supporting them.&nbsp; But Russia is &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re going to continue to fight.&nbsp; They are going to continue to pursue what President Putin&#8217;s ambition is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just step back a little bit &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; in terms of supply.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about specific</p>



<p>countries, but this has been an effort that&#8217;s been underway now &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for several months.&nbsp; Amos, Brett, many others as well.&nbsp; Algeria, Japan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What is the update in terms of &#8212; has supply been kicked in on the LNG side or on the oil side?&nbsp; Where does that stand, given the extensive effort in the leadup to now, to try and backfill and ensure stability on the supply side?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean for the global markets to &#8212; for natural gas?&nbsp; Both.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For natural gas or oil, on the global markets.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, let me start with the natural gas side because that we anticipated would be an issue for the Europeans primarily.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have had some success &#8212; Japan as an example, and I can see if there are others, too, to read out to all of you &#8212; where there was supply that was intended to go to Japan and other countries in Asia and redirect it to Europeans so that it could help backfill the potential shortage in natural gas.&nbsp; That is less an issue for us here in the United States and more an issue for the Europeans.&nbsp; And to your point, it is something we&#8217;ve been working on for some time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of global oil supply, I don&#8217;t have anything to read out for you at this point in time.&nbsp; Those conversations certainly have been ongoing, but the release &#8212; the coordinated release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve and the continued discussion about that has been a part of the effort to address the shortage or the potential for shortage in the marketplace.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But 60 million barrels is &#8212; I&#8217;m not trying to minimize it, but it&#8217;s a drop in the bucket given the scale of the, kind of, dislocation we&#8217;ve seen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a trigger in terms of the conversations with global allies, partners, players in the supply market that would cause them to come in, based on the conversations that have happened?&nbsp; Like, what it&#8217;s going to bring them in and make clear that the months of work you guys have put into this actually results in something tangible?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I certainly understand your question.&nbsp; What I was trying to convey is that that&#8217;s part of what we&#8217;ve done to date.&nbsp; But we are continuing conversations about a range of what would be needed moving forward.&nbsp; And there are a range of options on the table.&nbsp; I just can&#8217;t detail more specifics from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, last one.&nbsp; How much does it weigh on the administration, if you move towards cutting Russian imports of oil, that it would be a unilateral move in the face of what had been a very carefully calibrated coalition up to this point where energy was considered off the table, for the most part?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I would say this is one of the</p>



<p>reasons that I gave the example of how much &#8212; you know, our capabilities and our capacities are very different, both because we import such a smaller percentage of oil from Russia than the Europeans do, but also because we have a much larger capacity for producing our own oil.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it is a very different circumstance, and certainly we are going to continue to consult with, continue to convey where our plans, where our discussions are here internally with the Europeans.&nbsp; But I would look at it through a different prism than past coordinated efforts.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just follow up there?&nbsp; Just today, Russia said that it could cut off fuel through the Nord Stream 1 pipeline &#8212; Nord Stream 2.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, to what extent are you concerned that European allies, who depend so incredibly on these oil and gas imports from Russia, could really be stuck?&nbsp; I mean, like, what &#8212; I realize you&#8217;re making efforts, but, you know, to what extent does that factor in?&nbsp; And what do you say to Russia in terms of this threat?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we have been concerned from the beginning about steps that President Putin could take to impact neighboring countries, countries in Europe, through a range of means.&nbsp; And, certainly, access to energy and energy security is a part of that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s obviously one of the reasons we&#8217;ve been working with a range of partners on addressing what could be a natural gas shortage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you are right, Andrea, as you well know, that even &#8212; I mean, the Nord Stream 1, 2 threat aside, the reliance on importing &#8212; the import of Russian oil is so much more significant in Russia &#8212; excuse me, in Europe &#8212; that well over the course of time, it&#8217;s clear they recognize the need to diversify their means of getting oil.&nbsp; This is a bigger challenge and puts them in a more challenging position.&nbsp; And we recognize that from here, even as the President is considering steps that we could take from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it is one of the reasons why the President, why people like Amos Hochstein, Brett McGurk, other &#8212; others from our national security team have been engaging in a range of discussions over the course of the last several months.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I guess, a couple follow-ups just on them, and then I’ve got another question.</p>



<p>So, these conversations that are taking place, both in terms of securing additional sources or supplies of energy but also in terms of closing sanctions, loopholes, and &#8212; you know, it doesn&#8217;t seem like you&#8217;re getting a huge amount of traction.&nbsp; I mean, in terms of India, Pakistan, you know, and China has still not been, you know, helpful in this regard.&nbsp; How would you assess the success of that?</p>



<p>And then, just quickly on the &#8212; what you&#8217;re saying about the European supplies: So, are you saying that the coordinated action shouldn&#8217;t &#8212; I mean, one shouldn&#8217;t view the differentiation on energy as a failure of the coordination?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, on the second piece, yes, that&#8217;s what I was saying in that there &#8212; we have &#8212; we recognize, and the President and other national security officials have been very clear in our conversations, that while we have &#8212; we have a different circumstance as it relates to Russian oil because we import such a smaller amount and because we have our own production capabilities and capacities, and that is different.&nbsp; We recognize that.</p>



<p>On the first piece, tell me &#8212; sorry, what was the first part of your question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just the success of this outreach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, you’re sending people all over the globe, basically, to &#8212; you know, either virtually or in person &#8212; to continue to try to isolate Russia.&nbsp; And it doesn&#8217;t seem like you&#8217;re getting as much traction with some of these countries as you might have hoped.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t look at it through the isolating; that&#8217;s part of our overarching effort here, right?&nbsp; But as it relates to oil supply, what we&#8217;re trying to do is engage with energy producers and those with reserves of oil supply to make sure that we are addressing the supply in the marketplace.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, the coordinated release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve just a few days ago is an example of that.&nbsp; And I certainly understand you&#8217;re asking which countries here and where are we having those conversations.&nbsp; I understand those questions.&nbsp; I just can&#8217;t get into more specific details from here because it wouldn&#8217;t be constructive to our efforts to make progress.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; about Iran?&nbsp; I’m sorry.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yesterday, Secretary Blinken said that sanctions on Russia over Ukraine have nothing to do with cooperation with Moscow on the Iran nuclear deal.&nbsp; But today, Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov doubled down in saying that all participants must have “unhindered cooperation.”&nbsp; Are you doing anything to provide Russia any kind of written guarantees in order to bring this, you know, Iran nuclear deal over the finish line?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think on this, we&#8217;re making progress together.&nbsp; Russia is a member of the P5+1.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think anyone believes it&#8217;s in their interest for Iran to acquire a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; And that is how we&#8217;re approaching these negotiations and discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly, as the Secretary of State said just yesterday, we don&#8217;t believe that the sanctions on them have anything to do with that shared goal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is that status of those talks?&nbsp; What would you (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to make a great deal of progress.&nbsp; Obviously, the harder things always happen at the very end of the process.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where we are &#8212; stand at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you take question from the back?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, two quick ones on oil and then just one other one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned the meeting this morning with Britain, France, and Germany that the President had with the leaders.&nbsp; Did they, in that conversation this morning, express either a willingness or a hesitance to ban oil or limit oil imports to their countries from Russia?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Their countries all have wonderful spokespeople who can speak for those countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you guys going to do a readout?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We did do a readout.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You did already?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I missed it.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would just note that we&#8217;ve had ongoing conversations and we have a very open line of communication, as is evidenced by the President having this call this morning, about everything from what we&#8217;re seeing on the ground in Ukraine to security assistance deliveries to discussions about weapons to discussions about additional steps to squeeze President Putin in the financial sector.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Quickly on &#8212; there&#8217;s conversations up on Capitol Hill about bipartisan conversations about legislation that could ban the import of Russian oil into the United States.&nbsp; If a bill like that came to the President&#8217;s desk, would he sign it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, no, the President has not made a decision at this point in time.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s where we stand.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But that&#8217;s taking unilateral action as &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Is a bill on its way over here that’s passed Congress?&nbsp; I don’t think so.&nbsp; But the President has not yet made a decision.</p>



<p>I just gave for you &#8212; or tried to give for you a little bit of the reasoning and the thinking behind where we stand in our coordination with our allies and partners.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last question; you referenced it: the gruesome, awful picture on the front page of our paper today.&nbsp; Do you know if the President has seen that picture; what his personal reaction was to it, if so; and more broadly, does he &#8212; has he been affected on a personal level by some of the imagery that&#8217;s come out?&nbsp; And is that affecting or has he talked about how to incorporate that personal reaction into some of the policymaking over the last 10 days?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t know if he saw this specific &#8212; there are a lot of New York Times hard copies floating around this building, I can tell you, and other &#8212; and other newspapers and outlets you all work for, so I don&#8217;t know that he saw that specific photo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what I can tell you is that, you know, the President is somebody who, of course, has been working in national security and foreign policy for decades, through his career, right?&nbsp; He is also a father, a grandfather.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that anyone, including him, has seen those photos &#8212; whether on the front page of your paper or others, and not been moved.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sure I can speak personally that, you know, talking to my neighbors, my in-laws, I&#8217;m sure this is true for all of you as well: The personal impact people have felt in this country &#8212; it&#8217;s really moved people in this country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the President is absolutely a citizen of the United States, of course the leader of the free world, but also somebody who has enormous empathy for the plight of other human beings.&nbsp; And he has, of course, been impacted by the images he has seen, as we all have been.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are they war crimes?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Going back to Venezuela for a second &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; would they have to agree to release the U.S. citizens in prison there if the U.S. were to ease the current sanctions on oil exports?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s a really important question.&nbsp; There are different channels.&nbsp; And, obviously, we&#8217;re going to continue to do everything we can to bring anyone who is detained in Venezuela or any other part of the world home, but they happen through different tracks.&nbsp; They&#8217;re all a part of the conversation with Venezuela writ large, but not at the same time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And obviously, Vice President Harris is going to Poland and Romania this week.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit more about the White House&#8217;s objectives with her going over there and particularly what message you want to send to Russia with the Vice President being in that area?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; So, as you noted, the Vice President is leaving on her trip just in a couple of days, and she&#8217;ll be over there really showing the support of the United States for the work of our allies and partners, whether that is on refugees.&nbsp; And a number of these countries, including the ones she&#8217;ll be visiting, have welcomed hundreds of thousands of refugees from Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And she&#8217;ll also be talking about our ongoing range of options and assistance that we&#8217;ve been providing to the Ukrainian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, she is going to be there.&nbsp; I think it sends a strong message that the Vice President is going to be in &#8212; meeting with many of our eastern flank partners, NATO Allies to convey our commitment to working in lockstep with them and to &#8212; and to continuing to support their efforts in the region.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more quick one.&nbsp; This morning, the Democratic and Republican leaders of the committees that oversee trade said that they have a deal on legislation that would in part suspend normal trade relations with both Russia and Belarus.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if the White House supports that, either through legislation or through other avenues.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen those reports, but we don&#8217;t have any decision on a policy from here at this point in time.</p>



<p>Go ahead, in the middle.</p>



<p><a>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of questions.&nbsp; Over the weekend, British Prime Minister Boris Johnson took to the New York Times, had this op-ed in which he argued that the U.S, Western allies should &#8220;go further on economic sanctions.&#8221;&nbsp; He specifically said to expel &#8220;every Russian bank from SWIFT.&#8221;&nbsp; I know that there were limited actions.&nbsp; Does the United States support expelling every bank?</a></p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, typically what happens with SWIFT and removing instit- &#8212; or when we&#8217;re implementing this &#8212; and Iran is the best point of comparison here &#8212; is it&#8217;s done institution by institution.&nbsp; So that is the case here as well.&nbsp; It&#8217;s done institution by institution.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t taken options off the table, and I&#8217;m not taking options off the table here.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s been &#8212; we&#8217;ve implemented it in the same way with our European partners that we did when we implemented it as it relates to Iran.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Um, sorry &#8212; so just to be clear, though, there&#8217;s not limitat- &#8212; I mean, it sounds like there were limited institutions that were targeted thus far and &#8212; from &#8212; removing them from the SWIFT banking system.&nbsp; But you would be open to going further?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never taken that off the table.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; The other thing I wanted to ask you about &#8212; going back to the Iran nuclear deal &#8212; is: My understanding is that Russia is demanding guarantees that sanctions targeting the Kremlin over Ukraine do not hinder its trade with Iran that would be potentially reopened if this Iran nuclear deal moved forward.&nbsp; Could that throw a wrench in negotiations?&nbsp; And I am curious what the White House&#8217;s take is overall on Russians trying to put that ultimatum down.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think, as our Secretary of State said yesterday, we don&#8217;t believe it has anything to do with our shared goal of preventing Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you don’t see it as a way to potentially, I guess, limit the impact that&#8217;s current sanctions have on Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t believe Russia wants Iran to have a nuclear weapon either.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so &#8212; sorry, just to be clear: So, you don’t see the idea, though, that these sorts of sanction guarantees of its trade with Iran have any impact on the current sanctions that the U.S. and Western allies have imposed on Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think &#8212; and our Secretary of State spoke to this yesterday.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you one other question?&nbsp; In parts of southern Ukraine, it seems that Russia has shifted from a military takeover to, essentially, occupation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That it is now occupying parts &#8212; occupying towns.&nbsp; Does the White House support the Ukrainian people&#8217;s right to resist the occupation and, essentially, through any means necessary?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we certainly support the rights of the Ukrainian people to fight back.&nbsp; I would note that we have seen many Ukrainians; many, many members of the Ukrainian military; and certainly President Zelenskyy in leadership fight bravely, courageously over the course of the last 12 days.</p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s also true that the world needs to be prepared for a very long, difficult road ahead.&nbsp; While they are fighting bravely and we are standing with them and supporting them, the Russians are still intending to grind out military advances in the short term just by sheer manpower and firepower.</p>



<p>So, yes, we support their right to push back and to fight back against that.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On businesses: Is there any concern in the White House with all these Western companies that are suspending operations with Russia that that just ends up deepening ties between Russia and China, that this is really forcing Russia in its connections deeper into China?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, we&#8217;ve seen that for some time &#8212; right? &#8212; long before Russia invaded Ukraine &#8212; them moving a little bit closer together or closer together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What is true on the economic front, though, is that the G7 alone &#8212; and that is not the totality of the unity as it relates to these sanctions &#8212; accounts for about 50 percent of global GDP, while Russia and Ukrai- &#8212; and China, sorry, account for only 15 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, they can&#8217;t backfill the impact of these sanctions from China.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just not &#8212; not possible.&nbsp; Now, we&#8217;ve also seen China abide by the sanctions that have been put in place.&nbsp; They obviously abstained also from the U.N. Security Council vote and have made some comments about the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If they don&#8217;t abide by the sanctions, we always have &#8212; you know, we clearly have means to take steps, but that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve seen to date.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, it doesn’t sound like the White House is concerned that some of these withdrawals will backfire and create permanent ties between Russia and China that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we know they were &#8212; they were moving closer long before the invasion, which is, I think, an important component here.&nbsp; But as it relates to the economic ties, there&#8217;s not a way, just based on purely their place in the economic marketplace, for China to completely backfill the impact of the G7 and others &#8212; and others in the world and the financial sanctions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask one more?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Saudi Arabia &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; is there any discussion in the White House yet for the President to call the Crown Prince, MBS &#8212; Mohammed bin Salman &#8212; to talk about oil?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He spoke with the King just recently.&nbsp; And obviously, we have had Brett McGurk and Amos Hochstein travel to the region, talk about a range of issues, including security in the region and the war in Yemen, as well as energy security.&nbsp; But, no, I don’t &#8212; there&#8217;s no plans at this point, no.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, you detailed some of the challenges as it relates to the jets that are in Poland right now, the NATO base there &#8212; how you get into Ukraine and do it in a way that doesn&#8217;t instigate a wider war here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vladimir Putin, this weekend, warned that implementing a no-fly zone would be considered a declaration of war, but he also went further.&nbsp; His language was, via translator: &#8220;Any move in this direction will be viewed by us as a participation in the armed conflict.&nbsp; That very second, we will view them as participants…and it would not matter what members they are.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, why does the U.S. &#8212; or perhaps the U.S. and its NATO Allies have confidence that delivering those airplanes in any form will not be viewed by Vladimir Putin as an act of war?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, there&#8217;s already a war going on in Ukraine that&#8217;s been instigated by Vladimir Putin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A wider &#8212; he was referring to a &#8220;wider war&#8221; that would bring in them as an added participant.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think you ask an important question here, and it is: Where do these military planes take off from?&nbsp; That’s an important question, right?&nbsp; How do they land?&nbsp; How do they get there?&nbsp; The transporting of them.&nbsp; Those are all important factors.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he says &#8220;any move in this direction.&#8221;&nbsp; So even where they take off from almost doesn’t matter.&nbsp; By &#8220;any move&#8221; means even the provision of them would be viewed as an &#8220;act of war,&#8221; conceivably.&nbsp; No?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we can’t speak to President Putin&#8217;s &#8212; what&#8217;s in his mind, what&#8217;s in his brain, and the totality of what his intentions are.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already seen him take a range of steps.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve provided one billion dollars in security assistance.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not halting that, right?&nbsp; We&#8217;re not halting our support for the Ukrainians.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re not waiting for the advice of Vladimir Putin on what we&#8217;re going to do here as it relates to backfilling planes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the procurement or the providing of planes is up to Poland.&nbsp; They&#8217;re a sovereign country; they can decide.</p>



<p>I just wanted to outline some of the logistical challenges which are real, and they&#8217;re on a couple of layers.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Understood.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And given the conversation we&#8217;ve had earlier about Iran, Venezuela, and Saudi Arabia, the President, as a candidate, said in November of 2019, of Saudi Arabia &#8212; he said, we would make them, quote, “pay the price, and make them, in fact, the pariah that they are.”&nbsp; And there’s “very little social redeeming value in the present government in Saudi Arabia.”&nbsp; Does President Biden still stand by those words about the government of Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He does.&nbsp; He&#8217;s never stood away from them, Peter, but it&#8217;s also true that there is a war in Yemen, that there are security issues in the Middle East, that there are a range of steps we need to engage with all sorts of countries around the world on that are in &#8212; because it&#8217;s in our U.S. national security interests and in our interests.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, following up on that, Axios reported this morning that the President &#8212; there&#8217;s a deliberation here, at least, that the President might go to Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; Can you confirm those deliberations and perhaps provide a little bit more insight into what&#8217;s being discussed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s no current plans for the President to travel to Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The decision that you announced last week that the President would not be directly speaking with Vladimir Putin &#8212; has a decision amongst the Allies been made that that would be delegated to the European partners, that they would be the ones responsible for talking to Putin directly?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, but I would say that we very much support all of the diplomatic engagements our European partners or the Prime Minister of Israel or other leaders in the world are having, whether it&#8217;s with President Putin, as long as they are also engrazing [sic] &#8212; engaging with Ukrainian leadership, which we continue to encourage them to do.&nbsp; We also engage with them before and after all of these conversations.</p>



<p>So, what we said about the President speaking with President Putin is that now is not the moment.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean we close the door for &#8212; to forever.&nbsp; But while President Putin is invading &#8212; and in a brutal, horrific way &#8212; a foreign country, no, the President does not have an intention at this moment to speak with him.&nbsp; But that doesn&#8217;t mean he will never.&nbsp; You know, we assess that as time goes on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Okay.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll do this again tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, just a question on Venezuela.&nbsp; Who were the people who &#8212; the officials who went to Venezuela?&nbsp; Can you tell us about that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There have been a range of reports.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we can get you more details.</p>



<p>Thank you, everybody.  Thanks, everyone.  Have a great day.  Thank you.</p>



<p> 3:25 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/07/press-release-nominations-sent-to-the-senate-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 20:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;William H. Duncan, of Texas, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of El Salvador. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Jay Curtis Shambaugh, of Maryland, to be an Under Secretary of the Treasury, vice Brent James&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;William H. Duncan, of Texas, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of El Salvador.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Jay Curtis Shambaugh, of Maryland, to be an Under Secretary of the Treasury, vice Brent James McIntosh.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Denis Udall, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation for a term expiring April 15, 2023, vice Camilla C. Feibelman, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Teresa Arrington Fox Udall, of Colorado, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation for a term expiring October 6, 2022, vice Anne J. Udall, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Lesslie Viguerie, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kyrgyz Republic.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at a Clean Transit&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/07/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-a-clean-transit-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 19:47:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48528</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium Eisenhower Executive Office Building 11:49 A.M. EST THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you.  Thank you, Marc, for that incredible introduction but also for your incredible dedication to public service.  The people of Washington, D.C. and our nation thank you for your dedication. Well, good morning, everyone.&#160; Good morning.&#160; Today, we are joined by&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>11:49 A.M. EST<br></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you.  Thank you, Marc, for that incredible introduction but also for your incredible dedication to public service.  The people of Washington, D.C. and our nation thank you for your dedication.</p>



<p>Well, good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Today, we are joined by many leaders dedicated &#8212; who have always been dedicated &#8212; I know; I know you all &#8212; to improving the health and the wellbeing of all our communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg, thank you for your leadership.&nbsp; Administrator of our Environmental Protection Agency, Michael Regan, thank you for your leadership.&nbsp; These two guys joined me yesterday.&nbsp; We were in Selma talking about the connection between these issues and what it means to fight for social justice and equality.</p>



<p>Administrator of our Federal Transit Administration, Nuria Fernandez, thank you for your leadership.</p>



<p>And to the members of Congress who are here: I see you when you are walking the halls of our Capitol, when you are there where the cameras are on and where the cameras are off.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re always fighting for these issues and for the people of our nation.&nbsp; So I want to thank you all for being here this morning.</p>



<p>And to our labor leaders and our community leaders, our environmental leaders: Thank you all.&nbsp; Because this truly is about a group effort.</p>



<p>So, it is a special pleasure, and particularly to be together this week: the one-year anniversary of the passage of the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; And thank you, of course, to Gene Sperling, our American Rescue Plan Coordinator, and Mitch Landrieu, our administration&#8217;s Infrastructure Coordinator, who have done so much on behalf of our nation to make what we did in the halls of Congress hit the streets of America.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what it&#8217;s all about.</p>



<p>So I&#8217;ll begin with a short story.&nbsp; When I was attorney general of California, I heard about a town called Mira Loma.&nbsp; And this town had some of the worst air pollution in the state.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d been hearing stories about the grandmothers and the grandfathers in particular, asking, shouting, pleading: “Will someone pay attention to what is happening in our community?”&nbsp; They were demanding action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is a town of folks who work hard.&nbsp; They work hard.&nbsp; They are growing their families.&nbsp; It was a town where a lot of the folks were monolingual Spanish speaking, but were so dedicated &#8212; and were so dedicated to their community.</p>



<p>So, I went there.&nbsp; I went to go visit with them and to listen to them and to stand with them.&nbsp; And Mira Loma is a community not unlike communities around our nation &#8212; hardworking folks working hard jobs, just expecting, asking, righteously requiring that they be seen, that they be heard, and that their needs be taken seriously, and folks who are living in neighborhoods and communities across our country where they are in close proximity to large shipping warehouses or major highways.</p>



<p>In Mira Loma, every day, heavy-duty trucks made more than 15,000 trips to that town’s main roads, bringing with them, of course, soot and exhaust.&nbsp; And the air turned toxic.</p>



<p>The first time I went to Mira Loma, you could taste the metal in the air.&nbsp; My eyes burned.&nbsp; The toxicity in the air was that thick.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And studies, in fact, had shown &#8212; university studies had shown that children from Mira Loma were suffering from some of the poorest lung development of any communities in our state.&nbsp; People there told me that family members, relatives, friends were suffering from high rates of cancer, asthma, and heart disease.</p>



<p>And again, the fact is there are many Mira Lomas all over our country, communities that have been left out and left behind, and where pollution from heavy-duty trucks and buses has made the air poisonous to breathe.</p>



<p>And this pollution is also, of course, accelerating the climate crisis, threatening the future not just of our communities but of the entire world.&nbsp; And this is not how it has to be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Imagine a future: The freight trucks that deliver bread and milk to our grocery store shelves and the buses that take children to school and parents to work; imagine all the heavy-duty vehicles that keep our supply lines strong and allow our economy to grow &#8212; imagine that they produced zero emissions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, you all imagined it.&nbsp; That’s why we’re here today &#8212; because we have the ability to see what can be, unburdened by what has been, and then to make the possible actually happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, today, I am proud to announce that our administration is taking steps to build that better future by transforming our nation’s fleet of buses and trucks.&nbsp; And that transformation will begin with public buses.</p>



<p>This year, our Department of Transportation will make available nearly $1.5 billion &#8212; yes, Administrator Regan, with a “B” &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; in grants to help cities and towns electrify their fleet of public buses, build infrastructure to support their fleet, and train workers to run it.</p>



<p>These grants will make public transit more reliable and more affordable, which, of course, means shorter waits and more reliable commutes for folks who need to take public transit to get where they need to go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These buses will be built in America.&nbsp; And these grants will also be used to train drivers and mechanics to operate, maintain, and repair this new technology.&nbsp; This investment will create good jobs &#8212; jobs of the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we are not stopping there.&nbsp; Through our Department of Transportation, today we are also allocating $2.2 billion in funding from the American Rescue Plan &#8212; thank you, Congress &#8212; to 35 transit agencies spread across 18 states.&nbsp; This funding will help communities employ more transit workers and keep transit services running.</p>



<p>In addition, as Administrator Regan shared, today our EPA is issuing a proposed rule that will significantly &#8212; significantly reduce dangerous emissions from all new heavy-duty trucks and buses.</p>



<p>And again, as the Administrator shared, we are also announcing funding for, yes, one of my favorite topics: electric school buses.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s $17 million in grants will complement the $5 billion for clean school buses that we secured &#8212; thank you again &#8212; in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our transportation sector has reached a turning point.&nbsp; We are all in the midst of a turning point.&nbsp; We have the technology to transition to a zero-emission fleet.&nbsp; Our administration &#8212; together, all of us &#8212; is working to make that possibility a reality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can clean our air and protect the health of our children.&nbsp; We can connect all of our communities with affordable, accessible, and reliable public transportation.&nbsp; We can address the climate crisis and grow our economy at the same time.</p>



<p>And I am here today to say: Together, we all are doing just that.&nbsp; With the help of the American people, we are building a better future for all who call our dear country home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.  Thank you.  (Applause.) </p>



<p>END                      11:58 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joe&#160;Biden’s Call with President Macron of France, Chancellor Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Johnson of the United&#160;Kingdom</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/07/readout-of-president-joe-bidens-call-with-president-macron-of-france-chancellor-scholz-of-germany-prime-minister-johnson-of-the-united-kingdom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 18:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. held a secure video call today with President Emmanuel Macron of France, Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany, and Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom.&#160; The leaders affirmed their determination to continue raising the costs&#160;on Russia for its&#160;unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. &#160;They also underscored their commitment to&#160;continue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. held a secure video call today with President Emmanuel Macron of France, Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany, and Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom.&nbsp; The leaders affirmed their determination to continue raising the costs&nbsp;on Russia for its&nbsp;unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. &nbsp;They also underscored their commitment to&nbsp;continue providing security, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; In addition, they discussed their&nbsp;respective&nbsp;recent engagements with the Ukrainian and Russian presidents.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Department of Education Announces State-by-State American Rescue Plan Funding for Colleges and&#160;Universities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/07/fact-sheet-department-of-education-announces-state-by-state-american-rescue-plan-funding-for-colleges-and-universities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During Week of Anniversary of American Rescue Plan, Biden-Harris Administration Highlights Investments in Community Colleges, Historically Black Colleges and Universities, and Other Critical Institutions Today, the Department of Education announced state-by-state breakdown of funding for colleges and universities provided in the President’s American Rescue Plan – one of the largest one-time infusions of funding ever&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>During Week of Anniversary of American Rescue Plan, Biden-Harris Administration Highlights Investments in Community Colleges, Historically Black Colleges and Universities, and Other Critical Institutions</em></p>



<p>Today, the Department of Education announced state-by-state breakdown of funding for colleges and universities provided in the President’s American Rescue Plan – one of the largest one-time infusions of funding ever provided to the nation’s colleges and universities. These funds were provided through the Higher Education Emergency Relief Fund (HEERF) over the past year.</p>



<p>The American Rescue Plan provided:</p>



<ul><li>More than $10 billion to over 1,000 community colleges</li><li>More than $2.7 billion to Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs)</li><li>More than $190 million to Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities (TCCUs)</li><li>Approximately $11 billion to Hispanic-serving institutions (HSIs)</li><li>Approximately $5 billion to Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions (AANAPISIs)</li><li>Almost $1 billion to Predominantly Black Institutions (PBIs)</li></ul>



<p><strong>The Department of Education expects at least half of these funds will be used to provide direct financial relief to students.</strong> In addition to funding provided under previous coronavirus relief legislation, these funds are already being used by colleges and universities across the country to serve students and ensure learning continues during the COVID-19 pandemic. These funds are already having a significant impact on institutions and students:</p>



<ul><li>A <a href="https://www.acenet.edu/Research-Insights/Pages/Senior-Leaders/Presidents-Survey-HEERF.aspx">recent survey of college presidents by the American Council on Education</a> found HEERF enabled:<ul><li><strong><u>93% of colleges to provide direct financial support</u></strong> to students at risk of dropping out</li></ul><ul><li><strong><u>81% of colleges to keep student net prices similar to pre-pandemic levels</u></strong></li></ul><ul><li><strong><u>70% of colleges to continue to employ faculty, staff, and other employees</u></strong> otherwise at risk of unemployment</li></ul><ul><li><strong><u>63% of colleges to keep students and faculty safe</u></strong> by purchasing COVID-19 tests, health screenings, and health care</li></ul></li><li>Thousands of colleges and universities all across the country are <strong><u>using HEERF to keep students enrolled and on track to graduate, as well as make college more affordable</u></strong>, by providing emergency grants, discharging outstanding student debt or unpaid balances, and eliminating transcript withholding practices.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Factsheet by State/Territory:</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Alabama.pdf">Alabama</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Alaska.pdf">Alaska</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Arizona.pdf">Arizona</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Arkansas.pdf">Arkansas</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-California.pdf">California</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Colorado.pdf">Colorado</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Connecticut.pdf">Connecticut</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Delaware.pdf">Delaware</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Florida.pdf">Florida</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Georgia.pdf">Georgia</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Hawaii.pdf">Hawaii</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Idaho.pdf">Idaho</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Illinois.pdf">Illinois</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Indiana.pdf">Indiana</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Iowa.pdf">Iowa</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Kansas.pdf">Kansas</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Kentucky.pdf">Kentucky</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Louisiana.pdf">Louisiana</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Maine.pdf">Maine</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Maryland.pdf">Maryland</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Massachusetts.pdf">Massachusetts</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Michigan.pdf">Michigan</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Minnesota.pdf">Minnesota</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Mississippi.pdf">Mississippi</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Missouri.pdf">Missouri</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Montana.pdf">Montana</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Nebraska.pdf">Nebraska</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Nevada.pdf">Nevada</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-New-Hampshire.pdf">New Hampshire</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-New-Jersey.pdf">New Jersey</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-New-Mexico.pdf">New Mexico</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-New-York.pdf">New York</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-North-Carolina.pdf">North Carolina</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-North-Dakota.pdf">North Dakota</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Ohio.pdf">Ohio</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Oklahoma.pdf">Oklahoma</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Oregon.pdf">Oregon</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Pennsylvania.pdf">Pennsylvania</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Rhode-Island.pdf">Rhode Island</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-South-Carolina.pdf">South Carolina</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-South-Dakota.pdf">South Dakota</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Tennessee.pdf">Tennessee</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Texas.pdf">Texas</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Utah.pdf">Utah</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Vermont.pdf">Vermont</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Virginia.pdf">Virginia</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Washington.pdf">Washington</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-West-Virgina.pdf">West Virginia</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Wisconsin.pdf">Wisconsin</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-Wyoming.pdf">Wyoming</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ARP-Higher-Ed-DC.pdf">District of Columbia</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" />
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: State-by-State Analysis of Record $2.7 Billion American Rescue Plan Investment in Historically Black Colleges and&#160;Universities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/07/fact-sheet-state-by-state-analysis-of-record-2-7-billion-american-rescue-plan-investment-in-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 18:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During Week of Anniversary of American Rescue Plan, Administration Highlights Investments in Historically Black Colleges and Universities Today, the Department of Education announced state-by-state breakdown of over $2.7 billion in funding for Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) provided in the President’s American Rescue Plan. These funds were provided through the Higher Education Emergency Relief&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>During Week of Anniversary of American Rescue Plan, Administration Highlights Investments in Historically Black Colleges and Universities</em></p>



<p>Today, the Department of Education announced state-by-state breakdown of <strong><u>over $2.7 billion in funding for Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) provided in the President’s American Rescue Plan</u></strong>. These funds were provided through the Higher Education Emergency Relief Fund (HEERF) over the past year. HBCUs create pathways to opportunity for Black students and foster academic excellence throughout our nation. This infusion of federal funding – <strong><u>among the largest ever in the country’s HBCUs</u></strong> – is a key part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to shared prosperity and equity for all Americans. This funding also complements other American Rescue Plan funds for critical institutions of higher education that serve communities of color.</p>



<p><strong><u>The American Rescue Plan requires half of these funds to be used to provide direct financial relief to students; the Department of Education expects far more will ultimately be used for that purpose.</u></strong> In addition to funding provided under previous coronavirus relief legislation, these funds are already being used by colleges and universities across the country to serve students and ensure learning continues during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Thousands of colleges and universities all across the country are <strong><u>using HEERF to keep students enrolled and on track to graduate, as well as make college more affordable</u></strong>, by providing emergency grants, discharging outstanding student debt or unpaid balances, and eliminating transcript withholding practices.</p>



<p><strong>American Rescue Plan Funding to HBCUs by State/Territory:</strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Alabama: Over $334 million for 13 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Alabama A&amp;M University: $60,120,210</li><li>Alabama State University: $42,725,038</li><li>Bishop State Community College: $34,271,512</li><li>Lawson State Community College: $34,045,562</li><li>Tuskegee University: $30,961,457</li><li>Shelton State Community College: $29,004,331</li><li>H. Councill Trenholm State Community College: $21,002,921</li><li>Gadsden State Community College: $18,767,865</li><li>Miles College: $18,102,234</li><li>Talladega College: $14,112,105</li><li>J. F.&nbsp; Drake State Community and Technical College: $11,584,720</li><li>Oakwood University: $10,806,960</li><li>Stillman College: $9,171,243</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Arkansas: Nearly $61 million for 4 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>University of Arkansas at Pine Bluff: $25,138,852</li><li>Shorter College: $13,019,110</li><li>Philander Smith College: $11,774,144</li><li>Arkansas Baptist College: $10,779,046</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>California: Over $13 million for 1 HBCU</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Charles R. Drew University of Medicine and Science: $13,295,109</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Delaware: Nearly $36 million for 1 HBCU</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Delaware State University: $35,923,801</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>District of Columbia: Over $88 million for 2 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Howard University: $57,482,588</li><li>University of the District of Columbia: $30,918,101</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Florida: Over $156 million for 4 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Florida A&amp;M University: $99,274,125</li><li>Bethune Cookman University: $33,041,940</li><li>Edward Waters College: $13,228,709</li><li>Florida Memorial University: $10,641,947</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Georgia: Over $260 million for 8 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Morehouse School of Medicine: $56,785,507</li><li>Albany State University: $53,287,476</li><li>Clark Atlanta University: $47,762,468</li><li>Savannah State University: $41,412,308</li><li>Fort Valley State University: $26,524,053</li><li>Morehouse College: $15,541,496</li><li>Spelman College: $13,786,698</li><li>Paine College: $5,557,820</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Kentucky: Over $21 million for 2 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Kentucky State University: $15,109,665</li><li>Simmons College of Kentucky: $6,453,559</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Louisiana: Over $211 million for 6 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Southern University and A&amp;M College: $64,130,696</li><li>Grambling State University: $48,074,370</li><li>Southern University at New Orleans: $36,540,309</li><li>Xavier University of Louisiana: $31,406,850</li><li>Southern University at Shreveport ‐ Bossier City: $18,289,223</li><li>Dillard University: $12,710,006</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Maryland: Over $153 million for 4 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Morgan State University: $61,889,348</li><li>Bowie State University: $44,408,346</li><li>University of Maryland ‐ Eastern Shore: $26,844,541</li><li>Coppin State University: $20,440,423</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Mississippi: Over $237 million for 7 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Hinds Community College: $87,047,253</li><li>Jackson State University: $60,437,863</li><li>Alcorn State University: $33,482,855</li><li>Mississippi Valley State University: $22,861,645</li><li>Coahoma Community College: $19,112,009</li><li>Rust College: $8,224,611</li><li>Tougaloo College: $7,924,421</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Missouri: Over $38 million for 2 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Harris ‐ Stowe State University: $20,222,823</li><li>Lincoln University: $18,116,034</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>North Carolina: Over $307 million for 10 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>North Carolina A&amp;T State University: $93,092,139</li><li>North Carolina Central University: $62,903,281</li><li>Winston‐Salem State University: $42,169,266</li><li>Fayetteville State University: $41,559,265</li><li>Elizabeth City State University: $15,779,156</li><li>Johnson C Smith University: $14,375,251</li><li>Livingstone College: $13,710,891</li><li>Shaw University: $11,869,547</li><li>Saint Augustine&#8217;s University: $8,065,614</li><li>Bennett College: $4,068,757</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Ohio: Over $34 million for 2 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Central State University: $25,880,482</li><li>Wilberforce University: $8,123,992</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Oklahoma: Over $23 million for 1 HBCU</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Langston University: $23,093,393</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Pennsylvania: Over $25 million for 2 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Lincoln University: $18,531,228</li><li>Cheyney University of Pennsylvania: $6,928,018</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>South Carolina: Nearly $112 million for 8 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>South Carolina State University: $24,839,400</li><li>Benedict College: $22,424,080</li><li>Claflin University: $21,574,206</li><li>Allen University: $12,760,702</li><li>Denmark Technical College: $8,529,645</li><li>Morris College: $8,090,968</li><li>Clinton College: $7,170,012</li><li>Voorhees College: $6,553,949</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Tennessee: Over $133 million for 6 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Tennessee State University: $58,594,818</li><li>Meharry Medical College: $36,461,963</li><li>Lane College: $15,156,158</li><li>LeMoyne ‐ Owen College: $10,280,982</li><li>Fisk University: $7,506,145</li><li>American Baptist College: $5,682,740</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Texas: Nearly $304 million for 9 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Texas Southern University: $90,104,029</li><li>Prairie View A&amp;M University: $84,101,911</li><li>St Philip&#8217;s College: $70,663,484</li><li>Texas College: $12,378,810</li><li>Huston ‐ Tillotson University: $11,360,349</li><li>Jarvis Christian College: $10,982,554</li><li>Wiley College: $9,934,742</li><li>Paul Quinn College: $8,089,525</li><li>Southwestern Christian College: $6,085,111</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>U.S. Virgin Islands: Over $12 million for 1 HBCU</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>University of the Virgin Islands: $12,225,340</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Virginia: Over $141 million for 5 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Norfolk State University: $52,248,428</li><li>Virginia State University: $39,482,142</li><li>Hampton University: $31,205,244</li><li>Virginia Union University: $11,866,504</li><li>Virginia University of Lynchburg: $6,322,150</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>West Virginia: Over $28 million for 2 HBCUs</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>West Virginia State University: $16,998,872</li><li>Bluefield State College: $11,074,452</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Vice President Harris Announces Actions to Accelerate Clean Transit Buses, School Buses, and&#160;Trucks</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/07/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-actions-to-accelerate-clean-transit-buses-school-buses-and-trucks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Actions Will Deliver Cleaner Air, Healthier Neighborhoods, and Better Transportation Today, Vice President Kamala Harris is announcing major federal actions that will expand clean public transit and school buses, reduce emissions from dirty diesel trucks, and create good-paying jobs.&#160;The Biden-Harris Administration will modernize public transit that connects people to their jobs, school, health care,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>New Actions Will Deliver Cleaner Air, Healthier Neighborhoods, and Better Transportation</em></p>



<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris is announcing major federal actions that will expand clean public transit and school buses, reduce emissions from dirty diesel trucks, and create good-paying jobs.&nbsp;The Biden-Harris Administration will modernize public transit that connects people to their jobs, school, health care, and loved ones, freight trucks and ports that move goods through the American economy, and the iconic American yellow buses that bring children safely to school leveraging investments from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and American Rescue Plan investments, as well as a new proposed rule that would set heavy-duty vehicle emissions standards. Together, these actions will deliver better transportation for the American people while reducing air pollution that has long overburdened low-income communities and communities of color. They also boost American leadership on the zero-emissions transit, trucking, and port technologies of the future—to create good-paying, union jobs, improve public health, and confront climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Heavy-duty vehicles, like buses and trucks, make up nearly one-quarter of all U.S. transportation greenhouse gas emissions, and heavy-duty vehicles are the largest contributor of nitrogen oxides (NOx)—air pollution that is known to cause asthma, heart and lung disease, and other serious respiratory issues. Neighborhoods near highways, ports, and other congested areas are especially impacted by health problems and premature deaths associated with dirty diesel exhaust. These burdens disproportionately impact people of color and low-income households.<br><br>To seize new economic opportunities and address these environmental injustices and climate concerns, while expanding public transit and ensuring efficient delivery of goods, the Administration is announcing a fleet of new and expanded actions to advance clean heavy-duty vehicles, as part of our electric, zero-emissions transportation future:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Cleaner, More Convenient Public Transit:</strong> The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law represents the single largest investment in public transit in history. As part of the historic $5.5 billion expansion of the Low- and No-Emission Transit Vehicle Program, the Department of Transportation (DOT) is announcing $1.1 billion in funding for 2022 and an additional $372 million under the Bus and Bus Facilities program. The Low-No Program helps state and local governments purchase U.S.-built electric transit buses and other cleaner models, to improve local air quality and expand affordable, accessible, transportation options in communities across the country. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law increased Low-No program funding by ten times, compared to the prior five years.&nbsp; Also, as a result of changes enacted in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, the grants will dedicate funding to workforce training that helps protect and upskill transit workers – ensuring that those who work on transit vehicles today are ready to do so in the future. To keep transit workers on the job and transit services running, DOT is also announcing $2.2 billion in funding to 35 transit agencies across 18 states through the American Rescue Plan.<br></li><li><strong>Saving Lives, Reducing Emissions:</strong> The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is issuing a proposed rule that would, if finalized, dramatically reduce harmful nitrogen oxides (NOx) emissions from heavy-duty vehicles and set stronger greenhouse gas emissions standards for certain heavy-duty vehicle categories. This proposed rule would ensure heavy-duty vehicles and engines are as clean as possible while helping jump-start the transition to zero-emission vehicles in the heavy-duty fleet. When fully implemented, this rule will save roughly 2,000 lives annually, eliminate 18,000 cases of childhood asthma, and lead to 1.1 million fewer missed days of school.<br></li><li><strong>Electrifying School Buses: </strong>The Environmental Protection Agency is awarding $17 million to fund electric zero-emission and low-emission school buses. Through the American Rescue Plan, $7 million is being awarded to replace old diesel school buses in underserved communities with new, zero-emission electric buses. In addition, $10 million is being awarded to replace old diesel school buses with new cleaner buses through the Diesel Emissions Reduction Act (DERA) School Bus Rebate Program. This funding complements the $5 billion in funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law for clean school buses, the first tranche of which will become available in the coming months.<br></li><li><strong>Lower Emissions from Ports:</strong> The Department of Transportation is using new project eligibilities in the Port Infrastructure Development Program – which is now funded at the highest levels ever through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law – to advance clean port equipment like electric vehicle charging infrastructure for drayage trucks, cargo equipment, and harbor craft. <a href="https://www.maritime.dot.gov/PIDPgrants">Grant applicants</a> are encouraged to submit projects that reduce emissions, strengthen resilience, improve air quality in fenceline communities, and plan for the zero-emission ports of the future.<br></li><li><strong>Innovation on Clean Trucks of the Future:</strong> The Department of Energy is partnering with industry to expand zero-emission truck technology through its SuperTruck 3 Program, with the latest round of $127 million in funding focused for the first time on reducing costs and improving durability in hydrogen and battery electric trucks.<br></li><li><strong>Leading by Example:</strong> The General Services Administration is doubling the amount of zero-emission medium and heavy-duty vehicle models available to federal agencies, charging towards 100% zero emission vehicle acquisitions by 2035.</li></ul>



<p>These steps build upon President Biden’s Executive Order on Strengthening American Leadership in Clean Cars and Trucks, which he <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-steps-to-drive-american-leadership-forward-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/">signed</a> in August 2021 alongside American automakers and autoworkers, launching development of smart fuel efficiency and emissions standards across all vehicles. President Biden and Vice President Harris also secured historic investments in clean transportation through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and American Rescue Plan. The announcement today of $1.1 billion for clean transit buses through the $5 billion Lo-No Program expansion, $17 million for clean school buses, and the ongoing buildout of a national EV charging network will transform bus transit from city centers to rural towns – improving connectivity and quality of life – while contributing to President Biden&#8217;s goal to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 50-52% compared to 2005 levels by 2030.<br><br>Together, today’s actions will:<br><br><strong>Electrify Our Buses</strong><br>To accelerate our transition to clean public transit, over $5.5 billion is being infused into the Department of Transportation’s popular Low- and No-Emission Transit Vehicle Program through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law – by far the largest ever investment in this program, and ten times larger than the last five years of funding. The Low-No Program helps state and local governments purchase or lease zero-emission and low-emission transit buses and other vehicles and expand or retrofit supporting facilities. These include vehicles that use technologies such as battery electric and fuel-cell power to provide clean, quieter, and more efficient transit service in communities across the country. In 2022, $1.1 billion will be granted to clean and electrify transit buses – representing almost a billion dollars in new investment compared to last year. This comes on top of nearly $2 billion over five years, and $372 million in 2022, provided in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law for the Buses and Bus Facilities Competitive Program to be used in part for low or no emissions bus projects. &nbsp;The clean buses purchased by these grants will be made here in the United States, creating manufacturing jobs in places like Minnesota, Alabama, South Carolina, and California.<br><br>Also, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides the first-ever dedicated investment in our transit workforce to support the transition to new clean technologies like battery electric buses.&nbsp; Five percent of grants under the program – up to $280 million over five years – will be used to fund workforce development training, including registered apprenticeships and other labor-management training programs, to train and upskill transit workers to maintain and operate zero emission vehicles and related charging infrastructure.<br><br>To keep all of these buses running – along with our country’s trains, ferries and other transit services – the Department of Transportation is also announcing $2.2 billion in grants to 35 transit agencies across 18 states. These funds are made available through President Biden’s American Rescue Plan and will help public transit agencies pay for day-to-day operations, keep tens of thousands of employees on the payroll, and provide essential transportation services to workers across America.<br><br>The EPA is also moving to deploy more clean school buses – awarding $17 million in rebates to fund electric zero-emission and low-emission school buses. Through the American Rescue Plan, $7 million is being awarded to replace old diesel school buses with new, zero-emission electric buses. These funds are reserved exclusively for school districts in underserved communities, tribal schools, and the private fleets serving those schools. In addition, the EPA awarded $10 million to replace old diesel school buses with new electric, diesel, gasoline, propane, or compressed natural gas buses through longstanding Diesel Emissions Reduction Act (DERA) School Bus Rebates. Later this year, major new investments funded by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s new $5 billion clean school bus program will allow EPA to greatly expand the impacts of clean school bus deployment.<br><br><strong>Reduce Truck Emissions, Save Lives</strong><br>Today, the EPA announced a proposed rule that would reduce NOx emissions from new trucks by up to 90% by 2031 compared to today&#8217;s standards. The current regulations set under the Clean Air Act for trucks were last updated over 20 years ago. However, trucks meeting this standard are still major sources of NOx and other harmful pollutants.<br><br>All traditional truck engines combust fuel which leads to creation of NOx – a harmful pollutant and precursor to the formation of smog and particulates. This pollution makes it difficult to breathe, triggers asthma and other lung diseases and is associated with premature death. These harmful conditions disproportionately impact low-income communities and communities of color. Without the actions taken today and the resulting shift to low- and zero-emission vehicles, these communities will continue to bear the brunt of these emissions.<br><br>When this rule is fully implemented, there will be numerous benefits to communities around the country, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Lives Saved:</strong> Roughly 2,000 premature deaths avoided and 6,700 fewer hospital and ER visits each year;</li><li><strong>Healthy School Kids</strong>: 18,000 fewer cases of childhood asthma and 1.1 million fewer missed days of school each year;</li><li><strong>Productive Communities</strong>: 78,000 fewer missed days of work each year.</li></ul>



<p>In addition to strengthening NOx regulations, EPA and DOT are preparing to redouble the Administration&#8217;s commitment to zero-emissions trucks by using the upcoming Heavy-Duty GHG Phase 3 Program to set ambitious greenhouse gas and efficiency standards beginning in 2030. Because costs have fallen and state and local policy will drive deployment, zero-emission trucks and buses are entering the market much faster than anticipated when rules were previously set. To account for this, EPA is considering technical updates to its standards for model years 2027 to 2029 to better reflect new levels of market penetration in segments with expected zero-emission vehicle deployment.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Clean Our Port Operations</strong><br>The ports on our coasts, rivers, and Great Lakes will need to be transformed to eliminate pollution affecting neighboring communities, address climate change, and strengthen supply chain resilience. This includes a focus on reducing emissions from heavy-duty road vehicles and rail that play key roles in port operations.<br><br>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides the largest investment ever in the <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/president-biden-and-us-department-transportation-announce-historic-new-funding">DOT&#8217;s Port Infrastructure Development Program</a> – with the expansion designed to advance the Administration&#8217;s climate and environmental justice goals. Grant applicants are encouraged to submit projects that reduce emissions, strengthen resilience, and improve air quality in fenceline communities. These investments will touch all points of port operations – cleaning cargo handling equipment, harbor craft, and building out needed charging infrastructure for drayage trucks. The program also encourages master planning for port electrification and grid upgrades. In addition, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funded DOT to issue new grants to reduce truck idling and emissions at ports, including through the advancement of port electrification, which will complement other port investments.<br><br><strong>Catalyze Zero Emission Truck Infrastructure<br></strong>Through the President&#8217;s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, the Departments of Energy and Transportation are making significant investments in updating the nation&#8217;s trucking fleets and freight infrastructure to be cleaner and more efficient.<br><br>To spur investment in zero emission trucks, the Federal Transit Administration, in conjunction with the Federal Highway Administration, is helping states purchase medium and heavy-duty vehicles through the Congestion Mitigation and Air Quality Program. DOE&#8217;s Loan Program Office has been given expanded authority for manufacturing of clean medium and heavy-duty on-road vehicles as well as vehicles and components in the aviation, maritime, and rail sectors, pending future appropriations.<br><br>To advance the build-out of our nation&#8217;s network of 500,000 EV chargers, DOT’s recent EV charging guidance to states includes eligibility to support charging infrastructure for trucks. Given the unique needs of medium- and heavy-duty vehicles, DOE’s Sustainable Transportation offices are studying how to advance clean, affordable hydrogen and electrification corridor solutions to connect ports, highways, and end users, and provide clean freight solutions to move goods and materials from first mile to the last.<br><br><strong>Accelerate Path Towards Zero-Emission Trucks</strong><br>Through major advances in zero-emissions technology, clean trucks are becoming cheaper and more readily available. Today, the National Renewable Energy Lab published a study showing that zero emission electric medium and heavy-duty trucks can reach total-cost-of-driving parity with diesel counterparts for many vehicle types this decade and for all trucks by 2035. As technology continues to improve, and more infrastructure is deployed, more and more clean trucks will become cost-effective. That&#8217;s good for business and good for the planet.<br><br>In order to continue to drive down costs, the Department of Energy is investing in trucking innovation and next generation clean technologies. In 2009, DOE launched its SuperTruck Initiative to partner with industry to improve heavy-duty truck freight efficiency by 50%. This year, SuperTruck 3 is off to the races with a combined $127 million in funding to industry focused on reducing costs and improving durability in zero-emission hydrogen and battery electric trucks. In addition, its SuperTruck 2 Program is set to conclude this year having developed cost-effective technology that doubles the fuel economy for 18-wheeler trucks.<br><br>Multiple other research projects across government and industry are targeting progress in fuel cell electric trucks, batteries, and freight efficiency, including:</p>



<ul><li>Advanced Research on Integrated Energy Systems (ARIES) – providing a real world environment for testing large battery and fuel cell electric trucks.</li><li>Million Mile Fuel Cell Truck consortium – developing cost-effective technology with industry for next generation fuel cells.</li><li>21<sup>st</sup> Century Truck Partnership – launching a new electrification tech team focused on removing barriers to wide-scale truck electrification and deploying technology to improve freight efficiency.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Transform the Federal Truck Fleet</strong><br>This Administration is leading by example – acting as an early adopter by transforming its federal fleet of over 110,000 medium- and heavy-duty vehicles. [1] Today, federal agencies are able to acquire 38 different models of medium and heavy duty zero emissions vehicles through the General Services Administration – more than double the offerings in fiscal year 2021. The President&#8217;s Federal Sustainability Plan, outlined in <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/12/13/2021-27114/catalyzing-clean-energy-industries-and-jobs-through-federal-sustainability">Executive Order 14057</a>, also calls for 100% of all annual medium and heavy-duty vehicle acquisitions to be zero emissions by 2035.<br><br>The federal government will work with American vehicle, battery, and charging equipment manufacturers and installers to transform its truck fleet. This will accelerate the advancement of America&#8217;s industrial capacity to supply zero-emission trucks and electric batteries – creating and sustaining good-paying, union jobs in manufacturing, engineering, and skilled trades. This federal truck transformation complements the Administration&#8217;s commitment to 100% zero-emission light-duty vehicle acquisitions by 2027.<br> </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" />



<p>[1] (Non-Postal)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris to Commemorate the 57th Anniversary of Bloody&#160;Sunday</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/06/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-to-commemorate-the-57th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 02:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Edmund Pettus BridgeSelma, Alabama 3:34 P.M. CST THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, Selma.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; (Applause.)&#160;&#160;&#160;Kendra, thank you for those inspiring words.&#160; In the great tradition of Alabama State, you are a leader of outstanding passion and purpose, and it is wonderful to have shared the stage with you.&#160;So, Selma, before I begin, I want&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Edmund Pettus Bridge<br>Selma, Alabama</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br></p>



<p>3:34 P.M. CST<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, Selma.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Kendra, thank you for those inspiring words.&nbsp; In the great tradition of Alabama State, you are a leader of outstanding passion and purpose, and it is wonderful to have shared the stage with you.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, Selma, before I begin, I want to say a few words about the situation in Ukraine.&nbsp; Today, the eyes of the world are on Ukraine and the brave people who are fighting to protect their country and their democracy.&nbsp; And their bravery is a reminder that freedom and democracy can never be taken for granted by any of us.<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, it is a privilege to be among so many distinguished leaders, dedicated activists, friends, and American heroes &#8212; and to be with so many members of Congress, of our Cabinet, who are all representing our nation and representing our administration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is a particular honor to be joined by the family of Congressman John Lewis and the family of Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, today, we gather here on hallowed ground.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It was a chilly&nbsp;Sunday morning, 57 years ago, when 600 brave individuals set out from Selma.&nbsp; They were marching for the most fundamental right of American citizenship: The right to vote.<br>&nbsp;<br>They knew that if they wanted true freedom, if they wanted to claim what was theirs by birth and by right, they had to march on this bridge on that day.&nbsp; They were prepared for the worst.<br>&nbsp;<br>And on this bridge on that day the worst found them.&nbsp; Their peaceful protest was met with crushing violence.&nbsp; They were kneeling when the state troopers charged.&nbsp; They were praying when the billy clubs struck.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On this bridge on that day, those brave marchers continued to push forward to secure the freedom to vote, and they were pushed back.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, we stand on this bridge at a different time.&nbsp; We again, however, find ourselves caught in between &#8212; between injustice and justice, between disappointment and determination &#8212; still in a fight to form “a more perfect union.”&nbsp; And nowhere is that more clear than when it comes to the ongoing fight to secure the freedom to vote.<br>&nbsp;<br>A record number of people cast their ballots in the 2020 elections.&nbsp; It was a triumph of democracy in many ways.&nbsp; But not everyone saw it that way.&nbsp; Some saw it as a threat.&nbsp; And so, as powerful people have done many times in our nation&#8217;s history, they launched an assault on the freedom to vote.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Across the country, states passed anti-voting laws &#8212; laws that ban drop boxes and restrict early voting; laws that make it illegal to give food and water to voters who are standing and waiting in line; laws that, put simply, make it much more difficult for people to vote with an expectation that then we will not vote. &nbsp;Undemocratic laws. &nbsp;Un-American laws.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, last year, we all joined together.&nbsp; We locked arms<br>and lifted our voices and fought to pass federal voting rights legislation.&nbsp; We brought the Freedom to Vote Act and, yes, the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act to the floor of the Senate.<br>&nbsp;<br>And on the night of January 19th, every Republican senator in the United States Senate voted to block passage of this law.<br>&nbsp;<br>Over the past few months, I have traveled our country talking with so many people about our fight &#8212; our collective fight to safeguard and strengthen the freedom to vote: faith leaders, community leaders, students, activists, and organizers.&nbsp; And, yes, people are tired and frustrated and, at times, scared &#8212; scared that we risk losing the rights we fought so hard to win.<br>&nbsp;<br>I believe, at this moment, we are faced with a choice &#8212; a choice that we have faced many times before: Do we stand or do we fight?<br>&nbsp;<br>Gathered at this bridge, reflecting on its history, yes, I know the path forward is clear.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Remember, it took three tries for the marchers to cross the bridge.&nbsp; It took their sweat, their tears, their blood.&nbsp; It took their resilience, their determination, and their courage.&nbsp; And, yes, it even took the protection of the National Guard and federal marshals.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In a moment of great uncertainty, those marchers pressed forward and they crossed.&nbsp; We must do the same.&nbsp; We must lock our arms and march forward.&nbsp; We will not let setbacks stop us.<br>&nbsp;<br>We know that honoring the legacy of those who marched then<br>demands that we continue to push Congress to pass federal voting rights legislation &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and it also demands we continue to push the Senate not to allow an arcane rule to deny us this sacred right.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It demands we continue to lift up state legislatures that have passed pro-voter laws and that we keep fighting to prevent the passage of anti-voter laws.&nbsp; It demands we keep going to court to defend this sacred freedom.&nbsp; And it demands we register voters, volunteer as election workers, and, yes, of course, drive souls to the polls.<br>&nbsp;<br>And none of this is new, especially to so many of you who have been in this fight for so long.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I am here &#8212; again, here in Selma &#8212; to say thank you for your work, your sacrifice, and your dedication.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I have come here today to also remind you that we all stand together.&nbsp; President Biden and I are working for this cause every day.&nbsp; We have put the full power of the executive branch behind our shared effort.&nbsp; And if we all continue to work together, to march together, to fight together, we will secure the freedom to vote.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Selma, the future of our democracy is being decided now by you, by us, by the people.&nbsp; And ultimately, you are the ones &#8212; we are the ones &#8212; who must protect the freedom to vote.&nbsp; And we must not stop there.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Those who marched across this bridge &#8212; yes, they marched for the freedom to vote; they also marched for all of the rights and freedoms that voting unlocks.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; They marched for economic justice, for social justice, for racial justice &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and we must do the same.<br>&nbsp;<br>We must fight to ensure all the people of our nation &#8212; no matter where they start &#8212; have the opportunity to succeed.&nbsp; We must fight to move our nation forward while we reflect on why it matters.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just think: Last week, President Biden made history when he nominated the first Black woman, Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to the highest court in our land &#8212; the court where decisions are made about the Constitutional rights and liberties and freedoms of every American to generational effect.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’ll tell you what I think you know: Judge Jackson is a phenomenal jurist with a record of excellence &#8212; a record that proves her commitment not only to public service but to equal justice and equal rights.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as she makes history, Judge Jackson, like us all, stands on the shoulders of giants.&nbsp; She and we are their legacy &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the legacy of those who are with us today: Annie Pearl Avery &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Charles Mauldin &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Bernard Lafayette &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Sheyann Webb-Christburg &#8212; (applause); the legacy of those who are smiling down on us: Marie Foster &#8212; (applause) &#8212; J.D. Hunter &#8212; (applause) &#8212; C.J. Adams &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Amelia Boynton Robinson &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and of all those courageous foot soldiers for freedom who named &#8212; and whose names we know and sometimes names we will not know but who lift us up nonetheless.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The last time I was in Selma was the last time Congressman John Lewis stood on this bridge.&nbsp; For his whole life, and especially that day, John Lewis was the embodiment of strength and resilience, the epitome of dignity, grace, and perseverance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As he stood here that day, you could see the body that carried him across this bridge all those years ago had become fragile, but the spirit that carried him was as strong as ever.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; That’s right!<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; John Lewis &#8212; well, he never gave up the fight.&nbsp; He returned to this bridge again, and again, and again.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is that clarity of purpose, that relentless dedication, that spirit &#8212; the spirit of Selma &#8212; that we summon today.<br>&nbsp;<br>We will keep fighting.&nbsp; We will keep organizing. &nbsp;We will keep shouting.&nbsp; We will keep making good trouble.&nbsp; And we will march on until victory is won.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you, all.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, all.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;3:48 P.M. CST</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Anniversary of Bloody&#160;Sunday</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/06/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48437</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Sunday, March 7, 1965, time stopped and blood spilled as brave and righteous Americans sought to cross a bridge named after a Klansman in Selma, Alabama, to reach the other side of justice. Led by the late John Lewis, they marched to secure their sacred right to vote. Their heroism was met by batons&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Sunday, March 7, 1965, time stopped and blood spilled as brave and righteous Americans sought to cross a bridge named after a Klansman in Selma, Alabama, to reach the other side of justice. Led by the late John Lewis, they marched to secure their sacred right to vote. Their heroism was met by batons and tear gas. They were beaten, but not defeated. Their absolute courage forced America to look in the mirror and Congress to act. Soon after, President Johnson signed the Voting Rights Act of 1965.</p>



<p>But over time, the strength of that groundbreaking law has been weakened not by brute force, but by insidious court decisions. Today, we’re seeing states across the country propose or enact laws that make it harder to vote and have that vote counted — an onslaught of deeply dangerous efforts to suppress the vote and subvert entire elections.</p>



<p>In Selma, the blood of John Lewis and so many other courageous Americans sanctified a noble struggle. We are determined to honor that legacy by passing legislation to protect the right to vote and uphold the integrity of our elections, including the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act and the Freedom to Vote Act.</p>



<p>My Administration will continue implementing my <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/28/fact-sheet-biden-administration-promotes-voter-participation-with-new-agency-steps/">Executive Order</a> to promote voter participation, increase access to the ballot, and rally the country to protect voting rights and election integrity. Vice President Harris, marching in Selma today, will continue to lead this effort. The U.S. Justice Department has doubled its voting rights enforcement staff to stop discriminatory voting laws as the Voting Rights Act of 1965 empowered it to do. And I will continue to use every tool at my disposal to strengthen our democracy and keep alive the promise of America for all Americans.</p>



<p>The battle for the soul of America has many fronts. The right to vote is the most fundamental.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden meeting with National Union Labor&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/05/readout-of-president-biden-meeting-with-national-union-labor-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today,&#160;President Biden&#160;and Labor Secretary Marty Walsh met with 39 national union labor leaders. The President and Secretary Walsh met with labor leaders to discuss issues impacting union members and how the administration can help support working Americans.&#160; The President thanked the labor presidents for their support and outlined the steps the administration has taken to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today,&nbsp;President Biden&nbsp;and Labor Secretary Marty Walsh met with 39 national union labor leaders. The President and Secretary Walsh met with labor leaders to discuss issues impacting union members and how the administration can help support working Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President thanked the labor presidents for their support and outlined the steps the administration has taken to help union members in the first year of the administration. Secretary Walsh spoke of the need to work collaboratively to empower American workers and underscored the President’s support for strong unions as key to the middle class.&nbsp;The group further discussed the unprecedented economic growth and jobs numbers which announced 678,000 jobs added in February and a 3.8% drop in the unemployment rate, a total of 7.4 millions jobs added since the start of the administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The group discussed the wide range of accomplishments of the administration thus far creating union jobs and protecting Davis-Bacon provisions, including the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and the American Rescue Plan. The group echoed their thanks to the President, the Secretary and the Administration officials for the historic investment the administration has made in American workers.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
