<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 10:36:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Prioritizes Effectiveness, Accountability, and Transparency in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law&#160;Implementation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/29/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-prioritizes-effectiveness-accountability-and-transparency-in-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-implementation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) released initial guidance to federal agencies to set a strong foundation for effective, efficient, and equitable implementation of President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law—a historic investment in rebuilding roads and bridges, providing clean drinking water, and ensuring access to affordable internet. As the President said in the State&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) released initial <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/M-22-12.pdf">guidance </a>to federal agencies to set a strong foundation for effective, efficient, and equitable implementation of President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law—a historic investment in rebuilding roads and bridges, providing clean drinking water, and ensuring access to affordable internet. As the President said in the State of the Union, “in my administration, the watchdogs are back.” President Biden has a long-standing commitment to collaboration with Inspectors General (IGs) and the broader oversight community, dating back to his leadership as Vice President when he was tasked with implementation of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act. He has made clear that results and accountability go hand-in-hand, and that to deliver results for all Americans, the federal government must act—and support appropriate oversight of its activities—in a manner deserving of public trust. <br><br>The initial guidance will ensure that there is minimal fraud, waste, and abuse in the implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and projects are delivered on time and on budget by delivering results with accountability, effectiveness, and transparency, collaborating with inspectors general and the oversight community, and, providing technical and financial assistance for communities. The guidance was informed by the Infrastructure Implementation Task Force and stakeholders, reflects discussion with the oversight community, and reflects President Biden’s long-standing commitment to robust oversight and effective stewardship of taxpayer dollars.<br><br>This afternoon, President Biden and senior administration officials—including OMB Director Shalanda Young, Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator Mitch Landrieu, American Rescue Plan Implementation Coordinator Gene Sperling, and OMB Deputy Director for Management Jason Miller—will meet with agency Inspectors General (IGs) who have been providing oversight to the implementation of the American Rescue Plan and who will provide oversight of implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The meeting will also include the leadership of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE) and the Pandemic Response Accountability Committee (PRAC).  The President, his senior advisors, and IGs will discuss steps they are taking to ensure robust oversight of federal programs.<br><br>Upon signing the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, President Biden signed an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/15/fact-sheet-president-bidens-executive-order-establishing-priorities-and-task-force-for-implementation-of-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-law/">Executive Order </a>establishing the Task Force to coordinate effective implementation. Co-chaired by Senior Advisor and Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator Mitch Landrieu and National Economic Director Brian Deese, Task Force members include the heads of federal departments, agencies, and offices with infrastructure implementation responsibilities. The Task Force—which has held 11 Cabinet-level meetings—has focused on cross-agency coordination, ensuring public trust and accountability, and tackling important interagency issues like developing technical assistance and capacity-building resources for state, local, Tribal and territorial governments that will spend as much as 90 percent of the law’s funding. To date, each primary agency has identified an infrastructure implementation coordinator. The White House Infrastructure Implementation Team and agency coordinators have convened at least weekly since the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law was signed.<br><br><strong>DELIVERING RESULTS WITH ACCOUNTABILITY, EFFECTIVENESS, AND TRANSPARENCY</strong><br><br>One of the primary goals for implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law established by the President’s Executive Order was to “invest public dollars efficiently, avoid waste, and focus on measurable outcomes for the American people.” The initial implementation guidance issued by OMB today directs agencies to ensure accountable stewardship of Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding, building on effective practices from the Administration’s implementation of the American Rescue Plan, as well as existing financial management and reporting requirements set forth in statute and prior OMB guidance. Additional guidance may be issued by OMB on topics that require further direction, including on the implementation priorities set forth by the President in his Executive Order. The guidance includes direction on:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Using data and evidence. </strong>In designing and implementing Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Programs, agencies are charged to make evidence-based decisions, transparently describe the criteria for investment decisions, set and track measurable goals, performance indicators, and milestones, use data to measure and evaluate progress, and foster a culture of continuous improvement.</li><li><strong>Planning for program implementation.</strong> To ensure Bipartisan Infrastructure Law-funded programs are implemented efficiently and effectively, agencies must plan for program implementation to be consistent with statutory requirements and address the requirements, recommendations, and priorities in the President’s Executive Order and the new OMB guidance. This implementation planning must also include program-level financial management controls and risk mitigation strategies.</li><li><strong>Documenting selection criteria and review processes. </strong>Agencies must also document their review and selection process for discretionary programs, which must be consistent with the criteria, review, and selection information provided in Notices of Funding Opportunity (NOFOs), so that projects meet program goals.</li><li><strong>Reporting on awards and subawards. </strong>Agencies are already reporting monthly, including information about obligations and outlays, to USAspending.gov for all funding through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. Agencies are directed to ensure the quality and accuracy of award descriptions and recipient data on USAspending.gov to help inform the public of the purpose of the federal awards and where the funding ultimately goes.</li><li><strong>Going farther in post-award reporting. </strong>For grant and cooperative agreement programs funded through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, post-award reporting that demonstrates progress toward achieving outcomes will help maintain accountability to taxpayers and advance equity. The Administration is prioritizing post-award reporting of data with the following goals in mind: designing programs with clear goals and objectives; executing programs efficiently and effectively; promoting transparency and building trust with the public; delivering exemplary customer experience for recipients; and building capacity for evidence building. Agencies will take program-specific approaches to collecting and reporting post-award information about project location and phase of project implementation, going farther than past reporting requirements. Public-facing performance dashboards will be developed and shared online.</li></ul>



<p><strong>COLLABORATING WITH INSPECTORS GENERAL AND THE OVERSIGHT COMMUNITY</strong><br><br>At the President’s direction and through the leadership of the American Rescue Plan Implementation Coordinator Gene Sperling, the Administration has been collaborating across agencies and with the PRAC on the implementation and stewardship of programs funded through the American Rescue Plan. To institutionalize the President’s approach and the lessons learned in ARP implementation, OMB issued <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/M-22-04-IG-Cooperation.pdf">guidance</a> last December directing agency leaders to support the important role of agency IGs, including by communicating with their staffs the President’s expectation of cooperation with IG offices. &nbsp;<br><br>In the first five months of implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, the Task Force has regularly met with CIGIE and the Government Accountability Office (GAO), and leaders of agencies with infrastructure implementation responsibilities are meeting with their agency IGs, consistent with OMB’s Government-wide guidance on agency-IG cooperation.<br><br>The new OMB guidance directs agencies to continue this collaboration through implementation of programs funded through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The guidance includes direction on:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Engaging with IGs at the front end of program design. </strong>Agencies are directed to proactively engage with oversight entities, including agency IGs and the GAO, delivering on President Biden’s expectation that agencies ensure that programs balance efficient results, equitable access, and program integrity, including minimal waste, fraud, and abuse.</li><li><strong>Holding joint program review meetings with IGs. </strong>For new and expanded Bipartisan Infrastructure Law programs where significant program design is being implemented, agencies must engage with OMB and the agency’s IG for a dedicated joint review meeting to proactively discuss program design, risk mitigation strategies, financial controls, and data, tracking, and reporting. The “Gold Standard Meeting” process was developed by the White House American Rescue Plan Implementation Team and OMB, and these meetings have promoted proactive and transparent collaboration for new and expanded programs with tangible improvements.</li><li><strong>Identifying and mitigating risks. </strong>Agencies are directed to use enterprise risk management practices and cooperation with their IGs to identify and mitigate risks during program design, including putting in place financial management controls to address payment integrity risks. The OMB guidance charges agency leadership to inform their IG when the agency is deciding to take on added risk, especially in new or changed programs, to expand access to the program, or when leveraging new technology or systems.</li></ul>



<p><strong>PROVIDING TECHNICAL AND FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE FOR COMMUNITIES</strong><br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration is working to ensure that the benefits of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law reach all communities, including rural communities and communities that are marginalized, underserved, overburdened, or capacity constrained. These communities often lack adequate resources to navigate complex federal award-making processes. Building on ongoing Administration efforts, the new OMB guidance directs agencies to reduce barriers, including administrative burden, and increase access for communities, funding recipients, and funding beneficiaries. The guidance includes direction on:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Collaborating with state, local, Tribal, and territorial governments. </strong>The guidance charges agencies to collaborate with state, local, Tribal, and territorial governments to support communities in accessing infrastructure funding. This includes designating teams to provide central coordination among agencies and territorial governments, as well as teams to coordinate across agencies on rural issues and technical assistance for economically distressed, rural communities. In addition, agencies will ensure their Tribal relations or Tribal affairs offices have designated liaisons to coordinate with, so that the Administration expands technical assistance and support for Tribal governments.</li><li><strong>Providing technical assistance to underserved and capacity-constrained communities. </strong>Agencies are directed to use to the fullest extent possible existing and new technical assistance resources to support underserved and capacity-constrained communities, including rural communities, in accessing federal resources. This includes providing direct federal technical assistance in accessing grants and other types of financial assistance, as well as support for data infrastructure and tools for evidence building and use among funding recipients.</li><li><strong>Engaging with affected communities. </strong>Agencies are directed to, when feasible, engage affected communities so their perspectives and expertise inform policy development, program design, and delivery processes.  Agencies will focus particularly on underserved and capacity-constrained communities and stakeholders who may not have previously been able to apply for federal funding, including rural and urban communities and Tribal and territorial governments. </li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Minister for Foreign Affairs and for Defense Simon Coveney of&#160;Ireland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-minister-for-foreign-affairs-and-for-defense-simon-coveney-of-ireland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Simon Coveney, Minister for Foreign Affairs and Minister for Defense of Ireland.  They discussed their continued commitment to support Ukraine in the face of ongoing atrocities by Russia, as well as their ongoing coordination with international partners to impose severe costs on Moscow. They reviewed their efforts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Simon Coveney, Minister for Foreign Affairs and Minister for Defense of Ireland.  They discussed their continued commitment to support Ukraine in the face of ongoing atrocities by Russia, as well as their ongoing coordination with international partners to impose severe costs on Moscow. They reviewed their efforts to provide security, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine; to support refugees and displaced persons; and to address the impacts of the war on global food security.  They also talked about their countries’ close cooperation on shared global challenges, including in the United Nations Security Council. They underscored their enduring commitment to the Good Friday Agreement and the importance of preserving political and economic stability in Northern Ireland.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 28,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/28/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-28-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52038</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:16 P.M. EDT        MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Okay, two items for all of you at the top.&#160; Today, we released a report highlighting the historic small-business boom under the Biden-Harris administration.&#160; Last year, Americans applied to start 5.4 million new businesses &#8212; 20 percent more than any year&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:16 P.M. EDT       </p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, two items for all of you at the top.&nbsp; Today, we released a report highlighting the historic small-business boom under the Biden-Harris administration.&nbsp; Last year, Americans applied to start 5.4 million new businesses &#8212; 20 percent more than any year on record. &nbsp;And small businesses are creating more jobs than ever before.</p>



<p>And it’s been particularly strong for entrepreneurs of color.&nbsp; For example, Hispanic entrepreneurs started new businesses in 2021 at the fastest rate in more than a decade &#8212; 23 percent faster than pre-pandemic levels.</p>



<p>You heard the President say this today, but this approach is in stark contrast to congressional Republicans&#8217; tax plan, which would raise taxes by an average of almost $1,200 on nearly half of small-business owners.</p>



<p>Not only does President Biden reject congressional Republicans’ plans to increase taxes on half of small-business owners, he also has an economic strategy to keep the small-business boom going, including expanding access to capital, making historic investments in technical assistance programs to help entrepreneurs identify resources, leveraging federal procurement to direct hundreds of billions in government contracts to small businesses, and leveling the playing field for small-business owners to reforming the tax code.</p>



<p>I also wanted to note that today the Food and Drug Administration announced two proposed rules: one to prohibit menthol cigarettes and one to prohibit flavor- &#8212; flavored cigars.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The rules announced today would enforce regulations related to what stores sell and what companies manufacture and distribute, which is a critical &#8212; critical action to prevent children from becoming the next generation of smokers, help adult smokers quit, and significantly reduce tobacco-related health disparities.</p>



<p>With that, why don&#8217;t you kick us off.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, I have two questions about student loan forgiveness.&nbsp; First off, has the President concluded that he has the power to do this unilaterally?</p>



<p>And secondly, does he believe that means testing is the correct approach to student loan forgiveness?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s been no conclusion of any process internally yet.&nbsp; But you heard the President talk this morning about his ongoing consideration of how to provide additional relief to many Americans who are still &#8212; still have student loans, even though they have not paid a penny on federal student loans since he took office.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what was the second part of your question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he decided if he wants to do means testing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, he has talked in the past about how, you know, he doesn&#8217;t believe that &#8212; that millionaires and billionaires, obviously, should benefit or even people from the highest income.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s certainly something he would be looking at.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I just want to be very clear about the power to do this.&nbsp; He&#8217;s looking at doing this issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you&#8217;re not saying if he&#8217;s going to send a bill to Congress or he&#8217;s actually going to do it himself.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we definitely know he has the ability and the &#8212; the legal ability to sign a bill Congress passes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So what we&#8217;re really talking about is authorities through executive action, which we&#8217;re continuing to look at and he&#8217;s continuing to consider.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, what concerns does he have about the growing cost of college?&nbsp; You know, obviously, the cost of college has been rising very quickly.&nbsp; This would reduce borrowers’ out-of-pocket costs so they don’t have to pay down some of their debt.&nbsp; But what about that cost of the education up front?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it &#8212; from the beginning of his administration &#8212; and, I would say, through the course of his career &#8212; he has expressed an interest on the increasing cost of college and the barriers that that poses to people getting a two-year or four-year education.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He has taken a number of steps already since he took office to bring down costs for Americans, including bringing down the cost of college.</p>



<p>The American Rescue Plan provided nearly $40 billion in higher-education relief for colleges and universities, much of which was earmarked for emergency financial aid to help students to make college more affordable for college and &#8212; for current and future students.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He also called for and Congress passed a $400 increase in the maximum Pell Grant &#8212; the largest increase in over a decade.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And additionally, we have now approved the cancellation of more than $18.5 billion in student loan debt for more than 750,000 borrowers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So while he&#8217;s continuing to consider what executive actions he could take using his own authority &#8212; even though if Congress sent him a bill tomorrow, he could sign it and he would sign it to give $10,000 of student debt relief &#8212; we&#8217;ve also &#8212; he has not hesitated and has also taken additional steps.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the final question: a response to Republicans like Senator Romney who say this is a political giveaway to consider canceling student &#8212; student loan debt.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, you know, the President&#8217;s view is that, as the leader of the country, what he needs to do is continue to provide relief to people who need it most to help people get some extra breathing room.&nbsp; And that includes getting people con- &#8212; this consideration of getting people relief who have taken steps to further their education and maybe take steps to advance their &#8212; their family circumstances.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Switching gears to Title 42: The President said today that the administration would comply with whatever the courts decide.&nbsp; So, just to be clear, there&#8217;s not a plan to fight this decision?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That would be a decision made by the Department of Justice, but they haven&#8217;t even done a formal ruling that they&#8217;re considering at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But there&#8217;s the temporary restri- &#8212; the TRO.&nbsp; So, at this point, the administration is &#8212; doesn&#8217;t have anything to announce, in terms of fighting this?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They verbally did the TRO.&nbsp; They have not done, I don&#8217;t believe, a more formal, written one that has been looked at or considered by the Department of Justice at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q &nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President disagree with this ruling?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, it&#8217;s the Department of Justice to look at this.&nbsp; The President has talked about how he would &#8212; the authority is given to the CDC to make a decision about when the conditions exist to lift Title 42.&nbsp; They made that decision, and he certainly supports that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re preparing to lift it, through the Department of Homeland Security and an interagency process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if the CDC determined, like you just said, the order was no longer necessary, then it wouldn&#8217;t make sense to fight &#8212; to not fight this, to let that just stand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the Department of Justice would make that decision.&nbsp; There hasn&#8217;t even been a formal issuing by the court.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a verbal report.&nbsp; They said they would need to look at that.&nbsp; They would make any announcement about any legal action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I just want to ask you: We just continue to hear these Democratic senators that were briefed this week.&nbsp; Cortez Masto was the latest.&nbsp; She was briefed by the administration and said that even though you&#8217;ve been saying there&#8217;s this comprehensive plan to deal with the border after Title 42 is lifted, she has not seen a comprehensive plan.&nbsp; She said she did not hear a comprehensive plan on how they are going to address the surge or the resources needed to make sure we are addressing the drug trafficking across the border.</p>



<p>So your response to her and just, big picture, why Democrats aren&#8217;t united on this?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak for all Democrats. &nbsp;I can tell you that we share the frustration about how broken our immigration system is and how there need to be fixes at the border, whether that is smarter security funding or fixing the asylum processing system that&#8217;s long been broken.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we would welcome the interest of any Democrat or Republican to work with us on that effort and talk about and work for it &#8212; work on moving forward the bill the President proposed on his first day in office.</p>



<p>Secretary Mayorkas &#8212; who oversees this, of course &#8212; has been testifying.&nbsp; I think he has four &#8212; he&#8217;s testifying to four committees, including the House Judiciary Committee today.&nbsp; And he laid out six pillars of our plan, including components that address exactly those specific pieces: how we would surge resources, personnel, transportation, medical support; how we&#8217;re enhancing CBP processing; how we&#8217;re administrating &#8212; administering consequences for unlawful entry; how we&#8217;re bolstering the capacity of nongovernmental organizations; what we&#8217;re doing to target and disrupt the transnational criminal organizations; and how we&#8217;re going to deter irregular migration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this is not an immigration policy.  This is how we&#8217;re implementing the lifting of Title 42.  So we need a longer-term, more comprehensive immigration reform policy.  And we’d welcome any efforts to work with that with members of Congress. <br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  The request for $33 billion &#8212; how quickly do you expect it will move through Congress?  And when is the deadline for when you absolutely need it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m not here to set new deadlines.  But I can tell you that both needs are urgent.  Well, the &#8212; I would say that need is urgent, as is the need for COVID funding is urgent.<br>    <br>In terms of where we are with &#8212; with spending, just to give you a sense of &#8212; of the money that we&#8217;ve already &#8212; we&#8217;ve already allocated or already been giving &#8212; putting on the ground to the Ukrainians in the form of military assistance &#8212; I stumbled through that a little bit &#8212; as you know, we had $3.5 billion in military security assistance.  We have about $250 million of that left in drawdown.  So, obviously, we will work to expedite that and provide that to the Ukrainians. <br><br>But in order to continue to help assist them, help make sure they have the &#8212; the weapons they need, the artillery they need, the equipment they need, it is certainly urgent to move forward on this funding.</p>



<p>Q    And what is your view on why the economy shrunk 1.4 percent during the first quarter?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  So, GDP, which is what that&#8217;s a measure of, measures a couple of different components of economic data: consumption, investment, inventory, and exports.<br><br>On a number of these &#8212; these data components &#8212; we had very positive signs in this same set of data, including consumption; consumer spending was up by about 2.5 percent.  On investment, business investment, residential investment &#8212; both up as well. <br><br>And on exports, the number was down, but that is largely because our economy is doing better than many economies around the world.  So, while we were purchasing a lot of goods from other countries, there wasn&#8217;t the same capacity to purchase our goods.  That is &#8212; that is why that number was &#8212; was lower.<br><br>And then on inventory, which is another piece of data that is measured, quarter four of last year had the largest inventory number of any quarter in history, in large part because, as the supply chain problems were being fixed &#8212; thanks in large part to the President&#8217;s efforts &#8212; businesses were able to get goods, and they made enormous purchases &#8212; largest numbers to stock their inventory of any quarter in history.  And this &#8212; what this data is measuring is changes in growth from quarter to quarter. <br><br>So, because of that, even though this was the fifth-largest inventory quarter in history, in comparison with the fourth quarter of last year, it showed a decrease, which led to the &#8212; to the number.<br><br>But what &#8212; what economists &#8212; many economists &#8212; Jason Furman has spoken to this, and others &#8212; what they look at as measures of the strength of the economy and what they&#8217;re monitoring closely from quarter to quarter as important indicators are consumer spending, business investment, residential investment.  All of these increased at strong rates in the first quarter and as did the overall demand, and are good signs for the strength of the economy. <br><br>Q    And lastly, to what extent are you looking at cutting tariffs on Chinese goods as a way to ease inflation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Well, there&#8217;s an ongoing review of that led by Ambassador Tai at USTR.  And we are certainly continuing to look at where these tariffs &#8212; put in place by the prior administration &#8212; don&#8217;t make sense.  And one of the factors that we&#8217;re looking at as a part of this review is certainly the impact on jobs and wages and, of course, on inflation.  But we&#8217;re also looking at &#8212; and costs, of course, of goods. <br><br>But we&#8217;re also looking at where we have concerns about the economic policies and approaches of China.  But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point in terms of how that review is going. <br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q    Just one point of clarification: Does the President want this funding for Ukraine tied to the COVID-19 funding?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  We&#8217;re not making a predetermination of that from here.  We put forward both of these funding requests today because they&#8217;re both vital, they&#8217;re both important.  We need them both to help the Ukrainians and to help ensure we&#8217;re continuing our COVID programs here in this country and around the world.  But we&#8217;re not going to predetermine for Congress how they move forward.  There is just an urgency in moving them forward.<br><br>Q    Okay.  It was just confusing, because in his letter to Congress, he seemed to say he did want it tied to the COVID-19 funding, but he told reporters he didn&#8217;t care if it was tied to the COVID-19 funding.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  That was not the intention of how it was written.  It was intended just to convey we&#8217;re moving &#8212; we&#8217;re putting these both forward today.</p>



<p>Q    Okay.  So you’re not &#8212; so the White House is not saying that it should be tied to the COVID-19 funding?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  No.  We&#8217;re saying: These are both urgent.  We would like to move these forward.  We&#8217;ll work with you to determine how to get that done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And you said you don&#8217;t want to put a deadline on when Congress needs to pass and authorize this $33 billion request that the President has made.&nbsp; But how many more weeks can Ukraine go, based on what they have so far and based on the drawdown authority that the President still has, before you do start to see interruptions in military aid and economic assistance and humanitarian aid?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say, because we have $250 million left &#8212;<br><br>Q    That’s not very much, though, compared to what you’re asking for.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I know, I’m &#8212; I’m getting &#8212; I’m getting to your point.  I&#8217;m getting to the point here.<br><br>You know, there&#8217;s obviously more that&#8217;s needed.  And we want to be able to continue to provide a range of security and military assistance to the Ukrainians.<br><br>Now, we strategically frontloaded the military and security assistance we were providing a couple of weeks ago, expedited the delivery of it, because we knew that as Russia was repositioning in the east, and really re- &#8212; re- &#8212; changing their strategic approach to focus on the Donbas, they would need that on the front end. <br><br>So, it doesn&#8217;t mean that it will be exactly the same pace and every week, but certainly there is an urgency to getting this funding done.  There has been bipartisan &#8212; through.<br><br>There has been bipartisan support in the past, and we&#8217;re certainly looking forward to working with them to get this done as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>Q    And it would seem to suggest that there is a timeline, since officials told reporters today, briefing it, that they believe this is enough for Ukraine for the next five months to last through the end of the fiscal year &#8212; which, of course, that would start in a few days if you’re judging on a five-months timeline.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, that&#8217;s a different &#8212; that&#8217;s a different question than a timeline for getting the package done.  I mean, we did this on a fiscal year basis because that seemed to make sense, of course, and also because we wanted to do it over the long term for planning purposes.  But it doesn&#8217;t mean that the funding would be delivered tomorrow, obviously.  We have to get it through and move it through Congress.  And we want to do that as quickly as possible. <br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  A quick follow on student loans.  Today, the President said that he is not considering the $50,000 figure that some Democrats have pushed for.  Is there a range you can provide for what he is considering?  Is it more than the $10,000 both of you have mentioned before?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  He has said that before.  So, today was not the first time he has said that about $50,000 in the past.  I guess it&#8217;s been a few months.  I don&#8217;t have a top range for you.  I think he was just reacting to that size of the number. <br><br>He said in the past, and I&#8217;ve reiterated, that he would be happy to sign a piece of legislation or a bill that came to his desk that canceled $10,000 in student loans.  Could be more than that.  We&#8217;re looking at that.  But I think $50,000 was just his indication of that size and his opposition to that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Got it.&nbsp; And then today, when he was talking about the supplemental budget, he said that NATO Allies and EU partners are going to pay their “fair share of the cost as well.”&nbsp; How does he define “fair share”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  I think he was trying to send the message, which has already been underway, that we are going to continue to give a range of &#8212; and a significant range &#8212; amount of military and security assistance.  But other countries &#8212; we expect them to continue to step up as well, as this is going to be a sustained effort, a longer war, as we&#8217;ve talked about before.  We&#8217;re going to need other countries to continue to provide a range of assistance as well. <br>    <br>And we are far and away &#8212; the United States is &#8212; the largest provider of military, humanitarian, and economic assistance.  And other countries have taken steps.  I mean, Germany just announced this week &#8212; right? &#8212; their &#8212; their plan or their intention, and they may have been delivered, to provide tanks &#8212; something they have never done before. <br><br>A number of other countries have announced steps to provide a range of military assistance and weapons that they have never provided before. <br><br>But it was more the President sending a message about the need for every country to remain committed to this sustained and long-term effort to support the Ukrainians.<br><br>Q    But &#8212; but he&#8217;s not saying that they should be paying as much as the U.S. in terms of a monetary figure?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Every country is going to be able to provide different amounts and different types of assistance.  So it&#8217;s not prejudging that.  It&#8217;s just an ask and a reminder and a call to the world that we need to be in this for the long term, and we all need to continue to provide a range of assistance.</p>



<p>Q    And then one more on Paul Whelan.  Yesterday, I asked you about what his brother said.  Today, he himself issued a statement, and he is asking, “Why was I left behind?”  He mentioned he&#8217;s pleased Trevor is home with his family, but he is asking, “Why hasn&#8217;t more been done to secure my release?”  What is the administration&#8217;s response to Paul Whelan?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I would say that we will continue to do everything possible to bring Paul Whelan home.  We are in regular touch with his family and his family members.  And we don&#8217;t outline in detail everything we are doing publicly because our objective is to return him home with his family. <br><br>The President is focused on that.  And we would say to him, we &#8212; “We are going to continue to do everything possible to bring you home.”</p>



<p>Q    Can you say whether there has been any progress made in the past two, three months on their cases &#8212; on Whelan and Brittney Griner?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  It wouldn&#8217;t be constructive to outline or detail any specifics from here because our objective is to be successful, and talking about these cases publicly and getting into specifics often isn&#8217;t constructive toward that goal.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q    Jen, thank you.  I wanted to start by asking you a few questions about Ukraine.  The U.N. Secretary-General met with President Putin.  He&#8217;s meeting with President Zelenskyy.  He&#8217;s trying to strike a deal to get those who are in the steel plant out.  Ukrainian officials were very skeptical of these talks heading into this week.  Does the administration feel as though there&#8217;s been any progress that has come out of his talks with Putin and Zelenskyy?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I would say that it&#8217;s not for us to make a judgment from here.&nbsp; We are here to support the efforts of the Ukrainians and the Ukrainian leaders to pursue diplomatic talks and diplomatic engagements should they see that as constructive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have not seen evidence that President Putin or the Russians have taken steps &#8212; whether it is allowing for humanitarian convoys to move forward, humanitarian assistance, creating corridors &#8212; that would give an indication of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But our objective is: continue to implement the strategy that we laid out from early in this conflict, which is to provide the type of security and military assistance to help the Ukrainians fight and win on the battlefield &#8212; they obviously did that in Kyiv in pushing back the Russians &#8212; to give them economic and humanitarian assistance to strengthen their hand in diplomatic talks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Against the backdrop of the President&#8217;s announcement today and request for this $33 billion aid package, can you say: Is it the policy goal of the United States for Ukraine to defeat Russia?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, look, it depends on how you &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to define that from here.&nbsp; That&#8217;s for the Ukra- &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How would you define it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s for the Ukrainians to define.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we are going to do from here is to continue to provide them with a range of security and military assistance, as is evidenced by the package that the President proposed and put forward to Capitol Hill today; to strengthen their ne- &#8212; their hand at the negotiating table; and ensure that they have the support and backing of the United States and the world.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to be clear &#8212; and I understand what you&#8217;re saying: It&#8217;s for the Ukrainians to define.&nbsp; But does the United States think that success has to include Russians leaving all of the new portions of Ukraine that they currently invaded?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, we&#8217;re not going to define that from here, Kristen.&nbsp; There are a range of negotiations that may happen and may take place, and we&#8217;re just not going to get ahead of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me ask you about Build Back Better, if I might, or the remains of Build Back Better.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given that you are pushing for this new aid, given that you are pushing for pandemic aid as well, where does that fall right now on the agenda?&nbsp; Is there urgency to get those priorities passed as well?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; I mean, here&#8217;s the thing about Congress and governing: You &#8212; you can and you are able to do more than one thing at one time.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Just even look at the committees of jurisdiction in Congress.&nbsp; The committees that are considering and looking at, you know, some of the military assistance and security packages may not be the same that are considering and writing pieces of legislation on a reconciliation package.</p>



<p>There is a great deal of interest and passion on Capitol Hill among Democrats in moving forward on the President&#8217;s agenda and the President&#8217;s proposal to lower the cost of prescription drugs; to lower the cost of childcare, of healthcare, of eldercare.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue advocating and fighting for that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In order for it to get done against the backdrop of this election year, do you need to have a deal in place by Memorial Day &#8212; that has obviously been floated as the deadline?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not here to set new deadlines, Kristen.&nbsp; We know there is interest, there&#8217;s passion, there&#8217;s advocacy.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to do a lot of work behind the scenes, and we&#8217;re going to continue to fight to get it done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you don&#8217;t want to talk about deadlines, but if you could give us a reality check.&nbsp; The President said today he&#8217;s going to announce something on student loans in just a few weeks.&nbsp; You had said that there could potentially be an announcement by August &#8212; the end of the summer.&nbsp; Realistically, can we expect to hear something from the President in the next few weeks on this?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Stay tuned and we&#8217;ll see.&nbsp; Obviously, we have to continue a policy process.&nbsp; The President will make a decision.&nbsp; And once we have a decision to make, we’ll &#8212; we’ll, of course, announce that.</p>



<p>What I was getting at, really, is: The end of August is also the time that the student loan payment deferral &#8212; that&#8217;s the kind of period that it was extended through.&nbsp; So, it was more about making a decision before then.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We always like to beat timelines here.&nbsp; You know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On student loan debt &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the Committee for a Responsible Budget has spoken out against this, saying they&#8217;ve done a calculation that canceling $10,000 per borrower would cost $250 billion, $50,000 per borrower would cost $950 billion.&nbsp; What do you say to people, sort of, in their camp who are concerned that canceling student debt can have inflationary impact?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I haven&#8217;t looked at all those numbers and what incomes they would apply to, nor has there been a proposal that the President has put out on this front or anything that&#8217;s passed through Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what I would say, broadly speaking, is that when you look at the choices that need to be made, the President is looking at the impact of student loans &#8212; something that many people in this country, millions of Americans undertook to get a better education, to make sure they were advancing their own knowledge, to maybe help their family have a better life &#8212; that finding ways to provide relief to students, to make sure that these working-cla- &#8212; working families are getting relief is more important than tax cuts to millionaires, billionaires, and corporations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we can make choices about where we invest and where we think we can make the tax system more fair.&nbsp; But there isn&#8217;t even a bill that&#8217;s moved through Congress, nor have we put a proposal together.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t &#8212; those numbers aren&#8217;t based on any reality at this moment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But broadly speaking, is there any concern that, you know, given this narrative that it could have an inflationary impact that&#8217;s coming from critics of this administration who are looking at the economy, looking at inflation, and having problems with where it stands, is there a concern that, you know, canceling student debt could make it hard for the Joe Manchins of Congress to sign on to bills that would, you know, pass elements of Build Back Better that you guys are still trying to get through, which he said he won&#8217;t do because of inflation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to speak, obviously, for Senator Manchin.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t heard him make that point in the past either.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would say is that the way that inflation impacts people across the country is costs &#8212; right? &#8212; costs to their bank accounts, costs to their budgets.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re talking about here is how to provide people with relief, how they can &#8212; how we can provide them with relief or consider providing them with relief so that they have more money to spend on things in their lives.&nbsp; And providing student loan relief is exactly that.</p>



<p>And the President has taken a range of steps to address and lower costs for people.&nbsp; Considering this is one of them.&nbsp; Extending the pause on student loan payments is one of them.&nbsp; But also, fixing the glitch &#8212; the “family glitch” in the Affordable Care Act is another one of them.</p>



<p>So, when we talk about inflation, sometimes we talk about it like, you know, a 50,000-foot ivory tower economist might.&nbsp; And really, what in- &#8212; how inflation impacts people is costs and what they&#8217;re paying out of their pocket.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, actually, considering this would be helping Americans address exactly that issue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on this new report that the Department of Homeland Security is setting up a Disinformation Governance Board to tackle misinformation ahead of the midterms: Secretary Mayorkas said that part of its intention was to tackle misinformation in Hispanic communities especially.&nbsp; Can you give us an idea of what this board is going to be doing, what their authority would look like?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, Jacqui.&nbsp; I really haven&#8217;t dug into this exactly.&nbsp; I mean, we, of course, support this effort, but let me see if I can get more specifics.&nbsp; We know that there has been a range of disinfo out there about a range of topics &#8212; I mean, including COVID, for example, and also elections and eligibility.&nbsp; But I will &#8212; I will check and see if there&#8217;s more specifics.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s been some criticism of the person who&#8217;s been chosen to oversee this board.&nbsp; She had previously called the Hunter Biden laptop a “Trump campaign product,” seeming to discredit its validity &#8212; or validity of reporting surrounding that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How can you assuage concerns of people who are looking at this person who&#8217;s been appointed to this position and wondering if she&#8217;s going to be able to accurately judge misinformation now that a lot of that reporting has been proven to be factual in some ways?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t have any comments on the laptop.</p>



<p>But what I can tell you is that it sounds like the objective of the board is to prevent disinformation and misinformation from traveling around the country in a range of communities.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure who opposes that effort, and I don&#8217;t know who this individual is, so I have no comments on it specifically.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Her name is Nina Jankowicz.&nbsp; She also just recently made some polarizing comments about the Twitter &#8212; Elon Musk&#8217;s Twitter purchase.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just getting some pushback from critics who are saying this person may not be the right choice for a board that is run by the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; Can you speak to that at all?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any information about this individual.&nbsp; I can check on more information about the board.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How much of the original $13.6 billion for Ukraine has actually been spent at this point?&nbsp; Reporters are still trying to understand the answer to that.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I noted a little bit earlier, I think, in response &#8212; in proactive, preemptive response to this question, that, of the $3.5 billion on security, we&#8217;ve spent $3.25 billion of that already, which we have transparently provided regular info to all of you on.</p>



<p>In terms of the humanitarian and economic assistance, a lot of it has been allocated to how it would be spent.&nbsp; I can see if we have an update on what has actually gone to ground.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay. &nbsp;And secondly, on the &#8212; on the menthol ban, some Black community activists, the ACLU, members of the CDC have voiced concerns that it could push more of the illicit market, which would lead to racially profiling Black smokers.&nbsp; Can this administration ensure that won&#8217;t happen?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Because this rule would go after manufacturers and people who sell, not individuals who smoke menthol cigarettes.&nbsp; And it would save lives.</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note that the NAACP put out a statement saying: “For decades, the tobacco industry has been targeting African Americans and have contributed to the skyrocketing rates of heart disease, stroke, and cancer across our community.&nbsp; The tobacco industry is on a narrow quest for profit, and they have been killing us along the way.&nbsp; The NAACP has been calling for a ban on menthol cigarettes and flavored e-cigarettes for years now, and we applaud the FDA’s…plan…”</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;re talking about here is this &#8212; these rules are estimated that &#8212; it&#8217;s estimated that eliminating menthol and tobacco products could prevent up to 654,000 deaths over the next 40 years and up to 238,000 deaths among African Americans.</p>



<p>But this is not about going after individuals smoking menthol cigarettes; this is about manufacturers and people who are selling them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, why does President Biden believe pro-life taxpayers, Catholics among them &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On &#8212; on inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; should fund Title 10 clinics &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp; On inflation &#8212; hey!</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that advise women on how to get an abortion?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sir.&nbsp; We don’t &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re going down the row, and you’re giving these people five and six questions.&nbsp; I get one, don’t I?&nbsp; And the people back here too &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think if you could &#8212; if you could sit here and be respectful &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You give them five to six questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; of your colleagues here &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, again, my question is &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; that might work better.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; why does President Biden believe pro-life taxpayers &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sir.&nbsp; Sir.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Catholics among them &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think he’s the next question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Okay, so on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; should have to fund Title 10 clinics that advise women on how to get an abortion?&nbsp; Simple question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re being very disrespectful.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the AMLO meeting, your statement laid out a bunch of domestic issues that would be discussed, and regional issues &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; like economic cooperation, et cetera.&nbsp; I was wondering if the President was planning to raise AMLO’s attitude towards Russia and Ukraine.&nbsp; He’s been really loath to criticize Russia, and he hasn’t really joined this international effort.&nbsp; So, does the President plan to raise that tomorrow?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, it’s a good question.&nbsp; The primary focus of the meeting, as you outline, is about, kind of, getting ahead of the Summit of the Americas, talking about the agenda.&nbsp; Obviously, there’s a lot to be discussed as it relates to migration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this meeting was planned in advance of our long-term planning of the potential lifting of Title 42 as well.&nbsp; It is often on the President’s mind, as you know &#8212; Russia and Ukraine and the conflict.&nbsp; So, while it may not be on the preemptive agenda, we will have a more comprehensive readout once the meeting is concluded.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the GDP report, I&#8217;m just wondering if the contraction has the White House rethinking its support for the Fed’s plan to raise interest rates?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We continue to support the intention or stated intention of the independent Federal Reserve to recalibrate, and we support that effort.</p>



<p>I noted a lot of the different data measurements here because I think it&#8217;s important to note that the inventory piece was not unexpected.&nbsp; I mean, we actually spoke to it a couple of days ago as well, given the record inventory numbers from the fourth quarter of last year and the fact that it measures the comparison and the change of growth from quarter to quarter.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then lastly, this has happened while you came out here so you might not have heard about it, but Senator Manchin said at a hearing that he thinks the electric vehicle tax credit, quote, “makes no sense.”&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering what your reaction to that is and whether you think that further complicates a skinny reconciliation bill getting</p>



<p>through.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that Senator Manchin remains a friend of the President’s and someone we will continue to work with and look forward to continuing engagements with.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, again, my question: Why does President Biden believe pro-life taxpayers, Catholics among them &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, so, earlier you were asked about the economic &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; should fund Title 10 clinics that advise women on having an abortion?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you were asked about economic and humanitarian assistance aid amount.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m wondering: The military aid, it seems like the President said has, quote, “basically” run out.&nbsp; The military &#8212; I’m sorry, the humanitarian and economic aid, if it has not yet run out, could those funds be diverted first from the White House to additional security and military assistance?&nbsp; Is that something that you all can do?&nbsp; Is it something you are considering?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t believe.&nbsp; It’s a good question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe that&#8217;s under consideration in large part because the humanitarian and economic assistance is vital.&nbsp; Think about the number of the millions of refugees, the millions of people who have been &#8212; become homeless as a result of this &#8212; or no longer in their homes as a result of this war.&nbsp; And there are a range of economic needs that President Zelenskyy has spoken about himself about &#8212; that will be needed over the coming months.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s why there are multiple buckets, and that will continue to be the case.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of any consideration of reallocation of funds.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, the other question I was going to ask is: In terms of having the 250 military &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, $250 million in military assistance that remains, could you all essentially spend money on the front side in the coming weeks if Congress is unable to pass something, recoup it from the supplemental later?&nbsp; And if you do that, is there a limit how much money you can spend that way upfront?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Just so I understand &#8212; I may have to ask OMB this question &#8212; can we kind of get a line of credit of sorts?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Exactly.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; To &#8212; to kind of purchase or things along those lines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me check and see with our budgetary experts.&nbsp; No one knows more than how this works than Shalanda Young, so I will check with her and get back to you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the last question I was going to ask is: Is it the administration&#8217;s policy to continue to provide essentially an unlimited amount of money to Ukraine? &nbsp;I mean, is there a top-line budget?&nbsp; And is the thinking that the administration will continue to support Ukraine for as long as it needs, for how much money it needs?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we did this five-month request because we wanted to be able to do longer-term planning and work with the Ukrainians, our European partners.&nbsp; This is not all for Ukraine, it&#8217;s also for some of our Eastern European partners and others to help support them during this time as well.</p>



<p>But I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of where we will be in three months, four months, five months.&nbsp; Our objective is continue to support the Ukrainians.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of where we are at this point in time.</p>



<p>I can note &#8212; and I know this goes to Alex&#8217;s earlier question &#8212; I mean a little bit in terms of the other components, and I can see if there&#8217;s more of a specific of what&#8217;s been spent down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But when it comes to humanitarian, economic, food, and other security assistance, some of that funding is, you know, $1.7 billion to ensure continuity of Ukraine&#8217;s democratic operations and provide other macroeconomic assistance; hundreds of millions of dollars in food, shelter, and other humanitarian aid to Ukrainians.&nbsp; But we can also see if there&#8217;s more specifics on where we are with the spend-out of it.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, revisiting student loan debt and that issue.&nbsp; Why isn&#8217;t President Biden willing to go as high as $50,000?&nbsp; That&#8217;s the figure that Majority Leader Chuck Schumer has pointed to.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the figure that a lot of progressive Democrats have pointed to.&nbsp; So what about that number gives the President concern?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President himself has spoken to this in the past, so I&#8217;d really point you to his own words on this front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Remind me what he said then.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to get them to you after the briefing, but what I can tell you is that the President has said many times that he would be happy to sign a bill that would provide $10,000 in relief to individuals who have student loans, and Congress could send him that.&nbsp; That hasn&#8217;t happened yet.&nbsp; That could be the first focus of Congress, as an example.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s continuing to consider what he has the executive authority or authority to do with his own power.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m just not going to get ahead of that consideration process.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, again, it’s a simple question: Why does President Biden &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, you mentioned the $33 billion package and how urgent it is.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t yet really have a timeline on how urgent &#8212; you know, if it&#8217;s weeks or months. &nbsp;Can you detail at all sort of the White House strategy behind getting that money secured?&nbsp; The President, obviously, next week is going to Alabama to tour Lockheed Martin and the Javelins.&nbsp; It may be one opportunity &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, to see Javelins &#8212; Javelins being made.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That may be one opportunity to draw attention to this.&nbsp; Are there other things that the White House is doing strategically to get that urgency, you know, felt by members of Congress?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Look, I think you are going to see a full-court press from us on this funding, as well as the COVID funding, which is very &#8212; which is vital to the continuation of our fight against the pandemic.</p>



<p>And you will see that in the form of engagement with members on the Hill and committees; you will see that in the form of our Secretary of State, our Secretary of Defense, and other national security officials speaking publicly, testifying, as many of them are, and speaking to it during testimony.</p>



<p>And obviously, you noted, the President&#8217;s visit to the factory &#8212; the Lockheed Martin factory, I believe, in Alabama next week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Even the decision today for the President to make the announcement himself instead of doing just a background briefing and providing all of the details to all of you was an effort to talk through the vital need of this assistance, what it would go to, and elevate it to that level.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, is there any effort, I guess &#8212; you heard this a little bit from him today talking about how Ukrainians are giving up their lives, so the money &#8212; I guess, is there anything that the White House is doing to address the concern from some Americans that this is an awful lot of money going to a foreign country when we have domestic needs at home?</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t know if there&#8217;s anything proactively that you guys may do to try to make that case for why this amount of money is needed.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that we&#8217;ve also seen an incredibly heart- &#8212; heartfelt outpouring of support from the American people for the efforts of the United States to lead in standing up to Russian aggression and to stand up in favor and support of the Ukrainians.</p>



<p>You know, to the President, this is about American leadership in the world.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also about standing up for democracy versus autocracy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about standing up against one foreign country invading another foreign country.&nbsp; And, you know, it&#8217;s about American leadership in the world.</p>



<p>So, we will continue to articulate that and make that clear.&nbsp; And that is part of the reason why the President also detailed in specificity today what all of this would go to.&nbsp; I mean, some of it &#8212; a great deal of it is, of course, to military assistance to fight this war, but there is funding in there, as he noted this morning, for food security and ensuring that we are addressing any food shortages around the world.&nbsp; There is assistance that is going into humanitarian assistance and helping the outflow of refugees.&nbsp; And so, it was important to him personally to lay out the specifics in his remarks this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I follow up on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, again, a really simple question &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Looking ahead to the President’s &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s a simple process, sir.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) question.&nbsp; You give these people six questions in the front row.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Looking ahead to the President’s trip to Japan &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s disrespectful.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that was announced last night, I’m wondering if you can talk about &#8212; and the Quad summit.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m wondering if you can talk how the President will raise sort of a unified response to Russia &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; with India at the table and then also, sort of, the China-Taiwan issue.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, on the Japan &#8212; on the first part, on Russia, I would say, first, we&#8217;ve had a number of engagements, as you know, with leaders in India about our approach to supporting the Ukrainians in this &#8212; in this war, whether that is sanctions and the enormous sanctions package we&#8217;re putting in &#8212; we&#8217;ve put in place or, of course, the assistance we&#8217;ve provided.&nbsp; We will convey the same sentiments in this meeting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, this meeting is several weeks away, so a lot can certainly happen.&nbsp; And as you know, other members of the Quad have also been vital partners and vital, you know, supporters of the Ukrainians’ effort to fight the war, including Japan.&nbsp; I mean, Japan &#8212; just as an example &#8212; has not only provided a range of assistance, but they&#8217;ve also agreed to divert some of the LNG resources to help Europe.&nbsp; So there&#8217;s a number of steps they have also taken that will be a part of the discussion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly, the President will provide an update on what we&#8217;re doing and where things stand at that point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re just not quite there on previewing the agenda yet.&nbsp; Obviously, the President&#8217;s position on Taiwan has not changed.&nbsp; He will certainly restate it during this meeting, but I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll have more to preview as we get closer to the trip.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And China, Taiwan &#8212; how will that be raised as well?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, as we get closer to the trip &#8212; there&#8217;s not a change in our policy.&nbsp; Obviously, the President&#8217;s policy is based on the Taiwan Relations Act.&nbsp; That will continue.&nbsp; And as we get closer to the trip, I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll have more to preview.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; One question on Moldova and one on COVID.&nbsp; Do you have any update, any insight on the explosions in Transnistria earlier in the week?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if the Russians were to open a new front in Moldavian territory, would that trigger any new consequences for Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On the first part, I just don&#8217;t have new confirmation or new details to read out from here on &#8212; we&#8217;re still continuing to look at the explosions from earlier this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just not going to get ahead of a hypothetical at this point in time in terms of what consequences there would be.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yesterday, you were talking about how there&#8217;s great access to Paxlovid &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; in the country.&nbsp; You&#8217;re trying to get the word out on its effectiveness.&nbsp; One of the main issues with Paxlovid is that an individual who is eligible has to test positive, and then they have to race to get it within three days even though they&#8217;re quarantining.&nbsp; Is there any conversation within the administration to change that for an eligible individual to be able to get it preemptively?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think that would be a decision likely made by our health and medical experts, so I just don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It requires a prescription, right?&nbsp; But there are a range of ways to have those conversations with your doctor.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not sure it always involves a race to the doctor&#8217;s office.&nbsp; But different doctors can have virtual appointments and other means of getting prescriptions.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about consulting to ensure you&#8217;re eligible.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; So, I have a question on Ukraine, and then a follow-up on my colleague’s questions.&nbsp; Zelenskyy’s top advisor tweeted today that “Ukraine should decide whether to strike [Russian] military facilities.”&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve spoken to &#8212; on this before, but &#8212; you&#8217;re trying to avoid a hypothetical situation.&nbsp; But this seems like it&#8217;s getting closer towards a non-hypothetical situation.&nbsp; Can you &#8212; can you at least outline &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; outline &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I appreciated that.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; whether the administration believes that this is escalatory or could be constructive?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you know, one, I think it&#8217;s important to take a step back and remember what we&#8217;re talking about here.&nbsp; I mean, it is Russia that started this war, invaded Ukraine, and violated Ukraine&#8217;s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s Russian forces that have committed war crimes and horrifying atrocities.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s Russia that continues to attack Ukrainian targets in Ukraine every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So even if we are, dare I say, “getting into a hypothetical,” what we&#8217;re talking about here is not any intention of Ukraine invading Russia and trying to take Russian territory, going after Russian civilians, going after Russians’ hospitals.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about consideration of military targets.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something very different.&nbsp; So I just think that&#8217;s important context for everybody to consider.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Still on Ukraine: There&#8217;s no formal announcement as of right now about Jakarta inviting Zelenskyy to the G20.&nbsp; But our sources suggest that they are indeed inviting both Zelenskyy as well as Putin.&nbsp; So, under those circumstances, would the President consider attending?&nbsp; I know it&#8217;s still six months away.&nbsp; But under those circumstances, (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we certainly welcomed reports about Ukraine&#8217;s invitation.&nbsp; Obviously, we can&#8217;t confirm that on behalf of Indonesia, who is hosting.&nbsp; And the President has been clear about his view: This shouldn&#8217;t be business as usual, and that Russia should not be a part of this.</p>



<p>But, again, it&#8217;s six months away; we don&#8217;t even have confirmation of these reports.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m certainly not going to get into a hypothetical in this case.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to follow up on the issue of, you know, Americans being concerned about the amount of money being sent out to Ukraine: One of the things that the President outlined today in his speech was not just humanitarian assistance, but also allow pensions and social support to be paid to the Ukrainian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what would you say to the American public who says, “Okay, it&#8217;s one thing to help Ukrainian refugees with food and shelter, but why should we be paying for their pensions?”</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, look, I would say that we have provided a range of economic assistance, because we know that their economy has been devastated &#8212; not of their doing, because they were invaded by a foreign country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But how is that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And they&#8217;re going &#8212; let me &#8212; let me finish.&nbsp; And they are going to need assistance in order to recover.&nbsp; We provide assistance &#8212; economic and humanitarian assistance &#8212; to a range of countries around the world because that&#8217;s part of American leadership.&nbsp; And so, I would say that&#8217;s the reasoning for this assistance being proposed in the package.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on menthol &#8212; going back to the opposition in the Black community: I talked to Congresswoman Frederica Wilson today, and she said she&#8217;s opposing it.&nbsp; She says the President not &#8212; “should not only deal with menthol, but ban all” &#8212; instead of just menthol.&nbsp; She feels that it will cause a profiling issue.&nbsp; And she also says this is something that should not be dealt with in the midterms because it will split the Black community.&nbsp; What do you say to that?&nbsp; And are you talking to Frederica Wilson, Al Sharpton, Ben Crump, and others about this very issue?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me try to answer all your questions there.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ll let me know if I don&#8217;t, April, of course.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, this is a public health decision made by the FDA.&nbsp; And the objective of it was not to address politics or handle politics in one way or another, but to save lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the studies estimate that with menthol cigarettes &#8212; if they&#8217;re no longer available, it could prevent over 650,000 deaths, including 238,000 African Americans.&nbsp; There are also high rates of use by children and young adults.&nbsp; Menthol also increases the appeal of cigarettes, makes them easier to use, especially for kids.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we have seen, as you know, is decades of targeted marketing activities at the African American community to promote further purchasing and, in many ways &#8212; and, for many, addiction to these cigarettes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is not &#8212; but what I think is important for everybody to know and understand, including opponents, is: This is not targeting individuals.&nbsp; This is not to give anybody license to arrest somebody who is smoking a cigarette &#8212; a menthol cigarette.&nbsp; This is going after the manufacturers of this.&nbsp; It is going after those who are selling, because it is &#8212; it has &#8212; we have seen decades of marketing targeted activities at exactly these communities.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, with that said &#8212; as you say, “decades” &#8212; I mean, there has been efforts to stop the targeting through billboards in urban communities in the ‘90s, and on and on.&nbsp;&nbsp; This is decades old.&nbsp; But why now?&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s been progression, but why now instead of other issues?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, again, this is a public health decision that went through a public health process.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t made through a political prism or made, you know, for any other reason than the lives that it could save.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; At least seven sailors have died by suicide since the USS George Washington began undergoing (inaudible) overhaul.&nbsp; There have been three just within the last month.&nbsp; The Navy today confirmed three from prior years.&nbsp; Is the President aware of these suicides?&nbsp; Does he have any response to them?&nbsp; And is the military doing enough to make sure that it is promoting the mental wellbeing of our service members?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly the President is regularly briefed and is aware.&nbsp; And the service men and women and the stress and the pressure on them is something that is on his mind, including making sure we have the right mental healthcare, the right treatments for any individual who may be suffering from depression or anything that might lead to suicide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of an assessment of what the steps they are taking or what they&#8217;re doing, I&#8217;d really point you to the Department of Defense, who would be better versed to speak to the specifics.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And then to follow up on a question from yesterday about Ukraine and tariffs: The President could &#8212; today, if he wanted to &#8212; by executive action, undo these Trump-era tariffs on steel imports from Ukraine.&nbsp; Is there any reason why he wouldn&#8217;t do that?&nbsp; Does it have anything to do with pushback from unions?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s an ongoing consideration and process of reviewing a range of steps we can help &#8212; we can take to provide relief to the Ukrainians, a review of tariffs.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s a range of factors.&nbsp; And I just don’t have anything to preview in that process at this point.</p>



<p>Q    Okay.  But that is something that he is considering?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  There&#8217;s a range of options on the table.<br><br>Go ahead, in the back.<br><br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  I wanted to ask: The House is out next week, and usually that would be where an appropriations bill would start.  Given that the President is saying the COVID funding is so urgent, in addition to the Ukraine proposal, how do you see this playing out legislatively, in the quick that you need it to?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Well, this is something &#8212; now that we&#8217;ve put the proposal forward and put it forward and sent it up to the Hill, a lot of the work is happening behind the scenes, engagement with our legislative team &#8212; Steve Ricchetti, Louisa Terrell and this team &#8212; with leaders on the House side, the Senate side to move it forward as quickly as possible. <br><br>But in terms of the legislative mechanics, I&#8217;d really point you to leaders on the Hill for specifics on that.</p>



<p>Q    And one other question on COVID funding.  The Biden administration has been &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if “reticent” is the right word &#8212; to release spending that you&#8217;ve done on COVID tests, the rapid testing program, whether it&#8217;s how much you spent per test or overall.  Is that information that you&#8217;re planning to make public or planning to provide to the Senate and the House as they consider whether to provide more funding?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  The testing program in terms of people being able to order free tests?<br><br>Q    Yeah, the COVID tests (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  What specifically do you think we haven&#8217;t provided?<br><br>Q    The amounts that you spent per test or overall per contract &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m sure if members of Congress or committees are interested in information, we&#8217;ll have those discussions with them directly. <br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; My first question is about the security pact between China and the Solomon Islands.&nbsp; Do you have any concerns that China is taking advantage of what&#8217;s going on in the Pacific because the U.S. is so focused on Ukraine and Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know we have spoken to this a little bit in the past and expressed some concern at the time.&nbsp; I’ll have to talk to our national security team and see if we have any &#8212; any updates on recent developments.</p>



<p>Q    And I just have one more question about President Biden&#8217;s trip to Asia.  Could you confirm reports by some Asian media outlets that are saying that President Biden is going to announce some kind of China strategy during his trip to Korea and Japan?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Again, this trip is weeks away, which is a lifetime for us, so we&#8217;re not quite there yet on previewing specifics of the trip and what it will entail. <br><br>Why don’t we do the last one, and then I got to wrap it up.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; The Minnesota Department of Human Rights found that the city of Minneapolis and the MPD engaged in a pattern of practice of racial discrimination.&nbsp; They&#8217;re working on some consent decree, but we know that can take some time.&nbsp; Is there anything that the President can do moving forward?&nbsp; Can we say that the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act seems like it&#8217;s shelved for now?&nbsp; And has the President seen that report?&nbsp; What&#8217;s his reaction?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have any direct reaction from the President to that report.  I can certainly check with him on that.  We&#8217;re still consid- &#8212; continuing to consider a police reform executive order, as you know.  That&#8217;s &#8212; consideration is underway.  It continues to be underway.  And the President has every intention of signing one. <br><br>And, of course, we would, of cour- &#8212; still love to have bipartisan legislation passed through Congress.  We know the anniversary is coming up in just a few weeks.  And certainly, that&#8217;s something that remains on the President&#8217;s mind. <br><br>Thank you, everyone, so much.<br><br>4:07 P.M. EDT </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Meeting with Small-Business&#160;Owners</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/28/remarks-by-president-biden-before-meeting-with-small-business-owners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 21:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2:08 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; We’re joined today by five small-business owners who are helping power America’s economic recovery. And I want &#8212; I want to welcome the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, Isabella Guzmán.&#160; Nice to have you, kiddo.&#160; ADMINISTRATOR GUZMÁN:&#160; Thank you. THE PRESIDENT:&#160; And these enterprises and entrepreneurs&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>2:08 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; We’re joined today by five small-business owners who are helping power America’s economic recovery.</p>



<p>And I want &#8212; I want to welcome the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, Isabella Guzmán.&nbsp; Nice to have you, kiddo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ADMINISTRATOR GUZMÁN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And these enterprises and entrepreneurs know that an American economy is strong because America’s small businesses are strong.</p>



<p>Small businesses typically account for more than 40 percent &#8212; people don’t realize it &#8212; 40 percent of the gross domestic product of the United States.&nbsp; They create two thirds of all new jobs.&nbsp; And they employ nearly half &#8212; nearly half of all the private sector workers.</p>



<p>And today, thanks to the economic strategy, more &#8212; more small businesses are being created, and small businesses are creating more jobs faster than ever before.</p>



<p>Thanks in large part to the American Rescue Plan, last year, Americans applied to start 5.4 million &#8212; 5.4 million new businesses, 20 percent more than any other year on record.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We saw businesses with fewer than 50 workers create 1,900,000 jobs for the first three quarters of 2021 alone.&nbsp; That’s the highest rate of small-business creation ever &#8212; ever recorded in a single year.&nbsp; And we have some of the folks right here who did it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have every indication that this trend is going to continue.&nbsp; The reason for that is because we’re giving people financial security to take a risk and pursue their small-business dreams.</p>



<p>This boom has been particularly strong for entrepreneurs of color.</p>



<p>Hispanic entrepreneurs started new businesses in 2021 at a faster rate in more than a decade, 23 percent faster than the pre-pandemic levels.</p>



<p>And, you know, the five folks that join me today exemplify what a difference it makes when &#8212; when everyone gets a fair shot.</p>



<p>Jennifer was &#8212; was able to start growing her engraving business last year because of the Child Care Tax Credit and the small-business support of the Small Business Administration.</p>



<p>Jeff and Nicolas are master coffeemakers &#8212; roasters &#8212; who were able to open their first brick-and-mortar café last year.</p>



<p>And Eddie and Daniel were able to turn their food truck into a brick-and-mortar company of their own.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; That must feel pretty good, huh?</p>



<p>And they’re just some of the folks driving this economic recovery and reminding us that everything &#8212; that anything and everything is possible in America.</p>



<p>And my administration is working tirelessly to open doors for more outstanding entrepreneurs.&nbsp; You know, unfortunately, Republicans have a different approach.</p>



<p>The Republican plan, led by Senator Rick Scott of Florida, Chairman of the National Republican Senatorial Campaign Committee, would tax half of our small-business owners an extra $1,200 a year on average.</p>



<p>Not only do they oppose making big corporations pay their fair share, they want middle-class families and small-business owners to pay more.</p>



<p>Our administration estimates that the Republican proposal would raise taxes on 6.1 million small-business owners, including 82 percent of small-business owners who earn less than $50,000 a year.</p>



<p>That just doesn’t &#8212; that’s &#8212; that’s just not right.</p>



<p>Our administration wants to make it easier to start a business, easier for a small business to succeed.&nbsp; And our plan is to, one, expand access to capital for small businesses; make historic investments in technical assistance programs to help entrepreneurs thrive; and direct hundreds of billions of dollars in government contracts to small businesses in every community; and level the playing field &#8212; and I mean level the playing field for small business, making sure the largest corporations in America begin to pay their fair share.</p>



<p>And now I’m looking forward to discussing my plan and hearing from these remarkable entrepreneurs.&nbsp; Thank you for being here.</p>



<p>2:12 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Law Day, U.S.A.,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/28/a-proclamation-on-law-day-u-s-a-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 17:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America is unique among the nations of the world because we were not built around any particular tribe, religion, or ethnicity &#8212; instead, we were built around an idea: that all people are created equally and deserve to be treated equally throughout their lives. &#160;Though we have never fully lived up to that idea, we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America is unique among the nations of the world because we were not built around any particular tribe, religion, or ethnicity &#8212; instead, we were built around an idea: that all people are created equally and deserve to be treated equally throughout their lives. &nbsp;Though we have never fully lived up to that idea, we have never walked away from it either. &nbsp;It is an idea that serves as the heart of American democracy, enshrined in our Constitution 235 years ago on a summer day in Philadelphia. &nbsp;To uphold those fundamental principles of equality, &#8220;We the People&#8221; would stand sovereign in America as stewards and subjects of the law &#8212; and ours would be, in the words of John Adams, &#8220;a government of laws, and not of men.&#8221;<br><br>On Law Day, U.S.A., we recommit to extending the full promise of America to all Americans and to building a Nation in which the extraordinary power vested in &#8220;We the People&#8221; truly and equally reflects all of us. This year&#8217;s Law Day theme, &#8220;Toward a More Perfect Union: &nbsp;The Constitution in Times of Change,&#8221; is a reflection of this critical moment of reckoning for our democracy. &nbsp;The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on our communities has put a spotlight on lingering inequities that we&nbsp;must continue to address head on. &nbsp;Together, we must build a&nbsp;better America, anchored by the rule of law, to ensure that every one of us can live lives of limitless possibility.&nbsp; Amid unprecedented threats to democracy both here at home and across the globe, the world is watching America to see whether we can meet this moment.<br><br>The rule of law is the cornerstone for extending the Nation&#8217;s full promise to all of our people, including those who&nbsp;were originally excluded when our country was founded.&nbsp; Since&nbsp;my&nbsp;first day in office, I have taken action to ensure that everyone &#8212; regardless of race, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, ethnicity, religion, disability, income, or zip&nbsp;code &#8212; is ensured equal justice under the law and is entitled to an equal place in our democracy.&nbsp; My Administration continues to fight for voting rights legislation to protect that most sacred of rights from discriminatory and burdensome constraints, and continues to promote information about the election process and opportunities to register to vote. &nbsp;<br><br>The ongoing fight to strengthen American democracy informs our ability to support similar efforts around the world &#8212; including the heroic resistance of the Ukrainian people in the&nbsp;unprovoked and unjustified war Russia has thrust upon them.&nbsp; Their fight is part of a larger fight for essential democratic principles that unite all free people: &nbsp;the rule of law; free and fair elections; the freedom to speak, to write, and to assemble; the freedom to worship as one chooses; and the freedom of the press.&nbsp; These principles are essential in a free society, and we are leading efforts to advance good governance, transparency, and accountability and root out the corruption that undermines democratic institutions both at home and abroad.<br><br>This is a commitment we must all share.&nbsp; The Robert F. Kennedy Department of Justice Building bears an inscription from&nbsp;Plato: &nbsp;&#8220;Justice in the life and conduct of the State is possible only as first it resides in the hearts and souls of the&nbsp;citizens.&#8221;&nbsp; Our hearts and souls are up to the task.<br><br>On this Law Day, U.S.A., I encourage my fellow Americans to&nbsp;join me in pursuing the path of inclusion and equity over exclusion and hate, so that we may continue to perfect our Union&nbsp;and pass on a stronger democracy for generations to come.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, in accordance with Public Law 87-20, as amended, do hereby proclaim May 1, 2022, as Law Day, U.S.A. &nbsp;I call upon all Americans to acknowledge the importance of our Nation&#8217;s legal and judicial systems with appropriate ceremonies and activities, and to display the flag of the United&nbsp;States in support of this national observance.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-eighth day of April, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Request to Congress for Additional Funding to Support&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/28/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-request-to-congress-for-additional-funding-to-support-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 17:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 11:13 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, everybody.&#160; Good morning.&#160; I just signed a request to Congress for critical security, economic, and humanitarian assistance to help Ukraine continue to counter Putin’s aggression and &#8212; at a very pivotal moment. We need this bill to support Ukraine in its fight for freedom.&#160; And our NATO&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>11:13 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, everybody.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; I just signed a request to Congress for critical security, economic, and humanitarian assistance to help Ukraine continue to counter Putin’s aggression and &#8212; at a very pivotal moment.</p>



<p>We need this bill to support Ukraine in its fight for freedom.&nbsp; And our NATO Allies, our EU partners &#8212; they’re going to pay their fair share of the costs as well, but we have to do this.&nbsp; We have to do our part as well, leading the Alliance.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The cost of this fight is not cheap, but caving to aggression is going to be more costly if we allow it to happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We either back the Ukrainian people as they defend their country or we stand by as the Russians continue their atrocities and aggression in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Every day &#8212; every day, the Ukrainians pay for the &#8212; a price with &#8212; and the price they pay is with their lives for this fight.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we need to contribute arms, funding, ammunition, and the economic support to make their courage and sacrifice have purpose so they can continue this fight and do what they’re doing.</p>



<p>It’s critical this funding gets approved and approved as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>You know, long before Russia lost i- &#8212; launched its brutal invasion, I &#8212; I made clear how the United States would respond.&nbsp; I predicted they would invade, and they surely did.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We said we’d not send U.S. troops to fight Russian troops in Ukraine, but we would provide robust military assistance and try to unify the Western world against Russia’s aggression.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I said I would impose powerful sanctions on Russia and that we’d destroy and develop &#8212; we’d destroy this myth that somehow they could continue to move without the rest of the world acting; that we’d deploy additional forces to defend NATO territory, particularly in the east, along the Russian and Belarus borders.</p>



<p>That’s exactly &#8212; that’s exactly what we said we would do, and we did.</p>



<p>But despite the disturbing rhetoric coming out of the Kremlin, the facts are plain for everybody to see.&nbsp; We’re not attacking Russia; we’re helping Ukraine defend itself against Russian aggression.</p>



<p>And just as Putin chose to launch this brutal invasion, he could make the choice to end this brutal invasion.</p>



<p>Russia is the aggressor.&nbsp; No if, ands, or buts about it.&nbsp; Russia is the aggressor.&nbsp; And the world must and will hold Russia accountable.</p>



<p>Russia&#8217;s continued assault on &#8212; is yielding immense human costs.</p>



<p>We’ve seen &#8212; we’ve seen them leave behind horrifying evidence of their atrocities and war crimes in the areas they tried to control.</p>



<p>And as long as the assaults and atrocities continue, we’re going to continue to supply military assistance.</p>



<p><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I might note, parenthetically: You know, there’s a dinner this weekend to celebrate the press.&nbsp; Think of what the American press has done &#8212; the courage it has taken to stay in these warzones, the courage it has taken to report every single day.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’ve always had respect for the press, but I can’t tell you how much respect I have watching &#8212; watching them in these zones where they’re under fire, risking their own lives to make sure the world hears the truth.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Imagine if we weren’t getting that information.&nbsp; It’d be a different world.&nbsp; It’d be a different circumstance.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the past two months, Russia launched its brutal attack and has moved weapons and equipment to Ukraine at &#8212; we’ve moved &#8212; we’ve moved weapons and equipment to Ukraine at record speed.</p>



<p>Thanks to the aid we’ve provided, Russian forces have been forced to retreat from Kyiv.&nbsp; It doesn’t mean they’re not going to try to come back, but they’ve retreated thus far.</p>



<p><a>We’ve sent thousands of anti-armor, anti-[air] missiles, helicopters, drones, grenade launchers, machine guns, rifles, radar systems, more than 50 million rounds of ammunition.&nbsp; </a>The United States alone has provided 10 anti-armor systems for every Russian tank that is in Ukraine &#8212; 10 to 1.</p>



<p>We’re providing Ukraine significant, timely intelligence to help them defend themselves against the Russian onslaught.</p>



<p>And we’re facilitating a significant flow of weapons and systems to Ukraine from our Allies and partners around the world, including tanks, artillery, and other weapons.</p>



<p>That support is moving with unprecedented speed.</p>



<p>Much &#8212; much of the new equipment we’ve announced in the past two mon- &#8212; two weeks has already gotten to Ukraine, where it can be put to direct use on the battlefield.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, we have almost exhausted what we call &#8212; the fancy phrase &#8212; the “drawdown authority” that Congress authorized Ukraine &#8212; authorized for Ukraine in a bipartisan spending bill last month.&nbsp; Basically, we’re out of money.</p>



<p>And so, that’s why today, in order to sustain Ukraine as it &#8212; as it continues to fight, I’m sending Congress a supplemental budget request.</p>



<p>It’s going to keep weapons and ammunition flowing without interruption to the brave Ukrainian fighters and continue delivering economic and humanitarian assistance to the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>This so-called supplemental funding addresses the needs of the Ukrainian military during the crucial weeks and months ahead.&nbsp; And it begins &#8212; it begins to transition to longer-term security assistance that’s going to help Ukraine deter and continue to defend against Russian aggression.</p>



<p>This assistance would provide even more artillery, armored vehicles, anti-armor systems, anti-air capabilities that have been used so effectively thus far on the battlefield by the Ukrainian warriors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, and it’s going to deliver much-needed humanitarian assistance as well as food, water, medicines, shelter, and other aid to Ukrainians displaced by Russia’s war, and provide aid to those seeking refuge in other countries from Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s also going to help schools and hospitals open.&nbsp; It’s going to allow pensions and social support to be paid to the Ukrainian people so they have something &#8212; something in their pocket.&nbsp; It’s also going to provide critical resources to address food shortages around the globe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ukraine &#8212; Ukraine was one of the world’s largest agriculture producers.&nbsp; It typically grows 10 percent of all the wheat that’s shipped around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Putin has asserted sanctions are blocking food from Ukraine and Russia getting on the market &#8212; the sanctions we’ve imposed on Russia.&nbsp; Simply not true.</p>



<p>Putin’s war, not sanctions, are impacting the harvest of food and disrupting the movement of that food by land and sea to nations around the globe that need it.</p>



<p>This funding is going to help ease rising food prices at home as well, and abroad, caused by Russia’s war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>It’s going to help support American farmers produce more crops like wheat and oilseed, which is good for rural America, good for the American consumer, and good for the world.</p>



<p>And this supplemental request will use the Defense Production Act to expand domestic production and reserve &#8212; and the reserve of critical materials &#8212; materials like nickel and lithium that have been disrupted by Putin’s war in Ukraine and that are necessary to make everything from defense systems to automobiles.</p>



<p>And I hope Congress &#8212; I hope Congress will move on this funding quickly.&nbsp; I believe they will.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank Congress &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; for their support of the people of Ukraine.</p>



<p>And next week, I will be in Alabama to visit a Lockheed Martin plant that manufactures the Javelin anti-tank missile we’ve been sending to Ukraine, and to thank the American workers &#8212; thank them &#8212; for producing the weapons that helped stop Russia’s advances in Ukrainian cities like Kyiv.</p>



<p>Their hard work has played a critical role in ensuring Putin’s strategic failure in Ukraine, and they should know that we know it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition to this supplemental funding, I’m also sending to Congress a comprehensive package of &#8212; that will enhance our underlying effort to <s>accommodate</s> [hold accountable] the Russian oligarchs and make sure we take their &#8212; take their ill-begotten gains.&nbsp; Ha, we’re going to “accommodate” them.&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re going to seize their yachts, their luxury homes, and other ill-begotten gains of Putin’s kleptoc- &#8212; yeah &#8212; kleptocracy and klep- &#8212; the guys who are the kleptocracies.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; But these are bad guys.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This legislative package strengthens our law enforcement capabilities to seize property linked to Russia’s kleptocracy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s going to create new, expedited procedures for forfeiture and seizure of these &#8212; of these properties.&nbsp; And it’s going to ensure that when the oligarchs’ assets are sold off, funds can be used directly to remedy the harm Russia caused in their help &#8212; and help build Ukraine.</p>



<p>Additionally, yesterday, Ru- &#8212; Russia threatened two of our Allies with a cut-off of energy supplies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While America has ended all Russian fossil fuel imports because we are able to use our vast support &#8212; supply of power in our country, some European countries have faced more challenges in reducing their reliance on Russian fuel.</p>



<p>Russia has long claimed to be, quote, “the reliable source of energy” for the world.&nbsp; No matter what the differences are, their customers are always going to be &#8212; be in good shape.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But these actions prove that energy is not just a commodity that Russia sells to help meet other countries’ needs, but a weapon it will use to deploy against those who stand against their aggression.</p>



<p>So, let me be clear: We will not let Russia intimidate or blackmail their way out of these sanctions.&nbsp; We will not allow them to use their oil and gas to avoid consequences for their aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re working with other nations &#8212; like Korea, Japan, Qatar, and others &#8212; to support our effort to help the European allies threatened by Russia with gas blackmail and their energy needs in other ways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Aggression will not win.&nbsp; Threats will not win.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is just another reminder of the imperative for Europe and the world to move more and more of our power needs to clean energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the United States, we’re doing that right now.&nbsp; Last year, we <s>developed</s> [deployed] more solar, wind, and battery storage than any year in our history &#8212; enough to power 56 million American homes.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, we acted to bolster the &#8212; our reli- &#8211;the reliance on our nuclear energy facilities, which generates more than half of our carbon-free power.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re just getting started.&nbsp; I look at this as a serious problem, but also an enormous opportunity &#8212; an opportunity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bottom line: All these actions we&#8217;ve been taking are about the truth &#8212; this truth: Investing in Ukraine&#8217;s freedom and security is a small price to pay to punish Russian aggression, to lessen the risk of future conflicts.</p>



<p>You know, throughout our history, we&#8217;ve learned that when dictators do not pay the price for their aggression, they cause more chaos and engage in more aggression.&nbsp; They keep moving.&nbsp; And the costs, the threats to America and the world keep rising.</p>



<p>We can&#8217;t let this happen.</p>



<p>Our unity at home, our unity with our Allies and partners, and our unity with the Ukrainian people is sending an unmistakable message to Putin: You will never succeed in dominating Ukraine.</p>



<p>Finally, we&#8217;re going to continue to deliver critical support to Ukraine.&nbsp; We must also not let our guard down in our fight against COVID-19 at home and abroad.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I&#8217;m, again, urging Congress to act on my request for $22.5 billion in emergency resources so the American people can continue to protect themselves from COVID-19.</p>



<p>The reason we were so successful in the past is because I was able to work with drug manufacturers to order significant quantities of material we needed ahead of time to get in the front of the line.&nbsp; Without additional funding, we can&#8217;t preorder the amount of vaccines we need, and we risk losing our spot in line for vaccines that target multiple variants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re running out of supply for therapeutics like antiviral pills that we desperately need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without additional funding, we’re unable to purchase the lifesaving treatment for the American people.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve donated more vaccines and treatments to the world than all other nations in the world combined.&nbsp; If the U.S. won&#8217;t do it, no one else is really going to step up and do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without additional funding, the United States won&#8217;t be able to help stop the spread around the world and close off ongoing suppor- &#8212; sources of the supply chain disruptions.</p>



<p>Look, let&#8217;s get both of these critical tasks done.&nbsp; No delays, no excuses, just action now.&nbsp; Now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you all.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what’s your message to refugees on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how worried are you &#8212; how worried are you by &#8212; go ahead.&nbsp; No, you go.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Watch your head, man.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to get hurt.&nbsp; He&#8217;s turning that camera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m in a tight spot here, Mr. President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He&#8217;s a gentleman.&nbsp; Mr. President, I wanted to ask what your message is to Ukrainian refugees on the southwest border and those that are trying to flee Ukraine from the violence.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have made a direct means by which they can get from Europe, from Ukraine, directly to the United States, without going through the southern border.&nbsp; In the meantime, in the southern border, we&#8217;re trying to work through and make sure they &#8212; it’s an orderly process, they&#8217;re able to get in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But just so you know, we have said there&#8217;s no need to go to the southern border; fly directly to the United States.&nbsp; We set up a mechanism whereby they can come directly with a visa.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you.&nbsp; How worried are you by a growing number of Russian comments in the media and amongst some of their officials painting this conflict as actually already a conflict between NATO, the U.S., and Russia?&nbsp; And they&#8217;re painting in very alarmist terms, talking of nuclear weapons, saying it&#8217;s a life-or-death struggle, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just separately &#8212; well, connected to that: Lavrov himself self says it&#8217;s already a proxy war &#8212; not a direct war but a proxy war.&nbsp; So are either of those two things true?&nbsp; And do they worry you, those things?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re not true.&nbsp; They do concern me because it shows the desperation that Russia is feeling about their abject failure in being able to do what they set out to do in the first instance.</p>



<p>And so, it &#8212; I think it&#8217;s more of a reflection not of the truth but of their failure.&nbsp; And so, instead of saying that the &#8212; the Ukrainians, equipped with some capability to resist Russian forces, are doing this, they&#8217;ve got to say &#8212; tell their people the United States and all of NATO is engaged in &#8212; in taking out Russian troops and tanks, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s &#8212; number one, it&#8217;s an excuse for their failure.&nbsp; But number two, it&#8217;s also, if they really mean it, it&#8217;s &#8212; it’s &#8212; no &#8212; no one should be making idle comments about the use of nuclear weapons or the possibility that they&#8217;d use that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s irresponsible.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, back on the border, Title 42.&nbsp; A number of your Democratic friends are pressuring the White House</p>



<p>to maintain that policy.&nbsp; Can you give us a straight answer on whether you&#8217;re going to &#8212; whether you&#8217;re going to heed that request or you&#8217;re going to get rid of it?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I can give you a straight answer.&nbsp; We had proposed to eliminate that policy by the end of May.&nbsp; The Court has said we can’t so far.&nbsp; And what the Court says, we’re going to do.&nbsp; The Court could come along and say we cannot do that, and that&#8217;s it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, you say that this is not a proxy war, but Russia clearly disagrees.&nbsp; They say that war means war.&nbsp; So how concerned are you that they may start to act accordingly, even if you disagree?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We are prepared for whatever they do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What options do you have to ensure Poland and Bulgaria have sufficient supplies of gas?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; First of all, as you know, Poland has indicated they have significant reserves of gas that they have planned for, as does &#8212; not as much, but as does Bulgaria.&nbsp; And we have worked with our allies, from Japan on, to say that we may divert our sale of the natural gas that we&#8217;re sending to those countries and divert it directly to Poland and Bulgaria.</p>



<p>So, I &#8212; you know, that&#8217;s the most I can tell you right now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, how concerned are you about a recession, given the GDP report today showed a contraction of 1.4 percent in the first quarter?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not concerned about a recession.&nbsp; I mean, you&#8217;re always concerned about a recession, but the GDP, you know, fell to 1.4 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here&#8217;s the deal: We’re also had &#8212; last quarter, consumer spending and business investment and residential investment increased at significant rates, both for leisure as well as hard products, number one.</p>



<p>Number two, the &#8212; we are &#8212; unemployment is the lowest rate since 1970.&nbsp; A record 4.5 million businesses were created last year.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in a situation where the &#8212; you know, we have a very different view than Senator Scott and Republicans that want to raise taxes on the middle-class families and want to include half of small-business owners in that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think we&#8217;re &#8212; what you&#8217;re seeing is enormous growth in the country that was affected by everything from COVID and the COVID blockages that we &#8212; occurred along the way.</p>



<p>Now, you always have to be taking a look.&nbsp; And no one is predicting a recession now.&nbsp; They&#8217;re predicting &#8212; or some are predicting there may be recession in 2023.&nbsp; I&#8217;m concerned about it, but I know one thing: that, you know, if our Republican friends are really interested in doing something about dealing with the economic growth, they should help us continue to lower the deficit, which we&#8217;ve done last year &#8212; over $350 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They should be willing to work with us to have a tax code that is actually one that works and everybody pays their fair share.&nbsp; And they should be in a position where you shouldn&#8217;t be raising taxes on middle-class folks.&nbsp; You should be raising taxes on people who everyone acknowledges &#8212; and the vast majority of Republicans &#8212; aren&#8217;t paying their fair share.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve said it a hundred times: You have &#8212; you know, 50 major corporations of the Fortune 500 companies made $40 billion last year and didn&#8217;t pay single penny.&nbsp; No one under our proposal making under $400,000 a year will see a penny in their taxes go up.&nbsp; Not one penny.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What do you think about tying COVID aid to Ukraine aid?&nbsp; Do you think COVID aid and Ukraine aid should be tied together in legislation?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t care how they tie &#8212; how they do it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sending them both up.&nbsp; I mean, I &#8212; they can do it separately or together.&nbsp; But we need them both.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, Majority Leader Schumer said yesterday that you&#8217;re, quote, “getting closer” to using executive authority to cancel up to $50,000 in student loan debt.&nbsp; Can you confirm that?&nbsp; What exactly are you looking to &#8212; plan to do here in the coming &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You mean my spokesman said that?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Majority Leader Schumer.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, number one, one of &#8212; the first thing we did was reform the system that was in place that didn&#8217;t work for anybody that allowed people to write off debt if they engaged in public service.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve almost a million &#8212; seven hundred and eighty-five &#8212; don&#8217;t hold me to the exact number; I&#8217;ll get the number &#8212; seven hundred and some thousand have had debt forgiven &#8212; their whole debt forgiven because of their work working in &#8211;either as teachers or other means by which they qualify.&nbsp; And we continue to make that easier.</p>



<p>Secondly, I am considering dealing with some debt reduction.&nbsp; I am not considering $50,000 debt reduction.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m in the process of taking a hard look at whether or not there are going to &#8212; there will be additional debt forgiveness, and I&#8217;ll have an answer on that in the next couple of weeks.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>11:33 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Ukraine Supplemental Budget&#160;Request</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-ukraine-supplemental-budget-request/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 16:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 9:35 A.M. EDT MR. HASAN:  Good morning, everyone.  This is Abdullah from OMB.  Thanks for joining us on this call to discuss the Ukraine supplemental budget request.  As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to “administration officials,” and embargoed until 10:30 a.m. today. For your awareness, but not for reporting purposes,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>9:35 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. HASAN:  Good morning, everyone.  This is Abdullah from OMB.  Thanks for joining us on this call to discuss the Ukraine supplemental budget request.  As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to “administration officials,” and embargoed until 10:30 a.m. today.</p>



<p>For your awareness, but not for reporting purposes, joining us on the call today are [senior administration officials] and [senior administration official].&nbsp; We also have additional officials available to answer questions as needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will, however, just note at the top that, unfortunately, we do have a hard stop at 9:45.&nbsp; So we may not have a lot of time to get through questions, but we will try to get to as many as we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I will turn it over to our first administration official.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; From before this conflict began, we have laid out and now implemented a three-part strategy:</p>



<p>We have imposed powerful sanctions and unprecedented export controls on Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have bolstered NATO&#8217;s force posture on the eastern flank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have provided robust military and other assistance to Ukraine as it sought to defend its territory from an outrageous and unlawful Russian attack.</p>



<p>To meet this responsibility, over the course of the last two months, Congress appropriated and the President allocated roughly $14 billion in funding for security, humanitarian, and economic support that has allowed the United States to respond to Russia&#8217;s aggression in Ukraine at a scope, scale, and speed that has never been seen before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite having no boots on the ground, our assistance has made a significant difference on the battlefield, helping the brave citizens of Ukraine to win the Battle of Kyiv and to continue to deplete the Russian military.</p>



<p>These funds have also helped us to reinforce the eastern flank of NATO, maintain the unity of the Alliance in the face of Russian efforts to divide us, impose severe consequences on Russia and its enablers, and collect and provide intelligence so that our allies and partners have awareness of Russian intention.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, the conflict has now entered a different phase, and one that is no less dangerous, as Russia shifts the focus of its assault to Ukraine’s south and east.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we have said, this fight could well last months or more. This conflict will continue to test our unity and our collective resolve to provide Ukraine what it needs to succeed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks to the generosity of Americans and the leadership of President Biden, the United States has delivered, making us by far the largest supporter of Ukraine.&nbsp; The American people should be proud of that, but America and our allies must continue to deliver.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, the President will speak about the critical resources required for the United States to maintain our high level of assistance over the months to come.&nbsp; The President&#8217;s funding request is what we believe is needed to enable Ukraine’s success over the next five months of this war.&nbsp; And we have every expectation that our partners and allies, particularly those of the G7, as well as many other countries, will continue to provide comparable levels of assistance going forward so that each of us is doing our part.</p>



<p>My colleague will go over the specific assistance in the request with you next.&nbsp; The assistance includes funds that will allow us to ensure Ukraine has the weapons it needs to wage this fight, replenish our own stockpiles of key systems, help other countries to shift away from a dependence on Russian weapons, enable Ukraine&#8217;s government to continue performing basic functions, address food insecurity exacerbated by Russia&#8217;s war of aggression, and support Ukrainian refugees and the countries that are providing them sanctuary.</p>



<p>Also, as part of our effort to continue supporting Ukraine, President Biden will send a proposal for a comprehensive legislative package to make it easier to seize the assets of Russian oligarchs and elites, expand assets subject to seizure, and enable the proceeds to flow to Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We look forward to working with Congress on this.&nbsp; And as you know, the United States has already been working with Allies and partners to track down assets all over the world.&nbsp; For example, Treasury has sanctioned and blocked vessels and aircraft worth over a billion dollars, as well as frozen hundreds of millions of dollars of assets belonging to Russian elites in U.S. bank accounts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And earlier this month, the Department of Justice announced that Spain seized a 255-foot, $90 million yacht of sanctioned Russian oligarch Viktor Vekselberg at the request of the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This war will not end easily or rapidly, but the free world is united against this brutal invasion and we must continue to be in the best position possible to respond to a variety of scenarios.&nbsp; President Biden will call on Congress to keep this up.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Let me quickly walk through the three key areas of this $33 billion supplemental request.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, first, we&#8217;re calling on Congress to provide over $20 billion in military and other security assistance to keep weapons and ammunition flowing to the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; And this includes $5 billion in additional drawdown authority, $6 billion for the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative, and $4 billion for the State Department&#8217;s Foreign Military Financing program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, we&#8217;re calling on Congress to provide an additional $8.5 billion in economic assistance to help the government of Ukraine respond to the immediate crisis and continue to provide basic services to the Ukrainian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And third, we&#8217;re seeking &#8212; this provides $3 billion in additional humanitarian assistance and food security funding.&nbsp; And these resources will provide wheat and other commodities to people in need, build countries’ resilience to the global food supply and price shock, and provide lifesaving aid to displaced people &#8212; people displaced by Putin’s war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Finally, I want to highlight that this request also includes targeted funding to address economic disruptions at home and around the world due to Putin&#8217;s aggression.&nbsp; And that includes helping increase U.S. production of food crops, such as wheat and soybeans, and funding to allow the use of the Defense Production Act to expand domestic production of critical reserves &#8212; of reserves of critical minerals and materials that have been disrupted by Putin’s war and are necessary to make everything from defense systems to cars.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So let me just close there. &nbsp;Can we have time for questions?&nbsp; And I just want to say that continued bipartisan support in Congress is vital to ensuring the Ukrainian people have the resources they need to win this war, and the administration is committed to working with lawmakers in both parties and our global allies and partners to keep that aid flowing to Ukraine uninterrupted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So let me hand it back to Abdullah.</p>



<p>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And we will be ready to take questions now, Moderator.&nbsp; But just a heads up for reporters who will ask, “Where is the factsheet?”: Don&#8217;t waste your question on that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s coming to you shortly after this call.&nbsp; But with that, let&#8217;s go ahead and take questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys, thank you.&nbsp; Can you drill down on the seizing of Russian assets?&nbsp; As, of course, you know, there&#8217;s some concerns about due process on this, and the House bill had to be watered down.&nbsp; Do you think you are able to, today, seize ill-gotten gains and transfer them to Ukraine?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And a bit of a strategic question on the war: Do you think &#8212; in terms of the $20 billion they&#8217;re using for the weapons and requests from Europe to backfill that &#8212; that this is an opportunity for Eastern European countries to get more advanced weapons and indeed for Ukraine to get more integrated into Western and NATO weapons systems?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll answer the second question, and then I&#8217;ll turn it over to a colleague to answer the first question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, on sort of how the $20 billion will be used in the ways that you describe: You know, we have said from the beginning that while Russia had every intention of weakening and dividing the NATO Alliance, we fully expect and are using every resource we have available to us to do exactly the opposite.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re already seeing that outcome.&nbsp; The Alliance is far more unified, we believe, than it has been at any time in recent memory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Alliance members are fully committed to this fight, contributing directly, nearly all of them, to Ukraine&#8217;s efforts to defend its country, including through the provision of security assistance.&nbsp; That does deplete some of these countries’ supplies.&nbsp; We are discussing with them various ways in which we can help make sure that they are &#8212; continue to be able to defend themselves fully.&nbsp; And some of this funding will go toward that effort.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more to say about it as this fight goes on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll turn it now over to my colleague on the first question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I guess I’ll start with the end of the question.&nbsp; The Department of Justice has authorities today that allow it to seize assets that are involved in certain criminal wrongdoing.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve exercised that authority to seize assets of Russian oligarchs, including the yacht that [senior administration official] referred to earlier in his opening comments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;re seeking today is an expanded and expedited administrative process that would allow for the forfeiture of property that would be conducted within the Department of the Treasury.&nbsp; We worked closely with DOJ to ensure that that process affords people who have an interest in the property the opportunity to raise their interest and including seeking judicial review, and also that the property seized has a nexus to criminal conduct.&nbsp; That with those safeguards, you know, we feel confident that it satisfies the constitutional requirements.</p>



<p>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; Great, let&#8217;s try to squeeze in one more question real quick.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; My question is how you would like Congress to try to move this package.&nbsp; Do you have any preference of whether this moves with a COVID relief package that I guess is still TBD or if it would move on its own?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, this is [senior administration official].&nbsp; I’m the [redacted] at the Office of Management and Budget.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to say, you know, you&#8217;ll see &#8212; you&#8217;ll hear the President later today talk about this.&nbsp; And, you know, we&#8217;re &#8212; he&#8217;ll call for Congress to act on the supplemental request that he sent up earlier on COVID, and it certainly makes sense for them to move together.&nbsp; But you&#8217;ll hear a strong call for Congress to certainly take that up &#8212; take that COVID money back up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re not going to get too far ahead of the legislative process.</p>



<p>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; We will end it there.&nbsp; Thank you all for joining.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to go ahead and send some embargoed materials over now so you have those.</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call was embargoed and attributable to “administration officials” on background, embargoed until 10:30 a.m. today.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining.</p>



<p>9:45 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: White&#160;House Calls on Congress to Provide Additional Support for&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/fact-sheet-white-house-calls-on-congress-to-provide-additional-support-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 15:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51950</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The assistance the Biden-Harris Administration has provided to Ukraine to date has made a significant difference on the battlefield, helping Ukrainians defend their country and win the battle for Kyiv. Now, as the war shifts to and intensifies in Ukraine’s eastern front, the Biden-Harris Administration is calling on Congress to provide additional resources to help&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The assistance the Biden-Harris Administration has provided to Ukraine to date has made a significant difference on the battlefield, helping Ukrainians defend their country and win the battle for Kyiv. Now, as the war shifts to and intensifies in Ukraine’s eastern front, the Biden-Harris Administration is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-on-fiscal-year-2022-emergency-supplemental-funding/">calling on</a> Congress to provide additional resources to help ensure Ukraine’s democracy prevails over Putin’s aggression.<br><br>The supplemental resources Congress provided on a bipartisan basis in March have been critical to bolstering security in Eastern Europe, countering Russia’s malign activities in the region, and delivering critical humanitarian and economic assistance to Ukraine and neighboring partners. Almost all of the $3.5 billion in drawdown authority Congress provided in March has been exhausted as the Biden-Harris Administration has surged military assistance to Ukraine, which they have used to great effect. U.S. supplied weapons and ammunitions – including anti-tank and anti-air systems, helicopters, drones, grenade launchers, and more than 50 million rounds of ammunition – have been flowing into Ukraine daily, and the United States has been working with allies and partners to facilitate deliveries of additional weapons capabilities. The Defense Department has also used $1 billion in supplemental resources to reinforce NATO’s eastern flank and bolster NATO’s security posture to deter Russian aggression.</p>



<p>At the same time, the Administration is delivering humanitarian, economic, food, and other security assistance to Ukraine and the region. This includes roughly $1.7 billion to ensure continuity of Ukraine’s democratic operations and provide other macroeconomic assistance to the region. It also includes $650 million in military assistance to Ukraine, eastern flank countries, and other partners in the region, as well as hundreds of millions of dollars in food, shelter, and other humanitarian aid to help Ukrainians who have been displaced by Russia’s war.&nbsp;Supplemental resources are also supporting efforts to hold Putin and his cronies accountable for their war of choice, helping the United States seize billions in assets and holdings.</p>



<p>Continued bipartisan support in Congress is vital to ensuring that the Ukrainian people have the resources they need to win this war, and this Administration is committed to working with lawmakers and our global allies and partners to keep aid flowing to Ukraine uninterrupted and to support those devastated by the food crisis that Putin’s war has exacerbated.<br><br>The $33 billion in security, economic, and humanitarian aid requested today will:<br><br><strong><em>Help Ukraine Defend Itself Over the Long-Term</em></strong><br><br>The Administration is requesting $20.4 billion in additional security and military assistance for Ukraine and for U.S. efforts to strengthen European security in cooperation with our NATO allies and other partners in the region. This includes $5 billion in additional drawdown authority, $6 billion for the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative, and $4 billion for the State Department’s Foreign Military Financing program. These resources will put urgently needed equipment into the hands of Ukraine&#8217;s military and police, as well as help NATO deter and defend against Russian aggression over the long-term. These additional resources will be used to provide Ukraine and Eastern flank allies with:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Additional artillery, armored vehicles, anti-armor and anti-air capabilities </strong>flowing into Ukraine uninterrupted<strong>.</strong><br></li><li><strong>Accelerated cyber capabilities and advanced air defense systems</strong>, improved production capabilities for munitions and strategic minerals, and increased intelligence support.<br></li><li><strong>Assistance to clear landmines, improvised explosive devices, and other explosive remnants of war </strong>and for the Government of Ukraine in securing and addressing threats related to chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear materials.<br></li><li><strong>A stronger NATO security posture </strong>through support for U.S. troop deployments on NATO territory, including transportation of U.S. personnel and equipment, temporary duty, special pay, airlift, weapons system sustainment, and medical support.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Additional Economic Aid to Support Democracy in Ukraine</em></strong><br><br>The Administration is calling on Congress to provide an additional $8.5 billion in economic assistance to help the Government of Ukraine respond to the immediate crisis and continue to provide basic citizen services. This includes funds to:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Ensure Ukraine’s democratic government continues functioning; </strong>support food, energy, and health care services for the Ukrainian people; and assist the Ukrainian government in responding to operational challenges as businesses shutter and revenue collection plummets.<br></li><li><strong>Counter Russian disinformation and propaganda narratives</strong>, promote accountability for Russian human rights violation, and support activists, journalists, and independent media to defend freedom of expression.<br></li><li><strong>Support small- and medium- sized agrobusinesses during the fall harvest and for natural gas purchases</strong> by the Ukrainian state energy company in order to address critical food security, energy, and other emerging needs in Ukraine.</li></ul>



<p><em><strong>Address Humanitarian Needs due to Russia’s War<br></strong></em><br>The $3 billion in additional humanitarian assistance will provide critical resources to address food security needs around the globe, provide wheat and other commodities to people in need, build countries&#8217; resilience to global food supply and price shocks, and provide lifesaving aid to people displaced by or otherwise impacted by Putin’s War in Ukraine. This funding will mean:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Direct food support, including wheat and flour, for individuals in developing countries </strong>impacted by Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as helping countries build more resilient agricultural systems.<br></li><li><strong>Medical supplies, high thermal blankets, emergency health kits, safe drinking water, shelter materials</strong>, and other lifesaving humanitarian assistance for Ukrainians displaced by Russia’s war.<br></li><li><strong>Job training, trauma-informed mental health services, and resources for local school districts to support Ukrainians arriving in the United States, </strong>including the new Uniting for Ukraine program.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Bolster Sanctions Enforcement</em></strong><br><br>Resources will also bolster the Department of Justice’s KleptoCapture Task force efforts to pursue high value asset seizures from sanctioned individuals related to Russian actions in Ukraine. The Administration is also proposing legislation to streamline the process to recoup proceeds from seized and forfeited assets and use them to remediate the harm caused in Ukraine.<br><br><strong><em>Addressing Economic Disruptions at Home and Around the World Due to Putin’s Aggression</em></strong><br><br>An additional $500 million in domestic food production assistance will support the production of U.S. food crops that are experiencing a global shortage due to the war in Ukraine, for example, wheat and soybeans. Through higher loan rates and crop insurance incentives the request provides greater access to credit and lowers risk for farmers growing these food commodities, while lowering costs for American consumers.<br><br>Additional funding will also allow use of the Defense Production Act to expand domestic production of critical minerals and materials that have been disrupted by Putin’s war in Ukraine and that are necessary to make everything from defense systems to automobiles.&nbsp; This will help address economic disruptions and reduce price pressures at home and around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives on Fiscal Year 2022 Emergency Supplemental&#160;Funding</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-on-fiscal-year-2022-emergency-supplemental-funding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker:&#160;I am writing to provide you with my request for fiscal year (FY) 2022 emergency supplemental funding for critical security and economic assistance to Ukraine.&#160;I appreciate the Congress&#8217; continued bipartisan support for Ukraine, NATO, and other partner countries affected by Russia&#8217;s War in Ukraine.&#160; My Administration is committed to providing the Ukrainian people&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker:<br>&nbsp;<br>I am writing to provide you with my request for fiscal year (FY) 2022 emergency supplemental funding for critical security and economic assistance to Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>I appreciate the Congress&#8217; continued bipartisan support for Ukraine, NATO, and other partner countries affected by Russia&#8217;s War in Ukraine.&nbsp; My Administration is committed to providing the Ukrainian people the assistance they need.&nbsp; Our assistance to date has made a difference on the battlefield, helping Ukraine win the battle for Kyiv.&nbsp; This $33.0 billion request for&nbsp;additional funding and authority builds on the Congress&#8217; supplemental appropriation of $13.6&nbsp;billion on March 15, 2022, and seeks to address immediate and near-term security and economic needs.&nbsp; Additional security assistance will put urgently needed equipment into the hands of Ukraine&#8217;s military and police, including ammunition, armored vehicles, small arms, demining assistance, and unmanned aircraft systems.&nbsp; Economic assistance will provide Direct Budget Support to provide rapid, flexible funds to assist the Government of Ukraine in responding to the immediate crisis and continue to provide basic citizen services.&nbsp; Additional food security and humanitarian assistance will provide wheat and other commodities to people in need, build countries&#8217; resilience to global food supply and price shocks, and provide lifesaving aid to people displaced by or otherwise impacted by Russia&#8217;s War in Ukraine. &nbsp;Additionally, the request includes funding to support the production of United&nbsp;States food crops that are experiencing a global shortage due to the war in Ukraine, for example, wheat and soybeans helping to address rising food prices here at home and around the world.&nbsp; The request also would help increase domestic production for strategic minerals and materials produced in Russia or Ukraine and respond to global shortfalls and reduce price pressures.&nbsp; The request also outlines a number of authorities needed to support Ukraine, our European allies and&nbsp;partners, and address other emergent global needs.&nbsp; The details of this request are set forth in an enclosed addendum.<br>&nbsp;<br>Though we expect our NATO allies and EU partners will be making even larger collective contributions than the United States, there is no doubt that continuing to support Ukraine in this war against Russian aggression will require a substantial additional investment on our part.&nbsp; What I want to make clear to the Congress and the American people is this:&nbsp; the cost of failing to stand up to violent aggression in Europe has always been higher than the cost of standing firm against such attacks.&nbsp; That is as it always has been, and as it always will be.&nbsp; America must meet this moment, and do its part.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to the legislative proposals in this package, my Administration is also sending a proposal to the Congress to enhance the United States&#8217; ability to hold Russia accountable financially for its ongoing invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; These proposals would strengthen our whole-of-government approach &#8212; along with those of our international partners &#8212; by providing for expanded and expedited measures for investigating, prosecuting, and forfeiting assets of Russian oligarchs to&nbsp;be&nbsp;used for the benefit of Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, I also appreciate the Congress&#8217; bipartisan support for ensuring we can continue to provide the American people with the tools they need to protect themselves from COVID-19, and again urge the Congress to act promptly to provide the $22.5 billion I&nbsp;requested on March 2, 2022.&nbsp; Without additional funding, we are unable to purchase additional life-saving treatments for the American people, and we are losing our spot in line to other countries for vaccines that may provide better and more durable protection against multiple variants.&nbsp; We also must stop the spread of possible new variants from around the world as every COVID variant has emerged from overseas.&nbsp; We have to keep vaccinating the world to save lives here at home and protect our&nbsp;economy from further supply chain disruptions, but we need funding to help get shots into arms. &nbsp;To avoid needless deaths in the United States and around the world, I urge the Congress to include this much needed, life-saving COVID funding as part of this supplemental funding request.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I urge the Congress to address these critical and urgent needs promptly.&nbsp; The amounts included in this request are requested to&nbsp;be designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 4001(a)(1) and section 4001(b) of S. Con. Res. 14 (117th Congress), the concurrent resolution on the budget for FY 2022.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Gross Domestic&#160;Product</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-gross-domestic-product/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 13:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The American economy — powered by working families — continues to be resilient in the face of historic challenges. Last quarter, consumer spending, business investment, and residential investment increased at strong rates. The number of Americans on unemployment insurance remains at the lowest level since 1970. Later this morning, I will meet with small business&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The American economy — powered by working families — continues to be resilient in the face of historic challenges. Last quarter, consumer spending, business investment, and residential investment increased at strong rates. The number of Americans on unemployment insurance remains at the lowest level since 1970. Later this morning, I will meet with small business owners who are creating and growing their businesses at a historic rate. While last quarter’s growth estimate was affected by technical factors, the United States confronts the challenges of COVID-19 around the world, Putin’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, and global inflation from a position of strength.</p>



<p>We need to keep making progress — cutting costs for working families, making more in America, and creating good-paying jobs you can raise a middle-class family on. Congressional Republicans, led by Senator Scott, believe the way to fight these global challenges is by raising taxes on middle class families, including half of small business owners. I have a different approach. Congress should send to my desk a bipartisan innovation bill to bolster our supply chains and make more in America. And Congress needs to pass legislation to lower costs and lower the deficit, reducing families’ prescription drug and utility bills and restoring fairness to our tax code — without raising taxes on anyone making less than $400,000 per year. That’s how we grow our economy and strengthen the middle class.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
