<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 23:07:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Providing an Update on Russia and&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/15/remarks-by-president-biden-providing-an-update-on-russia-and-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 23:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 3:29 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Today, I’d like to provide an update on the crisis involving Russia and Ukraine. From the beginning of this crisis, I have been absolutely clear and consistent: The United States is prepared no matter what happens.&#160; We are ready with diplomacy &#8212; to be engaged in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>East Room</em></p>



<p>3:29 P.M. EST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Today, I’d like to provide an update on the crisis involving Russia and Ukraine.<br><br>From the beginning of this crisis, I have been absolutely clear and consistent: The United States is prepared no matter what happens.&nbsp;<br><br>We are ready with diplomacy &#8212; to be engaged in diplomacy with Russia and our Allies and partners to improve stability and security in Europe as a whole.&nbsp;<br><br>And we are ready to respond decisively to a Russian attack on Ukraine, which is still very much a possibility.<br><br>Through all of the events of the last few weeks and months, this has been our approach.&nbsp; And it remains our approach now.<br><br>So, today I want to speak to the American people about the situation on the ground, the steps we’ve taken, the actions we’re prepared to take, and what’s at stake for us and the world, and how this may impact on us here at home.<br><br>For weeks now, together with our Allies and partners, my administration has engaged in&nbsp;non-stop diplomacy.<br><br>This weekend I spoke again with President Putin to make clear that we are ready to keep pursuing high-level diplomacy to reach written understandings among Russia, the United States, and the nations of Europe to address legitimate security concerns if that’s what &#8212; his wish.&nbsp; Their security concerns and ours.<br><br>President Putin and I agreed that our teams should continue to engage toward this end along with our European Allies and partners.<br><br>Yesterday, the Russian government publicly proposed to continue the diplomacy.&nbsp; I agree.&nbsp; We should give the diplomacy every chance to succeed.&nbsp; I believe there are real ways to address our respective security concerns.<br><br>The United States has put on the table concrete ideas to establish a security environment in Europe.<br><br>We’re proposing new arms control measures, new transparency measures, new strategic stability measures.&nbsp; These measures would apply to all parties &#8212; NATO and Russia alike.<br><br>And we’re willing to make practical, results-oriented steps&nbsp;that can advance our common security.&nbsp; We will not sacrifice basic principles, though.<br><br>Nations have a right to sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp; They have the freedom to set their own course and choose with whom they will associate.<br><br>But that still leaves plenty of room for diplomacy<br>and for de-escalation.&nbsp; That’s the best way forward for all parties, in our view.&nbsp; And we’ll continue our diplomatic efforts in close consultation with our Allies and our partners.<br><br>As long as there is hope of a diplomatic resolution<br>that prevents the use of force and avoids the incredible human suffering that would follow, we will pursue it.<br><br>The Russian Defense Ministry reported today that some military units are leaving their positions near Ukraine.<br><br>That would be good, but we have not yet verified that.&nbsp; We have not yet verified that Russian military units are returning to their home bases.&nbsp; Indeed, our analysts indicate that they remain very much in a threatening position.&nbsp; And the fact remains: Right now, Russia has more than 150,000 troops encircling Ukraine in Belarus and along Ukraine’s border.<br><br>An invasion remains distinctly possible.&nbsp; That’s why I&#8217;ve asked several times that all Americans in Ukraine leave now before it’s too late to leave safely.&nbsp; It is why we have temporarily relocated our embassy from Kyiv to Lviv in western Ukraine, approaching the Polish border.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;ve been transparent with the American people and with the world about Russia’s plans and the seriousness of the situation so that everyone can see for themselves what is happening.&nbsp; We have shared what we know and what we are doing about it.<br><br>Let me be equally clear about what we are not doing:<br><br>The United States and NATO are not a threat to Russia.&nbsp; Ukraine is not threatening Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>Neither the U.S. nor NATO have missiles in Ukraine.&nbsp; We do not &#8212; do not have plans to put them there as well.<br><br>We’re not targeting the people of Russia.&nbsp; We do not seek to destabilize Russia.<br><br>To the citizens of Russia: You are not our enemy.&nbsp; And I do not believe you want a bloody, destructive war against Ukraine &#8212; a country and a people with whom you share such deep ties of family, history, and culture.<br><br>Seventy-seven years ago, our people fought and sacrificed side by side to end the worst war in history.<br><br>World War Two was a war of necessity.&nbsp; But if Russia attacks Ukraine, it would be a war of choice, or a war without cause or reason.<br><br>I say these things not to provoke but to speak the truth &#8212; because the truth matters; accountability matters.<br><br>If Russia does invade in the days or weeks ahead, the human cost for Ukraine will be immense, and the strategic cost for Russia will also be immense.<br><br>If Russia attacks Ukraine, it’ll be met with overwhelming international condemnation.&nbsp; The world will not forget that Russia chose needless death and destruction.<br><br>Invading Ukraine will prove to be a self-inflicted wound.<br><br>The United States and our Allies and partners will respond decisively.&nbsp; The West is united and galvanized.<br><br>Today, our NATO Allies and the Alliance is as unified and determined as it has ever been.&nbsp;&nbsp; And the source of our unbreakable strength continues to be the power, resilience, and universal appeal of our shared democratic values.<br><br>Because this is about more than just Russia and Ukraine.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about standing for what we believe in, for the future we want for our world, for liberty &#8212; for liberty, the right of countless countries to choose their own destiny, and the right of people to determine their own futures, for the principle that a country can’t change its neighbor’s borders by force.&nbsp; That&#8217;s our vision.&nbsp;&nbsp;And toward that end, I’m confident that vision, that freedom will prevail.<br><br>If Russia proceeds, we will rally the world to oppose its aggression.<br><br>The United States and our Allies and partners around the world are ready to impose powerful sanctions on [and] export controls, including actions that did not &#8212; we did not pursue when Russia invaded Crimea and eastern Ukraine in 2014.&nbsp;&nbsp;We will put intense pressure on their largest and most significant financial institutions and key industries.<br><br>These measures are ready to go as soon and if Russia moves.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll impose long-term consequences that will undermine Russia’s ability to compete economically and strategically.<br><br>And when it comes to Nord Stream 2, the pipeline that would bring natural gas from Russia to Germany, if Russia further invades Ukraine, it will not happen.<br><br>While I will not send American servicemen to fight Russia in Ukraine, we have supplied the Ukrainian military with equipment to help them defend themselves.&nbsp; We have provided training and advice and intelligence for the same purpose.&nbsp;<br><br>And make no mistake: The United States will defend every inch of NATO territory with the full force of American power.&nbsp; An attack against one NATO country is an attack against all of us.&nbsp; And the United States commitment to Article 5 is sacrosanct.&nbsp;<br><br>Already, in response to Russia’s build-up of troops, I have sent additional U.S. forces to bolster NATO’s eastern flank.<br><br>Several of our Allies have also announced they&#8217;ll add forces and capabilities to ensure deterrence and defense along NATO’s eastern flank.<br><br>We will also continue to conduct military exercises with our Allies and partners to enhance defensive readiness.&nbsp;<br><br>And if Russia invades, we will take further steps to reinforce our presence in NATO, reassure for our Allies, and deter further aggression.<br><br>This is a cause that unites Republicans and Democrats.&nbsp; And I want to thank the leaders and members of Congress of both parties who have forcefully spoken out in defense of our most basic, most bipartisan, most American principles.<br><br>I will not pretend this will be painless.&nbsp; There could be impact on our energy prices, so we are taking active steps to alleviate the pressure on our own energy markets and offset rising prices.<br><br>We’re coordinating with major enersy [sic] &#8212; energy consumers and producers.&nbsp; We’re prepared to deploy all the tools and authority at our disposal to provide relief at the gas pump.&nbsp;<br><br>And I will work with Congress on additional measures<br>to help protect consumers and address the impact of prices at the pump.<br><br>We are not seeking direct confrontation with Russia, though I have been clear that if Russia targets Americans in Ukraine, we will respond forcefully.<br><br>And if Russia attacks the United States or our Allies<br>through asymmetric means, like disruptive cyberattacks<br>against our companies or critical infrastructure, we are prepared to respond.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re moving in lockstep with our NATO Allies and partners to deepen our collective defense against threats in cyberspace.<br><br>Two paths are still open.&nbsp; For the sake of the historic responsibility Russia and the United States share for global stability, for the sake of our common future &#8212; to choose diplomacy.<br><br>But let there be no doubt: If Russia commits this breach<br>by invading Ukraine, responsible nations around the world&nbsp;will not hesitate to respond.&nbsp;<br><br>If we do not stand for freedom where it is at risk today, we’ll surely pay a steeper price tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; I’ll keep you informed.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3:50 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Hawaii Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/15/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-hawaii-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 21:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47338</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Hawaii and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, flooding, and landslides during the period of December 5 to December 10, 2021. Federal funding is available to state and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Hawaii and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, flooding, and landslides during the period of December 5 to December 10, 2021.<br><br>Federal funding is available to state and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storms, flooding, and landslides in the City and County of Honolulu and Maui County.<br><br>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.<br><br>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Benigno Bern Ruiz as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp;<br><br>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.<br><br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Emmanuel Macron of&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/15/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-emmanuel-macron-of-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 21:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France.  They reviewed their recent conversations with their Russian and Ukrainian counterparts, and affirmed their continued support for a diplomatic path forward. They discussed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts undertaken in close coordination with Allies and partners in response to Russia’s military buildup&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France.  They reviewed their recent conversations with their Russian and Ukrainian counterparts, and affirmed their continued support for a diplomatic path forward. They discussed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts undertaken in close coordination with Allies and partners in response to Russia’s military buildup along Ukraine’s borders, including their readiness to impose severe consequences and to reinforce the defensive posture on NATO’s eastern flank.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the National Association of Counties 2022 Legislative&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/15/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-national-association-of-counties-2022-legislative-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Washington HiltonWashington, D.C. 1:20 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you. Folks, my name is Joe Biden.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And I used to be a county councilman.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; And I ran for the Senate because it was too damn hard being in the council.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; It’s great to be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Washington Hilton<br>Washington, D.C.</em></p>



<p>1:20 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Folks, my name is Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I used to be a county councilman.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And I ran for the Senate because it was too damn hard being in the council.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>It’s great to be back with you all.&nbsp; Commissioner Larry Johnson of DeKalb County, Georgia, thank you for your leadership.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also want to thank all the folks working so hard here in the Washington Hilton to make this conference possible.&nbsp; Thank you all very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if you want to know how seriously I take the role you play on the frontlines in this country, just look at who I asked to come with you.&nbsp; You said you wanted to know what was going on.&nbsp; I sent you the whole damn administration.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Yeah, Secretaries &#8212; three Secretaries, an Administrator &#8212; Regan of the EPA; Gene Sperling leading the Rescue Plan implementation; Mitch Landrieu, who’s leading the implementation of the Infrastructure Law; and you all know Julie Rodriguez, my Director of Intergovernmental Affairs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And along with a number of other key deputies and &#8212; leading my economic strategy.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, I want to recognize my home county executive, Matt Meyer, so I can go back home.&nbsp; Matt, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Matt is doing one heck of a job, and I’m sure he’s told you the story, I heard, of the &#8212; my time in the county council.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I used to &#8212; I don&#8217;t know about you all, but commissioner, councilman &#8212; whichever your title is &#8212; you knock on the door and say, “My name is Joe Biden, and I’m a candidate for the county council.”&nbsp; And they look at you like, “Okay?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And you’re wondering &#8212; you’re wondering what the county council does, aren’t you?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Well, it affects their lives more than anybody else’s.&nbsp; No, it really does.&nbsp; You’re involved in everything.&nbsp;<br><br>When a constituent called, she said &#8212; I represented a &#8212; we had &#8212; we have one county that has 60 percent of the state’s population.&nbsp; And we had six councilmen.&nbsp; So a councilman’s district was seven times bigger than a house member and &#8212; in the state house &#8212; and three time bigger than the state senator.<br><br>And I represented a middle-class district to a working-class district, but there was one very wealthy neighborhood.&nbsp; And I got a call one night; the woman said to me &#8212; obviously not of the same persuasion as I was, politically &#8212; called me and said, “There’s a dead dog on my lawn.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I said, “Yes, ma’am.”&nbsp; I said, “Have you called county?”&nbsp; She said, “Yes, they’re not here.”&nbsp; And I said, “Well, I’ll get them in the morning.”&nbsp; She said, “I want it removed now.&nbsp; I pay your salary.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, I went over.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; I picked it up.&nbsp; She said, “I want it out of my front yard.”&nbsp; I put it on her doorstep.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>But I’ve gotten much better since then.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I know from personal experience how hard the job you have is.&nbsp; People &#8212; people having to phone or &#8212; you know, or not afraid to use that phone.&nbsp; I used to give out my phone number; can’t do that anymore.&nbsp; They don’t even allow me to have a phone anymore.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But I &#8212; I also know you work often on the basis of what other people &#8212; whether they’ve lost faith, they have faith, they lose faith in government &#8212; you’re there.&nbsp; You represent the frontlines of public service.&nbsp; It’s not hyperbole.<br><br>That’s why I was elected &#8212; one of the first calls I made was to your board of directors.&nbsp;&nbsp;And I reminded Judge Gary Moore, your past president, that this administration includes a President and Vice President who are both former county officials.&nbsp;&nbsp;And I promised I’ll always have you as a partner with us.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The partnership was critical when we passed American Rescue Plan &#8212; the most significant investment in the country’s local governments in American history.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I also inherited a tough situation in 2020.&nbsp; But after an incredibly difficult year, local and state governments have added 448,000 new jobs in 2021 &#8212; the strongest growth in 20 years.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, you know, it’s &#8212; it’s amazing what you all do.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; I’m not being solicitous.&nbsp; After a year of disruption for our kids, we were able to add education jobs in 2021, more than &#8212; more than any other year on record.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You got county law enforcement officers and first responders back on the job so ambulances could arrive on time and communities could be kept safe.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the big reason why America’s recovery has led the world is because of all of you and why, in my first year in office, more jobs were created than ever any time in America history &#8212; 6.6 million jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, folks, look, we had the strongest economic growth in nearly 40 years &#8212; 5.7 percent increase in the GDP.&nbsp; The unemployment rate dropped more than any time &#8212; any year in American history.&nbsp; Child poverty dropped by 40 percent, more than any year in American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And, folks, new business applications grew at a faster rate than any year on record.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Rescue Plan also was the first major relief bill to get directly to counties, because here is what I learned when I was a county councilman: If you get money for &#8212; for the state, what happens is it goes through the state legislature.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;And guess what?&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughs.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, I wanted to make sure the money goes directly to the counties.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Directly to the counties &#8212; no, really.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;We allocated $350 billion to state and local budgets.&nbsp;&nbsp;We made sure that $1 billion [$100 billion] of that went straight to the counties and cities.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;And look, I know how much it matters.&nbsp;&nbsp;It really matters giving you &#8212; giving you the ability, the flexibility, the control to meet both the short-term and long-term challenges you face.&nbsp; Which, by the way, even &#8212; and I &#8212; I&#8217;m not being critical of the state legislatures or to &#8212; or others, but people don’t know the full responsibility and &#8212; that you all have, even other elected officials.&nbsp; They &#8212; I mean, I&#8217;m not being solicitous.&nbsp; It’s just true.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, by the way, that Rescue Plan is still delivering.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I urge all of you to use the flexibility we built into the law and spend those funds wisely, to build a future around working people who make up the communities you run.&nbsp; Put these funds to work to keep people on the job, connect people with better jobs &#8212; providing retention bonuses for teachers and bus drivers, like Howard County, Maryland, did; adding healthcare centers and training new childcare workers, like &#8212; I hope I pronounce it &#8212; Deschutes County, Oregon.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; where are you, Deschutes County?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, what you did matters.&nbsp;<br><br>Helping unemployed parents get back to work by covering childcare costs, like Oakland County, Michigan, did.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Reducing gun crime by retaining police officers, like DeKalb County did in Georgia.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Expanding community violence intervention programs, like King County did in Washington.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ensuring people get the full benefit of one of the most consequential tax cuts for working families in our history.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We expanded the Childcare Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit included in the Rescue Plan.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the past, if you paid taxes and you had a good income, you could deduct $2,000 per child.&nbsp; So if you&#8217;re making 200 grand a year and you have three kids, you got to deduct 6,000 bucks off your &#8212; off the taxes you owed.&nbsp; Well, that’s fair.<br><br>But guess what?&nbsp; If you were making minimum wage and you had four kids, you didn’t get anything.&nbsp; It wasn’t refundable.&nbsp; You didn’t pay $8,000 in taxes.&nbsp; There wasn’t what &#8212; you couldn’t re- &#8212; you couldn’t reduce your taxes.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So we made sure it was refundable.&nbsp; Because guess what?&nbsp; It’s just as hard for a firefighter or a teacher or a cop who has the benefit of that tax break to raise his kids as for a wealthy person to raise their kid.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>No, and &#8212; and by the way, it’s not a criticism of the wealthy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just to think about it.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; It was well intended originally when &#8212; when the Childcare Tax Credit &#8212; when the Child Tax Credit existed early on.&nbsp; Because you said, “Well, we got to give a break for raising kids.”<br><br>But I remember it used to drive my dad nuts, because we had four kids.&nbsp; It was a lot less.&nbsp; It was less than a thou- &#8212; it was 1,000 bucks then.&nbsp; But, you know, if you&#8217;re making what was 12,000 bucks a year &#8212; that was like making 40 now or 50 &#8212; if you&#8217;re making that kind of money, you didn&#8217;t have any taxes you could deduct it from, so there wasn&#8217;t any benefit for your kids.<br><br>Look, that&#8217;s why the American Rescue Plan &#8212; we didn&#8217;t expand the amount &#8212; well, we expanded the amount, but I &#8212; even if we don&#8217;t expand the amount &#8212; middle-class tax cut &#8212; we made it refundable.&nbsp; So you get paid back what you would’ve had to pay, which you got to deduct if you made more money.&nbsp; So the money you &#8212; go directly into your pocket, helping with your kids.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why I’m so thankful for counties like Salt Lake County and Miami-Dade County &#8212; created programs to help lower-income folks who typically don’t even file taxes because they&#8217;re below minimum wage or don’t have any income to get the assistance they need but they have to file in order to get the assistance.<br><br>You all reached out and said, “Look, you have a benefit coming, but you got to file taxes.”&nbsp; And you helped them do it.&nbsp; You &#8212; and I used to have a friend who was a great basketball player back in the days when Providence had great teams &#8212; Providence College.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>No, I mean, they had &#8212; they had some superstars at the time.&nbsp;&nbsp;His name was Pete McLaughlin, and he wasn’t the &#8212; he passed away.&nbsp;&nbsp;But he wasn&#8217;t the &#8212; he used to say &#8212; he wasn’t the sharpest academic candle on the table, but he knew what was going on.&nbsp;&nbsp;And he knew how to &#8212; he said, you know &#8212; he had an expression: “You got to know how to know.”&nbsp;&nbsp;I can take you into the greatest library in the world, the Library of Congress; if you don&#8217;t know how to read the card catalog, it’s useless to you.&nbsp;&nbsp;You got to know how to know.<br><br>So, you’re helping people know how to know how to get inter- &#8212; what they need.&nbsp;&nbsp;And it&#8217;s all about making sure people [who] have more economic difficulty raising their families can finally get a benefit that wealthier people get in the tax burdens and the Child Tax Credit.<br><br>But, look, another thing that funding can support, thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill, is jobs.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to create millions &#8212; several million jobs.&nbsp; Folks, look, it took a long time and a lot of administration, but we finally passed a Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill.&nbsp; Everybody.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we finally ended “Infrastructure Week.”&nbsp; We got something done.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Everybody knew America was falling behind in infrastructure.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; After years of dead ends and broken promises, we came together &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; and we did something about it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not only has Infrastructure Week finally arrived, we can look forward to an infrastructure decade; that’s what this is for 10 years.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Just 92 &#8212; just 92 days after I signed the law, it’s already making a tangible difference.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We announced billions of funding allocations to put people to work in good-paying jobs cleaning up rivers in Ohio, chemical plants in Florida, and dozens of other sites; bolstering the energy grid with a stronger transmission lines and towers; modernizing bridges like the one I visited in Grafton County up in New Hampshire, where the weight restrictions could force school buses and firetrucks to go 10 miles out of their way to get on the other side of the river; and capping and plugging tens of thousands of orphaned oil wells and gas wells that continue to spew methane, which is a &#8212; deadly for the environment.&nbsp; Creating jobs as good as the folks who dug those wells in the first place with the same salaries.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This is only the beginning.&nbsp; Hundreds of billions in new investments are on the way.&nbsp; Now it’s time for the counties to get ready.&nbsp; You don’t have to wait until the projects start.&nbsp; You can use the resources from the American Rescue Plan now.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re going to need welders, pipefitters, advanced manufacturers ready to take on those jobs.&nbsp; And it takes training to do those jobs well, and that’s why union workers are the best in the world, because they actually get the job done cheaper because they don’t waste any time.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>But you can start &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I know you all know, but you can start those Rescue Plan funds now by building pathways to better jobs through union-based apprentice programs and on-the-job training.&nbsp; Like, you know, Maricopa County in Arizona, where they’re using American Rescue Plan funds to help young workers develop in-demand technical skills so you know what the country is going to need.&nbsp; Community colleges are doing it as well.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Boone County, Campbell County, Kenton County, Kentucky, where you’re expanding high-speed Internet to nearly 100,000 homes and businesses.<br><br>You know, how many times did you ride by a McDonald&#8217;s parking lot in the middle of the pandemic and see people out there sitting &#8212; a mom and dad &#8212; tying into the network so their kids could do their homework remotely?&nbsp; This is the United States of America, for God&#8217;s sake.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Cook County, Illinois, where you’re using Rescue Plan funds to work with the Southland Metals Hub, helping workers prepare to take on manufacturing and infrastructure jobs and strengthening the supply chains in the Heartland.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Rescue Plan funds we delivered to your count- &#8212; to your counties, they can help each of you build a strong, diverse workforce you’ll need to take up and take on these infrastructure jobs so that we’re &#8212; there are &#8212; more families can deal themselves into this booming economy.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The truth is, we have an incredible opportunity ahead of us.&nbsp; And that’s not hyperbole; we really do.&nbsp; We still have a lot of work to do to put together we’ve &#8212; we’ve proven that we can get big things done in this country bipartisanly.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we all know the challenges still remain.&nbsp; We’re still fighting a deadly virus.&nbsp; We still need more people to get vaccinated and boosted.&nbsp;<br><br>But thanks to our &#8212; your partnership, we’ve gone from 2 million people vaccinated, when I got elected, to 215 million people vaccinated.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;And &#8212; and, again, I’m not being solicitous.&nbsp;&nbsp;You’ve been critical partners since day one on masking, texing [sic] &#8212; testing, and vas- &#8212; vaccinations, standing strong against misinformation, and sometimes even withstanding shameful personal attacks.&nbsp;&nbsp;Through it all, you’ve led with patriotism and resolve.&nbsp;&nbsp;And you’ve saved lives.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Another challenge we face is eading- [sic] the &#8212; easing the burden on working families.&nbsp; This &#8212; there’s real inflation.&nbsp; And if you’re in a working-class family, it hurts.&nbsp; That’s why my Build Back Better plan &#8212; what it’s all about.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, families are getting clobbered by the cost of everyday things.&nbsp; You know, I know that gas and food prices are up; we’re working to bring them down.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I grew up in a family where the price at the pump was felt in the kitchen.&nbsp; Everybody knew.&nbsp; Everybody felt it.&nbsp; I understand.&nbsp; These are necessities, but they’re not the totality of what a family needs.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, while we work on supply chains and we work on bringing down the costs of the things that we’re talking about have gone up so high, we still have other ways we can reduce the burden on working-class families.&nbsp;<br><br>They still have to pay for childcare.&nbsp; Families can spend as much as $14,000 a year in some parts of the country for childcare.&nbsp; My plan: The cost of childcare for working families will cost 7 percent of your income.&nbsp; No more.&nbsp; And that helps millions of parents, especially women, get back to work.&nbsp; Twenty million of them are not working now.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, by the way, it ends up paying for itself when they’re back to work paying taxes.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, we still pay for &#8212; we still have to pay for prescription drugs.&nbsp; You want to benefit a family? &nbsp;Reduce the cost of the prescription drugs they have to pay.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>In America &#8212; in America, we pay the highest price for prescription drugs in the world &#8212; of any developed nation in the world.&nbsp; About two to three times what other countries pay.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me give you a &#8212; I can give you hundreds of examples; I’m giving you one.&nbsp; One anti-cancer drug to treat leukemia and lymphoma that costs $14,000 a month in the United States &#8212; that same exact drug, by the same drug company &#8212; the same company &#8212; that drug sold in France costs $6,000.&nbsp; Six thousand dollars.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Those of you who live on the Canadian border &#8212; you know, when you cross the border, you can buy the same drug for a hell of a lot less than you can buy in the United States.&nbsp; Same manufacturer.<br><br>Or take insulin: The costs of drug companies to provide insulin &#8212; a vial of insulin &#8212; costs less than $10 to make.&nbsp; But there are many families, like families I met last week in Culpeper, Virginia, paying $300 per vial for medicine they need every single day for Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; If they have good healthcare coverage &#8212; this family does &#8212; but they still have to pay $5,600 for prescriptions before their insurance kicks in.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Think about that: 200,000 American children with Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; Think about being one of those parents.&nbsp; “We don’t have insurance.”&nbsp; But you know your child, to live, needs that insulin.&nbsp; How do you look that child in the eye when you don’t have the income&nbsp;or you don’t have &#8212; you don’t have the insurance?&nbsp; What do you do?<br><br>Not only do you worry if your child may die, but you’re stripped of your dignity.&nbsp; You’re stripped of your sense of who you are, not being able to afford that child’s needs.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, we can cap the cost of insulin to $35 a month.&nbsp; Drug companies will still make money.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Now, let me digress just for a moment.&nbsp; I started the Cancer Moonshot, which I worked very hard on in the administration &#8212; the administration I served in last.&nbsp; And I held conferences all over the country with literally thousands of people and, at the same time, doing it virtually.&nbsp; And after one of them, I got the 12 largest drug companies in one room.&nbsp;&nbsp;And I said, “If you found a cure for a particular cancer” &#8212; and I named a cancer &#8212; I said, “What amount of money do you think you should be able to charge for that drug?”&nbsp;&nbsp;They said, “Whatever the market will bear.”&nbsp;<br><br>And I said, “Well, you know, many places, like Germany, you can get and make sure you make a profit that’s 20 to 30 percent &#8212; even 40 percent &#8212; more than your total investment.&nbsp;&nbsp; But once they set the price, that’s the only price you can pay to sell that drug.&nbsp; You still make 30, 40 percent profit after all your expenses you demonstrate.&nbsp; And the other provision is you can’t increase the price for that drug beyond the cost of inflation unless you’ve done additional work on the drug to improve it.”</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Think about where we’re going.&nbsp; We’re on the &#8212; we’re on the verge &#8212; thank God &#8212; of some significant breakthroughs in healthcare.&nbsp; But should it be based upon what you can afford to pay?&nbsp; If Congress acts, we could take care of things with the stroke of a pen tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have a generation of so-called “sandwich generation” &#8212; many of you are part of it &#8212; trying to take care of your children while taking care of your aging mom or dad.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We can help make it work &#8212; care for our elderly parents and have someone install a handrail in the shower, make sure they have steps that they can get up and down, someone can pick up their prescriptions while you’re working, and allow them to continue to live in the dignity of their home.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; That saves a hell of a lot of money, because the cost of that &#8212; and by the way, that’s available under Medicare now, except 880,000 people don’t &#8212; can’t get into the program yet.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s a lot cheaper to have mom and dad live at home with minimal expense than have the public pick up the cost of healthcare &#8212; of housing for the elderly.&nbsp; We can do all that and still save money so when they put their head on the pillow at night, they can have peace of mind.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m going to work like the devil to bring gas prices down.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we’re going to keep working to strengthen supply chains to bring the cost of every good down, particularly food and automobiles.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you know the best news of all of this?&nbsp; Nobody earning less than $400,000 a year will pay an additional penny in taxes for any of these services.&nbsp; We can do it without increasing the deficit.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As a matter of fact, last year, we reduced the deficit by $300 billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But by passing the elements of the Build Back Better plan, which reduced the burden on families, I got a letter from 17 Nobel laureates &#8212; came to me to say this plan, my plan, will ease long-term inflationary pressures.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, we can tackle these challenges, but only if we keep coming together.&nbsp; The fact is: We can’t do it without you.&nbsp; You understand what families are up against.&nbsp; You understand the cost if we fail to act.&nbsp; We need your voices, of the county officials, helping us &#8212; folks understand what our communities need.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If we can get this done, there’s no limit to what America can achieve.&nbsp; So let’s g- &#8212; let’s give working people a better chance than they’ve had, a quality they deserve, by investing in the future of every county.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let’s face these challenges head on, but let’s keep building back better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re the only country in the world where whatever crisis we’ve gone through, we’ve ended up on the other side better off than we were before we got into the crisis.&nbsp; We’re the only one.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And folks, let me say one other thing: I had a group of eight major utilities come to see me to tell me they wanted to see the Build Back Better plan put in place, even though they knew they were going to pay higher taxes; corporate taxes could go up to 24 percent.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, there are &#8212; of the major Fortune 500 companies, there are 52 that made over $40 billion, didn’t pay a single penny in tax.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; I know &#8212; I think you should be able to go out and make a million or a billion dollars if you have the capability, but just pay a little bit.&nbsp; Pay your fair share.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I’m serious.&nbsp; I’m serious.&nbsp; And that’s why we’re getting so much support for the things we’re doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why, for example &#8212; and it’s major corporations coming to us.&nbsp; For example, you ride through some fields in Iowa &#8212; I mean, excuse me, Ohio, and it looks like there’s nothing there except beautiful land stretched out.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; An outfit called Intel came to me and said, “We want to invest $20 billion in those fields, creating 7,600 jobs to build a facility and 3,500 jobs permanent; average salary of those permanent jobs, $135,000 a year.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know what they’re doing?&nbsp; They’re going to make computer chips, because there are no &#8212; you know, one third of inflation is a consequence of the cost of automobiles going up.&nbsp; Why are they going up?&nbsp; We invented the computer chip, but we don&#8217;t make it.&nbsp; We have to get it from &#8212; everyone from Taiwan to China to other places.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, we can do this.&nbsp; We can do this by reasserting who, in God&#8217;s name, we are: the United States of America.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing &#8212; I mean this from the bottom of my heart &#8212; there&#8217;s nothing beyond our capacity.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing we cannot do if we do it together.&nbsp; That&#8217;s always been who we are.&nbsp;<br><br>This is the United States of America.&nbsp; You can make a million bucks and still pay your fair share.&nbsp; And everybody &#8212; when have you ever seen &#8212; I was talking to somebody.&nbsp; I said, “You know, you go through…&#8221;&nbsp; Neighboring state of New Jersey, from Delaware &#8212; my area is down by the shore.&nbsp; You ride through an intersection where there&#8217;s a big circle and there are four or five roads coming off of it.&nbsp; And usually in the middle of that circle, there&#8217;s plant &#8212; you can &#8212; you know, you can plant trees and flowers and the like.&nbsp;<br><br>I can tell you the communities &#8212; and I said this to somebody and then they showed me a study that it was true.&nbsp; I can tell you whether the community has renters or owners.&nbsp; When they&#8217;re owners, that middle circle is beautiful; it&#8217;s planted.&nbsp; When they&#8217;re renters, they&#8217;re not.&nbsp; Doesn’t mean there’s anything wrong with renting, but it means engaging in the community.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, folks, when middle-class folks do well, there&#8217;s never been a time the wealthy don&#8217;t do very, very well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; So, folks, let’s stick to the people we need.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you for listening to me.&nbsp; May God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>1:48 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Department of Defense Releases New Report on Safeguarding our National Security by Promoting Competition in the Defense Industrial&#160;Base</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/15/fact-sheet-department-of-defense-releases-new-report-on-safeguarding-our-national-security-by-promoting-competition-in-the-defense-industrial-base/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of President Biden’s whole-of-government approach to promoting competition, the Department of Defense (DoD) released a new report today on the state of competition in the defense industrial base. The report surveys the state of competition across key defense sectors and finds that extreme consolidation poses risks to our nation’s national and economic security.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As part of President Biden’s whole-of-government approach to promoting competition, the Department of Defense (DoD) released a new report today on the state of competition in the defense industrial base. The report surveys the state of competition across key defense sectors and finds that extreme consolidation poses risks to our nation’s national and economic security. The report emphasizes that promoting competition is a top priority for DoD and outlines a series of actions that DoD will pursue to rebuild its competitive bench, lower costs for taxpayers, and safeguard our national security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The term “defense industrial base” (DIB) describes the vast network of companies that provide goods and services to DoD. These companies make up a significant part of our economy, ranging from small businesses and startups to some of the biggest corporations in the world. They provide products ranging from intercontinental ballistic missiles and highly specialized military satellites to everyday commercial products like batteries and laptops.</p>



<p>The report observes that extreme consolidation in the defense sector has reduced competition and heightened national security risks. Since the 1990s, the number of aerospace and defense prime contractors has shrunk from 51 to just 5. The same pattern has played out across categories of major weapons systems: for example, today, 90% of missiles come from 3 sources. Such consolidation leaves DoD increasingly reliant on a handful of companies for critical defense capabilities. It also hurts taxpayers, as companies no longer feel the competitive pressure to innovate or perform at the highest level to win contracts.</p>



<p>The report also emphasizes the need to rebuild DoD’s competitive bench by lowering barriers for small businesses and bringing in new entrants. Small businesses spur innovation, producing 16.5 times more patents than large firms, and form the next generation of suppliers to support the DoD mission. However, the number of small businesses in the DIB shrunk by over 40% over the past decade. Without action, DoD could lose an additional 15,000 suppliers over the next decade—a national security and economic risk that threatens key domestic capabilities. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The report outlines five lines of effort to achieve the goals of President Biden’s Executive Order on Promoting Competition in the American Economy, confront the challenges posed by industry consolidation, and ensure sufficient domestic capacity and capability in the defense industrial base:</p>



<ul><li><em>Strengthening Merger Oversight.</em> DoD faces a historically consolidated DIB, making careful attention by DoD in the review of any further mergers necessary. When a merger threatens DoD interests, DoD will support the Federal Trade Commission and Department of Justice in antitrust investigations and recommendations involving the DIB.<br></li><li><em>Addressing Intellectual Property Limitations</em>. Certain practices surrounding intellectual property (IP) and data rights have been used to limit competition in DoD purchasing. In its ongoing modernization of its approach to IP rights, DoD should remain conscious of potential unnecessary anticompetitive consequences of any new IP-related procedures do what it can to create IP-related procedures that do not result in unnecessary anticompetitive consequences.<br></li><li><em>Increasing New Entrants</em>. To counteract the trend of overall shrinking of the DIB, DoD should endeavor to attract new entrants to the defense marketplace by reducing barriers to entry. That includes through small business outreach, support, and use of acquisition authorities that provide DoD the flexibility to reduce barriers and attract new vendors.<br></li><li><em>Increasing Opportunities for Small Businesses</em>. DoD should increase small business participation in defense procurement, including with small disadvantaged businesses, women-owned small businesses, service disabled veteran owned small businesses, and HUBZone businesses, with an emphasis on increasing competition in priority industrial base sectors.<br></li><li><em>Implementing Sector-specific Supply Chain Resilience Plans</em>: DoD should take steps to ensure resilience in the supply chain for five priority sectors: casting and forgings, missiles and munitions, energy storage and batteries, strategic and critical materials, and microelectronics.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Advances Cleaner Industrial Sector to Reduce Emissions and Reinvigorate American&#160;Manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-advances-cleaner-industrial-sector-to-reduce-emissions-and-reinvigorate-american-manufacturing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Pro-Climate, Pro-Worker Actions Create Jobs and Harness the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, Federal Purchasing Power, and Trade Policy Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new actions across agencies to support American leadership on clean manufacturing—including low-carbon production of the steel and aluminum we need for electric vehicles, wind turbines, and solar panels, and the clean&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>New Pro-Climate, Pro-Worker Actions Create Jobs and Harness the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, Federal Purchasing Power, and Trade Policy</em></p>



<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new actions across agencies to support American leadership on clean manufacturing—including low-carbon production of the steel and aluminum we need for electric vehicles, wind turbines, and solar panels, and the clean concrete we need to upgrade our transportation infrastructure. These actions will create more good-paying jobs and follow on a historic comeback for American factories, with <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/MANEMP">367,000</a> manufacturing jobs added during President Biden’s first year in office, the most in nearly 30 years. Further strengthening our industrial base will revitalize local economies, lower prices for consumers, provide more pathways to the middle class through union jobs, and boost American competitiveness in global markets.&nbsp;<br><br>The industrial sector is also central to tackling the climate crisis, as it is currently responsible for nearly a third of domestic greenhouse gas emissions. By helping manufacturers use clean energy, efficiency upgrades, and other innovative technologies to reduce emissions, the Administration is supporting cleaner industry that can produce the next generation of products and materials for a net-zero economy. These same manufacturing improvements will also protect public health, by reducing releases of air and water pollutants and toxic materials that disproportionately harm low-income households and communities of color.<br><br>Today’s announcements will clean up industrial processes that have long been challenging sources of pollution; create good-paying, union jobs across American manufacturing; and use domestic procurement and global trade policy to reward clean, American-made materials:</p>



<ul><li>The Department of Energy is launching<strong> major clean hydrogen initiatives of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</strong>: $8 billion for Regional Clean Hydrogen Hubs that will create jobs to expand use of clean hydrogen in the industrial sector and beyond; $1 billion for a Clean Hydrogen Electrolysis Program to reduce costs of hydrogen produced from clean electricity; and $500 million for Clean Hydrogen Manufacturing and Recycling Initiatives to support equipment manufacturing and strong domestic supply chains.<br></li><li>The Council on Environmental Quality and White House Office of Domestic Climate Policy are establishing the <strong>first-ever Buy Clean Task Force</strong>, which will harness the federal government’s massive purchasing power to support low-carbon materials made in American factories. The General Services Administration and the Department of Transportation are also announcing new efforts to promote use of l<strong>ow-carbon materials in construction projects funded by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</strong>, and the State Department and U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate are securing corporate purchasing commitments for low-carbon materials and technologies through the <strong>First Movers Coalition</strong>.<br></li><li>The Administration is advancing<strong> carbon-based trade policies to reward American manufacturers of clean steel and aluminum</strong>. Working with the European Union, the Administration is taking steps to align global trade with climate goals, which will keep out dirty products and result in more jobs and lower prices for Americans.<br></li><li>The Council on Environmental Quality is issuing new <strong>guidance on responsible deployment of Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Sequestration (CCUS)</strong> technologies that can reduce emissions from heavy industry and help us achieve a net-zero economy. This guidance will support CCUS projects that create union jobs and protect communities from cumulative pollution impacts. Actions by agencies will incorporate environmental justice considerations across CCUS activities.&nbsp;<br></li><li>To equitably advance innovation across the entire sector, the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy is launching a new <strong>Initiative for Interdisciplinary Industrial Decarbonization Research</strong> with a focus on benefitting American workers and communities. The Department of Energy is working to establish the <strong>Industrial Technology Innovation Advisory Committee (ITIAC)</strong> to bring together a diverse group of stakeholders charged with creating a comprehensive strategy to lower the carbon footprint of America’s industrial base.</li></ul>



<p>These actions and continued implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will reduce climate pollution from industrial facilities, while growing the economy and creating jobs in producing clean materials—which customers around the world are increasingly demanding.<br><br>With a strong foundation in place from today’s announcements, the President’s Build Back Better agenda will further boost clean manufacturing and American competitiveness for decades to come, by supporting low-carbon processes across our industrial base; driving long-term investment in our clean steel, cement, and aluminum industries; and increasing domestic production of electric vehicles, wind turbines, solar panels, and more. Earlier this month, the House passed the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/04/statement-from-president-biden-on-house-passage-of-the-america-competes-act/">America COMPETES Act</a>, which would strengthen supply chains, lower prices, and create more manufacturing jobs, while decarbonizing the industrial sector—including through a $250 million Regional Clean Energy Innovation Program and new programs to decarbonize American steel.</p>



<p>Specifically, today the Administration is announcing new efforts on:<br><br><strong>Accelerating Clean Hydrogen</strong><br><br>Clean hydrogen can reduce emissions in many sectors of the economy, and is especially important for hard-to-decarbonize sectors and industrial processes, such as steel manufacturing. But clean hydrogen is not yet in widespread use. Targeted investments can help reduce costs, make new breakthroughs, and create jobs for American engineers, factory workers, construction workers, and others.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>To seize those opportunities, today the Department of Energy (DOE) is launching three major new initiatives of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law by issuing Requests for Information:</p>



<ul><li><strong>$8 billion for </strong><a href="https://eere-exchange.energy.gov/Default.aspx#FoaId5d96172f-e9b6-48ff-94ac-5579c3531526"><strong>Regional Clean Hydrogen Hubs</strong></a><strong>:</strong> DOE will support development of networks of clean hydrogen producers, potential consumers, and connective infrastructure. These regional hubs will advance the production, processing, delivery, storage, and end-use of clean hydrogen, including innovative uses in the industrial sector. DOE will prioritize hubs that can provide significant training and long-term job opportunities for residents of the region.<br></li><li><strong>$1 billion for a </strong><a href="https://eere-exchange.energy.gov/Default.aspx#FoaIda1255029-22c4-4c18-9e90-356e92cbb795"><strong>Clean Hydrogen Electrolysis Program</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Electrolysis (using electricity to split water into hydrogen and oxygen) allows for clean hydrogen production from carbon pollution-free power sources like wind, solar, and nuclear. This program will improve the efficiency and cost-effectiveness of these technologies, by supporting the entire innovation chain—from research, development, and demonstration to commercialization, and deployment.<br></li><li><strong>$500 million for </strong><a href="https://eere-exchange.energy.gov/Default.aspx#FoaIda1255029-22c4-4c18-9e90-356e92cbb795"><strong>Clean Hydrogen Manufacturing and Recycling RD&amp;D Activities</strong></a><strong>:</strong> DOE will also support American manufacturing of clean hydrogen equipment, including projects that improve efficiency and cost-effectiveness and support domestic supply chains for key components, through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s Clean Hydrogen Manufacturing Initiative. DOE is also launching Clean Hydrogen Technology Recycling Research, Development, and Demonstration activities, to fund innovative approaches to increase the reuse and recycling of clean hydrogen technologies.</li></ul>



<p>These Requests for Information will gather feedback from stakeholders and communities on future implementation and priorities for DOE to consider as it moves forward with maximizing the benefits of the historic clean hydrogen programs in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br><br>To further support DOE’s Hydrogen Shot to reduce the cost of clean hydrogen by 80% to $1 for one kilogram in one decade, last week DOE <a href="https://www.energy.gov/fecm/articles/us-department-energy-announces-28-million-develop-clean-hydrogen">announced</a> $28 million for R&amp;D and front-end engineering design projects to advance clean hydrogen in industrial uses, as well as the transportation and electricity sectors. DOE’s new <a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/fuelcells/h2-matchmaker"><strong>H2 Matchmaker</strong></a> resource is helping clean hydrogen producers, end-users, and others find opportunities to develop networks of production, storage, and transportation infrastructure. H2 Matchmaker displays a map using information received through an online form, which stakeholders can use to connect with others nearby.<br><br>The Administration’s <strong>Interagency Working Group on Coal and Power Plant Communities and Economic Revitalization</strong> is bringing together stakeholders from across the private sector, philanthropy, labor, and community-based organizations to catalyze new job opportunities for energy communities, including in clean hydrogen. For example, a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/15/readout-of-investment-roundtable-hosted-by-the-interagency-working-group-on-coal-and-power-plant-communities-and-economic-revitalization/">December roundtable</a> included discussion of efforts to reduce emissions and create jobs in the South Louisiana industrial corridor. The region is a finalist in the Economic Development Administration’s Build Back Better Regional Challenge. An initial grant will help them continue to plan their clean hydrogen cluster, and they are eligible to apply for a Phase 2 implementation grant.<br><br><strong>Launching “Buy Clean” Procurement</strong></p>



<p>The federal government is the largest purchaser in the world, with annual purchasing power of over $650 billion. To harness that power to support low-carbon, made in America materials, the Council on Environmental Quality and White House Office of Domestic Climate Policy are establishing the first-ever Buy Clean Task Force. As directed by the President’s December 2021 <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-catalyzing-americas-clean-energy-economy-through-federal-sustainability/">executive order</a> on federal sustainability, the Task Force will promote use of construction materials with lower embodied emissions and pollutants across their lifecycle—including each stage of the manufacturing process.</p>



<p>Other members include the Departments of Defense, Energy, and Transportation; the Environmental Protection Agency; the General Services Administration; and the White House Office of Management and Budget. The Task Force, which will continue to expand, is convening to develop recommendations on:</p>



<ul><li>Identifying materials, such as steel and concrete, as well as pollutants to prioritize for consideration in Federal procurement and federally funded projects</li><li>Increasing the transparency of embodied emissions through supplier reporting, including incentives and technical assistance to help domestic manufacturers better report and reduce embodied emissions</li><li>Launching pilot programs to boost federal procurement of clean construction materials&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>With the Buy Clean Task Force now established, the federal government is at the leading edge of using public procurement to increase demand for cleanly manufactured materials, along with states including California, Colorado, Minnesota, New York, and Washington.</p>



<p>Buy Clean efforts are already well underway at the General Services Administration (GSA), which manages a nationwide federal real estate portfolio and oversees approximately $75 billion in annual contracts. Over the past year, GSA has actively engaged stakeholders to learn and adopt best practices for reducing embodied emissions of buildings and materials. Today, GSA <a href="https://www.gsa.gov/about-us/newsroom/news-releases/gsa-announces-actions-to-reduce-emissions-from-building-materials-02152022">is issuing Requests for Information</a> (RFIs) focused on concrete and asphalt. In the coming weeks, GSA will use the RFI responses to shape the launch of <strong>national low-carbon concrete and sustainable asphalt standards for Land Port of Entry projects funded by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. </strong>This groundbreaking effort may include requiring Environmental Product Declarations (disclosing lifecycle impacts) and the use of concrete with at least 20% lower global warming potential, whenever available.</p>



<p>The Department of Transportation (DOT) is announcing new efforts to support <strong>use of low-carbon materials in federal transportation projects</strong>. A new pilot program will target key products and services to increase use of Environmental Product Declarations and incentivize acquisition of low-carbon materials. Additionally, DOT is standing up a Department-wide Embodied Carbon Working Group to assess and implement actions to reduce lifecycle emissions of construction materials used in transportation infrastructure.</p>



<p>The Administration is also bringing together large corporate purchasers to Buy Clean. At COP26, President Biden launched the <strong>First Movers Coalition</strong>, with 34 companies valued at $6 trillion—the biggest demand signal in history for innovation across hard-to-abate sectors, including heavy industry. Led by the State Department through the U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate and the World Economic Forum, and supported by the Departments of Commerce and Energy, the First Movers Coalition is making clean purchasing commitments, beginning with steel, shipping, trucking, and aviation. Today, the Administration is announcing plans to <strong>expand the First Movers Coalition to cover four additional sectors in 2022: aluminum, cement, chemicals, and carbon removal.</strong><br><br>The Administration is also <strong>mobilizing investment in the production of clean technologies</strong> by the Department of Energy, including the Loan Programs Office, the Department of Commerce, and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, as well as through a partnership between the First Movers Coalition and the Breakthrough Energy Catalyst. The First Movers Coalition will recruit additional companies and launch challenge competitions for suppliers to provide the breakthrough technologies that members have committed to purchase.<br><br><strong>Using Trade Policy to Reward Clean Manufacturing<br></strong><br>In October, the United States and the European Union <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/10/31/fact-sheet-the-united-states-and-european-union-to-negotiate-worlds-first-carbon-based-sectoral-arrangement-on-steel-and-aluminum-trade/">announced</a> their commitment to negotiate the <strong>world’s first emissions-based sectoral arrangement on steel and aluminum trade</strong> by 2024. Following on that announcement, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai, and senior White House officials are continuing to work with European Union counterparts on this unprecedented effort—never before have two global partners aligned their trade policies to confront the threats of climate change and global market distortions, ensuring that trade works to solve the challenges of the 21st century.<br><br>Together, the United States and European Union are working to restrict access to their markets for dirty steel and limit access to countries that dump steel in both markets, contributing to worldwide over-supply. The arrangement will be open to any interested country that wishes to join and meets criteria for restoring market orientation and reducing trade in high-emissions steel and aluminum products. It will thus drive investment in green steel and aluminum production in the United States, Europe, and around the world, ensuring a competitive U.S. steel and aluminum industry for decades to come.<br><br><strong>Responsibly Advancing CCUS Technologies</strong></p>



<p>Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Sequestration (CCUS) refers to technologies that remove carbon pollution from point sources like smokestacks, or from the ambient air, and permanently store the carbon. In factories, CCUS can reduce emissions from chemical reactions and high-temperature processes that are difficult and expensive to electrify. The best scientific analyses also find that to achieve a net-zero economy, we will need to remove carbon pollution that has already been released in the atmosphere. While CCUS can be an important tool in tackling the climate crisis, the benefits and impacts of potential projects vary significantly—requiring careful planning and oversight to ensure deployment is safe, equitable, and environmentally sound.<br><br>To help federal agencies advance CCUS responsibly, today <strong>the Council on Environmental Quality is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2022/02/15/ceq-issues-new-guidance-to-responsibly-develop-carbon-capture-utilization-and-sequestration/">issuing CCUS guidance</a>.</strong> This guidance, called for in the bipartisan USE IT Act, builds on CEQ’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2021/06/30/council-on-environmental-quality-delivers-report-to-congress-on-steps-to-advance-responsible-orderly-and-efficient-development-of-carbon-capture-utilization-and-sequestration/">June 2021 CCUS report</a> and addresses issues including:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Sound and transparent environmental reviews for CCUS projects</li><li>Incorporation of environmental justice and equity considerations to protect overburdened communities from any direct, indirect, and cumulative impacts</li><li>Meaningful public engagement and Tribal consultations from early in the process</li><li>Opportunities to create good-paying, union jobs and training programs</li><li>Life cycle analyses of carbon capture and utilization (CCU) and carbon dioxide removal (CDR) projects</li></ul>



<p>As agencies prepare to implement more than $12 billion in CCUS investments provided by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, this guidance will promote projects informed by community perspectives and aligned with climate, public health, and economic goals.<br><br>To further support responsible deployment:</p>



<ul><li>The Environmental Protection Agency is developing proposed rule revisions to <strong>strengthen the Greenhouse Gas Reporting Program to improve transparency on CCUS activities.</strong> This Program collects and publishes annual greenhouse gas data from large industrial sources, and the proposed updates would add reporting requirements for direct air capture and carbon storage.</li><li>To <strong>train a racially diverse, highly skilled generation of engineers and scientists for carbon management roles</strong>, DOE is announcing $5 million for university training and research projects, including $2 million for Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) and other Minority Serving Institutions (MSIs).</li><li>The Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council and its member agencies are working together to facilitate <strong>collaborative CCUS project reviews</strong>.</li><li>The Department of the Interior is working to <strong>establish safeguards for geologic sequestration</strong> on federally managed lands and is developing new regulations for geologic sequestration in the outer continental shelf as required under the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting Equitable Innovation Across the Industrial Sector</strong><br><br>Supporting the industrial sector to achieve net-zero emissions will provide benefits to communities across the country. To ensure that innovations in this sector meet the needs of diverse stakeholders, the Administration is launching a <strong>new Initiative for Interdisciplinary Industrial Decarbonization Research</strong>. Led by the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), this Initiative will bring together social scientists, engineering and physical scientists, community groups, industry, government, and other stakeholders. As a first step, OSTP is convening a workshop to get advice from social science thought leaders about the research agenda needed to support rapid, widespread industrial decarbonization. This research will help build the consensus necessary to ensure a just transition to clean industry, with new, good-paying jobs for American workers and health and economic benefits for communities.<br><br>To identify and catalyze the next generation of breakthroughs, DOE’s Advanced Manufacturing Office is working to establish the <strong>Industrial Technology Innovation Advisory Committee (ITIAC)</strong>. This federal advisory committee will bring together a diverse cross-section of the industrial sector to find viable decarbonization pathways that will equitably benefit the industrial workforce and surrounding communities. DOE has also issued a <a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/amo/articles/department-energy-seeks-input-technology-pathways-decarbonize-americas-industrial"><strong>Request for Information on Industrial Decarbonization</strong></a>. This RFI will provide insights on emerging technologies for industry to demonstrate or adopt, including for clean production of iron and steel, cement, chemicals, and food and beverages. The Advanced Manufacturing Office will use this information to shape priorities for reducing industrial emissions and increasing competitiveness.<br><br>Additionally, DOE is helping manufacturers optimize use of energy and materials while training the workforce of the future through its Industrial Assessment Centers—which provide no-cost energy assessments conducted by university-based teams of engineering students and faculty. <strong>Through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, DOE will expand the Industrial Assessment Centers program</strong> by offering specialized training to staff and students and increasing access to innovation and workforce development opportunities, particularly in disadvantaged communities. These actions build on a year of progress—in 2021, DOE’s Advanced Manufacturing Office <a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/amo/articles/amo-year-review-clean-energy-future-made-america">invested</a> more than $332 million in industrial technical assistance, education and workforce development, and R&amp;D at every stage of the supply chain.<br><br>The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is also partnering with manufacturers through the ENERGY STAR program, which challenges and supports industrial plants in improving energy efficiency and reducing greenhouse gas emissions. EPA is now <strong>expanding ENERGY STAR by incorporating carbon intensity metrics </strong>for certain industries. Going forward, EPA will continue to increase ENERGY STAR’s focus on ambitious emissions reductions that support net-zero goals across the industrial sector.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine&#160;Jean-Pierre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/14/press-briefing-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 23:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:34 P.M. EST MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hey.&#160; Good afternoon, all. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Hello. MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Happy Valentine’s Day or Galentine’s Day &#8212; whatever you celebrate.&#160; Hope everyone had a restful &#8212; a restful time after a big game last night.&#160; I can attest, here from the podium, there were some very&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:34 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; Good afternoon, all.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Happy Valentine’s Day or Galentine’s Day &#8212; whatever you celebrate.&nbsp; Hope everyone had a restful &#8212; a restful time after a big game last night.&nbsp; I can attest, here from the podium, there were some very disappointed Bengals fans here last night.&nbsp; But we definitely wish and congratulate the Rams all the best from the city of &#8212; and the city of LA, for sure.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is something that just went out, so just in case you guys all &#8212; you all didn’t get it yet: So, President Biden spoke today with Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom.&nbsp; The leaders discussed their recent diplomatic engagements with Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; They also reviewed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia&#8217;s continued military buildup on Ukraine&#8217;s borders and reaffirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>



<p>They discussed efforts to reinforce the defensive posture on NATO&#8217;s eastern flank and underlined the continued, close coordination among Allies and partners, including on readiness to impose severe consequences on Russia should it choose further military escalation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I have a few more things for all of you at the top.</p>



<p>Today marks four years since the Parkland shooting.&nbsp; As the President said this morning in a statement that I&#8217;m sure all of you have seen, “We can never bring back those we&#8217;ve lost.&nbsp; But we can come together to fulfill the first responsibility of our government and our democracy: to keep each other safe.&nbsp; For Parkland, for all those we&#8217;ve lost, and for all those left behind, it is time to uphold that solemn obligation.”</p>



<p>Since his first day in office, the President has worked to uphold that obligation and to save lives by preventing gun violence.&nbsp; He again called on Congress this morning to act, including to expand background checks to keep criminals from getting guns and to ban the sort of high-capacity magazines that were used to kill two NYPD officers.</p>



<p>And the President called again on Congress to fulfill his budget request for another half billion dollars to fight gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if Congress won’t act, the President is not going to just wait and sit back.&nbsp; He&#8217;s already done more than any other president in their first year in history to advance commonsense gun violence prevention measures, and he built on that just earlier this month with new measures he announced in New York City.</p>



<p>Last June, he laid out a comprehensive strategy to address gun violence from every angle, and the White House is working closely with agencies across the administration to deliver on that and save lives.&nbsp; The plan is comprehensive, addressing both the supply and demand side contributors of &#8212; to gun violence; pursuing prevention, intervention, and accountability; using every tool in the toolkit &#8212; regulation, enforcement, budget, the bully pulpit, and legislation; and pulling together the federal agencies for a whole-of-government effort to reduce gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Specifically, we&#8217;re addressing the root causes of gun violence by expanding educational and economic opportunities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going after especially dangerous firearms with new proposed regulations on ghost guns and stabilizing braces that turned pistols into rifles.</p>



<p>We’re stepping up federal law enforcement efforts against illegal gun trafficking, including through strike forces in major cities, and establishing a zero-tolerance policy for gun dealers who willfully sell guns illegally.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re providing cities and states with unprecedented amounts of money, including through the Rescue Plan, to invest in community policing and effective community violence, interventio- &#8212; intervention programs, and <s>AFT</s> [ATF].</p>



<p>During an event at the White House today, Vice President Kamala Harris announced, alongside FCC Chairwoman Rols &#8212; Ros &#8212; Rosenworcel and Senior Advisor Mitch Landrieu, that more than 10 million households are enrolled in the Affordable Connectivity Program, the nation&#8217;s largest-ever broadband affordability program created through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; The Affordability Connectivity Program enables low-income households to apply for discounts towards monthly Internet service and a one-time discount on tech equipment such as laptops or computers.</p>



<p>This is one of the many ways that the Biden-Harris administration is ensuring every American has access to reliable, affordable high-speed Internet.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law delivers and a historic &#8212; an historic $65 billion to ensure that every American has access to reliable high-speed Internet through a &#8212; through an historic investment in broadband infrastructure development, that inten- &#8212; that Internet service is affordable by lowering costs, increasing competition, and creating price transparency.</p>



<p>With that, please go ahead, Darlene.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; A couple of questions on Ukraine and then one on another topic.&nbsp; What is the reaction here to the Kremlin signaling that it&#8217;s ready to continue dialogue over Ukraine?&nbsp; And does the White House see that as sincere on the part of the Russians?&nbsp; How do you interpret it?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So &#8212; yeah.&nbsp; Thank you for the question.&nbsp; We are actively working to reach a diplomatic solution to de-escalate the crisis.&nbsp; Over the weekend, as you all know, the President spoke with President Putin, and we remain engaged with the Russian government in full coordination with our Allies and partners.&nbsp; The path for diplomacy remains available if Russia chooses to engage constructively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, we are clear-eyed about the prospects of that, given the steps Russia is taking on the ground, in plain sight.&nbsp; This is something that the National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, talked about right here on Friday &#8212; right before eyes, what we&#8217;re seeing with Russia: A new Russian &#8212; we&#8217;re seeing new Russian forces have been arriving at the Ukrainian border every day.</p>



<p>As we have said before, we are in the window when an invasion could begin at any time.&nbsp; We will not comment on any details of our intelligence information except that &#8212; except to say that it could begin this week, despite a lot of speculation that it would happen after the Olympics &#8212; again, something that Jake Sullivan said right here on Friday.</p>



<p>It remains unclear which path Russia will choose to take.&nbsp; The U.S. is ready for any situation.&nbsp; You know, President Biden has made it very clear on his call with Putin this weekend that if Russia undertakes a further invasion of Ukraine, the United States, together with our Allies and partners, will respond decisively and impose swift and severe costs on Russia.</p>



<p>President Biden reiterated that a further Russian invasion of Ukraine would produce widespread human suffering and diminish Russia&#8217;s standing.</p>



<p>So we are continuing to coordinate closely with our Allies and partners.&nbsp; President Biden spoke with President Zelenskyy yesterday and Prime Minister Boris Johnson &#8212; as I just read out to you, that call &#8212; this afternoon.&nbsp; And we are in close contact with our Allies, again, and partners, again, across all levels of government.</p>



<p>Our partnership with our European and NATO Allies have never been stronger and purposeful as we work collectively to de-escalate the tensions at the Ukraine-Russia border.</p>



<p>If Russia should choose to invade, the severe economic consequences and irrevocable &#8212; irrevocable reputational damage caused by taking innocent lives for a bloody war will only weaken the country, not strengthen it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And in that close coordination with Allies and partners, is the view that Russia&#8217;s willingness &#8212; what they say today about wanting to continue the dialogue &#8212; do you &#8212; is there a consensus that is &#8212; that that is sincere?&nbsp; I mean, how do all of you interpret what&#8217;s coming out of the Kremlin today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve been very clear about this. There is only one country who is currently building up their forces at the Ukraine border, and that&#8217;s Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as we have stated, as Jake Sullivan has stated, that we &#8212; in the past 10 days or so, we only continue to see a buildup, not a de-escalation.</p>



<p>So we are open to diplomacy.&nbsp; That door to diplomacy is open, as we have said.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so, that is what we&#8217;re &#8212; that&#8217;s what we want to be headed towards.</p>



<p>And, you know, if &#8212; we will &#8212; we will be ready for whichever decision that President Putin decides.&nbsp; But clearly, we would &#8212; we would prefer the path of diplomacy.</p>



<p>I also want to just say one more thing really quickly.&nbsp; This is something that my colleague, Kirby, said &#8212; John Kirby said at the Department of Defense just now &#8212; that Secretary Austin is going to travel to Belgium, Poland, and Lithuania.&nbsp; So that you all have this.&nbsp; The Secretary is going to meet with Allied defense ministers and NATO leadership to discuss Russia&#8217;s military buildup in and around Ukraine, reiterate the U.S. commitment to Article 5, and continue the Alliance&#8217;s progress on deterrence and defense while ensuring the Alliance is prepared to face tomorrow&#8217;s challenges.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one last question.&nbsp; In two weeks, the President is going to go up to the Capitol to deliver his first State of the Union message.&nbsp; Can you give us a status report on preparations for that?&nbsp; Has he been able to meet with his advisors on it, given everything that&#8217;s going on, or edit speech drafts, or just you have some sort of idea where that process stands?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, this is a President who was Vice President for 8 years, and he was senator for 36 years and has spent a lot of time listening to State of the Union speeches.&nbsp; So he understands the importance of delivering such a &#8212; a President delivering such a impactful speech and the &#8212; the purpose of talking about their successes &#8212; his success, in particular, this past year &#8212; and how he&#8217;s going to build on that success.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have anything more to share.&nbsp; But this is something that&#8217;s important to him.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s working towards delivering his speech not just to &#8212; not just to Congress, but also to the American public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Karine.&nbsp; I want to follow up on Darlene&#8217;s question and ask it in a different way, though.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Russia&#8217;s foreign minister is advising Putin today that Russia keep pursuing diplomatic negotiations.&nbsp; This is a yes-or-no question: Does this administration view that as a sign of de-escalation?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, what I was saying &#8212; and just to be even clearer &#8212; is that in the past 10 days or so, when you look at what is happening at the border of Ukraine, there &#8212; we are seeing more than 100,000 troops there.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just been an &#8212; every day, more and more troops, as I just read out at the top.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we are certainly open to having conversations and seeing a de-escalation.&nbsp; But right now, this is &#8212; that door is open for diplomacy, and this is up to President Putin.&nbsp; He has to make that decision.&nbsp; It is his decision to make on which direction he wants to take this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, in terms of the troop buildup there, there&#8217;s reporting today that a U- &#8212; citing a U.S. official that Russian units near Ukraine moved into attack positions.&nbsp; Is that the understanding of this administration, what you&#8217;re seeing there?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to go into any intelligence information.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not &#8212; clearly, we&#8217;re not going to share that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we have seen &#8212; and, you know, the National Security Advisor said this himself &#8212; we have seen an increase of forces at the border, not a decrease.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so, what we are saying to President Putin, with our European allies and partners &#8212; we&#8217;ve been working in coordination, in lockstep for these past several weeks, several months &#8212; is that that door to diplomacy is open and having that diplomatic conversation is a path that we would like to take.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, lastly, Jake Sullivan came out here and certainly got the attention of the entire world with the urgency of the briefing that he gave on Friday.&nbsp; In terms of the current state right now, is the situation as imminent today, right now, as it was on Friday?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, Jake Sullivan was also on the Sunday shows yesterday.&nbsp; And, you know, again, we are in the window when an invasion could begin at any time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we&#8217;re &#8212; again, I&#8217;m not going to comment on the intelligence information except to say that it could begin this week, despite a lot of speculation that it would only happen after the Olympics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Just to follow up on that, I understand you&#8217;re saying that you&#8217;ve only seen a troop buildup, but Russia has claimed today that it is winding down a number of military drills and exercises that have caused concern.&nbsp; Are you in a position to confirm if those claims are accurate or if they&#8217;re not?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not in a position to confirm that, but I do know John Kirby spoke to that just moments ago, so I would refer you to his comments and the Department of Defense.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And specifically about, you know, Ukraine and the Vatican, we have some reporting coming from there saying Ukraine has welcomed Vatican mediation of its conflict with Russia, and they&#8217;ve invited the Pope to visit the country as soon as possible.&nbsp; Is the President aware of that?&nbsp; Does he support such efforts?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I have not spoken to the President about that, so I can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t confirm if he&#8217;s aware or not.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Will the administration support such efforts?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; this is the first time I&#8217;m hearing about it, so I just need to talk to our team.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And one more on the $1 billion loan guarantee that the U.S. has agreed to make available to support the Ukrainian economy.&nbsp; Our reporting shows that the U.S. will need about $200 million to guarantee that loan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Do you &#8212; does the administration need to make more appropriat- &#8212; appropriations available to, sort of, you know, make sure that loan guarantee program works?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have the specifics on that piece, but I can confirm that it is something we are considering as part of the additional macroeconomic support we are exploring to help Ukraine&#8217;s economy amidst pressure resulting from Russia&#8217;s military buildup.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any specifics on the appropriation and what that would take &#8212; the process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would the U.S. support some statement from the Ukrainians that they&#8217;re no longer actively pursuing NATO membership or that they’d be willing to stall their pursuit of NATO membership as part of ongoing negotiations?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; As you know, NATO membership &#8212; NATO has an open-door policy.&nbsp; That is not something &#8212; that is something that Ukraine will have to decide on its own.&nbsp; That is not something that we are in consultation with or make, you know &#8212; or even decide on.&nbsp; That is something that NATO has to decide on and Ukraine.&nbsp; That&#8217;s up to them and their leadership on how they want to move forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake yesterday said that the two leaders, Presidents Putin and Biden, tasked their teams with continuing to talk or discuss, kind of, the state of play.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Do you have any idea, kind of, the construct of those discussions or what they’d entail, and if any have occurred since the discussion on Saturday?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I do believe Jake Sullivan had a conversation this morning with &#8212; with one of our &#8212; one of our European partners and allies &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I’m saying between the Russians and the &#8212; U.S. and Russia, directly, bilaterally.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, I see.&nbsp; I see.&nbsp; Oh.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to read out or predict.</p>



<p>And do you mean on the &#8212; on the staff level?&nbsp; Or do you mean like &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Just under the principal level.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, under the principal &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to read out.&nbsp; As you know, our staff here has been in constant contact with Russia, with Ukraine, and our NATO Allies as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, one last one.&nbsp; There&#8217;s concern in terms of &#8212; obviously, in the European economic side of things, if Russia continues to escalate, if there’s an invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the domestic side of things, is the White House economic team looking at anything that the President may need to pursue if an invasion comes to pass about what it could do?&nbsp; Obviously, oil markets being one, but I think just general instability in markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, I don&#8217;t have anything specific to read out to you &#8212; for you at this moment.&nbsp; As we talk about energy &#8212; I&#8217;m assuming that&#8217;s one of the things that you&#8217;re &#8212; you&#8217;re asking about, Phil &#8212; is, like, we are working with countries and companies around the world to ensure the security of supply and to mitigate against price shocks affecting the American people, Europe, and the global economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are continuing our discussions with major producers around &#8212; around the globe to supply &#8212; so supply meets demand.&nbsp; All tools are on the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A disruption in physical energy supplies trans- &#8212; transiting Ukraine would most acutely affect natural gas markets in Europe.&nbsp; And so, we are engaging our European allies to coordinate response planning, including how to deploy their existing energy stockpiles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have been working to identify additional volumes of non-Russian natural gas from North Africa and the Middle East to Asia and the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; we thank &#8212; we think &#8212; we thank <s>reent</s> [recent] comments by Japan about supporting Europe&#8217;s energy security through LNG shipments to the region.&nbsp; We are in discussion with major natural gas producers around the globe to understand their capacity and willingness to temporarily surge natural gas output and to allocate these volumes in European buyers.</p>



<p>We are also engaging with major buyers and suppliers of LNG to ensure flexibility in existing contracts and storage is managed and enables a diver- &#8212; diversion to Europe.</p>



<p>(Inaudible).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great, Karine.&nbsp; How are you?&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s a reporting quoting Ukraine officials as saying that President Zelenskyy&#8217;s statement today that an invasion is imminent on February 16 was, in fact, sarcastic or ironic and more of a commentary on this idea that there are countries or entities that know of a date certain.&nbsp; Is that sarcasm or irony the read of the NSC and the White House?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have a read on that.&nbsp; Here&#8217;s what I can tell you about &#8212; about that.&nbsp; I heard &#8212; I heard the statement, but I haven&#8217;t actually heard it in its full context, so the irony of all of it, I have &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t speak to.</p>



<p>But I’ll say this: While I&#8217;m not going to speak to intelligence matters, as I&#8217;ve said multipie- &#8212; multiple times already, our intelligence or intelligence-sharing with the Ukraines &#8212; Ukrainians &#8212; as we said before, we are in the window when an invasion could begin at any time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It remains unclear which path Russia will choose to take, because we do not know; it is his decision to make.&nbsp; We remain engaged with the Russian government in full coordination with our Allies and partners.&nbsp; The path for diplomacy remains available if Russia chooses to engage, again, constructively.</p>



<p>But we are clear-eyed about the prospects on the ground and are ready to impose severe costs on Russia, in coordination with our Allies and partners, if they attack Ukraine.</p>



<p><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And two other unrelated matters.&nbsp; Supreme Court: Is it still the expectation that the President will interview nominees this week?&nbsp; And do those that are under consideration know for certain that they&#8217;re on the shortlist of people being considered?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, I appreciate the interest here.&nbsp; Look, you know, after having a series of conversations and good discussions with lawmakers from both sides of the party, legal experts, scholars last week, the President continued to review materials as he considers deeply, deeply qualified candidates, as we have said, with strong experience, character, integrity, dedication to the Constitution and the rule of law.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything else to share on any interviews or who he has interviewed.&nbsp; But, you know, we don&#8217;t have anything else to share for today or for this week.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What’s that?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he interviewed someone, then?&nbsp; The way you just phrased that &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You just &#8212; you said “interviewed.”&nbsp; Yeah, that’s &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, I’m sorry.&nbsp; I meant to be &#8212; he has not interviewed potential nominees, to be clear.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But to just answer your last question is &#8212; we are on track, he is on track to select a SCOTUS nominee by the end of this month.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then just real quick &#8212; Robert Califf is still awaiting confirmation in the Senate to be FDA commissioner.&nbsp; It looks like that may happen tomorrow.&nbsp; Is the White House confident he&#8217;s got the votes?&nbsp; Have you lined up all the Democratic votes you might need for this?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll say this: We are confident Dr. Califf will be confirmed with bipartisan support and urge the Senate to confirm him tomorrow, as you just stated, Ed.&nbsp; It is critically important to have confirmed leadership at the FDA in the midst of a pandemic, as we all know.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He had a strong bipartisan showing coming out of committee, including from Ranking Member Burr.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important to remember he was confirmed 89 to 4 in 2016.&nbsp; Many folks who supported him then are still in the Senate.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are in &#8212; we are in a daily contact with HHS, who is leading the effort to get him confirmed.&nbsp; HHS and the White House officials are making a lot of calls to the Hill, figuring out which means need what information &#8212; which members need what information.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Becerra, our OLA team, and Steve Ricchetti are all making calls in support of Califf to a bipartisan group of Senate offices.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Dr. Califf himself has met &#8212; has met or is scheduled to meet with 47 senators, and that number continues to increase.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also one of the highest number of meetings of any nominees that have been done thus far.</p>



<p>Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In his conversation with President Putin, did President Biden give him any signal for how he could de-escalate?&nbsp; Would it have to be something visible, like moving forces somewhere?&nbsp; Could it be something in the realm of what&#8217;s verbal, like what we saw from Lavrov today?&nbsp; Is there anything that the President set out as a cue that could try to tamp things down?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the call between the two presidents was professional and substantive.&nbsp; So, it lasted a bit over an hour, as you all know, from the readout this past weekend.&nbsp; The two presidents agreed that our teams would stay engaged in the days ahead, but there was no fundamental change in the dynamic.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to close the loop on the Supreme Court: So, you&#8217;re not saying that the President has done &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; any interviews &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I’m not.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; at this point?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m not. &nbsp;Just to be clear.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I was &#8212; I meant potential interviews.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; The President has some travel scheduled this week.&nbsp; Given the volatility of world events, do you anticipate that if things were &#8212; and I know this is hypothetical, but often when there are unpredictable events, there can be changes to the schedule.&nbsp; Are you in a posture where you think that could be a situation where the President would remain at the White House or anything like that if things were to change?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you said, it is hard to read, Kelly O., a hypothetical or to give an answer to a hypothetical.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you know, the President deals with multiple things at once, and that&#8217;s what this President is prepared to do.</p>



<p>Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; On the, sort of, ripple effects of a potential invasion, is the administration prepared to block Russian oil imports to the U.S. if Russia invades, given that the imports have reached their highest prices in 11 years (inaudible)?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I mean, I just laid out what we&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking to countries and companies around the world, engaging with them on all of the different potential conse- &#8212; potential outcomes if this were to happen.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more specifics than that &#8212; than what I just laid out for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, one of the things that we have said over and over again, and the President has made this very clear to Vladimir Putin, is if Russia chooses to invade, there will be swift and severe economic consequences.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Wouldn’t it be difficult, though, for the U.S. to continue to import Russian oil after all of the rhetoric that we&#8217;ve put forward about Russia needing to not invade Ukraine and pressuring Germany to, you know, come out strongly on Nord Stream 2 and possible punishments for Russia if they were to take this step?&nbsp; Wouldn’t it be tough for the U.S. to continue, in that event, to import Russian gas?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, again, it&#8217;s a hypothetical.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just telling you what we have been very, very clear, the President has been clear, our national security advisor has been clear &#8212; we all have been clear, either from this podium or direct communication with Russia, whether it&#8217;s with the President or its leadership, that if they were to invade &#8212; and in coordination, in lockstep with our European Allies and partners, that&#8217;s how we&#8217;re moving forward here &#8212; that there would be there would be severe, decisive economic consequences.&nbsp; I cannot speak more to &#8212; more to that.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then the sanctions package that&#8217;s being worked out on Capitol Hill &#8212; I understand that the White House is involved in those discussions now.&nbsp; And congressional sources have told me that the White House has insisted on a waiver for North Stream 2, even after an invasion.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you confirm if that is true?&nbsp; And if so, why would the White House want a provision like that in a sanctions package coming out of Congress?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, when it comes to Nord Stream 2, we&#8217;ve been pretty clear about this.&nbsp; The President has said that &#8212; he said this during his press conference last week with the German Chancellor &#8212; if Russia further invades Ukraine, there will be &#8212; no longer be a Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; We will bring an end to it.&nbsp; And at this moment, Nord Stream 2 is not even operational.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is the White House directing Congress to put a waiver from Nord Stream 2 in a &#8212;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That is the first I&#8217;m hearing of that.&nbsp; I cannot speak to that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just telling you where we have been, in a very strong and definitive way, on Nord Stream 2.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, on a second topic, this news about the Durham investigation: Does the President have any concerns about a candidate for president using computer experts to infiltrate computer systems of competing candidates, or even the president-elect to &#8212; for the goal of creating a narrative?&nbsp; Is that something that &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That&#8217;s something I can&#8217;t speak to from this podium, so I refer you to the Department of Justice.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is what being described in that report &#8212; monitoring Internet traffic &#8212; is that spying?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I can&#8217;t speak to that report.&nbsp; I refer you to the Department of Justice.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Generally speaking though, would monitoring Internet traffic be &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Jacqui, my answer is not going to change.&nbsp; I refer you to the Department of Justice.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to that from here.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, thanks.&nbsp; What message does it send today to the Ukrainian government to be closing the embassy in Kyiv?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The embassy in Kyiv?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I have something on here.&nbsp; I know the &#8212; I know the State Department made announcement on this earlier.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the State Department announced today that they are temporary &#8212; temporarily relocating our embassy operations in Ukraine from our embassy in Kyiv to Lviv due to the dramatic acceleration in the buildup of Russian forces.&nbsp; A core team of embassy staff is remaining in Ukraine to engage with the Ukrainian government, coordinating diplomatic efforts and diplomacy to de-escalate the crisis &#8212; if the crisis continues.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I just wanted to also say this as well, because the State Department put out a statement on this.&nbsp; So, the State Department has no higher priority than the safety and security of Americans around the world.&nbsp; And that, of course, includes our colleagues serving at posts overseas.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, these prudent precautions in no way undermine our support for our commitment to Ukraine.&nbsp; Our commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity is unwavering.&nbsp; We also continue our sincere efforts to reach a diplomatic solution.&nbsp; And we remain engaged with the Russian government following President Biden&#8217;s call with Putin &#8212; with President Putin and the Secretary&#8217;s discussion with Foreign Minister Lavrov.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The path for diplomacy remains available if Russia chooses to engage in good faith.&nbsp; We look forward to returning our staff to the embassy as soon as conditions permit.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the meantime, we have made this very clear; the National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, has made this clear; the President himself has made this clear: that these measures, for one reason, the safety of our staff, as I mentioned.&nbsp; We strongly urge any remaining U.S. citizens in Ukraine to leave the country immediately.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That has been our message for the past several days and, honestly, the past several weeks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the White House have any comment on this Russian figure skater who&#8217;s allowed to maybe compete, as a doping investigation continues?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is this the right call?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a comment that I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to comment from here about that.&nbsp; I’d refer you to the committee &#8212; the Olympic Committee.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And really quickly: D.C.&#8217;s mayor today announced a vacc- &#8212; the vaccination requirement for some businesses will be dropped tomorrow and a mask mandate will be dropped by the end of the month.&nbsp; Does the White House support this?&nbsp; Will the President and the First Lady continue to visit businesses and restaurants as these rules change?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me just lay some stuff out for you here, because I know this has been a question that many have had.&nbsp; A number of governors have announced changes based on conditions in their particular states.&nbsp; That &#8212; that&#8217;s not new.&nbsp; That isn&#8217;t new. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, what I can say from here, as Dr. Fauci has said: As a country, we are making strong progress toward moving to a time when COVID is no longer a crisis.&nbsp; And Dr. Walensky has clearly said CDC is looking at all of their guidance, including mask guidance, in light of declining cases and hospitalizations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that may be getting lost in some of the reporting that we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; The CDC made clear they&#8217;re looking at their guidance, so just want to make that very clear.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But to put a finer point on this, CDC has to move carefully and deliberately to make sure these good trends are confirmed across the nation.&nbsp; CDC has a responsibility to make guidance for the entire country and everyone.&nbsp; They must consider its impact on a variety of constituencies, including people who are disabled, immunocompromised, and most vulnerable.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>We are spending significant time and energy on the path forward, working with experts and leaders within and &#8212; within and outside the government.&nbsp; And if this &#8212; if this progress continues, we expect updates in the weeks ahead.&nbsp; This is a huge, huge responsibility that we do not take <s>likely</s> [lightly], one that we take very seriously, and we want to make sure that we get this right.</a></p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; During their conversation on Sunday, the President of Ukraine purportedly invited President Biden to visit Ukraine in the coming days.&nbsp; And the Ukrainian President&#8217;s office said that a visit by the U.S. President would &#8220;be a powerful signal” and could “contribute to [the] de-escalation&#8221; of this crisis.&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s response to that invitation?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have any travel plans to announce or preview at this time.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll say this: You know, as you all know, President Biden spoke with Zelenskyy &#8212; as you just mentioned &#8212; this weekend.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken spoke with the Foreign Minister this morning.&nbsp; And we are in regular contact with the Ukrainian government throughout the administration, including here at the White House, at the State Department, at the Defense Department.&nbsp; I just laid out travel that the Secretary from Defense is going to be making, at the Treasury Department, and elsewhere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the President has also dispatched a number of senior administration officials to visit Ukraine in recent months, including Secretary Blinken who was just there recently, and &#8212; last month for meetings with Ukraine&#8217;s leader.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our North Star has been “nothing abo-” &#8212; &#8220;nothing about Ukraine without Ukraine.&#8221;&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard us say this over and over again.&nbsp; And we will continue to coordinate closely with Ukraine as we try to reach a diplomatic solution to the end of this crisis.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could I bring you back to the gun issue that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you talked about in the beginning?&nbsp; A bunch of years ago, a large number of people in the Bi- &#8212; in the Obama administration, including the current President, fought fiercely for closing the gun show loophole and described it as &#8220;the least that could be done,&#8221; and were very angry and upset when it didn&#8217;t pass, pushing &#8212; pushing also, at various times, for even more &#8212; you know, a ban on assault weapons and the like.&nbsp; You didn&#8217;t mention any of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President&#8217;s message today that he put out earlier didn&#8217;t mention any of that.&nbsp; Is it fair to assume that either they no longer &#8212; this President no longer thinks those things are needed or has simply abandoned any hope of getting them passed?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t assume that.&nbsp; I &#8212; one of the things I did say is we are encouraging Congress to act as well.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a legislation &#8212; legislative component to this, as you just laid out, so that is important as well.</p>



<p>But I do want to read a couple of quotes from &#8212; about the President&#8217;s exa- &#8212; executing on his historic comprehensive gun violence reduction strategy.&nbsp; So, there is support there for it.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;re talking about a specific thing, but I want to not just take our word for this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Brady has called the President’s plan “historic” and said “President Biden and his administration are truly taking comprehensive action to address violence in our country.”</p>



<p>Giffords commented the Biden-Harris administration &#8212; commended &#8212; pardon me &#8212; the Biden administration &#8220;for announcing a comprehensive strategy to prevent gun violence and protect public safety. . . .&nbsp;Gun violence is a complex problem&#8221; &#8212; as you can imagine, and as she stated &#8212; &#8220;that requires an array of solutions. &nbsp;President Biden and Vice President Harris understand[s] [that].”&nbsp; This is a quote from &#8212; from Giffords.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Everytown for Gun Safety said “President Biden is taking the comprehensive approach we need to address this crisis.”</p>



<p>And so, is there more work to do?&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re encouraging and urging Congress to act as well.&nbsp; But the President is going to do everything that he can from his perch to get this done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he would be satisfied that if &#8212; if the things that he&#8217;s pushing that are on that list and that you have talked about and that he talked about, that would be good enough?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We&#8217;re not calling it “good enough.”&nbsp; He is doing everything that he can from his perch &#8212; from the White House, from the federal government &#8212; and using every tool at our tool &#8212; on a toolbelt that we&#8217;ve talked about.&nbsp; We &#8212; that&#8217;s what we tried to do to make sure that we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re addressing a real problem, which is gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what &#8212; the other part of that is urging Congress to act as well, which we have been doing.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s not going to sit back.&nbsp; You heard me say that. &nbsp;He&#8217;s not going to sit back and wait; he&#8217;s going to act.&nbsp; But there &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he&#8217;s also not going to spend a whole lot of time or energy pushing for a ban on assault weapons or closing the gun show loophole that, just a bunch of years ago, he and others described as “vital.”</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll say this: We are constantly in conversation with folks in Congress &#8212; with leadership, with congressional members, with senators &#8212; that is an array of issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President is going to continue to fight to make sure that we get these guns off the street and we truly deal with gun violence.&nbsp; He is doing his part from the White House, and he&#8217;s going to continue to work towards that effort.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; A few questions.&nbsp; First on Afghanistan: The Biden administration appears to have been downplaying some accounts from ground commanders involved in the evacuation of Afghanistan.&nbsp; Over the past week, we heard a State Department spokesperson say that their criticism was “cherry-picked” from a larger report.&nbsp; We’ve heard President Biden himself reject those accounts.&nbsp; Jen, last week I believe, said that there was no after-action report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, two questions I wanted to ask you to clarify the White House position.&nbsp; One, does the White House agree that the evacuation should have become or should have been started earlier, which is what some senior military officials have asserted?</p>



<p>And secondly, did Jen misspeak last week when she said there was no after-action report?&nbsp; There&#8217;s been some reporting from a colleague of mine, over the weekend, that indicated there was indeed an after-action report that was reviewed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, to your last question: No, Jen did not misspeak last week.&nbsp; This Abbey Gate report is not the Pentagon&#8217;s boarder [sic] action &#8212; boarder [sic] ap- &#8212; broader after-action review on Afghanistan.&nbsp; That report will examine the final months of America&#8217;s longest war and cover from February 2020 through the end of the evacuation.&nbsp; So, no, she did not misspeak.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me just say something that I think it&#8217;s really important.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to quote John Kirby, who was &#8212; who did a Sunday show yesterday.&nbsp; I believe this was Fox News&nbsp; Sunday show.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll quote him here.&nbsp; He said:&nbsp; &#8220;I would also add…here in Washington, we have been planning for evacuation as far back as April. &nbsp;And there was no effort by Washington, certainly not by the National Security Council specifically, to slow down that planning, to slow down those pre-positioning of forces that we did in the summer, to slow down the actual execution of the evacuation.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, again &#8212; this is John Kirby, spokesperson for the Department of Defense: “So, again, these were documents that assert impressions and perspectives which are very important down at the tactical level, in real-time.&nbsp; We need to conduct a larger, more strategic level after-action review to get the whole sense of this.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re doing that.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Abbey report, again, is one important review of what occurred that day, but it should not be mistaken for a full follow-up on the last months of the war in Afghanistan.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And on a different topic &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to follow up on the earlier questions about the Supreme Court.&nbsp; I know you said that the President has not conducted any interviews with candidates yet, but does the White House &#8212; will the White House disclose which candidates the President does interviews with as he goes through this process?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What I can promise you right now is that the pro- &#8212; the President is going to make his selection for the Supreme Court justice by the end of this month.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we know.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what he stated.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we will do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last question.&nbsp; Vice President Harris is headed abroad to the Munich Security Conference this week.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about what the White House hopes she will accomplish there?&nbsp; And is she going to be sort of the sole representative of the administration in some of these meetings with counterparts?&nbsp; Are there going to be other administration officials as well?&nbsp; Can you sort of give us a sense of what the expectation is?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have any specifics, but I can say that we are very proud to have the Vice President lead the delegation to Munich this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have any specific details.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to talk to the team to see exactly what her schedule is going to look like.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re &#8212; we are &#8212; the President is proud that she&#8217;s going to be representing the United States.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have just a couple of quick ones.&nbsp; Following up on this Zelenskyy question, can you confirm whether President Zelenskyy asked President Biden to come to Ukraine this week, and whether the administration considered it at all?&nbsp; I know you don&#8217;t have travel to announce but &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; all I can tell you is what I just said.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have travel to confirm right now.&nbsp; That is what the President’s schedule looks like.&nbsp; And the &#8212; it&#8217;s certainly not confirming to go to visit Ukraine.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what now &#8212; our focus right now is to continue to have the conversations on the staff level to continue to make sure that we are &#8212; we keep that door to diplomacy open.&nbsp; There&#8217;s too much at stake.&nbsp; There are human lives at stake, which is what the President told President Putin.&nbsp; And that is our focus: How do we stop a war?&nbsp; That&#8217;s our focus.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Pfizer withdrew, late last week, its application for the vaccine for young kids.&nbsp; Is that a disappointment to the White House?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, I have something on that.&nbsp; So, FDA is committed to acting urgently to save lives amidst the pandemic, and they continue to work with Pfizer to review additional data on its vaccine for kids under five.</p>



<p>In recent days, new data &#8212; as you know, Tam &#8212; emerged regarding Pfizer&#8217;s submission to the FDA for its vaccine for kids under five years old.&nbsp; Based on FDA&#8217;s assessment of that new data, the agency concluded that additional information regarding a third dose should be considered as part of any authorization.</p>



<p>The initial data has been helpful to the process, but FDA believes more information, including the impact of a third dose, is important to the evaluation.&nbsp; So, that is the process &#8212; that is the process right now, currently, that&#8217;s working.&nbsp; And that should give parents everywhere confidence in the process &#8212; right? &#8212; because we want to make sure that the process is working.</p>



<p>FDA is in the middle of a thorough, independent regulatory process to review this vaccine.&nbsp; And if a vaccine is authorized, it will have met FDA&#8217;s rigorous standards.&nbsp; So, that is what the parents &#8212; as a parent myself, and I know you&#8217;re a parent &#8212; should be verly [sic] &#8212; very proud of that the FDA is doing this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the D.C. mask mandate, do you expect that mask mandate coming down to affect policy here on campus at</p>



<p>the White House?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as always, we say this: Local communities will make their own decisions as they have throughout the pandemic, and we&#8217;ll &#8212; what we&#8217;re going to do is we&#8217;re going to abide by the CDC guidance.&nbsp; So that is local communities make that decision and that is what they choose to do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the White House is not following the local guidelines here for your &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We&#8217;re following &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; here for this place that is in the city.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; To be clear, we are going to follow the CDC guidance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to do.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to the VP&#8217;s trip to Germany, is there discussion in the White House about whether she should go no matter what is happening in Ukraine, or has there been discussions about what might trigger her to cancel?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; any insight on that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s another hypothetical that I can&#8217;t answer.&nbsp; But what I can say is that we are proud that she&#8217;s going to be leading the U.S. delegation to Munich, and that is on &#8212; on schedule to happen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the embassy in Kyiv, do you know if all of the classified information has now been stripped from that building?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I do not have that information for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yeah, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I wanted to ask you a quick question on the Quad and Russia.&nbsp; Do you think Quad countries are unanimous on the issue of Russia?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Can you say &#8212; can you say that one more time, Lalit?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think the Quad countries &#8212; U.S., Japan, India, and Australia &#8212; they had a meeting in Australia recently.&nbsp; Do you think these countries are unanimous on the &#8212; on the Russian &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; On the Russia &#8212; the Russian issue in particular?</p>



<p>So, as you know, Secretary Blinken was just in the region, where he met with the Quad.&nbsp; It was an opportunity to discuss Russia&#8217;s ongoing threat to Ukraine.&nbsp; They discussed the threat that Russia&#8217;s aggression poses not only to Ukraine but to the entire international rules-based order, which has provided a foundation for decades of shared security and prosperity for the region and around the globe.</p>



<p>Throughout his meetings with the Quad partners, Secretary Blinken discussed the challenges Russia poses to the rules-based &#8212; based on international order and our readiness to support our European allies.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I&#8217;m asking this question because you know that India&#8217;s foreign min- &#8212; External Affairs Minister, S. Jaishankar said that India only follows multilateral sanctions, not country-specific sanctions.&nbsp; And as you&#8217;re looking towards country-specific sanctions from the U.S., because the U.N. Security Council is unlikely to vote for those sanctions because of the vetoes Russia and China have, are you in conversations with India that they should follow the U.S. sanctions as well?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, we&#8217;re not going to get into specifics.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been really clear about our discussions, so I&#8217;m not going into details on that but &#8212; beyond what we&#8217;ve read out from the Secretary&#8217;s meeting in Melbourne last week.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re working closely with a range of allies and partners, including India.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One final question.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What role President Biden expects India to play in the Quad?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, we will continue to build a strategic partnership in which the United States and India work together to promote stability in South Asia; collaborate in new domains such as health, space, cyberspace &#8212; which is important; deepen our economic and technology cooperation; and contribute to a free and open Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We recognize that India is a likeminded partner and leader in South Asia and the Indian Ocean, active in and connected to the Southeast Asia, a driving force of the Quad, and an engine for regional growth and development.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No problem.&nbsp; Oh, thank you.</p>



<p>Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; Don’t forget to get those flowers and those candy.&nbsp; (Laughter.) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:20 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Bipartisan Infrastructure&#160;Law</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-law/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 23:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47272</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 2:56 P.M. EST THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you so much, Llulisa.&#160; I &#8212; it is part of the reason that we are so excited about this effort &#8212; it is because it&#8217;s about investing in the future our nation, and that means investing in our future leaders and our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></p>



<p>2:56 P.M. EST<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Llulisa.&nbsp; I &#8212; it is part of the reason that we are so excited about this effort &#8212; it is because it&#8217;s about investing in the future our nation, and that means investing in our future leaders and our current leaders, of which Llulisa is one.&nbsp; So, thank you, Llulisa, for your leadership and your voice and your courage and your brilliance.&nbsp;<br><br>Mr. Roundtree, her principal, I want to say that she is doing a great job, and I want to thank you for all of the young students that you are mentoring.&nbsp; So, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So, it is a pleasure to be here today.&nbsp; And I want to thank Llulisa for really pointing out how essential the Internet is and how essential it is to have an Internet connection not only for the sake of their educational success, but in so many ways that is about understanding the full reality of a full human being.<br><br>So, it is a pleasure to be here today with also two true champions of our nation&#8217;s working people: FCC Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel, who has worked for years to make high-speed Internet more affordable and more accessible.&nbsp; And thank you, Chairwoman, for your leadership.&nbsp;<br><br>And Mitch Landrieu, our administration’s infrastructure coordinator.&nbsp; He is passionate and he is dedicated and has lived a life of service.&nbsp; And I thank you, Mitch, for all that you have done on this issue and so many other issues.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I will begin with what I believe is a simple truth: In the 21st century, high-speed Internet is a necessity &#8212; not a luxury, a necessity.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Our world has moved online.&nbsp; And that is why, from day one, the President and I have fought to make it easier for everyone to access and afford high-speed Internet.<br><br>Today, we are celebrating a major milestone in that fight.&nbsp; You see, during the pandemic, millions of people &#8212; families, in particular &#8212; depended on high-speed Internet.&nbsp;<br><br>Young people use the Internet to access digital textbooks, attend virtual classes, and collaborate on science projects all at their kitchen table.<br><br>Parents use the Internet to buy groceries, paper towels,<br>and other daily essentials.<br><br>The Internet allowed folks to take care of their children<br>and get their essential needs accomplished.&nbsp;<br><br>Business owners, like the one I met from Missouri last year, rely on the Internet to coordinate with suppliers overseas.<br><br>Many workers use the Internet to do their jobs virtually.<br><br>People everywhere use high-speed Internet to stream movies<br>for family movie night &#8212; Llulisa talked about that; to video chat with friends that are far away; to view a tutorial on how to fix that leaky faucet; to read the news, check the weather, or plan a trip.<br><br>For so many of us, we use of the Internet as an essential and integrated part of our daily lives, and we take it for granted.&nbsp;<br><br>And yet, today, more than 42 million people in our country &#8212; 42 million people &#8212; do not have access to high-speed Internet, which obviously means students are sitting in fast food restaurant parking lots to do their homework over public Wi-Fi because that is the only place that they have Internet access.<br><br>Seniors are taking their telemedicine visits not at home in the privacy of their home, but in local libraries with little or no privacy.<br><br>There are many reasons why it is so difficult for people in our nation to access reliable high-speed Internet.<br><br>And, today, we are here to talk about one of the most<br>common reasons: cost &#8212; the expense of it.&nbsp; Half of all the people who do not have high-speed Internet say it is because the monthly cost is too high.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Well, the President and I know that the cost of living has gone up, and we are working hard to help working families pay their bills.<br><br>Every person in our nation, and every parent, no matter how much they earn, should be able to access high-speed broadband Internet.&nbsp; And that is why we are here today.<br><br>So, last year, we fought for and passed, with a lot of great support, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which invested more than $14 billion to make high-speed Internet more affordable.<br><br>We also created the Affordable Connectivity Program<br>because we know access to affordable broadband is, of course, a vital issue.<br><br>And thanks to the Affordable Connectivity Program, one in four American households are now eligible to receive a discount<br>on their monthly Internet bill.&nbsp; And if your household qualifies, you will receive a voucher that will lower your Internet bill by $30 a month.<br><br>If you live on Tribal lands, that voucher will lower your bill by $75 a month.<br><br>The Affordable Connectivity Program also gives eligible households a one-time discount of up to $100&nbsp;to purchase a laptop,&nbsp;desktop computer, or tablet.<br><br>So, today, I am proud to announce that already more than 10 million American households have signed up for the Affordable Connectivity Program.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That’s right.&nbsp; Well, thanks to you all.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, yes, it is an historic accomplishment.<br><br>This milestone means more entrepreneurs are building digital businesses, more families are staying connected, more children in our country are able to do their homework at home.&nbsp; And this is only the beginning.<br><br>If you are eligible to receive affordable broadband support or even if you think you might be eligible, please call the number on the screen or visit &#8212; I’m going to give you a website &#8212;&nbsp;<s>ACPBenefit.gov</s>&nbsp;[ACPBenefit.org].&nbsp; And there, you can confirm whether you qualify, sign up for benefits, and learn how to redeem your voucher.<br><br>To make sure everyone knows this program is available, we are working with state and local governments to inform people that they are eligible.<br><br>We are working with community- and faith-based organizations to help people fill out their applications.<br><br>And we are calling on all Internet service providers to participate meaningfully in this program: to offer more affordable high-speed plans to customers and to spread the word to all eligible households.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This will take all of us working together.<br><br>And so, I’ll conclude with this: When we connect families and workers, students and small-business owners with high-speed Internet, we connect them to opportunity &#8212; the opportunity to work and learn remotely, to see a doctor online, to buy groceries through an app, to deposit a check without having to go to the bank.&nbsp; In short, the opportunity to live healthier, happier, efficient, and more prosperous lives.<br><br>This is what so much of our administration&#8217;s work comes down to: fighting to make sure that every person in our country has the tools they need to succeed, that has access to the opportunity they need to succeed.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, we are fighting to make sure every person has that opportunity to build something for themselves and for their families and for their community.<br><br>By making the essential technology of the 21st century more affordable, this program is doing just that for millions of Americans.<br><br>So, I thank you all, in particular the great leaders who are here today and have been working on this for such a long time.&nbsp; Thank you all for the work you have done and for the work you will continue to do to give parents, children, and all the members of our communities a fair shot at a better future.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you all, and take care.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;END &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;3:05 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/14/press-release-nominations-sent-to-the-senate-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 22:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Philip S. Goldberg, of the District of Columbia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Ambassador, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Korea. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Carrin F. Patman, of Texas, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Philip S. Goldberg, of the District of Columbia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Ambassador, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Korea.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Carrin F. Patman, of Texas, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Iceland.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Erik Kristopher Raven, of the District of Columbia, to be Under Secretary of the Navy, vice Thomas B. Modly.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Discussions with Conservation Leaders on $1.5 billion Investment and Implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure&#160;Law</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/14/readout-of-white-house-discussions-with-conservation-leaders-on-1-5-billion-investment-and-implementation-of-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-law/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 22:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Senior Advisor and White House Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator Mitch Landrieu and other senior administration officials, including Sarah Greenberger the Associate Deputy Secretary at the Department of Interior, discussed how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will build a better America by investing in the conservation of and access to our public lands. &#160;Landrieu outlined the President’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Senior Advisor and White House Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator Mitch Landrieu and other senior administration officials, including Sarah Greenberger the Associate Deputy Secretary at the Department of Interior, discussed how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will build a better America by investing in the conservation of and access to our public lands. &nbsp;Landrieu outlined the President’s commitment as part of the America the Beautiful Initiative to building partnerships with states, conservation groups, hunters, anglers, Tribes and others to conserve America’s lands and waters for future generations.</p>



<p>President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law includes billions for ecosystem restoration and resilience of America’s lands, invasive species detection and prevention,&nbsp; and native vegetation restoration efforts, on top of nearly $16 billion for cleaning up legacy pollution.&nbsp; On Friday, the Department of the Interior announced distribution of a record <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-announces-over-15-billion-support-state-wildlife-conservation-and">$1.5 billion</a> in Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration (WSFR) Program allocations to state wildlife agencies throughout the nation. The WSFR was reauthorized as part of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. &nbsp;Landrieu noted that these grants will make significant progress in our work to protect our cherished natural treasures, and together with other Bipartisan Infrastructure Law investments, will make significant progress in our work on collaborative conservation.  </p>



<p><strong>From today’s conversation: </strong>“The tremendous amount of ongoing, new, or improved collaboration between the federal government, states, local leaders, tribes, nonprofits, and everyone here today will make it possible to build back better. Conservation is something we can all agree on, and as the President has said repeatedly, there’s so much common ground for those who seek to find it.” – <em>Mitch Landrieu, Senior Advisor and White House Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator</em></p>



<p><strong>Participants:</strong></p>



<ul><li>National Wildlife Federation</li><li>Theodore Roosevelt Conservation Partnership</li><li>Ducks Unlimited</li><li>Trout Unlimited</li><li>National Wildlife Refuge Association</li><li>Mule Deer Foundation</li><li>Wildlife Society</li><li>National Fish &amp; Wildlife Foundation</li><li>Center for Sports Fishing Policy</li><li>National Marine Manufacturers Association</li><li>Watershed Results</li><li>Outdoor Industry Association</li><li>American Sportfishing Association</li><li>Boone and Crockett Club</li><li>The Wildlife Society</li><li>International Game Fish Association</li><li>National Deer Association</li><li>American Saltwater Guides Association</li><li>Backcountry Hunters &amp; Anglers</li><li>Wildlife Mississippi</li><li>National Wild Turkey Federation</li><li>Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation</li><li>Archery Trade Association</li><li>Wildlife Management Institute</li><li>Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies outgoing and incoming Presidents:<ul><li>Tony Wasley, Director, Nevada Department of Wildlife</li><li>Sara Parker Pauley, Director, Missouri Department of Conservation</li></ul></li></ul>



<p>See Fiscal Year 2022 Apportionment tables by state for the <a href="https://www.fws.gov/wsfrprograms/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WRFinalApportionment2022.pdf">Wildlife</a> and <a href="https://www.fws.gov/wsfrprograms/Subpages/GrantPrograms/SFR/SFRFinalApportionment2022.pdf">Sport Fish</a> Restoration funds <a href="https://www.fws.gov/wsfrprograms/">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
