<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:13:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden in Press Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/16/remarks-by-president-biden-in-press-conference-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hôtel du Parc des Eaux-VivesGeneva, Switzerland 7:20 P.M. CEST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; It&#8217;s been a long day for you all.&#160; (Laughs.)&#160; I know it was easy getting into the &#8212; the pre-meeting.&#160; There was no problem getting through those doors, was it &#8212; was there?&#160;&#160;Anyway, hello, everyone.&#160; Well, I’ve just finished the &#8212; the last meeting&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Hôtel du Parc des Eaux-Vives<br>Geneva, Switzerland</p>



<p>7:20 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a long day for you all.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I know it was easy getting into the &#8212; the pre-meeting.&nbsp; There was no problem getting through those doors, was it &#8212; was there?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Anyway, hello, everyone.&nbsp; Well, I’ve just finished the &#8212; the last meeting of this week&#8217;s long trip, the U.S.-Russian Summit.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I know there were a lot of hype around this meeting, but it’s pretty straightforward to me &#8212; the meeting.&nbsp; One, there is no substitute, as those of you who have covered me for a while know, for a face-to-face dialogue between leaders.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; And President Putin and I had a &#8212; share a unique responsibility to manage the relationship between two powerful and proud countries &#8212; a relationship that has to be stable and predictable.&nbsp; And it should be able to &#8212; we should be able to cooperate where it&#8217;s in our mutual interests.<br>&nbsp;<br>And where we have differences, I wanted President Putin to understand why I say what I say and why I do what I do, and how we’ll respond to specific kinds of actions that harm America&#8217;s interests.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, I told President Putin my agenda is not against Russia or anyone else; it&#8217;s for the American people: fighting COVID-19; rebuilding our economy; reestablishing our relationships around the world with our allies and friends; and protecting our people.&nbsp; That’s my responsibility as President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I also told him that no President of the United States could keep faith with the American people if they did not speak out to defend our democratic values, to stand up for the universal rights and fundamental freedoms that all men and women have, in our view.&nbsp; That’s just part of the DNA of our country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, human rights is going to always be on the table, I told him.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about just going after Russia when they violate human rights; it&#8217;s about who we are.&nbsp; How could I be the President of the United States of America and not speak out against the violation of human rights?<br>&nbsp;<br>I told him that, unlike other countries, including Russia, we&#8217;re uniquely a product of an idea.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard me say this before, again and again, but I&#8217;m going to keep saying it.&nbsp; What’s that idea?&nbsp; We don&#8217;t derive our rights from the government; we possess them because we&#8217;re born &#8212; period.&nbsp; And we yield them to a government.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, at the forum, I pointed out to him that that’s why we&#8217;re going raise our concerns about cases like Aleksey Navalny.&nbsp; I made it clear to President Putin that we&#8217;ll continue to raise issues of fundamental human rights because that&#8217;s what we are, that&#8217;s who we are.&nbsp; The idea is: &#8220;We hold these truths self-evident that all men and women…&#8221;&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t lived up to it completely, but we&#8217;ve always widened the arc of commitment and included more and more people.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I raised the case of two wrongfully imprisoned American citizens: Paul Whelan and Trevor Reed.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also raised the ability of Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty to operate, and the importance of a free press and freedom of speech.<br>&nbsp;<br>I made it clear that we will not tolerate attempts to violate our democratic sovereignty or destabilize our democratic elections, and we would respond.<br>&nbsp;<br>The bottom line is, I told President Putin that we need to have some basic rules of the road that we can all abide by.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also said there are areas where there&#8217;s a mutual interest for us to cooperate, for our people &#8212; Russian and American people &#8212; but also for the benefit of the world and the security of the world.&nbsp; One of those areas is strategic stability.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You asked me many times what was I going to discuss with Putin.&nbsp; Before I came, I told you I only negotiate with the individual.&nbsp; And now I can tell you what I was intending to do all along, and that is to discuss and raise the issue of strategic stability and try to set up a mechanism whereby we dealt with it.<br>&nbsp;<br>We discussed in detail the next steps our countries need to take on arms control measures &#8212; the steps we need to take to reduce the risk of unintended conflict.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’m pleased that he agreed today to launch a bilateral strategic stability dialogue &#8212; diplomatic speak for saying, get our military experts and our &#8212; our diplomats together to work on a mechanism that can lead to control of new and dangerous and sophisticated weapons that are coming on the scene now that reduce the times of response, that raise the prospects of accidental war.&nbsp; And we went into some detail of what those weapons systems were.<br>&nbsp;<br>Another area we spent a great deal of time on was cyber and cybersecurity.&nbsp; I talked about the proposition that certain critical infrastructure should be off limits to attack &#8212; period &#8212; by cyber or any other means.&nbsp; I gave them a list, if I&#8217;m not mistaken &#8212; I don&#8217;t have it in front of me &#8212; 16 specific entities; 16 defined as critical infrastructure under U.S. policy, from the energy sector to our water systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, the principle is one thing.&nbsp; It has to be backed up by practice.&nbsp; Responsible countries need to take action against criminals who conduct ransomware activities on their territory.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we agreed to task experts in both our &#8212; both our countries to work on specific understandings about what’s off limits and to follow up on specific cases that originate in other countries &#8212; either of our countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>There is a long list of other issues we spent time on, from the urgent need to preserve and reopen the humanitarian corridors in Syria so that we can get food &#8212; just simple food and basic necessities to people who are starving to death; how to build it and how it is in the interest of both Russia and the United States to ensure that Iran &#8212; Iran &#8212; does not acquire nuclear weapons.&nbsp; We agreed to work together there because it&#8217;s as much interest &#8212; Russia&#8217;s interest as ours.&nbsp; And to how we can ensure the Arctic remains a region of cooperation rather than conflict.<br>&nbsp;<br>I caught part of President&#8217;s &#8212; Putin&#8217;s press conference, and he talked about the need for us to be able to have some kind of modus operandi where we dealt with making sure the Arctic was, in fact, a free zone.<br>&nbsp;<br>And to how we can each contribute to the shared effort of preventing a resurgence of terrorism in Afghanistan.&nbsp; It&#8217;s very much in &#8212; in the interest of Russia not to have a resurgence of terrorism in Afghanistan.<br>&nbsp;<br>There are also areas that are more challenging.&nbsp; I communicated the United States’ unwavering commitment to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We agreed to pursue diplomacy related to the Minsk Agreement.&nbsp; And I shared our concerns about Belarus.&nbsp; He didn&#8217;t disagree with what happened; he just has a different perspective of what to do about it.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I know you have a lot of questions, so let me close with this:&nbsp;It was important to meet in person so there can be no mistake about or misrepresentations about what I wanted to communicate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I did what I came to do: Number one, identify areas of practical work our two countries can do to advance our mutual interests and also benefit the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Two, communicate directly &#8212; directly &#8212; that the United States will respond to actions that impair our vital interests or those of our allies.<br>&nbsp;<br>And three, to clearly lay out our country’s priorities and our values so he heard it straight from me.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I must tell you, the tone of the entire meetings &#8212; I guess it was a total of four hours &#8212; was &#8212; was good, positive.&nbsp; There wasn’t any &#8212; any strident action taken.&nbsp; Where we disagreed &#8212; I disagreed, stated where it was.&nbsp; Where he disagreed, he stated.&nbsp; But it was not done in a hyperbolic atmosphere.&nbsp; That is too much of what’s been going on.<br>&nbsp;<br>Over this last week, I believe &#8212; I hope &#8212; the United States has shown the world that we are back, standing with our Allies. &nbsp;We rallied our fellow democracies to make concert &#8212; concerted commitments to take on the biggest challenges our world faces.<br>&nbsp;<br>And now we’ve established a clear basis on how we intend to deal with Russia and the U.S.-Russia relationship.<br>&nbsp;<br>There’s more work ahead.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not suggesting that any of this is done, but we’ve gotten a lot of business done on this trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>And before I take your questions, I want to say one last thing.&nbsp; Folks, look, this is about &#8212; this about how we move from here.&nbsp; This is &#8212; I listened to, again, a significant portion of what President Putin&#8217;s press conference was, and as he pointed out, this is about practical, straightforward, no-nonsense decisions that we have to make or not make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ll find out within the next six months to a year whether or not we actually have a strategic dialogue that matters.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll find out whether we work to deal with everything from release of people in Russian prisons or not.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll find out whether we have a cybersecurity arrangement that begins to bring some order.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Because, look, the countries that most are likely to be damaged &#8212; failure to do that &#8212; are the major countries.&nbsp; For example, when I talked about the pipeline that cyber hit for $5 million &#8212; that ransomware hit in the United States, I looked at him and I said, &#8220;Well, how would you feel if ransomware took on the pipelines from your oil fields?&#8221;&nbsp; He said it would matter.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is not about just our self-interest; it&#8217;s about a mutual self-interest.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll take your questions.&nbsp; And as usual, folks, they gave me a list of the people I&#8217;m going to call on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, Jonathan, Associated Press.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; U.S. intelligence has said that Russia tried to interfere in the last two presidential elections, and that Russia groups are behind hacks like SolarWinds and some of the ransomware attacks you just mentioned.&nbsp; Putin, in his news conference just now, accepted no responsibility for any misbehavior.&nbsp; Your predecessor opted not to demand that Putin stop these disruptions.&nbsp; So what is something concrete, sir, that you achieved today to prevent that from happening again?&nbsp; And what were the consequences you threatened?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;Whether I stopped it from happening again &#8212; he knows I will take action, like we did when &#8212; this last time out. &nbsp;What happened was: We, in fact, made it clear that we were not going to continue to allow this to go on. &nbsp;The end result was we ended up withdrawing &#8212; they went withdrawing ambassadors, and we closed down some of their facilities in the United States, et cetera. &nbsp;And he knows there are consequences.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, look, one of the consequences that I know &#8212; I don&#8217;t know; I shouldn&#8217;t say this; it’s unfair of me &#8212; I suspect you may all think doesn&#8217;t matter, but I&#8217;m confidence it matters to him &#8212; confident it matter to him and other world leaders of big nations: his credibility worldwide shrinks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let&#8217;s get this straight: How would it be if the United States were viewed by the rest of the world as interfering with the elections directly of other countries, and everybody knew it?&nbsp; What would it be like if we engaged in activities that he is engaged in?&nbsp; It diminishes the standing of a country that is desperately trying to make sure it maintains its standing as a major world power.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so it&#8217;s not just what I do; it&#8217;s what the actions that other countries take &#8212; in this case, Russia &#8212; that are contrary to international norms.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the price they pay.&nbsp; They are not &#8212; they are not able to dictate what happens in the world.&nbsp; There are other nations of significant consequence &#8212; i.e. the United States of America being one of them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, just a quick follow on the same theme of consequences.&nbsp; You said, just now, that you spoke to him a lot about human rights.&nbsp; What did you say would happen if opposition leader Aleksey Navalny dies?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I made it clear to him that I believe the consequences of that would be devastating for Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll go back to the same point: What do you think happens when he&#8217;s saying, &#8220;It&#8217;s not about hurting Navalny,&#8221; this &#8212; you know, all the stuff he says to rationalize the treatment of Navalny &#8212; and then he dies in prison?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I pointed out to him that it matters a great deal when a country, in fact &#8212; and they asked me why I thought that it was important to continue to have problems with the President of Syria.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;Because he&#8217;s in violation of an international norm.&nbsp; It&#8217;s called a Chemical Weapons Treaty.&nbsp; Can&#8217;t be trusted.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s about trust.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about their ability to influence other nations in a positive way.<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, would you like to trade our economy for Russia&#8217;s economy?&nbsp; Would you like to trade?&nbsp; And, by the way, we talked about trade.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any problem with doing business with Russia, as long as they do it based upon international norms. It&#8217;s in our interest to see the Russian people do well economically.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a problem with that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But if they do not act according to international norms, then guess what?&nbsp; That will not &#8212; that only won&#8217;t it happen with us, it will not happen with other nations.&nbsp; And he kind of talked about that &#8212; didn&#8217;t he, today? &#8212; about how the need to reach out to other countries to invest in Russia.&nbsp; They won&#8217;t as long as they are convinced that, in fact, the violations &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, the American businessman who was in house arrest.&nbsp; And I pointed out, &#8220;You want to get American business to invest?&nbsp; Let him go.&nbsp; Change the dynamic.”&nbsp; Because American businessmen, they&#8217;re not &#8212; they’re not ready to show up.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t want to hang around in Moscow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, I &#8212; look, guys, I know we make foreign policy out to be this great, great skill that somehow is, sort of, like a secret code.&nbsp; Pract- &#8212; all foreign policy is, is a logical extension of personal relationships.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the way human nature functions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And understand, when you run a country that does not abide by international norms, and yet you need those international norms to be somehow managed so that you can participate in the benefits that flow from them, it hurts you.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a satisfying answer: &#8220;Biden said he&#8217;d invade Russia.&#8221;&nbsp; You know, it is not &#8212; you know.&nbsp; By the way, that was a joke.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not true. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But my generic point is, it is &#8212; it is more complicated than that.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>David Sanger.&nbsp; I thought I saw David.&nbsp; There he is.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; In the run-up to this discussion, there’s been a lot of talk about the two countries spilling down into a Cold War.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if there was anything that you emerged from in the discussion that made you think that he &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; With your permission, I’m going to take my coat off.&nbsp; The sun is hot.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; anything that would make you think that Mr. Putin has decided to move away from his fundamental role as a disrupter, particularly a disrupter of NATO and the United States?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And if I could also just follow up on your description of how you gave him a list of critical infrastructure in the United States.&nbsp; Did you lay out very clearly what it was that the penalty would be for interfering in that critical infrastructure?&nbsp; Did you leave that vague?&nbsp; Did he respond in any way to it?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me answer your first &#8212; well, I’ll second question, first.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I pointed out to him that we have significant cyber capability.&nbsp; And he knows it.&nbsp; He doesn&#8217;t know exactly what it is, but it&#8217;s significant.&nbsp; And if, in fact, they violate these basic norms, we will respond with cyber.&nbsp; He knows.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the cyber way.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; In the cyber way.<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two, I &#8212; I think that the last thing he wants now is a Cold War.&nbsp; Without quoting him &#8212; which I don&#8217;t think is appropriate &#8212; let me ask a rhetorical question: You got a multi-thousand-mile border with China.&nbsp; China is moving ahead, hellbent on election, as they say, seeking to be the most powerful economy in the world and the largest and the most powerful military in the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>You&#8217;re in a situation where your economy is struggling, you need to move it in a more aggressive way, in terms of growing it.&nbsp; And you &#8212; I don&#8217;t think he&#8217;s looking for a Cold War with the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s about a &#8212; as I said to him, I said, “Your generation and mine are about 10 years apart.&nbsp; This is not a &#8216;kumbaya&#8217; moment, as you used to say back in the &#8217;60s in the United States, like, &#8216;Let&#8217;s hug and love each other.&#8217;&nbsp; But it&#8217;s clearly not in anybody&#8217;s interest &#8212; your country’s or mine &#8212; for us to be in a situation where we&#8217;re in a new Cold War.&#8221;&nbsp; And I truly believe he thinks that &#8212; he understands that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But that does not mean he&#8217;s ready to, quote, figuratively speaking, “lay down his arms,” and say, “Come on.”&nbsp; He still, I believe, is concerned about being, quote, “encircled.”&nbsp; He still is concerned that we, in fact, are looking to take him down, et cetera.&nbsp; He still has those concerns, but I don&#8217;t think they are the driving force as to the kind of relationship he&#8217;s looking for with the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Jennifer.&nbsp; Jennifer Jacobs.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Is there a particular reason why the summit lasted only about three hours?&nbsp; We know you had maybe allotted four to five hours.&nbsp; Was there any reason it ran shorter?<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, did &#8212; President Putin said that there were no threats or scare tactics issued.&nbsp; Do you agree with that assessment, that there were no threats or scare tactics?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, did you touch on Afghanistan and the safe withdrawal of troops?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes, yes, and yes.&nbsp; Let me go back to the first part.<br>&nbsp;<br>The reason it didn&#8217;t go longer is: When is the last time two heads of state have spent over two hours in direct conversation across a table, going into excruciating detail?&nbsp; You may know of a time; I don&#8217;t.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t think of one.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we didn&#8217;t need, as we got through, when we brought in the larger group &#8212; our defense, our intelligence, and our foreign &#8212; well, our &#8212; my foreign minister &#8212; wasn’t the foreign minister &#8212; my Secretary of State was with me the whole time &#8212; our ambassador, et cetera.&nbsp; We brought everybody in.&nbsp; We had covered so much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so there was a summary done by him and by me of what we covered.&nbsp; Lavrov and Blinken talked about what we had covered.&nbsp; We raised things that required more amplification or made sure we didn&#8217;t have any misunderstandings.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so it was &#8212; it was &#8212; kind of, after two hours there, we looked at each other like, “Okay, what next?”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What is going to happen next is we&#8217;re going to be able to look back &#8212; look ahead in three to six months, and say, “Did the things we agreed to sit down and try to work out, did it work?&nbsp; Do we &#8212; are we closer to a major strategic stability talks and progress?&nbsp; Are we further along in terms of…” &#8212; and go down the line.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to be the test.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not sitting here saying because the President and I agreed that we would do these things, that all of a sudden, it&#8217;s going to work.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not saying that.&nbsp; What I&#8217;m saying is I think there&#8217;s a genuine prospect to significantly improve relations between our two countries without us giving up a single, solitary thing based on principle and/or values.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There were no threats issued?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no, no.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; There were no threats.&nbsp; There were &#8212; as a matter of fact, I heard he quoted my mom and quoted other people today.&nbsp; There was &#8212; it was very, as we say &#8212; which will shock you, coming from me &#8212; somewhat colloquial.&nbsp; And we talked about basic, basic, fundamental things.&nbsp; There was a &#8212; it was &#8212; and you know how I am: I explain things based on personal basis.&nbsp; “What happens if,” for example.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, there are no threats, just simple assertions made.&nbsp; And no “Well, if you do that, then we&#8217;ll do this” &#8212; wasn’t anything I said.&nbsp; It was just letting him know where I stood; what I thought we could accomplish together; and what, in fact &#8212; if it was &#8212; if there were violations of American sovereignty, what would we do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you share what you asked him about Afghanistan?&nbsp; What was your particular request for Afghanistan and the U.S. troops?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, he asked us about Afghanistan.&nbsp; He said that he hopes that we&#8217;re able to maintain some peace and security, and I said, “That has a lot to do with you.”&nbsp; He indicated that he was prepared to, quote, “help” on Afghanistan &#8212; I won&#8217;t go into detail now; and help on &#8212; on Iran; and help on &#8212; and, in return, we told him what we wanted to do relative to bringing some stability and economic security or physical security to the people of Syria and Libya.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we had those discussions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Yamiche.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much, Mr. President.&nbsp; Did you &#8212; you say that you didn&#8217;t issue any threats.&nbsp; Were there any ultimatums made when it comes to ransomware?&nbsp; And how will you measure success, especially when it comes to these working groups on Russian meddling and on cybersecurity?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, it’s going to be real easy.&nbsp; They either &#8212; for example, on cybersecurity, are we going to work out where they take action against ransomware criminals on Russian territory?&nbsp; They didn&#8217;t do it.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think they planned it, in this case.&nbsp; And they &#8212; are they going to act?&nbsp; We&#8217;ll find out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Will we commit &#8212; what can we commit to act in terms of anything affecting violating international norms that negatively affects Russia?&nbsp; What are we going to agree to do?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I think we have real opportunities to &#8212; to move.&nbsp; And I think that one of the things that I noticed when we had the larger meeting is that people who are very, very well-informed started thinking, “You know, this could be a real problem.”&nbsp; What happens if that ransomware outfit were sitting in Florida or Maine and took action, as I said, on their &#8212; their single lifeline to their economy: oil?&nbsp; That would be devastating.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re like &#8212; you could see them kind of go, &#8220;Oh, we do that,&#8221; but like, &#8220;Whoa.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>So it&#8217;s in &#8212; it&#8217;s in everybody&#8217;s interest that these things be acted on.&nbsp; We’ll see, though, what happens from these groups we put together.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask a quick follow-up question?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; The third one, yes.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, when President Putin was questioned today about human rights, he said the reason why he&#8217;s cracking down on opposition leaders is because he doesn&#8217;t want something like January 6th to happen in Russia.&nbsp; And he also said he doesn&#8217;t want to see groups formed like Black Lives Matter.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your response to that, please?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; My response is kind of what I communicated &#8212; that I think that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a ridiculous comparison.&nbsp; It&#8217;s one thing for literally criminals to break through cordon, go into the Capitol, kill a police officer, and be held unaccountable than it is for people objecting and marching on the Capitol and saying, “You are not allowing me to speak freely.&nbsp; You are not allowing me to do A, B, C, or D.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, they&#8217;re very different criteria.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Steve.&nbsp; Steve Holland, Reuters.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President &#8212; sorry &#8212; President Putin said he was satisfied with the answer about your comment about him being a &#8220;killer.&#8221;&nbsp; Could you give us your side on this?&nbsp; What did you tell him?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He’s satisfied.&nbsp; Why would I bring it up again?&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And now that you’ve talked to him, do you believe you can trust him?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, this is not about trust; this is about self-interest and verification of self-interest.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it&#8217;s about.&nbsp; So, I &#8212; virtually almost &#8212; almost anyone that I would work out an agreement with that affected the American people&#8217;s interests, I don&#8217;t say, “Well, I trust you.&nbsp; No problem.&#8221;&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see what happens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, as that old expression goes, “The proof of the pudding is in the eating.”&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to know shortly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Igor, Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, Mr. President.&nbsp; Hello, Mr. President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You want to go on the shade?&nbsp; You can&#8217;t &#8212; can you see?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah, yeah.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, I think you know attacks in civil society and the free &#8212; free press continue inside Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For example, Radio Free Europe &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Radio Liberty; Voice of America; Current Time TV channel, where I work, are branded foreign agents &#8212; and several other independent media.&nbsp; So, we are essentially being forced out in Russia 30 years after President Yeltsin invited us in.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My question is: After your talks with President Putin, how interested do you think he is in improving the media climate in Russia?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t put it that way, in terms of improving the climate.&nbsp; I would, in fact, put it in terms of how much interest does he have in burnishing Russia&#8217;s reputation that is not &#8212; is viewed as not being contrary to democratic principles and free speech.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s a judgment I cannot make.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s not because I think he &#8212; he is interested in changing the nature of a closed society or closed government&#8217;s actions relative to what he thinks is the right of government to do what it does; it&#8217;s a very different approach.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, there&#8217;s a couple of really good biogra- &#8212; I told him I read a couple &#8212; I read most everything he&#8217;s written and the speeches he&#8217;s made.&nbsp; And &#8212; and I&#8217;ve read a couple of very good biographies, which many of you have as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think I pointed out to him that Russia had an opportunity &#8212; that brief shining moment after Gorbachev and after things began to change drastically &#8212; to actually generate a democratic government.&nbsp; But what happened was it failed and there was a great, great race among Russian intellectuals to determine what form of government would they choose and how would they choose it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And based on what I believe, Mr. Putin decided was that Russia has always been a major international power when it&#8217;s been totally united as a Russian state, not based on ideology &#8212; whether it was going back to Tsar and Commissar, straight through to the &#8212; the revolution &#8212; the Russian Revolution, and to where they are today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that it&#8217;s clear to me &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said it &#8212; that I think he decided that the way for Russia to be able to sustain itself as a great &#8212; quote, “great power” is to in fact unite the Russian people on just the strength of the government &#8212; the government controls &#8212; not necessarily ideologically, but the government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that&#8217;s the &#8212; that&#8217;s the choice that was made.&nbsp; I think it &#8212; I &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to second guess whether it could have been fundamentally different.&nbsp; But I do think it does not lend itself to Russia maintaining itself as one of the great powers in the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, one more question &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on COVID &#8212; on COVID-19, Mr. President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, could we ask you one more question, please, sir?&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; Did military response ever come up in this conversation today?&nbsp; Did you &#8212; in terms of the red lines that you laid down, is military response an option for a ransomware attack?<br>&nbsp;<br>And President Putin had called you, in his press conference, an “experienced person.”&nbsp; You famously told him he didn&#8217;t have a soul.&nbsp; Do you now have a deeper understanding of him after this meeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But on the military &#8212; military response, sir?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, we didn&#8217;t talk about military response.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the spirit, Mr. President, of you saying that there is no substitute for face-to-face dialogue, and also with what you said at NATO that the biggest problems right now are Russia and China &#8212; you&#8217;ve spoken many times about how you have spent perhaps more time with President Xi than any other world leader.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So is there going to become a time where you might call him, old friend to old friend, and ask him to open up China to the World Health Organization investigators who are trying to get to the bottom of COVID-19?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get something straight.&nbsp; We know each other well; we&#8217;re not old friends.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just pure business.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I guess, my question would be that you&#8217;ve said that you were going to press China.&nbsp; You signed on to the G7 communiqué that said you &#8212; the G7 were calling on China to open up to let the investigators in.&nbsp; But China basically says they don&#8217;t want to be interfered with anymore.&nbsp; So, what happens now?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The impact &#8212; the world&#8217;s attitude toward China as it develops.&nbsp; China is trying very hard to project itself as a responsible and &#8212; and a very, very forthcoming nation; that they are trying very hard to talk about how they&#8217;re taking and helping the world in terms of COVID-19 and vaccines.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re trying very hard.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, certain things you don&#8217;t have to explain to the people of the world.&nbsp; They see the results.&nbsp; Is China really actually trying to get to the bottom of this?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One thing we did discuss, as I told you, in the EU and at the G7 and with NATO: What we should be doing and what I&#8217;m going to make an effort to do is rally the world to work on what is going to be the physical mechanism available to detect, early on, the next pandemic and have a mechanism by which we can respond to it and respond to it early.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to happen.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to happen.&nbsp; And we need to do that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any progress on the detained Americans, sir?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did Putin say about Paul Whelan and Trevor Reed?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, what do you say to the families of the detained Americans?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, why are you so confident Russia &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The families of the detained Americans, I have hope for.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Say it again; we can&#8217;t hear you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I said the families of the detained Americans came up and we discussed it.&nbsp; We’re going to follow through with that discussion.&nbsp; I am &#8212; I am not going to walk away on that issue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why are you so confident he&#8217;ll change his behavior, Mr. President?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not confident he&#8217;ll change his behavior.&nbsp; Where the hell &#8212; what do you do all the time?&nbsp; When did I say I was confident?&nbsp; I said &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said in the next six months you&#8217;ll be able to determine &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I said &#8212; what I said was &#8212; let&#8217;s get it straight.&nbsp; I said: What will change their behavior is if the rest of world reacts to them and it diminishes their standing in the world.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not confident of anything; I&#8217;m just stating a fact.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But given his past behavior has not changed and, in that press conference, after sitting down with you for several hours, he denied any involvement in cyberattacks; he downplayed human rights abuses; he even refused to say Aleksey Navalny’s name.&nbsp; So how does that account to a constructive meeting, as President &#8212; President Putin framed it?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If you don’t understand that, you&#8217;re in the wrong business.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>7:53 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Russia Presidential Joint Statement on Strategic Stability</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/16/u-s-russia-presidential-joint-statement-on-strategic-stability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 17:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, President of the United States of America Joseph R. Biden and President of the Russian Federation Vladimir Putin, note the United States and Russia have demonstrated that, even in periods of tension, they are able to make progress on our shared goals of ensuring predictability in the strategic sphere, reducing the risk of armed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We, President of the United States of America Joseph R. Biden and President of the Russian Federation Vladimir Putin, note the United States and Russia have demonstrated that, even in periods of tension, they are able to make progress on our shared goals of ensuring predictability in the strategic sphere, reducing the risk of armed conflicts and the threat of nuclear war.</p>



<p>The recent extension of the New START Treaty exemplifies our commitment to nuclear arms control. Today, we reaffirm the principle that a nuclear war cannot be won and must never be fought.</p>



<p>Consistent with these goals, the United States and Russia will embark together on an integrated bilateral Strategic Stability Dialogue in the near future that will be deliberate and robust. Through this Dialogue, we seek to lay the groundwork for future arms control and risk reduction measures.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on DACA Day</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-daca-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 22:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dreamers are Americans.&#160; Many have spent most of their lives in the United States.&#160; They live, study, work, and worship in our communities.&#160; They have served on the frontlines during the COVID-19 pandemic.&#160; In 2012, the Obama-Biden Administration created the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) policy.&#160; Since that date, DACA has allowed more than&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dreamers are Americans.&nbsp; Many have spent most of their lives in the United States.&nbsp; They live, study, work, and worship in our communities.&nbsp; They have served on the frontlines during the COVID-19 pandemic.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>In 2012, the Obama-Biden Administration created the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) policy.&nbsp; Since that date, DACA has allowed more than 800,000 immigrant youth who came to the United States as children to temporarily remain in our country, work lawfully, pursue their education and long for the day they could become citizens.</p>



<p>Twenty years ago, Congress introduced the first version of the bipartisan Dream Act, led by Senator Durbin (D-IL) and former Republican Senator Hatch.&nbsp; And over the years, bipartisan coalitions of lawmakers championed this bill.&nbsp; The&nbsp; American public overwhelmingly supports this legislation. But time and time again, the Senate has failed to act.</p>



<p>Only Congress can provide a permanent legislative fix to provide lasting stability for these young people and their families.  My immigration bill, the U.S. Citizenship Act, creates a pathway to citizenship for undocumented individuals in our country, including Dreamers.  In March, the House took a critical first step and passed the American Dream and Promise Act.   Congress must find a way to pass these legislative solutions and I will continue to work towards passage of legislation protecting Dreamers and creating a path to citizenship for  undocumented immigrants. These young people represent the best of America and we can’t let them down.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with President Guy Parmelin and Foreign Minister Ignazio Cassis of Switzerland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-guy-parmelin-and-foreign-minister-ignazio-cassis-of-switzerland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 22:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21121</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Guy Parmelin and Foreign Minister Ignazio Cassis of Switzerland.  President Biden thanked President Parmelin for hosting the U.S.-Russia Summit in Geneva on June 16, and he expressed appreciation for Switzerland’s unique historical role providing a neutral ground for diplomacy and negotiations.  The leaders discussed the strong&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Guy Parmelin and Foreign Minister Ignazio Cassis of Switzerland.  President Biden thanked President Parmelin for hosting the U.S.-Russia Summit in Geneva on June 16, and he expressed appreciation for Switzerland’s unique historical role providing a neutral ground for diplomacy and negotiations.  The leaders discussed the strong U.S.-Switzerland commercial, science and education, and security relationships.  President Biden thanked Switzerland for its 40 years of service as the U.S. Protecting Power in Iran.  He also welcomed Switzerland’s contribution to the global COVID-19 pandemic response including by hosting the Gavi vaccine alliance secretariat and its contributions to COVAX to facilitate equitable access and distribution of safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Action the Biden-Harris Administration Has Taken to Address the Border Challenge</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/action-the-biden-harris-administration-has-taken-to-address-the-border-challenge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden-Harris administration is working to rebuild our immigration system after four years of chaos and mismanagement. The trend of border apprehensions in May is a reduction of individuals (unique encounters) and families below the peak in 2019. Border numbers fluctuate, however, based on annual migration trends and that is why this administration is working&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden-Harris administration is working to rebuild our immigration system after four years of chaos and mismanagement. The trend of border apprehensions in <a href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/national-media-release/cbp-announces-may-2021-operational-update">May</a> is a reduction of individuals (unique encounters) and families below the peak in 2019. Border numbers fluctuate, however, based on annual migration trends and that is why this administration is working to establish lawful pathways for individuals to migrate or seek protection, address the root causes of migration, restore fair, orderly and humane means to apply for asylum and deter irregular migration. The administration has made significant progress at establishing a well-managed and secure border while also treating people fairly and humanely.&nbsp; The American people support this approach.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Improved Processing of Unaccompanied Children&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>The administration successfully reduced the number of unaccompanied children in U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) facilities <strong>from 5,676 in late March to 570 </strong>on June 14<strong>.</strong></li><li>The administration reduced the average amount of time children are in CBP facilities to <strong>26 hours, compared with 131 hours on April 1<sup>st</sup>.</strong></li><li>The administration has reduced the number of unaccompanied children in the care of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to <strong>under 16,000 from over 22,000 in late April.</strong><br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Removed Barriers to Unifying Children with Parents and Sponsors</strong><ul><li>HHS has surged case management resources to <strong>dramatically increase the rates by which children are united with their sponsors</strong>.</li><li>DHS and HHS <strong>rescinded an agreement from the former administration</strong> that subjected undocumented parents to immigration enforcement when they came forward to claim their child.</li><li>HHS <strong>expanded access to fingerprinting sites</strong> to conduct background checks on sponsors that has resulted in reduced backlogs and long-distance travel for sponsors.</li><li>With support from the United States Digital Service, HHS implemented <strong>the UC Bed Census</strong> that assists facilities and licensed providers with <strong>reporting bed capacity data, thereby improving bed count accuracy and data collection</strong>.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Put in Place Orderly Processes and Protocols at the Border</strong><ul><li>Through support and coordination with the Government of Mexico, the Department of State (State), and international organization partners, DHS has successfully processed over <strong>11,900 eligible people who had been returned to Mexico under the Migrant Protection Protocols (MPP) </strong>to reenter the United States to pursue their active U.S. immigration cases in a safe and orderly manner.</li><li>DHS has developed a partnership model, working with community-based organizations, cities, and counties <strong>to ensure that family units and single adults released from DHS custody are COVID tested and isolated in compliance with CDC recommendations.</strong></li></ul></li><li><strong>Expanded Lawful Pathways for Protection and Opportunity</strong><ul><li>DHS announced the availability of <strong>6,000 temporary, non-agricultural worker – or H-2B – visas</strong> for nationals of Honduras, El Salvador and Guatemala for FY 2021.</li><li>State and DHS <strong>reopened the Central American Minors (CAM) program</strong> to reunite children who are nationals of El Salvador, Guatemala or Honduras with their parents in the U.S. through refugee resettlement or humanitarian parole. On June 15th, State and DHS announced the second phase of CAM, which will expand access to the program to legal guardians (in addition to parents) and to U.S.-based parents or legal guardians who have a pending asylum application or pending U visa petition filed before May 15, 2021.</li><li>State and DHS resumed interviewing individuals via the <strong>Protection Transfer Arrangement (PTA)</strong> to expand protection for vulnerable nationals of El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.</li><li>The President issued a new FY 2021 Presidential Determination on refugees that created <strong>4,000 additional slots for refugees</strong> from Latin America and the Caribbean, which includes the Northern Triangle.</li><li>State is supporting the <strong>Regional Conference on Migration (RCM)</strong> through U.S.&nbsp; partner organizations to <strong>promote humane practices in labor migration agreements</strong> in the region.&nbsp; In late May, 61 participants from 11 RCM member countries, the private sector, and civil society organizations exchanged best practices on fair recruitment and protection of migrant workers.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Enhanced Migration Management</strong><ul><li>On June 10, the U.S. Government announced an additional $57 million in funds, including $46 million the President authorized from the Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund, to support <strong>urgent humanitarian needs of vulnerable refugees and migrants in Central America</strong> and third countries in the region, including the compounding effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on forced displacement.&nbsp; <strong>This builds on the $310 million in humanitarian support for the region announced in April.</strong>&nbsp;</li><li>The Department of State opened the first <strong>Migration Resource Center (MRC)</strong> in Guatemala to provide individuals with protection screenings and referrals to asylum, refugee resettlement, and parole options.&nbsp; The MRC will also have referrals for labor and reintegration programs for individuals who do not have protection needs.</li><li>The Department of Justice, with support from the Department of State, will create a <strong>regional task force to identify, disrupt, and prevent migrant smuggling and human trafficking operations</strong>.&nbsp;</li><li>DHS implemented “Operation Sentinel” – a U.S. government effort to <strong>crack down on international criminal organizations engaged in migrant smuggling </strong>by targeting their ability to travel, trade, and access financial assets in the United States. &nbsp;</li><li>On her trip to Guatemala, the Vice President announced a new <strong>Human Smuggling and Trafficking Task Force</strong> that will identify, disrupt, and prevent migrant smuggling and human trafficking operations.</li><li>On her trip to Mexico, the Vice President announced that U.S. and Mexican law enforcement agencies will partner to exchange information and take appropriate actions to address the shared priority of <strong>disabling human trafficking and human smuggling organizations.</strong></li><li>Mexico is <strong>increasing border checkpoints</strong> and <strong>deployed more than 12,000 security personnel to southern Mexico</strong>.</li><li>Mexico <strong>received 31,800 asylum requests</strong> from January to April, compared to 18,500 during the same period in 2019.</li><li>State has nearly <strong>quadrupled the number of radio ads in Central America</strong> to discourage irregular migration compared to January.&nbsp; State continues to run a comprehensive digital marketing campaign in the region, emphasizing the value of staying with family and building a better life at home.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Addressed the Root Causes of Migration</strong><ul><li>Demonstrated a strong U.S. commitment to good governance by <strong>redirecting&nbsp;funding for certain Salvadoran government institutions</strong> in response to democratic backsliding.</li><li>On her trip to Guatemala, the Vice President announced that the Department of Justice, with support from the Department of State, will create an <strong>anticorruption task force</strong> that will include U.S. prosecutors and law enforcement experts to investigate and prosecute corruption cases with a nexus in the United States, Guatemala, and the region.&nbsp;</li><li>On her trip to Guatemala, the Vice President announced that USAID and DFC will provide up to <strong>$48M in U.S. government resources to advance economic opportunity in Guatemala</strong> through support for entrepreneurs and innovators, expanding access to affordable housing, agricultural businesses, and development of micro, small, and medium enterprises.</li><li>USAID launched a three-year regional initiative to support local partners in the Northern Triangle to <strong>increase community resilience</strong> in the face of poverty, violence, poor governance, corruption, and climate change.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>To increase security in the region, <strong>USAID trained police officers</strong> on domestic violence procedures, trained investigators and analysts on the prosecution of human smuggling cases, and State Department-supported partners <strong>identified 19 human smugglers</strong> with outstanding warrants in the United States.</li><li>On her trip to Guatemala, the Vice President announced that USAID will provide up to $40 million over three years to launch the <strong>Young Women’s Empowerment Initiative that will focus on creating opportunities for young, primarily indigenous women.&nbsp;</strong></li><li>On her trip to Mexico, the Vice President witnessed the signing of an MOU between the United States and Mexico. &nbsp;This MOU establishes a partnership to <strong>address the lack of economic opportunities in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras by fostering agricultural development and youth empowerment programs</strong> in these countries to address the root causes of migration.<br></li></ul></li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 20:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Paloma Adams-Allen, of the District of Columbia, to be a Deputy Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Bonnie Glick. &#160; &#160; &#160;Tovah R. Calderon, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals for the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Paloma Adams-Allen, of the District of Columbia, to be a Deputy Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Bonnie Glick.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Tovah R. Calderon, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals for the term of fifteen years, vice Kathryn A. Oberly, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jia M. Cobb, of Virginia, to be United States District Judge for the District of Columbia, vice Emmet G. Sullivan, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Isobel Coleman, of New York, to be a Deputy Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, Jenny A. McGee.</p>



<p>     William E. Holloway, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the National Institute of Building Sciences for a term expiring September 7, 2021, vice Mary B. Verner, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;William E. Holloway, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the National Institute of Building Sciences for a term expiring September 7, 2024. &nbsp;(Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Amanda Howe, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, vice Craig Hooks, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Kenia Seoane Lopez, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the term of fifteen years, vice Ronna Lee Beck, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Sarah A.L. Merriam, of Connecticut, to be United States District Judge for the District of Connecticut, vice Janet C. Hall, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Sarala Vidya Nagala, of Connecticut, to be United States District Judge for the District of Connecticut, vice Vanessa Lynne Bryant, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Florence Y. Pan, of the District of Columbia, to be United States District Judge for the District of Columbia, vice Ketanji Brown Jackson, resigning.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Myrna Pérez, of New York, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Second Circuit, vice Denny Chin, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Javier Ramirez, of Illinois, to be Federal Mediation and Conciliation Director, vice Richard Giacolone.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Omar Antonio Williams, of Connecticut, to be United States District Judge for the District of Connecticut, vice Alvin W. Thompson, retired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp; &nbsp; ###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces His Intent to Nominate Nine More Individuals to Serve as Ambassadors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/president-biden-announces-his-intent-to-nominate-nine-more-individuals-to-serve-as-ambassadors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals – including four career members of the Senior Foreign Service – as ambassadors to represent the United States on the world stage: Julie Chung, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka Sharon L. Cromer,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals – including four career members of the Senior Foreign Service – as ambassadors to represent the United States on the world stage:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Julie Chung, </strong>Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka</li><li><strong>Sharon L. Cromer</strong><strong>, </strong>Nominee for U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of The Gambia</li><li><strong>Troy Damian Fitrell</strong>, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Guinea</li><li><strong>Thomas R. Nides</strong>, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the State of Israel</li><li><strong>Marc Ostfield</strong>, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Paraguay</li><li><strong>Ken Salazar</strong>, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the United Mexican States</li><li><strong>Julianne Smith</strong><strong>, </strong>Nominee for the United States Permanent Representative on the Council of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary</li><li><strong>C. B. “Sully” Sullenberger, III, </strong>Nominee for the rank of Ambassador during his tenure of service as Representative of the United States of America on the Council of the International Civil Aviation Organization</li><li><strong>Dr. Cynthia Ann Telles</strong>, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Costa Rica</li></ul>



<p>In April, President Biden announced his intent to nominate nine career foreign service officers as ambassadors.<br><br><strong>Julie Jiyoon Chung, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><br>Julie Chung, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the Acting Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs at the U.S. Department of State.&nbsp; She was previously Director of the Office of Japanese Affairs at the Department.&nbsp; She has served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Phnom Penh, Cambodia and Economic Counselor at the U.S. Embassy in Bangkok, Thailand.&nbsp; Earlier, Chung was Chief of Staff to the Transition Coordinator at the U.S. Embassy in Baghdad, Iraq.&nbsp; She has also served at the U.S. embassies in Colombia, Vietnam and Japan, and the U.S. Consulate General in Guangzhou, China.&nbsp; She is a Pickering Fellow.&nbsp; Chung earned a B.A. at the University of California-San Diego and an M.A. at Columbia University’s School of International and Public Affairs.&nbsp; She is the recipient of numerous awards, including the Secretary’s Distinguished Honor Award. Chung speaks Korean, Japanese, Spanish, and Khmer.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Sharon L. Cromer, Nominee for U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of The Gambia</strong><br>Sharon L. Cromer, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Career Minister, currently serves as the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Mission Director at the U.S. Embassy, Accra, Ghana. Previously she was the USAID Mission Director at the U.S. Embassy Dar es Salaam, Tanzania and she has also been USAID Mission Director at the U.S. Embassy in Abuja, Nigeria. In addition, Cromer also had an earlier assignment in Accra as Mission Director. In Washington, Cromer served as Senior Deputy Assistant Administrator and Acting Assistant Administrator in the Africa Bureau of USAID and also as the Deputy Assistant Administrator of the USAID Management Bureau. Among her other assignments, Cromer was first a Supervisory Contracting Officer, and then the USAID Deputy Mission Director, at the U.S. Embassy Jakarta, Indonesia. Early in her career, Cromer served as a Contracting Officer in Senegal, Ivory Coast, and Pakistan. Cromer earned her B.A. from Barnard College, Columbia University and her J.D. degree from Georgetown University Law School.<br><br><strong>Troy Damian Fitrell, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Guinea</strong><br>Troy Fitrell, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Counselor, is the Director of the Office of West African Affairs at the Department of State. He has served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. embassies in Ethiopia and Mauritius, as Deputy Director of the Department’s Office of Southern African Affairs, and as Deputy Director of the Office of International Security Cooperation in the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs. He was Senior Advisor to the United States Special Envoy for the Great Lakes of Africa, coordinating U.S. policy on the cross-border security, political, and economic issues in the Great Lakes region. Fitrell served as a Pearson Fellow on the staff of the House Foreign Affairs Committee and was a Watch Officer in the Department’s Nuclear Risk Reduction Center. He also served overseas at the U.S. embassies in Portugal, Guatemala, Zambia, Ghana and Denmark. Fitrell earned a B.A. at the University of Maryland and an M.S. at the National War College. He speaks French, Spanish, Portuguese, Swedish and Danish.<br><br><strong>Thomas R. Nides, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the State of Israel</strong><br>Thomas Nides is a distinguished public servant and business leader. Nides was the State Department’s Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources from 2010 – 2013. Earlier, Nides was Morgan Stanley’s Chief Administrative Officer, Chief Operating Officer and Secretary of the Board, the President and Chief Executive Officer of Burson-Marsteller, in New York and the Chief Administrative Officer of Credit Suisse First Boston in Washington, D.C. Nides was Chief of Staff to the U.S. Trade Representative Micky Kantor, was Senior Advisor to Speaker of the House Thomas S. Foley, and earlier to House Majority Whip Tony Coelho. He currently serves on the boards of the Partnership for Public Service, the International Rescue Committee, the Atlantic Council and the Urban Alliance Foundation, and currently serves as the Managing Director and Vice Chairman of Morgan Stanley. He is a Member of the Council on Foreign Relations and the former Chairman of the Board of the Woodrow Wilson Center appointed by President Obama. Nides received his B.A. degree from the University of Minnesota. He is the recipient of the Secretary of State’s Distinguished Service Award.<br><br><strong>Marc Ostfield, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Paraguay</strong><br>Marc Ostfield, a career member of the Senior Executive Service, is the Ombudsman of the U.S. Department of State. With over 30 years in foreign policy and national security, he has served in senior State Department roles, including as Acting Director/Deputy Director of the Foreign Service Institute (National Foreign Affairs Training Center); Director, Office of Policy and Global Issues in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs; Senior Foreign Affairs Officer for Science and Technology Cooperation; and Senior Advisor for Bioterrorism, Biodefense, and Health Security. Earlier, he created, led, and evaluated global health programs in Latin America and worldwide with international organizations, including as Chief of Behavior Change Communication for Family Health International. He is the recipient of a Presidential Rank Award, numerous State Department awards, the Meritorious Unit Award from the U.S. National Counterterrorism Center, the Diplomacy Fellowship from the American Association for the Advancement of Science, and the President’s Volunteer Service Award as a volunteer firefighter. Ostfield earned a B.A., M.S., and Ph.D. from the University of Pennsylvania. He speaks Spanish, Portuguese, French, and Arabic.<br><br><strong>Ken Salazar, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the United Mexican States</strong><br>Ken Salazar has served as U.S. Secretary of the Interior, Colorado U.S. Senator, and Colorado Attorney General. In 1998, Salazar was elected as Colorado Attorney General and became the first Latino ever elected to statewide office in Colorado. He was reelected as Attorney General in 2002. In 2004, Salazar was elected to the U.S. Senate for Colorado becoming the first Latino democrat to be elected to the United States Senate since 1972. During the Obama Administration, he served as Secretary of the Interior, where he had a lead role on energy and climate, and the nation’s conservation agenda. A native of Colorado, Salazar is a fifth-generation rancher in Colorado’s San Luis Valley. He is a partner at WilmerHale, an American law firm and the founder of the firm’s Denver office. Salazar represents clients on energy, environment, natural resources and Native American matters. Salazar has a B.S. from Colorado College and a J.D. from the University of Michigan. He also has honorary degrees from the Colorado School of Mines, the University of Massachusetts Lowell, the University of Colorado School of Law, the University of Denver School of Law, and Colorado College. His native language is Spanish.<br><br><strong>Julianne Smith, Nominee for the United States Permanent Representative on the Council of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary</strong><br>Julianne “Julie” Smith is currently serving as a Senior Advisor to the Secretary of State at the Department of State. Previously, she served as the Director of the Asia and Geopolitics Programs at the German Marshall Fund of the United States. From 2014 – 2018, she served as the Director of the Transatlantic Security Program at the Center for a New American Security (CNAS). Prior to joining CNAS, Julie served in the Obama administration. From 2012-2013, she served as both the Acting National Security Advisor and the Deputy National Security Advisor to Vice President Joseph Biden. Before the White House, she served as the Principal Director for European and NATO Policy in the Office of the Secretary of Defense in the Pentagon for three years. In 2012, she was awarded the Office of the Secretary of Defense Medal for Exceptional Public Service. Earlier in her career, Smith directed the Europe Program at the Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS). A native of Michigan, she received her B.A. from Xavier University and her M.A. from American University. She speaks German and French.<br><br><strong>C. B. “Sully” Sullenberger, III, Nominee for the rank of Ambassador during his tenure of service as Representative of the United States of America on the Council of the International Civil Aviation Organization</strong><br>C. B. “Sully” Sullenberger, III is a former United States Air Force fighter pilot, retired airline pilot, safety expert and keynote speaker.&nbsp; In 2009, as captain of US Airways flight 1549, he and his crew guided their aircraft to a successful emergency landing in the Hudson River with no fatalities.&nbsp; He has served as a NASA aviation safety research consultant.&nbsp; As an Air Line Pilots Association accident investigation committee member, he participated in a National Transportation Safety Board investigation of a major airline accident, leading to improved airline procedures and training for emergency evacuation.&nbsp; Sullenberger has a B.S. from the United States Air Force Academy, an M.S. from Purdue University and an M.A. from the University of Northern Colorado.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Dr. Cynthia Ann Telles, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Costa Rica</strong><br>Dr. Cynthia Telles is a Clinical Professor in the UCLA Department of Psychiatry at the UCLA David Geffen School of Medicine and serves on the Executive Committee of the UCLA Semel Institute for Neuroscience and Human Behavior. For over three decades, Telles has also been the Director of the UCLA Spanish-Speaking Psychosocial Clinic and is the founding and current Director of the UCLA Hispanic Neuropsychiatric Center of Excellence. She has served on the Board of the Pacific Council on International Policy, was the Chair of the Los Angeles/U.S. Section of the Mexico-Los Angeles Commission and has also engaged on numerous City of Los Angeles Commissions including on the Board of Airport Commissioners. On the national level Telles has been a member of the White House Commission on Presidential Scholars and the National Advisory Council of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services. Currently, she serves on the Board of the Kaiser Foundation Health Plan and Hospitals. She was a founding Board member of Americas United Bank, the first Hispanic commercial bank to be chartered in California in over 30 years. Her numerous philanthropic partnerships included service as the Chair of the California Community Foundation and as a member, Vice-Chair, and Chair of the Board of The California Endowment, the largest health foundation in California. Telles received a B.A. from Smith College and a Ph.D. in Clinical Psychology from Boston University. She speaks and reads Spanish fluently.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Gaggle by Senior Administration Officials En Route Geneva, Switzerland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/15/background-press-gaggle-by-senior-administration-officials-en-route-geneva-switzerland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 16:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Geneva, Switzerland 3:58 P.M. CEST&#160;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Okay, welcome to our flight to Geneva, Switzerland, on day seven of a lovely trip.&#160;I’m going to start by just giving an overview of the logistics for tomorrow so you all have an understanding of what the day looks like.&#160;So, around 1:00 p.m.,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Geneva, Switzerland</p>



<p>3:58 P.M. CEST<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay, welcome to our flight to Geneva, Switzerland, on day seven of a lovely trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’m going to start by just giving an overview of the logistics for tomorrow so you all have an understanding of what the day looks like.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, around 1:00 p.m., President Putin is expected to arrive &#8212; should be the first to arrive at the villa where the event is taking place, where the meeting is taking place.&nbsp; He will be greeted by the Swiss President on arrival and taken inside.&nbsp; President Biden will arrive after President Putin and will also be taken back inside.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Inside, they&#8217;ll share a short greeting with the Swiss President.&nbsp; They will, all three of them, walk back outside where there will be a &#8212; there will be press present for that moment.&nbsp; The only person who is expected to speak during that moment is the Swiss President.<br>&nbsp;<br>They will then go back inside and they will move into a smaller meeting &#8212; P plus one &#8212; on both sides.&nbsp; Then, after that meeting, there will be &#8212; there&#8217;s expected to be &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The P plus one, just a translator?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The plus one is the Secretary of State.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Who doesn’t speak Russian.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; There you go.<br>&nbsp;<br>Then there is a plan for there to be an expanded portion of the meeting, which is P plus five.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to give you the breakdown of time; we&#8217;ll see how the day goes tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>After the meeting concludes &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do we go into these photo ops?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sorry, that&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; There will be a spray of the first P-plus-one portion of the day.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the P plus five, who else is in?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We will get you that list.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But only a spray on the P plus one?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Correct.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The spray will be before or after the P plus one?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Before.&nbsp; At the beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>After the meeting concludes, as you all know, we expect President Putin to do his own press conference.&nbsp; I will let them confirm that, but I believe that&#8217;s the plan.&nbsp; And then President Biden will do a press conference after that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Those are the logistics.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me just also preface from the beginning, just for your expectations: We are not going to go much farther than where the President went during his press conference yesterday in terms of previewing the meeting.&nbsp; We are going to let him speak to that when he concludes the meeting tomorrow.&nbsp; But we still wanted to give an opportunity to have a discussion and provide any clarification as needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) question &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; P plus one: POTUS, Blinken, and a translator?&nbsp; The translators don&#8217;t count in the numbers?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; And an interpreter.&nbsp; That&#8217;s right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One each?&nbsp; One interpreter each, on each side?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;Each will have an interpreter, and President Putin will be accompanied by his foreign minister.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the Russians are saying four to five hours of talks.&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re expecting?&nbsp; Or what?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, in that neighborhood.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) press conference is eight o&#8217;clock, thereabout, for our planning purposes?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to see how the flow goes.&nbsp; This is diplomacy in action, David.&nbsp; Get on the ride.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Four or five hours straight?&nbsp; No break in between?&nbsp; Are they going to share any meals or anything like that?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No meals.&nbsp; We anticipate there will be breaks.&nbsp; But as [senior administration official] said, we&#8217;ve agreed with the other side that there will be some flexibility just so that the leaders can make determinations about the best way to conduct their business.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;Sorry, just to reiterate: No meal? &nbsp;They won&#8217;t sit &#8212; they won’t have not even tea? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Definitely not tea.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I presume &#8212; I presume that the principals and the participants can ask for some water or coffee or tea.&nbsp; I mean, it’s not &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No sort of formal &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Nothing formal.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) break bread<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No breaking of bread.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the position on the ambassadors?&nbsp; Do you expect to reach some sort of deal to send ambassadors back to the country?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of tomorrow, but both ambassadors will be in Geneva.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you want to start &#8212; you want to give us an idea of what to expect?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll start with the baseline of what the President said last night.&nbsp; You guys got to hear from him repeatedly, as there were multiple questions posed about the meeting tomorrow.&nbsp; And happy to answer any questions that you might have.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you expecting any specific agreements to emerge from this summit?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think we expect that there will be areas where the presidents will task out further work to their teams.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s about all I can say today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Backwards slightly, could tell us a bit more about the discussions the President had with the NATO leaders about tomorrow’s summit?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, the President, as he said yesterday, led off the discussion.&nbsp; He was the first leader to speak after the Secretary General.&nbsp; He gave about 10 minutes of remarks, which covered a number of different issues, but Russia was a critical point of emphasis in his comments.&nbsp; And he explained to the leaders what he intended to say.&nbsp; He did so privately, behind closed doors, so I&#8217;m not going to get into the details of it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he asked them to share whatever thoughts or advice they had about the meeting.&nbsp; And several leaders did respond with commentary.&nbsp; And as he said last night, those who spoke to the meeting were positive about the fact that he was doing it and positive about the fact that he was consulting with them in advance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also pledged to them that on an ongoing basis &#8212; to the extent, for example, we&#8217;re working with Russia on arms control-related issues &#8212; he would coordinate closely with NATO so that they had a chance to have input into the arms control agenda.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was there any specific mention of Russian S400 in the Turkey bilat with President Erdoğan?&nbsp; And will that issue be brought up in the meeting with President Putin?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; There was a mention of the Russian S400 system.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an issue between us and Turkey to do with our domestic law.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t anticipate it will be covered in the summit.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was there an agreement with President Erdoğan on the Russian S400 in exchange for Turkish presence at the Kabul airport?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, there was no linkage between the S400 and the Kabul airport.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to the Russians: The Russians were saying that one sort of quick for- step could be returning the ambassadors.&nbsp; Is that on the table?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; It is a possibility.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to confirm that until the two presidents have had the chance to meet.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Over the longer term, let me ask about the two big areas you&#8217;ve identified already that will be big subjects: strategic stability and cyber.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On strategic stability, is your concept here to work out from now to something that would be doable after New START expires?&nbsp; So, in other words, have something that rolls together, maybe with the Chinese and others?&nbsp; Or do you have more short-term goals?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And on cyber, I assume you have very short-term goals on ransomware &#8212; not allowing people to operate from their territory.&nbsp; But tell us about &#8212; to the degree you can &#8212; your longer-term goals on state-sponsored activities, since there&#8217;s been so much of that out of Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the first: We are flexible on the timing and format of agreements.&nbsp; It could be more comprehensive; it could be agreements that cover different pieces at different points in time.&nbsp; So, this is not necessarily a circumstance of waiting until New START is expired to do something.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But it is certainly the case &#8212; and I think this is implied in your question &#8212; that we do have a 2026 final expiration of New START.&nbsp; And a big part of the question that the two presidents are trying to answer through these talks is what comes after &#8212; what will come after New START.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) China and other players as well?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think, ultimately, we are going to need to have a sustained conversation with China on arms control-related issues.&nbsp; But the President has made clear that, at the outset, a bilateral discussion between the two biggest nuclear powers in the world is the way to start.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the cyber side?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, on the cyber side, obviously, ransomware will be a significant topic of conversation tomorrow.&nbsp; They will also discuss the broader issue of cyber norms, cyber rules of the road tomorrow in the discussion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President will make clear that if we see significant types of cyber activity, like we did with SolarWinds, he will respond like we did with SolarWinds.&nbsp; Beyond that, I&#8217;m not going to preview the conversation per the President&#8217;s desire to be able to have the discussion with Putin and then read it out after.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think that was a sufficient response on SolarWinds?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We believe that the response on SolarWinds was, as the President said at the time, proportional.&nbsp; We believe it sent a message about what the United States would and would not tolerate.&nbsp; And so, we judge<br>that the response we took was the right one.&nbsp; But, of course, this is a larger challenge that is going to require a consistent, steady policy on our part, and we will<br>approach the issue accordingly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s he going to say to Putin about the case of Aleksey Navalny?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll put it this way:<br>When the other side tries to say that there are issues that are off the table or that won&#8217;t be on the agenda, for the American President, nothing is off the table.&nbsp; Certainly human rights are not off the table, and individual high-profile cases are not off the table.&nbsp; But otherwise, I&#8217;m not going to preview what he&#8217;s going to say.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What will he say about Belarus and the recent incident with Ryanair?&nbsp; Is that going to be coming up as well?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s already said publicly that he viewed that as an act of egregious air piracy and completely inconsistent with international norms and the rule of law.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think you will hear anything inconsistent when he reads the meeting out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, I don&#8217;t want to be in the position of saying what he&#8217;s going to say to Putin.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have an objective, like a particular deliverable that you&#8217;re seeking?&nbsp; Or is that the wrong framing, because it&#8217;s not about deliverables for you right now?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; During &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not &#8212; we&#8217;re not expecting a big set of deliverables out of this meeting.&nbsp; We are seeking three basic things:<br>&nbsp;<br>First, a clear set of taskings about areas where working together can advance our national interest and make the world safer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, a clear laydown of the areas of America&#8217;s vital national interests, where Russian activities that run counter to those interests will be met with a response.<br>&nbsp;<br>And third, a clear explication of the President&#8217;s vision for American values and our national priorities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Those are the three things that we&#8217;re trying to accomplish, and the President will do that over the course of the meeting with President Putin.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you just tell us a little bit about how has the President prepped for this?&nbsp; What &#8212; you know, had he been meeting with advisors?&nbsp; What has he been doing for this?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; He&#8217;s been preparing for this like he prepares for every significant international engagement.&nbsp; He reviews the issues &#8212; written material; he cares about digging into the details.&nbsp; That very much matters to him.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s also had the opportunity to engage with a wide variety of advisors across the government who have deep expertise on Russia, as well as to hear from some outside experts as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you just speak a little bit more about the Baltic countries meeting?&nbsp; Why did the President feel like it was necessary to meet with them first before meeting with President Putin, on top of the NATO and EU allies?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Beyond being necessary, the President really loves those kinds of meetings.&nbsp; I went with him to Lithuania some years ago, and he&#8217;s just energized by the model and example of these vibrant democracies on the eastern flank.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But specifically, relative to the meeting tomorrow, he wanted to show quite publicly that he was going to stand in solidarity with NATO&#8217;s eastern flank allies, that he was going to consult with them in advance of the meeting, and that he was going to stand up for their interests in the meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did they have any advice for him on dealing with Putin, since they live in his neighborhood?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; They sure did.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did they say?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; But I’ll leave that to them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, come on.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; But, yes, they had good advice.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In all his long travels and associations with this part of the world, has he learned any Russian?&nbsp; I mean, literally, like a few words.&nbsp; Or does he speak a spattering of it?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Will he say “hello” in Russian, for example, or a “thank you” or anything?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he have conversation (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if he will say “hello.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; I actually &#8212; I have not heard him speak Russian, but I can&#8217;t confirm one way or the other.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you, guys.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>4:12 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at the U.S.-EU Summit Expanded Plenary Session</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/15/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-u-s-eu-summit-expanded-plenary-session/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 16:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Europa Building, European CouncilBrussels, Belgium 1:13 P.M. CEST&#160;PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, thank you.&#160; Thank you both very much.&#160; It’s been one of the great pleasures getting to know you both personally and (inaudible) our official positions.&#160; And we were at the G7, and again today &#8212; I apologize I kept my colleagues in the closed meeting.&#160;&#160;But&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Europa Building, European Council<br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>1:13 P.M. CEST<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you both very much.&nbsp; It’s been one of the great pleasures getting to know you both personally and (inaudible) our official positions.&nbsp; And we were at the G7, and again today &#8212; I apologize I kept my colleagues in the closed meeting.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I want to &#8212; you know, this is – I haven’t been back to Brussels or the EU since 2017, and since the &#8212; back then, also the first summit back in 2014.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I brought the A-team with me today.&nbsp; And, you know, I’ve said, both publicly and privately, that America is back, and this is why we’re here in full force.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I’m happy to have with me today the members of my Cabinet: Secretary of State, Anthony Blinken; he suffers from the problem of having worked with me for years.&nbsp; And also Trade Representative, Ambassador Katherine Tai, who has made some real progress already.&nbsp; And Secretary of Commerce, Gina Raimondo, who was a first-rate governor and one of the brightest people that we’ve worked with, and agreed to come on as our Secretary of Commerce.<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of the things that you and I were talking about – and will come as no shock to either of you: Europe is our natural partner, and the reason is we’re committed to the same democratic norms and institutions, and are &#8212; they are increasingly under attack.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we &#8212; I’ve said it before, and I apologize for repeating &#8212; oh, I didn’t mention Jake Sullivan (inaudible) National Security Advisor.&nbsp; I’m leaving out a lot of people here.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; I’m going to get in trouble.&nbsp; But anyway, we’ll get back to that in a minute.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we &#8212; you know, there’s a lot that is happening.&nbsp; I used to always &#8212; my friends would kid me while in the United States Senate, because I served there, for always quoting Irish poets.&nbsp; You think I quoted Irish poets because I’m Irish.&nbsp; That’s not the reason.&nbsp; I quote them because they’re the best poets in the world &#8212; that’s why.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>But all kidding aside, there is a &#8212; there is a stanza from a poem from an Irish poet, who (inaudible).&nbsp; He said, “All is changed, changed utterly: A terrible beauty has been born.”&nbsp; I think all has changed in the last 10, 12 years, and it’s not because of any one person.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think we’re in the midst of terrible beauty having been born &#8212; a great shift in technology, a great shift in the development of the world, and it’s causing great anxiety in each our countries and uncertainty among many of our colleagues of what’s going to be their place in the world.&nbsp; Are they going to be replaced by a new technology?&nbsp; Are they going to no longer have a job?&nbsp; And what are they going to do?<br>&nbsp;<br>And that comes along at the same time that that also generates &#8212; when an uncertainty is generated politically like that, by individuals, it also generates some folks who are less than &#8212; how can I say it? &#8212; some of them are like charlatans, trying to take advantage of those concerns.&nbsp; And we see it in Europe.&nbsp; We see it in the United States.&nbsp; We’ve seen it around the world.&nbsp; And it’s phony populism.<br>&nbsp;<br>So it seems to me that the best answer to deal with these changes is that &#8212; to have a circumstance where our economies grow, and they grow together, and they grow still based on the value set that united us in the first place.&nbsp; And I think we do share just the same basic values of human dignity and human rights as my colleagues.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll be very colloquial with you: My dad had a transition where, in the city we lived in, coal was dying; it was no longer relevant.&nbsp; You know, he was not a &#8212; my great grandfather was a coal miner; he was a mining engineer.&nbsp; But in northeastern Pennsylvania, when coal died &#8212; my dad was a salesperson &#8212; and the economy collapsed.&nbsp; And we moved to another part where there were jobs, in southern &#8212; into &#8212; down in Delaware, a very &#8212; just across the Pennsylvania border.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And my family &#8212; my siblings and I would hear him often use the following expression: He said, “Joe, a job is about a lot more than a paycheck.&nbsp; It’s about your dignity.&nbsp; It’s about respect.&nbsp; It’s about your place in the community.&nbsp; It’s about being able to look at your child in the eye and say ‘Honey, it’s&nbsp;going to be okay’ and mean it.”&nbsp; I think we sometimes forget that.&nbsp; It’s about the dignity of the worker and them being able to hold their head high.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so I think we have an enormous opportunity, if we think in terms of these changes &#8212; particularly in terms of global warming &#8212; if we think of them in terms of jobs.&nbsp; The kind of jobs that we’re going to have to create to preserve the environment are jobs that can pay well, that are going to be (inaudible) technologies that working-class, blue-collar workers, as we say in the States, will be able to make more money, be able to do well.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we have to, all of us, accommodate those changes and provide for them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I think we have a lot to deal with, from COVID-19 to whether or not we’re in a position that we can generate the kind of strengthening in transatlantic trade and technological cooperation.<br>&nbsp;<br>There are, sort of, a different set of priorities with the same objective: How do likeminded countries, sharing the same values, work together to improve the living standard for not only our people, but for the rest of the world?&nbsp; And I think we have the capacity to do that, and it’s going to take an awful lot of hard work and determination.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’ll conclude by saying: One of the reasons I’m optimistic is because of our younger generation, in Europe as well as the United States.&nbsp; The young generation &#8212; this one &#8212; is the best educated in American history.&nbsp; It is also the least prejudiced, the most open, and the most &#8212; the most committed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that we have reason to believe that if we provide the policies that are consistent, that provide for the kind of growth and opportunity for them &#8212; and education plays a gigantic part of that &#8212; I think we &#8212; I think the future is very, very bright.&nbsp; I think we have an opportunity to do some, really, very good things.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I should &#8212; as my mother would say, I should “hush up” and let this discussion move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:21 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces 4th Slate of Judicial Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/president-biden-announces-4th-slate-of-judicial-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 16:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing five new candidates for the federal bench and two new candidates for District of Columbia courts, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing five new candidates for the federal bench and two new candidates for District of Columbia courts, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.<br><br>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country &#8212; both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.<br><br>For example, this slate includes:</p>



<ul><li>A nationally-recognized leader on voting rights who would be the only Latina serving on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit</li><li>A former public defender and current civil rights plaintiff’s attorney who would be the second African American woman judge actively serving on the District Court for the District of Columbia</li><li>A federal prosecutor who would be the first judge of South Asian descent to serve on the District Court for the District of Connecticut</li><li>A Department of Justice lawyer with two decades of civil rights experience, including as Deputy Chief of the Appellate Section in the Civil Rights Division</li><li>A magistrate judge on the D.C. Superior Court with deep experience in domestic violence and family law issues</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s fourth round of names for federal judicial positions, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 24.<br><br>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move at an unparalleled speed with respect to judicial nominations. His first judicial nominations announcement was made faster than that of any new President in modern American history, and today’s announcement continues that trend.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>CIRCUIT COURT</u></strong><br><br><strong>MYRNA PÉREZ</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Myrna Pérez is the director of the Brennan Center’s Voting Rights and Elections Program at the New York University (NYU) School of Law. Ms. Pérez joined the Brennan Center in 2006. She has also been a lecturer-in-law at Columbia Law School since 2016. She previously served as an Adjunct Professor of Clinical Law at NYU School of Law from 2013 to 2015. Prior to joining the Brennan Center, Ms. Pérez was a Civil Rights Fellow at Relman, Dane &amp; Colfax, a civil rights law firm in Washington, D.C., from 2005 to 2006. Ms. Pérez served as a law clerk for Judge Anita B. Brody on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania from 2003 to 2004 and for Judge Julio M. Fuentes on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit from 2004 to 2005.<br><br>Ms. Pérez received her J.D. from Columbia Law School in 2003, her M.P.P. from Harvard Kennedy School in 1998, and her B.A. from Yale University in 1996. Prior to law school, she was a Presidential Management Fellow, serving as a policy analyst for the U.S. Government Accountability Office on issues including housing and health care.&nbsp;<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong><u>DISTRICT COURTS</u></strong><br><br><strong>SARAH A. L. MERRIAM</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the District of Connecticut</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Judge Sarah A. L. Merriam has served as a U.S. Magistrate Judge for the District of Connecticut since 2015. Previously, she served as an Assistant Federal Public Defender for the District of Connecticut from 2007 to 2015. Judge Merriam worked on political campaigns in Connecticut from 2006 to 2007. She was an associate at the Connecticut-based law firm Cowdery, Ecker &amp; Murphy from 2003 to 2006. Judge Merriam served as a law clerk for Judge Thomas Meskill on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit from 2002 to 2003 and for Judge Alvin Thompson on the U.S. District Court for the District of Connecticut from 2000 to 2002.<br><br>Judge Merriam received an LLM from Duke Law School in 2018, her J.D. from Yale Law School in 2000, and her B.A. from Georgetown in 1993. <br></p>



<p><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SARALA VIDYA NAGALA</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the District of Connecticut</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Sarala Vidya Nagala is the Deputy Chief of the Major Crimes Unit in the U.S. Attorney’s Office in the District of Connecticut, a role she has held since 2017. Ms. Nagala joined the U.S. Attorney’s Office in 2012, and has served in a number of leadership roles in the office, including as Hate Crimes Coordinator. Previously, Ms. Nagala was an associate at Munger, Tolles, &amp; Olson in San Francisco, California from 2009 to 2012. She began her legal career as a law clerk for Judge Susan Graber on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit from 2008 to 2009.<br><br>Ms. Nagala received her J.D. from the University of California at Berkeley School of Law in 2008 and her B.A. from Stanford University in 2005. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong>OMAR A. WILLIAMS</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the District of Connecticut</em></strong><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Judge Omar A. Williams has served as a Superior Court Judge in Hartford, Connecticut since 2016. In that role, Judge Williams has served on the New England Regional Judicial Opioid Initiative, the Sentence Review Division, and the Wiretap Panel. He was previously a Superior Court Judge in New London from 2014 to 2016. Prior to his appointment as a state court judge, Judge Williams was an Assistant Public Defender for the State of Connecticut Division of Public Defender Services from 2003 to 2014. <br><br>Judge Williams received his J.D. from the University of Connecticut Law School in 2002 and his B.A. from the University of Connecticut in 1998.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong>JIA M. COBB</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the District of Columbia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Jia M. Cobb is a partner at Relman Colfax, where she has practiced since 2012. Her plaintiff-side litigation practice focuses on fair housing, disability discrimination, employment discrimination, and cases at the intersection of civil rights and criminal justice. Ms. Cobb taught trial advocacy as an adjunct professor at American University Washington College of Law in 2011 and was a faculty member at Harvard Law School’s Trial Advocacy Workshop in 2010 and 2011. Prior to her time in private practice, Ms. Cobb served as a trial attorney at the Public Defender Service for the District of Columbia from 2006 to 2012. She began her legal career as a law clerk for Judge Diane Wood on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Seventh Circuit from 2005 to 2006.<br><br>Ms. Cobb received a J.D. from Harvard Law School, <em>cum laude</em>, in 2005 and a B.A. from Northwestern University, <em>magna cum laude</em>, in 2002. <br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong><u>LOCAL D.C. COURTS</u></strong><br><br><strong>TOVAH R. CALDERON</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Tovah R. Calderon currently serves as an Acting Deputy Assistant Attorney General in the U.S. Department of Justice’s Civil Rights Division. Ms. Calderon first joined the Department of Justice in 2001 through the Attorney General’s Honors Program and has held numerous roles within the department. Before her current detail with the Civil Rights Division, Ms. Calderon served as a Deputy Chief in the Division’s Appellate Section. Ms. Calderon has also served on detail to the White House Domestic Policy Council, the Civil Rights Division’s Policy and Strategy Section, and the Senate Judiciary Committee. From 2000 to 2001, she served as a law clerk for Judge Francis D. Murnaghan, Jr. on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit, as well as other judges on both the Fourth Circuit and the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland.<br><br>Ms. Calderon received her J.D. from the Howard University School of Law in 2000 and her B.A. from the University of Michigan in 1995. <br><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>KENIA SEOANE LOPEZ</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Judge Kenia Seoane Lopez is currently a Magistrate Judge on the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. Prior to her appointment in 2012, Judge Seoane Lopez served as a Bilingual Attorney Negotiator in the Domestic Violence Division of the District of Columbia Superior Court from 2009 to 2012. She previously served as an Assistant Attorney General in the Legal Services Section of the Child Support Division in the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia from 2005 to 2009. Judge Seoane Lopez served as a law clerk to the Justices on the Massachusetts Superior Court from 2002 to 2003 and Senior Judges on the Superior Court of the District of Columbia from 2004 to 2005.<br><br>Judge Seoane Lopez received her J.D. and M.A. in Latin American, Caribbean, and Iberian Studies from the University of Wisconsin in 2002 and her B.S. from Northeastern University, <em>cum laude</em>, in 1997.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
