<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 20:02:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology Anne Neuberger’s Travel to&#160;India</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/29/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-cyber-and-emerging-technology-anne-neubergers-travel-to-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 20:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From April 26-28, Deputy National Security Advisory for Cyber and Emerging Technologies Anne Neuberger traveled to India to participate in the Raisina Dialogue where she met with representatives from multiple countries and multilateral organizations to discuss cooperation on a range of global security and geopolitical issues. Neuberger’s visit continues the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to international&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>From April 26-28, Deputy National Security Advisory for Cyber and Emerging Technologies Anne Neuberger traveled to India to participate in the Raisina Dialogue where she met with representatives from multiple countries and multilateral organizations to discuss cooperation on a range of global security and geopolitical issues. Neuberger’s visit continues the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to international cooperation to ensure critical and emerging technologies work for, not against, democratic principles and security. Neuberger met with a range of Government of India officials to deepen our bilateral efforts to promote secure and open connectivity and a vibrant digital economy and to build our respective cybersecurity capacity to address shared threats. Finally, recognizing the importance of public and private sector cooperation, Neuberger also met with private sector representatives to discuss the key role of industry in advancing our shared objectives on cybersecurity and emerging technology, and to discuss new developments in 5G, artificial intelligence, semiconductors, and quantum technologies. Across all of her engagements, Neuberger emphasized the importance of strengthening U.S.-India collaboration in securing the technologies and infrastructure of the future while simultaneously bolstering security to protect against present-day cyber threats.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces AMTRAK Board Member&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/29/president-biden-announces-amtrak-board-member-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as members of the AMTRAK Board of Directors: David Capozzi, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors Anthony Coscia, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors Christopher Koos, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as members of the AMTRAK Board of Directors:</p>



<ul><li>David Capozzi, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors</li><li>Anthony Coscia, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors</li><li>Christopher Koos, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors</li><li>Samuel Lathem, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors</li><li>Robin Wiessmann, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>David Capozzi, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors</u></strong></p>



<p>David Capozzi is a retired federal senior executive. He was the Executive Director of the U.S. Access Board from 2008-2020 and was the Director of the Board’s Office of Technical and Information Services from 1992-2008. Prior to joining the Access Board, Capozzi was Director of Project ACTION and Vice President of Advocacy for Easter Seals, and was the National Advocacy Director for the Paralyzed Veterans of America. He was a member of the legal team and lobbying captain for the disability community that helped craft the Americans with Disabilities Act. Capozzi was the lead negotiator on the Department of Transportation’s Federal Advisory Committee that negotiated proposed regulations implementing the Air Carrier Access Act, and chaired the Urban Mass Transportation Administration’s (UMTA) ADA Federal Advisory Committee.</p>



<p>He received the 2020 Service to the Citizen Award and an award from the Zero Project recognizing his longstanding cooperative efforts with the European Commission to harmonize global ICT accessibility standards. Capozzi serves on the United Spinal Association’s Board of Directors, Mobility Fitness’ Advisory Committee, and Access Living’s Program Committee. He is an Advisory Council Member for Morphic, and a Member of the International Association of Accessibility Professionals Built Environment Taskforce. Capozzi graduated from the State University of New York (SUNY) at Buffalo School of Law, and was an honors graduate and Phi Beta Kappa recipient at SUNY at Buffalo with an undergraduate degree in Psychology. He and his wife Patti live in Gaithersburg, Maryland, and are the proud parents of adult triplets and their older brother.</p>



<p><strong><u>Anthony Coscia, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors</u></strong></p>



<p>Anthony R. Coscia serves as Chairman of AMTRAK Board of Directors appointed to the Board by President Barack Obama in 2010 and reappointed in 2015. Coscia is a partner and Executive Committee member of Windels Marx, LLP one of the region’s oldest law firms and has for over 30 years worked on transactions in the finance, real estate, healthcare, and infrastructure areas. Coscia also serves as a Director of OceanFirst Financial Corp and the Neighborhood Property Group, LLC; Vice Chairman of the Gateway Development Commission; and Senior Advisor to Oaktree Transportation Infrastructure Fund, L.P. He previously served as Chairman of Suez North America Inc. and a Director of Suez SA. He recently served on New Jersey Governor Murphy’s Restart and Recovery Commission.</p>



<p>Coscia was Chairman of the Board of Commissioners of the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey from 2003 through January 2011 where he played a leadership role in the rebuilding of Lower Manhattan after 9/11.&nbsp; From February 1992 to March 2003, Coscia served as Chairman of the New Jersey Economic Development Authority. In addition, Coscia serves on the Board of Directors of Georgetown University, the New Jersey Community Development Corporation, and the Regional Plan Association. He is also a member of The Partnership for New York City and The Economic Club of New York. Coscia is a Phi Beta Kappa graduate of Georgetown University School of Foreign Service and received his J.D. degree from Rutgers University School of Law.</p>



<p><strong><u>Christopher Koos, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors</u></strong></p>



<p>Mayor Chris Koos was elected to his first term on the Normal Town Council in April of 2001. He was sworn in as Mayor of the Town of Normal on February 17, 2003, and his current term runs until 2025. Koos has the longest running term of any mayor in Normal’s history. Koos is a Bloomington-Normal native, and attended Central Catholic High School and Illinois State University. He served his country in Vietnam as an Infantry Platoon Leader with the Army 101st Airborne/Airmobile Division. He served as Chairman of the Town of Normal Historic Preservation Commission for ten years, and during the restoration of the historic Normal Theater, served as Chair of the Restoration Advisory Committee and on the Normal Theater Advisory Board.</p>



<p>During his tenure on the Town Council, Koos represented the Town on the Bloomington-Normal Area Convention and Visitors Bureau Committee, Economic Development Council, and Illinois Municipal League. He is also very involved with the Bloomington-Normal Japanese Sister Cities Committee. The expertise of Koos in urban development and transportation were provided in testimony before the House Ways and Means Committee in 2014, and the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, Subcommittee on Transportation and Public Assets in 2016. He currently serves on the Advisory Board of Transportation for America and is Vice Chair for Passenger Rail with the US Conference of Mayors. During his tenure as the Chief Elected Official for the Town of Normal, development in the Central Business District included a Multimodal Transportation Center/City Hall, the Marriott Hotel and Conference Center, the Hyatt Place Hotel, the Children’s Discovery Museum, and other major multi-use construction.</p>



<p><strong><u>Samuel Lathem, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors</u></strong></p>



<p>Rev. Samuel E. Lathem was elected as the first African-American President of Delaware State AFL-CIO in October 2003, a position that he continues to hold today. In 1965, Lathem began work at the Chrysler Plant in Newark, Delaware. He was elected and served two three-year terms as Chief Steward in the Body Shop at Newark Assembly Plant. He was appointed as Civil Rights Chairman of Local 1183 UAW. He was then assigned the position of Administrator of the UAW-Chrysler Training Center in 1990 and was promoted to an International Rep of the UAW in February 1999. Lathem was ordained a Baptist Preacher in 1992 at the First Baptist Church of Morton, Pennsylvania by the New Hope Baptist Association. He currently serves as Associate Minister at Cornerstone Fellowship Baptist Church in Wilmington, Delaware.</p>



<p>Lathem&#8217;s spiritual integrity and diligence to serve his church and community has earned him the privilege of honored appointments such as the following: by Governor Dale Wolf to serve on the Interagency Council on Literacy, and by Governor Carper to serve on the Board of Directors for the Diamond State Port Corporation (Port of Wilmington) and the Workforce Investment Board. Lathem also serves as Chairman of the Delaware Advisory Council on Career and Vocational Education, and was appointed by Governor Minner to serve as the first African-American Delaware Commissioner on the Board of Directors of the Delaware River Bay Authority. Lathem serves on the Board of Directors for Junior Achievement, Kids Count Steering Committee, 4-H Foundation Committee, Board of Directors of SURJ (Stand Up for What&#8217;s Right and Just), Metropolitan Wilmington Urban League, and United Way of Delaware, and serves as a Member of the Coalition of Black Trade Unionists. Lathem is married to Jean Lathem, and has two stepsons and two grandsons.</p>



<p><strong><u>Robin Wiessmann, Nominee for Member of the AMTRAK Board of Directors</u></strong></p>



<p>Robin Wiessmann is Executive Director and CEO of the Pennsylvania Housing Finance Agency (PHFA).&nbsp; As CEO of PHFA, she manages operations and directs initiatives that promote development of affordable rental housing, and provide financing for homeownership.&nbsp; Prior to PHFA, Wiessmann served as Secretary of Banking and Securities in the cabinet of Pennsylvania Governor Tom Wolf, and previously as State Treasurer of the Commonwealth. Wiessmann has devoted her career to both the private and public sectors. As a national infrastructure investment banker, Wiessmann was a Founding Principal and President of Artemis Capital Group, the first women-owned investment banking firm on Wall Street, and held positions at Goldman Sachs and Merrill Lynch. Wiessmann served as Chairman of the Board for Vantagepoint Funds Mutual Fund, an Act 40 company, on the Board of the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board, a self-regulatory organization under the SEC, and as a Board member of the Duke University Sanford School of Public Policy. She chaired the Environmental Financing Advisory Board during the Clinton Administration.</p>



<p>Wiessmann is Secretary/Treasurer of the National Council of State Housing Agencies and is on the Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia’s Economic and Community Advisory Council. She served as Secretary of the Conference of State Bank Supervisors and Chair of the Non-Depository Committee, and served multiple other economic development, policy, and supervisory boards, including the Public School and State Employees’ Retirement Systems and the Investor Protection Trust. She is a recipient of the Arthur E. Armitage, Sr. Distinguished Alumni Award from Rutgers Law School and is a graduate of Lafayette College.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement between the United&#160;States and the European Commission on European Energy&#160;Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/29/joint-statement-between-the-united-states-and-the-european-commission-on-european-energy-security-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 18:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52126</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 28, the U.S.-EU Task Force on Energy Security met in person in Washington to discuss implementation of the March 25 Joint Statement by Presidents Biden and von der Leyen.  The meeting, chaired by Amos Hochstein, U.S. Senior Advisor for Energy Security, and Björn Seibert, Head of Cabinet of the European Commission President, reviewed progress&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On April 28, the U.S.-EU Task Force on Energy Security met in person in Washington to discuss implementation of the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/joint-statement-between-the-united-states-and-the-european-commission-on-european-energy-security/">March 25 Joint Statement</a> by Presidents Biden and von der Leyen. <br> <br>The meeting, chaired by Amos Hochstein, U.S. Senior Advisor for Energy Security, and Björn Seibert, Head of Cabinet of the European Commission President, reviewed progress on diversifying natural gas supplies to Europe and reducing Europe’s demand for natural gas. The discussion followed two recent Task Force convenings that included senior U.S. and European Commission officials, representatives of EU Member States, and industry participants.<br> <br>The sides also discussed the EU Energy Purchase Platform and plans to establish a framework to accelerate diversification of gas supply, including additional LNG supplies. The sides also discussed options to reduce Europe’s demand for natural gas, including with the deployment of heat pumps, technologies that promote energy efficiency and savings such as smart thermostats, and renewable energy.<br> <br>In the coming weeks, work will continue at technical and senior officials’ levels, and the Task Force decided to reconvene in person in June, to assess progress on the workplan.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on EPA Issuing Emergency Fuel Waiver for&#160;E15</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/29/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-epa-issuing-emergency-fuel-waiver-for-e15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 17:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is committed to doing everything he can to address the pain Americans are feeling at the pump as a result of Putin’s Price Hike and his unjustified war’s impact on global fuel supply. Today, the Environmental Protection Agency announced that it is issuing an emergency fuel waiver to allow E15 sales during the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is committed to doing everything he can to address the pain Americans are feeling at the pump as a result of Putin’s Price Hike and his unjustified war’s impact on global fuel supply. Today, the Environmental Protection Agency announced that it is issuing an emergency fuel waiver to allow E15 sales during the summer driving season.</p>



<p>The waiver is a critical step to address the fuel supply crisis and follows President Biden’s announcement earlier this month laying out actions to increase use of biofuels in order to reduce our reliance on fossil fuels, accelerate the clean energy transition, build real U.S. energy independence, support American agriculture and manufacturing, and save Americans money at the pump.&nbsp; At current prices, E15 can save a family 10 cents per gallon of gas on average and many stores sell E15 at an even greater discount and today’s waiver will allow families to pay that lower price for months to come. &nbsp;</p>



<p>This is just one step the President is taking to address the fuel supply and give Americans relief from the Putin Price Hike. The President authorized the release of one million barrels per day from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve for the next six months in the largest release in history as a war-time bridge, worked around-the-clock to build a coalition around the world to release an additional 60 million barrels, and is calling on Congress to make oil companies pay fees on wells from their leases that they haven’t used in years to encourage more domestic production right now. In addition, our Administration has finalized the strongest-ever fuel economy standards for vehicles, reducing the amount of fuel families need to purchase over time and making vehicles go farther on every gallon.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Teacher Appreciation Day and National Teacher Appreciation Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-teacher-appreciation-day-and-national-teacher-appreciation-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 17:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the husband of a lifelong educator, who continues to teach full-time as First Lady, I have often heard Jill say:  &#8220;Teaching is not what you do.  It&#8217;s who you are.&#8221;  Our Nation&#8217;s teachers are selfless, dedicated, and caring individuals who devote themselves to the well-being and progress of our students.  During this National Teacher&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As the husband of a lifelong educator, who continues to teach full-time as First Lady, I have often heard Jill say:  &#8220;Teaching is not what you do.  It&#8217;s who you are.&#8221;  Our Nation&#8217;s teachers are selfless, dedicated, and caring individuals who devote themselves to the well-being and progress of our students.  During this National Teacher Appreciation Day and throughout National Teacher Appreciation Week, we honor educators who touch the lives of students across America and who are essential to building the future of our Nation.<br><br>One of the greatest gifts our schools give to students and educators is time spent with one another &#8212; the daily opportunities to learn and grow together, face to face.  There is no substitute for the wisdom this experience brings.  That is why, when I took office, I made it a priority to reopen schools as quickly and safely as possible.  Today, I am proud that more than 99 percent of schools are open for full-time in-person instruction.  By following the science and making vaccines available for students, educators, and staff, we got kids back to school safely.<br><br>My Administration is working tirelessly to support educators. The American Rescue Plan provided a historic $122 billion investment to our Nation&#8217;s schools so they could safely reopen for in-person instruction, address students&#8217; mental health needs, hire more teachers, and make up for lost learning. Teachers have long been underpaid, and these funds help school districts increase compensation to recruit and retain the teachers that students need.<br>    <br>To counter the negative impacts of the pandemic on student learning, our educators have returned to the classroom with creative solutions.  They have partnered with communities to implement safety measures, increase students&#8217; access to mental health support, and equip them with critical life skills.  Teachers have also found new ways to address unfinished learning and engage meaningfully with students and families.  To support our educators, the Department of Education is offering unprecedented resources to help teachers meet student needs.  My Administration is also committed to strengthening pathways into the teaching profession for future educators of color, ensuring a more diverse workforce.<br>     <br>I will never forget the educators who encouraged me as a child.  Many of us remember our favorite teachers &#8212; the ones who instilled confidence in us, who encouraged us to dream boldly, and who helped us believe that we could achieve anything.  On National Teacher Appreciation Day and during National Teacher Appreciation Week, we pay tribute to educators who empower students across the country with the knowledge and skills they need to reach their potential and achieve their dreams.<br>    <br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 3, 2022, as National Teacher Appreciation Day and May 1 through May 7, 2022, as National Teacher Appreciation Week.  I call upon all Americans to recognize the hard work and dedication of our Nation&#8217;s teachers and to observe this day and this week by supporting teachers through appropriate activities, events, and programs.<br>    <br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Hurricane Preparedness Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-hurricane-preparedness-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 17:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each May, we raise awareness about the threat posed by hurricanes so that Americans living in potentially affected areas are more prepared for these powerful storms.  Over the last several years, hurricanes, typhoons, and tropical storms have occurred with greater frequency and intensity, causing tremendous destruction across the United States.  From the Gulf Coast and Caribbean Territories&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Each May, we raise awareness about the threat posed by hurricanes so that Americans living in potentially affected areas are more prepared for these powerful storms.  Over the last several years, hurricanes, typhoons, and tropical storms have occurred with greater frequency and intensity, causing tremendous destruction across the United States.  From the Gulf Coast and Caribbean Territories to New England, Hawaii, and the Pacific Territories, severe winds and flooding have cost lives, damaged homes, and caused financial setbacks for families.  During National Hurricane Preparedness Week, we recommit to improving our Nation&#8217;s resilience to hurricanes and to stopping climate change from exacerbating the impact of climate-related catastrophes in the future. <br><br>Last year was the third most active hurricane season &#8212; and one of the costliest ever recorded in the Atlantic basin.  Hurricane Ida made landfall in Louisiana and moved northeast, causing severe weather and flooding across Pennsylvania and New York.  Hurricane Henri, the first hurricane to hit the northeast in 30 years, killed more than a 100 people and caused billions of dollars in damages.  These and other hurricanes devastated infrastructure, economies, and communities in their path.  Hurricanes also take an emotional toll &#8212; especially on low-income communities and communities of color, who are more likely to live in areas that are vulnerable to climate and weather hazards.  I witnessed the aftermath of these storms firsthand in Louisiana, New Jersey, and New York as I walked with survivors through their devastated communities. <br><br>My Administration is committed not only to recovering and rebuilding in the aftermath of these climate-related events but also to preparing for them by strengthening the resiliency of our infrastructure and our communities. That is why I was proud to sign the historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law last year. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law includes long-overdue investments in coastal resilience, advances our understanding and forecasting of dangerous weather events, improves how we communicate forecasts to the public, and enhances the resiliency of underserved communities.<br><br>In addition, I have proposed more than $18 billion for climate resilience programs across the Federal Government in next year&#8217;s budget.  Federal investments will also incorporate new flood standards so that our communities are more resilient to flooding.  We are strengthening Federal coordination on meteorological services.  We are working with State and local governments to strengthen and adopt building codes so, when disasters strike, buildings and the people in them are safer. <br><br>But the Government cannot address hurricane and extreme weather resilience alone &#8212; every individual and family living in a part of the country that is threatened by these storms has an important role to play.  Staying informed, making sure your insurance policies are up to date, and having an emergency kit and plan ready are all important preparation steps.  More information on how to prepare for hurricane season is available on the Federal Emergency Management Agency&#8217;s Ready.gov website.<br><br>As we enter hurricane season, let us recommit to working together so that we can save lives; reduce damage to our homes, communities, and infrastructure; and recover more quickly when hurricanes and tropical storms strike. <br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 1 through May 7, 2022, as National Hurricane Preparedness Week.  I urge all Americans to help build our climate-resilient Nation, so that individuals and organizations are empowered to take action to make their communities more resilient to weather disasters.  I call on our Federal, State, Tribal, territorial, and local government agencies to share information that will protect lives and property.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Small Business Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-small-business-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For generations, small businesses across America have shaped and embodied our Nation&#8217;s entrepreneurial spirit and driven our economy forward.  Today, more than 32 million small businesses employ almost half of America&#8217;s workforce and represent the heart and soul of countless communities.  During National Small Business Week, we celebrate America&#8217;s small businesses and their enormous contributions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For generations, small businesses across America have shaped and embodied our Nation&#8217;s entrepreneurial spirit and driven our economy forward.  Today, more than 32 million small businesses employ almost half of America&#8217;s workforce and represent the heart and soul of countless communities.  During National Small Business Week, we celebrate America&#8217;s small businesses and their enormous contributions to American life and prosperity.<br><br>When I first took office, the pandemic had devastated America&#8217;s small business community.  Hundreds of thousands of small businesses had closed, main streets were shuttered, and millions more Americans were out of work through no fault of their own.  Even with the creativity and resilience of small business owners and workers, COVID-19 took an incalculable toll on so many lives and livelihoods.  That is why I made it a top priority to provide substantial, immediate relief to our Nation&#8217;s small businesses, giving them the tools, resources, and support they needed to reopen, rehire, and rebuild.<br><br>My American Rescue Plan and other emergency relief programs distributed hundreds of billions of dollars to millions of small businesses to keep the lights on and keep workers on the payroll.  My Administration also removed historic barriers to level the playing field for businesses across rural and urban America, especially businesses owned by veterans, women, and people of color.  These efforts have helped millions of small businesses not only weather the pandemic, but thrive.<br><br>My Administration is committed to unlocking new opportunities to help small businesses grow and compete.  Through the American Rescue Plan, our State Small Business Credit Initiative provides States, territories, and Tribal governments with resources to establish loan and equity capital programs to support entrepreneurs.  In addition, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law has created unprecedented contracting opportunities for small businesses in every community.  Already, more than 4,000 projects have been announced to upgrade America&#8217;s infrastructure, creating significant opportunities for small businesses to grow.  The law is delivering affordable high-speed internet access to every community &#8212; urban, rural, suburban, and Tribal &#8212; so every small business can use digital technologies and gain new customers across the country and around the world.  The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law makes the Minority Business Development Agency within the United States Department of Commerce a permanent entity &#8212; seeded with a record amount of funding &#8212; so minority-owned businesses can receive tailored assistance for their unique challenges and access the capital they need to grow.<br> <br>I firmly believe that equal opportunity is the bedrock of our democracy.  That is why my Administration is committed to using Federal procurement dollars to support firms owned by underrepresented people and to help small businesses build generational wealth.  Last year, I announced a set of reforms to increase contracting opportunities for underserved businesses by up to 50 percent by 2025.  We are also capitalizing on our historic investments in supply chain resilience and &#8220;Made in America&#8221; manufacturing so small businesses can innovate, compete, and build the products of tomorrow.  To position small businesses for success in the long term, the United States Small Business Administration&#8217;s Community Navigator Pilot program is forging stronger partnerships with local organizations to get resources to underserved small businesses.<br><br>Thanks to these initiatives and the resilience of the American people, America&#8217;s entrepreneurial spirit has never been stronger.  New business applications grew by more than 30 percent over the course of the pandemic, with almost 5.4 million new applications in 2021 alone.  More Americans than ever before &#8212; including more women and people of color &#8212; are following their dreams and starting new enterprises.  My Administration will continue to support them, build upon this remarkable resurgence, and strengthen the foundation of our economy with America&#8217;s small businesses at the forefront.<br><br>This National Small Business Week, let us renew our commitment to supporting our Nation&#8217;s small businesses.  From local &#8220;mom and pop&#8221; shops to innovative start-ups, small businesses are pillars of our communities and the engine of our economy.  By rebuilding our economy from the bottom up and middle out, we can maintain our global competitiveness and build a stronger Nation where everyone can succeed.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 1 through May 7, 2022, as National Small Business Week.  I call upon all Americans to recognize the contributions of small businesses to the American economy, continue supporting them, and honor the occasion with programs and activities that highlight these important businesses.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Foster Care Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-foster-care-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every May, we renew our commitment to ensuring that all youth in foster care have the love, support, and resources they need to thrive.  We also celebrate the families who provide safe and loving homes for our Nation&#8217;s foster children.  We share our appreciation for the dedicated volunteers and professionals who help our Nation&#8217;s foster&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Every May, we renew our commitment to ensuring that all youth in foster care have the love, support, and resources they need to thrive.  We also celebrate the families who provide safe and loving homes for our Nation&#8217;s foster children.  We share our appreciation for the dedicated volunteers and professionals who help our Nation&#8217;s foster youth find permanent homes and connect with their biological families when appropriate &#8212; many of whom are working hard to safely reunite with their children.<br><br>Today, nearly a third of children in foster care are being raised by kin &#8212; many of whom are grandparents.  This helps children retain family bonds and a sense of cultural identity, which are so important to a child&#8217;s resilience and well-being.  As children and families of color are disproportionately overrepresented in foster care, it is essential that we invest in culturally supportive services to nurture all children and families who are impacted by the child welfare system.<br><br>The COVID-19 pandemic has had a disproportionate impact on young people in foster care.  That is why my Administration implemented the Supporting Foster Youth and Families through the Pandemic Act &#8212; helping foster youth aging out of the system access services to stay in school, participate in job training programs, pay rent and other bills, and transition to adulthood.  My Administration also funded grants that help agencies connect kinship caregivers and foster parents to programs and services for children in their care and we continue to promote best practices that identify and notify relatives when a child has been placed into foster care.<br><br>This month, we also recognize the history of injustice in America&#8217;s foster care system &#8212; particularly against Black and Native Americans.  Relative to their white peers, Black and Native American children stay in foster care longer and are less likely to be adopted or reunited with their birth parents.  Furthermore, foster care systems do not provide children with disabilities or LGBTQI+ youth with the individualized support, resources, and safety measures they need and deserve.  My Administration stands with transgender youth in foster care and with all families that love and care for their children.<br><br>To improve our foster care system, I have proposed a significant funding increase and a package of reforms to expand prevention services so more children can remain safely in their own homes.  For children who need to be placed into foster care, my proposal provides States with incentives to place more children with relatives or adults with whom they are emotionally bonded, when appropriate.  It will also increase resources for youth who are aging out of foster care.  In addition, I have called for competitive grants for States to advance racial equity, expand prevention services, and improve education outcomes in our child welfare system.  My proposal would also help more low- and moderate-income families afford the costs of adoption and legal guardianship of children who would otherwise be in foster care.<br>   <br>National Foster Care Month is an opportunity for us to celebrate foster youth and the people who provide them with love and support.  It is our duty to help vulnerable children, and child welfare professionals and the families they serve.  Through education, volunteering, and partnerships, we can strengthen our communities and ensure that youth in foster care have the support they need for a future they deserve.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 2022 as National Foster Care Month.  I call upon all Americans to observe this month by reaching out in their neighborhoods and communities to the children and youth in foster care and their families, to those at risk of entering foster care, and to kin families and other caregivers.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Mental Health Awareness Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-mental-health-awareness-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each May we raise awareness about the importance of mental health and its impact on the well-being of all Americans, including children, adults, families, and communities across our Nation.  We also give thanks to the dedicated mental health providers whose service and support improve the lives of so many Americans.  We stand in solidarity with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Each May we raise awareness about the importance of mental health and its impact on the well-being of all Americans, including children, adults, families, and communities across our Nation.  We also give thanks to the dedicated mental health providers whose service and support improve the lives of so many Americans.  We stand in solidarity with those who are experiencing mental health conditions, renewing our commitment to providing them with the support they need and deserve. <br><br>Even before the pandemic, millions of Americans were experiencing stress, trauma, anxiety, and heightened levels of depression.  The COVID-19 pandemic exacerbated those conditions, creating an unprecedented mental health crisis across our country. Communities of color, frontline workers, health care workers, and individuals with eating disorders have been disproportionately impacted, and the rate of depression across the country has more than tripled compared to rates in 2019.<br><br>Mental health challenges among our youth have also been particularly acute due to disruptions in routines, increased social isolation, and learning loss.  Research has shown that social media plays a central role in increasing mental health challenges among young people &#8212; especially young women.  Emergency department visits for attempted suicide among girls in 2021 increased by more than 50 percent compared to 2020.  American Indians, Alaska Natives, Black youth, and LGBTQI+ youth also face a disproportionate risk of suicide.<br><br>Despite these disturbing trends, less than half of Americans struggling with mental illness receive the treatment they need &#8212; even fewer within Black and Brown communities. A variety of factors contribute to this problem. For example, too many communities lack sufficient numbers of mental health providers.  Even where there are enough mental health providers, our fragmentated system makes it difficult for people to access them.  Tragically, too, many Americans feel ashamed to reach out for help, or are stigmatized for seeking care.<br><br>My Administration is committed to transforming mental health care for all Americans. The American Rescue Plan laid the groundwork for this effort, investing nearly $5.5 billion nationwide to strengthen mental health and substance use care. It also invested billions of dollars in our Nation&#8217;s schools, including mental health treatment for students and staff.<br><br>But far more needs to be done. That is why in this year&#8217;s State of the Union Address, I outlined my vision for bolder investments to address our national mental health crisis. My strategy includes actions that will broaden the pipeline of behavioral health professionals in areas of greatest need, integrate mental health and substance use treatment into primary care, and expand access through more virtual care options.<br><br>In addition, last year the Surgeon General released an Advisory on Protecting Youth Mental Health that underscored the growing harms of digital technologies &#8212; especially social media &#8212; on the mental health of our youth.  It is time to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children, and demand that technology companies stop collecting the personal data of our children.  We must also continue researching the impact of social media on the mental health of our children, expand services in school to promote their well-being, and set them up for success so they can thrive as adults.<br><br>As my Administration works to expand suicide prevention and strengthen crisis care infrastructure within our communities, those who need immediate assistance can call the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline at 1-800-273-TALK &#8212; which will transition to a simple three-digit number, 988, in July.<br>Each of us has an important role to play in supporting our fellow Americans who are living with mental health conditions.  Learn the warning signs of emotional distress and suicide.  Engage affected loved ones in supportive dialogue.  Fight the prejudice and negative attitudes that discourages those in need from seeking mental health support.  Above all, let us collectively ensure that all children and adults experiencing mental health challenges are treated with the compassion, respect, and understanding they deserve.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 2022 as National Mental Health Awareness Month.  I call upon citizens, government agencies, private businesses, non-profit organizations, and other groups to join in activities and take action to strengthen the mental health of our communities and our Nation.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Jewish American Heritage Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-jewish-american-heritage-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 1654, a small ship carrying 23 Jewish refugees sailed into the port of present-day New York City.  Fleeing oppression and discrimination, these courageous women and men faced resistance from the colony&#8217;s leaders.  Nevertheless, they secured the right to remain and became the first Jewish communal presence to settle on American soil.  In so doing,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In 1654, a small ship carrying 23 Jewish refugees sailed into the port of present-day New York City.  Fleeing oppression and discrimination, these courageous women and men faced resistance from the colony&#8217;s leaders.  Nevertheless, they secured the right to remain and became the first Jewish communal presence to settle on American soil.  In so doing, they expanded the frontier of religious freedoms that would help define the bedrock principles upon which this Nation was built.  During Jewish American Heritage Month, we honor these 23 refugees and the centuries of successive generations of Jewish Americans, who &#8212; shaped by their own encounters with prejudice, persecution, and the promise of a better tomorrow &#8212; have emboldened our Nation to stand up for justice, equality, and freedom.</p>



<p>The story of America was written, in part, by Jewish Americans who, through their words and actions, embraced the opportunity and responsibility of citizenship knowing full well that democracy is not born, nor sustained, by accident.  Inspired by Jewish American communal leadership, our Nation&#8217;s first President pledged that our Government will &#8220;give to bigotry no sanction, to persecution no assistance.&#8221;  Inspired by Jewish American poetry, our shores have welcomed millions with the words &#8220;Give me your tired, your poor, your huddled masses yearning to be free.&#8221;  Throughout our country&#8217;s history, Jewish Americans have proudly served our Nation in uniform, in elected office, and on our Nation&#8217;s highest courts.  They have made enormous contributions to America&#8217;s cultural, scientific, artistic, and intellectual life, and they have marched, petitioned, and boarded buses to demand civil and political rights for all &#8212; from women&#8217;s rights to voting rights to workers&#8217; rights.</p>



<p>Today, we continue to strive to live up to our founding ideals.  As the scourge of white supremacy and antisemitic violence rises, my Administration remains committed to ensuring that hate has no safe harbor.  That is why we have created new laws that give us more tools to combat hate crimes; developed the first-ever National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism; provided assistance to religious organizations, places of worship, and nonprofits to protect their facilities and members; and named a new Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Antisemitism.  My Administration will use the full force of our judicial system to confront bigotry and antisemitism wherever and whenever it surfaces.</p>



<p>The Jewish American story, and the story of our Nation as a whole, is fueled by faith, resilience, and hope.  It is a story defined by a firm belief in possibilities, the resolve to make real the promise of America for all Americans, and a commitment to perfecting our Union, heeding the timeless words of Rabbi Tarfon, the first-century scholar who taught &#8220;It is not your duty to finish the work, but neither are you at liberty to neglect it.&#8221;</p>



<p>Three-hundred and sixty-eight years after those 23 brave Jewish refugees arrived in America, Jewish Americans continue to help our country thrive and prosper.  This month, we honor the timeless traditions, heritage, and contributions of Jewish Americans that drive our progress as a Nation each and every day.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 2022 as Jewish American Heritage Month.  I call upon all Americans to visit JewishHeritageMonth.gov to learn more about the heritage and contributions of Jewish Americans and to observe this month with appropriate programs, activities, and ceremonies.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
