<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 12:37:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Blueprint for a Fair, Orderly and Humane Immigration System</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-blueprint-for-a-fair-orderly-and-humane-immigration-system/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States can have an orderly, secure, and well-managed border while treating people fairly and humanely. In January, the Biden-Harris Administration launched a broad, whole of government effort to reform our immigration system, including sending to Congress legislation that creates a new system to responsibly manage and secure our border, provide a pathway to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States can have an orderly, secure, and well-managed border while treating people fairly and humanely.</p>



<p>In January, the Biden-Harris Administration <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/20/fact-sheet-president-biden-sends-immigration-bill-to-congress-as-part-of-his-commitment-to-modernize-our-immigration-system/">launched</a> a broad, whole of government effort to reform our immigration system, including sending to Congress legislation that creates a new system to responsibly manage and secure our border, provide a pathway to citizenship, and better manage migration across the Hemisphere.</p>



<p>In the six months since, the Administration has made considerable <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/action-the-biden-harris-administration-has-taken-to-address-the-border-challenge/">progress</a> to build a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system while continuing to call on Congress to make long overdue reforms to U.S. immigration laws. We successfully processed over 12,500 people who had been returned to Mexico under the Migrant Protection Protocols. We expanded lawful pathways for protection and opportunity, including the Central American Minors (CAM) program to reunite children with their parents in the United States. We strengthened collaborative migration management with regional partners, including through a new Human Smuggling and Trafficking Task Force to disrupt and prevent migrant smuggling and human trafficking operations. And we continue to deter irregular migration at our Southern border.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has accomplished this and more while reckoning with the prior Administration’s cruel and reckless immigration policies, which exacerbated long-standing challenges and failed to securely manage our border. Case in point: the total number of unique encounters at the Southern border to date this fiscal year remains below the total number of unique encounters to date during fiscal year 2019 under the Trump Administration.</p>



<p>Today the Administration is releasing a blueprint that outlines the next steps Federal agencies will be taking to continue implementing the President’s transformative vision for a 21st century immigration system that secures the border, fairly and efficiently considers asylum claims, strengthens regional migration management efforts in North and Central America, and addresses the root causes of migration from Central America. Success in building this fair, orderly, and humane immigration system won’t be achieved overnight, especially after the prior Administration’s irrational and inhumane policies, but this Administration has a blueprint to get there and is making real progress.</p>



<p>We will always be a nation of borders, and we will enforce our immigration laws in a way that is fair and just. We will continue to work to fortify an orderly immigration system.</p>



<p><strong>ENSURING A SECURE, HUMANE AND WELL-MANAGED BORDER</strong></p>



<p>The United States can allow people to exercise their legal right to apply for asylum while also reducing irregular migration and maintaining an orderly, secure, and well-managed border.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Making better use of existing enforcement resources. </strong>Since fiscal year 2011, U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s (CBP) discretionary budget has grown from $9.9 billion to $15 billion in FY 2021. The President’s Budget redirects resources from a needless border wall to make robust investments in smarter border security measures, like border technology and modernization of land ports of entry, that are proven to be more effective at improving safety and security at the border. These investments will serve as a force multiplier to the over 19,500 Border Patrol Agents currently helping secure our Nation’s borders and the over 25,500 CBP Officers working at our land, air, and sea ports. The investments will also facilitate more robust and effective security screening to combat human smuggling and trafficking and the entry of undocumented migrants.</li><li><strong>Improving the expedited removal process for those who arrive at the border.</strong> The Administration is working to improve the expedited removal process at the border to fairly and efficiently determine which individuals have legitimate claims for asylum and other forms of protection. Asylum and other legal migration pathways should remain available to those seeking protection. Those not seeking protection or who don’t qualify will be promptly removed to their countries of origin.</li><li><strong>Facilitating secure management of borders in the region </strong>by providing training and technical assistance, supporting the improvement of border infrastructure and technology, and promoting collaborative migration and border management approaches.</li><li><strong>Strengthening anti-smuggling and anti-trafficking operations </strong>by working with regional governments to investigate and prosecute individuals involved in migrant smuggling, human trafficking, and other crimes against migrants. In April 2021, DHS announced Operation Sentinel, a new operation targeting organizations involved in criminal smuggling.</li><li><strong>Bolstering public messaging on migration </strong>by ensuring consistent messages to discourage irregular migration and promote safe, legal, and orderly migration.</li></ul>



<p><strong>IMPLEMENTING ORDERLY AND FAIR PROCESSING OF ASYLUM APPLICATIONS</strong></p>



<p>The Administration is committed to fairly and efficiently considering asylum claims. Asylum and other legal migration pathways should remain available to those seeking protection. But those not seeking protection or who don’t qualify will be returned to their country of origin.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Establishing a dedicated docket to consider asylum claims.</strong> The Administration has set up a special immigration court docket to promptly and fairly consider the protection claims of certain recent arrivals.</li><li><strong>Further improving the efficiency and fairness of the U.S. asylum system </strong>by authorizing asylum officers to adjudicate asylum claims for those arriving at the border and establishing clear and just eligibility standards that harmonize the U.S. approach with international standards. The Administration has already begun to rescind Trump administration policies and decisions that unjustly prevent individuals from obtaining asylum. On June 16, the Department of Justice reversed two of the former administration’s rulings severely restricting asylum protections for victims of domestic and gang violence.</li><li><strong>Maximizing legal representation </strong>and legal orientation programs by working closelywith pro bono legal service providers. The President’s FY 2022 Budget requests $15 million to provide representation to families and vulnerable individuals, as well as $23 million to support DOJ legal orientation programs.</li><li><strong>Reducing immigration court backlogs</strong> by ensuring priority cases are considered in a timely manner and hiring more immigration judges. The FY 2022 Budget requests an additional 100 immigration judges and provides support for additional court staff to ensure the efficient and fair processing of cases.  The Department of Justice also restored the discretion of immigration judges to administratively close cases in another step to ensure priority cases are considered in a timely manner.</li></ul>



<p><strong>STRENGTHENING COLLABORATIVE MIGRATION MANAGEMENT WITH REGIONAL PARTNERS</strong></p>



<p>The United States seeks to expand U.S. and multilateral efforts to address the dire humanitarian situation in Central America and strengthen regional collaborative migration management.  The United States believes that all individuals should be able to have a safe, stable and dignified life within their own countries, while ensuring that asylum and other legal migration pathways remain available to those who need them.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing humanitarian support to address the acute needs that pressure individuals to abandon their homes</strong>.  U.S. efforts will address food insecurity and malnutrition, mitigate the impacts of successive droughts and food shortages, promote protection for vulnerable individuals, and provide materials to support rebuilding of homes and schools damaged by the hurricanes.  The United States will also work with the United Nations to mobilize international support for the deteriorating situation in the Northern Triangle. As part of these efforts, the United States in April <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/apr-27-2021-united-states-announces-increased-assistance-people-of-el-salvador-guatemala-honduras">provided</a> $255 million in assistance to meet immediate and urgent humanitarian needs for people in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, refugees, other displaced people, and vulnerable migrants in the region.</li><li><strong>Expanding access to international protection</strong> to provide safety to individuals closer to their homes by building and improving national asylum systems, enhancing efforts to resettle refugees, and scaling up protection efforts for at-risk groups.</li><li><strong>Establishing Migration Resource</strong> <strong>Centers</strong> in the Northern Triangle countries with the support of international organizations and in coordination with governments in Central America to provide referrals to services for people seeking lawful pathways for migration and protection.  The centers also provide referrals to reintegration support for migrants returned from the United States and other countries.</li><li><strong>Restarting and expanding the Central American Minors (CAM) program </strong>to provide children the opportunity to receive protection and reunite with parents in the United States. In March 2021, the United States reopened the CAM program and, in June 2021, expanded it to additional categories of eligible U.S.-based relatives who can petition for their children.</li><li><strong>Expanding refugee processing in the region</strong>, including in-country processing in Northern Triangle countries, and helping international organizations and local non-governmental organizations to identify and refer individuals with urgent protection needs to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program and other resettlement countries. The U.S. Department of State and Department of Homeland Security have resumed interviewing individuals via the Protection Transfer Arrangement (PTA) to expand protection for vulnerable nationals of El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.</li><li><strong>Expanding access to temporary work visas in the region.  </strong>DHS announced a supplemental increase of 6,000 H-2B visas for temporary non-agricultural workers from Honduras, Guatemala and El Salvador in FY 2021. The Administration is also exploring ways to enhance access to H-2A visas for temporary agricultural workers when there are insufficient qualified U.S. workers to fill these jobs, while ensuring strong labor protections for all workers.  The Administration will also encourage other governments to develop and expand regional labor migration programs that protect workers’ rights and allow access for individuals to find meaningful, temporary work.</li><li><strong>Reducing immigrant visa backlogs.  </strong>The United States aims to reduce the backlog of immigrant visa applications for Northern Triangle nationals as quickly as possible.</li></ul>



<p><strong>INVESTING IN CENTRAL AMERICA TO ADDRESS THE ROOT CAUSES OF MIGRATION</strong></p>



<p>We cannot solve the challenge at our border without addressing the lack of economic opportunity, weak governance and corruption, and violence and insecurity that compel people to flee their homes in the first place.  The impact of two major hurricanes in late 2020, a prolonged drought, and COVID-19 have aggravated these long-standing challenges.  The FY 2022 Budget requests $861 million to address the root causes of migration.    </p>



<ul><li><strong>Addressing economic insecurity and inequality </strong>by investing in programs that foster a business-enabling environment for inclusive economic growth; enhancing workforce development, health, and education; and building resilience to climate change and food insecurity so individuals can find economic opportunity at home. The U.S. will also work with stakeholders to increase trade and diversify industry, as well as with the private sector to build on the <em>Call to Action</em> to catalyze investments in the region and support economic development.</li><li><strong>Combatting corruption and strengthening democratic governance </strong>by working with governments, civil society, and independent media to improve government services, increase transparency, promote accountability and respect for human rights, sanction corrupt actors, and provide protection to at-risk youth, victims of violence, and other marginalized populations.</li><li><strong>Promoting respect for human rights, labor rights and a free press</strong> by working with governments and civil society to strengthen legal frameworks and build institutional capacity, hold perpetrators accountable, promote labor rights compliance, and ensure citizens have access to information from independent sources to inform their choices.</li><li><strong>Countering and preventing violence, extortion, and other crimes</strong> by strengthening accountable law enforcement, focusing on crime prevention, and encouraging regional cooperation to address shared criminal threats.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Combatting sexual, gender-based and domestic violence </strong>by working with governments and civil society to prevent and prosecute violence and support victims.</li></ul>



<p>While President Biden can implement significant parts of this strategy within his executive authority, <strong><u>Congress must also act.</u></strong>  Millions of noncitizens call our country home.  Immigrants are key a key part of our communities and make significant contributions to our economy.  Over the past year, millions of immigrants have risked their health to work side by side with other Americans to perform jobs that are essential to the functioning of the country.  They are Americans in every way but on paper.  The American public supports a path to citizenship and a fair and efficient legal immigration system that welcomes talent from around the globe and allows families to reunite and make a life in our country.</p>



<p><strong>Congress should pass </strong>through reconciliation or other means:</p>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">The U.S. Citizenship Act (H.R. 1177/S. 348)</span> that reunites families, gives businesses access to a workforce with full labor rights, and creates a path to citizenship for those already living and working in the United States.  These critical reforms, coupled with measures to address the root causes of migration from Central America, will relieve pressure at the border by dissuading irregular migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">The Dream and Promise Act (H.R. 6) and Farm Workforce Modernization Act (H.R. 1603)</span> to create a path to citizenship for Dreamers, TPS recipients, and farmworkers. Both bills passed the House with bipartisan support.  They will protect millions of families, children, and essential workers who live, work, study, and worship in our communities. </li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Meeting with Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi of Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/26/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-meeting-with-prime-minister-al-kadhimi-of-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi of Iraq to strengthen bilateral coordination under the Strategic Framework Agreement.&#160; Together they discussed expanded initiatives on climate, energy, education, and combatting the COVID-19 pandemic.&#160; They committed to a continued security partnership to ensure that ISIS can never resurge and to allow communities recovering&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi of Iraq to strengthen bilateral coordination under the Strategic Framework Agreement.&nbsp; Together they discussed expanded initiatives on climate, energy, education, and combatting the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; They committed to a continued security partnership to ensure that ISIS can never resurge and to allow communities recovering from terror to rebuild with dignity even as the United States shifts to a purely advisory role. The leaders reaffirmed their respect for Iraq’s democracy, the rule of law, and promoting a secure environment for Iraq’s upcoming elections in October. The leaders agreed on the vital importance of holding these elections on time, and welcomed the UN monitoring mission to support their full transparency and fairness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together, they discussed the important role of Iraq in the region and the significant diplomatic efforts led by Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi to improve and strengthen Iraq’s relationships in the region.&nbsp; They lauded the historic visit of Pope Francis to Iraq earlier this year, the trilateral summit with Egypt and Jordan, and the important role Iraq plays in promoting interfaith tolerance and the common bonds of humanity in the Middle East.&nbsp; They agreed that Iraq’s stability was central to the stability of the entire region.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and Prime Minister Mustafa Al-Kadhimi of the Republic of Iraq Before Bilateral Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/26/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-mustafa-al-kadhimi-of-the-republic-of-iraq-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 2:20 P.M. EDT&#160;PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, I&#8217;m honored to welcome the Prime Minister.&#160; We&#8217;ve known each other for some time.&#160; And welcome to the White House, welcome to the Oval, Mr. Prime Minister.&#160;&#160;Iraq has been a vital part for the &#8212; partner of the United States for some time now in the Middle East.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>2:20 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m honored to welcome the Prime Minister.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve known each other for some time.&nbsp; And welcome to the White House, welcome to the Oval, Mr. Prime Minister.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Iraq has been a vital part for the &#8212; partner of the United States for some time now in the Middle East.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve en- &#8212; I’ve engaged deeply in Iraq for my entire career back in the Senate, as Vice President, and as President. &nbsp;And I&#8217;ve worked with Iraq to &#8212; and matter of fact, my son Beau was in Iraq for a year with the Am- &#8212; with the Army National Guard.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the sacrifices that so many &#8212; so many have made to build the U.S.-Iraq partnership has been real, and it&#8217;s consequential.&nbsp; And my administration is committed to strengthening that partnership, Mr. Prime Minister.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the U.S-Iraqi Strategic Dialogue is about commitments that expand our cooperation on issues like healthcare, climate, energy.&nbsp; For &#8212; matter of fact, I wanted to tell you: I was told you &#8212; the half a million &#8212; 500,000 &#8212; doses of COVID vaccine we&#8217;re sending &#8212; I was told you were told they wouldn’t come for a while.&nbsp; They’ll be there in a couple of weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRIME MINISTER AL-KADHIMI:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; They’ll be there quickly. &nbsp;And &#8212; and, you know, we support strengthening Iraq’s democracy, and we&#8217;re anxious to make sure the election goes forward in October.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also committed to our security cooperation.&nbsp; Our shared fight against ISIS is critical for the stability of the region.&nbsp; And our counterterrorism cooperation will continue, even as we shift to this new phase we&#8217;re going to be talking about.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m looking forward to consulting with the Prime Minister today.&nbsp; We have a lot to talk about.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been a good friend.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m anxious to get going.<br>&nbsp;<br>Floor is yours, sir.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRIME MINISTER AL-KADHIMI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp;&nbsp;It&#8217;s a great honor to be here today with our American friends.&nbsp;&nbsp;We have strategic partnership.&nbsp;&nbsp;I&#8217;m happy to be here in Washington to discuss the future of our nation and how to improve this relation between our two countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>America, they help Iraq.&nbsp;&nbsp;Together we fight to defeat Daesh &#8212; ISIS.&nbsp;&nbsp;And I&#8217;d like to thank the American people on behalf of all Iraq’s people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Mr. President, I thank you for all the blood and treasure that America has given for a free and democratic Iraq.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, our relation is stronger than ever.&nbsp; Our partnership exists for economy, the environment, health, education, culture, and more.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m looking forward to work with you, Mr. President, to bring our two countries more closer for benefit of Iraq and United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>God bless our two countries.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: &nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, folks.<br>&nbsp;<br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.&nbsp;Whoa, whoa, whoa.&nbsp; Whoa. &nbsp;Hang on a second.&nbsp; If you want to talk about Iraq, ask me a question about Iraq.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How many troops would you like to see in Iraq by the end of this year?&nbsp; And how does the relationship changes, considering this is the last strategic dialogue that you have with Iraq and the Prime Minister?<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; This most recent dialogue you mean.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Correct.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve been talking a lot.&nbsp; Our foreign ministers, our Cabinet members have been talking.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking forward to seeing an election in October.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working very hard with the Iraqi government to make sure the U.N. and the GCC are &#8212; we have oversight; that there&#8217;s &#8212; these are full and fair elections.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ve been in &#8212; I&#8217;ve been in contact with Kadhimi.&nbsp; I have &#8212; anyway, I think things are going well.&nbsp; Our role in Iraq will be as a &#8212; dealing with not &#8212; it’s just to be available, to continue to train, to assist, to help, and to deal with ISIS as it &#8212; as it arrives.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re not going to be, by the end of the year, in a combat mission.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, Veterans Affairs.&nbsp; Mr. President, Veterans Affairs is going to have a mandate for its healthcare &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; You are such a pain in the neck, but I&#8217;m going to answer your question because we&#8217;ve known each other for so long. It has nothing to do with Iraq.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I take that as a compliment, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; (Laughs.) &nbsp;I&#8217;ll answer your question.&nbsp; Yes, Veteran Affairs is going to, in fact, require that all docs working in facilities are going to have to be vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>2:26 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe Biden on the Passing of Civil Rights Leader, Bob Moses</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/26/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-civil-rights-leader-bob-moses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 20:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaking in the spring of 1964 about his plans for Freedom Summer, Bob Moses summed up the heroic effort to register Black voters in the Deep South with a question: “What kind of society will we be?”  Throughout his remarkable life, Bob devoted his heart and soul to lead, teach, and organize generations of Americans&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Speaking in the spring of 1964 about his plans for Freedom Summer, Bob Moses summed up the heroic effort to register Black voters in the Deep South with a question: “<em>What kind of society will we be?</em>” <br><br>Throughout his remarkable life, Bob devoted his heart and soul to lead, teach, and organize generations of Americans to answer that question by making real the promise of our nation – that we are all created equal and deserve to be treated equally throughout our lives.<br><br>He did so with uncommon grace, calm, and humility despite every bullet, arrest, and unrelenting brutality he faced.<br><br>The violent and murderous response to the Freedom Summer he organized helped galvanize support for the landmark Voting Rights Act of 1965.  A celebrated educator by training and by heart, he understood education is a great equalizer and helped countless students, and our nation, realize their dreams and full potential.<br><br>From the polling stations of Mississippi and in classrooms of our nation, Bob always showed up and never, ever gave in. In his memory, let us continue his unfinished work and answer the question he asked us once before – to be a society that delivers on the promise of this nation.<br><br>With attacks on the right to vote unseen since the days of the Jim Crow system Bob helped to dismantle, I call on Congress again to pass the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act. Let us build the coalition of Americans of every race and background that he once formed to meet the urgency of the moment. And let us follow his towering legacy and ensure every American is treated with the dignity and respect they deserve.<br><br>Jill and I send our love and prayers to Bob’s wife, Janet, their four children, and their seven grandchildren.<br><br>May God bless Bob Moses.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 26, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/26/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-26-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 20:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1:04 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Happy Monday.&#160; Okay.&#160; Today, I wanted to start by providing a brief note on where we are with our battle against the pandemic at home.&#160;First, taking a step back: In December, the percentage of Americans willing to get a shot was in the 30s.&#160; We now have 70 percent&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1:04 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Happy Monday.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Today, I wanted to start by providing a brief note on where we are with our battle against the pandemic at home.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, taking a step back: In December, the percentage of Americans willing to get a shot was in the 30s.&nbsp; We now have 70 percent of adult &#8212; almost 70 percent, I should say, of adult Americans who have been vaccinated.&nbsp; That is a positive step forward, and it is an encouraging sign to us that we can still get more people vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Where we are today signals we&#8217;ve made pretty incredible progress with our vaccination effort.&nbsp; Sixty percent of adult Americans are fully vaccinated, including 80 percent of seniors.&nbsp; Nearly 90 percent of teachers have gotten a shot.&nbsp; Ninety-five percent-plus of physicians have been fully vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>For the second week in a row, last week the five states with the highest case rates &#8212; Arkansas, Florida, Louisiana, Texas, and California &#8212; had a higher rate of people getting newly vaccinated compared to the national average.&nbsp; Again, this is a positive trend.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And just one more recent proof point: In the reporting period from yesterday, nearly half a million Americans made the decision to get their first shot.<br>&nbsp;<br>Numbers like this signal to us people are understanding the urgency and importance of getting vaccinated, and rightfully so.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as you&#8217;ve heard me say in here a number of times, 162-plus million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; They have a very strong degree of protection against the variants.&nbsp; They are overwhelmingly avoiding severe illness, hospitalization, and, critically important, death.&nbsp; Unvaccinated individuals account for virtually all of the hospitalizations and deaths in the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And data out from the United Kingdom, which has experienced &#8212; experiencing its own surge in cases driven by Delta, showed hospitalization rates down 73 percent compared to December, when there were nearly identical case rates but almost no vaccinations.&nbsp; And what that means is the vaccinations are protecting people from hospitalizations in the United Kingdom, which is a positive sign.&nbsp; And deaths are down 93 percent &#8212; further proof that getting fully vaccinated is the best thing anyone can do to protect themselves and those around them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, we are seeing a significant rise in cases in certain parts of the country and amongst certain populations, and they&#8217;re concentrated primarily and overwhelmingly among the unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re hearing and you all are reporting on stories on those not getting vaccinated.&nbsp; Some of those&nbsp;&#8212; like a radio host in Tennessee &#8212; are saying from their hospital bed that they plan to be a strong advocate for the vaccine after recovering from severe illness because of COVID.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t want it to lea- &#8212; we don&#8217;t want that to be the breaking point for anyone, but we are seeing that across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, again, the reality is: It&#8217;s preventable.&nbsp; We welcome people&#8217;s questions around the country about vaccines and their efficacy.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll be here for people, whatever they want to talk about, as will people in local communities.&nbsp; But I just wanted to provide a quick update with all of your good questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Aamer, go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci said yesterday that recommending that the vaccinated wear masks is under active consideration.&nbsp; I was wondering where do things stand with that conversation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then also COVID-related:&nbsp;Considering that the administration is not moving at the moment to lift the restrictions on travel because of the Delta variant, is the administration weighing broader recommendations on telling Americans &#8212; and I know there are some places, like the UK &#8212; but, &#8220;Don&#8217;t go&#8221;?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say, for any of these recommendations, we are always going to be guided by our North Star &#8212; and that is the CDC and our health and medical experts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as I said last week, having an active &#8212; it would be actually surprising and odd if our health and medical experts were not having active &#8212; an active discussion about how to protect &#8212; best protect the American people.&nbsp; And there, of course, is an active discussion about a range of steps that can be taken, as there has been from the first day of this administration.<br>&nbsp;<br>Certainly, the surge in cases among unvaccinated, because of the Delta variant, prompts, you know, even more discussion about what actions can be taken.&nbsp; But we are going to &#8212; the CDC looks at data, they look at data across the country, in a range of regions across the country.&nbsp; And if they make an assessment, we will of course be here to follow their guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I may, just one more on tomorrow &#8212; I think it’s tomorrow&#8217;s visit to the ODNI.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any &#8212; what is the President going there to say, do?&nbsp; Is there any major announcements expected?&nbsp; And how much of this is about also sending a different or contrasting message with the previous President, who sometimes had some comments that were less than flattering about the intelligence community?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Let me just go back to your last question about the travel restrictions, if you don&#8217;t mind &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh &#8212; thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; because I just want to confirm it for those of you.&nbsp; So, given where we are today &#8212; and I think you&#8217;ve seen this, and those of you who have asked, we&#8217;ve confirmed this for &#8212; with the Delta variant, we will maintain existing travel restrictions at this point for a few reasons.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The more transmissible Delta variant is spreading both here and around the world.&nbsp; Driven by the Delta variant, cases are rising here at home, particularly among those who are unvaccinated, and appear likely to continue in the weeks ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>And to get to the other part of your question, the CDC just advised Americans against travel to the United Kingdom this past Monday, given the surge in cases.&nbsp; They will evaluate and make &#8212; and make recommendations based on health data.<br>&nbsp;<br>To your question about his &#8212; the President&#8217;s visit to ODNI tomorrow to see the Director of National Intelligence &#8212; first woman to lead the intelligence community in history, I&#8217;ll just note &#8212; yes, I think the President &#8212; one, he will go there to receive an update on their work, but also to thank them for their work during what has been, no doubt, a challenging time for members of the intelligence community over the last several years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;s someone who believes in the role of the intelligence community, of civil servants.&nbsp; He believes they&#8217;re the backbone of our government, and certainly he&#8217;ll make that clear.&nbsp; But, you know, I think you can all make the inherent contrast; I don&#8217;t think that will be a central part of his message tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; To follow up on masks, Dr. Fauci confirmed yesterday he was obviously part of the discussions.&nbsp; Is President Biden part of the discussions, as well, regarding whether to bring back the recommendations and/or any of his economic advisors?&nbsp; Just trying to understand who&#8217;s &#8212; who&#8217;s making the decision.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President receives regular updates from his COVID team.&nbsp; But the guidance &#8212; or the discussions are primarily between the health and medical experts about how we should proceed from here to address the rising cases in &#8212; from the Delta variant among unvaccinated and protect the American public.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything you can share about what they are considering &#8212; what are the pros and the cons for re-recommending masks for vaccinated people?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It &#8212; we don&#8217;t look at it through that prism.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t make these decisions or recommendations based on politics.&nbsp; They make them based on data.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So it&#8217;s quite simple: They look at data across the country.&nbsp; They make a determination about what steps they could recommend to protect more people and save more lives.&nbsp; And then, if they make a recommendation, as you&#8217;ve seen over the past several months, we will work to implement it.&nbsp; But it is not more complicated than that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; And one on Afghanistan.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In recent days, there have been several U.S. airstrikes against the Taliban.&nbsp; After the deadline for troop withdrawal on August 31st, will the U.S. continue to support Afghan forces in airstrikes?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve said we would maintain over-the-horizon capacity.&nbsp; Beyond that, I don&#8217;t have any other updates.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A group of healthcare professionals are saying that there should be mandates for all who work in the healthcare system because of what they say is an ethical need to do so, to be vaccinated.&nbsp; And we see that there are local communities that are bringing mask mandates or recommendations.&nbsp; So are we at a point where Americans should be looking to professional organizations, businesses, and local officials for guidance on what to do more than the federal government at this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say: We would hope that the guidance is aligned with &#8212; there are going to be localities that have higher vac- &#8212; higher rates of outbreaks that they may make additional recommendations.&nbsp; They may take steps to keep their community safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We certainly have seen, as you noted, that there are institutions, including across the health industry.&nbsp; As many of you have may have seen, today, 57 leading healthcare groups &#8212; including the American Medical Association, the American College of Physicians, the American Academy of Pediatrics, and the American Public Health Association &#8212; all called for all healthcare and long-term care employees to mandate employees be vaccinated against COVID.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, that is the healthcare industry where they are very much on the frontlines.&nbsp; And these actions, in our view, are meant to keep patients and employees safe.&nbsp; And, in fact, I expect our own federal healthcare providers may look at similar requirements, as they do with other vaccines.<br>&nbsp;<br>As it relates to what the American people should look to &#8212; look, the CDC is looking at data across the country.&nbsp; They provide broad public health guidance not based on politics, driven by science and data.&nbsp; And they make updates when they feel it is necessary to make updates, and then localities will apply that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you suggesting perhaps the VA would be making a similar recommendation or requirement?&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re hinting at there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; I think there&#8217;ll be more to &#8212; more to say in the coming days on that, Kelly.&nbsp; But I will tell you that we certainly believe that public &#8212; that health officials are on the frontlines of, you know, being vulnerable to getting COVID, and we certainly support these actions by these hospital associations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House view it as a benefit if employers, as varied as the NFL to hospitals, are trying to push vaccination?&nbsp; Would that close the gap, in your view, with some of those who&#8217;ve not yet done so for a variety of reasons?&nbsp; I mean, do you see this as another lever that might actually be helpful to the President&#8217;s goals?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It may.&nbsp; And beyond the President&#8217;s goals, it may save lives, and that&#8217;s the most important &#8212; important factor, in our view.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re seeing institutions, healthcare providers, colleges and universities, the NFL implement different approaches and steps to incentivize and increase vaccination rates.&nbsp; The more people are vaccinated, the more the country will be safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last one.&nbsp; Do you expect that for air travelers domestically in the United States who’ve been required to wear a mask by FAA regulation for a long time &#8212; that&#8217;s set to expire in September &#8212; should we anticipate that that would likely stay in place, given the Delta variant?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any &#8212; any guidance by our CDC.&nbsp; But certainly, they will continue to provide guidance on masks that keeps more people safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On COVID, Dr. Fauci says, “We&#8217;re going in the wrong direction.”&nbsp; Whose fault is that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, what he was referring to is the fact that because there&#8217;s still a large population of people in this country who are unvaccinated and we have the most transmissible variants that we&#8217;ve seen since the beginning of the pandemic that more people are getting sick with COVID.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s not &#8212; those numbers are not moving in the right direction.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s accurate and you can see it by data.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then on crime: It has been more than a month since the President announced his comprehensive strategy to prevent and respond to gun crime and ensure public safety.&nbsp; This weekend, in Chicago, 73 people were shot; 11 of them were killed.&nbsp; Does the President think his strategy is working?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think you and I both know that when there&#8217;s been rising crime rates across the country, including Chicago, for 18 months or more that, unfortunately, it&#8217;s not going to turn on a dime, and that we are working with Chicago &#8212; it&#8217;s one of the cities &#8212; one of the five cities we&#8217;re working with.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Department of Justice has a group in there to help address the transmitting &#8212; or, the selling of guns and get &#8212; that are getting into the hands of people who shouldn&#8217;t have them.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working closely with the mayor and local elected officials.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve benefited a huge amount from the federal assistance and funding that the President fought to include in the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And what our hope is is that we can work in partnership to bring crime down, save more people.&nbsp; In cities like Chicago, we know gun violence is a big driver of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And after a couple shootings here in D.C. last week, the Chief of Police blamed some of the crime on marijuana dealers.&nbsp; He said he knows that people know that marijuana laws have loosened up.&nbsp; Does the White House think that it may be time to get tougher on marijuana?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think as we look to the crime that has been happening in D.C. &#8212; again, one of the cities where we&#8217;ve seen rising violence over the past year and a half, one where we&#8217;re working in close partnership through both the DOJ Gun Trafficking Strike Forces and &#8212; as well as our Community Violence Prevent- &#8212; Intervention Collaborative, we&#8217;re looking to address a range of causes, but working in close partnership with the mayor and police &#8212; local police to bring crime down in our city.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Quick question on tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; January 6th’s Select Committee &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; first meeting takes place tomorrow here.&nbsp; It takes place tomorrow.&nbsp; Do you know if the President plans to watch any of it?&nbsp; And what are his expectations for the outcome?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, first, the President has called for, as you know, a full and independent investigation to the events of January 6th.&nbsp; And he continues to support Speaker Pelosi’s leadership of that work, including her decision to appoint Republican members who are similarly committed to this objective.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, in his view and our view, tomorrow&#8217;s hearing will be an opportunity to hear firsthand from the men and women in the Capitol Police and the Metropolitan Police Department who bravely protected our Capitol on that day.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>His goal is the same goal that Speaker Pelosi has, which is to get to the bottom of what happened and prevent it from happening in the future.&nbsp; And he trusts her leadership to do exactly that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will he be watching any of the hearings?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, he typically has quite a packed schedule.&nbsp; He does catch news clips, sometimes all of you are featured in them.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sure he will be kept abreast of the hearings and the work that&#8217;s happening on the Hill tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then a follow-up on COVID: We&#8217;re hearing from health experts who are increasingly voicing their concern for the FDA having yet to grant full approval to COVID vaccines.&nbsp; Folks are using phrases like “grave mistake,” “puzzling as to why they haven&#8217;t yet.”&nbsp; What is your understanding as to why we have not seen full approval yet from the FDA?&nbsp; And do you have any, kind of, expectation for when we might?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the FDA is the gold standard, in our view, and they move at the speed of science.&nbsp; They look at a range of data and they make sure that when they make conclusions and when they give full approval, they have confidence in the science and the data that backs that up.&nbsp; It wouldn&#8217;t be responsible to expedite that process at a faster speed than the science and data allows.<br>&nbsp;<br>Certainly, everyone is eager &#8212; as the mother of two children under 12 myself, I would love to have vaccines approved so I can get my kids vaccinated.&nbsp; We understand that completely and understand the desire to have full approval, of course, as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re hopeful to see that in the coming months as Sec- &#8212; as &#8212; I was going to call him “Secretary Fauci” &#8212; as Dr. Fauci has said.&nbsp; But again, we rely on them to determine their own timeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; “Coming months” are &#8212; does the White House believe that we could be losing valuable time in waiting for full approval if this is what&#8217;s keeping so many folks from getting<br>vaccinated at this point?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think what&#8217;s most important is that the FDA maintains itself as the gold standard in approving use of vaccines for approval.&nbsp; And the fact that they are always going to be driven by the speed of science, they&#8217;re going to have extensive data they look into, they&#8217;re going to have the best health and medical experts making that conclusion, that will maintain confidence over the long term.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, we all want to see vaccines fully approved, vaccines for kids under 12.&nbsp; I think every &#8212; most Americans would say that.&nbsp; But that we&#8217;re going to &#8212; it&#8217;s important they move at their own speed and the speed at the scientists.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On an international issue, I wanted to ask you about Tunisia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has dismissed the parliament, most of the government, and it&#8217;s been denounced by multiple parties as a coup.&nbsp; Does the White House see that as a coup and have any reaction to what&#8217;s happening there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, we&#8217;re concerned about the developments in Tunisia, which come as Tunisian authorities are seeking to stabilize their economy, confront a resurgence in the COVID-19 pandemic, and improve living standards for all Tunisians.<br>&nbsp;<br>We are in touch at a senior level, from both the White House and the State Department, with Tunisian leaders to learn more about the situation, urge calm, and support Tunisian efforts to move forward in line with democratic principles.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know and as you just asked about, these &#8212; there have been a lot of developments, even over the last 24 hours.&nbsp; A legal determination about a coup &#8212; a determination about a coup is a legal determination, and we would look to the State Department to conduct a legal analysis before making a determination.&nbsp; So there hasn&#8217;t been a conclusion on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then I just wanted to ask about the embassy in Tunis, which handles a lot of business for the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; region, including Libya, et cetera.&nbsp; Any changes, as far as operations there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve not been made aware of changes but, again, that would be a decision made by the State Department based on their diplomatic security advice on the ground.&nbsp; But &#8212; so I would send you to them for any &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then just on a different issue, you know, with people talking about COVID and what some of the impacts of this new surge that we&#8217;re seeing are going to be, there might be some economic impacts.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen some Wall Street banks bring down their forecasts for what GDP growth is going to look like for this year.&nbsp; If that continues to be an issue, would the White House consider more stimulus &#8212; the type that we saw earlier this year &#8212; $1,400 checks, et cetera?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think an important piece to note for all of you is that the way the American Rescue Plan was designed was for it to have lasting effects that would go over the series of several months, far beyond the initial months of implementation.&nbsp; So there are components of the American Rescue Plan that are still being implemented that will still be implemented for months to come.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a lesson we&#8217;ve learned from the past about how people will need assistance for a longer period of time than just a short window.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that there are areas &#8212; I mean, we&#8217;ve seen, obviously, data in the housing market &#8212; right? &#8212; where there are &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s an impact &#8212; an economic impact is on people being able to stay in rental properties or in their homes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are areas of continued implementation &#8212; I think you&#8217;re familiar with these, but I&#8217;ll just note them &#8212; including on the forbearance program that we have &#8212; we have implemented in recent months, where people will be able to apply &#8212; I&#8217;m just using this as an example because I think housing and being able to stay in your house has a big impact to the economy &#8212; people can still apply through the end of September and still benefit from forbearance for six months following and then even longer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, point is, there a number of programs &#8212; the Child Tax Credit, which as you know, we started implementing in monthly checks, but there&#8217;s still going to be a benefit through to next year &#8212; that are part of the American Rescue Plan that we will continue to implement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also say that there&#8217;s &#8212; when it comes to the economy, there&#8217;s no significant signs, according to our economists, at this point, that the Delta variant impact across the country.&nbsp; We&#8217;d expect that much of any economic impact would be felt in the communities with lower vaccination rates; that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doubling down on our efforts to ensure we&#8217;re reaching Americans with the vaccine where they are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s one of the notes that, I think, our Secretary of Commerce made last week as well.&nbsp; One of the biggest, most important steps people can take is to get vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one very quick one &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; about the meetings that Wendy Sherman &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; has been having in China.&nbsp; I know that both sides basically came out of those meetings saying that there were disagreements.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What does that tell us about the possibility for some kind of talks between Xi and Biden?&nbsp; I mean, you know, you kind of set this template that &#8212; you know, with Russia &#8212; that even if you have disagreements, you&#8217;re going to still have meetings at the highest level.&nbsp; So where does that stand and do you still see that as possible or likely?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say, broadly speaking, as it relates to diplomacy, that is how we feel.&nbsp; And it was important for Deputy Secretary Sherman to go to Beijing and have these meetings because we think it&#8217;s important for us to say directly to the Chinese officials in private what we say in public.&nbsp; It&#8217;s in our interest to be very clear to Beijing about where we stand and explain our concerns in detail.<br>&nbsp;<br>And our philosophy is that we should not avoid hard topics, and they are certainly a part of any discussion we have diplomatically.&nbsp; There are areas where we have concern we&#8217;re very straightforward about, whether it&#8217;s the crackdown on Hong Kong, ongoing genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang, abuses in Tibet, curtailing of media access.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are also areas where we might align: the climate crisis; counternarcotics; nonproliferation; regional concerns, including DPRK, Iran, Afghanistan, and Burma.<br>&nbsp;<br>A topic of &#8212; you know, the President continues to believe in face-to-face diplomacy.&nbsp; That is something he has long been an advocate for, and we expect there will be some opportunity to engage at some point.&nbsp; But it did not come up in the context of these meetings, and it wasn&#8217;t &#8212; that was not the purpose of these meetings.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kaitlan.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll go to you, Mike, next, and then we&#8217;ll go around the room.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions for you: One, does the President favor restrictions for unvaccinated people when it comes to restaurants, museums, concerts?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President favors using the CDC as his North Star and what the health and medical experts are going to advise on how to save more lives and protect people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, no, he doesn&#8217;t think that there should be restrictions on unvaccinated people, like some other countries have instituted?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He believes that we should be guided by the science and by the data, and so he will look to his health and medical team to advise on what steps we should take.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Iraq, what will the number of U.S. forces be by the end of this year, given the drawdown you&#8217;re going to confirm today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, one, it&#8217;s important to note that this is one in a series of strategic dialogues &#8212; or this has been an ongoing strategic dialogue.&nbsp; And at the early part of the strategic dialogue, we had about 9,000 troops.&nbsp; We are now at about 2,500 U.S. forces in Iraq.&nbsp; We are there, of course, at Iraq&#8217;s invitation to improve the capacity of Iraqi Security Forces and help them in the fight against ISIS.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, but the real &#8212; the real announcement today &#8212; or real news today, I should say, is about a change of mission.&nbsp; And the numbers will be driven by what is needed for the mission over time.&nbsp; So, it is more about moving to a more advising and training capacity from what we have had over the last several years.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; But regardless of the title and what their mission is, how many &#8212; what&#8217;s the number that we expect to be there by December, given it&#8217;s by the end of the year?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just say the most important part is that it is a change in mission, and that the mission is changing in Iraq, and that it will be driven by what is needed for the mission.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I&#8217;m not going to give you operational &#8212; nor will I have operational details.&nbsp; I would point you to the Department of Defense on that.&nbsp; But the first step is the change in mission, the end of combat &#8212; of a combat role in Iraq and moving to a more of a train, advise, and assist role.&nbsp; That is what the Iraqi leadership have conveyed they want to see on the ground.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two COVID-related questions.&nbsp; One on mandates, which we&#8217;re seeing obviously &#8212; as folks have said already here &#8212;&nbsp;more kinds of places embrace, whether they be local authorities or more businesses, or colleges and universities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>How much does the President and do the people around the President fear that his weighing in more heavily to embrace mandates by these other institutions &#8212; or even mandates that the federal government impose on the military or federal workers, or what have you &#8212; how much do you fear that that actually inflames the culture war and is counterproductive, and that people will harden their opposition to the idea of taking a vaccination because the President is the President and is &#8212; and, sort of, the more he weighs in, that it actually is counterproductive?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that&#8217;s an important point in that we look &#8212; we do not want to look at our objective of getting more people vaccinated through a political prism.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t.&nbsp; And the President certainly recognizes that he is not always the right voice to every community about the benefits of getting vaccinated, which is why we have invested as much as we have in local voices and empowering local trusted voices.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say, though, that mandates, as is evidenced by the hospital associations, those are meant to keep people safe across the country.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to judge our success here by whether we score political points.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to judge it by whether we are able to save more lives.&nbsp; And if the health and medical experts suggest those are &#8212; that&#8217;s the right way to go, then we will support that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, on the travel &#8212; the extension of the travel bans, is there a &#8212; is it an indefinite extension at this point?&nbsp; Is there an end date?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And given the concern about Delta that is leading the United States to keep those in place for now, does that suggest that Title 42, and the use of Title 42 at the southern border, is equally likely to be extended, at least for now, given the same concerns with the Delta virus, both here and abroad?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, nothing is indefinite because obviously our objective is to defeat the virus.&nbsp; So, no.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have a timeline to predict for you because it&#8217;s all about what success we have at getting more people vaccinated, getting more vaccines out to the world, and fighting the virus.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have never conveyed or announced a timeline for Title 42.&nbsp; So, nothing has changed in that regard.&nbsp; It remains in place, and it will remain in place as long as that is the guidance from our health and medical experts.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; On infrastructure, there&#8217;s a pretty robust blame game already going on this morning over the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tis the season.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; over the negotiations going awry.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m wondering if the White House is concerned that the negotiators will not finalize a deal soon.&nbsp; And how much time is President Biden willing to give these negotiators, considering we&#8217;re on a pretty tight timetable?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as is normal in the end stages of big negotiations, there are some outstanding issues.&nbsp; Democrats made an offer that was designed to resolve each of these outstanding issues, which involve proposed compromises on our part and theirs.&nbsp; As we always are at this point in the negotiations, we&#8217;re in close touch with Republicans and Democrats on the Hill about this, and confident &#8212; we remain confident, I should say, about reaching an agreement.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also interested in any Republican counteroffers.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I would say this is to be expected.&nbsp; We always know that there are &#8212; is some wrangling at the end of a process.&nbsp; I would say &#8212; tell you also that White House staff and negotiators worked through the weekend, as I think many of you know.&nbsp; The President worked the phones all weekend and is continuing to.&nbsp; We&#8217;re encouraged as we&#8217;ve reached the final issues that need to be worked out and are confident about the path forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, yes, time is not endless.&nbsp; We are certainly on a timeline here, and we will work closely with Leader Schumer to get it done.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you want to see something this week?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we&#8217;ve certainly conveyed &#8212; and, again, Leader Schumer has conveyed the need to move forward.&nbsp; And we are optimistic about the progress and focused on steadily moving forward.&nbsp; And we continue to see progress being made each day.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second question, on COVID: Is there any discussion at the White House, at this point, of President Biden getting a booster shot?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We would rely on the health and &#8212; the expertise of our health and medical experts, and that&#8217;s not a guidance that they are providing at this point in time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I know that you&#8217;ve said a lot about being guided by the science.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about the science that is driving the continuation of this kind of travel ban?&nbsp; The Delta variant is already dominant in the U.S., so how does keeping people from foreign countries out, like, protect people in the U.S.?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I&#8217;m not a doctor or a medical expert.&nbsp; I think that that would best be posed to a member of the CDC or one of our doctors.&nbsp; But I think their decision was made based on the fact that the Delta variant is more transmissible and is spreading around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yes, it is the dominant variant here in the United States. That doesn&#8217;t mean that having more people who have the Delta variant is the right step.<br>&nbsp;<br>They &#8212; and also, we see cases rising here at home, particularly among those who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; And again, they base their decisions on data, on health and medical expertise, and on a consideration of a range of factors, including keeping the American people safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the scientists who are making these decisions are medical experts.&nbsp; Is it the CDC that is making the decision?&nbsp; Like, who is the &#8212; who is making these decisions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is the CDC?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, I just wasn’t sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so &#8212; and also, on a separate issue, when it comes to the issues of, like, voting rights, police reform &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; there are civil rights groups, voting rights groups that are expressing frustration with the White House.&nbsp; They feel like it is not giving the priority that they feel like it should be, especially because of the rhetoric that has come from the President saying that this is &#8212; you know, that these issues are taking the country back and that these are really some of the biggest issues since the Civil War.&nbsp; And yet, they feel like there has not been movement and pressure to get something done &#8212; concrete, tangible &#8212; to get something done from the White House.&nbsp; What is your response to that frustration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say the President is also frustrated. He wants to sign a voting rights bill into law.&nbsp; He wants to sign police reform into law.&nbsp; He believes both are long overdue.<br>&nbsp;<br>It requires Congress moving forward on these pieces of legislation and sending them to his desk.&nbsp; The role he can play is he&#8217;s spoken out publicly about it multiple times, advocated for how this is a fundamental right people should have across the country is voting rights.&nbsp; He has worked in close coordination, as has our team, with civil rights groups and partnership.&nbsp; And he has conveyed to them, and I will convey again publicly: He is with them and stands with them in their frustration, their view that this is a vital step.&nbsp; But he needs Congress to send him legislation in order to sign it into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’m just going to jump around.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to jump around.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, no, sorry &#8212; I was going right here, to Nadia.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On Iraq, a senior White House official said that this Strategic Dialogue with Iraq is going to be the final one.&nbsp; So how does the White House envisage the relationship going forward?&nbsp; And how do you respond to criticism by Republican senators saying that you’re capitulating to the pro-Iran militias by announcing this withdrawal, as we expect later today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we feel this is a natural next step in these ongoing strategic dialogues and that we are moving to a phase not where we are ending our partnership; we are maintaining a presence in Iraq with a different mission, in coordination with leadership of, of course, the Iraqi leadership, and one where we feel we can continue to be quite constructive in fighting ISIS and fighting the dangerous threats from Iranian proxies.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is a shift in mission; it is not a removal of our partnership or our presence or our close engagement with Iraqi leaders.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, why has the President not nominated someone for FDA Commissioner yet?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s certainly eager to nominate someone.&nbsp; He wants to make sure we have the right person to nominate, and he&#8217;s not going to do it at a pace faster than having the right person to put forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has the White House had any additional staffers test positive for COVID-19?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think, again, our policy &#8212; just to reiterate it &#8212; which we announced last week, is that if there&#8217;s an individual who is &#8212; has close proximity to any of the four principles, as defined by the White House Medical Unit, in line with CDC guidelines on what that looks like, we will then make that information available and immediately public to all of you.&nbsp; So that has not been the case since we announced that policy, no.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just real quick.&nbsp; On &#8212; I know we&#8217;ve asked you a number of times about the mask recommendation for the vaccinated, and I know you have said overwhelming majority of the cases are in people who are vaccinated &#8212; or who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; But what is the level of concern about infections and people who are vaccinated?&nbsp; Because there are &#8212; we keep hearing reports of vaccinated people &#8212; you know, hospitals say that they&#8217;re seeing patients who are vaccinated coming in.&nbsp; What is the level of concern in the administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think we all have a responsibility to be very clear about the data and what it says and what it does not say.&nbsp; Ninety-seven percent of hospitalizations are for &#8212; with people who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; That remains the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>The data from the health and medical experts still continues to be that if you are vaccinated, you are protected and it’s very, very unlikely that you will get sick, you will get hospitalized as a result of getting a breakthrough case.&nbsp; That remains the case in data.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, there are individual cases.&nbsp; We expect there to be breakthrough cases; we know there will be.&nbsp; The more people who are vaccinated, the more, as a percentage of individuals who are vaccinated, who will get COVID.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the most important thing is that people are, across the country, largely protected from serious illness if they&#8217;re vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just &#8212; just one quick follow-up.&nbsp; So the 97 percent number &#8212; so the CDC said that that is from January to April.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a bit of an outdated number when you look at how many people have been vaccinated since then and the Delta variant.&nbsp; So why isn&#8217;t there any more updated information coming from the CDC about what the risk is now to people who are vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can certainly see what their cycles of data is.&nbsp; We rely on data across the country.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t rely on individual, anecdotal cases that are reported because sometimes they scare the public without being based on broad swaths of information that the public should look at and look at the whole assessment of.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think you&#8217;ve seen across the country, again, that they&#8217;ll &#8212; and hospital leaders have said this too &#8212; that the number of cases of people who are coming in &#8212; the vast, vast majority &#8212; are people who are not vaccinated.&nbsp; That continues to be the case from hospital systems across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I&#8217;m certainly happy to see if there&#8217;s more updated data that is available or when it might be available too.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Steve.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, I want to go back to this question about vaccine mandates.&nbsp; Has it been determined here that it would be inappropriate or illegal for the President to require federal employees, civilian or military, to be vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It hasn&#8217;t been determined that it would be illegal, no.&nbsp; But we have not made a determination about that, no.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So why not?&nbsp; I mean, the President today referred to the federal government as a &#8220;model employer.&#8221;&nbsp; It&#8217;s the largest single employer of Americans &#8212; civilian and military put together.&nbsp; Why couldn’t the federal government demonstrate to the country that model that you&#8217;re talking about encouraging in the private sector?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Steve, it is certainly prudent for the federal government to be looking at any steps, just like any employer is, to your point, of how we can incentivize people get &#8212; for getting vaccinated, protect more people, save more lives.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this point in time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Do you &#8212; does the administration view vaccine misinformation as a national security threat?&nbsp; And on top of that, is there any indication that there are mal-actors that are feeding misinformation in vaccines?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve talked about this a little bit in the past.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give it a new label, but what I will tell you and reiterate is that certainly misinformation is a factor.&nbsp; It travels through a range of mediums &#8212; some on social media; some on media; some through elected officials or public voices, unfortunately; and sometimes all of those pieces are connected to each other.&nbsp; That is a concern &#8212; a significant concern for us.&nbsp; Hence, we&#8217;ve spoken out against that.<br>&nbsp;<br>What was the last part of your question?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to know if the administration had seen the fingerprints of any kind of mal-actors, such as Vladimir Putin, feeding this misinformation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve said &#8212; I think maybe last week or the week before &#8212; that we did see some elements of misinformation around the effectiveness of mRNA vaccines previously from foreign actors.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t think we have a broader assessment than that at this point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about the OMB director.&nbsp; Does the administration have any potential nominee to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s a lot of interest.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates for you on that one.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, Jen.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you have any update for U.S. citizens overseas that have been patiently waiting to get vaccinated.&nbsp; Should they &#8212; do you suggest they fly back to the United States?&nbsp; Or should they wait in the countries they&#8217;re living in?&nbsp; Will the embassies be doing anything more to assist them?&nbsp; Or vaccines that have been donated to countries &#8212; should a portion of those be allocated for Americans?&nbsp; What &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a really good question.&nbsp; I know that we haven&#8217;t been working &#8212; at this point, to date, that I am aware of &#8212; through embassies on programs with American citizens.&nbsp; Let me check with the State Department and our COVID team, and see if there&#8217;s more on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yamiche, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks so much for taking my question.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve reiterated several times the President is following the science.&nbsp; Can you talk a bit about whether or not he&#8217;s concerned at all that the CDC might be taking too long to issue new mask mandates or even vaccine mandates now that we see cities like New York issuing vaccine mandates?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think it&#8217;s important to take a step back and remember what we&#8217;re talking about here.&nbsp; The CDC evaluates data from across the country, and they will make public health guidance.&nbsp; They will present public health guidance.&nbsp; They do that on a regular, periodic basis.&nbsp; They will continue to do that.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re always considering a range of options as we have been from the beginning of the administration; of course, we are, as we should be.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They are &#8212; they do not make laws.&nbsp; It is the guidance currently that if you are not vaccinated, you should wear a mask.&nbsp; It is the guidance currently that if you are over 12 years old, you should get vaccinated.&nbsp; And regardless, the most effective step we can take around the country is to get more people vaccinated.&nbsp; So that is where our focus needs to be, regardless of where the CDC may or may not land on any additional guidance.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When I talked to experts, they say vaccine mandates would be a big step toward getting more people vaccinated.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m just wondering when you see organizations, like nearly 60, coming out and saying, &#8220;Let&#8217;s at least mandate healthcare workers being vaccinated,&#8221; why isn&#8217;t the White House behind that?&nbsp; What science is telling the White House &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I just said we support the step they took.&nbsp; What I&#8217;m getting at is &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know, but &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; the CDC does not determine mandates.&nbsp; The CDC provides public health guidance on what can save people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; Getting vaccinated can save people&#8217;s lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, would it be fair to say that &#8212; I guess my question is: Does the White House at all see itself standing up &#8212; and maybe this is what you&#8217;re saying now &#8212; &#8220;Yes, there should be mandates specifically for healthcare workers or teachers or municipal workers.&#8221;&nbsp; Does the White House see that as a role that it should be taking?&nbsp; And is there any danger in not doing that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I just said a few minutes ago that we support the step of hospitals, and that that was a guide and could be a guide for us on what to do with our own healthcare workforce here from the federal government.&nbsp; Just to give you kind of a sense.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that 90 percent of teachers across the country are vaccinated.&nbsp; And that is, in part, because of prioritizing teachers early; on a number of them taking the responsible step &#8212; of course, 90 percent of them &#8212; to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That would be up to schools and localities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are certain powers that the federal government has and there&#8217;s certain powers the federal government does not have. But we&#8217;re talking about a couple of different things here.&nbsp; One is public health guidance by the CDC, which will be driven by data.&nbsp; That gives guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The laws will be implemented by others.&nbsp; They do not make laws; they give public health guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Then there are decisions by institutions, by localities, by hospital systems, who may make decisions about how they can protect their workforces.&nbsp; We certainly support that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can ask you one quick thing on January 6th?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just &#8212; I know you said that the President&#8217;s going to, obviously, be busy tomorrow.&nbsp; But could you talk a little bit more about what the President thinks about these four Capitol Police officers testifying before this committee?&nbsp; And does he have anybody else that he wants to see possibly testify if his goal is the same as Speaker Pelosi, as he said?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly he relies on the leadership of Speaker Pelosi in moving this process and this independent investigation forward.&nbsp; And the individuals who will be testifying were brave heroes on this day &#8212; a dark day in our democracy.&nbsp; The President absolutely believes that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note &#8212; it&#8217;s noteworthy that many of the Republicans in Congress who are the most vocal about supposedly supporting the police in law and order are the same ones who&#8217;ve dismissed and downplayed the shameful events of that day.&nbsp; I don’t think that should be lost on anyone either, especially given about 140 individuals were injured that day &#8212; enforcement officers &#8212; 100 law enforcement officers were injured that day, according to their own numbers and statistics.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think we have to wrap because you guys got to go and see the spray of the Iraqi Prime Minister.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:46 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/26/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-27/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 20:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Erek L. Barron, of Maryland, to be United States Attorney for the District of Maryland for the term of four years, vice Robert K. Hur, resigned. &#160; &#160; &#160;John R. Bass, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Erek L. Barron, of Maryland, to be United States Attorney for the District of Maryland for the term of four years, vice Robert K. Hur, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;John R. Bass, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be an Under Secretary of State (Management), vice Brian J. Bulatao.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Nicholas W. Brown, of Washington, to be United States Attorney for the Western District of Washington for the term of four years, vice Brian T. Moran, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;David L. Cohen, of Pennsylvania, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Canada.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Matthew M. Graves, of the District of Columbia, to be United States Attorney for the District of Columbia for the term of four years, vice Jessie K. Liu, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Joseph M. Green, of North Carolina, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation for a term expiring March 3, 2028. &nbsp;(Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Clifford D. Johnson, of Indiana, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of Indiana for the term of four years, vice Thomas L. Kirsch II, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Zachary A. Myers, of Maryland, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of Indiana for the term of four years, vice Joshua J. Minkler, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Judith DelZoppo Pryor, of Ohio, to be First Vice President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States for a term expiring January 20, 2025, vice Wanda Felton, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Rachael S. Rollins, of Massachusetts, to be United States Attorney for the District of Massachusetts for the term of four years, vice Andrew E. Lelling, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Trini E. Ross, of New York, to be United States Attorney for the Western District of New York for the term of four years, vice William Joseph Hochul, Jr., resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Vanessa Waldref, of Washington, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Washington for the term of four years, vice William D. Hyslop, resigned.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Made In America Week, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/26/a-proclamation-on-made-in-america-week-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 19:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Made in America Week recognizes a basic idea: &#160;when we spend taxpayer dollars, we should buy American products and support American jobs. &#160;The Congress passed the Buy American Act almost 90 years ago, but we have never fully lived up to this principle.&#160; During Made in America Week, we recognize that just as American manufacturing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Made in America Week recognizes a basic idea: &nbsp;when we spend taxpayer dollars, we should buy American products and support American jobs. &nbsp;The Congress passed the Buy American Act almost 90 years ago, but we have never fully lived up to this principle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During Made in America Week, we recognize that just as American manufacturing was the Arsenal of Democracy in World War&nbsp;II, American products and services must be part of the engine of American prosperity today. &nbsp;We also reject the defeatist view that the forces of automation and globalization mean we cannot have good-paying union jobs here in America.</p>



<p>My Administration is making &#8220;Buy American&#8221; a policy, not just a promise.&nbsp; We are closing loopholes and strengthening standards to ensure that the future is made in all of America &#8211;by all of America&#8217;s workers &#8212; in every region, of every background, in services, manufacturing, and agriculture.</p>



<p>That is why one of my first acts as President was to sign an Executive Order to tighten existing Buy American policies, and to lay out additional commitments to prevent big corporations and special interests from using loopholes to redirect American taxpayer dollars to foreign companies. &nbsp;And, I&nbsp;have named our Nation&#8217;s first-ever Made in America Director at&nbsp;our Office of Management and Budget.</p>



<p>When we Buy American, we will buy from all of America. &nbsp;We will include communities that have historically been left out of Government procurement, Black, Brown, and Native American small businesses and entrepreneurs in every region of the country. &nbsp;We&nbsp;will use a federally funded, national network called the Manufacturing Extension Partnership to help government agencies connect with new domestic suppliers across the country.</p>



<p>The COVID-19 pandemic demonstrated our need for greater manufacturing capacity in areas critical to public health, information and communications technology, and national defense.</p>



<p>To build our economy back better, we must have an industrial strategy based on public investment in new technologies, including the domestic production of clean energy goods, critical medical supplies, and the innovative industries of the future.&nbsp; We must prioritize the creation of high skill, high value jobs that empower workers and pay family-supporting wages. &nbsp;We must reject short-termism, offshoring, and a race to the bottom. &nbsp;That is why my Administration is committed to using Made in America policies that give America&#8217;s workers and companies the tools they need to compete and lead globally for&nbsp;decades to come.</p>



<p>We will send clear market signals so that entrepreneurs make the investments our Nation needs.&nbsp; We will ensure that Made&nbsp;in America preferences are applied consistently and transparently.&nbsp; We will gather data to reveal gaps in our industrial base, and work to close those gaps and boost our economy&#8217;s productive capacity. &nbsp;And we will ensure that diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility are at the center of all of these efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My Administration will maximize the Federal Government&#8217;s use of goods, products, and materials produced in, and services offered in, the United States.&nbsp; These purchases will maximize our efforts to empower workers and strengthen unionization, tackle the climate crisis, and build and rebuild critical supply chains so that we will never again have to rely on imports from unreliable trading partners to combat threats to our public health.</p>



<p>We will also reduce the need for waivers from Made in America rules by creating incentives for private investment in&nbsp;domestic supply chains in critical industries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we focus on &#8220;Made in America,&#8221; we are committed to strengthening relationships with allies and trading partners. &nbsp;Resilient supply chains must have built in redundancies &#8212; a&nbsp;health crisis or natural disaster in one location must never again threaten the global economy.&nbsp; We must work with our trading partners to promote equitable growth, protect workers&#8217; rights, and advance environmental justice globally.</p>



<p>By using Made in America policies as one tool of many to rebuild our industrial base and strengthen critical supply chains, we will help put the American dream within reach for our&nbsp;Nation&#8217;s families today, and for generations to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim July 26 through July 30, 2021, as Made in America Week.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this week and to celebrate with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-sixth day of July, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Celebrating the 31st Anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/26/remarks-by-president-biden-celebrating-the-31st-anniversary-of-the-americans-with-disabilities-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25017</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rose Garden 11:28 A.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Madam Vice President, Tyree &#8212; you’re an inspiration.&#160; Thank you for sharing your story.&#160;Thirty-one years ago today, on the South Lawn of the White House, President George H.W. Bush signed the Americans with Disabilities Act.&#160; He surrou- &#8212; he was surrounded by disability advocates and bipartisan members of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rose Garden</p>



<p>11:28 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Madam Vice President, Tyree &#8212; you’re an inspiration.&nbsp; Thank you for sharing your story.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thirty-one years ago today, on the South Lawn of the White House, President George H.W. Bush signed the Americans with Disabilities Act.&nbsp; He surrou- &#8212; he was surrounded by disability advocates and bipartisan members of the United States Congress, just as we are today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Speaker Pelosi &#8212; welcome, by the way, Madam Speaker &#8212; Chairman Leahy, Leader McCarthy, Senator Casey, Congressman Scott, Congressman La- &#8212; where is here? &nbsp;There you are, Paul [Jim]. &nbsp;You understand this better than anybody does. &nbsp;And I want to thank you, Congressman, for all your work. &nbsp;And I want to thank you all for being here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second &#8212; by the way, where’s mom?&nbsp; Mom &#8212; is she here?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. BROWN:&nbsp; She’s at home watching.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, she’s watching.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. BROWN:&nbsp; She’s watching.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I thought she looked &#8212; I said, “Mom is out there.”&nbsp; I was going to ask her to stand up.&nbsp; But, Mom, you can’t stand up if you’re home.&nbsp; But, folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; give you &#8212; thank you for what you’ve done.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Second Gentleman is here as well.&nbsp; Thank you for being with us as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And some of the same folks who fought so hard for this landmark legislation are with us today.&nbsp; I just got off the phone with one of them &#8212; a guy named Tom Harkin.&nbsp; And yest- &#8212; or two days ago, I was on the phone with one who just had his 98th birthday, Bob Dole.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But no one worked harder than Tony Coelho to get this done.&nbsp; House Majority Leader Steny Hoyer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Others weren’t able to join us today but were instrumental in bringing this to life &#8212; dear friends, as I said, like<br>Tom Harkin and Bob Dole.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I also spoke &#8212; as I said, Bob is &#8212; wanted to pass on his regards, as did Tom.&nbsp; Tom is up in Wisconsin working on &#8212; he said on ADA, doing something up there.&nbsp; Now, he didn’t explain exactly what.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are still more with us that are here in spirit, like Ted Kennedy, Major Owens &#8212; Congressman Major Owens, and countless other advocates.<br>&nbsp;<br>I was enormously proud to be a co-sponsor to the ADA as Pat Leahy was, as well, if I’m not mistaken, as a member of the United States Senate.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’m proud to be here today, as President, alongside so many fearless champions who represent the ongoing legacy of this law, from the foundations to its future.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thirty-one years ago, after its passage, many Americans have never lived in a world without the ADA.&nbsp; Generations have grown up not knowing a time before it existed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But many of us can still recall an America where a person with a disability was denied service in restaurants and grocery stores, and could be; where a person using a wheelchair couldn’t ride on a train or take a bus to work or to school; where an employer could refuse to hire you because of a disability.&nbsp; An America&nbsp;that wasn’t built for all Americans.<br>&nbsp;<br>Then we passed the ADA and made a commitment to build a nation for all of us.&nbsp; All of us.&nbsp; And we moved America closer to fulfilling that promise of liberty and justice, and maybe most importantly, dignity and equality for all.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, and perhaps most importantly, we did it together.&nbsp; This was a Democratic bill signed by a Republican president.&nbsp; A product of passion and compassion, not partisanship.&nbsp; Progress that wasn’t political, but personal, to millions of families.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll never forget the moment the ADA passed.&nbsp; And you may remember it, Pat.&nbsp; Standing on the floor of the United States Senate, and Tom Harkin saw the recognition &#8212; he rose.&nbsp; And the first time &#8212; first time in the history that I’m aware of &#8212; in the United States Senate, he stood up and he signed in a speech to his brother.&nbsp; Tom wasn’t just sending a message to millions of deaf and hard-of-hearing folks; he was speaking to his brother, Frank.&nbsp; It was personal to him.<br>&nbsp;<br>It was personal to Bob Dole, as well, who lost the use of his right arm in a heroic effort during World War Two; who laid out in a hospital for almost three years &#8212; his injury listed, and they also lasted an entire lifetime.<br>&nbsp;<br>But like so many Americans, he turned his disability,<br>his apparent limitation, into greater purpose and will.&nbsp; He made &#8212; he made the rights of disabled Americans a lifelong cause.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And for more than 60 million Americans living with disabilities, the ADA is so much more than a law; it&#8217;s a source of opportunity, participation, independent living, and respect and dignity, the bulwark against discrimination, and a path to independence.<br>&nbsp;<br>And for our nation, the ADA is more than a law as well; it&#8217;s testament to our character as a people, our character as Americans.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a triumph of American values.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, of course, this law didn&#8217;t bring an end to the work we need to do.&nbsp; Today, too many Americans still face barriers to freedom and equality.&nbsp; But thanks to this movement that spans all races, beliefs, backgrounds, and generations, we&#8217;re once again making progress together.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In my first day in office, I was proud to sign an executive order establishing a government-wide commitment to advancing equity, including people with disabilities.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I was proud to appoint the first-ever White House Disability Policy Director, Kim Knackstedt.&nbsp; Where are you, Kim?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Where is Kim?&nbsp; Thank you, Kim.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;m ensuring that dignity and rights of disabled Americans are lifted up in every policy we purzue [sic] &#8212; pursue, from continuing to make sure that this administration looks like America, appointing people with disabilities to positions across the government.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In the American Rescue Plan, we were able to include substantial support for schools that better serve students with disabilities, that &#8212; expanding access to vaccines for disabled Americans.<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of my Build Back Better plan &#8212; it was already mentioned &#8212; we propose $400 billion to expand access to home- and community-based care &#8212; (applause) &#8212; helping people with disabilities and older adults live more independently.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;m glad that Congress is beginning to move on the Better Care Better Jobs Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; championed by my buddy, Bobby Casey &#8212; Bobby, thank you &#8212; which builds on that effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>This past year, the entire nation saw just how vital our caregivers are and how critical home-based care truly is for so many Americans.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This legislation will help ensure that caregivers are fairly compensated for their work.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; In addition, I&#8217;ve also called on Congress to eliminate the discriminatory sub-minimum wage provisions &#8212; (applause) &#8212; that too often keep people with disabilities from getting good jobs with fair wages.<br>&nbsp;<br>And because of additional executive orders I&#8217;ve signed, we&#8217;re working to remove barriers that hold back disabled Americans from exercising their sacred right to vote.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;re ensuring that the federal government is a model employer when it comes to wages, accommodations, and opportunities to advance people with disabilities.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a firm commitment.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And today &#8212; (applause) &#8212; finally, I&#8217;m proud to announce a new effort &#8212; the first of its kind &#8212; to help Americans grappling with long-term effects of COVID-19 that doctors call &#8220;long COVID.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>Many Americans who seemingly recover from the virus still face lingering challenges like breathing problems, brain fog, chronic pain, and fatigue.&nbsp; These conditions can sometimes &#8212; can sometimes rise to the level of a disability.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;re bringing agencies together to make sure Americans with long COVID, who have a disability, have access to the rights and resources that are due under the disability law &#8212; (applause) &#8212; which includes accommodations and services in the workplace, in school, and our healthcare system so &#8212; so they can live their lives in dignity and get the support they need as they continue to navigate these challenges.<br>&nbsp;<br>We made important progress, but we still have work to do.&nbsp; We have to keep going to ensure that every single American has a chance to contribute their talents and thrive and succeed.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I know that today’s fearless advocates, some of whom are with us today, are going to accomplish incredible things.<br>&nbsp;<br>People like &#8212; like M- &#8212; excuse me, people like Mr. Tootle.&nbsp; Where are you?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Stand up, man.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I want to thank you for your continued efforts to build an America for everyone, and as I said, you courageous advocates who led the way 31 years ago &#8212; a long time before the foundation for progress is strong, though.&nbsp; It&#8217;s part of the mor- &#8212; moral bedrock of our nation and something every American should be proud of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now it’s my honor to sign the proclamation on the 31st anniversary of the ADA.<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank you all.&nbsp; May God bless you and all of you dealing with disabilities.&nbsp; You&#8217;re &#8212; you are an inspiration to all of us.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; You’re an absolute inspiration. (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>May God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Now I&#8217;m going to walk over and sign this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to invite up, though &#8212; Nancy, come on up.&nbsp; Steny.&nbsp; I think we ought to get you up here.&nbsp; You were &#8212; you&#8217;re a big part of it &#8212; Tony Coelho.&nbsp; Am I leaving anybody out?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Pat.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Pat, you &#8212; you were there at the time.&nbsp; Why don’t you get your rear end up here and put your &#8212;&nbsp;(laughter).<br>&nbsp;<br>The Leader is taking his camera, because Pat would rather use his camera than, I think, anything else.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Come on.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah, come on.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Come on up.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Tony, you get right in the back here.&nbsp; You were a big, big, gigantic part of this.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Pat, come on.&nbsp; Get in.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; The anniversary of the Americans with Disability Act 2021.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(The executive order is signed.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Tony.&nbsp; (Hands a pen.)<br>&nbsp;<br>REPRESENTATIVE COELHO:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>LEADER HOYER:&nbsp; Thank you, sir.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good to see you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Madam Speaker.&nbsp; Pat.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENATOR LEAHY: &nbsp;Thank you, sir.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And this hero right there.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I will, but I want to make sure I got all the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Gives pen to Ms. Brown.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. BROWN:&nbsp; Thank you so much.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.&nbsp; (Applause.) Let&#8217;s keep it going.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, would it be helpful if employers mandated vaccines, sir?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you have confidence you can get the unvaccinated Americans vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have to.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, are you confident there will be an infrastructure deal this week &#8212; a bipartisan infrastructure deal?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know me &#8212; I’m always optimistic.&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>11:40 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 26</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/26/bill-signed-h-r-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 17:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, July 26, 2021, the President signed into law: H.R. 26, the “Construction Consensus Procurement Improvement Act of 2021,” which amends the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021, to correct a provision on the prohibition on the use of reverse auctions for awarding Federal contracts.  Thank you to Representatives James Comer (KY-01) and Ro Khanna&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, July 26, 2021, the President signed into law:<br><br>H.R. 26, the “Construction Consensus Procurement Improvement Act of 2021,” which amends the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021, to correct a provision on the prohibition on the use of reverse auctions for awarding Federal contracts. </p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives James Comer (KY-01) and Ro Khanna (CA-17) as well as Senators Rob Portman (OH) and Mazie Hirono (HI) for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act, 2021.</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/26/a-proclamation-on-anniversary-of-the-americans-with-disabilities-act-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 16:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thirty-one years ago, on July 26, 1990, our Nation moved closer to the fulfillment of its foundational promise when we passed the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA). &#160;This landmark law affirms and protects the fundamental rights of people with disabilities &#8212; the right to equal opportunity, economic self-sufficiency, independent living, and equitable participation in every&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Thirty-one years ago, on July 26, 1990, our Nation moved closer to the fulfillment of its foundational promise when we passed the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA). &nbsp;This landmark law affirms and protects the fundamental rights of people with disabilities &#8212; the right to equal opportunity, economic self-sufficiency, independent living, and equitable participation in every aspect of American life.&nbsp; For more than three decades, the&nbsp;ADA has made our communities, our economy, and our country stronger and more vibrant.&nbsp; It has helped to uphold the dignity of the estimated 61 million Americans who live with a disability &#8212; in short, it is a triumph of American civil rights.</p>



<p>I was enormously proud to co-sponsor the ADA, the passage of&nbsp;which was a testament not only to fearless advocacy, but to bipartisan progress.&nbsp; A Democratic bill signed by a Republican President, the ADA was made possible thanks in no small part to&nbsp;the passion and persistence of Senators Tom Harkin and Ted Kennedy and Congressmen Major Owens and Tony Coelho.&nbsp; I will never forget the moment just after the ADA&#8217;s passage, when Senator Harkin delivered a speech in American Sign Language from&nbsp;the Senate floor &#8212; a tribute to his older brother, Frank, who was deaf.&nbsp; That moment was an emotional reminder for all of&nbsp;us of just how personal and powerful the passage of the ADA would be for millions of American families.</p>



<p>Despite the extraordinary progress we have made over the past 31 years, the fight for equitable access and inclusion is far from over.&nbsp; The COVID-19 pandemic has compounded the longstanding inequities and biases that exist for&nbsp;people with disabilities; persistent discrimination and the inability to access services continues to threaten the health and well-being of far too many Americans. &nbsp;Throughout the pandemic, people with disabilities have faced heightened risks &#8212; particularly those who lack access to caregiver or support services, those who live in community homes, and the disproportionate share of people with disabilities employed in industries that suffered due to the pandemic.&nbsp; Children and students living with disabilities have also faced an especially challenging year, forced to navigate and adapt to online learning as the virus upended their usual school routines.</p>



<p>As we work to finish the job of defeating COVID-19, my Administration is committed to building on the legacy of the ADA.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan is providing funding to expand access to home- and community-based services under Medicaid, which will allow more people with disabilities to live safely and independently in their homes.&nbsp; My Build Back Better agenda would build on this by making significant investments in home- and community-based services for people with disabilities and older Americans.&nbsp; It will also spur the creation of quality jobs with good pay, good benefits, and the ability to organize and collectively bargain for caregivers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My Administration is also committed to advancing the rights of people with disabilities in the workplace to support economic self-sufficiency.&nbsp; I have proposed eliminating outdated provisions in the Fair Labor Standards Act that allow employers to pay workers with disabilities less than the minimum wage.&nbsp; My&nbsp;proposal includes funding this transition with $2 billion to expand access to competitive, integrated employment opportunities for workers with disabilities.&nbsp; In addition, I am committed to making the Federal Government a model employer &#8212; including for people with disabilities &#8212; to set the gold standard for how best to support inclusion and provide appropriate accommodations.&nbsp; To&nbsp;that end, I recently signed an Executive Order to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility in the Federal Workforce &#8212; a pledge to lead by example to promote economic stability and good paying jobs for Americans with disabilities.</p>



<p>Before I became President, I promised that every policy my Administration pursued &#8212; from rebuilding our middle class, to fighting climate change, to achieving universal health coverage &#8212; would be created with the full inclusion and dignity of Americans with disabilities in mind.&nbsp; I am proud to say that since my first day in office, my Administration has delivered on that promise.&nbsp; As we celebrate the monumental legacy of the ADA, we recommit ourselves today to upholding and strengthening its protections &#8212; and continuing to advance equity, dignity, access, and inclusion together with the disability community as&nbsp;we build our Nation back better.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim July 26, 2021, the Anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act.&nbsp; I encourage Americans across our Nation to celebrate the 31st year of this civil rights law and the many contributions of individuals with disabilities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-sixth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.         </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">  JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
