<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 20:10:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 20:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Paloma Adams-Allen, of the District of Columbia, to be a Deputy Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Bonnie Glick. &#160; &#160; &#160;Tovah R. Calderon, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals for the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Paloma Adams-Allen, of the District of Columbia, to be a Deputy Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Bonnie Glick.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Tovah R. Calderon, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals for the term of fifteen years, vice Kathryn A. Oberly, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jia M. Cobb, of Virginia, to be United States District Judge for the District of Columbia, vice Emmet G. Sullivan, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Isobel Coleman, of New York, to be a Deputy Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, Jenny A. McGee.</p>



<p>     William E. Holloway, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the National Institute of Building Sciences for a term expiring September 7, 2021, vice Mary B. Verner, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;William E. Holloway, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the National Institute of Building Sciences for a term expiring September 7, 2024. &nbsp;(Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Amanda Howe, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, vice Craig Hooks, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Kenia Seoane Lopez, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the term of fifteen years, vice Ronna Lee Beck, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Sarah A.L. Merriam, of Connecticut, to be United States District Judge for the District of Connecticut, vice Janet C. Hall, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Sarala Vidya Nagala, of Connecticut, to be United States District Judge for the District of Connecticut, vice Vanessa Lynne Bryant, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Florence Y. Pan, of the District of Columbia, to be United States District Judge for the District of Columbia, vice Ketanji Brown Jackson, resigning.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Myrna Pérez, of New York, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Second Circuit, vice Denny Chin, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Javier Ramirez, of Illinois, to be Federal Mediation and Conciliation Director, vice Richard Giacolone.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Omar Antonio Williams, of Connecticut, to be United States District Judge for the District of Connecticut, vice Alvin W. Thompson, retired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp; &nbsp; ###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces His Intent to Nominate Nine More Individuals to Serve as Ambassadors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/president-biden-announces-his-intent-to-nominate-nine-more-individuals-to-serve-as-ambassadors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals – including four career members of the Senior Foreign Service – as ambassadors to represent the United States on the world stage: Julie Chung, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka Sharon L. Cromer,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals – including four career members of the Senior Foreign Service – as ambassadors to represent the United States on the world stage:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Julie Chung, </strong>Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka</li><li><strong>Sharon L. Cromer</strong><strong>, </strong>Nominee for U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of The Gambia</li><li><strong>Troy Damian Fitrell</strong>, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Guinea</li><li><strong>Thomas R. Nides</strong>, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the State of Israel</li><li><strong>Marc Ostfield</strong>, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Paraguay</li><li><strong>Ken Salazar</strong>, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the United Mexican States</li><li><strong>Julianne Smith</strong><strong>, </strong>Nominee for the United States Permanent Representative on the Council of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary</li><li><strong>C. B. “Sully” Sullenberger, III, </strong>Nominee for the rank of Ambassador during his tenure of service as Representative of the United States of America on the Council of the International Civil Aviation Organization</li><li><strong>Dr. Cynthia Ann Telles</strong>, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Costa Rica</li></ul>



<p>In April, President Biden announced his intent to nominate nine career foreign service officers as ambassadors.<br><br><strong>Julie Jiyoon Chung, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><br>Julie Chung, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the Acting Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs at the U.S. Department of State.&nbsp; She was previously Director of the Office of Japanese Affairs at the Department.&nbsp; She has served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Phnom Penh, Cambodia and Economic Counselor at the U.S. Embassy in Bangkok, Thailand.&nbsp; Earlier, Chung was Chief of Staff to the Transition Coordinator at the U.S. Embassy in Baghdad, Iraq.&nbsp; She has also served at the U.S. embassies in Colombia, Vietnam and Japan, and the U.S. Consulate General in Guangzhou, China.&nbsp; She is a Pickering Fellow.&nbsp; Chung earned a B.A. at the University of California-San Diego and an M.A. at Columbia University’s School of International and Public Affairs.&nbsp; She is the recipient of numerous awards, including the Secretary’s Distinguished Honor Award. Chung speaks Korean, Japanese, Spanish, and Khmer.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Sharon L. Cromer, Nominee for U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of The Gambia</strong><br>Sharon L. Cromer, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Career Minister, currently serves as the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Mission Director at the U.S. Embassy, Accra, Ghana. Previously she was the USAID Mission Director at the U.S. Embassy Dar es Salaam, Tanzania and she has also been USAID Mission Director at the U.S. Embassy in Abuja, Nigeria. In addition, Cromer also had an earlier assignment in Accra as Mission Director. In Washington, Cromer served as Senior Deputy Assistant Administrator and Acting Assistant Administrator in the Africa Bureau of USAID and also as the Deputy Assistant Administrator of the USAID Management Bureau. Among her other assignments, Cromer was first a Supervisory Contracting Officer, and then the USAID Deputy Mission Director, at the U.S. Embassy Jakarta, Indonesia. Early in her career, Cromer served as a Contracting Officer in Senegal, Ivory Coast, and Pakistan. Cromer earned her B.A. from Barnard College, Columbia University and her J.D. degree from Georgetown University Law School.<br><br><strong>Troy Damian Fitrell, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Guinea</strong><br>Troy Fitrell, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Counselor, is the Director of the Office of West African Affairs at the Department of State. He has served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. embassies in Ethiopia and Mauritius, as Deputy Director of the Department’s Office of Southern African Affairs, and as Deputy Director of the Office of International Security Cooperation in the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs. He was Senior Advisor to the United States Special Envoy for the Great Lakes of Africa, coordinating U.S. policy on the cross-border security, political, and economic issues in the Great Lakes region. Fitrell served as a Pearson Fellow on the staff of the House Foreign Affairs Committee and was a Watch Officer in the Department’s Nuclear Risk Reduction Center. He also served overseas at the U.S. embassies in Portugal, Guatemala, Zambia, Ghana and Denmark. Fitrell earned a B.A. at the University of Maryland and an M.S. at the National War College. He speaks French, Spanish, Portuguese, Swedish and Danish.<br><br><strong>Thomas R. Nides, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the State of Israel</strong><br>Thomas Nides is a distinguished public servant and business leader. Nides was the State Department’s Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources from 2010 – 2013. Earlier, Nides was Morgan Stanley’s Chief Administrative Officer, Chief Operating Officer and Secretary of the Board, the President and Chief Executive Officer of Burson-Marsteller, in New York and the Chief Administrative Officer of Credit Suisse First Boston in Washington, D.C. Nides was Chief of Staff to the U.S. Trade Representative Micky Kantor, was Senior Advisor to Speaker of the House Thomas S. Foley, and earlier to House Majority Whip Tony Coelho. He currently serves on the boards of the Partnership for Public Service, the International Rescue Committee, the Atlantic Council and the Urban Alliance Foundation, and currently serves as the Managing Director and Vice Chairman of Morgan Stanley. He is a Member of the Council on Foreign Relations and the former Chairman of the Board of the Woodrow Wilson Center appointed by President Obama. Nides received his B.A. degree from the University of Minnesota. He is the recipient of the Secretary of State’s Distinguished Service Award.<br><br><strong>Marc Ostfield, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Paraguay</strong><br>Marc Ostfield, a career member of the Senior Executive Service, is the Ombudsman of the U.S. Department of State. With over 30 years in foreign policy and national security, he has served in senior State Department roles, including as Acting Director/Deputy Director of the Foreign Service Institute (National Foreign Affairs Training Center); Director, Office of Policy and Global Issues in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs; Senior Foreign Affairs Officer for Science and Technology Cooperation; and Senior Advisor for Bioterrorism, Biodefense, and Health Security. Earlier, he created, led, and evaluated global health programs in Latin America and worldwide with international organizations, including as Chief of Behavior Change Communication for Family Health International. He is the recipient of a Presidential Rank Award, numerous State Department awards, the Meritorious Unit Award from the U.S. National Counterterrorism Center, the Diplomacy Fellowship from the American Association for the Advancement of Science, and the President’s Volunteer Service Award as a volunteer firefighter. Ostfield earned a B.A., M.S., and Ph.D. from the University of Pennsylvania. He speaks Spanish, Portuguese, French, and Arabic.<br><br><strong>Ken Salazar, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the United Mexican States</strong><br>Ken Salazar has served as U.S. Secretary of the Interior, Colorado U.S. Senator, and Colorado Attorney General. In 1998, Salazar was elected as Colorado Attorney General and became the first Latino ever elected to statewide office in Colorado. He was reelected as Attorney General in 2002. In 2004, Salazar was elected to the U.S. Senate for Colorado becoming the first Latino democrat to be elected to the United States Senate since 1972. During the Obama Administration, he served as Secretary of the Interior, where he had a lead role on energy and climate, and the nation’s conservation agenda. A native of Colorado, Salazar is a fifth-generation rancher in Colorado’s San Luis Valley. He is a partner at WilmerHale, an American law firm and the founder of the firm’s Denver office. Salazar represents clients on energy, environment, natural resources and Native American matters. Salazar has a B.S. from Colorado College and a J.D. from the University of Michigan. He also has honorary degrees from the Colorado School of Mines, the University of Massachusetts Lowell, the University of Colorado School of Law, the University of Denver School of Law, and Colorado College. His native language is Spanish.<br><br><strong>Julianne Smith, Nominee for the United States Permanent Representative on the Council of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary</strong><br>Julianne “Julie” Smith is currently serving as a Senior Advisor to the Secretary of State at the Department of State. Previously, she served as the Director of the Asia and Geopolitics Programs at the German Marshall Fund of the United States. From 2014 – 2018, she served as the Director of the Transatlantic Security Program at the Center for a New American Security (CNAS). Prior to joining CNAS, Julie served in the Obama administration. From 2012-2013, she served as both the Acting National Security Advisor and the Deputy National Security Advisor to Vice President Joseph Biden. Before the White House, she served as the Principal Director for European and NATO Policy in the Office of the Secretary of Defense in the Pentagon for three years. In 2012, she was awarded the Office of the Secretary of Defense Medal for Exceptional Public Service. Earlier in her career, Smith directed the Europe Program at the Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS). A native of Michigan, she received her B.A. from Xavier University and her M.A. from American University. She speaks German and French.<br><br><strong>C. B. “Sully” Sullenberger, III, Nominee for the rank of Ambassador during his tenure of service as Representative of the United States of America on the Council of the International Civil Aviation Organization</strong><br>C. B. “Sully” Sullenberger, III is a former United States Air Force fighter pilot, retired airline pilot, safety expert and keynote speaker.&nbsp; In 2009, as captain of US Airways flight 1549, he and his crew guided their aircraft to a successful emergency landing in the Hudson River with no fatalities.&nbsp; He has served as a NASA aviation safety research consultant.&nbsp; As an Air Line Pilots Association accident investigation committee member, he participated in a National Transportation Safety Board investigation of a major airline accident, leading to improved airline procedures and training for emergency evacuation.&nbsp; Sullenberger has a B.S. from the United States Air Force Academy, an M.S. from Purdue University and an M.A. from the University of Northern Colorado.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Dr. Cynthia Ann Telles, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Costa Rica</strong><br>Dr. Cynthia Telles is a Clinical Professor in the UCLA Department of Psychiatry at the UCLA David Geffen School of Medicine and serves on the Executive Committee of the UCLA Semel Institute for Neuroscience and Human Behavior. For over three decades, Telles has also been the Director of the UCLA Spanish-Speaking Psychosocial Clinic and is the founding and current Director of the UCLA Hispanic Neuropsychiatric Center of Excellence. She has served on the Board of the Pacific Council on International Policy, was the Chair of the Los Angeles/U.S. Section of the Mexico-Los Angeles Commission and has also engaged on numerous City of Los Angeles Commissions including on the Board of Airport Commissioners. On the national level Telles has been a member of the White House Commission on Presidential Scholars and the National Advisory Council of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services. Currently, she serves on the Board of the Kaiser Foundation Health Plan and Hospitals. She was a founding Board member of Americas United Bank, the first Hispanic commercial bank to be chartered in California in over 30 years. Her numerous philanthropic partnerships included service as the Chair of the California Community Foundation and as a member, Vice-Chair, and Chair of the Board of The California Endowment, the largest health foundation in California. Telles received a B.A. from Smith College and a Ph.D. in Clinical Psychology from Boston University. She speaks and reads Spanish fluently.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Gaggle by Senior Administration Officials En Route Geneva, Switzerland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/15/background-press-gaggle-by-senior-administration-officials-en-route-geneva-switzerland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 16:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Geneva, Switzerland 3:58 P.M. CEST&#160;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Okay, welcome to our flight to Geneva, Switzerland, on day seven of a lovely trip.&#160;I’m going to start by just giving an overview of the logistics for tomorrow so you all have an understanding of what the day looks like.&#160;So, around 1:00 p.m.,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Geneva, Switzerland</p>



<p>3:58 P.M. CEST<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay, welcome to our flight to Geneva, Switzerland, on day seven of a lovely trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’m going to start by just giving an overview of the logistics for tomorrow so you all have an understanding of what the day looks like.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, around 1:00 p.m., President Putin is expected to arrive &#8212; should be the first to arrive at the villa where the event is taking place, where the meeting is taking place.&nbsp; He will be greeted by the Swiss President on arrival and taken inside.&nbsp; President Biden will arrive after President Putin and will also be taken back inside.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Inside, they&#8217;ll share a short greeting with the Swiss President.&nbsp; They will, all three of them, walk back outside where there will be a &#8212; there will be press present for that moment.&nbsp; The only person who is expected to speak during that moment is the Swiss President.<br>&nbsp;<br>They will then go back inside and they will move into a smaller meeting &#8212; P plus one &#8212; on both sides.&nbsp; Then, after that meeting, there will be &#8212; there&#8217;s expected to be &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The P plus one, just a translator?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The plus one is the Secretary of State.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Who doesn’t speak Russian.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; There you go.<br>&nbsp;<br>Then there is a plan for there to be an expanded portion of the meeting, which is P plus five.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to give you the breakdown of time; we&#8217;ll see how the day goes tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>After the meeting concludes &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do we go into these photo ops?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sorry, that&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; There will be a spray of the first P-plus-one portion of the day.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the P plus five, who else is in?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We will get you that list.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But only a spray on the P plus one?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Correct.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The spray will be before or after the P plus one?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Before.&nbsp; At the beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>After the meeting concludes, as you all know, we expect President Putin to do his own press conference.&nbsp; I will let them confirm that, but I believe that&#8217;s the plan.&nbsp; And then President Biden will do a press conference after that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Those are the logistics.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me just also preface from the beginning, just for your expectations: We are not going to go much farther than where the President went during his press conference yesterday in terms of previewing the meeting.&nbsp; We are going to let him speak to that when he concludes the meeting tomorrow.&nbsp; But we still wanted to give an opportunity to have a discussion and provide any clarification as needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) question &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; P plus one: POTUS, Blinken, and a translator?&nbsp; The translators don&#8217;t count in the numbers?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; And an interpreter.&nbsp; That&#8217;s right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One each?&nbsp; One interpreter each, on each side?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;Each will have an interpreter, and President Putin will be accompanied by his foreign minister.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the Russians are saying four to five hours of talks.&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re expecting?&nbsp; Or what?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, in that neighborhood.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) press conference is eight o&#8217;clock, thereabout, for our planning purposes?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to see how the flow goes.&nbsp; This is diplomacy in action, David.&nbsp; Get on the ride.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Four or five hours straight?&nbsp; No break in between?&nbsp; Are they going to share any meals or anything like that?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No meals.&nbsp; We anticipate there will be breaks.&nbsp; But as [senior administration official] said, we&#8217;ve agreed with the other side that there will be some flexibility just so that the leaders can make determinations about the best way to conduct their business.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;Sorry, just to reiterate: No meal? &nbsp;They won&#8217;t sit &#8212; they won’t have not even tea? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Definitely not tea.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I presume &#8212; I presume that the principals and the participants can ask for some water or coffee or tea.&nbsp; I mean, it’s not &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No sort of formal &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Nothing formal.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) break bread<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No breaking of bread.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the position on the ambassadors?&nbsp; Do you expect to reach some sort of deal to send ambassadors back to the country?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of tomorrow, but both ambassadors will be in Geneva.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you want to start &#8212; you want to give us an idea of what to expect?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll start with the baseline of what the President said last night.&nbsp; You guys got to hear from him repeatedly, as there were multiple questions posed about the meeting tomorrow.&nbsp; And happy to answer any questions that you might have.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you expecting any specific agreements to emerge from this summit?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think we expect that there will be areas where the presidents will task out further work to their teams.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s about all I can say today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Backwards slightly, could tell us a bit more about the discussions the President had with the NATO leaders about tomorrow’s summit?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, the President, as he said yesterday, led off the discussion.&nbsp; He was the first leader to speak after the Secretary General.&nbsp; He gave about 10 minutes of remarks, which covered a number of different issues, but Russia was a critical point of emphasis in his comments.&nbsp; And he explained to the leaders what he intended to say.&nbsp; He did so privately, behind closed doors, so I&#8217;m not going to get into the details of it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he asked them to share whatever thoughts or advice they had about the meeting.&nbsp; And several leaders did respond with commentary.&nbsp; And as he said last night, those who spoke to the meeting were positive about the fact that he was doing it and positive about the fact that he was consulting with them in advance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also pledged to them that on an ongoing basis &#8212; to the extent, for example, we&#8217;re working with Russia on arms control-related issues &#8212; he would coordinate closely with NATO so that they had a chance to have input into the arms control agenda.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was there any specific mention of Russian S400 in the Turkey bilat with President Erdoğan?&nbsp; And will that issue be brought up in the meeting with President Putin?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; There was a mention of the Russian S400 system.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an issue between us and Turkey to do with our domestic law.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t anticipate it will be covered in the summit.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was there an agreement with President Erdoğan on the Russian S400 in exchange for Turkish presence at the Kabul airport?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, there was no linkage between the S400 and the Kabul airport.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to the Russians: The Russians were saying that one sort of quick for- step could be returning the ambassadors.&nbsp; Is that on the table?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; It is a possibility.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to confirm that until the two presidents have had the chance to meet.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Over the longer term, let me ask about the two big areas you&#8217;ve identified already that will be big subjects: strategic stability and cyber.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On strategic stability, is your concept here to work out from now to something that would be doable after New START expires?&nbsp; So, in other words, have something that rolls together, maybe with the Chinese and others?&nbsp; Or do you have more short-term goals?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And on cyber, I assume you have very short-term goals on ransomware &#8212; not allowing people to operate from their territory.&nbsp; But tell us about &#8212; to the degree you can &#8212; your longer-term goals on state-sponsored activities, since there&#8217;s been so much of that out of Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the first: We are flexible on the timing and format of agreements.&nbsp; It could be more comprehensive; it could be agreements that cover different pieces at different points in time.&nbsp; So, this is not necessarily a circumstance of waiting until New START is expired to do something.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But it is certainly the case &#8212; and I think this is implied in your question &#8212; that we do have a 2026 final expiration of New START.&nbsp; And a big part of the question that the two presidents are trying to answer through these talks is what comes after &#8212; what will come after New START.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) China and other players as well?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think, ultimately, we are going to need to have a sustained conversation with China on arms control-related issues.&nbsp; But the President has made clear that, at the outset, a bilateral discussion between the two biggest nuclear powers in the world is the way to start.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the cyber side?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, on the cyber side, obviously, ransomware will be a significant topic of conversation tomorrow.&nbsp; They will also discuss the broader issue of cyber norms, cyber rules of the road tomorrow in the discussion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President will make clear that if we see significant types of cyber activity, like we did with SolarWinds, he will respond like we did with SolarWinds.&nbsp; Beyond that, I&#8217;m not going to preview the conversation per the President&#8217;s desire to be able to have the discussion with Putin and then read it out after.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think that was a sufficient response on SolarWinds?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We believe that the response on SolarWinds was, as the President said at the time, proportional.&nbsp; We believe it sent a message about what the United States would and would not tolerate.&nbsp; And so, we judge<br>that the response we took was the right one.&nbsp; But, of course, this is a larger challenge that is going to require a consistent, steady policy on our part, and we will<br>approach the issue accordingly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s he going to say to Putin about the case of Aleksey Navalny?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll put it this way:<br>When the other side tries to say that there are issues that are off the table or that won&#8217;t be on the agenda, for the American President, nothing is off the table.&nbsp; Certainly human rights are not off the table, and individual high-profile cases are not off the table.&nbsp; But otherwise, I&#8217;m not going to preview what he&#8217;s going to say.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What will he say about Belarus and the recent incident with Ryanair?&nbsp; Is that going to be coming up as well?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s already said publicly that he viewed that as an act of egregious air piracy and completely inconsistent with international norms and the rule of law.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think you will hear anything inconsistent when he reads the meeting out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, I don&#8217;t want to be in the position of saying what he&#8217;s going to say to Putin.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have an objective, like a particular deliverable that you&#8217;re seeking?&nbsp; Or is that the wrong framing, because it&#8217;s not about deliverables for you right now?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; During &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not &#8212; we&#8217;re not expecting a big set of deliverables out of this meeting.&nbsp; We are seeking three basic things:<br>&nbsp;<br>First, a clear set of taskings about areas where working together can advance our national interest and make the world safer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, a clear laydown of the areas of America&#8217;s vital national interests, where Russian activities that run counter to those interests will be met with a response.<br>&nbsp;<br>And third, a clear explication of the President&#8217;s vision for American values and our national priorities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Those are the three things that we&#8217;re trying to accomplish, and the President will do that over the course of the meeting with President Putin.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you just tell us a little bit about how has the President prepped for this?&nbsp; What &#8212; you know, had he been meeting with advisors?&nbsp; What has he been doing for this?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; He&#8217;s been preparing for this like he prepares for every significant international engagement.&nbsp; He reviews the issues &#8212; written material; he cares about digging into the details.&nbsp; That very much matters to him.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s also had the opportunity to engage with a wide variety of advisors across the government who have deep expertise on Russia, as well as to hear from some outside experts as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you just speak a little bit more about the Baltic countries meeting?&nbsp; Why did the President feel like it was necessary to meet with them first before meeting with President Putin, on top of the NATO and EU allies?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Beyond being necessary, the President really loves those kinds of meetings.&nbsp; I went with him to Lithuania some years ago, and he&#8217;s just energized by the model and example of these vibrant democracies on the eastern flank.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But specifically, relative to the meeting tomorrow, he wanted to show quite publicly that he was going to stand in solidarity with NATO&#8217;s eastern flank allies, that he was going to consult with them in advance of the meeting, and that he was going to stand up for their interests in the meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did they have any advice for him on dealing with Putin, since they live in his neighborhood?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; They sure did.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did they say?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; But I’ll leave that to them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, come on.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; But, yes, they had good advice.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In all his long travels and associations with this part of the world, has he learned any Russian?&nbsp; I mean, literally, like a few words.&nbsp; Or does he speak a spattering of it?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Will he say “hello” in Russian, for example, or a “thank you” or anything?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he have conversation (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if he will say “hello.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; I actually &#8212; I have not heard him speak Russian, but I can&#8217;t confirm one way or the other.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you, guys.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>4:12 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at the U.S.-EU Summit Expanded Plenary Session</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/15/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-u-s-eu-summit-expanded-plenary-session/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 16:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Europa Building, European CouncilBrussels, Belgium 1:13 P.M. CEST&#160;PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, thank you.&#160; Thank you both very much.&#160; It’s been one of the great pleasures getting to know you both personally and (inaudible) our official positions.&#160; And we were at the G7, and again today &#8212; I apologize I kept my colleagues in the closed meeting.&#160;&#160;But&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Europa Building, European Council<br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>1:13 P.M. CEST<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you both very much.&nbsp; It’s been one of the great pleasures getting to know you both personally and (inaudible) our official positions.&nbsp; And we were at the G7, and again today &#8212; I apologize I kept my colleagues in the closed meeting.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I want to &#8212; you know, this is – I haven’t been back to Brussels or the EU since 2017, and since the &#8212; back then, also the first summit back in 2014.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I brought the A-team with me today.&nbsp; And, you know, I’ve said, both publicly and privately, that America is back, and this is why we’re here in full force.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I’m happy to have with me today the members of my Cabinet: Secretary of State, Anthony Blinken; he suffers from the problem of having worked with me for years.&nbsp; And also Trade Representative, Ambassador Katherine Tai, who has made some real progress already.&nbsp; And Secretary of Commerce, Gina Raimondo, who was a first-rate governor and one of the brightest people that we’ve worked with, and agreed to come on as our Secretary of Commerce.<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of the things that you and I were talking about – and will come as no shock to either of you: Europe is our natural partner, and the reason is we’re committed to the same democratic norms and institutions, and are &#8212; they are increasingly under attack.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we &#8212; I’ve said it before, and I apologize for repeating &#8212; oh, I didn’t mention Jake Sullivan (inaudible) National Security Advisor.&nbsp; I’m leaving out a lot of people here.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; I’m going to get in trouble.&nbsp; But anyway, we’ll get back to that in a minute.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we &#8212; you know, there’s a lot that is happening.&nbsp; I used to always &#8212; my friends would kid me while in the United States Senate, because I served there, for always quoting Irish poets.&nbsp; You think I quoted Irish poets because I’m Irish.&nbsp; That’s not the reason.&nbsp; I quote them because they’re the best poets in the world &#8212; that’s why.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>But all kidding aside, there is a &#8212; there is a stanza from a poem from an Irish poet, who (inaudible).&nbsp; He said, “All is changed, changed utterly: A terrible beauty has been born.”&nbsp; I think all has changed in the last 10, 12 years, and it’s not because of any one person.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think we’re in the midst of terrible beauty having been born &#8212; a great shift in technology, a great shift in the development of the world, and it’s causing great anxiety in each our countries and uncertainty among many of our colleagues of what’s going to be their place in the world.&nbsp; Are they going to be replaced by a new technology?&nbsp; Are they going to no longer have a job?&nbsp; And what are they going to do?<br>&nbsp;<br>And that comes along at the same time that that also generates &#8212; when an uncertainty is generated politically like that, by individuals, it also generates some folks who are less than &#8212; how can I say it? &#8212; some of them are like charlatans, trying to take advantage of those concerns.&nbsp; And we see it in Europe.&nbsp; We see it in the United States.&nbsp; We’ve seen it around the world.&nbsp; And it’s phony populism.<br>&nbsp;<br>So it seems to me that the best answer to deal with these changes is that &#8212; to have a circumstance where our economies grow, and they grow together, and they grow still based on the value set that united us in the first place.&nbsp; And I think we do share just the same basic values of human dignity and human rights as my colleagues.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll be very colloquial with you: My dad had a transition where, in the city we lived in, coal was dying; it was no longer relevant.&nbsp; You know, he was not a &#8212; my great grandfather was a coal miner; he was a mining engineer.&nbsp; But in northeastern Pennsylvania, when coal died &#8212; my dad was a salesperson &#8212; and the economy collapsed.&nbsp; And we moved to another part where there were jobs, in southern &#8212; into &#8212; down in Delaware, a very &#8212; just across the Pennsylvania border.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And my family &#8212; my siblings and I would hear him often use the following expression: He said, “Joe, a job is about a lot more than a paycheck.&nbsp; It’s about your dignity.&nbsp; It’s about respect.&nbsp; It’s about your place in the community.&nbsp; It’s about being able to look at your child in the eye and say ‘Honey, it’s&nbsp;going to be okay’ and mean it.”&nbsp; I think we sometimes forget that.&nbsp; It’s about the dignity of the worker and them being able to hold their head high.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so I think we have an enormous opportunity, if we think in terms of these changes &#8212; particularly in terms of global warming &#8212; if we think of them in terms of jobs.&nbsp; The kind of jobs that we’re going to have to create to preserve the environment are jobs that can pay well, that are going to be (inaudible) technologies that working-class, blue-collar workers, as we say in the States, will be able to make more money, be able to do well.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we have to, all of us, accommodate those changes and provide for them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I think we have a lot to deal with, from COVID-19 to whether or not we’re in a position that we can generate the kind of strengthening in transatlantic trade and technological cooperation.<br>&nbsp;<br>There are, sort of, a different set of priorities with the same objective: How do likeminded countries, sharing the same values, work together to improve the living standard for not only our people, but for the rest of the world?&nbsp; And I think we have the capacity to do that, and it’s going to take an awful lot of hard work and determination.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’ll conclude by saying: One of the reasons I’m optimistic is because of our younger generation, in Europe as well as the United States.&nbsp; The young generation &#8212; this one &#8212; is the best educated in American history.&nbsp; It is also the least prejudiced, the most open, and the most &#8212; the most committed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that we have reason to believe that if we provide the policies that are consistent, that provide for the kind of growth and opportunity for them &#8212; and education plays a gigantic part of that &#8212; I think we &#8212; I think the future is very, very bright.&nbsp; I think we have an opportunity to do some, really, very good things.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I should &#8212; as my mother would say, I should “hush up” and let this discussion move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:21 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces 4th Slate of Judicial Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/president-biden-announces-4th-slate-of-judicial-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 16:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing five new candidates for the federal bench and two new candidates for District of Columbia courts, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing five new candidates for the federal bench and two new candidates for District of Columbia courts, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.<br><br>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country &#8212; both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.<br><br>For example, this slate includes:</p>



<ul><li>A nationally-recognized leader on voting rights who would be the only Latina serving on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit</li><li>A former public defender and current civil rights plaintiff’s attorney who would be the second African American woman judge actively serving on the District Court for the District of Columbia</li><li>A federal prosecutor who would be the first judge of South Asian descent to serve on the District Court for the District of Connecticut</li><li>A Department of Justice lawyer with two decades of civil rights experience, including as Deputy Chief of the Appellate Section in the Civil Rights Division</li><li>A magistrate judge on the D.C. Superior Court with deep experience in domestic violence and family law issues</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s fourth round of names for federal judicial positions, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 24.<br><br>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move at an unparalleled speed with respect to judicial nominations. His first judicial nominations announcement was made faster than that of any new President in modern American history, and today’s announcement continues that trend.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>CIRCUIT COURT</u></strong><br><br><strong>MYRNA PÉREZ</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Myrna Pérez is the director of the Brennan Center’s Voting Rights and Elections Program at the New York University (NYU) School of Law. Ms. Pérez joined the Brennan Center in 2006. She has also been a lecturer-in-law at Columbia Law School since 2016. She previously served as an Adjunct Professor of Clinical Law at NYU School of Law from 2013 to 2015. Prior to joining the Brennan Center, Ms. Pérez was a Civil Rights Fellow at Relman, Dane &amp; Colfax, a civil rights law firm in Washington, D.C., from 2005 to 2006. Ms. Pérez served as a law clerk for Judge Anita B. Brody on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania from 2003 to 2004 and for Judge Julio M. Fuentes on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit from 2004 to 2005.<br><br>Ms. Pérez received her J.D. from Columbia Law School in 2003, her M.P.P. from Harvard Kennedy School in 1998, and her B.A. from Yale University in 1996. Prior to law school, she was a Presidential Management Fellow, serving as a policy analyst for the U.S. Government Accountability Office on issues including housing and health care.&nbsp;<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong><u>DISTRICT COURTS</u></strong><br><br><strong>SARAH A. L. MERRIAM</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the District of Connecticut</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Judge Sarah A. L. Merriam has served as a U.S. Magistrate Judge for the District of Connecticut since 2015. Previously, she served as an Assistant Federal Public Defender for the District of Connecticut from 2007 to 2015. Judge Merriam worked on political campaigns in Connecticut from 2006 to 2007. She was an associate at the Connecticut-based law firm Cowdery, Ecker &amp; Murphy from 2003 to 2006. Judge Merriam served as a law clerk for Judge Thomas Meskill on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit from 2002 to 2003 and for Judge Alvin Thompson on the U.S. District Court for the District of Connecticut from 2000 to 2002.<br><br>Judge Merriam received an LLM from Duke Law School in 2018, her J.D. from Yale Law School in 2000, and her B.A. from Georgetown in 1993. <br></p>



<p><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SARALA VIDYA NAGALA</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the District of Connecticut</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Sarala Vidya Nagala is the Deputy Chief of the Major Crimes Unit in the U.S. Attorney’s Office in the District of Connecticut, a role she has held since 2017. Ms. Nagala joined the U.S. Attorney’s Office in 2012, and has served in a number of leadership roles in the office, including as Hate Crimes Coordinator. Previously, Ms. Nagala was an associate at Munger, Tolles, &amp; Olson in San Francisco, California from 2009 to 2012. She began her legal career as a law clerk for Judge Susan Graber on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit from 2008 to 2009.<br><br>Ms. Nagala received her J.D. from the University of California at Berkeley School of Law in 2008 and her B.A. from Stanford University in 2005. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong>OMAR A. WILLIAMS</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the District of Connecticut</em></strong><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Judge Omar A. Williams has served as a Superior Court Judge in Hartford, Connecticut since 2016. In that role, Judge Williams has served on the New England Regional Judicial Opioid Initiative, the Sentence Review Division, and the Wiretap Panel. He was previously a Superior Court Judge in New London from 2014 to 2016. Prior to his appointment as a state court judge, Judge Williams was an Assistant Public Defender for the State of Connecticut Division of Public Defender Services from 2003 to 2014. <br><br>Judge Williams received his J.D. from the University of Connecticut Law School in 2002 and his B.A. from the University of Connecticut in 1998.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong>JIA M. COBB</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the District of Columbia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Jia M. Cobb is a partner at Relman Colfax, where she has practiced since 2012. Her plaintiff-side litigation practice focuses on fair housing, disability discrimination, employment discrimination, and cases at the intersection of civil rights and criminal justice. Ms. Cobb taught trial advocacy as an adjunct professor at American University Washington College of Law in 2011 and was a faculty member at Harvard Law School’s Trial Advocacy Workshop in 2010 and 2011. Prior to her time in private practice, Ms. Cobb served as a trial attorney at the Public Defender Service for the District of Columbia from 2006 to 2012. She began her legal career as a law clerk for Judge Diane Wood on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Seventh Circuit from 2005 to 2006.<br><br>Ms. Cobb received a J.D. from Harvard Law School, <em>cum laude</em>, in 2005 and a B.A. from Northwestern University, <em>magna cum laude</em>, in 2002. <br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong><u>LOCAL D.C. COURTS</u></strong><br><br><strong>TOVAH R. CALDERON</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Tovah R. Calderon currently serves as an Acting Deputy Assistant Attorney General in the U.S. Department of Justice’s Civil Rights Division. Ms. Calderon first joined the Department of Justice in 2001 through the Attorney General’s Honors Program and has held numerous roles within the department. Before her current detail with the Civil Rights Division, Ms. Calderon served as a Deputy Chief in the Division’s Appellate Section. Ms. Calderon has also served on detail to the White House Domestic Policy Council, the Civil Rights Division’s Policy and Strategy Section, and the Senate Judiciary Committee. From 2000 to 2001, she served as a law clerk for Judge Francis D. Murnaghan, Jr. on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit, as well as other judges on both the Fourth Circuit and the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland.<br><br>Ms. Calderon received her J.D. from the Howard University School of Law in 2000 and her B.A. from the University of Michigan in 1995. <br><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>KENIA SEOANE LOPEZ</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Judge Kenia Seoane Lopez is currently a Magistrate Judge on the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. Prior to her appointment in 2012, Judge Seoane Lopez served as a Bilingual Attorney Negotiator in the Domestic Violence Division of the District of Columbia Superior Court from 2009 to 2012. She previously served as an Assistant Attorney General in the Legal Services Section of the Child Support Division in the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia from 2005 to 2009. Judge Seoane Lopez served as a law clerk to the Justices on the Massachusetts Superior Court from 2002 to 2003 and Senior Judges on the Superior Court of the District of Columbia from 2004 to 2005.<br><br>Judge Seoane Lopez received her J.D. and M.A. in Latin American, Caribbean, and Iberian Studies from the University of Wisconsin in 2002 and her B.S. from Northeastern University, <em>cum laude</em>, in 1997.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-EU Summit Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/u-s-eu-summit-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 16:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Towards a Renewed Transatlantic Partnership The United States and the European Union represent 780 million people who share democratic values and the largest economic relationship in the world. We have a chance and a responsibility to help people make a living and keep them safe and secure, fight climate change, and stand up for democracy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Towards a Renewed Transatlantic Partnership</strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li>The United States and the European Union represent 780 million people who share democratic values and the largest economic relationship in the world. We have a chance and a responsibility to help people make a living and keep them safe and secure, fight climate change, and stand up for democracy and human rights. We laid the foundations of the world economy and the rules-based international order after World War II based on openness, fair competition, transparency, and accountability. Some of the rules need an update: to protect our health, our climate and planet, to ensure democracy delivers and technology improves our lives.</li><li>We, the leaders of the European Union and the United States, met today to renew our Transatlantic partnership, set a Joint Transatlantic Agenda for the post-pandemic era, and commit to regular dialogue to take stock of progress.</li><li>Together, we intend to: (i) end the COVID-19 pandemic, prepare for future global health challenges, and drive forward a sustainable global recovery; (ii) protect our planet and foster green growth; (iii) strengthen trade, investment, and technological cooperation; and (iv) build a more democratic, peaceful, and secure world. We are committed to uphold the rules-based international order with the United Nations at its core, reinvigorate and reform multilateral institutions where needed, and cooperate with all those who share these objectives.<br><br><strong>I. End the COVID-19 pandemic, prepare for future global health challenges, and drive forward a sustainable global recovery</strong></li><li>Ending the COVID-19 pandemic through global cooperation is our first priority. We promote equitable and affordable access and delivery of safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines, diagnostics, and therapeutics through the Access to COVID-19 Tools Accelerator. We commit to continuing to support the COVAX Facility and encourage more donors to make 2 billion vaccine doses available worldwide by late 2021. We aspire to vaccinate at least two thirds of the world’s population by the end of 2022.</li><li>A Joint U.S.-EU COVID Manufacturing and Supply Chain Taskforce has been established to deepen cooperation and identify and resolve issues around expanding vaccine and therapeutics production capacity, including by building new production facilities, maintaining open and secure supply chains, avoiding any unnecessary export restrictions, and encouraging voluntary sharing of know-how and technology on mutually-determined terms including through the ACT-A. We are committed to strengthen global health security, pandemic preparedness, and response to health emergencies and future outbreaks. We plan to leverage our strengths to help countries build the capacities to prevent, detect, and respond to infectious disease threats.  We intend to work together with like-minded countries this year to explore options towards sustainable global health and health security financing, supported by strengthened global accountability, tracking and allocation of global health security financing, including the Independent Panel for Pandemic Preparedness and Response (IPPPR) recommendation toward a Global Health Threats Council.</li><li>We resolve to reinforce cooperation to reform the World Health Organization (WHO), including advancing sustainable financing and improving its internal operations. We welcome the “Rome Declaration” principles endorsed at the G20 Global Health Summit and the outcomes of the World Health Assembly, including the establishment of a Working Group on Strengthening WHO Preparedness and Response to Health Emergencies that will prioritize the assessment of the benefits of developing a WHO convention, agreement, or other international instrument on pandemic preparedness and response and provide a report to be considered at the special session of the Health Assembly in November 2021. We will continue to engage in health research initiatives, including to develop medical countermeasures in a much shorter period of time, to support the regional surge capacity to produce them, and to facilitate trade in essential medical goods. We call for progress on a transparent, evidence-based, and expert-led WHO-convened phase 2 study on the origins of COVID-19, that is free from interference, and we commit to working together toward the development and use of a swift and independent means for investigating such outbreaks in the future.</li><li>We welcome G7 discussions to build back better for the world—orienting development finance tools toward the range of challenges faced by developing countries, including in resilient infrastructure and technologies, addressing the impact of climate change, health systems and security, developing digital solutions, and advancing gender equality and education. We intend to jointly drive forward a sustainable and inclusive global recovery, in line with the UN 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development that leaves no one behind and prioritizes the most vulnerable and marginalized, protects our climate and planet, protects human rights, empowers women and girls and creates decent jobs. We will enhance our cooperation on sustainable connectivity and high-quality infrastructure. We intend to continue providing assistance to countries in need, address debt vulnerabilities, and stimulate domestic reforms and increased private investment.  To address the problem of unsustainable debts faced by many countries in the aftermath of the COVID-19 pandemic, we plan to promote the swift and transparent implementation of the G20 Common Framework for debt treatment and explore innovative instruments such as debt swaps. Recognizing the increase in food insecurity and malnutrition projected, including as a result of the pandemic, we commit to building resilient food systems.</li><li>We resolve to support efforts to ensure safe and secure global mobility. We will establish a joint U.S.-EU Experts’ Working Group to exchange information and expertise to reinitiate safe and sustainable travel between the EU and the United States. We welcome progress made by the United States and the EU toward additional EU member states meeting the requirements necessary for visa-free travel to the United States and intend to continue our dialogue towards visa waiver travel.<br><br><strong>II.</strong> <strong>Protect our planet and foster green growth</strong></li><li>Climate change, environmental degradation, and the loss of biodiversity are mutually-reinforcing, extraordinary threats to humanity. We plan to continue and strengthen our cooperation to tackle climate change, environmental degradation and the loss of biodiversity, promote green growth, protect our oceans, and urge ambitious action by all other major players.</li><li>We are committed to the Paris Agreement and its effective and strengthened implementation. To provide an effective platform for cooperation in this regard, we commit to establish a U.S.-EU High-Level Climate Action Group. We intend to lead by example through becoming net zero greenhouse gases (GHG) economies no later than 2050 and implementing our respective enhanced 2030 targets / Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs). We resolve to engage our international partners to achieve an ambitious outcome at the 26th UN Climate Change Conference of the Parties (COP26), making every effort to keep a 1.5 degree Celsius limit on global temperature within reach. We intend to closely coordinate to promote robust climate measures, address the risk of carbon leakage, and cooperate on sustainable finance, including by providing the private sector with usable tools and metrics. </li><li>We are determined to accelerate a climate-neutral future and ensure a just transition that leaves no one behind, including through low greenhouse gas emission technologies, an increasing uptake of renewable energies, a stronger engagement to promote clean energy innovation in Mission Innovation, increased energy efficiency and methane emissions reduction, sustainable food systems, including climate-smart agricultural systems, and sustainable and smart mobility. We commit to rapidly scaling up technologies and policies that further accelerate the transition away from unabated coal capacity and to an overwhelmingly decarbonized power system in the 2030s, consistent with our respective 2030 NDCs and 2050 net zero commitments. The U.S.-EU Energy Council will continue to lead coordination on strategic energy issues, including decarbonization of the energy sector, energy security, and sustainable energy supply chains. We resolve to increase our cooperation on transition towards a climate-neutral, resource-efficient and circular economy.  In this context, we intend to work towards a Transatlantic Green Technology Alliance that would foster cooperation on the development and deployment of green technologies, as well as promote markets to scale such technologies.   </li><li>We intend to continue to scale up efforts to meet the USD 100 billion per year climate finance goal through to 2025, in the context of meaningful mitigation actions and transparency on implementation from public and private sources, as well as to continue to scale up finance contributing to climate adaptation action.  In order to fulfill the objectives of the Paris Agreement, we stress that international investments in unabated coal must stop now and call for global efforts to phase out unabated coal in energy production. We resolve to take concrete steps towards an absolute end to new direct government support for unabated international thermal coal power generation in third countries by the end of 2021, including through Official Development Assistance, export finance, investment, and financial and trade promotion support. We commit to reviewing our official trade, export, and development finance policies towards these objectives.</li><li>We are strongly determined to halt and reverse biodiversity loss by 2030 and take urgent action to address its drivers. In this context, we are committed to the goal of conserving or protecting at least 30 percent of the global land and 30 percent of the global oceans by 2030. We commit to contribute to this goal by conserving or protecting at least 30 percent of our own land, including terrestrial and inland waters, and coastal and marine areas by 2030 according to national circumstances and approaches. We plan to actively restore nature for the benefit of the health and well-being of our citizens, and step up our cooperation on deforestation and wildlife trafficking. We encourage others to make similar commitments to support efforts that benefit both climate and biodiversity, and protect our oceans. We plan to jointly promote a successful and ambitious post-2020 global biodiversity framework at the 15<sup>th</sup> UN Biodiversity Conference of the Parties (COP15). We also encourage partners to join multilateral efforts at the UN Environment Assembly to consider next steps at the global level to tackle plastics pollution.</li><li>We commit to working together to protect our oceans, including by combatting marine litter. We resolve to support the designation of new marine protected areas in the Southern Ocean, and continue cooperating for the purpose of the sustainable blue economy, sustainable fishing, prevention of Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated (IUU) Fishing, and research through the All-Atlantic Ocean Research alliance. We will also plan to work together at the next UN Ocean Conference and at the intergovernmental conference on Marine Biodiversity beyond National Jurisdiction.<br><br><strong>III. Strengthen trade, investment, and technological cooperation</strong></li><li>We commit to grow the U.S.-EU trade and investment relationship as well as to uphold and reform the rules-based multilateral trading system. We intend to use trade to help fight climate change, protect the environment, promote workers’ rights, expand resilient and sustainable supply chains, continue to cooperate in emerging technologies, and create decent jobs. We resolve to stand together to protect our businesses and workers from unfair trade practices, in particular those posed by non-market economies that are undermining the world trading system.</li><li>We resolve to drive digital transformation that spurs trade and investment, strengthens our technological and industrial leadership, boosts innovation, and protects and promotes critical and emerging technologies and infrastructure. We plan to cooperate on the development and deployment of new technologies based on our shared democratic values, including respect for human rights, and that encourages compatible standards and regulations.  </li><li>To kick-start this positive agenda and to provide an effective platform for cooperation, we establish a high-level U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council (TTC). The major goals of the TTC will be to grow the bilateral trade and investment relationship; to avoid new unnecessary technical barriers to trade; to coordinate, seek common ground, and strengthen global cooperation on technology, digital issues, and supply chains; to support collaborative research and exchanges; to cooperate on compatible and international standards development; to facilitate regulatory policy and enforcement cooperation and, where possible, convergence; to promote innovation and leadership by U.S. and European firms; and to strengthen other areas of cooperation. The cooperation and exchanges of the TTC will be without prejudice to the regulatory autonomy of the United States and the European Union and will respect the different legal systems in both jurisdictions. Cooperation within the TTC will also feed into coordination in multilateral bodies and wider efforts with like-minded partners, with the aim of promoting a democratic model of digital governance.</li><li>The TTC will initially include working groups with agendas focused on technology standards cooperation (including on AI, Internet of Things, among other emerging technologies), climate and green tech, ICT security and competitiveness, data governance and technology platforms, the misuse of technology threatening security and human rights, export controls, investment screening, promoting SMEs access to, and use of, digital technologies, and global trade challenges. It will also include a working group on reviewing and strengthening our most critical supply chains. Notably, we commit to building a U.S.-EU partnership on the rebalancing of global supply chains in semiconductors with a view to enhancing U.S. and EU respective security of supply as well as capacity to design and produce the most powerful and resource efficient semiconductors.</li><li>In parallel with the TTC, we intend to establish a U.S.-EU Joint Technology Competition Policy Dialogue that would focus on approaches to competition policy and enforcement, and increased cooperation in the tech sector. To support collaborative research and innovation exchanges, we promote a staff exchange program between our research funding agencies, and we intend to explore the possibility of developing a new research initiative on biotechnology and genomics, with a view to setting common standards. A new implementing arrangement between the EU Joint Research Centre and the U.S. National Institute of Standards and Technologies aims to expand cooperation to new areas. We also resolve to deepen cooperation on cybersecurity information sharing and situational awareness, as well as cybersecurity certification of products and software.</li><li>We commit to work together to ensure safe, secure, and trusted cross-border data flows that protect consumers and enhance privacy protections, while enabling Transatlantic commerce.  To this end, we plan to continue to work together to strengthen legal certainty in Transatlantic flows of personal data. We also commit to continue cooperation on consumer protection and access to electronic evidence in criminal matters.</li><li>We salute having reached an Understanding on a Cooperative Framework for Large Civil Aircraft, reflecting a new transatlantic relationship in this area.  We are committed to make this framework work to promote a level playing field, overcome long-standing differences, avoid future litigation, and more effectively address the challenge posed by non-market economies. We will engage in discussions to allow the resolution of existing differences on measures regarding steel and aluminum before the end of the year.  In this regard, we are determined to work together to resolve tensions arising from the U.S. application of tariffs on imports from the EU under U.S. Section 232, and will work towards allowing trade to recover from its 2020 lows and ending the WTO disputes. We commit to ensure the long-term viability of our steel and aluminum industries, and to address excess capacity.  We are determined to foster a fair, sustainable, and modern international tax system and cooperate to reach a global consensus on the question of taxation of multinational companies through the G20/OECD Inclusive Framework and look forward to reaching an agreement at the July meeting of G20 Finance Ministers and Central Bank Governors.  </li><li>We intend to work cooperatively on efforts to achieve meaningful World Trade Organization (WTO) reform and help promote outcomes that benefit our workers and companies. We commit to work together to advance the proper functioning of the WTO’s negotiating function and dispute settlement system, which requires addressing long-standing issues. Plurilateral mechanisms can provide a means for addressing new trade concerns when multilateral solutions are not possible. We plan to continue to cooperate on special and differential treatment, and on our joint transparency proposal. We intend to seek to update the WTO rulebook with more effective disciplines on industrial subsidies, unfair behavior of state-owned enterprises, and other trade and market distorting practices. We intend to work closely together, and with the wider support of the Membership of the WTO, to conclude a meaningful agreement on fisheries subsidies, and to a trade policy response to the COVID-19 pandemic that facilitates expansion of production and equitable access to vaccines, and to work towards a WTO Ministerial later this year that contributes to a more effective and modernized rules-based trading system.</li><li>We commit to strengthen our cooperation on space by building on the Galileo – GPS Agreement. This could include making progress on access to Galileo’s Public Regulated Service signal, engaging on space-based Earth observation to support climate policies, for instance by monitoring CO2 levels and emergency services, as well as exchanging on our respective approaches on space traffic management.<br><br><strong>IV. Build a more democratic, peaceful and secure world</strong></li><li>Together, the European Union and the United States are an anchor for democracy, peace, and security around the world, to peacefully prevent and resolve conflicts, uphold the rule of law and international law, and promote human rights for all, gender equity and equality, and the empowerment of women and girls, including by working together through multilateral institutions including the UN Human Rights Council. Together, we resolve to address humanitarian needs and stand up for international humanitarian law as well as expand the resource base for humanitarian action<strong>.</strong> We reject authoritarianism in all its forms around the globe, resisting autocrats’ efforts to create an environment that protects their rule and serves their interests, while undermining liberal democracies. We intend to enhance cooperation on the use of sanctions to pursue shared foreign policy and security objectives, while avoiding possible unintended consequences for European and U.S. interests. In this respect, we resolve to continue to engage on issues on which we might have different approaches.</li><li>We intend to support democracy across the globe by defending media freedom; advancing a free and open internet; fostering responsible behavior in cyberspace; upholding transparency and combatting corruption in financial systems, politics, and the economy; tackling disinformation; protecting civil society and civic space; advancing women’s political participation and empowerment; and protecting the human rights of all people. We resolve to lead by example at home. We intend to partner in the Summit for Democracy, committing to concrete actions to defend universal human rights, prevent democratic backsliding, and fight corruption. We plan to increase cooperation and exchange information and expertise to increase resilience against and to counter foreign information manipulation and interference, all forms of coercion including economic pressure, hybrid threats, malicious cyber activities, terrorism and violent extremism, and other common security threats. We resolve to support the ability of civil society and independent media to operate freely, and to protect and defend journalists in order to hold governments accountable.</li><li>We intend to closely consult and cooperate on the full range of issues in the framework of our respective similar multi-faceted approaches to China, which include elements of cooperation, competition, and systemic rivalry. We intend to continue coordinating on our shared concerns, including ongoing human rights violations in Xinjiang and Tibet; the erosion of autonomy and democratic processes in Hong Kong; economic coercion; disinformation campaigns; and regional security issues. We remain seriously concerned about the situation in the East and South China Seas and strongly oppose any unilateral attempts to change the status quo and increase tensions. We reaffirm the critical importance of respecting international law, in particular the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS) noting its provisions setting forth the lawful maritime entitlements of States, on maritime delimitation, on the sovereign rights and jurisdictions of States, on the obligation to settle disputes by peaceful means, and on the freedom of navigation and overflight and other internationally lawful uses of the sea. We underscore the importance of peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait, and encourage the peaceful resolution of cross-Strait issues. We intend also to coordinate on our constructive engagement with China on issues such as climate change and non-proliferation, and on certain regional issues.</li><li>We stand united in our principled approach towards Russia and we are ready to respond decisively to its repeating pattern of negative behavior and harmful activities, which Russia must address to prevent the further deterioration of relations including on the list of so-called unfriendly states.To coordinate our policies and actions, we plan to establish a U.S.-EU high-level dialogue on Russia. We condemn Russia’s continued actions to undermine Ukraine’s and Georgia&#8217;s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and independence. We call on Russia to ensure foreign diplomatic missions in Russia can operate in a safe, secure, and productive fashion. We urge Russia to stop its continuous crackdown on civil society, the opposition, and independent media, and release all political prisoners. At the same time, we keep channels of communication open and possibilities for selective cooperation in areas of common interest. We also commit to work together to address the urgent and escalating threat from criminal ransomware networks that pose risks to our citizens and companies.</li><li>We are determined to continue to stand in support of the sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity of the EU’s Eastern partners and will support the reform path of Ukraine, Georgia, and the Republic of Moldova. We resolve to work towards long-term peace, resilience, and stability in the South Caucasus. We stand with the people of Belarus and their demands for human rights and democracy. We resolve to hold the Lukashenka regime to account for its escalating attacks on human rights and fundamental freedoms and for endangering aviation safety through the unprecedented and unacceptable forced diversion of an EU passenger airplane under false pretenses, and the subsequent arrest of a journalist as part of a continuing assault on opposition voices and the freedom of the press.    </li><li>We intend to further strengthen our joint engagement in the Western Balkans, including through the EU-facilitated dialogue between Belgrade and Pristina on normalization of their relations, and by supporting key reforms for EU integration. We resolve to work hand-in-hand for sustainable de-escalation in the Eastern Mediterranean, where differences should be settled through dialogue in good faith and in accordance with international law. We aim for a cooperative and mutually beneficial relationship with a democratic Turkey. We plan to join efforts for a stable and secure Middle East and North Africa. The European Union and the United States welcome the ceasefire in the conflict in the Middle East and reaffirm the need for Israelis and Palestinians to enjoy equal measures of freedom, security, prosperity, and democracy on the basis of a two-State solution. In light of the growing humanitarian needs across Syria and the COVID 19 pandemic, we call on the UN Security Council to ensure that humanitarian aid can reach all people in need in Syria, including through cross border and cross line operations. We also regret the recent illegitimate elections in Syria and call on the international community to hold the Assad regime accountable for its brutal crimes and to work together to advance a political resolution to the conflict in line with UNSC resolution 2254. We reaffirm our commitment to support Libya in its path towards peace, security, and stability, and to work with parties in Yemen to agree to the UN’s proposal for an immediate ceasefire.</li><li>We are committed to peace and sustainable development in Africa. The political, human rights, security, and humanitarian situation in Ethiopia, Somalia, and the Sahel countries is of grave concern. We share deep concerns about the growing political and ethnic polarization throughout Ethiopia that threatens the country’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. We condemn ongoing atrocities, including widespread sexual violence, and we welcome the ongoing OHCHR investigations and call for full accountability for reported human rights violations in Tigray and for the perpetrators to be brought to justice. We also call for the withdrawal of foreign forces, and unimpeded humanitarian access. Following the Summit on financing African economies, we plan to act together with our African partners to ensure equitable access to safe and effective vaccines, and to provide financial support towards a sustainable recovery. We are determined to significantly amplify, on a voluntary basis, the impact of the proposed general allocation of Special Drawing Rights by the IMF for Africa.</li><li>We intend to work together with our partners for a free and open Indo-Pacific, which is inclusive, based on the rule of law and democratic values, and will contribute to the security and sustainable development of the region. We intend to work together to promote a swift return to democracy in Burma. In view of the withdrawal of international troops from Afghanistan, we intend to work closely to support the ongoing peace process and sustain regional stability and protect human rights gains, in particular for women and girls.</li><li>We further commit to strengthen our cooperation with the countries of Latin America and the Caribbean to support socio-economic recovery, address economic vulnerability, and push for stronger democratic governance, including supporting a negotiated outcome that leads to free and fair elections in Venezuela.</li><li>We resolve to work together to retain the Arctic as a region of peace and stability and collaborate, in particular through the Arctic Council, to ensure a clean habitat and constructive cooperation on climate change, environmental protection, and sustainable economic development benefiting the region’s inhabitants.</li><li>We resolve to work together to counter the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction and renew global arms control efforts. We emphasize our support for the ongoing diplomatic efforts and negotiations in Vienna aimed at facilitating the return of the United States to the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA) as well as the full and effective implementation of the deal by Iran and the United States. We share serious concerns about steps taken by Iran, which are inconsistent with the JCPOA. The European Union and the United States recognize that, alongside the return to full and effective implementation by Iran of its nuclear related commitments, the lifting of sanctions constitutes an essential part of the JCPOA. The JCPOA remains critical to ensuring the exclusively peaceful nature of Iran’s nuclear program and to upholding the global nuclear non-proliferation architecture.</li><li>We resolve to revive dialogue on migration and mobility, including innovative solutions on effective and safe migration policy in cooperation with third countries, including via the U.S.-EU Platform on Migration and Asylum.</li><li>We welcome the EU’s invitation to the United States to join the PESCO project Military Mobility as an important step towards closer U.S.-EU partnership in security and defense.  We recognize the contribution EU security and defense initiatives can make to both European and Transatlantic security and plan to launch a dedicated dialogue on security and defense and pursue closer cooperation in this field.  We commit to work towards an Administrative Arrangement for the United States with the European Defence Agency, with discussions, including on modalities and conditions for a closer and mutually beneficial cooperation in this framework, beginning as soon as possible.  We reaffirm our unwavering support for robust NATO-EU cooperation and to the commitments outlined and principles enshrined in the 2016 and 2018 Joint Declarations.  We will work jointly to raise the level of NATO-EU ambition in order to further strengthen this mutually reinforcing key strategic partnership. </li></ol>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/15/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-national-strategy-for-countering-domestic-terrorism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 14:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (June 14, 2021) 7:06 P.M. EDT&#160;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Hello, everybody.&#160; This is [senior administration official].&#160; Thank you very much for making time to talk tonight as we approach the release of the first National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism tomorrow morning.&#160;&#160;As you&#8217;ll recall, President Biden indicated that we would be releasing this strategy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(June 14, 2021)</p>



<p>7:06 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hello, everybody.&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you very much for making time to talk tonight as we approach the release of the first National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism tomorrow morning.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you&#8217;ll recall, President Biden indicated that we would be releasing this strategy in his remarks in Tulsa recently.&nbsp; And so what I&#8217;m going to give you tonight is a sense of how we have done this work and what the main lines of effort are in the national strategy that will be released tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Since January 20th, the President has focused on addressing the elevated threat of domestic terrorism.&nbsp; And he has been equally focused on ensuring that our efforts to counter it take place within the context of upholding American civil rights and civil liberties.&nbsp; Those are the very freedoms that make us unique.<br>&nbsp;<br>He has discussed this issue many times with key Cabinet members, including with Attorney General Garland, Homeland Security Secretary Mayorkas, Secretary of Defense Austin, Secretary of State Blinken, and others.&nbsp; And he has emphasized the necessity to conduct this work in a way that never undermines those freedoms, those values, and those legal guardrails.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In order to get objective and fast at &#8212; in order to get an objective and fact-based review of the threats that we face, President Biden tasked the intelligence and law enforcement communities during his first week in office to produce a comprehensive assessment of today&#8217;s domestic violent extremist threat.&nbsp; The goal underpinning that assessment was to establish a factual basis about the risk that domestic terrorists pose upon which we could then formulate a strategy and an implementation plan for countering domestic terrorism.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>An unclassified summary of that baseline study was released in March, and it found that domestic violent extremists, motivated by a range of ideologies, pose an elevated threat to our country in 2021, with racially or ethnically motivated violent extremists &#8212; and specifically those who espouse the superiority of the white race &#8212; and anti-government militia violent extremists posing the most lethal threat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Further, it found that violent extremists to promote the superiority of the white race have the most persistent transnational connections and may be in frequent contact with violent extremists abroad.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>However, it&#8217;s important to underscore that the study provided to us by ODNI did not find a robust nexus between domestic terrorism and foreign actors.&nbsp; This is largely today an inside-out problem, not an outside-in problem, although we do know that our adversaries are seeking to sow divisions in our society.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The strategy, which builds upon this fact-based assessment, seeks to organize U.S. government efforts to counter domestic terrorism into four pillars.&nbsp; This overarching goal is the prevention, disruption, and deterrence of domestic terrorism.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I&#8217;ll do now is outline for you the main lines of effort in these four pillars.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The first pillar seeks to understand and analyze and share domestic-terrorism-related information.&nbsp; It builds directly off of the ODNI threat assessment that I described.&nbsp; Our goal is to enhance domestic terrorism analysis and improve information sharing throughout law enforcement at the federal, state, local, Tribal, and territorial level, and where appropriate with private sector partners.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Department of Justice and the Federal Bureau of Investigation has implemented a new system to methodically track domestic terrorism cases nationwide.&nbsp; The Department of State, as well as the intelligence and law enforcement communities, will continue to learn more from foreign partners about the international dimensions of this threat.<br>&nbsp;<br>Pillar two involves the prevention of domestic terrorism recruitment and mobilization to violence.&nbsp; Drawing on the expertise of a variety of federal departments and agencies, we will work with communities to help them become more resilient to prevent individuals from ever reaching the point of committing terrorist violence.&nbsp; To do this, we&#8217;ll be strengthening domestic terrorism prevention resources and services.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For the first time, the Department of Homeland Security has designated domestic violent extremism as a national priority area within the Department of Homeland Security grant program. &nbsp;And that means that more than $77 million will be allocated to state and local and other partners to prevent, protect against, and respond to domestic violent extremism.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, the Department of Defense is incorporating training for servicemembers separating or retiring from the military, who may potentially be targeted by those who seek to radicalize them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We will work to improve public awareness of federal resources to address concerning or threatening behavior before violence occurs.&nbsp; And on that, I would just note that one of the things we&#8217;re talking about is the need to do something in this space, like the “See something” &#8212; “If you see something, say something” concept that has been promulgated previously by DHS.&nbsp; This involves creating contexts in which those who are family members or friends or co-workers know that there are pathways and avenues to raise concerns and seek help for those who they have perceived to be radicalizing and potentially radicalizing towards violence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We will also be (inaudible) efforts to address online terrorist recruitment and mobilization to violence through increased information sharing with the technology sector and through the creation of innovative approaches to fostering digital literacy and building resilience to terrorist recruitment and mobilization.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One of the principal tools now at our disposal is our decision to join the Christchurch Call to Action to Eliminate Terrorist and Violent Extremist Content Online.&nbsp; This is an international partnership between governments and technology companies that works to develop new solutions to eliminating terrorist content online while safeguarding the freedom of online expression.&nbsp; The previous administration had decided against participation in this important endeavor, and we determined that it was in our interest to join it and to work collaboratively with countries that share our values and the private sector in countering these pernicious developments in which online platforms are used to promote radicalization and violence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Pillar three involves the disruption and deterrence of domestic terrorist activity.&nbsp; The work of federal law enforcement, as well as our state, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement partners, is critical to countering domestic terrorism.&nbsp; The U.S. government will increase support to these law enforcement partners in addressing domestic terrorism nationwide.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>U.S. attorney&#8217;s offices and FBI field offices across the country have formally made domestic terrorism a top priority and are tracking comprehensively domestic-terrorism-related cases, reallocating or requesting appropriate funding and resources as needed to target the threat.&nbsp; That includes over $100 million in additional resources for the Department of Justice, the FBI, and the Department of Homeland Security that are included in the President&#8217;s fiscal year 2022 budget to ensure that we have the analysts, investigators, prosecutors, and other personnel, and resources that we need to thwart domestic terrorism and bring domestic terrorists to justice when the law has been broken.&nbsp; State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement will have access to increased intelligence sharing and training on domestic terrorism and associated threats as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Within the federal government, we have a special responsibility to ensure that we address the possibility of insider threats, especially among those who have the opportunity to be working in law enforcement or in the military.&nbsp; The Office of Personnel Management will consider updates to the forms used to apply for sensitive roles in the federal government that could assist investigators in identifying potential domestic terrorism threats.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Department of Defense, Department of Justice, and Homeland Security Department are similarly pursuing efforts to ensure that domestic terrorists are not employed within our military or law enforcement ranks, and that they improve their screening and vetting processes.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Training and resources will be developed for state, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement partners, as well as for sensitive private sector partners, to enable them to enhance their own employee screening program and to prevent individuals, who pose domestic terrorism threats, from being placed in positions of trust.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The fourth pillar of this strategy involves confronting long-term contributors to domestic terrorism.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important to recognize that there are broader efforts that must be pursued in tandem to the work that we will do specifically to counter the domestic terrorism challenge.&nbsp; This work has to happen in parallel to the strategy to address some of the long-term drivers and enablers of domestic terrorism, including economic inequality, those who feel left behind by the 21st century economy, structural racism, and the proliferation of guns.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That is work that will be data across our administration over the years of our time in service and will be an essential contributor to the outcomes that we seek on this front.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So with that, I&#8217;m going to hand the mic over to [senior administration official] and ask if he has any additional remarks that he wants to make before we open this up to questions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, thank you.&nbsp; I appreciate people joining and I&#8217;ll hand it back to [senior administration official] to facilitate questions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; We can turn it back over to the moderator now for Q&amp;A.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, there.&nbsp; Thanks so much for having the call.&nbsp; Hopefully you can hear me.&nbsp; I wanted to &#8212; so, a couple of questions.&nbsp; One, you mentioned the request the Biden administration has made through the budgetary process.&nbsp; I mean, is this strategy basically acknowledging that the federal government does need to hire, recruit, you know, additional investigators, analysts, and prosecutors in order to really combat this issue?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Secondly, I know there was some talk earlier about potentially examining the authorities around the no-fly list and adding some extremist groups to those lists.&nbsp; Can you provide us an update on that as well?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then I&#8217;m hoping you can just provide a bit more specifics in terms of the relationship with tech companies.&nbsp; We often hear that a lot &#8212; that the government is trying to work with social media companies. &nbsp;What is being done specifically?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thank you for the questions.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll take them in order.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>To start out, I think what the budget request, as well as the strategy document, reflects is a sense that this threat is &#8212; as the professionals and experts in our government conveyed in that March assessment and at other opportunities &#8212; is elevated.&nbsp; That’s their word, not mine.&nbsp; And that tackling it means ensuring that we do have the resources and personnel to address that elevated threat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That, of course, can&#8217;t wait for the process of ensuring that we get additional resources, recruiting and training individuals; that is already happening.&nbsp; And, of course, you see manifestations of that, including in the pretty extraordinary pace and scope of work done by investigators and prosecutors in the wake of the January 6 events.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the sense that this threat is going to remain persistent, that we will continue to step up and augment our efforts to address it, I think is captured, in part, by that budget request, by the strategy, and by the desire to ensure that FBI &#8212; as well as broader DOJ and DHS, among others &#8212; have the personnel and resources they need to tackle this threat specifically, even while addressing international terrorism and all the other threats they&#8217;re charged with protecting Americans from.<br>&nbsp;<br>On your second question: The strategy will have a brief mention of the sort of watch-listing issue that you flagged.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll say that the strategy and our work under it leaves in place preexisting law and preexisting policy in this area while clarifying what its implementation means in light of the current threat environment.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, what I mean by that is this: When individuals who meet the existing standards &#8212; meaning, known or suspected terrorists with international connectivity &#8212; when they meet those standards, they will be considered for appropriate watch-listing, regardless of their ideology.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s the goal here, is being ideologically neutral.&nbsp; And those who pose a threat to public safety and air travel, or other forms of public safety, meet the relevant thresholds, whatever their particular political motivation, ideological motivation might be &#8212; we want to ensure we&#8217;re offering the necessary protection from the threat they might pose.<br>&nbsp;<br>That ideological neutrality is being carried across the watch-listing enterprise while also leaving in place the sort of mechanisms for anyone who believes an error has been committed &#8212; the redress procedures available to individuals in appropriate circumstances to seek a correction if they believe one is appropriate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, you asked about tech companies, and it&#8217;s an important part of the strategy because a great deal of the relevant recruitment, radicalization, mobilization to violence does happen online.&nbsp; Again, that&#8217;s not me saying that; that&#8217;s the experts and professionals who assessed that in that March 2021 report assessment and continue to assess that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there are a number of ways in which we&#8217;re trying to augment our efforts to get at that challenge.&nbsp; One is by enhancing, augmenting the information-sharing the government does with tech companies so as to facilitate their more assertive voluntary enforcement of their terms of service on their platforms to protect other users from those who might pose threats of violence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We, as a government, see different things from what any particular tech company might see.&nbsp; Any particular tech company often knows its own platform very well.&nbsp; But the government sees things &#8212; actually, threats of violence &#8212; across platforms.&nbsp; They see the relationship between online recruitment, radicalization, and violence in the physical world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, helping to illuminate these threats is a process that has already begun between the government and the tech sector.&nbsp; And it will continue, again, specifically on this issue set, given the priority we’re placing in addressing it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The second piece of this is, as [senior administration official] mentioned, our recent endorsement of the Christchurch Call.&nbsp; That forum allows us to leverage other governments that share our concerns in this area, as well as our commitment to free expression online in addressing some of these challenges with tech companies, and doing so with civil society stakeholders fully integrated into the conversation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then the third piece I&#8217;ll flag in this area &#8212; and this gets mentioned in the strategy as well &#8212; is fostering programming that can build digital literacy and other forms of resilience to domestic terrorist recruitment online and, frankly, other forms of malicious content online that bad actors deliberately try to disseminate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You&#8217;ve seen this in DHS’s recent call for grant proposals where they specifically invited digital literacy programming.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ll see other efforts in this area to try to help build that digital fitness across the (inaudible).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much for doing this.&nbsp; The strategy mentions that the Defense Department is reviewing it and updating its definition of “prohibited extremist activities.”&nbsp; So we&#8217;re clear: Does that mean the Defense Department is looking into whether participating in an extremist group is grounds for separation?&nbsp; Because right now, simply being a member of, say, a white supremacist group is not enough to get a service member involuntarily separated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks for the good question.&nbsp; And, obviously, the Defense Department has really shown a lot of leadership on this, starting early in this administration, to ensure that those critical and sensitive positions &#8212; positions of trust that service members and others within the Defense Department hold &#8212; can&#8217;t be abused or exploited for the sort of nefarious purposes that domestic terrorists would like to see them exploited for.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as the strategy indicates, they are relooking at a number of things, and one of those is the one you rightly flag, which is how they understand &#8212; quite literally how they define “extremism” for these purposes.&nbsp; They are working that quite hard, both as a policy matter with the security experts and with lawyers at the Defense Department and elsewhere, to ensure they&#8217;re doing this in a way they feel ratchets up the protections but also respects expression and association protections, again, for service members and for others.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I know that they will have more to say as they complete their review.&nbsp; But in a sense, the work &#8212; the critical work that they&#8217;re doing through their Countering Extremism Working Group is something of an implementing arm within the Defense Department for the overall U.S. government&#8217;s strategic approach that you&#8217;ll see laid out (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for the opportunity.&nbsp; I wonder if you could talk a little bit about why this strategy doesn&#8217;t take a position on what may be the biggest public policy question in the domestic terrorism arena, which is whether there should be a new statute criminalizing domestic terrorism.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, also, could you talk about what is going to be the inevitable criticism on the right &#8212; that this strategy calls for using the tools of counterterrorism against, essentially, far-right extremists?&nbsp; Even though you&#8217;re saying it&#8217;s going to be ideologically neutral, we&#8217;re already hearing a lot of rhetoric from Republicans and Trump supporters who fear that that&#8217;s not the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On the first question, the President wanted his Justice Department and his new Attorney General to take a hard look at the question of whether new authorities are necessary based on facts and analysis.&nbsp; And so the strategy request that the Justice Department review this question and come back to him with a recommendation &#8212; based upon that, we can move forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we concluded that we didn&#8217;t have the evidentiary basis yet to decide whether we wanted to proceed in that direction or whether we have sufficient authority, as they currently exist at the federal level in conjunction with possible in all 50 states, to continue as we are currently organized in the pursuit of prosecution in this arena.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, [senior administration official], I’ll let you answer another.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, sure.&nbsp; Thanks for the good questions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, on the second: You know, we have been rigorous here in grounding this work and the work of the experts and the professionals.&nbsp; Their threat assessment that guided us in our strategy and policy development is &#8212; that&#8217;s part of why we ensured that Congress had that threat assessment in full when it was delivered in March, and that the public &#8212; including you all, of course &#8212; had the opportunity at least to see the unclassified executive summary, which establishes that this is a real threat, an elevated threat, in the words of those professionals, and that therefore formulating a strategy to tackle it makes sense.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we have been rigorous not just in the crafting of the strategy, but also in its implementation, which is well underway, in remaining laser-focused on violence and the threat of violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is a strategy that is agnostic as to political ideology or off the spectrum.&nbsp; What matters is when individuals take their political or other grievances and turn that &#8212; unacceptably, unlawfully &#8212; into violent action.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where it comes within the sway of &#8212; so, in the document, that&#8217;s where it&nbsp;becomes something that is &#8212; deemed domestic terrorism, it requires the sort of response that cannot only protect public safety, but in a sense, protect threats to our democratic integrity.<br>&nbsp;<br>You&#8217;ll notice,&nbsp;in the document, that when we list some of the recent incidents that speak to the elevated threat level, that they come across the political spectrum.&nbsp; We acknowledge the shooting at the Congressional baseball game, the attack on police officers in Dallas, just as we acknowledge the attack in Charlottesville and the attack on the Capitol on January 6th.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it&#8217;s not motivating politics or ideology that matters for us or, more importantly, for the strategy and implementation; it&#8217;s when political grievances become acts of violence.&nbsp; And we remain laser-focused on that, and that&#8217;s how we&#8217;ll continue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys, thanks very much.&nbsp; Two questions &#8212; one on the Pentagon.&nbsp; You talked about how the Pentagon is going to be training for those departing the military.&nbsp; The services have resisted some of that training and some of that acknowledgement that there&#8217;s a threat.&nbsp; Can you talk about whether you think this strategy overcomes that resistance, or you think that resistance is lowering?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then to zoom out a little bit and talk about a question that the Europeans are asking about the current trip: A lot of experts in this space say that, you know, there have been people focused on this issue for years, and they just haven&#8217;t had the political top cover in the last few years.&nbsp; You&#8217;re obviously trying to provide that political top cover now.&nbsp; What guarantee can you try and make that that political top cover will outlast these four years?&nbsp; Thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On the first question: Look, Secretary Austin has made this a priority, and as you know, the Pentagon is one of the most disciplined and hierarchical organizations in the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, the efforts to pursue this in a rigorous way, to develop a plan that will enable the Department of Defense to ensure that if people are both, as they are recruited into the military and as they leave the military, and within those two bounds, when they&#8217;re in the military &#8212; that they are people who are worthy of the role of a military member if &#8212; and to, when they leave, are not preyed upon &#8212; is something that we trust that all those who are leading the services will support, if that&#8217;s the direction that the Secretary of Defense asked them to move.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And on the second: Look, we have based this strategy on hard evidence.&nbsp; And what we will continue to do, as I indicated at the outset, is provide the facts, as they&#8217;re developed, to our country, to American citizens, to understand what we&#8217;re up against here and to do our work to counter, as [senior administration official] just said, those who seek to use violence to achieve their political ends.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that is going to be a project for us for the foreseeable future and in which we are investing many agencies of the government and resourcing them appropriately and asking our citizens to participate.&nbsp; Because, ultimately, this is really about homeland security being a responsibility of each citizen of our country to help us achieve.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, we will do our very best in the years that we have in service and seek to embed this pattern of action and behavior in a way that will create conditions of public safety and, at the same time, ensure that people can express their political views as is appropriate in a democracy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; On page 18 of the strategy document, it talks about finding ways to identify and analyze financial activity associated with domestic terrorists, including those through existing provisions of the Bank Secrecy Act.&nbsp; I&#8217;m curious what specifically would you be doing with the Bank Secrecy Act.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks for the question.&nbsp; And, look, the Treasury Department has, under the Bank Secrecy Act and otherwise, some important authorities that help them be a part of the overall U.S. government approach to understanding illicit financial flows.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something we have tried to bring to bear with respect to counterterrorism, generally.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a significant part of how we&#8217;ve made some progress in addressing international terrorist threats, like al Qaeda and ISIS and others since 9/11.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as we ensure that we are bringing the full suite of tools &#8212; the appropriate ones &#8212; to bear on the domestic terrorism problem, there is, of course, the possibility that there may be those sorts of financial flows be identified, and once identified, the possibility they can be disrupted.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So that is, as with a number of pieces of this strategy, something whose full impact, I think, we&#8217;ll see as we move forward with implementation.&nbsp; (Inaudible) emphasize implementation is well underway, but in some ways, it takes time to see which pieces pay the biggest dividends.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think what that is an acknowledgement of in the strategy is the role that Treasury can help play in identifying when funds are being used in illicit ways to support this, ultimately, unlawful activity.&nbsp; And to the extent that&#8217;s determined to be happening, they and law enforcement have various tools at their disposal to clamp down on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I want to thank you all for joining us.&nbsp; We have to hop off now.&nbsp; Attorney General Garland will speak tomorrow morning at 11:00 a.m.&nbsp; I hope you&#8217;ll be able to tune into his speech.&nbsp; And other members of the Cabinet will also be participating in various events.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thanks again, and look forward to talking soon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>7:35 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden, President of the European Council Charles Michel, and President of the European Commission Ursula von der Leyen Before the U.S.-EU Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/15/remarks-by-president-biden-president-of-the-european-council-charles-michel-and-president-of-the-european-commission-ursula-von-der-leyen-before-the-u-s-eu-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 14:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Europa Building, European CouncilBrussels, Belgium 12:13 P.M. CEST PRESIDENT MICHEL: &#160;Well, Mr. President, dear Joe, we are so pleased to welcome you in Brussels. &#160;You are back in Brussels, and America is back on the global scene. &#160;It’s great news. &#160;It’s great news for our Alliance. &#160;It’s also great news for the world. &#160;And we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Europa Building, European Council<br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>12:13 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT MICHEL: &nbsp;Well, Mr. President, dear Joe, we are so pleased to welcome you in Brussels. &nbsp;You are back in Brussels, and America is back on the global scene. &nbsp;It’s great news. &nbsp;It’s great news for our Alliance. &nbsp;It’s also great news for the world. &nbsp;And we are really delighted to work with you in order to tackle, together, some important global challenges.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: &nbsp;Well, I think we have a great opportunity to work both with the EU, as well as NATO. &nbsp;And we’re &#8212; we&#8217;re feeling very good about it. &nbsp;We found the reception to be good, and I &#8212; and America is back. &nbsp;</p>



<p>We are &#8212; (inaudible) we&#8217;ve never fully left, but we are reasserting the fact that it’s overwhelmingly in the interest of the United States of America to have a great relationship with NATO and with the EU. &nbsp;I have a very different view than my predecessor did. &nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I’m looking forward to talking with you all about what we&#8217;re about to do, and &#8212; and I&#8217;m anxious to begin.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN: &nbsp;And a very warm welcome for my part, too. &nbsp;What a pleasure to have you here. &nbsp;What an honor to have you here. &nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the fact that you are coming so early in your mandate, I think, underlines your personal attachment to Europe, and we really appreciate that.</p>



<p>And indeed, the last four years have not been easy. &nbsp;The world has dramatically changed. &nbsp;Europe has changed. &nbsp;But we wanted to reassure you: We are friends and allies and we are very much looking forward to working together. &nbsp;(Inaudible.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: &nbsp;Well, what a great opportunity. &nbsp;(Inaudible.) &nbsp;Thank you.</p>



<p>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Mr. President, did you agree on a Turkish presence in Afghanistan?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: &nbsp;Did I agree on a &#8212; what?</p>



<p>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Turkish presence in Afghanistan, after you met with Mr. Erdoğan yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: &nbsp;Did I agree on a Turkish &#8212;</p>



<p>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Did you discuss or agree on any kind of Turkish presence in Afghanistan after your withdrawal?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: &nbsp;Oh, we had &#8212; we had long discussions, and I feel very good about our meeting. &nbsp;And I’ll let the &#8212; I’ll let the Turks tell you about it.</p>



<p>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Mr. President, do you have an agreement on Airbus and Boeing?</p>



<p>(The President crosses his fingers.)</p>



<p>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Mr. President, what do you like about EU the most?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: &nbsp;I like the presidents. &nbsp;(Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>12:16 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on Agreement with the European Union on Boeing-Airbus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-agreement-with-the-european-union-on-boeing-airbus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 13:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20951</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the United States and the European Union made a major breakthrough in the Boeing-Airbus trade dispute, which has lasted more than 16 years. Both the U.S. and EU agreed to suspend our tariffs for five years, and we committed to ensuring a level playing field for our companies and our workers. Significantly, we also&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the United States and the European Union made a major breakthrough in the Boeing-Airbus trade dispute, which has lasted more than 16 years. Both the U.S. and EU agreed to suspend our tariffs for five years, and we committed to ensuring a level playing field for our companies and our workers. Significantly, we also agreed to work together to challenge and counter China’s non-market practices in this sector that give China&#8217;s companies an unfair advantage. The U.S. and EU will work together in specific ways that reflect our high standards, including collaborating on inward and outbound investment and technology transfer. It’s a model we can build on for other challenges posed by China’s economic model.<br><br>This week, at the G7, at NATO, in my meeting with the leaders of the European Union, and in all my bilateral meetings with world leaders, I’ve been making the case that the U.S. and Europe—and democracies everywhere—are stronger when we work together to advance our shared values like fair competition and transparency. Today&#8217;s announcement demonstrates exactly how that can work in practice.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: U.S. – EU Understanding on a Cooperative Framework for Large Civil Aircraft</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/fact-sheet-u-s-eu-understanding-on-a-cooperative-framework-for-large-civil-aircraft/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 13:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[United States and EU Reach Agreement to Address Shared Challenges from China At the outset of his trip, the President was clear that his goal was to demonstrate the capacity of democracies to both meet the challenges and deter the threats of this new age. And, he was clear that he wanted to demonstrate that the United States could&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>United States and EU Reach Agreement to Address Shared Challenges from China</em></p>



<p><br>At the outset of his trip, the President was clear that his goal was to demonstrate the capacity of democracies to both meet the challenges and deter the threats of this new age. And, he was clear that he wanted to demonstrate that the United States could lead the world’s democracies in a foreign policy for the middle class. Today’s announcement that the US and European Union (EU) have reached an agreement in the Boeing-Airbus dispute and agreed to address shared challenges from China does just that. The US and EU will suspend tariffs for five years and work together to challenge and counter China’s non-market practices in this sector in specific ways that reflect our standards for fair competition. This includes collaboration on inward and outbound investment and tech transfer.  <br><br>Today’s agreement represents a model the US can build on for other challenges posed by China. The President routinely says that we are strongest when we work with our friends and allies — today’s announcement is a demonstration of that in action. <br><br>And, this deal will shore up the longer-term competitiveness and innovation of a key sector that is one of most important sources of middle-class jobs at home. The aerospace sector employs over 500,000 workers directly and supports over 700,000 jobs in related industries. Boeing itself employs over 140,000 workers across all 50 states. Through its supply chain, it purchases over a billion parts from over ten thousand American businesses.<br><br>The US and the EU are home to 780 million people who share democratic values and the largest economic relationship in the world. Together, we wrote the rules of the road based on democratic values, fair competition, and transparency after World War II and we need to work together to update these rules. This announcement comes on the day of the US-EU Summit, an opportunity to rebuild U.S.-EU ties, raise the ambition of the relationship, and commit to working together on the global stage.<br><br>The United States and the European Union agreed to a framework to promote a level playing field, overcome longstanding differences, and address common challenges — including our shared concerns with China’s unfair and coercive economic practices. The strengthening of our trade and investment relationship with the European Union is a top priority for the Administration, and our early efforts have been successful.<br><br>Both sides agreed to the following general principles to guide their future cooperation:<br><br><strong>Suspend the tariffs related to this dispute for five years. </strong>This signals a mutual determination to embark on a fresh start in the relationship. The agreement also retains flexibility for the United States to reapply tariffs if we’re no longer competing on a level playing field. <br><br><strong>Establish a Working Group to analyze and overcome any disagreements that may arise between the sides.</strong> The Working Group will collaborate on and continue discussing and developing these principles and appropriate actions. The Trade Ministers leading the Working Group will consult at least yearly. The Working Group will meet on request or at least every 6months.<br><br><strong>Ensure that our workers and industries can compete on a level playing field.</strong> The U.S. and EU agreed to clear statements on acceptable support for large civil aircraft producers that affirm the outcomes of the disputes and the intention of the parties to ensure that our workers and industries can compete on a level playing field.<br><br><strong>Confront the threat we face from China’s ambitions to build a sector upon non-market practices, including:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Meaningful cooperation on&nbsp;countering&nbsp;(1) investments in the EU and the United States by non-market actors, which can lead to the appropriation of technology; and (2) outward investments into China that are influenced by non-market forces.&nbsp;<br></li><li>Identifying where joint work is needed to take parallel action against non-market practices.<br></li><li>Sharing information regarding these and other areas&nbsp;to forge a common approach&nbsp;in the large civil aircraft sector.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
