<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:50:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20021</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Rufus Gifford, of Massachusetts, to be Chief of Protocol, and to have the rank of Ambassador during his tenure of service, vice Sean P. Lawler, resigned. &#160; &#160; &#160;Grant T. Harris, of California, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce, vice Nazakhtar Nikakhtar. &#160; &#160; &#160;Neil Harvey MacBride,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Rufus Gifford, of Massachusetts, to be Chief of Protocol, and to have the rank of Ambassador during his tenure of service, vice Sean P. Lawler, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Grant T. Harris, of California, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce, vice Nazakhtar Nikakhtar.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Neil Harvey MacBride, of Virginia, to be General Counsel for the Department of the Treasury, vice Brian Callanan.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Caral E. Spangler, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Army, vice John E. Whitley.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Larry D. Turner, of North Carolina, to be Inspector General, Department of Labor, vice Scott S. Dahl, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;David Weil, of Massachusetts, to be Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division, Department of Labor, vice Cheryl Marie Stanton.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp; &nbsp; ###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Executive Order Blocking Property and Suspending Entry Into the United States of Certain Persons Contributing to the Destabilizing Situation in the Western Balkans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/fact-sheet-executive-order-blocking-property-and-suspending-entry-into-the-united-states-of-certain-persons-contributing-to-the-destabilizing-situation-in-the-western-balkans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20015</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order to further address the ongoing national emergency declared in Executive Order (E.O.) 13219 of June 26, 2001, and continued in E.O. 13304 of May 28, 2003, related to the Western Balkans.&#160; Today’s E.O. provides additional sanctions authorities, including to target individuals who threaten the peace, security, stability, or&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order to further address the ongoing national emergency declared in Executive Order (E.O.) 13219 of June 26, 2001, and continued in E.O. 13304 of May 28, 2003, related to the Western Balkans.&nbsp; Today’s E.O. provides additional sanctions authorities, including to target individuals who threaten the peace, security, stability, or territorial integrity of any area or state in the Western Balkans as well as those responsible for or complicit in, or who have directly or indirectly engaged in, serious human rights abuse in the Western Balkans, among other things.&nbsp; The E.O. the President is signing today builds on the existing national emergency and expands the designation criteria, to address such challenges as corruption, and other actions that obstruct key institutions and international agreements. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Corruption anywhere directly damages the foreign policy, national security, and economic health of the United States and our partners and allies.&nbsp; That is why the United States is committed to promoting accountability and combating impunity for those involved in significant corruption in the Western Balkans and throughout the world.&nbsp; By definition, corruption serves the interests of those few who engage in it, lining their own pockets and accountable only to their own personal interests, not the interests of a country or its people.&nbsp; Corruption saps economic growth, facilitates organized crime, and undermines confidence in democratic processes.&nbsp; These forces open the door for our strategic adversaries to undermine democracy, stymie progress toward effective and accountable governance and prevent the Western Balkans region from achieving full integration into transatlantic institutions.&nbsp; They allow individuals to exploit weak rule of law and to profit from systemic corruption at the expense of ordinary citizens.&nbsp; They thereby constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Specifically, the E.O. the President is signing today:</p>



<ul><li>Underscores the United States’ longstanding commitment to implementation of the post-war agreements and institutions established following the breakup of the former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia;<br></li><li>Expands sanctions designation criteria to include activities, among others, related to:&nbsp; threatening the peace, security, stability, or territorial integrity of any area or state in the Western Balkans; undermining democratic processes or institutions in the Western Balkans; engaging in serious human rights abuse in the Western Balkans; and engaging in corruption related to the Western Balkans;<br></li><li>Expands our ability to target actors engaged in a violation of, or an act that has obstructed or threatened the implementation of, any regional security, peace, cooperation, or mutual recognition agreement or framework or accountability mechanism related to the Western Balkans beyond previous E.O.s, to include the Prespa Agreement, the Conclusions of the Peace Implementation Conference, and the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals, the successor to the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia; and<br></li><li>Clarifies that the geographic scope of the Western Balkans includes the territory of&nbsp;the former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia and the Republic of Albania.</li></ul>



<p>All property and interests in property of persons designated pursuant to this E.O. that are or come within the United States or the possession or control of U.S. persons are blocked, and U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in transactions with them.&nbsp; In addition, individuals sanctioned under this E.O. will be banned from entering the United States or holding a U.S. visa.&nbsp; Ensuring the security and political stability of the Western Balkans region is consistent with the Biden Administration’s commitment to advancing core U.S. national security interests, including the protection of democratic institutions. &nbsp;The Administration will continue to address the challenges in the region head on.&nbsp; The Department of the Treasury, in consultation with the Department of State will continue to update the list of individuals subject to sanctions under this order.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House and President Pro Tempore of the Senate Regarding the War Powers Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-and-president-pro-tempore-of-the-senate-regarding-the-war-powers-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20009</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Mr. President:) I am providing this supplemental consolidated report, prepared by my Administration and consistent with the War Powers Resolution (Public Law 93-148), as part of my efforts to keep the Congress informed about deployments of United States Armed Forces equipped for combat. MILITARY OPERATIONS IN SUPPORT OF UNITED STATES COUNTERTERRORISM&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Mr. President:)<br><br>I am providing this supplemental consolidated report, prepared by my Administration and consistent with the War Powers Resolution (Public Law 93-148), as part of my efforts to keep the Congress informed about deployments of United States Armed Forces equipped for combat.<br><br>MILITARY OPERATIONS IN SUPPORT OF UNITED STATES COUNTERTERRORISM EFFORTS<br><br>In furtherance of counterterrorism efforts, the United States continues to work with partners around the globe, with a particular focus on the United States Central and Africa Commands&#8217; areas of responsibility.&nbsp; In this context, the United&nbsp;States has deployed forces to conduct counterterrorism operations and to advise, assist, and accompany security forces of select foreign partners on counterterrorism operations.&nbsp; In the majority of these locations, the mission of United States military personnel is to facilitate counterterrorism operations of foreign partner forces and does not include routine engagement in combat.&nbsp; In many of these locations, the security environment is such that United States military personnel may be required to defend themselves against threats or attacks, and, to that end, the United States may deploy United States military personnel with weapons and other appropriate equipment&nbsp;for force protection.&nbsp; Specific information about counterterrorism deployments to select countries is provided below, and a classified annex to this report provides further information.<br><br>Military Operations Against al-Qa&#8217;ida, the Taliban, and Associated Forces and in Support of Related United States Counterterrorism Objectives<br><br>Since October 7, 2001, United States Armed Forces, including Special Operations Forces, have conducted counterterrorism combat operations against al-Qa&#8217;ida, the Taliban, and associated forces. &nbsp;Since August 2014, these operations have targeted the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS), also known as the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), which was formerly known as al-Qa&#8217;ida in Iraq.&nbsp; In support of these and other overseas operations, the United States has deployed combat-equipped forces to several locations in the United States Central, European, Africa, Southern, and Indo-Pacific Commands&#8217; areas of responsibility.&nbsp; Such operations and deployments have been reported previously, consistent with Public Law 107-40, Public Law 107-243, the War Powers Resolution, and other statutes.&nbsp; These ongoing operations, which the United States has&nbsp;carried out with the assistance of numerous international partners, have been successful in seriously degrading ISIS capabilities in Syria and Iraq.&nbsp; If necessary, in response to terrorist threats, I will direct additional measures to protect the people and interests of the United States.&nbsp; It is not possible to know at this time the precise scope or the duration of the deployments of United States Armed Forces that are or&nbsp;will be necessary to counter terrorist threats to the United&nbsp;States.<br><br><strong>Afghanistan.</strong>&nbsp; On April 14, 2021, I directed the withdrawal of United States forces from Afghanistan starting on May 1, 2021, and concluding by September 11, 2021.&nbsp; Since May 1, 2021, we have been withdrawing United States forces in a safe, deliberate, and responsible manner and in full coordination with&nbsp;our partners and allies in Afghanistan.&nbsp; Additionally, we&nbsp;are making plans to ensure the security of our diplomats who&nbsp;may remain in Afghanistan, while also re-organizing our counterterrorism capabilities outside Afghanistan to address threats to the United&nbsp;States homeland and United States interests that may arise from inside Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Iraq and Syria.</strong>&nbsp; As part of a comprehensive strategy to defeat ISIS, United States Armed Forces are working by, with, and through local partners in conducting airstrikes and other necessary operations against ISIS forces in Iraq and Syria and against al-Qa&#8217;ida in Syria.&nbsp; A small presence of United States Armed Forces remains in strategically significant locations in Syria to conduct operations, in partnership with indigenous ground forces, to address continuing terrorist threats emanating from Syria.&nbsp; United States Armed Forces in Iraq continue to advise, coordinate with, and provide support to select elements of the Iraqi security forces, including Iraqi Kurdish security forces. &nbsp;Support to Iraqi security forces includes training, equipment, communications support, and intelligence support.&nbsp; United States Armed Forces also provide limited support to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization mission in Iraq.&nbsp; Actions in Iraq are being undertaken in coordination with the Government of Iraq and the Kurdistan Regional Government, and in conjunction with coalition partners.<br><br>As reported in February 2021, I directed a targeted military strike against infrastructure in eastern Syria used by Iran‑supported non-state militia groups.&nbsp; Those non-state militia groups were involved in attacks against United States and Coalition personnel in Iraq.&nbsp; These groups were also engaged in ongoing planning for future such attacks.&nbsp; I directed this action consistent with my responsibility to protect United States citizens both at home and abroad and in furtherance of United States national security interests, pursuant to my constitutional authority to conduct United States foreign relations and as Commander in Chief and Chief Executive.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Arabian Peninsula Region.&nbsp; </strong>A small number of United States military personnel are deployed to Yemen to conduct operations against al-Qa&#8217;ida in the Arabian Peninsula and ISIS.&nbsp; The United States military continues to work closely with the Government of the Republic of Yemen and regional partner forces to degrade the terrorist threat posed by those groups.<br><br>I have directed an end to United States support for the Saudi‑led Coalition&#8217;s offensive military operations against the&nbsp;Houthis in Yemen.&nbsp; United States Armed Forces, in a non‑combat role, continue to provide military advice and limited information to regional forces for defensive and training purposes only as they relate to the Saudi-led Coalition&#8217;s campaign against the Houthis in Yemen.&nbsp; Such support does not involve United States Armed Forces in hostilities with the Houthis for the purposes of the War Powers Resolution.<br><br>United States Armed Forces are deployed to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia to protect United States forces and interests in&nbsp;the region against hostile action by Iran or Iran-backed groups.&nbsp; These forces, operating in coordination with the Government of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, provide air and missile defense capabilities and support the operation of&nbsp;United&nbsp;States fighter aircraft.&nbsp; The total number of United&nbsp;States forces in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia is approximately 2,742.<br><br><strong>Jordan.&nbsp; </strong>At the request of the Government of Jordan, approximately 2,976 United States military personnel are deployed to Jordan to support Defeat-ISIS operations, to enhance Jordan&#8217;s security, and to promote regional stability.<br><br><strong>Lebanon.&nbsp; </strong>At the request of the Government of Lebanon, approximately 83 United States military personnel are deployed&nbsp;to Lebanon to enhance the government&#8217;s counterterrorism capabilities and to support the counterterrorism operations of Lebanese security forces.<br><br><strong>Turkey.&nbsp; </strong>United States Armed Forces remain deployed to Turkey, at the Turkish government&#8217;s request, to support Defeat-ISIS operations and to enhance Turkey&#8217;s security.<br><br><strong>East Africa Region.&nbsp; </strong>At the direction of the prior administration, the majority of United States forces in Somalia redeployed or repositioned to neighboring countries prior to my inauguration as President.&nbsp; United States Armed Forces based outside Somalia continue to counter the terrorist threat posed by ISIS and al-Shabaab, an associated force of al-Qa&#8217;ida, in Somalia.&nbsp; Since the last periodic report, United States forces have conducted a small number of airstrikes against al-Shabaab, and remain prepared to conduct airstrikes against ISIS and al‑Shabaab terrorists. &nbsp;United States military personnel conduct periodic engagements in Somalia to train, advise, and assist regional forces, including Somali and African Union Mission in&nbsp;Somalia forces, during counterterrorism operations.&nbsp; United&nbsp;States Armed Forces are deployed to Kenya to support counterterrorism operations in East Africa. &nbsp;United States military personnel continue to partner with the Government of Djibouti, which has permitted use of Djiboutian territory for basing of United States Armed Forces.&nbsp; United States military personnel remain deployed to Djibouti, including for purposes of staging for counterterrorism and counter-piracy operations in the vicinity of the Horn of Africa and the Arabian Peninsula, and to provide contingency support for embassy security augmentation in East Africa, as necessary.<br><br><strong>Lake Chad Basin and Sahel Region.</strong>&nbsp; United States military personnel in the Lake Chad Basin and Sahel Region continue to conduct airborne intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance operations and to provide support to African and European partners conducting counterterrorism operations in the region, including by advising, assisting, and accompanying these partner forces.&nbsp; Approximately 808 United States military personnel remain deployed to Niger.<br><br><strong>Cuba.&nbsp; </strong>United States Armed Forces continue to conduct humane and&nbsp;secure detention operations for detainees held at Guantanamo&nbsp;Bay, Cuba, under the authority provided by the 2001&nbsp;Authorization for the Use of Military Force (Public Law&nbsp;107-40), as informed by the law of war.&nbsp; There are 40&nbsp;such&nbsp;detainees as of the date of this report.<br><br><strong>Philippines.&nbsp; </strong>United States Armed Forces deployed to the Philippines are providing support to the counterterrorism operations of the armed forces of the Philippines.<br><br>MILITARY OPERATIONS IN EGYPT IN SUPPORT OF THE MULTINATIONAL FORCE AND OBSERVERS<br><br>Approximately 379 United States military personnel are assigned&nbsp;to or supporting the United States contingent of the&nbsp;Multinational Force and Observers, which have been present in&nbsp;Egypt since 1981.<br><br>UNITED STATES AND NORTH ATLANTIC TREATY ORGANIZATION OPERATIONS IN KOSOVO<br><br>The United States continues to contribute forces to the Kosovo Force (KFOR), led by the North Atlantic Treaty Organization in cooperation with local authorities, bilateral partners, and international institutions, to deter renewed hostilities in Kosovo.&nbsp; Approximately 707 United States military personnel are&nbsp;among KFOR&#8217;s approximately 4,000 personnel.<br><br>I have directed the participation of United States Armed Forces in all of the above-described operations pursuant to my&nbsp;constitutional and statutory authority as Commander in Chief and as Chief Executive (including the authority to carry out Public Law 107-40, Public Law 107-243, and other statutes), as well as my constitutional and statutory authority to conduct the&nbsp;foreign relations of the United States.&nbsp; Officials of my Administration and I communicate regularly with congressional leadership, relevant congressional committees, and other Members of Congress with regard to these deployments, and we will continue to do so.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Sincerely,<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to Certain Congressional Committees Regarding Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/letter-to-certain-congressional-committees-regarding-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Mr. Chairman: Consistent with section 1215(d) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (Public Law 116-283), I&#160;have&#160;determined that a waiver of the limitation under subsection 1215(a) is important to the national security interests of the&#160;United States. As I announced on April 14, 2021, after almost 20 years,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Mr. Chairman:<br><br>Consistent with section 1215(d) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (Public Law 116-283), I&nbsp;have&nbsp;determined that a waiver of the limitation under subsection 1215(a) is important to the national security interests of the&nbsp;United States.<br><br>As I announced on April 14, 2021, after almost 20 years, it is&nbsp;time to end America&#8217;s longest war and bring our troops home.&nbsp; I&nbsp;reached this conclusion after conducting a rigorous policy review process and consulting closely with our allies and partners, with our military leaders and intelligence personnel, with our diplomats and our development experts, with the Congress and the Vice President, and with the President of Afghanistan and many other leaders around the world.<br><br>We went to Afghanistan in 2001 for a clear and just purpose:&nbsp; to&nbsp;apprehend those who attacked our country on September 11, 2001; to root out al-Qa&#8217;ida; and to prevent future attacks against the United States from Afghanistan.&nbsp; As a Senator, I&nbsp;supported sending our military to Afghanistan for those reasons.&nbsp; Our original mission had overwhelming support in the&nbsp;Congress and our allies and partners rallied to our side and&nbsp;stood with us in Afghanistan.<br><br>We have long since accomplished the objectives that sent us to Afghanistan.&nbsp; It has been 10 years since we delivered justice to&nbsp;Osama bin Laden.&nbsp; The terrorist threat from al-Qa&#8217;ida in Afghanistan is significantly degraded.<br><br>Over the last 20 years, however, the terrorist threat to the United States has become more dispersed around the globe.&nbsp; Keeping thousands of troops concentrated on the ground in Afghanistan no longer makes sense as the most effective counterterrorism strategy when the threat has metastasized across the Middle East, Africa, and Asia.&nbsp; Our focus and posture&nbsp;need to adapt accordingly.<br><br>As we draw down United States troops, we will not take our eye off the&nbsp;terrorist threat in Afghanistan.&nbsp; The United States will reorganize our counterterrorism capabilities and assets in the region to prevent the reemergence of a terrorist threat in Afghanistan.&nbsp; We will hold the Taliban and the Afghan government accountable to their commitments not to allow terrorists to threaten the United&nbsp;States or its allies from Afghan soil. &nbsp;And we will refine our national strategy to monitor and disrupt terrorist threats wherever they arise.<br><br>Over the past few decades, the United States and our partners have trained hundreds of thousands of Afghan troops. &nbsp;The Afghan National Defense and Security Forces currently number close to 300,000, and they will continue to fight valiantly to protect the Afghan citizens. &nbsp;With the support of the Congress, we will continue to support the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces. &nbsp;We will also continue to support the rights of Afghan women and girls and to maintain significant humanitarian and development assistance to Afghanistan.<br><br>We will continue to pursue diplomacy and fully support peace talks between the Government of Afghanistan and the Taliban, facilitated by the United Nations.&nbsp; And we will encourage other nations in the region, especially Pakistan, to do more to support Afghanistan and to support stability in the country.&nbsp; But we will not allow United States troops to be a bargaining chip between warring parties in other countries.&nbsp; That is a recipe for staying indefinitely in Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br><br>We will withdraw responsibly, deliberately, and safely, in full coordination with our allies and partners.&nbsp; Our NATO allies and operational partners, who have stood shoulder-to-shoulder with us for almost 20 years and who have also made great sacrifices, will now withdraw alongside our forces as we stand by our enduring principle of &#8220;in together, out together.&#8221;<br><br>Finally, I want to acknowledge the tremendous debt of gratitude we owe as a Nation to the women and men who have served honorably in Afghanistan since 2001.&nbsp; They and their families have made incredible sacrifices for our Nation that we can never fully repay. I look forward to working with the Congress to continue supporting our forces and veterans and on countering the challenges our Nation faces across the globe.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Sincerely,<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Actions and Policies of Certain Members of the Government of Belarus and other Persons to Undermine Democratic Processes or Institutions of Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/08/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-actions-and-policies-of-certain-members-of-the-government-of-belarus-and-other-persons-to-undermine-democratic-processes-or-ins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On June 16, 2006, by Executive Order 13405, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions and policies of certain members&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On June 16, 2006, by Executive Order 13405, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions and policies of certain members of the Government of&nbsp;Belarus and other persons to undermine Belarus&#8217;s democratic processes or institutions, manifested in the fundamentally undemocratic March 2006 elections; to commit human rights abuses related to political repression, including detentions and disappearances; and to engage in public corruption, including by diverting or misusing Belarusian public assets or by misusing public authority.</p>



<p>The actions and policies of certain members of the Government of Belarus and other persons continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on June 16, 2006, must continue in effect beyond June 16, 2021.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13405.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 8, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Actions and Policies of Certain Members of the Government of Belarus and other Persons to Undermine Democratic Processes or Institutions of Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-actions-and-policies-of-certain-members-of-the-g/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date. &nbsp;In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the actions and policies of certain members of the Government of Belarus and other persons to undermine democratic processes or institutions of Belarus that was declared in Executive Order 13405 of June&nbsp;16, 2006, is&nbsp;to continue in effect beyond June 16, 2021.<br><br>The actions and policies of certain members of the Government of&nbsp;Belarus and other persons to undermine Belarus&#8217;s democratic processes or institutions, to commit human rights abuses related to political repression, and to engage in public corruption continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat&nbsp;to the national security and foreign policy of the United&nbsp;States. &nbsp;Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13405 with respect to Belarus.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Sincerely,<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on Blocking Property And Suspending Entry Into The United States Of Certain Persons Contributing To The Destabilizing Situation In The Western Balkans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-blocking-property-and-suspending-entry-into-the-united-states-of-certain-persons-contributing-to-the-destabiliz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), I hereby report that I have issued an&#160;Executive Order in order to expand the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13219 of June 26, 2001 (Blocking Property of Persons Who Threaten International Stabilization Efforts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>), I hereby report that I have issued an&nbsp;Executive Order in order to expand the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13219 of June 26, 2001 (Blocking Property of Persons Who Threaten International Stabilization Efforts in the Western Balkans), as amended by&nbsp;Executive Order 13304 of May 28, 2003 (Termination of Emergencies With Respect to Yugoslavia and Modification of Executive Order 13219 of June 26, 2001), finding that the situation in the territory of the former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia and the Republic of Albania (the Western Balkans), over the past two decades, including the undermining of post-war agreements and institutions following the breakup of&nbsp;the former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, as well&nbsp;as widespread corruption within various governments and institutions in the Western Balkans, stymies progress toward effective and democratic governance and full integration into transatlantic institutions, and thereby constitutes an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.<br><br>The order broadens the geographic scope of the existing sanctions regime to include Albania and augments designation criteria for current threats to United States national security and foreign policy interests in the region, including obstruction of&nbsp;democratic and judicial processes, corruption, and organized crime.&nbsp;<br><br>Actions undermining post-war agreements and institutions following the breakup of the former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, as well as widespread corruption within various governments and institutions in the Western Balkans, stymies progress toward effective and democratic governance and full integration into transatlantic institutions, and thereby constitutes an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; I have therefore determined that it is necessary to block the property and interests in property of any persons who are determined by&nbsp;the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, to have undermined democratic processes or&nbsp;institutions, undermined any regional security, peace, cooperation, or mutual recognition agreement or framework or accountability mechanism, engaged in serious human rights abuse, or directly or indirectly engaged in corruption related to the Western Balkans.&nbsp; All executive departments and agencies are directed to take all appropriate measures within their authority to carry out the provisions of the order.<br><br>I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Sincerely,<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Western Balkans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-western-balkans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 19:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)  Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) </p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.  In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the Western Balkans that was declared in Executive Order 13219 of June 26, 2001, is to continue in effect beyond June 26, 2021.<br><br>The threat constituted by the actions of persons engaged in, or assisting, sponsoring, or supporting, (i) extremist violence in the former Republic of Macedonia (what is now the Republic of North Macedonia) and elsewhere in the Western Balkans region, or (ii) acts obstructing implementation of the Dayton Accords in Bosnia or United Nations Security Council Resolution 1244 of June 10, 1999, in Kosovo, has not been resolved.  In addition, Executive Order 13219 was amended by Executive Order 13304 of May 28, 2003, to take additional steps with respect to certain actions that obstruct implementation of, among other things, the Ohrid Framework Agreement of 2001 relating to the former Republic of Macedonia (what is now the Republic of North Macedonia).<br><br>The acts of extremist violence and obstructionist activity outlined in these Executive Orders are hostile to United States interests and continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.  For this reason, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared with respect to the Western Balkans in Executive Order 13219.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,<br><br>                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Blocking Property And Suspending Entry Into The United States Of Certain Persons Contributing To The Destabilizing Situation In The Western Balkans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/08/executive-order-on-blocking-property-and-suspending-entry-into-the-united-states-of-certain-persons-contributing-to-the-destabilizing-situation-in-the-western-balkans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 19:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act&#160;(50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.) (NEA), section 212(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952 (8 U.S.C. 1182(f)), and&#160;section&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act&nbsp;(50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq</em>.) (NEA), section 212(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952 (8 U.S.C. 1182(f)), and&nbsp;section 301 of title 3, United States Code,</p>



<p>I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of&nbsp;America, hereby expand the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13219 of June 26, 2001 (Blocking Property of Persons Who Threaten International Stabilization Efforts in the Western Balkans), as amended by Executive Order 13304 of May 28, 2003 (Termination of Emergencies With Respect to Yugoslavia and Modification of Executive Order 13219 of June&nbsp;26, 2001), finding that the situation in the territory of&nbsp;the former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia and the Republic of Albania (the Western Balkans), over the past two decades, including the undermining of post-war agreements and institutions following the breakup of the former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, as well as widespread corruption within various governments and institutions in the Western Balkans, stymies progress toward effective and democratic governance and full integration into transatlantic institutions, and thereby constitutes an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Accordingly, I hereby order:<br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">1.</span>  (a)  All property and interests in property that are in the United States, that hereafter come within the United States, or that are or hereafter come within the possession or control of any United States person of the following persons are blocked and may not be transferred, paid, exported, withdrawn, or otherwise dealt in:  any person determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State:<br>          (i)    to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged in, actions or policies that threaten the peace, security, stability, or territorial integrity of any area or state in the Western Balkans;<br>          (ii)   to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged in, actions or policies that undermine democratic processes or institutions in the Western Balkans;<br>          (iii)  to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged in, a violation of, or an act that has obstructed or threatened the implementation of, any regional security, peace, cooperation, or mutual recognition agreement or framework or accountability mechanism related to the Western Balkans, including the Prespa Agreement of 2018; the Ohrid Framework Agreement of 2001; United Nations Security Council Resolution 1244; the Dayton Accords; or the Conclusions of the Peace Implementation Conference Council held in London in December 1995, including the decisions or conclusions of the High Representative, the Peace Implementation Council, or its Steering Board; or the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia, or, with respect to the former Yugoslavia, the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals;<br>          (iv)   to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged in, serious human rights abuse in the Western Balkans;<br>          (v)    to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged in, corruption related to the Western Balkans, including corruption by, on behalf of, or otherwise related to a government in the Western Balkans, or a current or former government official at any level of government in the Western Balkans, such as the misappropriation of public assets, expropriation of private assets for personal gain or political purposes, or bribery;<br>          (vi)   to have materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order; or <br>          (vii)  to be owned or controlled by, or to have acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order.<br>     (b)  The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or any license or permit granted before the date of this order. </p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">2.</span>  The prohibitions in section 1 of this order include:<br>     (a)  the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order; and<br>     (b)  the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">3.</span>  I hereby determine that the making of donations of the types of articles specified in section 203(b)(2) of IEEPA (50 U.S.C. 1702(b)(2)) by, to, or for the benefit of any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to section 1(a) of this order would seriously impair my ability to deal with the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13219, as amended by Executive Order 13304, and as expanded in this order, and I hereby prohibit such donations as provided by section 1 of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">4.</span>  (a)  The unrestricted immigrant and nonimmigrant entry into the United States of noncitizens determined to meet one or more of the criteria in section l(a) of this order would be detrimental to the interests of the United States, and the entry of such persons into the United States, as immigrants or nonimmigrants, is hereby suspended, except when the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, determines that the person&#8217;s entry would not be contrary to the interests of the United States, including when the Secretary of State or Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, so determines, based on a recommendation of the Attorney General, that the person&#8217;s entry would further important United States law enforcement objectives. <br>     (b)  The Secretary of State shall implement this order as it applies to visas pursuant to such procedures as the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, may establish. <br>     (c)  The Secretary of Homeland Security shall implement this order as it applies to the entry of noncitizens pursuant to such procedures as the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may establish.<br>     (d)  Such persons shall be treated by this section in the same manner as persons covered by section 1 of Proclamation 8693 of July 24, 2011 (Suspension of Entry of Aliens Subject to United Nations Security Council Travel Bans and International Emergency Economic Powers Act Sanctions).</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">5.</span>  (a)  Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.<br>     (b)  Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">6.</span>  For the purposes of this order:<br>     (a)  the term &#8220;entity&#8221; means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;<br>     (b)  the term &#8220;noncitizen&#8221; means any person who is not a citizen or noncitizen national of the United States;<br>     (c)  the term &#8220;person&#8221; means an individual or entity; and<br>     (d)  the term &#8220;United States person&#8221; means any United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">7.</span>  For those persons whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order who might have a constitutional presence in the United States, I find that because of the ability to transfer funds or other assets instantaneously, prior notice to such persons of measures to be taken pursuant to this order would render those measures ineffectual.  I therefore determine that for these measures to be effective in addressing the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13219, as amended by Executive Order 13304, and as expanded by this order, there need be no prior notice of a listing or determination made pursuant to this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">8.</span>  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order.  The Secretary of the Treasury may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury.  All executive departments and agencies of the United States shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to implement this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">9.</span>  Nothing in this order shall prohibit transactions for the conduct of the official business of the Federal Government by employees, grantees, or contractors thereof.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">10.</span>  (a)  Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>          (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>          (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>     (b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>     (c)  This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.                       </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"> JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>    June 8, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Western Balkans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/08/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-western-balkans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 19:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On June 26, 2001, by Executive Order 13219, the President declared a national emergency with respect to the Western Balkans pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy&#160;of the United States constituted by the actions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On June 26, 2001, by Executive Order 13219, the President declared a national emergency with respect to the Western Balkans pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy&nbsp;of the United States constituted by the actions of persons engaged in, or assisting, sponsoring, or supporting, (i)&nbsp;extremist violence in the former Republic of Macedonia (what&nbsp;is now the Republic of North Macedonia) and elsewhere in&nbsp;the Western Balkans region, or (ii) acts obstructing implementation of the Dayton Accords in Bosnia or United Nations Security Council Resolution 1244 of June 10, 1999, in Kosovo.&nbsp; The President subsequently amended that order in Executive Order&nbsp;13304 of May 28, 2003, to take additional steps with respect to certain actions that obstruct implementation of, among other things, the Ohrid Framework Agreement of 2001 relating to Macedonia.</p>



<p>The actions of persons threatening the peace and international stabilization efforts in the Western Balkans, including acts of extremist violence and obstructionist activity, continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat&nbsp;to the national security and foreign policy of the United&nbsp;States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on June 26, 2001, must continue in effect beyond June&nbsp;26, 2021.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1&nbsp;year the national emergency declared with respect to the Western Balkans in Executive Order 13219.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register </em>and&nbsp;transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 8, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
