<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 21:26:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement from Vice President Kamala Harris on Administration’s Voting Rights Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/01/statement-from-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-administrations-voting-rights-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 21:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every American has a right to have their voice heard at the ballot box, and no American should be kept from voting early, voting by mail, or voting at all. Our democracy is strongest when everyone participates, and it is weaker when people are left out. Throughout the arc of our nation’s history, many have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Every American has a right to have their voice heard at the ballot box, and no American should be kept from voting early, voting by mail, or voting at all. Our democracy is strongest when everyone participates, and it is weaker when people are left out.<br><br>Throughout the arc of our nation’s history, many have worked—and many have died—to ensure that all Americans can cast a ballot and have their vote counted. Today, that hard-won progress is under assault.<br><br>In the last election, more people voted than ever before. Since then, more than 380 bills have been introduced across the country that would make it harder for Americans to vote. These bills seek to restrict the options that make voting more convenient and accessible, including early voting and vote by mail. Our Administration will not stand by when confronted with any effort that keeps Americans from voting. <br><br>We must protect the fundamental right to vote for all Americans regardless of where they live. There are two important bills in Congress that would do just that. The For the People Act would provide all Americans with fair and accessible voting options, and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act would prevent discriminatory changes to voting laws and procedures. <br><br>President Joe Biden asked me to help lead our Administration’s effort to protect the fundamental right to vote for all Americans. In the days and weeks ahead, I will engage the American people, and I will work with voting rights organizations, community organizations, and the private sector to help strengthen and uplift efforts on voting rights nationwide. And we will also work with members of Congress to help advance these bills.<br><br>The work ahead of us is to make voting accessible to all American voters, and to make sure every vote is counted through a free, fair, and transparent process. This is the work of democracy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre Aboard Air Force One En Route Tulsa, OK</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/01/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-aboard-air-force-one-en-route-tulsa-ok/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:42 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; All right.&#160; Got a few things for you all at the top.&#160;&#160;Today in Tulsa, the President will tour the Greenwood Cultural Center, meet with surviving members of the community, and deliver remarks to commemorate the Tulsa Race Massacre.&#160;One hundred years ago, the thriving Black community of Greenwood in Tulsa, Oklahoma, was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:42 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Got a few things for you all at the top.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today in Tulsa, the President will tour the Greenwood Cultural Center, meet with surviving members of the community, and deliver remarks to commemorate the Tulsa Race Massacre.<br>&nbsp;<br>One hundred years ago, the thriving Black community of Greenwood in Tulsa, Oklahoma, was ruthlessly attacked by a violent, white supremacist mob.&nbsp; An estimated 300 Black Americans were killed, and another 10,000 were left destitute and homeless.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is honored to have the opportunity to listen to them and learn from the survivors of the community.&nbsp; He plans to convey his heartfelt gratitude for their bravery in sharing the stories of the trauma and violence that was wrought on them and their families.&nbsp; And &#8212; and frankly, he plans to discuss his shared sense of frustration and pain that justice has been denied to these families for so long.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As the President will explain in his remarks, he is traveling to Tulsa to shine a light on what happened and to make sure America knows the story in full.&nbsp; He will explain that we need to know our history &#8212; from the original sin of slavery, through the Tulsa Race Massacre, to racial discrimination in housing &#8212; in order to build common ground to truly repair and rebuild.<br>&nbsp;<br>This morning, on the centennial of that massacre, the Biden-Harris administration announced new steps to help narrow the racial wealth gap and reinvest in communities that have been left behind by failed policies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The administration is expanding access to two key wealth creators &#8212; homeownership and small business ownership &#8212; in communities of color and disadvantaged communities by launching a first-of-its-kind inter- &#8212; interagency effort to address inequity and racial bias in home appraisals and conducting rulemaking to aggressively combat housing discrimination; using the federal government&#8217;s purchasing power to grow federal contracting with small business &#8212; small, disadvantaged businesses by 50 percent, translating to an additional $100 billion over five years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This builds on the President&#8217;s historic approach to advancing equity and racial justice across the whole of federal government.<br>&nbsp;<br>On day one, the President signed an executive order directing federal agencies to identify concrete opportunities to advance equitable outcomes &#8212; which has already led to the Department of Agriculture announcing a new $6 billion initiative to help small and socially disadvantaged producers; the Department of Transportation imposing an unprecedented pause on a highway project in Texas to review civil rights and enviro- &#8212; environmental justice concerns.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President has proposed historic plans &#8212; the American Rescue Plan, the American Jobs Plan, the American Families Plan &#8212; that will make generational investments in racial justice and support underserved communities like Tulsa, who face challenging economic conditions resulting from histories of discrimination and disinvestment.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One more thing, as soon as I get there.&nbsp; One more update for &#8212; for all of you.&nbsp; Meat producer JBS notified us on Sunday that they are the victims of a ransomware attack.&nbsp; The White House has offered assistance to JBS, and our team and the Department of Agriculture have spoken to their leadership several times in the last day.&nbsp; JBS notified the administration that the ransom demand came from a criminal organization likely based in Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The White House is engaging directly with the Russian government on this matter and delivering the message that responsible states do not harbor ransomware criminals.&nbsp; The FBI is investigating the incident and CISA is coordinating with the FBI to offer technical support to the company in recovering from the ransomware attack.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>USDA has reached out to several major meat processors in the United States to ensure they are aware of the situation.&nbsp; We&#8217;re assessing any impacts on supply, and the President has directed the administration to determine what we can do to mitigate any impacts as they may become necessary.<br>&nbsp;<br>Combating ransomware is a priority for the administration.&nbsp; President Biden has already launched a rapid strategic review to address the increased threat of ransomware to include four lines of effort: one, distribution of ransomware infrastructure and actors working closely with the private sector; two, building an international coalition to hold countries who harbor ransom actors accountable; expanding cryptocurrency analysis to find and pursue criminal transaction; and reviewing the USG&#8217;s ransomware policies.<br>&nbsp;<br>This builds on President Biden&#8217;s executive order, which is now being implemented.&nbsp; The executive order outlines five high-priority cybersecurity initiatives that, if implemented, will reduce the risk of cyberattacks including ransomware.<br>&nbsp;<br>We call on organizations across government and the private sector to take the threat of ransomware seriously and modernize their cyber defenses, including implementing the practices in the executive order.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>CI- &#8212; CISA has also built a toolkit to further guide organizations on addressing ransomware threats: CISA.gov/ransomware.&nbsp; That is the site that they have built.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, can we have you move in a little bit, just so you&#8217;re not talking in the doorway?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just to make sure we&#8217;re picking this up.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I &#8212; all I heard you say was &#8220;ransomware.&#8221;&nbsp; Can you just briefly summarize what you were talking about there for us &#8212; or those of us that couldn&#8217;t hear clearly?<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m so sorry.&nbsp; I can repeat that part again.&nbsp; Do you mean about the cyberattacks in general?&nbsp; You guys didn&#8217;t hear any of it?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All I heard was &#8220;ransomware&#8221; and I heard &#8220;agriculture&#8221; at one point.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, this is the JBS cyberattack, which happened &#8212; which occurred recently.&nbsp; So, one &#8212; one more &#8212; it was another update that we had for all of you.&nbsp; The meat producer J- &#8212; JBS notified us on Sunday that they are &#8212; that they are the victims of a ransomware attack.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The White House has offered assistance to J- &#8212; JBS, and our team at the Department of Agriculture have spoken to their leadership several times in the last day.<br>&nbsp;<br>JBS notified the administration that the ransom demand came from a criminal organization likely based in Russia.&nbsp; So, the White House is engaging directly with the Russian government on this matter and delivering the message that responsible states do not harbor ransomware criminals.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The FBI is investigating the incident, and CISA is coordinating with the FBI to offer technical support to the company in recovering from the ransomware attack as well.&nbsp; USD- &#8212; USDA has reached out to several major meat processors in the United States to ensure they are aware of the situation.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re assessing any impacts on supply, and the President has directed the administration to determine what we can do to mitigate any impacts as may become necessary.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And on the President&#8217;s meeting tomorrow with Senator Capito: Is it just Senator Capito, or is it Senator Capito and other Republican senators?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, it&#8217;s just with Senator Capito.&nbsp; That is the meeting that &#8212; where he&#8217;s having tomorrow.&nbsp; This is to discuss the counteroffer.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, the President and the Republicans in &#8212; on the Senate have been in a good-faith, healthy discussion on the American Jobs Plan &#8212; how to move forward; how do we invest in our infrastructure; building roads, bridges, and making sure that we&#8217;re creating jobs as well, which is what the President wants to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>They came back with nearly a trillion-dollar counteroffer.&nbsp; And so, the President is going to have a conversation with Senator Capito tomorrow to continue those discussions that they&#8217;ve been having the past several weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has &#8212; does the President have any reaction to what&#8217;s going on in Israel with the government there?&nbsp; Has he spoken to any of the leaders involved, like Prime Minister Netanyahu or the others who are vying for that job?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so, Jeff, as you can imagine, we&#8217;re not going to comment publicly on government formation while that process is underway.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re just not going to comment at this time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one &#8212; just one other topic, with regard to the Texas voting restrictions.&nbsp; There are calls from Democrats now for the President and for Congress to &#8212; for the U.S. Congress and congressional Democrats to do more to help stop what&#8217;s going on there.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House&#8217;s reaction to that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, just to &#8212; just to state a couple of things here.&nbsp; The Texas legislation is part of a concerted attack on our democracy being advanced in statehouses across the country on the basis of the same repeatedly disproven lies that led to the assault on our nation&#8217;s Capitol on January 6th.<br>&nbsp;<br>This must stop.&nbsp; We need to make it easier, not harder, for all eligible voters to register and cast their ballots.&nbsp; We need to move forward, not backwards.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The fact of the matter is that the Texas &#8212; Texas legislation would make it harder to vote in a state where it is already too hard for many to vote.&nbsp; Among other restriction provisions, the bill would have restricted the ability to apply for and help others apply for voting by mail, including a provision forcing people with disabilities to identify as such; given expansion permissions to partisan watchers in a way likely to lead to interference with both voters and officials; made it harder for local election officials to open polls at times that work for voters, including on Sunday mornings and at late-night hours that accommodate shift &#8212; shift workers.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President put out a pretty &#8212; a statement over the weekend about this, about his thoughts on how &#8212; how un-American and un-democratic what we’re seeing across the country and in Texas, in particular, because that was the most recent &#8212; recent legislation that came forth.&nbsp; And so, he&#8217;ll have more to say in &#8212; in short order later today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, what does it mean that the President is going to visit Tulsa, which was relatively obscure in the history books, at a time when Republican legislatures are really trying to beat back attempts to teach racist history at school?&nbsp; I&#8217;m thinking of the 1619 Project and other backlash to racist historical events.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so on that question, Mario, the President strongly believes that the federal government has no role in setting school curriculums.&nbsp; Setting academic curriculum is the responsibility of state and local officials.&nbsp; Curricular decisions should be &#8212; shouldn&#8217;t be driven by politics, as you can imagine, but the President does believe that it is important for our nation&#8217;s students to fully understand our history.<br>&nbsp;<br>America is the greatest democracy in the world because of our founding ideals of liberty and freedom.&nbsp; Our democracy is strongest when our citizens understand the times in our history (inaudible) we have not lived up to these ideals, so that we can all strive together to form a more perfect union.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, does the President support reparations for the families of the victims of the Tulsa Massacre?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the President believes that what these survivors have endured is tragic and devastating.&nbsp; First and foremost, he is honored to have the opportunity to listen to them and learn from their experiences.&nbsp; He also plans to convey his heartfelt gratitude for their bravery in sharing the stories of the trauma and violence that was wrought on them and their families.&nbsp; And that is &#8212; that is going to be his focus today, and that&#8217;s what he wants to do.&nbsp; He wants to hear (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will he specifically talk about any government effort to repay those families in this meeting with a couple of survivors, but the others who he won&#8217;t be meeting with today?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, you know, the fact that 100 years after a violent racist mob destroyed an entire neighborhood, murdered hundreds of innocent people, and burned churches to the ground, there &#8212; there are survivors of that violence who are still forced to fight for recognition should &#8212; should &#8212; should appall us all.&nbsp; And that is the focus of what the President wants to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He wants to make sure that this is on record, that this is not forgotten &#8212; a story that has not been told is told.&nbsp; And, you know, it is an indictment of systemic racism that these survivors have been forced to fight for literally 100 years to have their humanity recognized and to have justice served, and justice and fairness still eludes them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden believes we have to take core steps right now to fight systemic racism, things like fighting redlining, supporting funding for under schools &#8212; underfunded schools that are too often located in predominantly Black and brown neighborhoods, and more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also supports a study, as we&#8217;ve said before, into reparations, but believes that, first and foremost, the task in front of us is not to root out &#8212; is to root out systemic racism where it exists right now.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s a &#8212; central to all of his agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>As I mentioned in the topper, he has put equity in everything &#8212; in every plan that he&#8217;s put forward, if you think about the American Rescue Plan and how that&#8217;s going to cut down poverty by more than 50 percent &#8212; child poverty in Black communities.&nbsp; You think about the American Families Plan, the American Jobs Plan &#8212; all of those things also has equity at the middle of it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If you think about the COVID task force &#8212; the Racial Task Force, we actually have a COVID task force that deals with making sure we don&#8217;t leave communities behind.&nbsp; And so, that has been his focus throughout his presidency thus far.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One thing, just to follow up.&nbsp; Can I just follow up really quickly, because &#8212; on that point?&nbsp; The NAACP president says, “You can&#8217;t begin to address the racial wealth gap without addressing the student loan debt crisis.”&nbsp; So, with everything that the White House announced today ahead of this trip to Tulsa, why wasn&#8217;t cancellation of student debt a part of that?&nbsp; And is this still something the President is considering?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, the American Families Plan, which is included in the President&#8217;s budget, includes a historic $46 billion of investments in HBCUs, Tribal colleges and universities, and minority-serving institutions.&nbsp; These institutions are critical to helping underrepresented students move to the top of the income ladder.&nbsp; And so, President Biden is calling for a historic investment in affordability through subsidized tuition and expanding institutional and &#8212; grants.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These investments will enable America&#8217;s HBCUs, TSCUs, and MSIUs to tackle long standing inequalities in post-secondary education.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Buttigieg, over the weekend, talked about the week of June 7th as another important milestone in terms of the negotiations over an infrastructure package.&nbsp; Is that the moment at which, if there isn&#8217;t the kind of progress the White House has wanted to see already, the White House goes ahead and moves alone?&nbsp; The Transportation Committee &#8212; the chairman on the Democratic side has already set a markup for a different infrastructure proposal at that point.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, thanks &#8212; thanks for the question.&nbsp; So, look, as you just stated, you know, the President is &#8212; as I stated earlier, he is thank- &#8212; he is &#8212; he is appreciative and heartened by the good &#8212; good, you know &#8212; the good-faith effort that we&#8217;ve seen from Republican senators.&nbsp; But as the President said last week, we do need to finish these negotiations soon because we’re in a race to win the 21st century.&nbsp; And the pandemic exposed just how badly we need to invest in the foundation of this country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The House Transportation and Infrastructure Committee is doing a markup on infrastructure on June 9th, as well, which is a relevant date in terms of the overall timeframe.&nbsp; And so, we are working actively with members of the House, of the Senate this week so that there is a clear direction on how to advance much-needed jobs legislation when Congress resumes legislative business during the week of June 7.<br>&nbsp;<br>So this week will be incredibly critical.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve mentioned and announced, Senator Capito is going to be meeting with the President tomorrow, and we&#8217;ll continue to have these conversations as we move forward in the next few weeks &#8212; in the next couple days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could you circle back to the NAACP criticism about student debt cancellation?&nbsp; Should we expect the President to address that at all today in his remarks?&nbsp; Or what does the White House make of that pretty harsh criticism from the NAACP on that front?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; As I stated, you know, in his American Families Plan, this is a priority &#8212; you know? &#8212; making sure that he made historical investment into HBCUs, Tribal colleges and universities, and minority-serving institutions.&nbsp; And he wants to keep to that promise and is going to work very hard towards that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today it&#8217;s going to be about, clearly, the Tulsa &#8212; Tulsa Massacre that happened 100 years ago, commemorating that, having conversations with the survivor.&nbsp; He announced, as we know, some key &#8212; some key elements on how he wants to deal with, you know, the wealth gap in communities, in particular minority communities, Black communities.&nbsp; So he&#8217;ll talk a little bit about that as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of him, and he&#8217;ll have more to say later today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more commodity question.&nbsp; OPEC decided to boost production.&nbsp; Did the President speak to any OPEC leaders about that move?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t have any comment on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, just to expand on Jeff’s question about Texas: The White House seems to have preferred ignore everything that former President Trump says and does &#8212; right? &#8212; ever since he’s left office.&nbsp; But isn&#8217;t this, kind of, the elephant in the room?&nbsp; Because he is the one pushing all this, you know, election theories and, you know, pretty successfully.&nbsp; There are millions and millions of Americans who seem to be, you know, drinking it and following it and acting on it, and pressuring their own elected officials.&nbsp; So does the President &#8212; does he ever plan to try and address this head on &#8212; what&#8217;s going on out there?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I mean, a couple of things.&nbsp; You know, the President spoke about it.&nbsp; We put out a statement yest- &#8212; over the weekend.&nbsp; It’s part of a &#8212; as the President stated over the weekend &#8212; look, it’s part of an assault on democracy that we’ve seen far too often this year, and often disproportionately targeting Black and brown Americans.&nbsp; And it’s wrong; it’s un-American.&nbsp; In the 21st century, we should be making it easier, not harder, for every eligible voter to vote.<br>&nbsp;<br>So he is again calling on Congress to pass the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Amendment Act, and will continue to call on Americans &#8212; every party and persuasion &#8212; to stand up for our democracy and protect the right to vote and the integrity of our elections.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, look, you know, if you look back to November of 2020, that was an election to save our democracy, right?&nbsp; That was exactly what this election &#8212; that election was about.&nbsp; The President clearly won, because he&#8217;s now President.&nbsp; But President Biden also understands it&#8217;s going to take time to bring everyone together.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He was &#8212; he was elected partially because people thought he would be a president that would bring both sides together.&nbsp; And that is the work that he&#8217;s been trying to do for the past hundred, you know, thirty days now &#8212; I’ve lost track of how many days &#8212; of trying to bring bipartisanship back &#8212; something we haven&#8217;t seen in, you know &#8212; in D.C. in some time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And if you think about the American Rescue Plan, that had bipartisan support across the country &#8212; Republicans, Democrats, and independents.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the President is going to continue to do: try to bring both sides together and work with Congress to get the For the People Act passed, the John Lewis Voting Rights Act passed.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to continue to do.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll have &#8212; he&#8217;ll actually have more to say about that later today, so I don&#8217;t want to get ahead (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Senator Joe Manchin has expressed some concerns about the voting rights bill.&nbsp; Obviously, a crucial vote to push that forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’m so sorry, say that (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Senator Joe Manchin has expressed concerns.&nbsp; Has the President had any outreach with him or his office?&nbsp; Should we expect, you know, some more from the President on being more forceful in trying to get that passed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, like I said, Tyler, we’re going to have more.&nbsp; The President will have more to say about this later today.&nbsp; And as you could imagine, he talks to members on the Hill &#8212; House members, senators &#8212; pretty regularly.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been meeting with them pretty regularly on both sides of the aisle, and they&#8217;ve talked on &#8212; about an array of issues.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so I&#8217;m going to not get ahead of what he&#8217;s going to say later today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one other topic.&nbsp; Is there any reaction from the White House to the reports that Denmark was assisting the U.S. in wiretapping some of these European leaders?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, in 2014, the United States issued a full review of our approach to overseas surveillance.&nbsp; President Obama issued a presidential directive that changed our approach in significant ways.<br>&nbsp;<br>We will work with our European allies and partners to address any questions through the appropriate national security channels.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) on Tulsa.&nbsp; Do you have any details on the survivors that he&#8217;s going to be meeting with?&nbsp; How many?&nbsp; If you don&#8217;t have names, can you say how many, how big the group is?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;ll have more for all of you pretty &#8212; as we get closer to the meetings.&nbsp; I think what we announced was that he was going to meet with three of the survivors.&nbsp; And so we’ll have more.&nbsp; We’ll have more on that as we get closer to the meeting to share with you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you able to say at what point the President learned about what happened in Tulsa 100 years ago?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so, as you can imagine, it’s a story the President has been long familiar with, a story that has not been told.&nbsp; The President wants to make sure it’s not a forgotten story.&nbsp; And the President wants to put it on record, which is one of the reasons why he’s coming today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I just wanted to read out a Tweet that he put out last year about this, which is: “The Tulsa Race Massacre is one of the worst incidents of racial violence in our history &#8212; and it has been erased from our national conscious[ness] for far too long.&nbsp; It’s time we reckon with what happened in 1921.”<br>&nbsp;<br>So this is, like I said, something that the President has been familiar with for some time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just a housekeeping thing on that, on the survivors meeting.&nbsp; Just a housekeeping: Could we put in the request with you that we’d love to see that?&nbsp; I know it’s closed as of right now, but if there’s a photo op that we could get, that’s a very significant meeting that I think people would like to see or have a chance to hear from the President after he has sat down with them.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, a follow-up:&nbsp;Is there any consideration, given this latest ransomware attack &#8212; is there any rethinking of the summit with Vladimir Putin in two weeks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that?&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; Say that &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any rethinking of the summit with Vladimir<br>Putin in two weeks, given this latest ransomware attack?&nbsp; You said a criminal organization based in Russia.&nbsp; And conversations (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Appreciate the question.&nbsp; So we do not regard, as you can imagine, this meeting with the Russian President as a reward.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; We regard it as a vital part of defending America&#8217;s interests.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden is meeting with Vladimir Putin because of our country&#8217;s differences, not in spite of them.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot we have to work through.&nbsp; President Biden is the most effective communicator of American values and priorities, and hearing directly from President Putin is the most effective way to understand what Russia plans and intends.<br>&nbsp;<br>There is no substitute &#8212; right? &#8212; for a leader-to-leader engagement, particularly for complex relationships.&nbsp; So it is important for President Biden to sit down with President Putin, face to face, to be clear about where we are, to understand where he is, to try to manage differences and to identify areas where we can make progress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you so much, everybody.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:07 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Black Music Appreciation Month, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/01/a-proclamation-on-black-music-appreciation-month-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 18:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout our history, there has been no richer influence on the American songbook than Black music and culture.&#160; From early spirituals born out of the unconscionable hardships of slavery; to the creation of folk and gospel; to the evolution of&#160;rhythm and blues and jazz; to the ascendance of rock and roll, rap, and hip-hop &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Throughout our history, there has been no richer influence on the American songbook than Black music and culture.&nbsp; From early spirituals born out of the unconscionable hardships of slavery; to the creation of folk and gospel; to the evolution of&nbsp;rhythm and blues and jazz; to the ascendance of rock and roll, rap, and hip-hop &#8212; Black music has shaped our society, entertained and inspired us, and helped write and tell the story of our Nation.</p>



<p>During Black Music Appreciation Month, we honor the innovative artists whose musical expressions move us, brighten our daily lives, and bring us together.&nbsp; Across the generations, Black music has pioneered the way we listen to music while preserving Black cultural traditions and sharing the unique experiences of the Black community.&nbsp; Black artists have dramatically influenced what we all hear and feel through music &#8212; joy and sadness, love and loss, pride and purpose.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Black music has always stood on its own &#8212; a beacon of resilience and resistance &#8212; while at the same time helping to shape countless other musical and cultural traditions.&nbsp; From the&nbsp;syncopated rhythms of jazz to the soulful expressions of R&amp;B, Black music spans an extraordinarily broad spectrum of genres and styles.&nbsp; The distinct voices and instruments of Black artists have filled the halls of the Apollo Theater in New York City, Preservation Hall in New Orleans, the Fillmore in San Francisco, and other iconic venues throughout the United States and around the world, energizing audiences and inspiring millions.&nbsp; The music created and expressed by Black communities has paved the way for generations of musicians across all races, creeds, colors, religions, sexual orientations, and identities.&nbsp; The creativity and spirit of Black music is everywhere, and our Nation and the world are richer for it.</p>



<p>This month, we also honor the many important contributors to our Nation&#8217;s musical heritage that are no longer with us.&nbsp; And although they have taken their final bows, their musical legacies and influence will live on in our hearts and souls, and&nbsp;inspire a new generation of artists and fans.</p>



<p>In appreciating the indelible contributions of Black Americans to the music landscape, we must also recognize the crisis of racial inequity that Black Americans have faced in America for centuries &#8212; a crisis that is often reflected and challenged in Black music.&nbsp; We must rededicate ourselves to rooting out systemic racism from every part of our society, and&nbsp;work together to advance racial justice and equity.&nbsp; In the music industry, that work includes identifying and eliminating barriers that Black creatives face in producing and maintaining ownership of their music and other creations. &nbsp;In this month of June, we celebrate the Black music that has shaped and enlivened our lives and our country, and recommit ourselves to advancing racial equity for artists &#8212; and for everyone.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2021 as Black Music Appreciation Month.&nbsp; I&nbsp;call upon public officials, educators, and all the people of the United States to observe this month with appropriate activities and programs that raise awareness and appreciation of&nbsp;Black music.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this<br>first day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Homeownership Month, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/01/a-proclamation-on-national-homeownership-month-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 18:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For millions of Americans, homeownership is the cornerstone of a life with security, with dignity, and with hope. A home is more than four walls and a roof; it is a place where we can celebrate triumphs and weather the trials of life. A place where we can watch our families grow and prosper. A&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For millions of Americans, homeownership is the cornerstone of a life with security, with dignity, and with hope. A home is more than four walls and a roof; it is a place where we can celebrate triumphs and weather the trials of life. A place where we can watch our families grow and prosper. A place that helps us build wealth we can pass down to our children and our grandchildren.</p>



<p>The aspiration to own a home is connected deeply to the American dream. It has driven generations of Americans, in search of a place to call one&#8217;s own.</p>



<p>Today, for people across the United States, the desire to own a home burns as brightly as it ever has. Yet the stark reality is that, for too many, the dream of homeownership is becoming more difficult to realize and sustain. This is especially true in the wake of the economic devastation inflicted by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>We also know that people of color continue to face discrimination in our housing market &#8212; when trying to secure mortgages, to have their homes appraised, and to live in neighborhoods where their families can thrive. In recent years, the homeownership gap between Black and white families reached its widest point since 1968, when banks could still legally discriminate against borrowers based on the color of their skin.</p>



<p>This is economically and morally wrong, and it is why, as President, I have made it a central priority to expand stability and opportunity within our housing market. On my first day in office, I took executive action to extend foreclosure moratoriums for nearly 11 million households with mortgages guaranteed by the Federal Government. My Administration introduced and passed the American Rescue Plan, which will deliver nearly $10 billion in relief for homeowners who have fallen behind on their mortgage payments during the pandemic. And to create greater opportunities for homeownership moving forward, we have proposed the American Jobs Plan &#8212; which can spur the construction and rehabilitation of more than 500,000 homes for buyers of more modest means.</p>



<p>The Department of Housing and Urban Development will continue to advance affordable and sustainable homeownership throughout our Nation. This will require that we help more hardworking Americans purchase their first homes, increase access to credit and mortgage insurance for borrowers of color, and fully enforce the 1968 Fair Housing Act &#8212; to root out systemic discrimination from our housing market and break down the unjust barriers that prevent too many Americans from buying a home.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2021 as National Homeownership Month. I call upon the people of this Nation to recognize the enduring value of homeownership and to recommit ourselves to helping more Americans realize that dream.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Ocean Month, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/01/a-proclamation-on-national-ocean-month-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 18:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The world&#8217;s ocean basins are critical to the success of our&#160;Nation and, indeed, to life on Earth.&#160; The ocean powers our&#160;economy, provides food for billions of people, supplies 50&#160;percent of the world&#8217;s oxygen, offers recreational opportunities for us to enjoy, and regulates weather patterns and our global climate system.&#160; During National Ocean Month, we&#160;celebrate our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The world&#8217;s ocean basins are critical to the success of our&nbsp;Nation and, indeed, to life on Earth.&nbsp; The ocean powers our&nbsp;economy, provides food for billions of people, supplies 50&nbsp;percent of the world&#8217;s oxygen, offers recreational opportunities for us to enjoy, and regulates weather patterns and our global climate system.&nbsp; During National Ocean Month, we&nbsp;celebrate our stewardship of the ocean and coasts, and reaffirm our commitment to protecting and sustaining them for&nbsp;current and future generations.</p>



<p>My Administration is dedicated to improving our Nation&#8217;s public health by supporting resilient ocean habitats, wildlife, and resources in which all Americans rely on.&nbsp; Through our &#8220;America the Beautiful&#8221; initiative, we are working with State, Tribal, and local partners to conserve at least 30&nbsp;percent of United States lands and waters by 2030 &#8212; so that our natural world can continue to supply the food, clean air, and clean water that every one of us depends on to survive.&nbsp; We are also committed to supporting safe, plentiful, and sustainable seafood harvesting for domestic consumption and export, and reducing public health risks such as harmful algal blooms that have proliferated as a result of climate change and the acidification of our waters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ocean has always been essential to our economy, and that will remain true as we build back better and develop the clean industries and good jobs of the future.&nbsp; My plan to dramatically expand offshore wind energy over the next 10&nbsp;years will provide good-paying union jobs and a sustainable source of clean energy.&nbsp; Investing in resilient, reliable coastal infrastructure &#8212; including modern ports and waterways &#8212; that can withstand the impacts of rising seas and powerful storms will keep our economy competitive in the global marketplace while making our families safer. &nbsp;Conserving and restoring coastal wetlands and habitats will also strengthen our&nbsp;efforts to tackle climate change, improve the resilience of&nbsp;coastal communities, and help restore nursery areas that are important to our fisheries. &nbsp;Investing in our fishing communities and supporting local seafood supply options will&nbsp;also be critical to helping us build a climate-resilient, sustainable ocean economy.</p>



<p>Climate change is a global challenge that is integrally linked to the ocean.&nbsp; By protecting our ocean and coastal ecosystems and resources, we are also protecting the worldwide economies and people that depend on them. &nbsp;To address these challenges, we&nbsp;are building on our Nation&#8217;s long legacy of ocean exploration and research to gain new insights into ocean ecosystems and biodiversity and ways the ocean can sequester and store carbon.&nbsp; Marine life, changing ocean conditions, and plastic and other pollution pay no attention to national boundaries. &nbsp;That is why&nbsp;we must focus on a worldwide approach to conservation and sustainability.&nbsp; In collaboration with our international partners, my Administration will continue America&#8217;s global leadership in ocean science, stewardship, and conservation.&nbsp; Our&nbsp;engagement in international efforts, such as the United Nations Decade of Ocean Science for Sustainable Development, reflects the priorities and values of my Administration to ensure that ocean science delivers greater benefits for the American people, the people of the world, and international ocean ecosystems.</p>



<p>My Administration is also committed to delivering climate justice, including ensuring equitable access to our ocean and coasts for all Americans &#8212; and working to ensure that Indigenous Americans, Black Americans, and other people of color are no longer forced to shoulder disproportionate climate and environmental burdens, as they historically have.&nbsp; My Administration will work hard to further break down the barriers many communities of color face by creating new opportunities to diversify ocean-related access and workforces. &nbsp;We will also equip educators with tools to teach our Nation&#8217;s youth how to become a powerful generation of ocean stewards.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is imperative that we take proper action now to ensure that the ocean continues to thrive.&nbsp; During National Ocean Month, we recognize the central role of a healthy ocean in sustaining all of our lives, and pledge to find innovative ways to conserve, protect, and restore our ocean.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim June 2021 as National Ocean Month. &nbsp;I call upon Americans to take action to protect, conserve, and restore our ocean and coasts.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty‑one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Great Outdoors Month, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/01/a-proclamation-on-great-outdoors-month-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 18:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19313</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America&#8217;s great outdoors, diverse landscapes, and pristine waterways are a limitless source of pride, inspiration, and sustenance of both body and soul &#8212; and an essential part of our national identity. &#160;It is our shared responsibility as Americans to be good stewards of these irreplaceable treasures for our children and grandchildren, and for generations to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America&#8217;s great outdoors, diverse landscapes, and pristine waterways are a limitless source of pride, inspiration, and sustenance of both body and soul &#8212; and an essential part of our national identity. &nbsp;It is our shared responsibility as Americans to be good stewards of these irreplaceable treasures for our children and grandchildren, and for generations to come. &nbsp;During Great Outdoors Month, we celebrate our Nation&#8217;s natural wonders, and rededicate ourselves to conserving nature&#8217;s splendor for all Americans and safeguarding our environment against the existential threat of climate change and other challenges.</p>



<p>Our Nation is blessed by an abundance of incredible outdoor spaces that provide opportunities for exploration, recreation, and rejuvenation. &nbsp;From the Sierra Nevadas to the Ozark Trail to the Everglades &#8212; to local trails and parks in every part of the country &#8212; the outdoors inspire creativity, provide educational opportunities, and bring communities together.&nbsp; This past year, so many of us have developed an even greater appreciation for the powerful role that outdoor spaces play in our physical and mental well-being &#8212; providing outlets for activity, solace, and&nbsp;connection in the midst of a devastating pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now more than ever, we must rise to meet the challenges of&nbsp;environmental degradation, climate change, and inequitable access to nature.&nbsp; The natural world provides critical resources that sustain all life on Earth &#8212; from the air we breathe and the water we drink to the food we eat.&nbsp; Ensuring that we maintain healthy ecosystems and a resilient planet is not just a matter of environmentalism.&nbsp; It is also critical to our health, our safety, the security of our families, and the strength of our economy.</p>



<p>My Administration is committed to taking swift action to address the existential threat of climate change. &nbsp;I have proposed a major investment to put Americans to work building critical industries to produce and deploy clean technologies &#8212; reducing harmful emissions, and putting us on the path to a more&nbsp;sustainable and equitable future while creating millions of&nbsp;good-paying jobs.&nbsp; We are going to put Americans to work building a clean, resilient power grid; capping hundreds of thousands of abandoned oil and gas wells and coal mines to put a&nbsp;stop to methane leaks; constructing the next generation of electric vehicles; and developing new carbon capture and green hydrogen technologies on farms and in factories to make everything from our steel and cement to our agricultural sector cleaner and more sustainable.&nbsp; We will also speed up implementation of the Great American Outdoors Act, which invests in conservation projects that will benefit communities across the country &#8212; including Black and brown communities that have too often been excluded from our great outdoor spaces. My&nbsp;Administration has also outlined a new &#8220;America the Beautiful&#8221; initiative to bring the Federal Government together with State, Tribal, and local partners to conserve at least 30&nbsp;percent of our lands and waters by 2030. &nbsp;</p>



<p>During Great Outdoors Month, I encourage all Americans to&nbsp;explore our Nation&#8217;s beautiful outdoor spaces.&nbsp; As we enjoy the&nbsp;great outdoors &#8212; from national parks to our own backyards &#8212; let us rededicate ourselves to conserving our Nation&#8217;s natural spaces for our own well-being, and for the health, safety, prosperity, and fulfillment of generations to come.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim June 2021 as Great Outdoors Month. &nbsp;I urge all Americans to explore the great outdoors, to experience our Nation&#8217;s natural heritage, and to continue our Nation&#8217;s tradition of preserving and conserving our lands for future generations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty‑one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-fifth.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Caribbean-American Heritage Month, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/01/a-proclamation-on-national-caribbean-american-heritage-month-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 18:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America&#8217;s diversity is and always has been the defining strength of our Nation &#8212; in every generation, our society, spirit, and shared ambitions have been refreshed by wave after wave of immigrants seeking out their American dream. &#160;Throughout our history, Caribbean Americans have brought vibrant cultures, languages, traditions, and values that strengthen our country and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America&#8217;s diversity is and always has been the defining strength of our Nation &#8212; in every generation, our society, spirit, and shared ambitions have been refreshed by wave after wave of immigrants seeking out their American dream. &nbsp;Throughout our history, Caribbean Americans have brought vibrant cultures, languages, traditions, and values that strengthen our country and add new chapters to our common story. &nbsp;In recognition of Caribbean Americans&#8217; countless gifts and contributions to our Nation, we celebrate National Caribbean-American Heritage Month.</p>



<p>Caribbean Americans have made our country more innovative and more prosperous; they have enriched our Nation&#8217;s arts and culture, our public institutions, and our economy. &nbsp;I am honored to celebrate this National Caribbean-American Heritage Month alongside Caribbean-American barrier-breaking public servants in my Administration &#8212; including Vice President Kamala Harris, Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro Mayorkas, Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona, and Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice &#8212; all of whom continue to be sources of pride and inspiration for Caribbean Americans across the country.</p>



<p>Caribbean-American intellects and artists like James Weldon Johnson, the poet who gave us the anthem, <em>Lift Every Voice and Sing;</em> celebrated neo-expressionist painter Jean-Michel Basquiat; and John B. Russwurm, the first Caribbean-American editor of a U.S. newspaper, have left a lasting impact on our country.&nbsp; Caribbean-American jurists like Constance Baker Motley, the first Black woman appointed to the Federal bench, and the Nation&#8217;s first Latina Supreme Court Justice, Sonia Sotomayor, have made innumerable contributions to the American justice system.&nbsp; Shirley Chisholm, the daughter of Caribbean immigrants, blazed new trails as our Nation&#8217;s first Black Congresswoman &#8212; and the first Black woman to launch a major-party bid for the Presidency.&nbsp; Public servants like Antonia Novello, our Nation&#8217;s first female Surgeon General, and Colin Powell, our first Black Secretary of State, have followed in her footsteps, charting new paths of their own in service to the American people.</p>



<p>Despite the powerful legacy of achievement of Caribbean Americans, many members of the Caribbean-American community continue to face systemic barriers to equity, opportunity, and justice.&nbsp; Systemic racism has uniquely impacted Black and Latino immigrant communities, including Caribbean Americans, leading to disparities in health care, education, housing, criminal justice, and economic opportunity.&nbsp; My Administration is committed to addressing those entrenched disparities &#8212; and to bringing our Nation closer to its promise that all people are created equal and deserve to be treated equally throughout their lives.&nbsp; That is why I have launched a whole-of-government approach to advancing racial justice and equity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During National Caribbean-American Heritage Month, we celebrate the legacy and essential contributions of Caribbean Americans who have added so much to our American fabric.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2021 as National Caribbean-American Heritage Month. &nbsp;I encourage all Americans to join in celebrating the history, culture, and achievements of Caribbean Americans with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty‑one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-fifth.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Immigrant Heritage Month, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/01/a-proclamation-on-national-immigrant-heritage-month-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 13:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America is, always has been, and always will be a Nation of immigrants.&#160; It was the premise of our founding; it is reflected in our Constitution; it is etched upon the Statue of Liberty &#8212; that &#8220;from her beacon-hand glows world-wide welcome.&#8221;&#160; During National Immigrant Heritage Month, we reaffirm and draw strength from that enduring&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America is, always has been, and always will be a Nation of immigrants.&nbsp; It was the premise of our founding; it is reflected in our Constitution; it is etched upon the Statue of Liberty &#8212; that &#8220;from her beacon-hand glows world-wide welcome.&#8221;&nbsp; During National Immigrant Heritage Month, we reaffirm and draw strength from that enduring identity and celebrate the history and achievements of immigrant communities across our Nation.</p>



<p>Across each generation throughout our history, wave after wave of immigrants have enriched our Nation and made us better, stronger, more innovative, and more prosperous. &nbsp;The American story includes the story of courageous families who ventured here &#8212; be it centuries ago, or just this year &#8212; from every part of the world to seek new possibilities and help to forge our Nation.&nbsp; In every era, immigrant innovators, workers, entrepreneurs, and community leaders have fortified and defended us, fed us and cared for us, advanced the limits of our thinking, and broken new ground.</p>



<p>After an especially difficult period marked by both the COVID-19 pandemic and the all-too-frequent demonization of immigrants, it is vital that our Nation reflect on the leadership, resilience, and courage shown by generations of immigrant communities, and recommit ourselves to our values as a welcoming Nation.&nbsp; We recognize all of the workers, many of whom are immigrants, who have contributed to the food security, health, and safety of all Americans during this challenging year &#8212; and every year. &nbsp;And we honor the sacrifices made by immigrants who serve on the front lines of the pandemic as health care providers, first responders, teachers, grocers, farm workers, and other essential workers. &nbsp;It was these same immigrant families and communities of color who were disproportionately struck by the virus. &nbsp;In honor of those we&#8217;ve lost, let us dedicate ourselves as a Nation to protecting one another and doing our part to put an end to this pandemic for good.</p>



<p>The promise of our Nation is that every American has a fair shot and an equal chance to get ahead, yet systemic racism and persistent barriers have denied this promise to far too many immigrants throughout our history and today.&nbsp; I have placed equity at the center of my Administration&#8217;s agenda.&nbsp; From day one, I promised that my Administration would reflect the full diversity of our Nation &#8212; and today, nearly one-third of my Administration&#8217;s 1,500 political appointees are naturalized U.S. citizens or children of immigrants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have directed Federal agencies to rebuild trust in our immigration system that has been lost, to reach out to underserved communities unable to access the opportunities our Nation offers them, to offer again a welcoming humanitarian hand to the persecuted and oppressed, and to reduce barriers to achieving citizenship and equality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I am honored to serve alongside Vice President Harris, the first daughter of immigrants to hold the Office of the Vice President, and to work with so many dedicated public servants who are immigrants &#8212; and who carry with them every day the legacies of their families&#8217; sacrifice and resilience.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Despite the progress our Nation has made since our founding, there is more work to be done to extend the full promise of America to all our people. &nbsp;Nearly 11 million people in this country are undocumented &#8212; and it is time that the Congress acts by passing the U.S. Citizenship Act of 2021, the immigration reform plan that I introduced on day one of my Presidency.&nbsp;My plan would provide a pathway to lawful permanent residency and citizenship for these undocumented immigrants, including Dreamers, individuals with Temporary Protected Status, farm workers, and other essential workers who contribute to our Nation every day.</p>



<p>Vice President Harris and I affirm that immigrants historically have made and continue to make our Nation stronger. &nbsp;I urge my fellow Americans to join us this month in celebrating immigrant heritage, stories, and cultures.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2021 as National Immigrant Heritage Month. &nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to learn more about the history of immigrant communities throughout the generations following our Nation&#8217;s founding, and to observe this month with appropriate programming and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer Pride Month, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/01/a-proclamation-on-lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-and-queer-pride-month-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The uprising at the Stonewall Inn in June, 1969, sparked a liberation movement &#8212; a call to action that continues to inspire us to live up to our Nation&#8217;s promise of equality, liberty, and justice for all.&#160; Pride is a time to recall the trials the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer (LGBTQ+) community has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The uprising at the Stonewall Inn in June, 1969, sparked a liberation movement &#8212; a call to action that continues to inspire us to live up to our Nation&#8217;s promise of equality, liberty, and justice for all.&nbsp; Pride is a time to recall the trials the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer (LGBTQ+) community has endured and to rejoice in the triumphs of trailblazing individuals who have bravely fought &#8212; and continue to fight &#8212; for full equality. &nbsp;Pride is both a jubilant communal celebration of visibility and a personal celebration of self-worth and dignity.&nbsp; This Pride Month, we recognize the valuable contributions of LGBTQ+ individuals across America, and we reaffirm our commitment to standing in solidarity with LGBTQ+ Americans in their ongoing struggle against discrimination and injustice.</p>



<p>The LGBTQ+ community in America has achieved remarkable progress since Stonewall.&nbsp; Historic Supreme Court rulings in recent years have struck down regressive laws, affirmed the right to marriage equality, and secured workplace protections for LGBTQ+ individuals in every State and Territory.&nbsp; The Matthew Shepard and James Byrd, Jr. Hate Crimes Prevention Act broadened the definition of hate crimes to include crimes motivated by sexual orientation or gender identity.&nbsp; Members of the LGBTQ+ community now serve in nearly every level of public office &#8212; in city halls and State capitals, Governors&#8217; mansions and the halls of the Congress, and throughout my Administration. &nbsp;Nearly 14&nbsp;percent of my 1,500 agency appointees identify as LGBTQ+, and I am particularly honored by the service of Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg, the first openly LGBTQ+ person to serve in the Cabinet, and Assistant Health Secretary Dr. Rachel Levine, the first openly transgender person to be confirmed by the Senate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For all of our progress, there are many States in which LGBTQ+ individuals still lack protections for fundamental rights and dignity in hospitals, schools, public accommodations, and other spaces.&nbsp; Our Nation continues to witness a tragic spike in violence against transgender women of color.&nbsp; LGBTQ+ individuals &#8212; especially youth who defy sex or gender norms &#8212; face bullying and harassment in educational settings and are at a disproportionate risk of self-harm and death by suicide.&nbsp; Some States have chosen to actively target transgender youth through discriminatory bills that defy our Nation&#8217;s values of inclusivity and freedom for all.</p>



<p>Our Nation also continues to face tragic levels of violence against transgender people, especially transgender women of color. &nbsp;And we are still haunted by tragedies such as the Pulse Nightclub shooting in Orlando. &nbsp;Ending violence and discrimination against the LGBTQ+ community demands our continued focus and diligence. &nbsp;As President, I am committed to defending the rights of all LGBTQ+ individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My Administration is taking historic actions to finally deliver full equality for LGBTQ+ families. &nbsp;On my first day in office, I signed an Executive Order charging Federal agencies to fully enforce all Federal laws that prohibit discrimination on the basis of gender identity or sexual orientation. &nbsp;As a result, the Federal Government has taken steps to prevent discrimination against LGBTQ+ people in employment, health care, housing, lending, and education.&nbsp; I also signed an Executive Order affirming all qualified Americans will be able to serve in the Armed Forces of the United States &#8212; including patriotic transgender Americans who can once again proudly and openly serve their Nation in uniform &#8212; and a National Security Memorandum that commits to supporting LGBTQ+ Federal employees serving overseas.&nbsp; My Administration is also working to promote and protect LGBTQ+ human rights abroad.&nbsp; LGBTQ+ rights are human rights, which is why my Administration has reaffirmed America&#8217;s commitment to supporting those on the front lines of the equality and democracy movements around the world, often at great risk.&nbsp; We see you, we support you, and we are inspired by your courage to accept nothing less than full equality.</p>



<p>While I am proud of the progress my Administration has made in advancing protections for the LGBTQ+ community, I will not rest until full equality for LGBTQ+ Americans is finally achieved and codified into law.&nbsp; That is why I continue to call on the Congress to pass the Equality Act, which will ensure civil rights protections for LGBTQ+ people and families across our country. &nbsp;And that is why we must recognize emerging challenges, like the fact that many LGBTQ+ seniors, who faced discrimination and oppression throughout their lives, are isolated and need support and elder care.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During LGBTQ+ Pride Month, we recognize the resilience and determination of the many individuals who are fighting to live freely and authentically.&nbsp; In doing so, they are opening hearts and minds, and laying the foundation for a more just and equitable America.&nbsp; This Pride Month, we affirm our obligation to uphold the dignity of all people, and dedicate ourselves to protecting the most vulnerable among us.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2021 as Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer Pride Month.&nbsp; I call upon the people of the United States to recognize the achievements of the LGBTQ+ community, to celebrate the great diversity of the American people, and to wave their flags of pride high.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-Harris Administration Champions LGBTQ+ Equality and Marks Pride Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/01/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-champions-lgbtq-equality-and-marks-pride-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden issued a proclamation affirming June 2021 as Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer (LGBTQ+) Pride Month, marking a time a time of hope, progress, and promise for LGBTQ+ Americans across the country. After four years of relentless attacks on LGBTQ+ rights, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken historic actions to accelerate the march&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden issued a proclamation affirming June 2021 as Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer (LGBTQ+) Pride Month, marking a time a time of hope, progress, and promise for LGBTQ+ Americans across the country. After four years of relentless attacks on LGBTQ+ rights, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken historic actions to accelerate the march toward full LGBTQ+ equality. From protecting the civil rights of every LGBTQ+ American, enabling all qualified Americans – including transgender Americans – to serve their country in uniform, ensuring that LGBTQ+ Americans are leaders at every level of the federal government, to protecting and defending the human rights of LGBTQ+ persons around the world, the Biden-Harris Administration is a consistent and reliable partner in the fight for equality at home and abroad.</p>



<p>Too many LGBTQ+ Americans across our nation continue facing discrimination and hate, especially LGBTQ+ people of color and transgender Americans, and some states are attempting to roll back the clock on equality with discriminatory bills that target LGBTQ+ people and families. The Biden-Harris Administration reaffirms that no one should face discrimination or harassment because of who they are or whom they love. As President Biden said during his first joint address to Congress, the President has the back of LGBTQ+ people across the country and will continue fighting for full equality for every American – including through continuing to urge the U.S. Senate to pass the Equality Act and provide overdue civil rights protections to LGBTQ+ people and families across the country. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This Pride Month, the Biden-Harris Administration celebrates the historic progress made towards LGBTQ+ equality since President Biden took office, including:</p>



<p><strong>Signing One of the Most Comprehensive Executive Orders in History on LGBTQ+ Rights on His First Day in Office.&nbsp;</strong>Within hours of taking the oath of office, President Biden signed an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-preventing-and-combating-discrimination-on-basis-of-gender-identity-or-sexual-orientation/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;Preventing and Combating Discrimination on the Basis of Gender Identity or Sexual Orientation. The Executive Order established that it is the official policy of the Biden-Harris Administration to prevent and combat discrimination against LGBTQ+ individuals, and to fully enforce civil rights laws to prevent discrimination on the basis of gender identity or sexual orientation. The President directed all federal agencies to implement fully all federal laws that prevent discrimination on the basis of sex, to include sexual orientation and gender identity. This Executive Order is one of the most consequential policies for LGBTQ+ Americans ever signed by a U.S. President. As a result of that Order, agencies have already taken key steps to advance LGBTQ+ equality.</p>



<ul><li>The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS)&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/05/10/hhs-announces-prohibition-sex-discrimination-includes-discrimination-basis-sexual-orientation-gender-identity.html">announced</a>&nbsp;it will interpret and enforce Section 1557 of the Affordable Care Act and Title IX to prevent discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>To address the pervasive discrimination LGBTQ+ families continue to face in housing, the Department of Housing and Urban Development&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/hud_no_21_021">announced</a>&nbsp;it will interpret the Fair Housing Act to prevent discrimination in housing and rental assistance against LGBTQ+ people. HUD will require state and local jurisdictions who receive funding through its Fair Housing Assistance Program to apply the same protections.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>In response to the continuing discrimination many LGBTQ+ individuals face in credit and lending services, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau&nbsp;<a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/about-us/newsroom/cfpb-clarifies-discrimination-by-lenders-on-basis-of-sexual-orientation-and-gender-identity-is-illegal/">announced</a>&nbsp;that it will enforce against discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity in credit and lending services.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The Department of Justice&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/crt/page/file/1383026/download">issued new guidance</a>&nbsp;to agencies clarifying that Title IX sex discrimination protection includes protection on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>To ensure that LGBTQ+ Veterans are treated with dignity and respect, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) has undertaken an&nbsp;<a href="https://blogs.va.gov/VAntage/85152/secretary-orders-review-vas-transgender-policies/">agency-wide review</a>&nbsp;of its policies and practices to remove barriers that transgender veterans and their families face.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>To advance protections for incarcerated individuals who are transgender, the Department of Justice filed a statement of interest in litigation clarifying that it is DOJ’s position that transgender prisoners should be assigned to housing that aligns with their gender identity, and that transgender prisoners should receive medically-necessary gender affirming care.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Launching a Whole-Of-Government Initiative to Advance Equity and Justice for Underserved Communities, Including LGBTQ+ Communities.&nbsp;</strong>On his first day in office, President Biden signed a historic&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-advancing-racial-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through-the-federal-government/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;establishing a cross-government initiative to advance equity and justice for communities who have been left behind, underserved, or discriminated against by federal policies, laws, and programs, including LGBTQ+ communities. The President directed all agencies to take steps to advance equity by taking comprehensive action to root out bias from federal programs and policies, engage with underserved communities, and ensure that federal resources equitably reach all Americans, including LGBTQ+ Americans.</p>



<p><strong>Enabling All Qualified Americans to Serve Their Country in Uniform.&nbsp;</strong>In his first week in office, President Biden&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/25/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-enabling-all-qualified-americans-to-serve-their-country-in-uniform/">signed</a>&nbsp;an Executive Order reversing the ban on openly transgender servicemembers serving in the Armed Forces, enabling all qualified Americans to serve their country in uniform. President Biden believes that gender identity should not be a bar to military service, America’s strength is found in its diversity, and an inclusive military strengthens our national security As a result of his Executive Order, the Department of Defense issued new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Releases/Release/Article/2557220/dod-announces-policy-updates-for-transgender-military-service/">policies</a>&nbsp;which prohibit discrimination against transgender servicemembers, provide a path for transgender servicemembers to access gender-affirming medical care, and require that all transgender servicemembers are treated with dignity and respect. Patriotic transgender servicemembers are once again able to openly and proudly serve our Nation in uniform.</p>



<p><strong>Advancing an Equitable Recovery from COVID-19 for LGBTQ+ Americans across the Country.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden knows that LGBTQ+ individuals and families have been disproportionately burdened by the COVID-19 health crisis and economic crisis. Even before COVID-19, LGBTQ+ Americans were more likely to be uninsured and unemployed, and were more likely to experience poverty, have a pre-existing condition, and experience food insecurity. These barriers have posed unique risks to the physical and financial health of LGBTQ+ people during this crisis. The President’s American Rescue Plan makes significant investments in an equitable recovery, and is helping LGBTQ+ families across the country recover from COVID-19 by:</p>



<ul><li>Addressing food insecurity among LGBTQ+ communities by increasing the value of nutrition assistance by 15 percent.</li><li>Advancing health equity for LGBTQ+ Americans, who remain more likely to be uninsured, by improving access to and affordability of health coverage through the Marketplace, and expanding mental health resources.</li><li>Supporting LGBTQ+ Americans, who are more likely to experience unemployment and continue to face discrimination in the job market, by extending unemployment insurance benefits critical to helping many families, including LGBTQ+ families, stay afloat.</li><li>Addressing the disproportionate rates of housing insecurity and homelessness faced by LGBTQ+ Americans, especially transgender youth, by expanding emergency rental assistance programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Signing and Leading Implementation of a Presidential Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex Persons Around the World.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/04/memorandum-advancing-the-human-rights-of-lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-queer-and-intersex-persons-around-the-world/">directed</a>&nbsp;all agencies engaged abroad to ensure that United States diplomacy and foreign assistance promote and protect the human rights of LGBTQ+ persons. His Memorandum establishes that it “shall be the policy of the United States to pursue an end to violence and discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, or sex characteristics, and to lead by the power of our example in the cause of advancing the human rights of LGBTQ+ persons around the world.” As previously&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-is-advancing-lgbtqi-human-rights-at-home-and-across-the-globe/">highlighted</a>&nbsp;by the White House, Departments and Agencies are already making progress in areas towards the goals outlined in the &nbsp;Presidential Memorandum, including: strengthen existing efforts to combat the criminalization by foreign governments of LGBTQ+ people and expand efforts to combat discrimination, homophobia, transphobia, and intolerance on the basis of LGBTQ+ status or conduct; protect vulnerable LGBTQ+ refugees and asylum seekers; help ensure the Federal Government has a swift and meaningful response to serious incidents that threaten the human rights of LGBTQ+ persons abroad; and build coalitions with like-minded nations to counter discrimination against LGBTQ+ people around the world.</p>



<p><strong>Establishing the White House Gender Policy Council to Advance Gender Equity and Equality.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden signed an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/08/executive-order-on-establishment-of-the-white-house-gender-policy-council/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;establishing the White House Gender Policy Council to advance gender equity and equality across the whole of the government, including by addressing barriers faced by LGBTQ+ people, in particular transgender women and girls, across our country. &nbsp;<br><br><strong>Ensuring Educational Environments are Free from Sex Discrimination and Protecting LGBTQ+ Students from Sexual Harassment.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden signed an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/08/executive-order-on-guaranteeing-an-educational-environment-free-from-discrimination-on-the-basis-of-sex-including-sexual-orientation-or-gender-identity/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;recommitting the Federal Government to guarantee educational environments free from sex discrimination, including sexual harassment and including discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity, and directing the Department of Education to review and as necessary consider revising agency actions that are inconsistent with that policy. The Executive Order charged the Department of Education with reviewing the significant rates at which students who identify as LGBTQ+ are subject to sexual harassment, including sexual violence.</p>



<p><strong>Signing a National Security Memorandum Supporting Federal Employees Serving Overseas, including LGBTQ+ Employees.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden signed a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/04/memorandum-revitalizing-americas-foreign-policy-and-national-security-workforce-institutions-and-partnerships/">National Security Memorandum</a>&nbsp;on Revitalizing America’s Foreign Policy and National Security Workforce, Institutions, and Partnerships. The Memorandum directs agencies to take steps to retain, develop, promote, and support LGBTQ+ and other national security employees, and employees with LGBTQ+ family members.<br><br><strong>Ensuring Transgender Americans Can Access Emergency Shelter That Dignifies and Respects Their Identity.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Housing and Urban Development&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/HUD_No_21_069">restored protections</a>&nbsp;for transgender individuals seeking emergency shelter and homeless services. HUD reaffirmed its commitment that no person be denied access to housing or other critical services because of their gender identity.<br><br><strong>Creating a Historically Diverse Cabinet and Administration.&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;The Biden-Harris Administration includes barrier-breaking LGBTQ+ leaders, including Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg, who is the first openly gay Cabinet Secretary confirmed by the U.S. Senate, and Assistant Secretary for Health Dr. Rachel Levine, who is the first openly transgender person ever confirmed by the U.S. Senate. President Biden has assembled the most diverse Administration in our Nation’s history, and is proud to serve alongside the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/29/fact-sheet-100-days-in-biden-harris-administration-makes-history-with-presidential-appointees/">14 percent</a>&nbsp;of all appointees who identify as lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer.</p>



<p><strong>Issuing the First White House Proclamation for Transgender Day of Visibility.&nbsp;</strong>On March 31, 2021 President Biden became the first U.S. President to issue a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/31/a-proclamation-on-transgender-day-of-visibility-2021/">proclamation</a>&nbsp;commemorating Transgender Day of Visibility. The proclamation honored and celebrated the achievements and resiliency of transgender individuals and communities, and recognized the generations of struggle, activism, and courage that have brought our country closer to full equality for transgender and gender non-binary people in the United States and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Ensuring Pride Flags Fly on U.S. Embassies Around the World. </strong>The State Department announced it will allow U.S. diplomatic outposts to fly the Pride flag on the same flagpole as the U.S. flag at their embassy or consulate, demonstrating that the United States will lead on LGBTQI+ human rights around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
