<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 19:31:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and Environmental Protection Agency Administrator Michael&#160;Regan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/17/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-environmental-protection-agency-administrator-michael-regan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 19:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Cleveland, Ohio 10:09 A.M. EST&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; So, hi, everyone.&#160; It’s great to be joined by EPA Administrator Michael Regan on our trip to Lorain, Ohio.&#160;Building a better America requires us to confront legacy pollution and clean up the environment, ensuring our kids drink clean water and creating good-paying union&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Cleveland, Ohio</p>



<p>10:09 A.M. EST<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, hi, everyone.&nbsp; It’s great to be joined by EPA Administrator Michael Regan on our trip to Lorain, Ohio.<br>&nbsp;<br>Building a better America requires us to confront legacy pollution and clean up the environment, ensuring our kids drink clean water and creating good-paying union jobs in the process.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, today, President Biden will announce $1 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to accelerate cleanup and restoration of the Great Lakes’ most environmentally degraded sites.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks to these investments, we are tackling climate change, strengthening our nation’s resilience to extreme weather, and providing clean drinking water, all while creating good-paying union jobs.<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I will turn it over to Administrator Regan who will give out &#8212; give a topper for you guys and then take maybe two or three questions, and then head back.<br>&nbsp;<br>Administrator?<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Listen, it&#8217;s an honor to join President Biden for this $1 billion investment in the restoration of Great Lakes.&nbsp; This is good all around.&nbsp; You know, the Great Lakes support drinking water for about 40 million residents.&nbsp; And also, this billion dollars will support about 1.3 million jobs while also protecting ecosystems so we can have a balanced ecosystem.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re really excited about that.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is a shot in the arm.&nbsp; Of the 25 sites along the Great Lakes that are listed as areas of concern, we believe that this billion-dollar investment will allow for us to clean up 23 of those 25 by the year 2030, so &#8212; 22 of 25 by 2030.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re really excited about expediting some of these projects, expediting the cleanup, continuing to provide safe drinking water, but also looking at infrastructure investments and work that will create a more resilient Great Lakes from climate change, as well as from pollution like PFAS and some of the legacy pollutions that we&#8217;ve seen in the Great Lakes.&nbsp; So, exciting day for the folks in Ohio as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Administrator, I have a climate change question for you.&nbsp; What timeline do you see the remaining U.S. coal plants getting shut down?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And if the Supreme Court limits the EPA&#8217;s ability to regulate greenhouse gas emissions, how much of a blow will that be to the President&#8217;s climate agenda, and how will you decarbonize the power sector?<br>&nbsp;<br>ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;re paying close attention to this Supreme Court case.&nbsp; Obviously, that case is focused on the specific regulation of greenhouse gases and whether we can regulate outside the fence line.&nbsp; But nevertheless, you know, EPA has bread-and-butter regulations that also focus on the power sector as well.&nbsp; We focus on regional haze, regulating mercury, coal ash contamination.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we are aligning all of our regulations so that we can basically present a suite of regulations to the industry at one time so that they can understand all of the investments that they will need to protect public health and the environment.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ll have to determine whether or not those investments warrant the longevity of these coal plants.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, when you look at the bread-and-butter regulations that are true to the Clean Air Act, which we&#8217;re obligated to execute on, plus what the Supreme Court is going to do, we see a future of tremendous economic pressure on this industry.&nbsp; And I think the industry will have to determine how they close and when they close.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, regardless of where the Supreme Court goes, you think that the economic pressure will be enough?<br>&nbsp;<br>ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; I think that there are a lot of public health regulations that span air quality, water quality, and land management that these utilities have to take into consideration to determine, again, what investments will they have to make today to comply with those laws and what the longevity of these various coal plants are across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It will vary from state to state, plant to plant, but at least we are in a position where we want to begin rolling out these regulations so that there&#8217;s no surprise.&nbsp; We want certainty.&nbsp; We want the industry to have certainty.&nbsp; But we also want the environmental community and our folks that are looking at public health to understand that EPA is going to do its job.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to do our job.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to follow our statutory authority, our regulatory authority.&nbsp; And we hope many of the aspects that the President is advocating for in Build Back Better will help complement this glide path.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Administrator, how much of today&#8217;s announcement is due to the fact that the President&#8217;s Build Back Better plan has stalled on Capitol Hill?&nbsp; There isn&#8217;t much sign of progress up there.&nbsp; How much of today&#8217;s announcement is due to that and the fact that that plan, which has a lot of climate and environmental provisions that a lot of supporters were hoping would pass, has stalled out right now and that fate is uncertain?<br>&nbsp;<br>ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; Which announcement are you referring to?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today.&nbsp; The Great Lakes and promoting what the infrastructure bill does for the environment.<br>&nbsp;<br>ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; Oh, I think that this announcement is a wonderful opportunity to highlight why the President led this effort for the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; I mean, this at heart is an infrastructure action.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the infrastructure bill.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, again, $1 billion investing in shoring up the drinking water for over 40 million people; all of the projects that go into ecosystem protection &#8212; dredging, pollution contamina- &#8212; pollution containment &#8212; this is an opportunity to highlight that the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law really does focus on infrastructure, people, jobs, and the environment.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>None of this is &#8212; you know, you don&#8217;t have to choose between a healthy environment and economic prosperity.&nbsp; And the President is demonstrating that they actually go hand-in-hand.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Administrator.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Can we ask you some Russia questions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, no, absolutely.&nbsp; Are you guys done?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>ADMINISTRATOR REGAN:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, give me one second, guys.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, Karine, if you could just speak up; it was hard to hear your opening.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I’m sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard. &nbsp;Yeah. &nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m trying to be safe here, so I apologize.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Zeke.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; First, does the White House have any response to Moscow expelling the deputy chief of mission?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, so Russia&#8217;s actions against our deputy chief of mission, who was a key member of the embassy&#8217;s leadership team, was unprovoked.&nbsp; Now more than ever, it is critical that our countries have the necessary diplomatic personnel in place to facilitate communication between our governments.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The State Department has said they consider this as an escalatory step.&nbsp; And I would refer you &#8212; I would refer you to them for further comment on this.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On that subject, the President said that he believes there’s a &#8220;high&#8221; risk now of a &#8212; of a further Russian invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; Does the President plan to adjust his travel schedule or his meetings in the next couple of days to monitor the situation?&nbsp; Was there any discussion of canceling this trip so that he could monitor the situation in Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; any updates on any travel for this President.&nbsp; As you know, the &#8212; a President deals with multiple things at one time.&nbsp; And so, what &#8212; but as the President said, this is a &#8220;very high&#8221; risk &#8212; the question that he was asked on his way to Air Force One.<br>&nbsp;<br>But as we have said, we are in the window where we believe an attack could come at any time and that it would be preceded by a fabricated pretext that the Russians use as an excuse to launch an invasion, which could take many forms.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we believe it&#8217;s important that the world be watching for that pretext and that people treat any such claims with the appropriate skepticism, especially when they come from Russian state media sources and aren&#8217;t backed up by the independent media reporter &#8212; reporting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Russia relies on confusion and obfuscation to cover its attacks.&nbsp; We would all expect &#8212; expect it and be ready for it.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s just from the (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just pick up on the pretext, Karine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would one of those pretexts be where Moscow might be planning to stage an incident in the rebel-held areas to justify an attack on Ukraine from the east?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, just &#8212; let me just give you some examples.&nbsp; So that false pretext could take a number of different forms: a provocation in Donbas; a claim about NATO activity by land, at sea, or in the air; an incursion into Russian territory.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so we are &#8212; already have seen an increase in false claims by the Russians in the past few days, including reports of an unmarked grave of civilians &#8212; of civilians allegedly killed by the Ukrainian armed forces; statements Ukraine is committing genocide in eastern Ukraine; that the U.S. and the Ukraine are developing biological or chemical weapons; and what the West &#8212; that the West is funneling in guerrillas to kill locals.&nbsp; Each of these allegation is categorically false.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve been very clear about this, and we should expect more false, again, reports from Russian state media over the coming days.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen this playbook before from Russia: their previous military incursions into Ukraine and in Georgia.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, again, this is &#8212; this is something that we are anticipating and that the President has talked about to expect a potential pretext.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can the White &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President planning to do anything to change Putin’s mind?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me &#8212; I just want to &#8212; I also want to lay out some stuff that we’re doing today.&nbsp; So you guys &#8212; I think you guys saw the reporting that Secretary Blinken will speak directly to the U.N. Council this morning on his way to Munich about the gravity of the situation in Ukraine, and signal our intense commitment to diplomacy, to offer and emphasize the path toward de-escalation, and to make it clear to the world that we are doing everything we can to prevent war.<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; but the evidence on the ground is that Russia is moving toward an imminent invasion.&nbsp; This week, the Russian government said that it would withdraw troops from the broder [sic] &#8212; from the Ukraine border.&nbsp; And they received a lot of attention for that claim but &#8212; here and around the world.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we know that is absolutely false, which you&#8217;ve heard us say from &#8212; coming from our administration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, we have now confirmed that, in the last several days, Russia has increased its troops presence along that Ukraine border by as many as 7,000 troops, with some arriving in the past 24 hours.&nbsp; This is cause of serious concerns.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So the Russians have also said in recent days that they are prepared to engage in diplomacy as we and our allies have repeatedly offered.&nbsp; But every indication we now know is they mean only to engage in Potemkin diplomacy where they publicly offer to talk and make claims about de-escalation while privately mobilizing for war.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we continue to receive indications that they could launch a false pretext, as I just mentioned, and so we just want to make sure that the world is aware and knows that this is a possibility, because it is indeed part of the Russian playbook.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ukraine says that pro- &#8212; Ukraine says that pro-Russian forces &#8212; excuse us.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>(Gaggle interrupted.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ukraine says that pro-Russian forces have &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, the door is broken, guys.&nbsp; Hold on one second.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ah.&nbsp; Please hold.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; A broken door.&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Try &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let’s try this again.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Trying again.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Ukraine says that pro-Russian forces have shelled a kindergarten.&nbsp; Can the White House confirm that that is the case?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that one more time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That pro-Russian forces have shelled a kindergarten in Ukraine &#8212; i.e. attacked a kindergarten.&nbsp; Is that intelligence that the White House can confirm?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I cannot confirm that from here.&nbsp; That is something that the Department of Defense can &#8212; we should &#8212; I refer you to them.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have that intel or information, and so I don&#8217;t have anything here to share on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And in terms of the false-flag warnings that you said, do you have any sense of &#8212; I mean, the President said the invasion could happen at any time.&nbsp; Do you have any sense of timing for these false-flag operations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we have said that we are within the window of an invasion happening, which could be led by a pretext.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have an exact timing for you, but we had said it could happen before the &#8212; during the Olympics or after.&nbsp; And so we are in that window, which is why you heard from the President directly, saying that it is a very high possibility.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just last on this topic for me.&nbsp; What else is the White House doing or planning to do to prepare Americans for the possibility of a war in Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, one of the reasons that the President spoke the other day is to speak directly to the American public and to the world about what to expect and what process and &#8212; what process we were taking in this crisis that Russia, remember, has created.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, he wanted to be direct.&nbsp; He wanted to lay down what we&#8217;ve been doing for the last several months, the last several weeks for the American public, and talked about the impact of this potential &#8212; if Russia decides to invade, how this would impact the American public.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s one way that the President is communicating with the American public.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we have been very, very clear, the President has been very clear for the last several months, the last several weeks, and being &#8212; and being transparent about how we&#8217;re moving forward with our European allies and partners in this moment, and what we&#8217;re trying to do to deter and how we&#8217;re trying to go to the direction of diplomacy.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so that is &#8212; that is the direction that we&#8217;re still working on, hence why Secretary Blinken is up in New York today and will continue to have those conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, are there any plans for the President to pick up the phone and call Vladimir Putin?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think he answered that himself not too &#8212; moments ago.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to read out.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more to add to what the President said.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on a quick, separate issue: Does the President have confidence that the Senate will be able to avert a government shutdown?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; As you know, we work closely with the Senate and with Congress in general, and that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s our &#8212; that&#8217;s our path: is to avert a government shutdown.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s our what?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That&#8217;s our path: to avert a government shutdown.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he received assurances from congressional (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more to say except that that is something, clearly, that is a priority for us to make sure that there is not a government shutdown, and we are in constant communication with members on the Hill.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, has President Biden been able to review the written response from Russia?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s his reaction to that so far?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; This is the &#8212; the written &#8212; the response?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I can confirm we just received a response from the Russian Federation, and we will refer you to State.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything yet specific to share.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say &#8212; has he been able to see it this morning before coming on this trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I cannot confirm.&nbsp; I think he did answer this question on his way here, but I don&#8217;t have anything more to share.&nbsp; I would refer you to State on any specifics.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, Taiwan&#8217;s ambassador to the U.S. has said that they want to be part of this Indo-Pacific new economic framework that you guys are about to launch, but instead they have applied for the CPTPP instead.&nbsp; Do you have any comment on this and on the broader fact that, you know, allies and partners in the region are, frankly, unhappy that the Indo-Pacific economic framework does not include opening up American markets, which is the thing that they most want in order to become closer to the U.S. rather than China?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, that work is well underway as we consult with the Indo-Pacific partners, Congress, and other stakeholders.&nbsp; We’ll have more to share as the process is ongoing.&nbsp; As I just started saying, it&#8217;s underway.<br>&nbsp;<br>This framework would define our shared objectives around trade facilitation, standards for a digital economy and technology, supply chain resiliency, decarbonization and clean energy, infrastructure, worker standards, and other areas of share interest.<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t have more information to share at this time, but we are committed to strengthening trade and investment in the region in a manner that promotes good-paying American jobs, high standards, and supply chain resiliency, and offer the same benefits for our Indo-Pacific partners.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the other thing that you&#8217;ve been promising to launch early this year is the Build Back Better World plan, which was supposed to be early this year.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s still another one of those things that you&#8217;ve been promising since June.&nbsp; And so, what&#8217;s the holdup?&nbsp; We know that Daleep Singh has made these listening tours to Latin America, to Africa.&nbsp; Is it that you&#8217;re not finding enough pilot projects, or is it COVID? Or what&#8217;s the holdup?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, the President is very committed to his Build &#8212; the Build Back Better World plan.&nbsp; So, at the United State- &#8212; as the United States and our partners further develop and implement the Build Back Better World initiative, we recognize that robust, meaningful partnership will be critical to ensure that Build Back Better World delivers infrastructure that meets the needs of middle- and lower-income countries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s what our team has been doing: traveling to South &#8212; South America, as you just mentioned, Africa, and the Middle East.&nbsp; We will have more details to come in the coming months on how to continue to implement this initiative and the projects the U.S. government is investing with allies and partners.&nbsp; And like I said, this is something that the President is committed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you’re confirming that the launch is going to be delayed?&nbsp; Just confirming that the launch of BW- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We’ll just &#8212; we’ll have more to share in the next several months.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re &#8212; continue to work with &#8212; yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, has the President interviewed any potential Supreme Court nominees?&nbsp; And where is he right now in this process of evaluating potential picks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, the President has had &#8212; he&#8217;s had a series of discussions with lawmakers from both sides of the aisle.&nbsp; You know, he continues to review materials as he considers deeply qualified candidates, as you’ve heard us say &#8212; immensely qualified candidate with strong experience, character, integrity, dedication to the Constitution and the rule of law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Potentially, you know, he could begin talking to &#8212; interviewing nominees as soon as this week, but I don&#8217;t have any specifics to share.&nbsp; The thing that I can confirm is that &#8212; and as you&#8217;ve heard me say before and as you’ve heard Jen say before &#8212; is that we are going &#8212; he is going to have a selection by the end of this month.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, I couldn’t hear.&nbsp; You said “he could begin” &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So he could begin interviewing potential nominees as soon as this week, but I do not have any &#8212; anything to provide.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today is Thursday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Good &#8212; good point.&nbsp; Good point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does that mean that he has not &#8212; does that mean that he has not done an interview yet?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I just don&#8217;t have anything to confirm for you right now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Monday, you were able to tell us that he hadn&#8217;t interviewed anyone then.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Because you had asked over the weekend and what he was doing that weekend.&nbsp; And I was able to &#8212; I &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, he’s just not been working for four days?&nbsp; Like, what&#8217;s going on? &nbsp;(Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to share or to confirm or not confirm on this.&nbsp; This is something &#8212; again, he&#8217;s reviewing materials &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Don’t the American people deserve to know what the President is doing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; I think the President &#8212; they’ll know when he makes his selection and how he came to that process once he has selected that person.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, this is something that the President knows how this goes, as being the Chair of the Judiciary Committee for many years, having to &#8212; having oversaw &#8212; overseen many Supreme Court nomination hearings.&nbsp; He knows how this process works &#8212; being the Vice President. &nbsp;So this is nothing new to him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But he wants to make sure &#8212; again, this is a rigorous process.&nbsp; He wants to make sure that this important life- &#8212; lifetime commitment is done in a way that&#8217;s, again, rigorous and has &#8212; and lands with the most qualified &#8212; he picks the most qualified person to have (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jenny &#8212; Jenny hasn’t had a chance yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jenny.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On &#8212; back on the Russia issue and the sanctions package and the Congress that&#8217;s broken down, you could say, on the bipartisan measures.&nbsp; Right now, it seems like they&#8217;re just headed towards a resolution to support Ukraine.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; do you think that&#8217;s sufficient, or would you want to see a bipartisan sanctions package to show resolve?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, it&#8217;s important to show a united front to Russia.&nbsp; We appreciate the bipartisanship support for actions we&#8217;ve taken and will take if Russia further invades Ukraine.&nbsp; So that is important to show that force of bipartisanship.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, we continue to believe that a bipartisan bill will send the strongest message to Putin and serve as a united show of force.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s &#8212; you know, that&#8217;s &#8212; we think it&#8217;s important that they&#8217;re doing that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it doesn’t seem like they&#8217;re headed that way.&nbsp; I mean, the Republicans basically pulled out of negotiations, and now it just seems like a non-binding resolution.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, we&#8217;ll leave that process to Congress.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re saying is: We appreciate the bipartisan support that we have seen from Congress in the past several weeks for the actions and what we&#8217;re trying to do, clearly in partnership, in lockstep &#8212; partnership with European allies and partners.&nbsp; And so, we think that&#8217;s important, showing that force.&nbsp; But anything with Congress, I will leave it to them to talk about and see (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more on another issue in Congress that is important to you and has sort of broken down: on the competition China bill.&nbsp; That also seems to have stalled. &nbsp;There&#8217;s not really any sign that they&#8217;re moving to conference or that, you know, either &#8212; both chambers are in at the same time.&nbsp; So the timing and the substance seem to be a problem here.&nbsp; Can you lay out a little bit how you&#8217;re trying to get this over the finish line?&nbsp; Of course, this won&#8217;t be doable before the State of the Union.&nbsp; How important is it for the President what you&#8217;re doing there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, it&#8217;s important.&nbsp; And, you know, we are in constant communication with Congress on a whole &#8212; whole list of issues.&nbsp; And that, clearly, is one that&#8217;s critical and important.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll just continue to have those conversations with Congress.&nbsp; It is important to us to make &#8212; to move forward with that.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to continue to make sure that we&#8217;re talking to Congress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any sense of timing on when this would &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a sense of timing on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one follow-up on the deputy ambassador who was pushed out of Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Expelled.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Will there be any retaliation from the U.S. side for that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything. &nbsp;Literally, that just happened, so I don&#8217;t have anything to share on what happens next.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to pick up on the State of the Union &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just to put a fine point on Zeke&#8217;s question about today&#8217;s trip, you know, a senior State Department official said this morning that this &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; On whose trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I said: Just to put a fine point on Zeke’s question about this trip today &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; a senior State Department official this morning said that this is “perhaps the most perilous moment for peace and security since the end of the Cold War.”&nbsp; So can &#8212; you know, is there concern that this trip could distract the President from thinking about Ukraine and Russia?&nbsp; Is there a member of his national security team traveling today who&#8217;s going to keep him updated?&nbsp; Like, how are you managing to juggle, you know, both of these things?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I go back to what I said before: Every President, whether it&#8217;s a Democrat President &#8212; a Democratic President or a Republican, has dealt with multiple crises at once.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what this President is doing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He was Vice President before.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been in the Senate.&nbsp; He knows how to deal with diff- &#8212; you know, multiple &#8212; again, multiple crises at the same time.&nbsp; We have an NSC person that travels with him at all trips, and he will be kept updated.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is not going to deter him from what he needs to do for the American public.&nbsp; This is just part of the job.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, the President has been very clear.&nbsp; He has spoken about how we are moving with our &#8212; again, with our European allies and partners forward with dealing with the crisis that Russia has created on the Ukraine border.&nbsp; And that has not changed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He &#8212; as you know, we&#8217;ve read out multiple conversations that he&#8217;s had with leaders.&nbsp; He spoke to the Germany Chancellor yesterday to get an update from him.&nbsp; He spoke to Putin just on Saturday.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s continuing to have conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our &#8212; his NSC staff, and Secretary Blinken, the Department of Defense &#8212; Secretary Austin &#8212; are all talking to their counterparts practically every day.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; he&#8217;s going to keep &#8212; he&#8217;s going to be able to keep up to date on what&#8217;s happening.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who has the President called today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who &#8212; is the President calling anyone today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a call to read out today.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a call to (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more follow-up.&nbsp; Does this &#8212; given what the President just said, that it seems like it&#8217;s headed towards a potential invasion in the coming days, does this make him change his weekend plans at all?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new on his &#8212; on his weekend pro- &#8212; plans or change in plans.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to pick up on the State of the Union, does the President expect to deliver his speech in a chamber where people don&#8217;t have to wear masks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, I &#8212; look, we&#8217;re going to follow the guidance &#8212; the CDC guidance.&nbsp; And clearly, we&#8217;ll be in touch with &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But where is he right now in terms of lifting up federal &#8212; you know, CDC guidance in terms of masks and other health protocols?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Just in general?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we follow &#8212; I mean, we&#8217;ve been pretty clear about this: We follow the CDC guidance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we follow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; And Jeff Zients is saying that they&#8217;re going to change it sometimes, maybe this week or next.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right, well, they&#8217;re looking at all of the guidance; that&#8217;s what Dr. Walensky said yesterday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; No, what I mean is: The last time the President spoke, he said that, you know, he &#8212; he feels like it&#8217;s too early, too premature.&nbsp; Is that changing at all?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, what he said was: We have to look at the science and we got to look at what &#8212; and listen to the experts.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing by allowing CDC to go through their process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As to what comes next, I don&#8217;t have anything to do.&nbsp; They&#8217;re an independent body.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to make that decision.&nbsp; And Dr. Walensky spoke to that specifically yesterday, and I&#8217;ll leave that to what she said.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one last thing from me.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President still expecting to host in person the U.S.-ASEAN Summit in Washington?<br>&nbsp;<br>(The plane experiences turbulence.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, my gosh.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s also supposed to happen early this year.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Give me one second as I try to hold on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; President Biden looks for &#8212; looks forward &#8212; looks forward to welcoming ASEAN leaders to Washington, D.C., for a U.S.-ASEAN special summit in the coming months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t have more details to share at this time, but we&#8217;ll keep you all posted.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are committed to strengthening our partnership with ASEAN as well as its &#8212; as to its cert- &#8212; centrala- &#8211;centrality.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been working to deepen our cooperation in the region and promote a free and open Indo-Pacific.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, will he address the Ukraine situation at all at the top of his speech today in Ohio, or is just going to be Great Lakes?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, the focus here is the billion-dollar initiative that we &#8212; that you just heard from the EPA Administrator focusing on the Great Lakes and what we&#8217;re doing, how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is delivering in that component of what &#8212; what we talk about, and making sure that the climate change &#8212; and we&#8217;re doing what we can to clean &#8212; to clean the Great Lakes.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s going to be the focus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;s going to talk about that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be there with the local representative who&#8217;s going to meet us on the ground.&nbsp; As you know, the EP- &#8212; the EPA Administrator is there &#8212; is here joining us for this trip, and that&#8217;s going to be the focus of today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, does he plan on meeting with the congressional delegation, the local &#8212; Tim Ryan who is running for Senate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, today &#8212; we&#8217;ll &#8212; I don&#8217;t think any &#8212; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t think we have anybody else besides the re- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kaptur?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s anybody else that&#8217;s going to be on the ground.&nbsp; I think the two senators had other &#8212; have other things.&nbsp; Like, I think they had some votes that they needed to get to or deal with.&nbsp; So, we don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; anything more to share on their involvement for today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you say &#8212; the Ohio governor is not here, correct?&nbsp; Not going to meet him &#8212; meet with him today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No. No.&nbsp; Though I &#8212; we&#8217;ll have a list of who is going &#8212; who is going to be on the ground with us.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was the Ohio governor invited?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; You know, we &#8212; we &#8212; you know, when we visit a state, we always reach out to the governor and to the local electeds in that state, include &#8212; including congressional members that represent that district.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re in constant communication with folks when we come into the state.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything else on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have &#8212; do you have one more comment on Iran?&nbsp; It&#8217;s going &#8212; moving into, like, the final phases.&nbsp; Do you have anything to comment on the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, I do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the latest &#8212; on negotiations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have the latest on negotiations, but I &#8212; you know, I do have what we have been &#8212; what we have said with talks before, which is that Iran &#8212; with Iran, you know, it reached an urgent point on mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We won&#8217;t negotiate in public, as we have said before, but we can say a deal that addresses the core concerns of all sides is in sight.&nbsp; If it&#8217;s not reached in the coming weeks, however, Iran&#8217;s ongoing nuclear advances will make it impossible for us to return to the JCPOA.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here&#8217;s the bottom line here: We&#8217;re confronting a very dangerous situation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Under the JCPOA, Iran&#8217;s nuclear program was slightly constrained and monitored by international inspectors.&nbsp;&nbsp;Since the previous administration ceased U.S. participation in the deal, Iran has rapidly accelerated its nuclear program and reduced cooperation with international inspectors in nonperformance of JCPO- &#8212; commitments.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Thanks, Karine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>10:39 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Marine One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/17/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 15:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 9:17 A.M. EDT    Q    Mr. President, how high is the threat of a Russian invasion right now?  THE PRESIDENT:  It&#8217;s very high. Q    Why? THE PRESIDENT:  It’s very &#8212; because they have not &#8212; they have not moved any of their troops out.  They’ve moved more troops in, number one.  Number two, we have reason to believe&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>9:17 A.M. EDT   <br> <br>Q    Mr. President, how high is the threat of a Russian invasion right now? <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  It&#8217;s very high.<br> <br>Q    Why?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  It’s very &#8212; because they have not &#8212; they have not moved any of their troops out.  They’ve moved more troops in, number one.  Number two, we have reason to believe that they are engaged in a false-flag operation to have an excuse to go in.  Every indication we have is they&#8217;re prepared to go into Ukraine, attack Ukraine &#8212; number one. <br> <br>Number two, I&#8217;ve been waiting for a response from Putin for my letter that &#8212; my response to him.  It’s come to that Moscow embassy.  They&#8217;re faxing it here.  Not faxing it, they&#8217;re sending it here.  I have not read it yet.  I cannot comment on it.<br> <br>Q    Have you been briefed on it in any way?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  No- &#8212;<br> <br>Q    Do you think he&#8217;s going to go through with this, sir?  Is your sense that this is going to happen now?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Yes.  Not &#8212;<br> <br>Q    When?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I &#8212; my sense is this will happen within the next several days. <br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>Q    How many days are we talking?<br> <br>Q    Is there any diplomatic path still available, Mr. President? <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Yes, there is.  There&#8217;s a clear diplomatic path.  That&#8217;s why I asked Senator &#8212; Senator &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; Secretary Blinken to go to the United Nations and make his statement today.  He&#8217;ll lay out what that path is.  I&#8217;ve laid out a path to Putin as well on, I think, Sunday.  And so, there is a path.  There is a way through this, but by diplomacy.<br> <br>Q    Will you speak to Putin again? <br> <br>Q    Are you going to call Putin?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m not calling Putin.  I have no plans to call Putin right now.  Thank you.<br> <br>9:18 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call Previewing the Vice President&#8217;s Trip to Munich,&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/16/background-press-call-previewing-the-vice-presidents-trip-to-munich-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 02:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  6:18 P.M. EST &#160;MODERATOR:&#160; Hey, thanks.&#160; And thank you, everyone, for joining us today.&#160; As mentioned, today&#8217;s call is to preview the Vice President&#8217;s trip to Munich.&#160; This call will be on background, attributed to &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;&#160; And the contents are embargoed until the end of the call.&#160; And by joining the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Via Teleconference</em><strong> </strong></p>



<p>6:18 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hey, thanks.&nbsp; And thank you, everyone, for joining us today.&nbsp; As mentioned, today&#8217;s call is to preview the Vice President&#8217;s trip to Munich.&nbsp; This call will be on background, attributed to &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;&nbsp; And the contents are embargoed until the end of the call.&nbsp; And by joining the call you are agreeing to those ground rules.<br><br>For your awareness, our speakers today are [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].&nbsp;Hereinafter&nbsp;they&#8217;ll&nbsp;be&nbsp;referred to as &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;<br><br>But before we get to the Vice President&#8217;s program in Munich, I wanted to turn over to another speaker, [senior administration official], who will offer some brief opening remarks.&nbsp;<br><br>So, over to you, [senior administration official].<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I just wanted to give everybody an update on the latest situation in Russia and Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>So, yesterday, the Russian government said it was withdrawing troops from the border with Ukraine.&nbsp; They received a lot of attention for that claim both here and around the world, but we now know it was false.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, we have now confirmed that in the last several days, Russia has increased its troop presence along the Ukrainian border by as many as 7,000 troops, with some arriving as recently as today.&nbsp;<br><br>The Russians have also said in recent days that they are prepared to engage in diplomacy as we and our Allies have repeatedly offered.&nbsp; But every indication we have now is they mean only to publicly offer to talk and make claims about de-escalation while privately mobilizing for war.&nbsp;<br><br>We continue to receive indications that they could launch a false pretext at any moment to justify an invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; That false pretext could take a number of different forms: a provocation in the Donbas; a claim about NATO activity by land, at sea, or in the air; an incursion into Russian territory.&nbsp;<br><br>We have already seen an increase in false claims by the Russians in the past few days, including reports of an unmarked grave of civilians allegedly killed by the Ukrainian armed forces, statements that the U.S. and Ukraine are developing biological or chemical weapons, and that the West is funneling in guerrillas to kill locals.&nbsp; Each of these allegations is categorically false, and we should expect more false reports from Russian state media over the coming days.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen this playbook before: their previous military incursions into Ukraine and in Georgia.&nbsp;<br><br>We don&#8217;t know what form the false pretext will take, but we hope the world is ready.&nbsp; Just as Russia&#8217;s claims about withdrawing troops were false, so will be whatever false pretext they invent to justify this war of choice.&nbsp; No one should take these claims at face value.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Nevertheless, we will continue to pursue diplomacy over the coming days while being prepared to respond swiftly and decisively if Russia chooses to launch a new attack on Ukraine.<br><br>Russia keeps saying it wants to pursue a diplomatic solution; their actions indicate otherwise.&nbsp; We hope they will change course before starting a war that will bring catastrophic death and destruction.&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks.&nbsp; And I will now turn it over to the other senior administration officials.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; And just before we get there &#8212; just to confirm, all the speakers that are speaking today are on background to be referred to as &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;&nbsp; So, all the remarks here are as &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>With that, thank you to our first speaker.&nbsp; We’ll now turn it over to preview the Vice President&#8217;s trip to Munich.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a pleasure to have this opportunity to talk with everybody.&nbsp; As you all have just heard, we are in a very decisive moment.&nbsp; And the Vice President is leading the U.S. delegation to the Munich Security Conference this year as a resounding signal that engagement with our Allies and partners is an absolutely critical part of our overall diplomacy and our approach to this situation.&nbsp;<br><br>Throughout the course of her trip, you can expect that she will be discussing the full range of issues:&nbsp;<br><br>First, the unity that we have achieved with our European allies and that we are determined to maintain.&nbsp;<br><br>Second, the economic measures that we have prepared and may need to deploy depending on how things play out.&nbsp;<br><br>Third, U.S. and NATO force posture.<br><br>Fourth, support for Ukraine.<br><br>And five, the diplomatic path to de-escalation that we have offered, that we hope the Russians will take us up on.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll just have to wait and see.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, as you know, we have already undertaken very intensive engagements with our Allies and partners over the course of the last several months, and the Vice President&#8217;s trip will be a high-level continuation of those efforts.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>At Munich, there will be several dozen world leaders present, and all of them are going to be focused on this very pressing challenge that is at the top of mind for us.&nbsp; So, we expect that the conference, but particularly the Vice President&#8217;s schedule, is going to be very intense and it will include a series of high-stakes, high-level diplomatic talks.<br><br>She will be engaging with a number of leaders, and I&#8217;m going to mention just a few.&nbsp;<br><br>On Friday, she is going to meet with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg.&nbsp; She will also have a multilateral meeting with the leaders of the three Baltic states: Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia.&nbsp;<br><br>In both of these meetings, she will discuss the latest developments related to Russia&#8217;s build-up on Ukraine&#8217;s border, our work together on deterrence and diplomacy, our force posture and our readiness to further reinforce NATO Allies on the eastern flank.&nbsp; And, of course, she will, as she always does, reaffirm our sacred commitment to NATO&#8217;s Article 5 commitment.<br><br>In addition to those international meetings, the Vice President will also hold a separate engagement with the congressional members who are attending the Munich Security Conference.&nbsp; There will be a very large contingent of congressional members &#8212; two large bipartisan, bicameral codels are attending.&nbsp; And their intention is to use their participation to demonstrate the commitment of the United States to our Allies and our partners, and to show that it is both bipartisan and very, very strongly held.<br><br>So, with that, let me turn it over to my colleague, who will take us&nbsp;through Saturday&nbsp;and address a couple of other issues.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; I’ll walk you through the second day, Saturday, of what is really a busy weekend of activities.&nbsp; And the main event on Saturday will be the Vice President’s speech as a formal part of the Munich Security Conference.&nbsp; And in this speech, as throughout her public engagements over the weekend, she will be addressing the situation on Ukraine’s border and the threat of Russian aggression and the latest state of play in what obviously has been &#8212; remains a fluid situation.</p>



<p>I won’t get into hugely specific details about her speech, but I can give you some of the themes I think you can expect her to address.&nbsp; And one would be stock-taking of the really remarkable unity that we’ve achieved across the transatlantic community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reality is we think that the West is more united and NATO is stronger than they have been in decades.&nbsp; And that applies to our diplomacy, where we have together put forward our diplomatic approach to Russia; militarily, where we&#8217;ve coordinated extremely closely on force posture adjustments that we&#8217;ve been making together with our NATO Allies; and then on the economic side as well, including the severe sanctions that we intend to impose on Russia if it further invades Ukraine.</p>



<p>The Vice President will underscore how that unity is a source of strength that will allow us to respond swiftly and severely to any further Russian aggression.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would just note on that, on these themes, you know, this is something that the Biden-Harris administration has emphasized from day one &#8212; the importance of allies and partners across the board, not just in security issues and not just in Europe, but, in general, the importance of allies and alliances.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;re seeing that play out in this crisis in Europe today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Her speech will also focus on reassuring our allies and partners of our commitments and how we&#8217;re committed to bolstering NATO and reinforcing our allies in the face of Russian aggression.&nbsp; And she&#8217;ll talk about how a further invasion of Ukraine, we believe, will leave Russia weaker and not stronger.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, lastly, she will also address the broader stakes here.&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;re focused mostly on the very serious threat to the country of Ukraine.&nbsp; But it goes beyond that.&nbsp; Russia poses a threat, in what it&#8217;s doing here, to the European and international order.&nbsp; And the Vice President will underscore that and make it clear.</p>



<p>After the speech, she&#8217;ll have a number of other engagements with other world leaders on the margins of the conference, and we&#8217;ll provide details as they happen.&nbsp; I suspect it&#8217;ll be a large numbers &#8212; large number.&nbsp; As you know, there are a lot of leaders at the conference, but I&#8217;ll just flag two of particular importance here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One is that she’ll meet with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine.&nbsp; And that&#8217;ll be a real opportunity to underscore our commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and to further coordinate the diplomatic efforts that have been underway to provide economic and defensive security assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, secondly, we anticipate she&#8217;ll have the opportunity to engage with Chancellor Scholz of Germany &#8212; I should say “further opportunity” to engage.&nbsp; As you know, he was here at the White House just last week.&nbsp; And the Vice President looks forward to the opportunity to speak further with him about this crisis and more.</p>



<p>So that is a sense of the speech and what we have planned for the second day in Munich.</p>



<p>The last thing I would say before we look forward to your questions: Just to note that, in addition to Vice President Harris&#8217;s engagement &#8212; engagements with heads of state in Munich, some of which we&#8217;ve described, the State Department announced earlier today that Secretary Blinken is also traveling to Munich to engage with his foreign ministry counterparts.&nbsp; Our Ambassador to NATO, Julie Smith, will also be there.&nbsp; And this just further underscores the importance of this gathering at this particular critical time.<br>Thanks a lot.&nbsp; And with that, maybe over to my colleague to open it up for questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Moderator, could you please provide instructions to ask questions?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; Can you hear me?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I am just curious about, you know, a lot of the details that were laid out, obviously, at the top of the call.&nbsp; And how does sort of the calculus change if Russia does invade Ukraine when the Vice President is in Munich?&nbsp; If you can just talk a little bit about the contingencies that have been planned for a situation like that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Nandita.&nbsp; Thanks very much for the question.&nbsp; As my colleague said at the start, we are in a fluid situation.&nbsp; This is something that we&#8217;ve talked about from the very beginning in terms of what we have seen in terms of the buildup and the fact that it is continuing.</p>



<p>And our determination to stand together with our Allies, to have very strong unity within NATO as well as across the European Union is unflagging.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Her reason for going to Munich is to meet with what we think is over three dozen heads of state who will be there.&nbsp; She will hold these highest-level meetings to consult with them on the latest developments and to ensure that the transatlantic community, the NATO Alliance, that we speak with one voice that is strong and resolute.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Community Violence Intervention Collaborative&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/16/readout-of-white-house-community-violence-intervention-collaborative-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 23:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director Julie Rodriguez convened the third national meeting of The White House Community Violence Intervention Collaborative (CVIC), a cohort of 16 jurisdictions committed to using American Rescue Plan funding or other public funding to scale and strengthen their CVI infrastructure. Investing in evidence-based community&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director Julie Rodriguez convened the third national meeting of The White House Community Violence Intervention Collaborative (CVIC), a cohort of 16 jurisdictions committed to using American Rescue Plan funding or other public funding to scale and strengthen their CVI infrastructure. Investing in evidence-based community violence interventions (CVI) to reduce gun violence is a key pillar of President Biden’s comprehensive strategy to prevent and respond to gun crime. Mayors, law enforcement leaders, CVI experts, and representatives from more than a dozen philanthropic institutions participated in today’s meeting, along with the four lead training and technical assistance (TTA) providers—Cities United, Community Based Public Safety Collective, Health Alliance for Violence Intervention (HAVI), and the National Institute of Criminal Justice Reform—and Hyphen, which anchors the initiative.</p>



<p>Announced in June 2021, the Collaborative is an 18-month initiative to enhance partnerships and coordination in each jurisdiction and to facilitate peer-to-peer learning around effective community-based public safety strategies. National experts and federal agencies are providing training and technical assistance (TTA) to help communities assess their existing public safety ecosystem, identify gaps, and build the capacity to expand programming that saves lives and provides needed services to communities impacted by gun violence.<br><br>To date, CVIC jurisdictions have committed more than $300 million of American Rescue Plan funds to invest in public safety and CVI strategies. Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and Intergovernmental Affairs Director Julie Rodriguez called upon CVIC participants – including mayors, law enforcement, community violence intervention leaders, and philanthropic supporters – to expediently deploy these dollars so community violence intervention programs and CVIC communities can expand their capacity ahead of the summer months, when gun crime historically increases.</p>



<p>Jurisdictions participating in the CVI Collaborative include:</p>



<ul><li>Atlanta, GA</li><li>Austin, TX</li><li>Baltimore, MD</li><li>Baton Rouge, LA</li><li>Chicago, IL</li><li>Detroit, MI</li><li>King County, WA</li><li>Los Angeles, CA</li><li>Memphis, TN</li><li>Miami-Dade County, FL</li><li>Minneapolis &amp; St. Paul, MN</li><li>Newark, NJ</li><li>Philadelphia, PA</li><li>Rapid City, SD</li><li>St. Louis, MO</li><li>Washington, DC</li></ul>



<p>Philanthropies supporting CVIC include:</p>



<ul><li>Arnold Ventures  </li><li>Ballmer Group </li><li>The California Endowment </li><li>The California Wellness Foundation </li><li>The Annie E. Casey Foundation </li><li>Emerson Collective </li><li>Ford Foundation</li><li>Heising-Simons Foundation  </li><li>Joyce Foundation </li><li>Kresge Foundation </li><li>The John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation </li><li>Microsoft Corporation </li><li>Open Society Foundations </li><li>Silicon Valley Community Foundation </li><li>Charles and Lynn Schusterman Family Philanthropies</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces OSTP&#160;Leadership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/16/president-biden-announces-ostp-leadership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 23:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced that Dr. Alondra Nelson will perform the duties of director of the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) and Dr. Francis Collins will perform the duties of Science Advisor to the President and Co-Chair of the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology until&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced that Dr. Alondra Nelson will perform the duties of director of the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) and Dr. Francis Collins will perform the duties of Science Advisor to the President and Co-Chair of the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology until permanent leadership is nominated and confirmed. These appointments will allow OSTP and the President’s Science and Technology agenda to move seamlessly forward under proven leadership.<br><br>Nelson currently serves as OSTP’s Deputy Director for Science and Society. Nelson has directed priority efforts to protect the integrity of science in the federal government, broaden participation in STEM fields, strengthen the U.S. research infrastructure, and ensure that all Americans have equitable access to the benefits of new and emerging technologies and scientific innovation. She has played a key role in overseeing the implementation of the President’s early directives on Restoring Trust in Government Through Scientific Integrity and Evidence-Based Policymaking and on Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government.<br><br>Collins recently stepped down as the director of the National Institutes of Health, after serving as its Director for more than 12 years, under three Presidents. As the longest serving Presidentially-appointed director of NIH he oversaw the work of the largest supporter of biomedical research in the world, from basic to clinical research. He was awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom in November 2007. He will continue to run a research lab at NIH, which he has run since 1993.<br><br>In the selections of Dr. Alondra Nelson and Dr. Francis Collins, President Biden has doubled down on science. The selections are responsive to the dual importance of a strong OSTP that can drive science and technology solutions to our greatest challenges – and the very specific attention the President wants to give to the creation of a new ARPA-H research and discovery agency, the building of support for a Cancer Moonshot 2.0, the search for a new head of NIH, and the broad advisory work of PCAST.<br><br><strong>Dr. Alondra Nelson, Deputy Director of Science and Society of OSTP and Performing the Duties of Director of OSTP<br></strong><br>Alondra Nelson, Ph.D., serves as the inaugural Deputy Director for Science and Society in the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy. In this role, she brings social science expertise, including attention to issues of social inequality, explicitly into the work of Federal science and technology strategy and policy. Dr. Nelson is also Harold F. Linder Chair and Professor at the Institute for Advanced Study, an independent research center in Princeton, NJ. She was president of the Social Science Research Council, an international research nonprofit from 2017-2021. She was previously professor of sociology at Columbia University, where she also served as the inaugural Dean of Social Science. Dr. Nelson’s research contributions are situated at the intersection of political and social citizenship, on the one hand, and emerging science and technology, on the other. Dr. Nelson connects these dimensions in a range of widely acclaimed publications, including, most recently, The Social Life of DNA. Dr. Nelson is a member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the American Academy of Political and Social Science, the American Philosophical Society, and the National Academy of Medicine.<br><br><strong>Dr. Francis Collins, Acting Science Advisor to the President and Acting Co-Chair of the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology</strong><br><br>Francis S. Collins, M.D., Ph.D., is the former director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH). As the longest serving Presidentially-appointed director of NIH — spanning 12 years and three presidencies — he oversaw the work of the largest supporter of biomedical research in the world, from basic to clinical research. Dr. Collins is a physician-geneticist noted for his landmark discoveries of disease genes and his leadership of the international Human Genome Project, which culminated in April 2003 with the completion of a finished sequence of the human DNA instruction book. Dr. Collins&#8217; research laboratory has discovered a number of important genes, including those responsible for cystic fibrosis, neurofibromatosis, Huntington&#8217;s disease, a familial endocrine cancer syndrome, and most recently, genes for type 2 diabetes, and the gene that causes Hutchinson-Gilford progeria syndrome, a rare condition that causes premature aging. Dr. Collins is an elected member of the Institute of Medicine and the National Academy of Sciences. Dr. Collins was awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom in November 2007, the National Medal of Science in 2009, and the Templeton Prize in 2020.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Secretary General of Japan’s National Security Secretariat Akiba&#160;Takeo</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/16/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-secretary-general-of-japans-national-security-secretariat-akiba-takeo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 22:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Akiba Takeo, Secretary General of Japan’s National Security Secretariat, to discuss the ongoing situation in Russia and Ukraine. Sullivan reviewed recent developments on the ground, and noted that Russian forces remain postured to attack Ukraine at any time. The two discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts by the international&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Akiba Takeo, Secretary General of Japan’s National Security Secretariat, to discuss the ongoing situation in Russia and Ukraine. Sullivan reviewed recent developments on the ground, and noted that Russian forces remain postured to attack Ukraine at any time. The two discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts by the international community and Sullivan reiterated President Biden’s statement that the door remains open to diplomacy. Sullivan thanked Secretary General Akiba for Japan’s recent decision to divert some Liquefied Natural Gas supplies to Europe, and he underscored the importance of a strong international response to any further Russian aggression against Ukraine. Secretary General Akiba emphasized that Japan is committed to closely coordinating with the United States and the G-7 in response to further Russian aggression against Ukraine.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/16/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-chancellor-olaf-scholz-of-germany-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 22:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany. The leaders discussed their respective conversations with President Putin and President Zelenskyy regarding Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. They reaffirmed their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and underscored the importance of continued transatlantic coordination on diplomacy and deterrence measures and the reinforcement of NATO’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany. The leaders discussed their respective conversations with President Putin and President Zelenskyy regarding Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. They reaffirmed their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and underscored the importance of continued transatlantic coordination on diplomacy and deterrence measures and the reinforcement of NATO’s eastern flank if Russia further invades Ukraine. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 16,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/16/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-16-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 21:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:09 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Okay, a couple of items for you at the top. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Today, we learned that retail sales increased by 3.8 percent in January, exceeding expectations.&#160; This strong, inflation-adjusted increase reflects the resilience of the economy, even in the face&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:09 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Okay, a couple of items for you at the top.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, we learned that retail sales increased by 3.8 percent in January, exceeding expectations.&nbsp; This strong, inflation-adjusted increase reflects the resilience of the economy, even in the face of Omicron.<br><br>Compared to this time last year, sales at grocery stores, restaurants, and clothing stores, among others, increased, underscoring the strength of the American economy as we recovered from the pandemic.<br><br>This data builds on the historic economic progress we’ve seen over the last year and an extremely strong jobs report last month despite Omicron, which was well above expectations.<br><br>In 2021, the economy created 6.7 million jobs &#8212; the strongest year of job growth on record.&nbsp; The unemployment rate declined more than any year on record.&nbsp; And we achieved a 4 percent unemployment rate years earlier than previously projected thanks to the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>Small-business applications and inflation-adjusted household income are both up, and child poverty and hunger are down.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re obviously going to continue to build on this progress.<br><br>Second, today we’re marking 60 days of action strengthening America’s trucking workforce.&nbsp; This is not just about recruitment but also retaining truckers to ensure we can move more goods around the country and lower costs for the American people.<br><br>Over 70 percent of all goods in America are shipped by truck, and America’s trucking workforce plays a critical role in the supply chain and the broader economy.<br><br>But outdated infrastructure, the pandemic, and a historic volume of goods moving through our economy have strained capacity across the supply chain, including in trucking.<br><br>Two months ago, the President launched a multi-agency effort to support and expand access to quality truck driving jobs now and in the year ahea- &#8212; and in the years ahead.<br><br>While more work remains, we have made remarkable progress in the last 60 days.&nbsp; We have expanded Registered Apprenticeship Programs.&nbsp; We’ve launched the Safe Driver Apprenticeship Pilot to connect American adults under 21 to good-paying jobs in the trucking industry.&nbsp; We’ve cut red tape so it’s easier for drivers to get commercial driver licenses.<br><br>And we’ve met with veterans service organizations representing nearly 4 million veterans to discuss ways the administration and industry can attract, train, place, and retain veterans in trucking jobs.<br><br>And we will announce the results of the Labor Department’s 90-day apprenticeship program, of course, over the next &#8212; after the next 30 days.<br><br>This week, Secretary Buttigieg will also sign the charter document for the Women of Trucking Advisory Board, which will provide recommendations to address challenges facing women in trucking, such as barriers to entry, on-the-job safety risks, workplace harassment, mentorship, and more.<br><br>Finally, a very quick preview for the President’s trip to Ohio tomorrow.<br><br>It’s been just 90 days since &#8212; time flies &#8212; with the Pres- &#8212; since the President signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And tomorrow, he will travel to Lorain, Ohio, and deliver remarks on how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law delivers for the American people by investing in clean-up and restoration efforts in the Great Lakes region and surrounding waterways.<br><br>These investments will allow for a major acceleration of progress that will deliver significant environmental, economic, health, and recreational benefits for communities throughout the region, including helping people in the community access clean water.<br><br>So, those of you going to Ohio, now you have a little more detail.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead, Darlene.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; One, are there any plans being made for the President to meet with Republicans on the Senate Judiciary Committee as a group, the same way he met with Democrats on the committee last week?</p>



<p>     MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  So, he’s continuing to engage with Democrats and Republicans about his Supreme Court process.  I don&#8217;t have anything to preview or predict in terms of a meeting with the Senate Judiciary Republicans.<br><br>Q    Okay.  Second question.  Is there a date for when the President will send his FY23 budget proposal to the Hill?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have a date, either, for you at this point in time.  I think Shalanda Young has conveyed it was expected to be after the State of the Union.<br><br>Q    Okay.  And then the last question is: With the Vice President getting ready to go to Germany for the Munich Security Conference, can you talk a little bit about what her marching orders from the President are?  And will she be going with any deliverables or any concrete proposals, specifically to help Europe deal with its energy and natural gas needs?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, she will be traveling, as many of you have been following this know, to Munich, Germany, to attend the February 18th to 20th Munich Security Conference.  She will build on the President’s and the national security team’s intensive engagement with European allies and partners, and emphasize &#8212; and continue to emphasize with our partners our ironclad commitment to our NATO Allies, underscore our commitment to Ukraine&#8217;s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and reaffirm our shared interest in upholding the principles that have underpinned European peace and security.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; She&#8217;ll be participating in the formal conference &#8212; formal program of the conference, as well as engaging with allies and partners and meeting with leaders on the margins.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know her team is planning for a preview call for all of you, I believe later this evening, to give you more details of those bilateral meetings.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I would say, in terms of her engagements and what the President expects, he expects and knows, given she is the first in the room and the last in the room, that she will continue to convey to the rest of the world, again, our ironclad commitment to our NATO Allies, our commitment to defending the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Ukraine, and our commitment to putting in place severe economic consequences should Russia invade.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Can you comment on Russia&#8217;s investigation into claims of alleged mass graves of civilians supposedly killed by Ukrainian forces in the Russian-controlled regions in eastern Ukraine?&nbsp; Do you believe this is part of the false-flag operations that you&#8217;ve been warning of?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me start by saying, as you heard the President say yesterday and Secretary Blinken earlier today: We&#8217;re in the window where we believe an attack could come at any time, and that would be preceded by a fabricated pretext that the Russians use as an excuse to launch an invasion.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; and we&#8217;ve talked about this a bit in here &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen these tactics used in the past.&nbsp; So those could include, but not be limited to, the report you just referenced, claims of provocation in Donbas, false state media reports &#8212; which I think you should all &#8212; everybody should keep their eyes open and aware of that potential &#8212; fake videos, false accusations about chemical weapons or accounts of attacks on Russian soldiers that have not actually occurred.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So there could be a range of false flags and pretexts that we would expect would precede an invasion. &nbsp;And, again, we remain in that window.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you provide any update on the intelligence assessment of who was behind the cyberattacks of Ukraine&#8217;s Ministry of Defense and certain banks yesterday?&nbsp; Can U.S. officials say that Russia was behind the attacks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any new details on an attribution.&nbsp; Cyber attribution takes time, in part because adversaries usually try to hide their tracks and it takes time to gather and analyze relevant information.&nbsp; And these can be &#8212; these types of incidents &#8212; DDoS incidents can be particularly hard &#8212; harder to trace.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we have also been in close touch with our Ukrainian counterparts to offer support in the investigation and response to these incidents.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You may have seen the statement from the Ukraine Ministry of Defense that the United States and other partners immediately reached out with support and that some sites are coming back online.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I would note, again, as I said yesterday, we&#8217;ve been warning for months, both publicly and privately, in our engagements with the Ukrainians and the Europeans that the potential for Russia to conduct cyber operations in Ukraine is part of their playbook as well.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we&#8217;re particularly concerned, but we don&#8217;t have anything new in terms of specific attribution.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you done, Mary?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Yes, go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Okay.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughs.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Didn’t mean to interrupt.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;So polite.&nbsp;&nbsp;Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Secretary of State Blinken today said that he has seen evidence that Vladimir Putin is actually moving critical military assets toward the border with Ukraine and not away from the border as Putin has claimed.&nbsp;&nbsp;So does the administration believe that Putin is actually escalating this crisis in real time?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, I think, as Secretary Blinken also said, the Russian troops remain massed in a very threatening way at the border.&nbsp;&nbsp;And he was responding, I believe, to a question &#8212; a good question about whether they were delivering on what they had promised yesterday.&nbsp;&nbsp;And the answer was no; there&#8217;s, you know, what Russia says and there&#8217;s what Russia does.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we&#8217;re watching very closely what steps they&#8217;re taking.&nbsp;&nbsp;But they remain amassed in a threatening way at the border.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;There has not yet been, to our awareness, an actual invasion.&nbsp;&nbsp;This date had been circled on the calendar as one that this administration, that other governments worldwide were watching very closely.&nbsp;&nbsp;What do you make of the fact that at this point &#8212; it is now darkness in that region &#8212; there hasn&#8217;t been a military invasion?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, Kristen, without getting into any intelligence or conversations we would have with Allies or partners, what we had conveyed last week, and you heard Jake Sullivan convey very clearly, is that we were in the window.&nbsp; We remain in the window.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there still as much hope for diplomacy today?&nbsp; Is there more hope?&nbsp; Where does that thinking stand?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We &#8212; of course, the door continues to be open to diplomacy.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken spoke with Foreign Minister Lavrov yesterday.&nbsp; Jake Sullivan speaks with his Ukrainian counterpart nearly every day, if not every day.&nbsp; We remain &#8212; the President, of course, is going to speak with Chancellor Scholz later this afternoon.&nbsp; So there are &#8212; it is moving forward &#8212; diplomatic conversations on many channels.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One quick follow-up to a question you got yesterday about a potential gas tax holiday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said all options were on the table.&nbsp; Can you go a little further?&nbsp; Are there actually discussions going on between the White House and Democrats on Capitol Hill about moving forward with a gas tax holiday?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I also said yesterday no decisions have been made, and that remains the case.&nbsp; So we always have an open dialogue with members of Congress, and all options remain on the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One housekeeping thing first.&nbsp; Speaking of Secretary Blinken, he was at an event earlier today here in town and said he was cutting his time short there in order to have a meeting with the boss &#8212; the President.&nbsp; Was something added to the schedule this afternoon, or is there something forthcoming?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Without knowing the details of the Secretary’s schedule, I think the President had the PDB this morning, so it may have been that.&nbsp; I can check if there&#8217;s anything different than that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Beyond that, Foreign Minister Lavrov told Secretary Blinken yesterday that Russia&#8217;s written response to the U.S.-NATO proposals would be transmitted, quote, “in the coming days.”&nbsp; Has it been received, or is this potentially productive, or seen as a possible delay tactic?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we look forward to receiving it, as Secretary Blinken has conveyed.&nbsp; As of my knowledge before I came out for this briefing, I think we&#8217;re still waiting for that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any update on the U.S. assessment of the video released by Russia claiming to show some tanks ending military drills near Ukraine?&nbsp; I know there was a lot of concern about whether this was legit.&nbsp; Has there been any determination that it is?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any new assessment of that, Ed.&nbsp; I think what we are watching very closely is not just what they say but what they do.&nbsp; I understand you&#8217;re referencing a video, but we&#8217;ve also seen, as the Secretary confirmed this morning, continued problematic, troubling buildup of troops at the border and surrounding Ukraine.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to ask you if the President is meeting today or soon with Supreme Court nominees because &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What if I ans- &#8212; what if I was prepared to answer it today?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, are you?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You’re missing out.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you?&nbsp; Have there been any meetings?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I am not going to provide a &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; day-by-day update, Ed.&nbsp; I just had to mess with you there a little bit.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just for the record, I wasn’t going to ask.&nbsp; But I am curious &#8212; I am curious: This is a President who’s been a participant in this for decades.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He knows that in the run-up to a decision there is a public campaign, there&#8217;s sort of a backroom lobbying effort by people close to nominees.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been some of that going on in this case.&nbsp; What does he make &#8212; I’m not commenting specifically on anyone&#8217;s story or letters sent or anything, but what does he make of that attempt to influence an administration as they make a decision?&nbsp; And does he welcome it, or does he see it &#8212; if it gets a little too personal, perhaps, or petty &#8212; as detrimental to the process?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think because of the President&#8217;s long history and long background you referenced as the former chairman of the Judiciary Committee, as the former Vice President, I believe he&#8217;s probably overseen or been engaged with more Supreme Court nominee processes than anyone in history.&nbsp; He is not going to be swayed by public campaigns or public sniping or lobbying efforts.&nbsp; He is going to pick an eminently qualified Black woman to nominate to the Supreme Court, and he has a number of potential choices that he&#8217;s very excited about.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just real quick on this: The Club for Growth is now running ads in English and in Spanish targeting Latino audiences and suggesting that the President’s focus on nominating a Black woman to the Court versus qualified Latino judges &#8212; and they list a few in their ad &#8212; is racist.&nbsp; What do you make of that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the Supreme Court has been around for 230 years; there&#8217;s never been a Black woman who served on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; The President believes that&#8217;s a problem with past processes and not a lack of qualified Black women to serve on the Supreme Court.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are also opportunities &#8212; perhaps in the future, we&#8217;ll see &#8212; to nominate others; we don&#8217;t know at this point in time.&nbsp; But the President is proud of the range of credible, qualified candidates he&#8217;s looking at and looking forward to making an announcement soon.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; A quick follow-up on the cyber stuff.&nbsp; Would the U.S. consider a disruptive attack against Russia, similar to the DDoS one right now being waged against Ukraine?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Say that one more time.&nbsp; What &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; If the U.S. would consider, like, a distributed denial-of-service attack.&nbsp; Like, we just talked about potential &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; cyber responses.&nbsp; Is that one of the potential options?&nbsp; Like &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In terms of what we would do in response?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to outline or detail what options the President would have at his disposal.&nbsp; Again, he can take any step, seen and unseen.&nbsp; He has the right to do that.&nbsp; But we have not even made an attribution at this point in time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fair enough.&nbsp; Russia&#8217;s lower house of parliament voted on Tuesday to ask Putin to recognize the self-declared Donetsk and Luhansk People&#8217;s Republics.&nbsp; Blinken said today that that move “would necessitate a swift and firm response from the United States in full coordination with…Allies and partners.”&nbsp; What might such a response look like? &nbsp;Sanctions, export controls?&nbsp; What kind of &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s a range of options we have at our disposal.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to outline those from here.&nbsp; But I would also just reiterate a couple of points that Secretary Blinken made in his statement, which includes the fact that the Kremlin&#8217;s support of this amounts to the “Russian government&#8217;s wholesale rejection of its commitments” &#8212; its own commitments &#8212; “under the Minsk agreement[s],” which is certainly the reason to have such a strong reaction to it from the Secretary of State.&nbsp; And “[e]nactment…further undermine[s] Ukraine&#8217;s sovereignty and territorial integrity,” constituting a “gross violation of international law.”<br><br>So, hence we have &#8212; as you said, he conveyed in his statement that “necessitates a swift and firm response from the United States in full coordination with our Allies and partners.” &nbsp;But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point in time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick follow-up on oil.&nbsp; CNN is reporting that NSC Middle East Coordinator, Brett McGurk, and State Department Energy Envoy Amos Hochstein are in Riyadh today.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hochstein (inaudible) &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for that.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; in case you have to restate his name on television.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Amos &#8212; are in Riyadh today to press the Saudis to pump more oil.&nbsp; And I wondered if you could confirm that.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can confirm they&#8217;re on a trip.&nbsp; There are a range of range of topics to discuss, including Yemen.&nbsp; And as you know, we &#8212; engaging with our partners around the world about ensuring supply meets demand is part of our objective from here as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s one of the objectives of the meeting as well?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have more details on the meeting at this point in time.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The Secretary of State said today that they have not seen “meaningful pullback” by Russia when it comes to the forces that they’ve put on Ukraine&#8217;s border.&nbsp; What would meaningful pullback look like to the United States?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to define that by troop numbers.&nbsp; I think we will know it when we see it, which is a verifiable reduction of troops at the border of Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you&#8217;re not looking at a certain metric or anything like that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nothing that I&#8217;m going to outline from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President updated the number yesterday, changing it from about 130,000 that we believed that Russia had amassed on the border to closer to 150,000.&nbsp; How long does the United States believe Russia can maintain that kind of a force posture?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he also said including in Belarus and&nbsp;encircling Ukraine &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; as well, to be clear.&nbsp; In terms of their ability to maintain that, I&#8217;m not going to get into intelligence from here.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But there&#8217;s no judgment on &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nothing I&#8217;m going to outline from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; My last question: On the CIA station that is being relocated closer to the border of Poland, outside of Kyiv, does the U.S. have concerns that that will affect their ability to be able to track Russia&#8217;s movements from Ukraine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;You have a lot of intelligence questions today, which is absolutely fine, but there&#8217;s nothing I can detail on that from here either.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But no concern that the- &#8212; moving the CIA station out of the capital is going to affect that ability?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to speak about our intelligence processes in Ukraine or in the surrounding area from here.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Following up on Kristen’s question.&nbsp; Obviously, the invasion didn&#8217;t happen today.&nbsp; The Pentagon was eyeing today as a possible date that some &#8212; we could see some sort of action, some sort of invasion.&nbsp; Does the White House think that Putin could be bluffing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; About what?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About his intention to move forward.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not invade or to invade?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, either way.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, President Putin has said he doesn&#8217;t intend to invade.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also said he&#8217;s prepared &#8212; he&#8217;s prepared to do that and has lined up troops at the border to &#8212; to invade.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re &#8212; we are waiting for President Putin&#8217;s comments to assess what is being prepared around the border.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Do you think that your efforts to put all this intelligence out about his &#8212; you know, what might happen next might have deterred something that we could’ve seen in the last 24 hours?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s part of our obj- &#8212; has been part of our objective overall, Jacqui &#8212; right? &#8212; is to make it more difficult for the Russians, for President Putin to lay a predicate for war, to &#8212; when our objective is to try to avoid war, prevent war.<br><br>Now, it&#8217;s ultimately up to President Putin to decide what steps he&#8217;s going to take, but putting out specific details about the types of false-flag operations, their efforts to push misinformation through Russian media &#8212; the types of tactics they&#8217;ve used in the past &#8212; that&#8217;s all a part of our effort to make it more difficult for them to use these tactics and keep the eyes of the global community open.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then has this whole standoff underscored the importance of NATO Allies spending 2 percent of their GDP towards defense?&nbsp; Is that something that the White House will be pressing in the future from our Allies?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that the Vi- &#8212; President pressed for when he was Vice President.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then can I ask about a second topic: the Durham investigation?&nbsp; Durham says there was an outside company with ties to the Clinton camp monitoring server data info on the Executive Office of the President through the Obama administration, possibly into the Trump administration.&nbsp; Do you know if there&#8217;s still a system picking up server data on the EOP &#8212; and if not, when it stopped?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I know you asked my colleague a few questions about this the other day, but I would point you &#8212; any questions about this to the Department of Justice.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, is what was described in the filing there &#8212; monitoring internet traffic &#8212; is that &#8212; generally speaking, would that be considered something along the lines of spying?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I would point you to the Department of Justice.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, thanks.&nbsp; Is that U.S. confident at this point that all intelligence and sensitive material has been removed and destroyed from the U.S. embassy in Kyiv?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, there&#8217;s obviously steps every embassy takes when they move or relocate, but I&#8217;m not going to get into those details from here.&nbsp; I&#8217;d point you to the State Department if there&#8217;s more they&#8217;d like to share.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And oil prices are nearing $100 a barrel.&nbsp; That’s a milestone that hasn&#8217;t been reached since 2014.&nbsp; What steps is the administration taking at this point to deal with high oil prices?&nbsp; Have you been talking to allies about a coordinated global release of oil?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have been in touch with allies and partners, suppliers out there on the global stage for weeks now in preparation for a range of impacts of &#8212; you know, in anticipation of an invasion or, actually, an impact of an invasion, both for natural gas and oil prices on the market.<br><br>We will continue those engagements, of course.&nbsp; As I&#8217;ve said and I said yesterday: For the President, all options remain on the table.&nbsp; As you know, in the past or recent months, he tapped the Strategic Petroleum Reserve &#8212; 50 million barrels. Those have been released over the course &#8212; or 40 million of them, I think, to date have been released over the course of time.&nbsp;<br><br>We also remain, of course, engaged with Congress and countries around the world about how to meet the demands out there.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; The President urged Congress, this week, to act on gun control on the anniversary of Parkland shooting.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been five months now since David Chipman’s nomination was withdrawn.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the current timetable for nominating an ATF director?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we certainly would love to have an ATF director in place for the first time in, I think, a decade&nbsp;&#8211;someone confirmed.&nbsp; And unfortunately, I would say David Chipman was eminently qualified for the position and was not able to move forward.&nbsp; And the President would like to nominate someone to replace him, but I don&#8217;t have anything on the timeline.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In an effort to pry the window open a bit wider into the President&#8217;s thinking on the Supreme Court &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what is the thinking here about some of the pushback that&#8217;s been aired on the Left with respect to Judge Michelle Childs in South Carolina?&nbsp; Does the President reject that criticism that she hews to or has hewn &#8212; hewed? &#8212; too closely to corporate interests?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; some of the criticism I&#8217;ve seen out there is related to her labor record.&nbsp; If you look at South Carolina, the AFL in South Carolina endorsed her and has been supportive of her.<br><br>I think the President &#8212; in response &#8212; or just to go back to Ed&#8217;s question, which I think is similar &#8212; the President is not interested in public griping or in lobbying campaigns or efforts to trash other candidates.&nbsp; He is going to keep his blinders on, look at the qualifications, the cases, the backgrounds, the credentials of these eminently qualified nominees.&nbsp; All of the ones he&#8217;s considering would make excellent, qualified Supreme Court justices, and that&#8217;s where his focus remains.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On background and qualifications, how important is it to the President that his choice have served as a public defender?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to get into any more specifics of the qualifications.&nbsp; You have a short window left before you will know, probably, who he has selected.&nbsp; And you will have more, I&#8217;m sure, analysis to do at that time.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the stalled Fed nominations to the Banking Committee.&nbsp; Chairman Brown said today that he&#8217;s refusing to move the other picks separate from Sarah Bloom Raskin.&nbsp; He also said that he spoke to President Biden and that President Biden is standing by Senate Democrats on this.&nbsp; So, is the White House backing that strategy of holding all the nominees up and essentially waiting for Republicans to show up in the Banking Committee to vote?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And I was in the Oval Office when the President spoke with Senator Brown, so I can confirm &#8212; not that there was any doubt &#8212; that he conveyed exactly that to the senator, that he agrees that Republicans are AWOL on the fight against inflation on this &#8212; at this pivotal moment in our economy.&nbsp;<br><br>Everyone understands we need a full Federal Reserve Board &#8212; the first one in nearly a decade &#8212; to tackle infas- &#8212; inflation and bring prices down for American families.&nbsp;<br><br>So, no, we are not advocating for splitting the nominees.&nbsp;&nbsp;We support Chairman Brown’s decision to keep all five on the Fed board, pushing them forward through the committee.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we believe Republicans need to do their jobs and show up to vote for these nominees.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;You spoke about the urgency with inflation and other issues facing the Fed.&nbsp;&nbsp;But given that Republicans show no signs of bending and that the Senate is poised to go on recess by the end of the week, I mean, how likely or unlikely is it that we’re going to see a vote before the end of the month on these nominees?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would point you to Chairman Brown for that.&nbsp; He is very committed, and I’m sure &#8212; and then, I think, as you’ve seen him publicly, can be quite a bulldog when we wants to get something done.&nbsp; So, we support his efforts to get these five nominees forward.&nbsp; There’s a couple days left.&nbsp;<br><br>And all we’re asking is for Republicans to show up and do their job.&nbsp; They can vote against people or &#8212; but not showing up is not &#8212; is not delivering on the commitment you made to the American people when they elected you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lastly, on that issue, Senator Toomey was at an event where he said he believed the Fed was basically able to perform at full strength, even without the confirmed nominees.&nbsp; Your reaction to that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s no question that having a full Federal Board fighting inflation &#8212; at a time where that is the stated number-one concern of many Republicans, many Democrats, and many in the American public &#8212; would be the ideal scenario here.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said a couple times just now that the President is not going to be swayed by lobbying efforts.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m wondering:&nbsp; If that&#8217;s the case, what does he make of Congressman Clyburn’s pretty aggressive push for one specific judge, Judge Childs?&nbsp; Does that count as lobbying?&nbsp; Is the President listening to that?&nbsp; This is obviously someone he has in high esteem and is close with.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Of course, he does.&nbsp; He has him in high esteem.&nbsp; He is close with him.&nbsp; But, again, the President &#8212; who is someone who has been though a number of these processes before, who has overseen hearings, who has played a role as Vice President in helping select incredible nominees and now Supreme Court justices to serve &#8212; he is going to consult broadly, and then he is going to look at their credentials, review cases, and make a decision about the right person to nominate for the Court.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I think the only other angle left on the interviews that you have not been asked is: Will you tell us when the interviews are complete?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Unlikely.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I will tell you &#8212; the President will tell you when there’s a nominee.&nbsp;<br><br>The good news is March 1st is around the corner.&nbsp; So, you know, we remain on track, and you don&#8217;t have too much longer to wait.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Last night, voters in San Francisco voted to recall three school board members.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if the White House has any reaction to that result?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; We, of course, did see that.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any reaction directly to the decision by the local school board.&nbsp;<br><br>But I would just reiterate that the President&#8217;s objective has been keeping schools open, from the beginning.&nbsp; And now, at this point in time, 99 percent of schools are open, in large part because of the funding in the American Rescue Plan and efforts that he and his Secretary of Education undertook to ensure schools had the resources and the information needed to keep schools open.<br><br>We understand where parents are coming from when they want schools to be open as well.&nbsp; And the President recognizes the mental health impact it has on kids for them not to be open.&nbsp; So, we don&#8217;t have any specific comment on the local school &#8212; the local decision about the local school board leaders, but that remains the President&#8217;s objective.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on education more broadly, we saw that be an issue in the Virginia gubernatorial race; obviously, this is the issue here in San Francisco.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering what the White House or the President&#8217;s message is to parents about &#8212; you addressed school reopening, but, more broadly, some of the issues that we&#8217;ve seen play &#8212; about equity, about curriculum &#8212; play in some of these electoral races.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, tell me more about specifically &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, in San Francisco, specifically, there was controversy over the renaming of schools.&nbsp; There &#8212; in Virginia, conversations about critical race theory.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering whether the White House or the President thinks that some of these school boards &#8212; maybe in San Francisco and other places &#8212; have moved too far to the left, adopted liberal policies beyond, you know, what voters seemingly approve of &#8212; or just more generally, how the President thinks of education and some of these issues around equity and inclusion.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first that the President is married to a teacher, so he certainly trusts in the role of teachers and educators across the country and the kind of curriculum that they are providing.<br><br>I&#8217;m not going to have any specific comment on any local school board or the politics of school boards, as it relates to any political race either, though.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Going back to the Senate Banking Committee, would the White House support a rule change to allow the Senate majority to discharge the nomination directly from committee, as they do with legislation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I believe that &#8212; I would really point you to Chairman Brown’s team and office.&nbsp; I think they have spoken to this and conveyed &#8212; I don&#8217;t think that there is a path forward for that, but I would point you to them for any comment.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And yesterday, Secretary of State Antony Blinken said that he was, quote, “troubled” by new charges that are being brought against Russian activist Alexei Navalny.&nbsp; Would the White House consider, in consultation with its allies, potentially, sanctions on individual leaders maybe in Putin’s circle to stop this or other efforts that you all could do to help Navalny and the Russian opposition?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are a range of sanctions under consideration on his inner circle.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, finally, congressional Democrats, again, are talking about student loan cancellation.&nbsp; Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez discussed this earlier this week, and Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer has also talked about the importance of canceling student loan debt.&nbsp; Why is this not an issue that &#8212; with broad public support and support within his own party in Congress &#8212; has the President not worked or pushed harder on to cancel the debt?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President has conveyed he&#8217;d be happy to sign a bill into law that all of those members could work to get passed.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, finally, yesterday marks the 30th House Democrat to announce their retirement from Congress.&nbsp; Is the White House at all concerned that this is indicative of a political climate in the broader country, in his own party?&nbsp; And could, simply, the retirements of very senior Democrats on the Hill potentially have implications for the White House&#8217;s domestic agenda?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, I have to be a little careful.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve learned &#8212; I&#8217;ve learned my lesson the hard way about talking about politics from up here.&nbsp;<br><br>There are a range of retirements every cycle for a variety of reasons.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re focused on is working with members to deliver for the American people.&nbsp; And we expect that anyone who&#8217;s going to be out there answering questions to people who may vote for them in the future, that they will hopefully talk about the work they&#8217;ve done with the President to create the greatest 12 months of job creation in our nation&#8217;s history, the largest drop in unemployment rate on record, the largest reduction in childhood poverty ever, the strongest economic growth this country has seen in nearly 40 years.<br><br>So, there&#8217;s a lot we&#8217;re going to be focused on.&nbsp; The President himself has conveyed he&#8217;s looking forward to being out there when it&#8217;s time for political season.&nbsp; But beyond that, I&#8217;m a little limited in what I can convey from here.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I actually do have something.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One thing.&nbsp; The &#8212; I think &#8212; circling back to something I think we asked Karine about a couple of days ago, but &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The mayor of the District of Columbia has announced that she&#8217;s going to significantly reduce the restrictions &#8212; the COVID restrictions.&nbsp; The indoor mask wearing, I think, comes off at the end of the month.&nbsp; The requirement to show proof of vaccination has ended, I think, as of yesterday.&nbsp;<br><br>The campus &#8212; the White House campus is in Washington, D.C., obviously, like, affected by the metrics that are around, in terms of case counts and hospital counts and what have you.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, does &#8212; does that &#8212; are you guys going to follow some of the recommendations that the mayor has put out?&nbsp; Or are you going to wait for the CDC to make their recommendations before you change any of the activities on this campus?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’ll wait for the CDC.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve said &#8212; and I know you had a COVID briefing a little bit earlier today &#8212; that they&#8217;re continuing to review mask guidelines and how different communities in the country should assess them, but we&#8217;ll wait for the CDC is make any changes here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the Supreme Court, I think I&#8217;ve thought of one more way, which is to &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; which is only to say that when the President said the other day that he was considering &#8220;about four&#8221; nominees, did he mean three?&nbsp; Did &#8220;about four&#8221; mean three?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the President &#8212; the President meant &#8220;about four,&#8221; and I don&#8217;t have anything further to add to that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could it be five?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I actually do have another way to &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to get at that.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the President traveling tomorrow, could we &#8212; could you rule out that the announcement would come this week?&nbsp;<br><br>And would you flesh out more details on what you expect the announcement to look like?&nbsp; Sometimes we&#8217;ve seen them take place in primetime with events in the East Room.&nbsp; Is that what the President is looking out for his announcement?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any details on that to preview at this point in time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I had to try.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the State of California &#8212; a couple of California-themed questions for you.&nbsp; So, the EPA is finalizing a rule that would give California a waiver to &#8212; and the authority to set its own emission standards.&nbsp; Why does the administration think it&#8217;s important for California to have the ability to set its own emission standards?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This is a great question.&nbsp; I know I have something on this, but I don&#8217;t have it in front of me.&nbsp; So let me get you &#8212; it to you after the briefing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And to follow up on that though: Even with the waiver, California is expected largely to stick to the Biden administration standards, but the President has indicated in the past that he does look to California on these issues.&nbsp; So, if California were to institute stricter standards &#8212; say on either heavy-duty vehicles, for instance &#8212; would that be something that the administration would seriously consider mirroring?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question, but I don&#8217;t have anything to predict or preview on that front.&nbsp; Obviously, the President&#8217;s objective remains lowering emissions in the country and reaching his ambitious climate goals that he set.&nbsp; But in terms of what future steps look like, I don&#8217;t have anything to predict at this point in time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one last one on California &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but not on emissions.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; President Biden has been supportive of Governor Gavin Newsom in many instances.&nbsp; Does he support Governor Newsom&#8217;s decisions to drop the universal mask mandate in California, even as masks continue to be required in California schools?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there are a number of states who have made decisions &#8212; not just California &#8212; and announcements.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;ve said and I can repeat is that we will continue to look for and abide by CDC guidance from the federal government.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we will follow.&nbsp; But different leaders will make decisions based on what they think is best for their communities.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great, thank you.&nbsp; One more on SCOTUS.&nbsp; Everyone is going to try.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is a new tactical maneuver.&nbsp; Senator Grassley, the ranking Republican on the Judiciary Committee, today told reporters on the Hill that he is under the impression that President Biden is doing interviews this week.&nbsp; Can you confirm or deny what Senator Grassley said?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We said &#8220;as early as this week.&#8221;&nbsp; That&#8217;s all the detail I have for you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Afghanistan: This week marked six months since the withdrawal from Afghanistan.&nbsp; From this podium, Jake Sullivan told us that the commitment to allies there is sacrosanct.&nbsp; The administration committed to doing everything it could to get our allies out, but tens of thousands of allies &#8212; hundreds of thousands if you include families &#8212; including the SIV people in the pipeline, are still there and struggling.&nbsp; What exactly is the administration doing to get them out?&nbsp; Because on the ground and from Congress, my sources say they think you&#8217;re doing nothing.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that we have successfully helped &#8212; I can get you the specific number, but I believe it&#8217;s hundreds depart from Afghanistan: partners, allies, people who have stood by our side since we withdrew from Afghanistan at the end of August.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve worked in partnership with allies and partners in the region, including the Qataris, where we have our diplomatic presence.&nbsp; We are the largest contributor of humanitarian assistance of any country in the world, which we continue to provide through &#8212; through proven third-party aid organizations as well.&nbsp; And flights just resumed, I think a couple of weeks ago, through Qatar Airways, and that will also play a role in helping.<br><br>But we remain committed to working with our partners in the region and to helping those who want to leave Afghanistan who have been serving by our side for 20 years to help do that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And could you help me &#8212; I can follow up &#8212; get numbers on women in particular?&nbsp; And &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would point to the State Department, and they have &#8212; they would have any details on specific numbers.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The British Prime Minister said that Russia is sending signal &#8212; or mixed signals or messages.&nbsp; They say they&#8217;re open to &#8212; for diplomacy and they keep on building the military back up on the border.&nbsp; Does the White House believe actually that the Russians are using deceitful tactics?<br><br>And can you update us on the talks in Vienna &#8212; Iran talks?&nbsp; Do you think that we&#8217;re closer to getting a deal?&nbsp; You, yourself, said that February is a vital month, that this is crunch time.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So on the first question, you know, as Secretary Blinken said this morning, there is what Russia says and then there&#8217;s what Russia does.&nbsp; And we certainly believe that they will continue to use false-flag operations, efforts to deceive &#8212; lay a predicate for war, which is why we have been putting out as much information as we can on that front, so that the world is aware and knows what to look for and watch for.&nbsp; And we do that, of course, in partnership with our allies around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>As it relates to Iran, they &#8212; I believe they&#8217;re still in the eighth round of negotiations.&nbsp; You know, of course, as we&#8217;ve said in the past, you know, we would certainly support efforts or the opportunity to have direct engagement with the Iranians.&nbsp; We won&#8217;t &#8212; we&#8217;ve said that a deal &#8212; our focus remains on a deal that addresses the core concerns of all sides.&nbsp;<br><br>And if it&#8217;s not reached in the coming weeks &#8212; as we&#8217;ve said before, but this remains the case &#8212; Iran&#8217;s ongoing nuclear advances will make it impossible for us to return to the JCPOA.&nbsp;<br><br>So, bottom line is: Under the JCPOA, Iran&#8217;s program was tightly constrained and monitored by international inspectors.&nbsp; Since the previous administration ceased U.S. participation, Iran has rapidly accelerated and reduced cooperation.&nbsp; And that is, hence, why we are where we are.<br><br>But we &#8212; they are continuing to engage &#8212; of my last update on this. &nbsp;But, again, I&#8217;d reiterate that the President asked a team to present &#8212; to put together a range of options in the event those need to be considered.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So, on Monday, it was the one-year anniversary of the phase one trade deal with China going into effect.&nbsp; Written into that deal is very specific enforcement language.&nbsp; So, when does the administration trigger that language against China because they haven&#8217;t lived up to that agreement?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, so, the phase one trade agreement that the President &#8212; I think you&#8217;re &#8212; I think that&#8217;s not exactly accurate, as my understanding of what the status of this is at this point &#8212; or what anything that&#8217;s triggered or not triggered.&nbsp; The &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s not &#8212; yeah, it&#8217;s not an automatic trigger, but there is specific language in there as to what the enforcement is.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, so, first, you know, when he was running for president, the President made clear that the phase one deal did not address the core problems with China&#8217;s state-led economy and harmful economic practices.&nbsp;<br><br>USTR, since that period of time, has been making a concerted effort to see if China will show serious intent to make good on their purchase commitments.&nbsp; But the fact that they have not met those illustrates the limitations of the framework we inherited.&nbsp; They&#8217;re still in discussions about them.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t have, kind of, an update on that.&nbsp; I would leave that to Katherine Tai, our ambassador.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a sense of urgency now that China and Russia are moving closer together?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that has been the case for some time now.&nbsp; It also does not change the fact that if Russia were to invade, the size and seriousness of the economic consequences and package &#8212; that&#8217;s not something that China would have the ability to fill in the gaps on.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>Oh &#8212; oh, yes. &nbsp;I got to go.&nbsp; Aurelia, why don’t you do the last one?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Climate change &#8212; a complete change of topic.&nbsp; According to a report published yesterday, by 2050, the sea level on U.S. coasts would rise by one foot, which means 40 percent of American people who live in coastal areas would see more damaging floods.&nbsp; What is the administration doing about it?&nbsp; And does the President feel he is doing enough to fight climate change?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you’ve heard the President say, time and time again &#8212; especially when he goes and visits communities that have been impacted by major weather events &#8212; one in three Americans live in a county hit by a weather disaster this past year, which is a pretty startling statistic.&nbsp; And last year, extreme weather cost America $99 billion.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we know &#8212; we know climate change is real.&nbsp; Anyone who doubts it: That&#8217;s further evidence climate change is real, and it&#8217;s exacerbating the extreme weather conditions.&nbsp; And certainly, this report is further evidence of that.&nbsp;<br><br>What the President has done is, of course, work to pass the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which &#8212; a lot of people focus on roads, rails, and bridges &#8212; important parts &#8212; but it also has an enormous investment in strengthening our nation&#8217;s resilience to extreme weather and climate change while reducing greenhouse gas emissions, replacing lead pipes so everyone has access to clean water. &nbsp;And we&#8217;ve also been mobilizing an all-of-government approach to deploy and implement critical clean energy projects.<br><br>But I would also note that this is one of the reasons the President is going to continue to press for key components of his agenda &#8212; his Build Back Better agenda &#8212; including a historic investment in addressing the climate crisis.<br><br>Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.<br><br>1:51 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/16/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-83/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 20:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 11:02 A.M. EST MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning.&#160; And thanks for joining us.&#160; Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on the state of the pandemic.&#160; Dr. Fauci will present the latest science on vaccine effectiveness.&#160; I’ll provide an overview of how we’re planning for the path ahead.&#160; And Dr. Tom Inglesby joins us&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:02 A.M. EST</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; And thanks for joining us.&nbsp; Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on the state of the pandemic.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci will present the latest science on vaccine effectiveness.&nbsp; I’ll provide an overview of how we’re planning for the path ahead.&nbsp; And Dr. Tom Inglesby joins us to discuss how we’re increasing domestic testing capacity.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ll start with Dr. Walensky.<br>&nbsp;<br>Dr. Walensky?<br>&nbsp;<br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; I’d like to start by walking you through today’s data.&nbsp; The current seven-day daily average of cases is about 147,000 cases per day, a decrease of about 40 percent over the previous week.<br>&nbsp;<br>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 9,500 per day, a decrease of about 28 percent over the previous week.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, the seven-day average of daily deaths are about 2,200 per day, which is a decrease of about 9 percent over the previous week.<br>&nbsp;<br>Omicron cases are declining, and we are all cautiously optimistic about the trajectory we are on.&nbsp; Things are moving in the right direction, but we want to remain vigilant to do all we can so that this trajectory continues.<br>&nbsp;<br>As we see the Omicron wave continue to wane, we know that you may have questions regarding what prevention strategies are really necessary for this moment, especially as people are so eager to remove them.<br>&nbsp;<br>At CDC, we provide public health guidance to help communities make decisions based on the risk at the local level &#8212; community-level guidance that offers the public information they need to stay safe and protect others.<br>&nbsp;<br>As I said last week, we are looking at all of our guidance based not only on where we are right now in the pandemic, but also on the tools we now have at our disposal &#8212; such as vaccines, boosters, tests, and treatments &#8212; and our latest understanding of the disease.<br>&nbsp;<br>As we consider future metrics, which will be updated soon, we recognize the importance of not just cases which continue to result in substantial or high community transmission in over 97 percent of our counties in the country, but critically, medically severe disease that leads to hospitalizations.<br>&nbsp;<br>We must consider hospital capacity as an additional important barometer.&nbsp; Our hospitals need to be able to take care of people with heart attacks and strokes.&nbsp; Our emergency departments can’t be so overwhelmed that patients with emergent issues have to wait in line.<br>&nbsp;<br>We are assessing the most important factors based on where we are in the pandemic, and we&#8217;ll soon put guidance in place that is relevant and encourages prevention measures when they are most needed to protect public health and our hospitals.&nbsp; We want to give people a break from things like mask-wearing, when these metrics are better, and then have the ability to reach for them again should things worsen.<br>&nbsp;<br>If and when we update our guidance, we will communicate that clearly, and it will be based on the data and the science.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>However, it’s also important to remember, regardless of the level of disease burden in your community, there are still very important times to continue to wear your mask.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you are symptomatic or feeling unwell, you should wear a mask.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you are in the 10 days after a COVID diagnosis, you should wear a mask.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you were exposed to someone with COVID-19 and are quarantining, you should wear a mask.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>I know that everyone is anxious to move beyond this pandemic and some of the ways we have had to change the way we live over the last two years.<br>&nbsp;<br>We all share the same goal: to get to a point where COVID-19 is no longer disrupting our daily lives; a time when it won’t be a constant crisis, rather something we can prevent, protect against, and treat.<br>&nbsp;<br>Moving from this pandemic will be a process led by the science and epidemiologic trends and one that relies on the powerful tools we already have including vaccines, boosters, testing, and treatment.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.&nbsp; I’ll now turn it over to Dr. Fauci.<br>&nbsp;<br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; What I’d like to do over the next couple of minutes is try to address for you a question that is now frequently being asked following the data that has come out from the cohorts who have been followed, following their third shot of an mRNA vaccine, namely their boost.&nbsp; And the question people ask is: “Will I” &#8212; “I” being everyone &#8212; “need now a fourth booster shot?”<br>&nbsp;<br>So let me tell you what we know so far.<br>&nbsp;<br>Next slide.<br>&nbsp;<br>What we do know is that data from, now, multiple studies &#8212; and I’ll show you an example of a couple of these &#8212; of vaccine effectiveness show that, for the immunocompetent people, a single booster shot continues to provide high levels of protection against severe disease caused by Omicron.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This should not be confused with the fact that for many immunocompromised people, already a second booster shot &#8212; namely a fourth dose of an mRNA &#8212; is recommended because of what we know about their poor response to the initial regimen.<br>&nbsp;<br>And again, as I&#8217;ll show, and new CDC data indicate, that booster shots are safe and well tolerated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, let&#8217;s get to some of the representative data.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is a slide from the UK looking at vaccine effectiveness against hospitalization with Omicron.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re looking at the diminution of efficacy or effectiveness after dose two.&nbsp; And the time at the bottom is weeks.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re looking at two separate vaccines: the Pfizer-BioNTech and the Moderna.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as you can see with hospitalizations, although it goes down from the initial very high 90-plus percent &#8212; it goes down to around 78 or 80 percent, nonetheless it&#8217;s still at a high level, relatively speaking.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is an even larger study &#8212; a large cohort study from the CDC, recently put out in the MMWR &#8212; their VISION Network.<br>&nbsp;<br>I want you to concentrate at the two-dose vaccine efficacy at four to five months against Omicron.&nbsp; And again, it goes down to 58 percent.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>However, at four to five months, even though it has come down over a period of time &#8212; you could see it go from 91 to 88 to 78.&nbsp; Nonetheless, the level of 78 is still a good protective area.&nbsp; As I&#8217;ll get to soon, I&#8217;ll show you what that means looking forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I do want to mention, on the next slide, the safety of this, because we often get asked that.&nbsp; If you look at the CDC from February 11th, and look at their monitoring systems &#8212; the V-Safe and the VAERS &#8212; it&#8217;s very clear that for people 18 years of age or older who&#8217;ve seen the same mRNA vaccine brand for all their vaccinations, they actually experience fewer adverse reactions following the booster dose than they did after the second dose.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And in fact, 92 percent of reports to VAERS, which is all adverse events related or not, are not considered serious.&nbsp; And headache, fever, and muscle pain were the most frequently reported reactions.&nbsp; And the V-Safe data found medical care was rarely received after a booster dose.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, let&#8217;s go to the last summary slide.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The dynamics of COVID-19 outbreak, as Dr. Walensky just showed you a moment ago, continue to point in a sharp downward direction.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Vaccination and boosting will be critical in maintaining that downward trajectory, particularly when you&#8217;re talking about the red curve of severe disease leading to hospitalization.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And getting back to the first question that I posed in my first slide: The potential future requirement for an additional boost or a fourth shot for mRNA or a third shot for J&amp;J is being very carefully monitored in real time.&nbsp; And recommendations, if needed, will be updated according to the data as it evolves.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll stop there.&nbsp; And back to you, Jeff.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thanks, Doctors.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll discuss how we&#8217;re thinking about the moment we&#8217;re in and are planning for the future of this virus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve made tremendous progress in our ability to protect ourselves against COVID-19.&nbsp; Seventy-five percent &#8212; three out of every four adults &#8212; are fully vaccinated, and two thirds of eligible adults have gotten their booster shot.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For all Americans, both the vaccinated and unvaccinated, we have strong tools, including free at-home tests and free high-quality masks that provide added layers of protection.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And importantly, we have a range of effective treatments and therapeutics, including pills that are up to 90 percent effective at preventing severe illness and hospitalization.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As a result of all this progress and the tools we now have, we&#8217;re moving toward a time when COVID isn&#8217;t a crisis but is something we can protect against and treat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President and our COVID team are actively planning for this future.&nbsp; As we look forward, we&#8217;ll continue to enhance the powerful set of tools that we have at our disposal.&nbsp; Vaccines, booster shots, tests, and treatments will keep protecting our most vulnerable, including the immunocompromised.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>A vaccine for our youngest kids is on the horizon.&nbsp; And as always, we&#8217;ll prepare for the potential of any new variant to ensure we&#8217;re ready to respond immediately and protect people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Throughout this planning process, our team has been working with experts both inside and outside of government, local public health leaders, governors, business leaders, and partners across our health agencies to benefit from their expertise and ideas.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ll have more to say on this in the coming weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>And while we’re not where we all want to be yet, we’re encouraged by the dramatic declines we’re seeing in cases and hospitalizations nationwide.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President’s COVID plan is clearly working, and we believe the American people will be well-served by our deliberate and thorough approach to planning for the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, let me turn it to Dr. Tom Inglesby, Senior Advisor to the White House COVID Response, to give an update on our work to increase and sustain testing capacity.<br>&nbsp;<br>Dr. Inglesby?<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; DR. INGLESBY:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; And great to be with you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me start by stepping back.&nbsp; Last January, when President Biden took office, there were no at-home rapid COVID tests available on the U.S. market.<br>&nbsp;<br>This January, we had hundreds of millions of at-home tests available to Americans.&nbsp; The President was able to commit to purchasing 1 billion new at-home tests to distribute to Americans for free.&nbsp; And in addition, we had expanded capacity for lab-based tests to more than 2 million tests per day.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is major progress.&nbsp; And there’s no question the significant overall national testing capacity that we now have is a direct result of administration’s actions.<br>&nbsp;<br>We recognized the role that rapid tests would play in the fight against COVID, and we pursued all means to scale them up dramatically.<br>&nbsp;<br>We used the Defense Production Act, invested $3 billion to expand and accelerate manufacturing, and created a new, faster pathway for manufacturers to seek FDA authorization.&nbsp; We’ve secured raw materials, expanded the industrial base, and built inventory to support lab-based testing.<br>&nbsp;<br>To expand access, we invested in free tests in schools, pharmacies, community centers, long-term care facilities, and made rapid tests free through all private insurers.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we know that as Omicron cases decline, demand for tests will wane as well.&nbsp; That’s why we’re taking an important new step.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, we’re issuing a formal Request for Information from the testing industry, aimed at sustaining and expanding domestic manufacturing and testing capacity for this coming year.<br>&nbsp;<br>The information being sought includes proposed solutions to managing market volatility and addressing supply chain challenges, as well as what it will take to scale up manufacturing and bring new technologies and manufacturing processes online.<br>&nbsp;<br>The request also emphasizes equity and the need for manufacturers to ensure at-home tests are easy to use and accessible for all, including for people who are blind or visually impaired and those living with disabilities.<br>&nbsp;<br>The information we receive will help guide our new investments.&nbsp; And it’s a key part of planning and implementing our longer-term testing strategy and preparing for future testing needs.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re taking steps now to sustain and expand the domestic testing capacity in this country, and we’ll be ready if we face a new variant or surge in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>This work will happen alongside efforts to accelerate the work of promising, new testing companies as they seek FDA authorization, along with a new NIH program aimed at bringing the costs of testing down, and along with funding for rapid study of new variants.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ll also keep acting aggressively to make testing widely available and easy to access, at little or no cost, so they continue &#8212; so that they continue to be free at convenient locations like local pharmacies, online retailers, and community health centers.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks to the work over the past year and steps we’re taking now, the U.S. testing infrastructure will continue to expand and become stronger.<br>&nbsp;<br>Testing will remain a critical part of our overall COVID response strategy.&nbsp; We’re making investments now for whatever this virus brings in the time ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I’ll turn it back to you, Jeff.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thanks, Doctor.&nbsp; And with that, let’s open it up for some questions.&nbsp; Over to you, Kevin.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; We have time for a few questions today.&nbsp; First, let’s go to Sabrina Siddiqui at the Wall Street Journal.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you as always for doing the briefing.&nbsp; As you consult with experts on transitioning to the next phase of COVID, are there specific benchmarks that you’re looking at?&nbsp; Is it still a transmission or are there &#8212; is there a certain rate that you want to hit with respect to hospitalizations and deaths, in order to be able to loosen certain restrictions?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, this is perhaps a question for Dr. Walensky, but is there any talk of issuing guidance on test-to-stay for a daycare, as in childcare centers?&nbsp; That’s something some parents have pushed for because, right now, a lot of daycares shut down with simply one positive case or they don’t let children who even present any symptoms &#8212; they don’t let them attend even &#8212; unless they have a negative PCR.&nbsp; So, is that something that you’ve looked at &#8212; test-to-stay &#8212; for daycare and childcare centers?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, do you want to talk about daycare centers, first?<br>&nbsp;<br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp;&nbsp;Yeah.&nbsp;&nbsp;Sure.&nbsp;&nbsp;So, our test-to-stay data that we have is largely &#8212; the science around it is largely in settings where people are masked, which is why our test-to-stay strategy is now both use masks, but also using two tests a day [week].<br>&nbsp;<br>In our early childcare guidance that was put out though, we do have some flexibility in there, recognizing the challenges associated with children who can&#8217;t wear masks and in these settings, and actually do offer some flexibility for returning to those settings in &#8212; you know, during certain situations.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So as to our planning process, you know, I want to be very clear that our highest first priority is fighting Omicron. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As Dr. Walensky said, cases and hospitalizations are coming down but are still at elevated levels.&nbsp; At the same time, we are preparing for the future.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been clear that, as a country, we&#8217;re making strong progress toward moving to a time when COVID is no longer a crisis.&nbsp; We are actively reaching out to healthcare &#8212; public healthcare experts acro- &#8212; inside and outside of government to get their input.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working very closely with state and local leaders, including governors and business leaders.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as Dr. Walensky said earlier, the CDC is looking at all of its guidance, including mask guidance, in light of declining cases and hospitalization.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we are running a very thorough, deliberate process, and we will get this right.<br>&nbsp;<br>Next question, please.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Tommy Christopher.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Yes, thank you again for the briefing.&nbsp; My question is &#8212; I know that there&#8217;s been a lot of media pressure because some states with Democratic governors have eased mask mandates, but it&#8217;s my understanding that a lot of these changes are gradual.&nbsp; So, could you talk about the timelines for some of these state reg rules, as you understand them, and how they could coincide with the CDC’s deliberations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?<br>&nbsp;<br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; So maybe just to say: Many of these state-based policies have come out in phased approaches that they are talking about, you know, something that might happen in a week or two, masks that might come off in a week or two at the end of February, early March.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, of course, our metrics are going to examine, as Jeff said and as I previously said, issues related to cases, certainly issues related to severity of disease and hospital capacity.&nbsp; And we anticipate that many of these will intersect in terms of timing.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Zeke Miller, AP.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Jeff, you mentioned that among the people you&#8217;ve &#8212; the White House has been talking to &#8212; business leaders and other folks who aren&#8217;t scientists &#8212; does this &#8212; does that indicate that this sort of move to the next phase is not just a scientific decision; it&#8217;s sort of balanced by sort of economic concerns and other prerogatives, not just health &#8212; you know, sort of strictly health and safety on one side?<br>&nbsp;<br>And second, in terms of that timeline, you know, it &#8212; what should we expect that rollout should look like?&nbsp; You know, will&nbsp;it be individual pieces of guidance from CDC if that time and place comes, or a major speech from the President?&nbsp; And how does the administration view its responsibility to get people who right now maybe want to wear masks and, sort of, convince them that the science will allow them to take it off when that is the CDC guidance?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; A lot &#8212; a lot there, Zeke.&nbsp; I want to be clear that everything is driven by science and public health.&nbsp; Obviously, it&#8217;s important to understand the perspectives of different constituencies, including for businesses &#8212; how they think through bringing workers back to work, as an example.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But public health, science, medicine is the center of the work here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of masking, obviously individuals &#8212; and I&#8217;ll turn to you, Dr. Walensky &#8212; under any situation may choose to wear a mask &#8212; a high-quality mask &#8212; and that &#8212; that&#8217;s a good thing and a matter of personal choice.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Dr. Walensky?<br>&nbsp;<br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And I want to sort of indicate, as I mentioned earlier, there are times where we do want people to continue to wear a mask if they are in the 10 days after they&#8217;ve been diagnosed with COVID; they&#8217;re feeling better.&nbsp; But we want to make sure that they have &#8212; they know that they should be masking during those last several days when they might continue to be infectious.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there are clear times when we want people to continue to wear a mask.&nbsp; And I think as we have fewer and fewer cases, people will become more comfortable with taking off their mask. But as Jeff noted, we want &#8212; we certainly want people to have the flexibility to wear one if they so choose.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; And then in terms of timing, you know, as I said, we&#8217;re running a very thorough, inclusive process &#8212; the science and the medicine at the center.&nbsp; We&#8217;re moving deliberately.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, I think we will have more to say on this across the coming weeks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Next question, please.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Anne Flaherty, ABC.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; So, just to clarify on one point, and then a question for Jeff.&nbsp; Dr.&nbsp; Walensky, you said you did plan to update the guidance soon.&nbsp; I want to clarify that that is indoor masking, and if you can say that that might come as early as next week.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, Jeff, if you could say, has anyone within the administration indicated to the CDC at all that they would like to see revised mask guidance by the end of the month?&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Maybe I&#8217;ll start and just say we are looking at an overview of much of our guidance, and masking in all settings will be a part of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll just say that CDC is clearly in the lead here on both the substance and the timing of masking guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Next question, please.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp;&nbsp;Josh Wingrove, Bloomberg.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Hi there.&nbsp;&nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;I&#8217;m wondering if Dr. Inglesby can give us an update on the at-home testing program, in particular any metrics around how many orders have been placed, how many tests have been shipped, how many tests you have on hand.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And more broadly, Jeff, I&#8217;m wondering if you can speak to Secretary Blinken&#8217;s remarks earlier this week regarding the goal &#8212; the President&#8217;s goal of vaccinating the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;What more do you think you need, in particular in a supplemental from Congress, for instance, to be able to get more shots into arms globally to hit the President&#8217;s 70 percent goal by September or come closer to it?&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll &#8212; let me take a response first to the question about the COVIDTests.gov and the at-home test ordering.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today is an important day actually, in that we hit a milestone &#8212; 50 million shipped orders to households across all states, Tribes and territories.&nbsp;&nbsp;That&#8217;s a total of 200 million individual tests shipped to Americans across the country.&nbsp;&nbsp;So, 85 percent of the initial orders are now out the door.&nbsp;&nbsp;And in the next several days, we will complete the shipping of all of the initial orders.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to emphasize the Postal Service is doing, really an outstanding job here.&nbsp;&nbsp;Once the package ships, over 60 percent are delivered within 24 hours and 90 percent within 48 hours.&nbsp; So they are packing and shipping incredibly quickly and efficiently.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is an effort that has no precedent.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been incredibly strong demand and incredibly strong execution shipping 200 million tests directly to Americans’ doorsteps.&nbsp; So, really, a very strong performance across the board.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of continuing to make progress on global vaccinations, you know, we are &#8212; America is clearly leading the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve committed 1.2 billion doses to the world &#8212; free, no strings attached.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already shipped well over 400 million to 112 different countries.&nbsp; Each day, millions of doses get shipped.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The emphasis is on continuing to supply those 1.2 billion doses, and at the same time to help countries get shots in arms.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s an effort that USAID and the State Department are taking the lead on, along with CDC, to help build confidence in other countries, to create better access, to set up mobile clinics.&nbsp; And that becomes the effort going forward that becomes most important &#8212; is taking vaccines and turning them into vaccinations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Next question, please.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Joyce Frieden at MedPage Today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Yeah, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; I guess this is for Mr. Inglesby.&nbsp; I&#8217;m curious about your efforts in expanding at-home testing.&nbsp; I think people are still seeing that if they want to buy a test, the prices are pretty high.&nbsp; Is anything being done in terms of trying to get the prices down?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>DR. INGLESBY:&nbsp;&nbsp;Sure, yeah.&nbsp;&nbsp;And so, I think, as you know, on January 15th, the administration required private insurers to cover the full cost of over-the-counter tests.&nbsp;&nbsp;So that&#8217;s 150 million Americans covered by private insurance can now go to a pharmacy or to an online retailer and get over-the-counter tests fully covered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;About 50 to 60 million people are now in insurers &#8212; covered by insurers where you can do that directly at the cash register with your insurance card.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we&#8217;re working with insurers to encourage them to create those point-of-sale options.&nbsp;&nbsp;Medicaid covers these tests.&nbsp;&nbsp;Medicare will cover these tests by spring.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;So we&#8217;re moving in the direction where these tests should be completely covered for Americans, and they are now for many Americans.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp;&nbsp;I&#8217;d add to Tom&#8217;s statement that, you know, we&#8217;ve also &#8212; in addition to the 200 million we&#8217;ve already shipped free to Americans’ doorsteps, we&#8217;ve secured a billion in total, so there&#8217;s another 800 million tests that are either contracted for or are in the process of being contracted for that’ll be available free to the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;And there are also 20,000 free testing sites across the U.S. where people can get tested for free at local pharmacies and other convenient locations, including community health centers.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, plenty of options on free testing across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Next question, please.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; A couple of more questions.&nbsp; Let’s go to Jaqueline Howard at CNN.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; Dr. Inglesby, you mentioned here on CNN this morning that the government will be making high-quality masks available for kids and that process is underway.&nbsp; Can you share more details on how is that going to work and when might families get to have these masks in hand?&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Tom, go ahead.&nbsp; Dr. Inglesby &#8212; sorry.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; DR. INGLESBY:&nbsp; So, as you know, that already 230 million masks have been delivered to pharmacies and community health centers as part of the administration&#8217;s effort to deliver high-quality masks around the country.&nbsp; And that process will continue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are now in the process of planning for the distribution of masks for children.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more to say about that in the days ahead.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s a commitment to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a process underway, certainly, for all adults to get masks now for free at pharmacies and community health clinics across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Let’s go to Meg Tirrell at CNBC.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, thanks.&nbsp; Just thinking about a potential transition to thinking about gauging a pandemic by its effects on hospitals and severe disease, how should people take into account the risk of long COVID as they’re considering whether to keep masks on, as we hear it could be affecting, you know, 10 to 30 percent of people who get COVID, no matter the severity of their case?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci?<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, certainly long COVID is something that we take very seriously.&nbsp; We know we&#8217;re studying it really quite intensively now over the last year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We know that you don&#8217;t necessarily have to be hospitalized to get long COVID, that it ranges from people who are mildly to moderately symptomatic to individuals who are actually requiring hospitalization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are a number of factors that seem to be associated in recent studies with long COVID, ranging from things like Type 2 diabetes to viral load to reactivation of CMV &#8212; of EBV, excuse me, as well as things like autoantibodies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;We don&#8217;t really understand very much, but we&#8217;re learning, literally, on a week-by-week, month-by-month basis.&nbsp;&nbsp;But in direct answer to your question, Meg, you certainly want to protect against all infection; we&#8217;d like to do that.&nbsp;&nbsp;We certainly want to protect against symptomatic infection; we&#8217;d like to do that.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we don&#8217;t take lightly long COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that has to be put into the equation of what our ultimate goals are.&nbsp; But, clearly, the thing that is the most important is keeping people out of the hospitals for most of the reasons that I think Dr. Walensky explained very, very clearly that not only relate to the person with COVID-19 but the impact that it has on the rest of society outside of the context of COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, everybody.&nbsp; We look forward to the next briefing.</p>



<p>11:32 A.M. EST</p>



<p><br>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/COVID-Press-Briefing-2.16.22-pdf.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/COVID-Press-Briefing-2.16.22-pdf.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 15,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/15/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-15-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 4:17 P.M. EST MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, I have two items for all of you at the top.&#160; Today we have some exciting updates on our competition agenda.&#160; First, we have progress on our administration’s effort to lower the price of Internet for millions of Americans.&#160; I bet&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>4:17 P.M. EST<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, I have two items for all of you at the top.&nbsp;<br><br>Today we have some exciting updates on our competition agenda.&nbsp; First, we have progress on our administration’s effort to lower the price of Internet for millions of Americans.&nbsp; I bet you there are people who once lived in apartments or still do in this room who will love this, if you haven&#8217;t already seen it.<br><br>Today, the FCC announced important steps to increase competition in the market for high-speed Internet, which President Biden requested in his executive order on competition.<br><br>As some of you may know, the landlord, if you live in an apartment, sometimes requires you to purchase Internet service from one source.&nbsp; And today, the FCC voted on a bipartisan, unanimous basis to crack down on exclusivity agreements between landlords and Internet providers, known as “sweetheart deals,” which lock tenants in apartments and office buildings into just one option for Internet.<br><br>That might be good for the landlord and for the Internet service provider but bad for tenants, bad for American &#8212; the American people, bad for people living in apartment buildings who may have to pay more and accept lower quality service.<br><br>More than a third of Americans live in apartments and condos, and many businesses operate in multi-tenant buildings, like office buildings or malls, so this is a sweeping problem the FCC is starting to fix today.<br><br>And second, a competition update that is relevant for our national security: Today, the Department of Defense released a new report required by the President’s competition executive order, explaining the new actions to promote competition in defense contracting.&nbsp;<br><br>This report details that since the 1990s, the number of aerospace and defense prime contractors has shrunk from 51 to just 5.&nbsp; That consolidation means taxpayers have to pay more for defense services, and it threatens our national security.&nbsp; Strengthened merger oversight is one of the five actions the Defense Department is taking to address the problem.<br><br>We&#8217;ve already seen concrete progress on that front this week.&nbsp; On Sunday, the FTC successfully blocked Lockheed Martin’s $4 billion attempt to acquire Aerojet &#8212; a proposed megamerger of major defense suppliers.&nbsp;<br><br>The FTC had filed a lawsuit explaining that the merger would jack up the price the U.S. government has to pay, while delivering lower quality and less innovation.&nbsp;<br><br>Also wanted to note &#8212; last item from me at the top &#8212; is we’re thrilled the Senate did its job today and confirmed the renowned clinical trialist Dr. Robert Califf once again to the job of FDA Commissioner and once again on a bipartisan basis.<br><br>He brings to this critical post a lifetime of knowledge and the institutional experience that will ensure he hits the ground running and is guided by the science on critical missions facing the FDA &#8212; from continuing to lead the fight against COVID-19, to combatting the opioid crisis, to ensuring the safety of our nation’s food supply.<br><br>Josh, why don’t you kick us off.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two things on Ukraine.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, markets have obviously already been reacting to that situation.&nbsp; Gasoline prices are up 20 cents a gallon over the last 30 days on average.&nbsp;<br><br>Is the President saying that if people are paying more at the pump, that is essentially a direct result of Vladimir Putin&#8217;s actions and he is to blame for the current burst we&#8217;ve seen in higher prices?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President wasn&#8217;t making a market assessment or how the market moves.&nbsp; What he was conveying very &#8212; very clearly to the American public is that if Russia to &#8212; were to invade and we were to put in place crippling sanctions, that would have consequences or an impact here at home.<br><br>So I know that wasn&#8217;t exactly how you were asking the question, but that was what he was conveying in his answer.&nbsp; In terms of the price of gasoline, what we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; as we know, back in December, it went down by about 10 cents, thanks to tapping the Strategic Petroleum Reserve &#8212; something where there&#8217;s still releases that have been ongoing.&nbsp;<br><br>The President also made clear in his remarks that he is open to &#8212; all options are on the table to help bring down the price of gasoline.&nbsp; But he wasn&#8217;t making a market assessment; he was just making clear to the public that if Russia invades and we put in place crippling sanctions, that would have an impact on the public.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then secondly, on Ukraine, the President talked about diplomatic efforts.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could you go into more detail on what those diplomatic efforts could be?&nbsp; Is this going to be more U.S. interaction?&nbsp; Could there be a face-to-face meeting with Putin?&nbsp;<br><br>And then how would you define success under diplomacy?&nbsp; Is it as simple as no invasion or are there broader goals you&#8217;re looking for, given that everything is now on the table &#8212; or more things are on the table?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, on the first part: You may have seen, or not, that our Secretary of State spoke with Foreign Minister Lavrov earlier today.&nbsp; The President spoke with President Macron earlier today as well.&nbsp; I think the readout just went out to all of you, or it should be in your inboxes as well.&nbsp;<br><br>And what he means by “ongoing diplomacy” is that it will continue at the pace and urgency that you have seen from him over the last several weeks and from his team.&nbsp; And it &#8212; some of it will come from the President.&nbsp; Some will come from high-level members of his national security team.&nbsp; And some of it will come from our European partners or NATO Allies, who we remained in very close contact with.<br><br>In terms of engagement with President Putin, you &#8212; as you know, he spoke with him on Saturday.&nbsp; And he believes in the power of leader-to-leader diplomacy, but I don&#8217;t have a prediction of a next engagement at this point in time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what about &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, sorry.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How do you define success?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wanted &#8212; sorry, I didn’t get to that last part of your question.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, the &#8212; how we define success is, I think, how a lot of our European partners and NATO Allies would define it, which would be a de-escalation &#8212; a proven de-escalation at the border of Ukraine, where the Russians are pulling back their troops, where they are making clear to all of &#8212; to the global community, to the media, to the public that they are not invading Ukraine and backing that up with actions.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Following up on this energy question in terms of the impact on our energy, which the President mentioned &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and then the consequences here at home.&nbsp; What should Americans be prepared for?&nbsp; Worst-case scenario, what should they expect if this happens?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what the President was touching on was the fact that if Russia decides to invade, there could be consequences here at home.&nbsp; And that could have an impact on energy prices, which could have an impact on prices at the gas pump.<br><br>And we&#8217;re taking &#8212; while we are taking active steps to alleviate the pressure on our own energy markets &#8212; and every option is on the table to offset rising prices, as you saw the President act last fall &#8212; a range of options remain on the table &#8212; he also wanted to be very clear and direct with the American people about what the impact could be and the fact that, in his view, defending democracy and liberty is never without cost, but we need to convey to the American people exactly what that could look like.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on Russia.&nbsp; If President Putin decides not to invade, does President Biden consider that a victory?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the world &#8212; the global community would consider that a victory.&nbsp; But again, I think what the President’s view is and what the national security team’s view is, is that this is ultimately up to President Putin.<br><br>And every step we&#8217;ve taken up to date over the last weeks and even months &#8212; to coordinate with our NATO Allies; to stay in lock- &#8212; in close touch with leaders in Congress and members about what our plans are; to put together a crippling sanctions package &#8212; what we are doing is we’re presenting the choice to President Putin.&nbsp; He, ultimately, is going to decide which path he chooses.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, I just wanted to close the loop on a few things.&nbsp; So the &#8212; Ukraine has been experiencing a number of cyberattacks today.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A number of its banks were affected.&nbsp; The Defense Ministry was affected. &nbsp;Has the United States attributed those attacks to Russia?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything on the attribution at this point in time.&nbsp; I know there have been a range of reports.&nbsp; What I can say is that we have been in touch with the Ukrainians, our Allies and partners &#8212; working with them to deter and respond to malicious cyberactivity.&nbsp;<br><br>We have also been warning for weeks and months, both publicly and in our engagements with the Ukrainians as well as our European partners, about the potential for Russia to conduct cyber operations in Ukraine, but I don’t have anything more specific on attribution at this point.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just, you know, kind of moving a little bit into the realm of the hypothetical.&nbsp; There are a lot of steps that &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, boy.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; There are a lot of steps that Russia could take that are short of an invasion but that are still, you know, aggressive &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you know, including cyber, including &#8212; there&#8217;s this step that their congress has taken on recognizing its breakaway regions in Ukraine as being, you know, separatist legitimately &#8212; and the separatist regions.&nbsp; Would the U.S. respond to any &#8212; any things like that with sanctions as you would to, you know, an actual invasion?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have conveyed before and I’ll reiterate now that we would be prepared to respond <s>with</s> [to] a range of malicious activities or actions that the Russians were to take.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then one more thing.&nbsp; I know that you &#8212; there&#8217;s &#8212; you know, you’ve said that there is very little daylight with you and European allies on this issue.&nbsp; The German Chancellor said today that Ukraine joining NATO is simply not on the table; it’s not on &#8212; an agenda item right now.&nbsp; Is that how you would characterize it from the White House?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as you’ve heard the President conveying and you just heard him convey in his remarks, our view from the United States is that nations have the right to sovereignty, to territorial integrity, freedom to set their own course and choose who they associate with.&nbsp;<br><br>So we, the United States &#8212; we&#8217;re never going to pressure or any country to join or not join a global alliance.&nbsp; That is up to them and up to the other members of NATO.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just &#8212; you say all options are on the table.&nbsp; Let’s be more specific: On the possibility of a gas tax, how would they &#8212; would the White House support doing that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have nothing to predict for you at this point, but all options remain on the table.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He said in his speech, “If Russia attacks Americans in Ukraine, we will respond.”&nbsp; Is there specific intelligence suggesting that some kind of targeted attack on Americans in Ukraine is possible?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t think he was suggesting that.&nbsp; I think, as we’ve conveyed, as we&#8217;ve warned and been very clear about the risks that would be posed to anyone who&#8217;s in Ukraine, including American citizens, were Russia to invade &#8212; one of the biggest militaries in the world &#8212; that there would be serious risk to civilians.&nbsp; That&#8217;s, I think, what he was conveying.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with the Ukrainian President slated to be out of his country this weekend to go to the Munich Security Conference, does the U.S. think that&#8217;s a good idea for him to be gone right now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we have an assessment on that from here.&nbsp; Obviously, the Munich Security Conference is an opportunity for any leader to engage with, communicate with other leaders in the world.&nbsp; And, obviously, the Vice President is going, as you know.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He’s got a busy day, obviously, with Ukraine, but has the President talked to any Supreme Court nominee?&nbsp; Have any interviews been scheduled?&nbsp; Will they happen in person or virtually?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m going to disappoint you here, Ed, and just convey that I think we&#8217;re not going to give day-to-day updates from here, moving forward, about whether or not he&#8217;s done interviews.&nbsp;<br><br>What I can confirm for you is we&#8217;re still on track to &#8212; for the President to make a decision and make an announcement before the end of the month, which is in two weeks.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We file that under the &#8220;got to ask.&#8221;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He will do some interviews in the next two weeks.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I can confirm for you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There we go.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jacqui.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been told for a long time that some cyberattacks would likely precede an invasion.&nbsp; So, if it turns out that Russia is behind what happened today &#8212; or is &#8212; I guess, how I should phrase it is: Is there work being done quickly to figure out if Russia is behind what happened today so that sanctions can be imposed before there is bloodshed? &nbsp;Or is the calculus still sort of centering on force on force or some, you know, passing over the border?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, we are constantly doing those assessments.&nbsp; And certainly, as any cyberattack happens, that is certainly a process that happens behind the scenes and that our intelligence community and our national security community undertakes, as it would be in this case as well.<br><br>I would note, though, as it relates to sanctions: One, there&#8217;s a range of means that we could respond, both seen and unseen, to a &#8212; to a cyberattack or any other attack.&nbsp; And the President has the purview to do whatever he chooses in that regard.&nbsp;<br><br>But our view remains that the crippling package of sanctions is an effective deterrent.&nbsp; So if you do that all in advance, what is to stop them from moving forward?<br><br>Now, that may be a different policy issue &#8212; difference of opinion, I should say, on policy issues with some in Congress, and that&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; But that is our view from the administration.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, this may or may not be related at all, but is there any information on what caused the power outage on the North Lawn?&nbsp; Every TV network lost power at the same time<br>during the President’s remarks.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It was a very inconvenient time, I will just note, for all of you &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The timing was suspect, yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; and for us.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any assessment of that, no.&nbsp; Or &#8212; yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, does the White House view Ukraine giving up on NATO aspirations as a possible off ramp?&nbsp; I understand that, you know, the President has said, the administration has said over and over that NATO members would not, you know, encourage &#8212; or would not &#8212; would not give up that ability for someone else to join.&nbsp;<br><br>But, you know, they do have a long way to go, and now that there&#8217;s, you know, all of this concern that if there was a member &#8212; if they did become members, it could potentially trigger Article 5.<br><br>Is there any discussion among NATO Allies about, you know, how significant it would be if Zelenskyy were to make that offer himself?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have not raised that from the United States.&nbsp; And again, I would reiterate what I said a little bit earlier, which is that our position is that we are not going to pressure Ukraine or any country to join or not join an alliance, that it is &#8212; nations have the right to sovereignty and territorial integrity, and that&#8217;s a choice for them to make.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, why is the administration encouraging Americans who are evac- &#8212; or fleeing through Poland to be &#8212; to bring proof of COVID-19 vaccination?&nbsp; As I understand it, Poland does not require that.&nbsp; So is there going to be a shift in messaging for Americans who are trying to get out through Poland?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would check with the State Department on that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to follow up with you &#8212; for you on your behalf as well.<br><br>Go ahead, Kristen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to circle back to the idea of what de-escalation would look like and how the administration would trust that it were actually real.&nbsp; Do you have a sense of how many troops you would need to actually see with your own eyes, through satellite images or otherwise, would need to withdraw in order for this administration to feel as though Putin were, in fact, de-escalating (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, Kristen, that is a decision that we would make in partnership with our NATO Allies &#8212; right? &#8212; and European countries.&nbsp;<br><br>And you look at everything from satellite imagery &#8212; something that many of you have access to &#8212; to validation and verification of what they&#8217;re saying they would do.<br><br>So I can&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to be in a position, nor would I expect the Defense Department would be, to give you a troop number, but I think it would be very clear if that were a step they were taking.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And I think there’s been a lot of mixed messages publicly coming out today.&nbsp; Among them, the NATO Secretary-General that there is cause for “cautious optimism” when it comes to some of these talks that are happening behind the scenes.&nbsp; Does the administration, does the President share that cautious optimism?&nbsp; Because we heard from the President very firm language.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President also conveyed it would be positive if it was verified that they pulled back their troops.<br><br>And certainly, the openness to diplomacy is something that everybody should support and I think our NATO Allies would support as well.<br><br>At the same time, we&#8217;ve seen this playbook before.&nbsp; And especially given the history of President Putin and the Russians, their history of false-flag operations, of misinformation, we need to verify.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So &#8212; and I guess that&#8217;s my question: Does the administration share the NATO Secretary General&#8217;s cautious optimism?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I don&#8217;t think we need to put in more words than what the President just conveyed in a speech to the country.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The GOP senators have unveiled a sanctions bill.&nbsp; Have you assessed whether or not this is something the administration wants to see some movement on, this is something that you would potentially support, given that the bipartisan talks stalled?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not yet, because it just came out.&nbsp; But again, our view remains that a bipartisan effort would be the best effort moving forward.&nbsp; And as I conveyed to Jacqui a few minutes ago, you know, our view continues to be that the crippling sanctions package we&#8217;ve designed is meant to be a deterrent.<br><br>Go ahead, Ken.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the Senate is working on this stopgap funding bill that, you know, the deadline is Friday.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the level of confidence that the President will be able to sign that extension by Friday?<br><br>And, separately, has the administration been talking to the two Republican senators who have raised concerns &#8212; Senator Lee and Blackburn?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are engaged with a range of Democrats and Republicans, and certainly we are hopeful that we will be able to sign this.<br><br>I would note, though, that I believe &#8212; and correct me if I&#8217;m wrong here &#8212; that one of Senator Blackburn&#8217;s primary concerns is about a relation to the &#8212; to the funding of crack pipes.&nbsp; Is this correct?&nbsp; Which is not an issue.<br><br>So, this is a &#8212; this is an issue &#8212; what is happening here is the potential to hold up funding in the government and important programs around an issue that is not an issue, because we&#8217;ve been very clear that we are not providing funding for crack pipes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, the Senate Banking Committee had planned to vote on your Fed nominees today.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There was a holdup there.&nbsp; Republicans have objected to Sarah Bloom Raskin’s nomination.&nbsp; What does the administration think of this delay?&nbsp; And is the administration going to provide any additional details to Senator Toomey &#8212; some of the issues that he’s raised?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say that this is a very extreme step that&#8217;s totally irresponsible, in our view.&nbsp; It&#8217;s never been more important to have confirmed leadership at the Fed to help continue our recovery and fight inflation.&nbsp; And, obviously, they have a unique role to play, an important &#8212; a vital role to play as it relates to inflation.&nbsp; And I think Democrats and Republicans have agreed on that for decades.&nbsp;<br><br>So Republicans are out there saying, “Inflation is a problem.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a huge issue.”&nbsp; We agree.&nbsp; And then they&#8217;re not even bothering to show up to even vote against these nominees to the Federal Reserve.&nbsp; What message is that sending to the American public?<br><br>So we &#8212; and I would note, just on Sarah Bloom Raskin, since you asked me about her as well: You know, she&#8217;s one of the most qualified individuals to ever be nominated to the Federal Reserve.&nbsp; She&#8217;s made the strongest ethics commitments in the history of the Fed, even as she&#8217;s made extensive disclosures to the Banking Committee as a natural part of the process.<br><br>Senator Toomey has continued to promote false allegations that have already been shot down by ethics experts, the Kansas City Fed, the founder of Reserve Trust, and Sarah Bloom Raskin herself.<br><br>So we&#8217;re going to continue to work with Chairman Brown on a path forward and look forward to the Banking Committee eventually holding a vote to commit these &#8212; to confirm these five nominees.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any entertaining of other options if it stalls in committee?&nbsp; You know, there appears to be some question about whether the Senate as a whole can advance these nominations.&nbsp; Is that something you’re exploring?&nbsp; Or is that something that you don’t think you have the power to do?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean in terms of different legislative processes or different &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s some speculation that the full Senate could, sort of, skip the committee vote if it stalls out in bringing them forward.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I don’t &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe the Senate has that power, or does it have to go through a committee?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our focus right now is on working with Chairman Brown on moving these nominees through the committee.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask also on COVID funding?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; HHS briefed Congress this week, requesting what &#8212; $30 billion in funding.&nbsp; Can you just give us a sense of &#8212; A, can you confirm that?&nbsp; B, what, in particular, do you need this funding for?&nbsp; And has the existing funding been allocated?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, HHS&#8217;s briefing today, or this afternoon, was a part of our regular conversations with Congress about various resources it needs, including what is needed for COVID response.&nbsp; This is important because, while we continue to have sufficient funds to respond to the current Omicron surge in the coming weeks, our goal has always been to ensure that we are well prepared to stay ahead of the virus.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve been in these ongoing conversations about what those needs might look like, and this was a part of that effort.<br><br>In terms of funds that have been allocated or spent, more than 90 percent &#8212; so, available Rescue Plan funds, which is where the funding has come from to date, have been obligated or allocated.&nbsp; Ninety percent of that has been for purchases of vaccines and therapeutics, vaccine distribution efforts that have gotten shots in arms, testing, including for schools and at other high-need locations.<br><br>Resources from the Rescue Plan and prior COVID response bills have enabled us to respond forcefully to the Delta and Omicron surges.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re trying to do now is stay ahead and stay in contact with Congress about what those needs might look like.<br><br>Q &nbsp;And Secretary Blinken said yesterday that the U.S. is not on pace right now to meet the President&#8217;s goal &#8212; or the WHO goal of vaccinating 70 percent of the world by later this year. &nbsp;Is any of this funding aimed at jumpstarting global vaccination efforts? &nbsp;And can you talk a little bit about why you&#8217;re not on pace? &nbsp;Is it, for instance, a supply problem? &nbsp;Or is it a problem with what Secretary Blinken called &#8220;last-mile&#8221; type stuff, getting &#8220;shots in arms&#8221; &#8212; to borrow language of the COVID group?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is &#8212; that is an undervalued part of it, I should say.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m &#8212; thank you for raising that part of it.<br><br>So, right now, we&#8217;ve shipped over around 440 million doses and are continuing to aggressively share around 10 million doses a week to the world free of charge.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the first country to buy doses for the sole purpose of sharing them with the world.&nbsp; We also bought, as you know, a billion doses.&nbsp;<br><br>And Secretary Blinken, I think, made those comments in part because he wants to rally the world to do more.&nbsp;<br><br>But a big part of our effort right now and where we have seen challenge is turning vaccines into vaccination, which means working closely with our partners on the ground and dealing with hyperlocal issues countries may be facing to increase vaccination.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is a big part of the focus of Ambassador Power and USAID&#8217;s Global Vaccination initiative, but part of it is that “shots in arms” component.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have countries started deferring their U.S. donations because the capacity is the problem more than the supply?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There have been moments, yes, where countries are not able to receive the doses that we&#8217;re able to provide.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Raise &#8212; creating a gas tax holiday takes legislation.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering, what are other things that the President could do on his own to mitigate a gas price hike because of Ukrainian conflict?&nbsp; What else can he do by himself?&nbsp;<br><br>And in terms of releasing oil from the SPR, have you made a determination of how much cost rise that would offset?&nbsp; In other words, what good does it do?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; And those are assessments that our economic team is constantly, of course, making.&nbsp; We did see even the anticipation of the release, back in December, helped lower the price by about 10 cents.&nbsp; But that &#8212; those assessments are constantly being made.<br><br>In terms of &#8212; without a decision being made, which I know you&#8217;re not asking, but just to be clear: There are steps the President has taken in the past, obviously tapping the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; He has also engaged, we have engaged with oil-producing countries around the world.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something we will continue to do because, clearly, we need to ensure that the supply out in the global market is meeting the demand.&nbsp; And, obviously &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mean, encouraging other countries to produce more?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re saying?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, okay.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been a part of our effort, even as we anticipate what impact there could be from an invasion.&nbsp; So, as you know, there&#8217;s obviously a difference between natural gas shortages and the impact on home heating, which is largely a regional issue, but we have been still &#8212; in Europe &#8212; but we&#8217;ve been still working with partners on that as well, but also on the supply of gas out in the market &#8212; oil, I should say, or gas.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said that &#8220;an invasion remains distinctly possible.&#8221;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some senior administration officials said, a couple days ago, that &#8220;as soon as this week.&#8221;&nbsp; Is that still the timeline, or has anything shifted based on kind of mixed messages of the last couple of days?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a new assessment.&nbsp; As I think you heard the President say, it&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s a distinct possibility, but we don&#8217;t have a new assessment of a decision being made either.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, I know there&#8217;d been internal discussions about giving a speech like the one the President gave &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; today for some time.&nbsp; Why today?&nbsp; And then, the intent behind it: Obviously, it seemed to be looking to hit on multiple audiences to deliver specific messages to them.&nbsp; So why &#8212; why today?&nbsp; And why that range of messages?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, Phil &#8212; Phil, I mean, you all have been covering this very closely &#8212; the potential of an invasion, our diplomatic engagements &#8212; and there&#8217;s no question the American people have been consuming what you have been reporting.&nbsp;<br><br>But I think we felt and the President felt it was important to be very clear and direct with the American people about what the impact could be on them, what the consequences would be, what our values are, and why it is important to stand by not just the territorial integrity and sovereignty of a country, but also stand among our Allies and partners around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>So, it was very important to him to lay out very clearly what &#8212; the steps we&#8217;ve taken, the actions we’re prepared to take, what&#8217;s at stake for the United States and the world, and how this will impact us here at home.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of why today: It wasn&#8217;t based on &#8212; obviously, as you saw &#8212; a desire to put out a new policy or based on something new internally.&nbsp; It was just our &#8212; the President&#8217;s interest and feeling it was time to speak directly to the American people about all of those issues.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just last one.&nbsp; On the first point that you made there: Is there concern, either by the President or inside the White House, that perhaps the understanding or support for, kind of, traditional Western alliances that have been a pillar over the last 80 years is waning or doesn&#8217;t exist to the degree that it used to?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, I think, Phil &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Inside the country, I mean.&nbsp; Inside the country.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, no, it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any data assessment of that.&nbsp; But we also are fully aware of the fact that, right now, the American people are still grappling with a pandemic.&nbsp; They&#8217;re grappling with rising costs.&nbsp; Some &#8212; two iss- &#8212; two big issues the President speaks to quite frequently.&nbsp;<br><br>And it was important to him to be able to lay out clearly for them what this, you know, potential conflict, potential invasion &#8212; in a place that may feel far away &#8212; and how it could impact them &#8212; how that could impact them, and his engagement.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you, Jen.&nbsp; President Biden today said there&#8217;s 150,000 Russian troops encircling Ukraine.&nbsp; That appeared to be a higher number than previously reported.&nbsp; I think 130,000 is how, most recently, we&#8217;ve seen it characterized.&nbsp; So was the President confirming an actual escalation of Russian troops?&nbsp; Or why did he present a new number there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think over the last dozen days or so we&#8217;ve seen a dramatic acceleration and buildup of troops.&nbsp; And so, the President said in his remarks very carefully, it’s encircling Ukraine on the border and also in Belarus.&nbsp; And so, I think he felt it was important to give an assessment of where things stand.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, secondly, regarding a gas tax holiday, you said, quote, &#8220;All options remain on the table.&#8221;&nbsp; There is right now a bill from Senate Democrats that would institute a suspension of the gas tax for the rest of the year.&nbsp; Does the White House support that specific bill?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t made any decision about additional steps at this point in time.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; As you mentioned earlier, Vice President Harris is headed to the Munich Security Conference this week.&nbsp; Does the President plan to also send Secretary Blinken?&nbsp; And if so, would a last-minute addition suggest a different or perhaps reduced or more limited role for Vice President Harris at that conference?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s any plans to limit or reduce the Vice President&#8217;s role at the Munich Security Conference or at the global stage &#8212; on a global stage.&nbsp; She&#8217;s going to give a speech while she&#8217;s there.&nbsp; And she is a vital and important representative for the United States and our values and our intentions at this point in the world.&nbsp;<br><br>But in terms of plans for Secretary Blinken to attend or not, I can check with the State Department and see.&nbsp; There are plenty of leaders to meet with, so more bandwidth.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on &#8212; on a different note: The President continues to talk about his Build Back Better plan.&nbsp; He did so today; did a couple of events last week.&nbsp; What is the White House expectation at this point about the future of that plan?&nbsp; Is there any evidence of any sort of forward movement, forward progress, even on a pared-back version of that?&nbsp; There doesn&#8217;t seem to be a lot of optimism or action right now on Capitol Hill.&nbsp; But can you talk about what the White House expectation is for that and why the President continues to bring this up?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President continues to bring it up because, as we talk about the impact of inflation &#8212; which most people experience in their daily lives as rising costs &#8212; one of the ways that we can address that is by passing legislation that will help lower costs for Americans, whether it&#8217;s childcare or healthcare or the cost of prescription drugs.&nbsp; And we can do that and fully pay for it by making the tax system more fair.&nbsp;<br><br>So, what is encouraging to the President is that there is broad support for lowering costs for the American people in all of those categories and for making the tax system more fair. &nbsp;And we are continuing to work in lockstep and in partnership with a range of senators. &nbsp;And they’re having their own discussions about moving these efforts forward.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much, Jen.&nbsp; One question on Asian Americans, and one question on Ukraine.&nbsp; On Asian Americans: Actually, the Team USA Gold Medal winner, Chloe Kim, revealed, as an Asian American, according to AP, quote, “…she was tormented online daily.&nbsp; She says she was consumed by the fear that her parents could be killed whenever she heard the news about another brutal assault on an Asian person.”&nbsp; Unquote.<br><br>Actually, under President Biden&#8217;s watch, in 2021, the anti-Asian hate crimes increased by 339 percent.&nbsp; It seems we don&#8217;t see much action taken by the White House.&nbsp; And even in a press briefing, the very last time you mentioned about Asian Americans was last May.&nbsp; So, will the President take some action or even just record a video, like what he did last year to raise the awareness?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me say first that Chloe Kim &#8212; I&#8217;m obsessed with the Olympics, so I&#8217;m just going to give you a little biography here, but she&#8217;s 21 years old, and she made those comments, which is incredibly courageous and brave that she spoke out about the fear she had &#8212; the fear she has for her family members.&nbsp; And she&#8217;s not the only Asian American to do that, but she is somebody who is now a double Gold medalist.&nbsp; Amazing.&nbsp; And so I just want to take a moment to applaud her for her courage in doing that.<br><br>I will say that the President has put in place a task force.&nbsp; He has hired a senior-level staffer to be a representative and be someone who can speak to these threats and these concerns and these fears felt by the Asian American community, because there&#8217;s a number of steps we need to take and continue to take to address.<br><br>And we&#8217;ve seen this rise, unfortunately, because of hate-filled rhetoric and language around the origins of the pandemic.&nbsp; And that is something that Asian Americans across the country have been feeling.&nbsp;<br><br>So I can just reiterate for you that the President is absolutely committed to continuing to speak out, to crack down, to take steps, and again, would thank Chloe Kim for her courage.<br><br>Go ahead, Amna.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me &#8212; I just have to keep going because we got a &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a couple quick on Ukraine, Jen.&nbsp; President Biden said that we should give diplomacy every chance to succeed.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken, after his call with Foreign Minister Lavrov, said that a window remains open to resolve this peacefully.&nbsp; I just &#8212; on the timeline, how long does the President think that window should stay open if there&#8217;s no invasion but also no pullback of Russian troops?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what&#8217;s the alternative if we don&#8217;t leave the open &#8212; the window to diplomacy open, right?&nbsp; I mean, you know, our objective, obviously, is that you heard the President say today there is no threat the United States is posing to Russia, to the Russian people.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no threat that Ukraine is posing to Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>What we&#8217;re working to do here is leave a forum for de-escalation for &#8212; and prevent a war.&nbsp; And so, for &#8212; to us, the door to diplomacy should always be open, and we should always look for opportunities to de-escalate.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any concern this turns into, like, a frozen conflict basically, where troops just stay on the border and there’s no invasion but also no pullback?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, there&#8217;s going to have to be a continued dialogue and discussion.&nbsp; But Russia not invading Ukraine and not risking and impacting the lives of many, many people in that country, including potentially American citizens, would certainly be a step we would welcome.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on what Americans should prepare for: You mentioned the threat of cyberattacks.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President mentioned that as well.&nbsp; And we know Homeland Security has previously mentioned they&#8217;ve seen an uptick in scanning on U.S. critical infrastructure and so on.&nbsp; Should Americans be prepared for a potential Russian cyberattack on critical U.S. infrastructure or other networks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say: Even before we&#8217;ve been discussing the buildup of troops at the border, and even before we&#8217;ve been discussing the bellicose rhetoric, we have seen an uptick in cyber activity by malicious actors around the world, either those living in countries or the countries themselves.&nbsp;<br><br>And so that is something &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any new threat or new warning to post today, but that is something we have certainly been amping and increasing our focus on, as an &#8212; as a threat that&#8217;s emerging but has been the case for the last several years.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you take a question on Africa?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; One second.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;ll go to you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, just this hour, lawmakers put out a bipartisan statement warning President Putin.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve said from the podium that the White House doesn&#8217;t need Congress to pass the sanctions package to implement your own sanctions package, but wouldn&#8217;t it have sent a stronger message if there had been an agreement reached?&nbsp; What message do you think it sends to Putin that all we got out of Congress was a statement?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think President Putin knows very clearly, because he&#8217;s heard it directly from President Biden&#8217;s mouth, that if he invades &#8212; if he invades Ukraine, that there will be crippling sanctions, and we don&#8217;t need Congress to act in order to do that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when will the President make a decision on any new energy policies to impact prices at the pump?&nbsp; Because even without an invasion, prices have risen beyond where they were before the emergency reserve release back in November.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You&#8217;re right.&nbsp; And the President is very focused on making sure we&#8217;re doing everything we can to lower the cost for Americans in any way it hits them, whether it&#8217;s prices at the pump, or when you go buy a pound of meat, or wherever it may be.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re continuing to assess.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s continuing to look at options.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a prediction of &#8212; of any decision though.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On Africa &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go to you after, Simon.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Switching topics entirely.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President is headed later this week to Ohio.&nbsp; He said that he&#8217;d like to be out in communities with people &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; frequently.&nbsp; How often would he like to be out there per week?&nbsp; What are you guys (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Every day?&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; well, but when he says that &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what is your anticipation?&nbsp; Is he looking to travel two, three days a week?&nbsp; And when would you expect that to ramp up?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, I think you can expect that to increase around the State of the Union and after.&nbsp; And I think we are constrained by a couple of things, including the CR funding but also the fact that there is a whole lot going on in the world.&nbsp; Even though he can be President anywhere, he also has a responsibility to sometimes be in the White House &#8212; or oftentimes be in the White House.&nbsp; So &#8212; but he&#8217;s looking forward to getting out there more in the coming weeks.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he have anywhere specific that he hasn’t been yet, or places that he hasn’t been, that he feels &#8212; frequently enough &#8212; that he&#8217;d really like to get back to?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Good question.&nbsp; I would venture to guess that he has probably been nearly everywhere, given he ran for President a couple times and Vice President.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I meant since he’s been &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As President, I don’t have any prediction of states or a readout of states that he is looking forward to going to, but I’m sure he &#8212; he is looking forward to traveling around the country &#8212; blue states, red states &#8212; across the gamut. &nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On Africa, you said &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay, Simon.&nbsp; I’ll go to you.&nbsp; Go ahead, Simon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; It’s been three months.&nbsp; So, if you can allow me to ask two questions.&nbsp; The President spoke with Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed of Ethiopia on January 10.&nbsp; It’s been almost a month now &#8212; more than a month since that call took place.&nbsp; And the WHO yesterday released a statement saying that they still don’t have access to the Tigray region for humanitarian access because the government is not allowing them to have fuel.<br><br>So, is the President still interested in anything else apart from Ukraine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Of course, he is.&nbsp; The President has to be the &#8212; a global leader in the world.&nbsp; And he is responsible for not just what&#8217;s happening around the world but also what&#8217;s happening domestically.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me give you an update or a comment from here:<br><br>We are hopeful that recent steps taken by the government of Ethiopia and other actors might open a path to resolving the conflict.&nbsp; Over the last month, the Prime Minister has taken steps to promote dialogue, release political prisoners, and enable expanded delivery of medical supplies in the Tigray region.&nbsp; We continue to have serious concerns about the humanitarian situation in Ethiopia, and we are focused on working with our parties &#8212; with all parties to end the source of the suffering, the military conflict.<br><br>Go ahead, Karen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; President Zelenskyy tomorrow is calling for a day of unity &#8212; a national holiday tomorrow in Ukraine.&nbsp; His message for the last couple of days, if not longer, has been “don’t panic” to Ukrainians.<br><br>Does the administration have concerns that Zelenskyy and Ukrainian leaders have not adequately prepared the Ukrainian people for a Russian invasion?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to speak to that.&nbsp; What I can speak to is what we feel our role and responsibility is, which is to provide a range of information about what we see at the border, what we see Russia preparing, and our assessment of what impact that could be.&nbsp; Every leader makes their own decisions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you have an update on the humanitarian assistance that the U.S. is talking with European allies should that happen and the Ukrainian people need that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I know we &#8212; Secretary Blinken made an announcement &#8212; I believe it was yesterday &#8212; about additional assistance.&nbsp; Let me just see if I have any more details on it in here, and if not, I will get that to you shortly after the briefing, Karen.&nbsp; Let me just see.<br><br>Let&#8217;s see here.&nbsp; Let me get you &#8212; I can get you &#8212; let&#8217;s see.&nbsp;<br><br>Last &#8212; so, we did offer &#8212; we just announced &#8212; sorry &#8212; a&nbsp; sovereign loan guarantee to Ukraine of up to $1 billion to bolster Ukraine&#8217;s economy amidst pressure resulting from Russia&#8217;s military buildup.&nbsp; This builds on the $3 billion in sovereign loan guarantees we issued to Ukraine between 2014 and 2016.<br><br>We&#8217;ve also committed more security assistance to Ukraine in the last year than at any point in history &#8212; $650 million.&nbsp;<br><br>And we also announced we&#8217;re launching a new Partnership Fund for a Resilient Ukraine with our European &#8212; with our Allies and partners to include &#8212; to continue to expand on that.<br><br>The last thing is we &#8212; the Export-Import Bank has made available $3 billion in support for projects in Ukraine, and&nbsp;the Development Finance Corporation has a current investment portfolio in Ukraine of approximately $800 million across more than a dozen projects.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve obviously provided a range of assistance, which we will continue to build on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, will Vice President Harris be meeting with President Zelenskyy when she&#8217;s in Munich?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything on her planned meetings at this point in time.&nbsp; I expect we&#8217;ll have more as we get a little bit closer, and I expect they&#8217;ll do a preview call from her team as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then an Olympics question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Does the administration have any reaction to the IOC’s decision to allow Russian figure skater &#8212; I’m going to butcher her name &#8212; Kamila Valieva to continue competing in the Olympics after her doping scandal?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, I would point you to the statement made by the U.S. Olympic and Paralympic Committee, who oppose the decision made in Beijing, saying it, quote, “appears to be another chapter in the systemic and pervasive disregard for clean sport by Russia.”&nbsp;<br><br>But these were independent decisions made by the <s>U.S. Anti-Doping</s> [International Testing] Agency and Court of Arbitration for Sport.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any additional comment from here.&nbsp; I would point you, again, to the U.S. Olympic Committee.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the U.S. Energy Information Administration shows data that Russian oil being imported in the U.S. has been increasing over the past year.&nbsp; In May of 2021, it was the most on record.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the President said he wants to use all tools to keep gas prices down.&nbsp; Is he looking at temporary things to keep gas prices down should there be a Russian invasion?&nbsp; Or is there any consideration in reversing some of the policies and going back to increasing U.S. energy independence?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to detail for you, inclu- &#8212; in terms of what he is considering.&nbsp; But our overarching objective is to decrease the impact on American consumers and increase the impact on Russian leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you talked about the boycott on the Republicans of the Fed nominees.&nbsp; Does the White House support allowing four of the five nominees to go through and then dealing with Sarah Bloom Raskin later?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, we are working with Chairman Brown to move all five nominees forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Right there.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Do you have any update on maybe steps the White House is taking in the event that the trucker protesting in Canada heads to the U.S. and, also, especially to D.C. around the time of the State of the Union?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; our Department of Homeland Security team has been assessing and I gave an update last week that they also increased support &#8212; federal support around the Super Bowl when there were those reports.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note the Super Bowl did move forward and there was no halting of that, so that is a positive development as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we are constantly assessing any impacts or any security impacts.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to ask &#8212; back to the Supreme Court.&nbsp; The President received a report with recommendations on how to reform the Supreme Court late last year.&nbsp; Has he at all reviewed the report yet and taken a position on it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t a &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t &#8212; I would just remind everyone: It wasn&#8217;t recommendations; it was a broad assessment from across the gamut of scholars from all ends of the political spectrum who were looking at a range of historic issues as it relates to the Court.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has been reviewing that, but I don&#8217;t have anything to read out for you on that front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The other thing I wanted to ask you was about voting rights.&nbsp; The President signed this expansive executive order a year ago on voting.&nbsp; I believe Susan Rice put out &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; an update on it in September or October.&nbsp; Could you provide an update on what agencies are doing?&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to start beginning seeing elections as soon as next month.&nbsp; I believe that&#8217;s in Texas, but other states are going to start to have them.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, I do have a lot on this, not in front of me.&nbsp; So, in terms of what agencies are working on or what they&#8217;ve been working on and what they&#8217;ve basically been doing &#8212;&nbsp; so you&#8217;re &#8212; have more detail on this than maybe others do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But all of the agencies were tasked with putting together their own plans to expand voting access, and they&#8217;ve been working on those plans.&nbsp; They&#8217;re all at different points in the review process and how it will be implemented.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if you look at past examples, where &#8212; I think it was back in the ‘90s &#8212; where if you went to the DMV to renew your driver&#8217;s license, they would offer you the opportunity to register to vote &#8212; you know, stuff like that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me see if we can get you something &#8212; and anyone else who&#8217;s interested &#8212; after the briefing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, we&#8217;ll do one more.&nbsp; And then we&#8217;ll wrap it up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; One on China, one on Afghanistan.&nbsp; First of all, China&#8217;s foreign ministry has been really critical of U.S. rhetoric on the Russia-Ukraine crisis, calling it “hyping up the possibility of warfare,” saying the U.S. is “clamoring for bloc confrontation.”&nbsp; What does the White House make of this rhetoric?&nbsp; Are you going to take any action against it, either through talk or other means?&nbsp; And what do you make this closeness between Moscow and Beijing?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the &#8212; first, the meeting that they had a couple of weeks ago reflects an approach both countries have already taken for some time, which is to move closer together.&nbsp; We know, and we&#8217;ve said before, but China is not in a position to compensate Russia for their economic losses.&nbsp; And we have tools to deploy if we see foreign companies, including those in China, trying to backfill sanctions.<br><br>You know, I would say our overarching view, though, is that if Russia chooses to move forward, it will cost China and how it&#8217;s viewed in the eyes of Europe and the world.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something for them to assess.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are trying to prevent a war here.&nbsp; That is why we are putting information out and why we are engaging with the global community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then how do you respond to Afghans who are critical of the executive order that proposes to split the frozen Afghan money?&nbsp; They say that, you know, they weren&#8217;t involved in the 9/11 attacks, so why are they getting less of these funds that they&#8217;re entitled to?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that, first &#8212; let me start with the fact that this is one step in the process.&nbsp; No funds can be transferred until the courts make a ruling.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What the President was trying to do was enable certain U.S.-based assets belonging to Afghanistan’s central bank to be used to benefit the Afghan people, otherwise it would have been held &#8212; right? &#8212; and that money wouldn&#8217;t have been going.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, that&#8217;s why we saw &#8212; and he took a proactive step to facilitate access to $3.5 billion of those assets for the benefit of the Afghan people and Afghanistan&#8217;s future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>More than &#8212; as you know, many U.S. victims of terrorism, including the relatives of victims who died in the September 11&nbsp; terrorist attacks have brought claims against the Taliban and are pursuing these assets in federal court.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, more than $3.5 billion in assets are going to remain in the United States and are subject to the ongoing litigation.&nbsp; But what I think it&#8217;s important for people to know and understand is he took this proactive step to sign the executive order in an effort to try to provide some of this funding to the Afghan people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When will that happen?&nbsp; When will &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the courts have to rule in order for it to happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the other half &#8212; the $3.5 billion?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; The court &#8212; that has &#8212; it has to &#8212; the courts have to rule in order for any of the funding to move forward, I believe, is my understanding.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But why &#8212; how is that proactive then?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He’s making clear that he believes that half of the funding should go to the Afghan people to &#8212; for humanitarian purposes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will President Biden meet in person with the Russian president?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I answered that question a little bit earlier.<br><br>5:04 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
