<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:25:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Keeping our Promise to Veterans Suffering from Toxic Environmental&#160;Exposures</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-keeping-our-promise-to-veterans-suffering-from-toxic-environmental-exposures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America’s veterans are the best of us. I’ve always believed that we have a sacred obligation to equip all those we send into harm’s way and to care for them and their families when they come home. That’s especially true for veterans suffering the visible and invisible wounds of war, whether they were injured in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America’s veterans are the best of us. I’ve always believed that we have a sacred obligation to equip all those we send into harm’s way and to care for them and their families when they come home. That’s especially true for veterans suffering the visible and invisible wounds of war, whether they were injured in combat or breathed in toxic smoke from burn pits on base. We can and must do more to address the harms that come from hazardous exposures, which have gone unaddressed for far too long.</p>



<p>We learned a horrible lesson after Vietnam, when the harmful effects of exposure to Agent Orange sometimes took years to manifest, and too many veterans were left unable to access the care they needed. I refuse to repeat that mistake when it comes to the veterans of our wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</p>



<p>In my State of the Union address, I announced that we would propose expanding disability and health benefits to veterans suffering from nine rare respiratory cancers. Today, the Department of Veterans Affairs is delivering on that promise and upholding that sacred obligation to the women and men who have worn the uniform of our country. This new action is guided by science and driven by a desire to ensure that our nation’s veterans receive timely access to the benefits and services they deserve.</p>



<p>Supporting our veterans is a critical part of the Unity Agenda I proposed for our nation. No matter where we live or who we voted for in the last election, we all agree that we should serve our veterans as well as they have served us. My Administration will continue to do everything in its power to support our nation’s veterans, and I urge Congress to pass bipartisan legislation to comprehensively address toxic exposures and further deliver the vital benefits our veterans have earned. I will sign it immediately.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Nominee for Ambassador to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/president-biden-announces-nominee-for-ambassador-to-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intention to nominate veteran U.S. diplomat Bridget A. Brink to serve as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ukraine. Bridget A. Brink, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ukraine Bridget A. Brink, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, currently serves as the U.S. Ambassador to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intention to nominate veteran U.S. diplomat Bridget A. Brink to serve as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ukraine.</p>



<p><strong>Bridget A. Brink, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ukraine</strong></p>



<p>Bridget A. Brink, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, currently serves as the U.S. Ambassador to the Slovak Republic.&nbsp;Prior to that, she served as Senior Advisor and Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs at the U.S. Department of State, with responsibility for issues related to Eastern Europe and the Caucasus.&nbsp;She also served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassies in Tashkent, Uzbekistan, and Tbilisi, Georgia. Brink spent her twenty-five-year career in the Foreign Service focused on advancing U.S. policy in Europe and Eurasia.&nbsp;She was the Director for the Aegean and the South Caucasus at the National Security Council and served in the State Department as the Deputy Director for Southern European Affairs, Special Assistant to the Under Secretary for Political Affairs, and Cyprus Desk Officer.&nbsp;She began her career in Belgrade, Serbia.</p>



<p>Originally from Michigan, Brink is the recipient of numerous performance awards. She holds Master’s degrees in International Relations and Political Theory from the London School of Economics and Political Science, as well as a Bachelor’s degree in Political Science from Kenyon College. She speaks Russian and has studied Slovak, Serbian, Georgian, and French.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/24/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-naftali-bennett-of-israel-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 17:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of Israel to discuss shared regional and global security challenges, including the threat posed by Iran and its proxies. The two leaders emphasized the strong personal bond they have developed since the Prime Minister’s visit to Washington last summer. This personal relationship has animated&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of Israel to discuss shared regional and global security challenges, including the threat posed by Iran and its proxies. The two leaders emphasized the strong personal bond they have developed since the Prime Minister’s visit to Washington last summer. This personal relationship has animated the work of our diplomatic and national security teams, enabling both countries to arrive at common positions on difficult matters. The President welcomed the visit to Washington this week by the Prime Minister’s National Security Advisor. The President also accepted an invitation to visit Israel in the coming months. The President took note of ongoing efforts between Israeli and Palestinian officials to lower tensions and ensure a peaceful conclusion to the holy season of Ramadan. He affirmed his unwavering support for Israel and its defense needs, and welcomed the historic $1 billion allocation to replenish Israel’s Iron Dome system. The two leaders committed to stay in regular contact to follow up on the important work of the U.S-Israel Strategic Consultative Group, chaired by their respective National Security Advisors.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Passing of Former Senator Orrin&#160;Hatch</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/24/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-former-senator-orrin-hatch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51683</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I and the entire Biden family are saddened to learn of the passing of Orrin Hatch, the longest-serving Senator in Utah’s history, and the longest-serving Republican Senator in our nation’s history. Orrin Hatch once shared in an interview that he had a soft side, and he had a tough side. To serve with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I and the entire Biden family are saddened to learn of the passing of Orrin Hatch, the longest-serving Senator in Utah’s history, and the longest-serving Republican Senator in our nation’s history.</p>



<p>Orrin Hatch once shared in an interview that he had a soft side, and he had a tough side. To serve with Orrin, as I did for over three decades, was to see—and appreciate—both.</p>



<p>He was the fighter who carried with him the memory of his humble upbringing near Pittsburgh, who never humored a bully, or shied from a challenge. The young man who, upon receiving his degree from Brigham Young University, was the first in his family to graduate college; the young lawyer who built a successful law practice; and the Senator who sprinted from meeting to meeting because there was so much to do—indeed, when Senator Hatch retired, he had sponsored or co-sponsored more legislation than any Senator at the time.</p>



<p>I saw that energetic, sharp-elbowed Orrin in the many battles we had over tax policy, the right of workers to join a union, and many others.</p>



<p>At the same time, Senator Hatch was also a man of deep faith; a gentle soul who wrote songs and poems, and shared them with friends, colleagues, and the world. This was the Orrin who looked out for the people who often didn’t have a voice in our laws and our country. I saw this in his efforts to pass the Americans with Disabilities Act and the Children’s Health Insurance Program.</p>



<p>When I first launched the Cancer Moonshot as Vice President, one of the first visits I made was to the Huntsman Cancer Institute in Salt Lake City, at Orrin’s request. We both saw speeding the pace of cancer research as an issue that transcended political divisions.</p>



<p>When I cast my 10,000<sup>th</sup> vote in the Senate, Orrin came to the Senate floor and we had a chance to speak. I said that the greatest perk one has as a Senator was access to people with serious minds, a serious sense of purpose, and who cared about something. That was Orrin.</p>



<p>He was, quite simply, an American original.</p>



<p>Jill and I send our deepest sympathies to Elaine, and all of the Hatch children, grandchildren, and great-grandchildren.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Armenian Remembrance&#160;Day</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/24/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-armenian-remembrance-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 24, 1915, Ottoman authorities arrested Armenian intellectuals and community leaders in Constantinople. Thus began the Armenian genocide—one of the worst mass atrocities of the 20th century. Today, we remember the one and a half million Armenians who were deported, massacred, or marched to their deaths in a campaign of extermination, and mourn the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On April 24, 1915, Ottoman authorities arrested Armenian intellectuals and community leaders in Constantinople. Thus began the Armenian genocide—one of the worst mass atrocities of the 20th century. Today, we remember the one and a half million Armenians who were deported, massacred, or marched to their deaths in a campaign of extermination, and mourn the tragic loss of so many lives.</p>



<p>As we reflect on the Armenian genocide, we renew our pledge to remain vigilant against the corrosive influence of hate in all its forms. We recommit ourselves to speaking out and stopping atrocities that leave lasting scars on the world. And, as we mourn what was lost during the Meds Yeghern, let us redouble our efforts toward healing and building the better, more peaceful world that we wish for our children. A world where human rights are respected, where the evils of bigotry and intolerance do not mark our daily lives, and where people everywhere are free to pursue their lives in dignity and security.</p>



<p>This is also a moment to reflect on the strength and resiliency of the Armenian people. After enduring a genocide, the Armenian people were determined to rebuild their community and their culture, so often in new homes and new lands, including the United States. Armenian Americans are a vital part of the fabric of the United States. They make our nation stronger and more dynamic, even as they continue to carry with them the tragic knowledge of what their ancestors endured. We recognize their pain and honor their story.</p>



<p>Today, 107 years later, the American people continue to honor all Armenians who perished in the genocide.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Orthodox&#160;Easter</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/23/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-orthodox-easter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 22:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I send warm wishes to all our friends in the Orthodox Christian community observing Easter. We rejoice with you in the Resurrection of Jesus Christ and the triumph of light over darkness. During this sacred season, we hold in our prayers all those who are suffering from the brutality of war and persecution.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I send warm wishes to all our friends in the Orthodox Christian community observing Easter. We rejoice with you in the Resurrection of Jesus Christ and the triumph of light over darkness.</p>



<p>During this sacred season, we hold in our prayers all those who are suffering from the brutality of war and persecution. We mourn with all those who have lost loved ones or who fear for their safety, and rededicate ourselves to working for peace with justice and for the freedom and security of all people.</p>



<p>This year, we have once more seen the essential ways in which Orthodox Christians strengthen our nation and world: through compassion and service to others; demonstrations of interfaith solidarity; advocacy for religious freedom for everyone, everywhere; and care for creation. Let us continue to spread the message of Easter joy through our shared work to build a world that values the inherent dignity and infinite worth of every human being.</p>



<p>May the peace of Christ be with you now and always. Happy Easter.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Lowering Costs for American&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/22/remarks-by-president-biden-on-lowering-costs-for-american-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 01:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grand Hall, Green River CollegeAuburn, Washington 1:19 P.M. PDT&#160;&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Juliana, my colleagues &#8212; I’m taking her back to Washington.&#160; We’re going to get my &#8212; the rest of my bill passed.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; We’re going to get it done. MS. JULIANA GRACEFFO:&#160; Yes, we are. THE PRESIDENT:&#160; By the way, I hope I don’t embarrass&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Grand Hall, Green River College<br>Auburn, Washington</p>



<p>1:19 P.M. PDT&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Juliana, my colleagues &#8212; I’m taking her back to Washington.&nbsp; We’re going to get my &#8212; the rest of my bill passed.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; We’re going to get it done.</p>



<p>MS. JULIANA GRACEFFO:&nbsp; Yes, we are.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; By the way, I hope I don’t embarrass her, but she’s off to Notre Dame next year.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I’ve done the commencement there a couple times.&nbsp; I told her if she sees me on campus, I don’t want her say “Joe who?” when I come up to see her.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Promise?</p>



<p>MS. JULIANA GRACEFFO:&nbsp; Promise.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; God love you.&nbsp; Thank you very, very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>MS. JULIANA GRACEFFO:&nbsp; Thank you so much (inaudible).</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mom.</p>



<p>Elisa and Juliana, thank you for that introduction.&nbsp; And, you know, as my mother would say, “God love you.”&nbsp; You’re saving lives.&nbsp; You’re saving lives by pointing out what needs to be done.</p>



<p>You know, the &#8212; I want to start off, though, by pointing out a couple things.&nbsp; Number one, as was mentioned earlier, my wife Jill is a community college professor.&nbsp; I believe she’s the only &#8212; (applause) &#8212; she’s the only First Lady ever to work full-time.&nbsp; And she’s still working full-time as a community college professor.&nbsp; And that’s not why &#8212; that’s why she’s not with me today.</p>



<p>But one of the things we’re also working on, just parenthetically &#8212; and this is a great &#8212; this is a great college.&nbsp; It really is.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thanks in part to the leadership of the Governor, you have one of the best systems in the country.</p>



<p>And I want you to know, though, that we know and I know firsthand &#8212; my wife is an English professor and teaches writing as well &#8212; the number of students who come back to schools like this and the community college where Jill teaches, Northern Virginia Community College, are coming back having not been in school for a long time, many times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re coming back because they want to better their lives, breaking their necks to get here.&nbsp; Some of them &#8212; and they’re &#8212; the average age of my wife’s students is 28 years of age.&nbsp; That’s the average age.&nbsp; People coming back from &#8212; coming through difficult circumstances they find themselves in.&nbsp; And back east, a number of immigrant families coming through.</p>



<p>And the cost is still &#8212; no matter how the states try to control it, it still matters.</p>



<p>So, one of the things that &#8212; it didn’t do all I wanted to do, but I was just able to sign the new budget bill that increases the Pell Grants by $400 a year.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; The largest increase in 10 years.&nbsp; But we have to do more.</p>



<p>Look, I want to say a special thank you to Governor Inslee for his welcome and his partnership across a broad range of issues.&nbsp; I &#8212; including strengthening the pen- &#8212; the economy, your economy, and fighting the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, you know, I refer to him, and I &#8212; he knows this to be true because when I was back seeking the nomination, he is the “Environmental Governor” of the nation.&nbsp; This guy is leading the whole country.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And you have one heck of a congressional delegation, starting &#8212; (applause) &#8212; starting with my friend, Patty Murray.&nbsp; You know, when we passed the Recovery Act &#8212; the first bill we passed &#8212; I went to Patty and I said, “I want to deal with the Child Tax Credit,” which was something that had to be done.&nbsp; Patty has been fighting for it for years and years and years.&nbsp; I got it passed.&nbsp; We got it passed.&nbsp; And it reduced child poverty in America by 40 percent.&nbsp; But because of a couple folks &#8212; because we don’t have this &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we lack 1 Democrat and 50 Republicans from &#8212; keeping it from passing this time around.</p>



<p>But it really fundamentally changed the lives of millions of people, Patty.&nbsp; You know it better than I do.&nbsp; But it reduced child poverty by 40 percent.</p>



<p>And she talked about &#8212; earlier about &#8212; about the cost of childcare.&nbsp; I was a single dad for five years when my wife and daughter were killed in an automobile accident.&nbsp; And everybody &#8212; and I commuted every day &#8212; did 250 miles, 270 miles a day from Wilmington, Delaware, to Washington, D.C., on Amtrak.</p>



<p>Everybody thought I did it because I just wanted to be home.&nbsp; And that’s true.&nbsp; But I did it because I couldn’t possibly afford childcare.&nbsp; I was a United States senator.&nbsp; I had the dubious distinction for 36 years of being listed as the poorest man in the Senate.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I was making a lot of money as a senator, from my perspective, and I didn’t think I should be making any money other than my salary as a senator.</p>



<p>And I could not possibly afford &#8212; even back in 1972 and ‘3, I could not afford childcare.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I went home every single night, over a million two hundred million miles &#8212; -two hundred thousand miles worth over my career.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, folks, we got &#8212; we &#8212; there&#8217;s easy answers.&nbsp; There&#8217;s easy answers.&nbsp; We can do all that Patty and I and others have been talking about, and not one person in America making less than $400,000 a year will see a single, solitary increase in their taxes.&nbsp; Not one.&nbsp; Not a single increase.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, folks, you know, I&#8217;m &#8212; you know, I’ve sometimes been called by some of my interesting Republican friends &#8212; we&#8217;re all &#8212; “Democrats are all socialists.”&nbsp; I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; And I think if you can make a billion dollars or a million dollars or a hundred million, you should be able to do it.&nbsp; But pay your fair share.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Pay your fair share.</p>



<p>I come from the corporate state of the world, Delaware.&nbsp; More corporations are incorporated in Delaware than every other state in the Union combined.&nbsp; And I got elected six times as senator notwithstanding that.</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the point: Of the Fortune 500 companies, 40 of them last year, they made $40 billion and didn&#8217;t pay a single, solitary penny in taxes.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not right.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just not fair.&nbsp; All you got to do is just pay a fair share.&nbsp; And we can do all of this and so much more, but that&#8217;s not what &#8212; my point of being here tonight &#8212; or today, I should say.</p>



<p>And Senator Cantwell, she&#8217;s been a champion in this state, a key player in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and delivering high-speed Internet all across the state of Washington.&nbsp; And &#8212; because we&#8217;re going to outcompete the rest of the world.&nbsp; She understands how we do it.&nbsp; We got to have you have access &#8212; access to that information.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Think about it: During the pandemic, how many of your &#8212; you parents had to drive your kids into a McDonald&#8217;s parking lot to get on the Internet to be able to do your homework?&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; This the United States of America, for God&#8217;s sake.&nbsp; The United States of America.&nbsp; Because of this lady and others, we are going to see to it every single place in this country &#8212; rural, urban, and suburban &#8212; has access to high-speed Internet.</p>



<p>(Applause.)</p>



<p>And Congressman Schrier, who represents the district &#8212; a doctor, an MD, who knows what folks go through in our healthcare system and knows how to make it better.&nbsp; You know, this includes how to fill the nursing shortage to help colleges like this one train and prepare the next generation of nurses and healthcare workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My wife and her at &#8212; when at Delaware Community College and now Northern Virginia, teaches an awful lot of nurses &#8212; an awful lot of nurses.&nbsp; And, by the way, docs are okay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been a significant consumer of healthcare in my career, unfortunately.&nbsp; I was hospitalized for the better part of seven months with two cranial aneurysms and an embolism, and my son Beau was &#8212; came back as a decorated war hero from the state &#8212; from Iraq after a year with stage four glioblastoma and spent 15 months at the end just hanging on.</p>



<p>And, you know, doctors let you live.&nbsp; Nurses, male and female &#8212; I&#8217;m not joking &#8212; any of you in nursing programs &#8212; they make you want to live.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I think it&#8217;s the single-most underrated profession in the United States of America.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; When I was at Walter Reed all those months, I&#8217;d lay there in that ICU and look at the &#8212; at the monitors.&nbsp; And you know if any of those lines go flat, you&#8217;re in trouble.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But seriously, after a while &#8212; and you&#8217;ve seen this, Doc &#8212; you just get tired.&nbsp; Wasn’t in pain; just get tired.&nbsp; You just want to stop.</p>



<p>And my nurses &#8212; I remember to this day their names &#8212; they’d come in and they’d change the pillow, they’d rub my head, they’d do something &#8212; they’d keep you moving, talk to you.&nbsp; Talk to you.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why, what I did was &#8212; they &#8212; everybody who comes out of an intensive care unit, the joke is &#8212; in hospitals &#8212; is they either get taken out in a &#8212; the nurses never see them again.&nbsp; They either get taken out in a bag and &#8212; or they never want to come back.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I used to go back once a month and have dinner for the nurses every night &#8212; on the nightshift, to thank them.</p>



<p>So any of you who are &#8212; anybody in &#8212; well, I&#8217;m not sure how many are part of the college, but any of you studying nursing, keep it &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Nurses are over here!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, God love them.&nbsp; No, I really mean it.&nbsp; And I don’t want to disappoint you, but the male nurses are as consequential as the female nurses.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, anyway, I just wanted to mention that.  And I want to thank <s>Congresswoman</s> [Congressman] Kilmer and &#8212; for the nearby district &#8212; the 6th District, I guess.  He&#8217;s leading the charge in the economy to make sure that &#8212; that we leave no community behind. </p>



<p>And we&#8217;re also joined today by Larsen and &#8212; and &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I know it.&nbsp; You got &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Smith.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I got it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; DelBene, who&#8217;s a real champion for working families.&nbsp; And while she couldn&#8217;t be here today, Congresswoman Jayapal is doing an incredible job in the state.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; She&#8217;s visiting &#8212; she&#8217;s been a great partner of mine and worked really closely with me.&nbsp; And she&#8217;s visiting her &#8212; her family now, and she&#8217;ll be back shortly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, folks, we&#8217;re all laser-focused on lowering the costs for you and your families across the board.&nbsp; And a big way to do that is lower the cost of healthcare &#8212; healthcare especially in the area of prescription drugs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The governor of this state has already gotten insulin down to 35 bucks for &#8212; I guess it&#8217;s a year you&#8217;ve done it so far.&nbsp; Is that right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, either &#8212; earlier this month, President Obama came back to the White House.&nbsp; He&#8217;s a good friend.&nbsp; He came back to the White House for the first time in a long time to celebrate the 12th anniversary of the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we talked about how hard it was to get it done in the first place and why we were so determined to get it done.&nbsp; It was for the people who desperately needed it and had no alternatives and deserve to be treated with, as my dad &#8212; the word &#8212; word he used most is: Everyone is entitled to be treated with “dignity.”&nbsp; Everyone.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no loss of your dignity like not being able to take care of a child who&#8217;s sick or a wife or a spouse, a husband.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And countless Americans lie in bed at night staring up at the ceiling wondering, “What happens &#8212; what happens if I get sick?&nbsp; What happens if I get prostate cancer and my wife gets breast cancer?&nbsp; What do we do?&nbsp; How do we take care of the family?&nbsp; Who&#8217;s going to pay for it?&nbsp; What&#8217;s going to happen?”&nbsp; Thousands and thousands of Americans stare at that ceiling.</p>



<p>So we did it with the idea that, in America, healthcare should be a right, not a privilege.&nbsp; And, well, with the help of the leaders here, at a federal and state level, we began to make some good &#8212; good on the proposition of fighting and defending and improving the Affordable Care Act after it got passed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, if we can hold for a second here, remember &#8212; my colleagues remember I was out of office one year as Vice President, at the end of the term, in the 2018 elections.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you remember, the other team wanted to do away with Obamacare.&nbsp; They had scores of court cases, scores of votes to try to eliminate it.&nbsp; But what happened was a lot of people didn&#8217;t &#8212; Barack is kind of a humble guy.&nbsp; And I used to say to him after we won that Affordable Care fight &#8212; I said, “We ought to take a victory lap, let people know what happened.”&nbsp; He said, “We don&#8217;t have time.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have time.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, guess what?&nbsp; I went into 58 races that year to campaign where there was an incumbent Republican and a Democrat running, and (inaudible) Republicans who wanted to eliminate the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp; And what I pointed out was: If, in fact, that Republican won that year and they took back the Congress, what was going to happen?&nbsp; Anyone with a preexisting condition could not get coverage again, not just through the Affordable Care Act, but couldn&#8217;t get coverage in your personal insurance you paid for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all of a sudden, people went, “Whoa, we won 44 of those races.”&nbsp; And the one thing knowing they were going to eliminate &#8212; eliminate the idea that if you have a preexisting condition, you couldn&#8217;t get coverage.&nbsp; You &#8212; now you can under the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Within the first months of my administration, we passed the landmark American Rescue Plan, a law that not only helped us get COVID-19 under control and our economy back on track, but got millions of people more &#8212; people insured more &#8212; millions of people more insured under the Affordable Care Act.</p>



<p>We made it easier for people to sign up for coverage in the middle of the pandemic.&nbsp; We opened a Special Enrollment Period and gave millions of Americans more time to enroll in the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We quadrupled the number of navigators out in the communities helping folks know how to sign up to get the coverage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And here in the Washington State, about 240,000 folks signed up for ACA coverage just last year &#8212; an additional 240,000.&nbsp; And we are continuing to expand Medicaid in states.</p>



<p>You know, there are a total of 36 states who said we’re going to cover &#8212; even though the federal government was saying we’re going to cover for free in the beginning, and they have to eventually sign on to help pay for it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, we added two more states.&nbsp; That’s millions of people who have now Medicaid coverage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over 31 million Americans now have health insurance through the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp; And that includes &#8212; (applause).&nbsp; And that includes nearly 900,000 people across the state of Washington.</p>



<p>Four out of five Americans can find quality coverage for under $10 a month on the Affordable Care Act.</p>



<p>We made it cheaper to purchase the premium plans under the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp; The average family today, since we passed that law in our administration, are saving $2,400 on their annual premiums and getting better coverage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s $200 savings every month, allowing them to have more money available for other needs in their lives with inflation, with Putin’s gas tax, with their groceries because of the loss of access to the wheat fields in Russia and in Ukraine, prescription drugs, and other necessities.&nbsp; That $200 can make a difference in a month.</p>



<p>The bottom line is this: The Affordable Care Act is stronger now than it’s ever been.&nbsp; And we’re strengthening it even further.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, I signed an executive order directing the federal agencies to continue doing everything they can in their power to expand &#8212; to expand the quality of the affordable healthcare coverage.</p>



<p>This work builds on what we’ve done to end those surprise charges you often see on medical bills, particularly at hospitals.&nbsp; If any of you have been hospitalized &#8212; I hope you haven’t had to, but if you’ve been lately and you found out your coverage doesn’t cover a certain particular doctor, you tend to get a surprise bill for a couple thousand bucks because, without your knowledge, they had another doctor looking at what was &#8212; what you needed to do.&nbsp; No surprise bills anymore.&nbsp; They can’t do that.&nbsp; They can’t do that.&nbsp; No more surprise medical billing.</p>



<p>And separately, we’re fixing &#8212; (applause).&nbsp; And separately, we’re fixing what was referred to as the &#8220;family glitch&#8221;.&nbsp; What &#8212; that is a common issue facing 5 million Americans who can’t get financial help or get coverage under the Affordable Care Act.</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the problem: Under the current rules, a working mom is told that as long as she can afford employer-based coverage herself, she can’t qualify for premium subsidies in the Affordable Care Act to afford coverage for the rest of her family.&nbsp; And so, we changed that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We proposed that, starting next year, working families will get the help they need to afford family coverage under the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp; And as a result, these families will save hundreds of dollars a month.</p>



<p>With this change, it’s estimated that 200,000 presently uninsured Americans will gain coverage.&nbsp; Nearly one million Americans &#8212; (applause) &#8212; nearly one million Americans will see their coverage become more affordable.&nbsp; This is considered one of the best things &#8212; the biggest thing my administration can do is lower costs and expand coverage.</p>



<p>We talked about &#8212; you know, I’ve talked about and it was mentioned by several who spoke before me about just a little breathing room.</p>



<p>I was raised in a town in Delaware.&nbsp; It was a nice neighborhood.&nbsp; It was four &#8212; a three-bedroom split-level home in a developing suburban area &#8212; a housing development.&nbsp; That &#8212; with four kids, a mom and a dad, and a grandpop living with us.</p>



<p>And the walls were thin.&nbsp; And you could hear &#8212; I remember, one day &#8212; this is a true story &#8212; one day, I could &#8212; one night I hear my dad was really restless getting up and down.&nbsp; And I asked my mom the next morning before I went to school what was wrong with Dad.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She said, “They told him, honey, that they’re not going to cover insurance any more in his job.”&nbsp; Health insurance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, like I said, it’s about dignity.&nbsp; It’s about worrying about your family.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we need to keep this fight up.&nbsp; And Republicans and I &#8212; as you know, I get criticized by the press because I’m not &#8212; I’m not partisan enough, okay?</p>



<p>Well, this is not your father’s Republican Party, as I said.&nbsp; They continue to attack the Affordable Care Act and want to eliminate it.&nbsp; They’re unrelenting.&nbsp; Multiple court challenges, sabotage from the previous administration, over 70 attempts to repeal the law by Republicans in Congress.&nbsp; Seventy times.</p>



<p>In fact, just last month, Republican Senator Jon &#8212; excuse me, Ron Johnson from Wisconsin said that if the Republicans get back in power and take back the House and the Senate, they should repeal the Affordable Care Act again.</p>



<p>Twelve years later, Republicans still haven’t stopped their attacks on this lifesaving law.</p>



<p>So, pay close attention.&nbsp; If they have their way, it means 100 million Americans with a preexisting condition will once again be denied health &#8212; be denied health coverage &#8212; not hyperbole; this is a fact &#8212; will be denied healthcare coverage by their insurance companies.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the law was before Obamacare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, tens of millions of Americans could lose their coverage, including young people, who will no longer be able to be covered by their parents’ plans up to age 26.&nbsp; Premiums are going to go through the roof.&nbsp; So, there’s a lot at stake.</p>



<p>Well, I’ve got a better idea: Instead of destroying</p>



<p>the Affordable Care Act, let’s keep building on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Extend the American Rescue Plan subsidies that we’ve already passed, allowing premiums and expanded coverage &#8212; lower premiums, expanded coverage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Close the Medicaid coverage gap that locks nearly 4 million Americans out of coverage just because they’re in states who refused to expand Medicaid.</p>



<p>And let’s do something that will bring down prices, lower the cost of prescription drugs.</p>



<p>Let me note parenthetically: The only thing that Medicare cannot negotiate with healthcare providers on are drugs.&nbsp; They can tell you they&#8217;re only going to pay X amount of money for doctor visits, Y amount of money for a particular operation, et cetera.&nbsp; But the only thing they can&#8217;t negotiate are prescription drugs, except for one area.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We insisted a long time ago that the department that relates to the military &#8212; you have a great guy running Veterans Affairs now.&nbsp; Veterans Affairs can say, “We&#8217;re not going to pay you any more than X or Y for this particular drug.”&nbsp; But you can&#8217;t do that for anything else &#8212; Medicare can&#8217;t do that anywhere else.</p>



<p>In America, we pay the highest prescription drug cost</p>



<p>of any developed nation in the world.&nbsp; That’s a fact.&nbsp; It’s about two and a half to three times higher than paid for the same exact drug, the same manufacturer in other countries.</p>



<p>For example, the anti-cancer drug to treat leukemia and lymphoma costs <s>$1,400</s> [$14,000] a month in the United States.  Some of you may know that.  The same exact drug, the same exact company, same distribution costs $6,000 &#8212; not $14,000 &#8212; in France.  Same company.  American company.  Same exact amount.  It’s unconscionable. </p>



<p>Today, one in four Americans who need prescription drugs struggle to afford them.</p>



<p>Nearly 30 percent of people needing essential drugs &#8212; doses that they’re supposed to take &#8212; 30 percent skipped their doses because they want to extend life of the drug that they need.</p>



<p>Many people use over-the-counter drugs instead, and they cut pills in half because they can’t afford them.&nbsp; And there’s others who simply not fill their prescriptions at all.</p>



<p>As I said, for God’s sake, this is the United States of America.&nbsp; What are we doing?&nbsp; It’s simply wrong, especially since it doesn’t cost the drug companies nearly as much to make the drug or the research that went into it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There’s a system they have, noted in Germany and other countries, that the drug company can charge &#8212; the price is set when they &#8212; when they, in fact, try to bring the drug on market.&nbsp; It&#8217;s like, in our case, the FDA approve it.&nbsp; And the way it works is: They go, “How much did you invest to come up with the drug?&nbsp; How much did you put in?”&nbsp; And they allow a healthy profit of 10, 20, 30, 40 percent and say, “That&#8217;s what you can sell it for in our country unless you invest more to improve the drug and show you put more into it.&nbsp; Otherwise, it can&#8217;t go below the cost of inflation.”</p>



<p>Look, the insulin we’re talking about: You know how much it makes &#8212; costs to make that vial of insulin?&nbsp; Ten dollars.&nbsp; T-E-N.&nbsp; Ten dollars to treat diabetes.&nbsp; Ten dollars.&nbsp; A condition that affects millions of Americans, including a congresswoman.</p>



<p>Look, some families have to pay hundreds of dollars a month, some even over a thousand dollars.&nbsp; The average cost is $863 a month &#8212; or, excuse me, $683 a month for lifesaving insulin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You just heard Elisa and <s>Julia</s> [Juliana] talk about trying to afford insulin and treat the Type 1 diabetes.</p>



<p>Imagine what it’s like if you don’t have insurance and you don’t have the cash to look at your child, knowing what they need and knowing there’s not a damn thing you can do about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Not only is your child put in jeopardy, you’re deprived of your dignity.&nbsp; How do you look at your child and deal with it?&nbsp; There’s no excuse.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; We’re not asking drug companies to do anything that they can’t afford.&nbsp; And if you think it doesn’t affect you, it does.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Everyone has less money in their pocket today because of the high cost of healthcare.&nbsp; Over the past decade, healthcare costs have gone up 50 percent, and a major reason of that increase is the cost of the drugs in healthcare.</p>



<p>Folks, while we may not agree on everything, I think it’s safe to say that all of us, whatever our background, our age, where we live, agree that prescription drugs are outrageously expensive.</p>



<p>So, here’s what I’m proposing &#8212; (applause).</p>



<p>I met with the 12 largest drug manufacturers when I did the initiative the Pres- &#8212; the last President, Obama, when I was Vice President, allowed me to do to deal with the cost of this.&nbsp; And I met with them.&nbsp; And I said &#8212; they said, “What if you find the cure for a particular drug?&nbsp; What should you be able to charge for a major cancer facility?”&nbsp; They said, “Whatever the market will bear.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>I said, “No.”&nbsp; I said, “Here’s the deal &#8212; here’s what I think you should do: If you have to spend millions of dollars, you should be able to recoup everything you put into it.&nbsp; But if it’s way beyond the cost of the average American, the federal government should step up and compensate you for it so that the &#8212; in fact, the American people can still have lifesaving drugs.”</p>



<p>So, here’s what I’m proposing, with the help of the members of Congress:</p>



<p>First, let’s cap the cost of insulin at $35 a month.&nbsp; That still means &#8212; it costs them $10 &#8212; three and a half times as much it costs them.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, let’s end the days when companies could increase prices with no oversight and no accountability.</p>



<p>If drug companies increase their prices faster than the rate of inflation, they should have to face a steep tax.&nbsp; We’re saying that &#8212; by the way, we wouldn’t let utility companies do it.&nbsp; Utilities can’t, all of a sudden, raise their cost of the utilities you’re paying.&nbsp; We’re saying, “Drug companies, you are finally going to be held accountable when you raise prices for the American people.”&nbsp; You should be able to make a significant profit, but not gouge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, let’s cap the amount that seniors on Medicare</p>



<p>have to spend for prescription drugs each year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you’re on Medicare, you won’t have to spend more than $2,000 out of pocket, which is a lot of money, and that’s no more than $170 a month no matter how many prescriptions you’re taking, because Medicare will take up the rest.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Drug companies, insurance companies, Medicare would pick up the rest of the cost.</p>



<p>And finally, let’s give Medicare the power to negotiate</p>



<p>prescription drug prices.&nbsp; For every other type of healthcare &#8212; (applause) &#8212; uses it to leverage lower prices for American seniors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But for prescription drugs, the only prescription drugs</p>



<p>Medicare is prohibited by law from negotiating to get the best deal for seniors.</p>



<p>And by the way, it doesn’t put the drug company &#8212; we’re just saying we’re not going to &#8212; Medicare is not going to buy it.&nbsp; They’re not going to buy it beyond a certain price.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It doesn’t mean you can’t continue to manufacture and ask a billion dollars for it.&nbsp; But the federal government is not going to pay for it.</p>



<p>It’s long past time we get rid of these absurd limitations.&nbsp; Let Medicare negotiate pri- &#8212; fair prices that reflect the cost of research and development and the need for a significant profit but also affordable for seniors.</p>



<p>Let me close with this: I grew up in family where if prices went up for things that were daily requirements like the gallon of gasoline, it became a discussion at the kitchen table.&nbsp; It mattered.&nbsp; It was always on the margins.&nbsp; We felt it.</p>



<p>That’s why I’m so focused on doing everything I can to lower the cost of gas and energy, and accelerate our transition to clean energy.&nbsp; I also know there are other basic needs that affect the standard of living for most families.</p>



<p>I was a single dad, as I said, for five years.&nbsp; I couldn’t afford childcare.&nbsp; No way I could.&nbsp; But I had a sister and a brother.&nbsp; We have an expression in my family &#8212; for real, not a joke &#8212; “If you have to ask, it’s too late.”&nbsp; Think about what that means.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, when my wife and daughter were killed and the boys came home from the hospital, I found out my sister and her husband had already moved into my house.&nbsp; I had bought a &#8212; I had purchased an old farmhouse &#8212; a colonial farmhouse in northern Delaware.&nbsp; And it had a little barn on it as well.&nbsp; It was only a couple acres.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My brother came in and spent money changing the barn and the &#8212; the upstairs of the barn into an apartment.&nbsp; My brother and sister moved in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’d dropped my kids off every morning when I’d go to the train station with my mom.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But look, as I said, I had a good job.&nbsp; How do people make it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I know childcare is hard.&nbsp; It costs a lot of money.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why, with your members of Congress &#8212; led by Patty, who’s an absolute leader on this &#8212; I want to cap the child- &#8212; the ch- &#8212; the cost of childcare for families making under $125,000 to 7 percent of your income.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>We can do these things without raising taxes a penny to anyone, as I said, making over &#8212; under 400,000 bucks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The bottom line is this: When I was running for the President, you heard me say a thousand times &#8212; you probably got tired of it, and you&#8217;re tired of it now &#8212; that we&#8217;re going to build this economy around you, the American middle class.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to &#8212; because when the middle class does well, the poor have a way up and the wealthy do very well.&nbsp; They never hurt when the middle class is doing well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re going to deal in people and the places that have been left out and left behind.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re making progress.</p>



<p>Over the course of my presidency &#8212; so far, 14 months &#8212; we&#8217;ve created 7.9 million good-paying jobs.&nbsp; More jobs created in 14 months than any presidency in a year ever.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The unemployment rate is 3.6 percent, down from 6.4 percent when I took office.&nbsp; The fastest decline in unemployment at the start of any presidency ever recorded.</p>



<p>Washington State, you&#8217;ve added 218,000 jobs, and unemployment dropped from 6.3 to 4.2 percent.</p>



<p>Last year, in 2021, we cut &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and all this was going on.&nbsp; We cut the deficit.&nbsp; You know, my &#8212; all my friends talk about how they care about the deficit?&nbsp; We cut it $350 billion last year.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And this year, in 2022, we’re on track to cut the deficit by more than &#8212; I want &#8212; mark it down because you’ll &#8212; you’ll remind me of this &#8212; by $1.3 trillion &#8212; 1.3.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; If that stays on course, it’d be the largest one-year reduction of a deficit in history.</p>



<p>This is particularly important now as we work to reduce pressure on inflation.&nbsp; From Washington State to all across America, we’ve gone from “on the mend” to “on the move.”</p>



<p>We’re coming at our &#8212; at our challenges from a position of strength.</p>



<p>I’m more optimistic.&nbsp; I’m more optimistic about America today than I’ve been in my whole life and my whole career, because I fee- &#8212; see a future that’s within our grasp.</p>



<p>We’re the only nation on Earth &#8212; think about this now &#8212; we’re the only nation on Earth that has always come out of every crisis we’ve ever met stronger than when we went in it.&nbsp; No other nation in the world can say that.&nbsp; It’s because of you, because of the ingenuity and determination of the American people.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve just looked at opportunity and seized it.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re doing today.</p>



<p>So as my Grandfather Finnegan used to say, “With the grace of God and the goodwill of the neighbors and the crick not rising, we&#8217;re going to do well.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s going to be hard for a while getting through the cost of gasoline and energy because of Putin and the war, but we&#8217;re going to do it.</p>



<p>And with your help &#8212; and I say to all the folks who are students here, I wish you well.&nbsp; We need you badly.&nbsp; You&#8217;re &#8212; and the reason I&#8217;m so optimistic &#8212; think about it &#8212; you are the least prejudiced, the most involved, the most concerned generation in American history.&nbsp; You really are.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>God bless you all.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>1:54 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s meeting with Prime Minister Shmyhal of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/22/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-prime-minister-shmyhal-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 23:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Prime Minister Denys Shmyhal of Ukraine this afternoon. Mr. Sullivan conveyed the United States’ unwavering commitment to supporting the government and people of Ukraine. The two discussed the security, economic, and humanitarian assistance the United States is providing, including the new support announced by President Biden yesterday, and ongoing efforts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Prime Minister Denys Shmyhal of Ukraine this afternoon. Mr. Sullivan conveyed the United States’ unwavering commitment to supporting the government and people of Ukraine. The two discussed the security, economic, and humanitarian assistance the United States is providing, including the new support announced by President Biden yesterday, and ongoing efforts with international partners to impose further costs on Russia for its unprovoked aggression.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden on Earth Day and at Signing of an Executive Order Strengthening the Nation’s Forests, Communities, and Local&#160;Economies</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/22/remarks-by-president-biden-on-earth-day-and-at-signing-of-an-executive-order-strengthening-the-nations-forests-communities-and-local-economies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 22:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Seward ParkSeattle, Washington 11:07 A.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, everybody.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; My name is Joe Biden.&#160; I work for Patty Murray.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Been doing it for a long time. I can’t think of a better place to celebrate Earth Day &#8212; this magnificent park.&#160; I’ve only been here once before.&#160; I came to speak years&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Seward Park<br>Seattle, Washington</p>



<p>11:07 A.M. PDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, everybody.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; My name is Joe Biden.&nbsp; I work for Patty Murray.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Been doing it for a long time.<br><br>I can’t think of a better place to celebrate Earth Day &#8212; this magnificent park.&nbsp; I’ve only been here once before.&nbsp; I came to speak years ago, and, on my own, I came up here to take a look.&nbsp; And it’s really quite beautiful.<br><br>Governor Inslee, who is known where I’m from as the “Environmental Governor,” and Mayor&nbsp;<s>Harley</s>&nbsp;[Harrell], Senator Murray, Senator Maria Cantwell, and all &#8212; I mean, you’ve got everybody here.&nbsp; You got Representatives Smith, Larsen, DelBene, Schrier.&nbsp; And it’s an honor to be here in this beautiful park with you all.<br><br>You know, Edward Abbey, the writer who once worked as a Park Ranger &#8212; I didn’t know he had been a Park Ranger, to tell you the truth &#8212; wrote the following: “Every man, every woman, carries in heart and mind [an] image of [an] ideal place, the right place, the one true home, known or unknown, actual or visionary.”<br><br>For many Seattle families, I think we’re in that place right now, here in this park and places like this.&nbsp; There are not that many like this, unfortunately.<br><br>And all around this country, there used to be a hell of a lot more forests like this.&nbsp; But we’re doing everything we can.&nbsp; Everybody behind me and all of you want desperately to protect what we have and increase what we have.<br><br>You know, our natural wonders are, you know, inspired &#8212; they’re a reflection that inspires us to take action.<br><br>You know, my mother had an expression &#8212; and I apologize to my colleagues, they’ve heard me do two things my whole career: quote my mother and father and quote Irish poets.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I’m not going to quote any Irish poets today, okay?&nbsp; But, you know, she’d say, “Out of everything difficult, something good will come if you look hard enough for it.”<br><br>And I think that we’re in one of those moments in world history and in American history where we’ve reached the point that the crisis on the environment has become so obvious, with the notable exception of the former President, that we &#8212; we really have an opportunity to do things we couldn&#8217;t have done 2, 5, 10 years ago.<br><br>And I want to &#8212; I want to talk about that today with leaders who understand that to their core, the folks standing behind me.&nbsp; I wish you didn&#8217;t have to stand.&nbsp; Don’t you guys have any chairs?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We’re good.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m not used to them standing for me, you know.&nbsp; Anyway.<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal: As I said, Governor Inslee is the climate governor, and I&#8217;ve gone to him throughout asking him for advice and counsel.&nbsp; And thanks for welcoming me back to Washington State, Gov.&nbsp;<br><br>And to Mayor &#8212; Mayor Harrell, the passport to the city is very much appreciated.&nbsp; I hope I don&#8217;t do anything to have it revoked.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br><br>And, Congressman Smith, thank you for your commitment to the environment, including helping our Armed Forces transition to clean energy technologies.&nbsp;<br><br>One of the things I found out as the President of the United States: I get to spend a lot of that money.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I get to decide where &#8212; no, I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to completely &#8212; but before &#8212; we&#8217;re &#8212; I’m going to start the process where every vehicle in the United States military &#8212; every vehicle is going to be climate friendly.&nbsp; Every vehicle.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, I mean it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’re spending billions of dollars to do it.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; and it&#8217;s going to matter.&nbsp; You know, it matters.&nbsp; You know, in my view, this crisis, as I said, is a genuine opportunity &#8212; an opportunity to do things we wanted to do, and only now it’s become so apparent.&nbsp;<br><br>On this day, 52 years ago, millions of Americans of every age and background rallied together on Earth Day.&nbsp;<br><br>A guy I worked with as a young senator back in those days was a guy named Gaylord Nelson from Wisconsin.&nbsp; And the guy who helped organize Earth Day was a guy who was from Delaware and worked for me as well, and &#8212; Mike McCabe.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And, you know, it was &#8212; they had a vision, a vision for a healthier and more prosperous America.&nbsp; And over time, they delivered.&nbsp; They delivered. &nbsp;Cleaner water.&nbsp; Proof that a sustainable environment can mean a stronger economy.&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; and one of the things I&#8217;m proudest of in our administration: Before I went into detail with my, quote, “Green Agenda,” I got all the unions together.&nbsp; Literally, got all the unions.&nbsp; (Inaudible) the unions view it as against their interests.<br><br>And starting with the IBEW Electrical, because they endorsed it.&nbsp; And every union has stepped up because they figured it out.&nbsp; Their jobs &#8212; they&#8217;re the ones who can help us transition in ways like never before.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not going to cost them jobs; it&#8217;s going to increase jobs.&nbsp; The IBEW is going to be building&nbsp;<s>50,000</s>[500,000] electric stations &#8212; electric charging stations all across America, for example.<br><br>And so, look, change continues today, and the new generation of Americans are helping us lead the way against the threat of climate change.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You know, every time I get a little down &#8212; I don&#8217;t know about my colleagues; I suspect they’re the same &#8212; I just turn on a television or take a look at all the young people.&nbsp; This young generation is not going to put up with the &#8212; all that stuff.&nbsp; No, they’re not.&nbsp; I mean, they&#8217;re &#8212; they are really, really energized, whether it&#8217;s basic human rights or it&#8217;s the environment.&nbsp; They&#8217;re just not stopping.&nbsp; And from day one of my administration, we&#8217;ve stood with them.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Governor, I hate to admit it, but I was part of that early Earth Day.&nbsp; I was only seven years old, but &#8212; (laughter).&nbsp; God, I &#8212; oh, my Lord, I can&#8217;t even believe I said that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But anyway, it&#8217;s been a passion of mine as long as I&#8217;ve been involved in public life.&nbsp; The first thing &#8212; what got me involved in politics &#8212; not that it matters to you all, but I was thinking about it on the way over here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I was a young attorney in Delaware, and they wanted &#8212; across the top of my state, they wanted to connect two highways, and it’s through what is the most beautiful part of the state.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But instead of being willing to do it in an area that, in fact, had no consequence for the environment, they decided to put it through areas that were &#8212; that were straighter and &#8212; but more damaging.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I got involved to try to stop the construction of that highway, which I did.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what got me involved.&nbsp; And it caused me great problems because I ended up having to run for the county council, which was the hardest job I ever had.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; At any rate &#8212;<br><br>But as a matter of fact, in 1986, in the United States Senate, I introduced and we passed the first Global Climate Protection Act &#8212; the first time &#8212; and it was a warming legislation in the Senate.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And on Earth Day, you know, we convened last year over 40 leaders from around the globe, reasserting America&#8217;s leadership on climate after four years of an administration denying that there was a climate crisis, denying that there was any need to do anything about the environment.&nbsp;<br><br>And the commitments galvanized that meet- &#8212; at that meeting, including our own goal of cutting emissions from 50 to 52 percent below&nbsp;<s>‘25</s>[‘05] levels by 2030 and reaching net-zero emissions by 2050, taking the steps the United States needs to limit the planet&#8217;s warming to no more than 1.5 degrees Celsius.&nbsp; And the rest of the world started to come along.&nbsp; We did more than set bold goals; we acted to achieve them.<br><br>Last year, with all the disappointments we faced &#8212; but last year, the United States deployed the most solar, wind, and battery storage in American history.&nbsp; And we made record-setting investments in clean energy in rural America.<br><br>For example, we have a $1 billion program that no one knows about except the Department of Agriculture &#8212; the grants and loans for farmers and rural co-ops to deploy solar and storage and powerlines to carry clean energy across the country.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re investing in technology so you can &#8212; you can heat and cool your home when the sun doesn&#8217;t shine and the wind doesn&#8217;t blow, because out here in Silicon Valley, you&#8217;re developing the battery technology I &#8212; they showed me one that is about a little bit wider than this podium, about that thick, and about this wide that, in fact, you can install in your home.&nbsp; And when the sun ain&#8217;t shining, that stored electricity runs the whole deal.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And by the way &#8212; by the way, windmills don&#8217;t cause cancer.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And across the country, we have enough clean energy capacity to power now 56 million homes.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, here&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing with automobiles.&nbsp; I &#8212; I&#8217;m an automobile buff.&nbsp; I have a ‘68 Corvette that does nothing but pollute the air.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t drive it very much.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And &#8212; but I brought together the automobile manufacturers.&nbsp; And Mary&nbsp;<s>Berry</s>[Barra], who was &#8212; who runs General Motors, is a fine, fine person.&nbsp; At the time, she was suing the state of California &#8212; General Motors &#8212; for their increased mileage requirements that exceeded the federal standard &#8212; I mean, exceeded &#8212; yes, the federal standard.&nbsp; And the argument Ford &#8212; General Motors was making was you couldn&#8217;t exceed the federal standard locally.&nbsp;<br><br>And we had a long talk.&nbsp; And I didn&#8217;t suggest it, but she dropped that suit and contacted me and said, “I&#8217;m going to make a commitment.”&nbsp; I brought together the American automobile industry and they agreed on an ambitious goal: 50 percent electric vehicles by &#8212; sales by the year 2030.”&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s the commitment they made.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t make it for them.&nbsp; They made it, because they realized what the future is.&nbsp;<br><br>I saw it when I drove Ford&#8217;s all-electric 150 pickup truck, which, I might add &#8212; this was disappointing &#8212; is faster than my Corvette.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Now, you think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a (inaudible).&nbsp; You know, although I did suggest if I&#8217;m out of office and they had the first electric Corvette, I want to buy it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But at any rate, you know &#8212; and my &#8212; when I &#8212; I drove the electric Jeep Wagoneer around the South Lawn of the White House.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, to date, automakers have announced investments of more than $100 billion in EV manufacturing &#8212; $100 billion.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s along with us setting ambitious standards to cut pollution in cars and trucks to boost fuel economy standards, which we’re going to be announcing very soon, upping the mileage requirement that &#8212; for the minimum mileage requirement.&nbsp;<br><br>But that’s not all.&nbsp; The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law &#8212; which the folks behind me are the reason why that occurred &#8212; I signed provides billions of dollars for a nationwide network of 500,000 charging stations &#8212; 500,000.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And will &#8212; and with electric school buses &#8212; by the way, I went down to North Carolina.&nbsp; You should see the factory down there.&nbsp; These buses &#8212; they have electric vehicles.&nbsp; It has a platform, folks, from me to you, about that thick; weighs about six zillion pounds.&nbsp; No engine.&nbsp; Nothing else.&nbsp; That’s it.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; but it’s all electric.&nbsp; All electric.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; We’re going to eliminate tens of thousands of diesel school buses, which pollute the air and pollute the lungs.&nbsp;<br><br>And, look, industry &#8212; this industry and union workers are all stepping up.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a lot more.<br><br>Here in Washington State, you&#8217;re going to triple the federal commitment to your Link &#8212; we’re going to triple the federal commitment to your Link Light Rail system, speeding progress on the largest transit &#8212; (applause) &#8212; as my colleagues in the Senate will recall, I was referred to as “Mr. Amtrak.”&nbsp; I&#8217;ve taken over 1,200,000 miles in Amtrak commuting &#8212; commuting every single day &#8212; you think I’m joking &#8212; for 36 years every single day when the Senate was in session to go home and see my kids.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; but the folks &#8212; you know, it’s a simple proposition.&nbsp; Most people don’t realize it.&nbsp; Given a choice to go from point A to point B and rail &#8212; electric rail &#8212; or drive your automobile, if you can get there fast &#8212; as fast or faster on rail, you take the rail.&nbsp; The estimates take &#8212; will take millions of vehicles off the road.&nbsp; The largest transit construction project in the country that runs entirely on clean energy.<br><br>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides $66 billion &#8212; it’s passed &#8212; $66 billion for freight rail; $39 billion for public transit; $10.6 billion for clean electric buses; and $2.5 billion for clean ferries on my coast of Delaware and out here for you all.&nbsp;<br><br>This will take millions of cars worth of pollution off the road and get people to places quicker.<br><br>You know, look, I think one Amtrak train carries as many passengers &#8212; I know this statistic &#8212; as six lanes of a major interstate highway.&nbsp; That’s how many passengers it carries.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, it matters.<br><br>We saw new standards &#8212; we set new standards.&nbsp; We slashed methane and brought over 100 nations together when I was at the &#8212; at the big meeting we had in Europe.&nbsp; A hundred nations around the globe.&nbsp; And I got them to &#8212; I &#8212; there&#8217;s two things I was able to accomplish.&nbsp; One, I got a pledge &#8212; a pledge from a hundred &#8212; I think it was 144 of them &#8212; that they would eliminate methane and do the same thing we’re doing to keep it.&nbsp; It’s the most damaging of all the pollutants that are going up.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We also set new standards for super-polluting HFC emissions.&nbsp; Remember the big fight we had?&nbsp; I know it, because when I almost lost an election because the DuPont company makes &#8212; long story.&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>But, look, we set new standards for cleaner cement.&nbsp; You say, “What the hell are you talking about, Joey?”&nbsp; This is probably the only audience to understand &#8212; cleaner cement.&nbsp; Cement is an incredible pollutant &#8212; an incredible pollutant.&nbsp; And it matters because cement is responsible for 8 percent of the global climate emissions.&nbsp; Cement.&nbsp; I got to admit to you, as long as I&#8217;ve been involved in this, until two years ago, I didn&#8217;t know that.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re delivering across the country.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Lots of folks have promised it, but my administration is actually delivering and revitalizing communities across Appalachia.<br><br>Look, folks, I come from Scranton, Pennsylvania, where I was raised.&nbsp; The reason I got to Delaware is coal died.&nbsp; My dad was not in the coal mines; he was in sales &#8212; but the whole economy died.&nbsp; And, you know, you can understand why in places like West Virginia and Southeastern Pennsylvania, why people were worried about doing away with coal.&nbsp; You know, but it&#8217;s their jobs; they wonder what they&#8217;re going to do.&nbsp;<br><br>But guess what?&nbsp; In the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill, the law is going to help us cap and seal abandoned mines &#8212; thou- &#8212; there’s thousands of abandoned mines &#8212; cap and seal them.&nbsp; They’re no longer going to see pollution in the air or the water.&nbsp; The laws putting abandoned mine workers to work at the same salary they were working digging the mines in the first place.&nbsp; There are several thousand of these wells that have to be capped.&nbsp; And they have to harvest the energy.&nbsp; And they’re going to get paid.<br><br>So, we’ve provided alternatives.&nbsp; They are manufacturing and installing solar panels where they once dug for coal.<br><br>Look, here out &#8212; out here in the West, we are repowering retired power plants and clean ener- &#8212; clean hydrogen and advanced nuclear, making them economic hubs again.<br><br>And in the Heartland, in fields that feed our country, we’re planting cover crops to pull carbon out of the air and out of the atmosphere.&nbsp; You know, they’re becoming carbon sinks.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, across the country, we set the first-ever national conservation goal and protected more land and water than any other administration on record in our first year, because we can do it.&nbsp; And now the farmers are beginning to realize, “If I put things in conservation, I get paid for putting cover crops down that absorb carbon.&nbsp; It makes sense to me.”&nbsp; It keeps the land open, and it makes the environment much better.&nbsp; And they get paid for it.&nbsp; And they should get paid for it.&nbsp; It’s their land.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We’re protecting natural wonders and cultural treasures, national monuments.&nbsp;<br><br>I remember a little girl came up to me with her &#8212; I don’t know where &#8212; how it happened, but I was walking outside and a woman came up with her little girl and said &#8212; she said, “Mr. Pwesident, please protect Bears Ears.”&nbsp; I said, “I beg your pardon, honey.”&nbsp; She said, “Please protect Bears Ears.”&nbsp; I said, “Bears Ears?”&nbsp; She said, “Yes.”&nbsp; And I knew what Bears Ears was because I’ve tried to take my kids to almost every national park.&nbsp; And I said, “Okay, honey.”&nbsp; She said, “Pwomise me.&nbsp; Pwomise me.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we did.&nbsp; Bears Ears.&nbsp; Forests like the Tongass Forest.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And, by the way, we got some of the conservative Republicans to support it in their state.&nbsp; We got some support for it.&nbsp;<br><br>And now we’re working to restore the salmon runs here in the Northwest.<br><br>Look, we’re putting America on the cutting edge.&nbsp; We’ve approved the first commercial-scale offshore wind project in federal waters, which has already broken ground with U.S workers and U.S. steel, who are going to be building these facilities.<br><br>By the way, I was up in &#8212; in Colorado and looking at the facilities we have there.&nbsp; You know, we now have &#8212; we now have windmills that the blades on those windmills &#8212; 102 yards long.&nbsp; You hear me?&nbsp; 102 yards long.&nbsp; They can be placed way out in the ocean.&nbsp; And, you know &#8212; and, by the way, I made it clear to my friends up in Nantucket and that area, “I don’t want to hear anymore about you don’t like looking at them.”&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; They’re pretty.<br><br>But seriously.&nbsp; It’s incredible the breakthroughs that we’re making.&nbsp; Once you tell a nation that “We can do this, go do it,” it’s amazing what happens.&nbsp; It’s amazing what happens.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>We’ve launched the first-ever commercial flight powered by 100 &#8212; 100 percent sustainable aviation fuel.&nbsp; It lifted off with fuel grown here in America.&nbsp; Grown in America.<br><br>We set the first net-zero commitments for U.S. steel companies, and now we’re rewarded for clean air &#8212; clean production through our first-ever international carbon-based trade deal, which makes clean American steel cheaper to buy than dirty steel from other countries.&nbsp; And we’re making it clear to the rest of the world that’s what we’re going to do.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ve put environmental justice at the center of what we do, addressing the disproportionate health, environmental, and economic impacts that have been borne primarily by communities of color &#8212; places too often left behind.<br><br>I grew up when &#8212; when coal died in Scranton, I moved &#8212; we moved to Delaware, where my dad had grown up.&nbsp; We moved to a little steel town called Claymont, Delaware, which was right at that arch that goes up into the Pennsylvania area there.&nbsp; And it’s near a place called Marcus Hook, where there were more &#8212; at the time, more oil refineries than in Houston &#8212; in Houston.&nbsp; Because of 10 million people in the Delaware Valley up there.<br><br>And I &#8212; we &#8212; I went to the small little school that was about a mile from the apartment complex we lived in, and &#8212; a little school called Holy Rosary.&nbsp; And I &#8212; you couldn’t walk to school because, although it was a four-lane access highway, it was just too dangerous to cross some of the streets.<br><br>And my mother would get &#8212; and when it came spring &#8212; I mean it became the fall &#8212; this is the God’s truth &#8212; and you’d get in the car, there’s a little frost on the window, turn on the windshield wiper, there’d be an oil slick.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I have asthma, and 80 percent of the people who, in fact, we grew up with have asthma.&nbsp; That’s what you call a fenceline community.&nbsp; I understand what it’s like.&nbsp; I &#8212; we only lived there &#8212; I went to school there for 12 years.&nbsp; But I didn’t live there that whole time.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>My generic point is: If you take a look, my state used to be &#8212; thank God it&#8217;s no longer &#8212; had the highest cancer rate of any state in the nation because we have fenceline communities going down Route 9, and going down along the Delaware River &#8212; major facilities, oil plants, and the like.&nbsp; And the people that get hurt are the people who live on the other side of those fences.&nbsp;<br><br>I made a commitment: They’re the people who are going to get helped as we move this.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the people where the money is going to go to help their neighborhoods.&nbsp; They’re &#8212;<br><br>And this Bipartisan Infrastructure Law gives communities the money they need to get forever chemicals &#8212; PFAS &#8212; off &#8212; out of their water.&nbsp; They’re deadly, deadly.&nbsp; And a lot of it’s responsible because we, the government, and the fe- &#8212; and the military has engaged in activities that we didn’t realize how it was dangerous, over the years.&nbsp; But we’re going to get rid of it all.&nbsp;<br><br>We started replacing 100 percent &#8212; 100 percent of all the lead pipes and poison &#8212; that poison our water in America.&nbsp; Four hundred thousand schools and daycare centers &#8212; their kids can’t turn on that water without getting &#8212; or worried about there’s lead in that &#8212; in that water.&nbsp; Ten million homes in America and here in this city and this state.<br><br>Because every American and every child should be able to turn on a faucet and drink clean water, which will also create thousands of good-paying jobs for plumbers and pipefitters and others.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, look &#8212; all you got to do is look around: Cities and states are acting, businesses are acting, I&#8217;m acting.&nbsp; We need Congress to act as well.&nbsp; And the people behind me are pushing Congress hard.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; They are pushing Congress hard, calling them to pass new investments and tax credits aimed directly at lowering costs for families.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, you talk about, you know, a couple &#8212; there’s only two senators that occasionally don&#8217;t vote with me.&nbsp; That&#8217;s right, right?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Literally, 48 &#8212; they talk about the split in the Democratic Party.&nbsp; There&#8217;s virtually no split in the Democratic Party.&nbsp; We just happen to have 50 presidents.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You know, you have 50 senators and 50 Democrats and 50 Republicans.&nbsp; I mean, any one can change the dynamic.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp;<br><br>But all kidding aside, 48 percent of my Democratic colleagues in the Senate vote with me 94 percent of the time.&nbsp;&nbsp;So it&#8217;s not like we have a split, but we don&#8217;t have &#8212; we have virtually no Republicans.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s some.&nbsp; We get up to as many as seven or eight will vote.&nbsp; This ain&#8217;t your father&#8217;s Republican Party.&nbsp; Not &#8212; not a joke.&nbsp; All you got to do is look what is being played on &#8212; played this morning about the tape that was released.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You know, but all kid- &#8212; kidding aside, this is the MAGA party now.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; you know, you got the senator from Texas and others.&nbsp; These guys are a different breed of cat.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not like what I served with for so many years.&nbsp;<br><br>And the people who know better are afraid to act correctly, because they know they&#8217;ll be primaried.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ve had &#8212; I won&#8217;t mention any of them; I promised I never would, and I won’t &#8212; but up to six come to me and say, “Joe, I want to be with you on such and such but I can&#8217;t.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll be primaried.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll lose my race.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll lose my race.”&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, folks, we got to &#8212; this is going to start to change.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, that bill that we talked about that is the infrastructure bill, there were two pieces of it.&nbsp; And it was one bill initially.&nbsp; And that bill had about 800,000 &#8212; $800 million in it for environmental-related issues.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, the one that didn&#8217;t pass &#8212; the part that didn&#8217;t pass yet is the one that has $531 million for environmental.&nbsp; But we got lot done though in the bill that passed, called the Infrastructure Bill, that has to do with the environment, including tax credits for purchases of electric and fuel-cell vehicles now &#8212; new or used.&nbsp;<br><br>But you’re going to save a typical driver about 80,000 &#8212; 8 &#8212; $80 a month from not having to pay gas at the pump.&nbsp; Tax credits for folks to buy solar panels and heat pumps and more efficient windows, saving each an average of $500 a year to do this &#8212; just making your home tighter so you don&#8217;t leak the heat and leak the air conditioning going out.<br><br>You know, and my pen is ready.&nbsp; My pen is ready to sign.&nbsp; I&#8217;m anxious to sign these.&nbsp; Get some of these bills to my desk.<br><br>And we can’t forget &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we can’t forget that achieving our ambitious climate goals is going to require nature itself to play a role.<br><br>You know, if you compare the map of North America in 1620 &#8212; and we have some of these maps &#8212; with America today, you’ll see much of our devas- &#8212; how much we’ve devastated our forests.&nbsp;<br><br>I mean, it used to be &#8212; if you’d look, from the Atlantic Coast almost to the Mississippi River was heavy forests, and we took it all down over those years.<br><br>That’s why today I&#8217;m signing an executive order to conserve our forests that do so much to protect us.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, our forests are our planet&#8217;s lungs.&nbsp; They literally are recycling and cycling CO2 out of the atmosphere.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what they do.&nbsp;<br><br>By the way, more the &#8212; I spent time down in the Amazon and in Colombia and in Brazil, and guess what?&nbsp; More carbon is taken out of the air in the Amazon &#8212; that carbon sink &#8212; than every bit of carbon that is generated on a daily basis in the entire United States from every source.&nbsp;<br><br>So what we should be doing and I&#8217;m trying to get done &#8212; and they&#8217;re not going to maybe like this &#8212; we should be paying the Brazilians not to cut down their forest.&nbsp; We got to cut ours down.&nbsp; We got to cut ours down.&nbsp; We got the benefit of it.&nbsp; Because we’ve got these third-world countries &#8212; not third world; some are &#8212; in Africa and in &#8212; and in South America &#8212; we got to &#8212; the industrial countries have to help.<br><br>Scientists estimate that the protection and restoration of our natural lands and waters can provide more than one third of the solution to climate change, just &#8212; just that, if we did nothing else.&nbsp;<br><br>So today, I&#8217;m about to sign an executive order to strengthen our forest on federal lands and make them and the local economies they support more resilient in the face of wildfires.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ve flown over every major wildfire in this country with FEMA since &#8212; not every; a couple I didn&#8217;t, but the vast majority of them &#8212; and it&#8217;s devastating.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve seen it from helicopters with FEMA just flying over here and Idaho.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t get to go to Oregon, but California.&nbsp; It&#8217;s absolutely devastating.&nbsp;<br><br>So we&#8217;re going to work with state and local and Tribal governments to map, catalog, and then conserve old-growth forests on our public lands.&nbsp;<br><br>These are the forests &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we&#8217;re going to do this.&nbsp; These are the forests that store, sequester incredible amounts of carbon, and help us fight climate change.&nbsp; The forests that are &#8212; are home to majestic trees, like the ones here in the &#8212; this park’s “Magnificent Forest.”&nbsp;<br><br>You know, the executive order I&#8217;m going to sign is going to make good on the international forest protection commitments from the proposal I made in Scotland, at&nbsp;<s>Glasgow</s>[COP] 26.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I got 140 countries to sign up and say that, together &#8212; and we represent 90 percent of the world&#8217;s forest.&nbsp; And this includes our own effort to crack down on trafficking of illegal logged wood and prod- &#8212; and products like the ones illegally deforesting areas around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In addition to that, I put in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill a &#8212; that we&#8217;re going to plant 1.2 billion trees &#8212; 1.2 billion trees across this country to begin the vital work of reforesting America.&nbsp; It makes sense and it also makes a big difference &#8212; (applause) &#8212; including in our cities and on our city streets.&nbsp;<br><br>The executive order also recognizes that when it comes to protecting our communities from floods and storms, nature can help us as well.&nbsp; For example, when it comes to stopping flooding, sometimes a wetland is more effective than a seawall.&nbsp; I live along a state where it&#8217;s only &#8212; the average &#8212; three feet above sea level &#8212; the state of Delaware, the Delaware River, the Delaware Bay, and the Atlantic Ocean.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, you saw what happened, by the way, down on the Gulf.&nbsp; You saw what happened in Louisiana when they had that &#8212; you know, it matters whether that &#8212; there&#8217;s a wetlands.&nbsp; They&#8217;re significantly more consequential than seawalls.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In order to help bring more of those nature-based solutions into our planning, we have to move quickly.<br><br>And with this executive order on Earth Day, we&#8217;re also showing this moment of maximum threat and urgency can also be a moment of enormous hope and enormous opportunity.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, that we &#8212; you know, that we carry “in heart and mind the image of the ideal place, the right place, the one true home, known or unknown, actual or visionary.”<br><br>I know you all feel it.&nbsp; And you wouldn&#8217;t be sitting here in the cold with your coats not on if you didn’t.&nbsp;<br><br>So I&#8217;m now going to sign this executive order.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;re going to make &#8212; I just think this is the beginning of a new day.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to just have to overtake the opposition on this.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So thank you all for being here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to sign this executive order.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>“Strengthening the Nations Forests, Communities, and Local Economies”.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s all about planting about 1,200,000,000 trees.&nbsp;<br><br>So &#8212; and, by the way, anybody bring their shovels?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; All right.<br><br>(The executive order is signed.)&nbsp;<br><br>Is this a state park or is this a city park?<br><br>GOVERNOR INSLEE:&nbsp; City.&nbsp;<br><br>MAYOR HARRELL:&nbsp; City park.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Mr. Mayor?&nbsp;<br><br>MAYOR HARRELL:&nbsp; Yes, sir?<br><br>SECRETARY HAALAND:&nbsp; On Tribal land!&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me give you this.&nbsp;<br><br>GOVERNOR INSLEE:&nbsp; Right here.&nbsp; Right here.&nbsp; He’s right behind you.&nbsp;<br><br>(Signing pen is handed to the Mayor.)<br><br>MAYOR HARRELL:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp;<br><br>And, by the way, notice who runs the Department of Interior now.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>All right.&nbsp; Well, thanks.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>11:37 A.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan meeting with Secretary Gustavo Beliz of&#160;Argentina</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/22/statement-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-meeting-with-secretary-gustavo-beliz-of-argentina/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 20:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Argentine Secretary for Strategic Affairs Secretary Gustavo Beliz at the White House to discuss joint efforts to address the crisis in Ukraine, including Argentina’s leadership at the Human Rights Council and addressing food security and energy resilience.  They also spoke of the importance of responding to humanitarian&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Argentine Secretary for Strategic Affairs Secretary Gustavo Beliz at the White House to discuss joint efforts to address the crisis in Ukraine, including Argentina’s leadership at the Human Rights Council and addressing food security and energy resilience.  They also spoke of the importance of responding to humanitarian crises.  In addition, they continue their work on the roadmap for bilateral cooperation and a partnership for sustainable and inclusive development that has led to dialogues on information and communications technology, clean energy, satellite technology, and human rights since their first meeting in August 2021. They highlighted the importance of the knowledge economy and leading-edge technology in the recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic and promoted cooperation in strategic sectors such as green energy and lithium production.  They noted the importance of a democratic and free internet and the importance of secure and trustworthy information and communications technology and services.  They spoke about the importance of strengthening the multilateral development banks and attracting U.S. private investment to build a green, equitable, and inclusive  recovery from the pandemic.  Mr. Sullivan and Secretary Beliz discussed President Biden and President Fernandez’s vison and shared commitments towards sustainable and inclusive development in the region that will be highlighted in the Summit of the Americas.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
