<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 16:02:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 16:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48728</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Shereef Elnahal, Nominee for Under Secretary for Health, Veterans Health Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs Ray Jefferson, Nominee for Under Secretary for Benefits, Veterans Benefits Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs Rita Landgraf, Nominee&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Shereef Elnahal, Nominee for Under Secretary for Health, Veterans Health Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Ray Jefferson, Nominee for Under Secretary for Benefits, Veterans Benefits Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Rita Landgraf, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Aging, Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Roselyn Tso, Nominee for Director of the Indian Health Service, Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Patrick Murphy, Nominee for Chair of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Jonathan Woodson, Nominee for Vice Chair of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>William Blake, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Michael Blecker, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Christine Hill, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Joyce Johnson, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Lucretia McClenney, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>José Ramos, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Shereef Elnahal, Nominee for Under Secretary for Health, Veterans Health Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Shereef Elnahal is a physician leader who has served as President and Chief Executive Officer of University Hospital in Newark, NJ since 2019. Prior to this role, Elnahal served as New Jersey’s 21st Health Commissioner, appointed by Governor Phil Murphy and confirmed unanimously by the New Jersey Senate. He was the first Muslim member of New Jersey&#8217;s Cabinet in state history. He also served as Assistant Deputy Under Secretary for Health for Quality, Safety, and Value at the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs from 2016 through 2018, overseeing quality of care for the Veterans Health Administration (VHA). He co-founded the VHA Innovation Ecosystem, a program that continues to foster the spread of innovation and best practices that improve veteran care across the nation.</p>



<p>Elnahal led University Hospital through the COVID-19 public health emergency, and also set up one of the first COVID-19 vaccination sites in NJ, vaccinating the state&#8217;s first health care worker on December 15th, 2020. In addition, Elnahal has overseen improvements in care quality and patient safety at the hospital. He has brought his public health background to bear in community-based programming, including a recently announced partnership with a developer and the NJ Housing and Mortgage Financing Authority to provide supportive housing to homeless patients; a hospital-based violence intervention program that has served as a national model; and a program that deploys trusted chaplains as community health workers.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ray Jefferson, Nominee for Under Secretary for Benefits, Veterans Benefits Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Ray Jefferson is the President of Jefferson Group, a global leadership development consultancy, as well as the Chair and Co-Founder of the Service Academies Global Summit. Earlier in his career, Jefferson served as a White House Fellow and worked as a Special Assistant to the U.S. Secretary of Commerce. Additionally, he served as a Fulbright Fellow in Singapore; as the Deputy Director for Hawaii’s Department of Business, Economic Development and Tourism; and as a Leadership Consultant with McKinsey &amp; Company based in Singapore. In 2009, President Barack Obama appointed Jefferson as the Senate-confirmed U.S. Assistant Secretary for Veterans’ Employment and Training at the U.S. Department of Labor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jefferson graduated from the U.S. Military Academy at West Point in 1988 and served as an Army Officer with the infantry, Rangers, and Special Forces. Jefferson lost all five fingers on his left hand while attempting to protect his teammates from a hand grenade detonating prematurely during training. He attended Harvard&#8217;s Kennedy School of Government, earning an MPA in Strategic Management, and went on to earn an MBA from Harvard Business School. Jefferson’s commitment to service has been recognized throughout his career, including when he was selected by then-Secretary of State Colin Powell as one of the two inaugural recipients of the Harrison H. Schmitt Fulbright Alumni Leadership Award for dedication to public service. Jefferson is a member of the Asia Society, Council on Foreign Relations (life member), Fulbright Association, HBS African-American Alumni Association, NAACP, Special Forces Association, 75th Ranger Regiment Association, and Young Presidents’ Organization. Born and raised in Guilderland, New York, he now considers home to be Honolulu, Hawaii.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rita Landgraf, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Aging, Department of Health and Human Services</u></strong></p>



<p>Rita Landgraf joined the University of Delaware’s College of Health Sciences in 2017 as Professor of Practice and Distinguished Health and Social Services Administrator in Residence. She also serves as Director of the UD Partnership for Healthy Communities, a cross-college, cross-state initiative. Landgraf serves as a leader within the Dean’s Office and supports a variety of activities including community engagement and outreach, development of a Master’s level degree in public health, and the college’s pipeline program. Landgraf’s focus is concentrated on the social, economic, and environmental conditions that support and sustain healthy communities and the relationship of these conditions to promote equity in health, a cost-effective health system, and the advancement of policy.</p>



<p>From 2009 to 2017, Landgraf served as Cabinet Secretary of the Delaware Department of Health and Social Services under Governor Jack Markell. As Secretary, she led the principal agency charged with keeping Delawareans healthy, ensuring they get the health care they need, and providing children, families, individuals with disabilities and seniors with the essential services. She managed one of the largest departments in Delaware’s government that included Medicaid, aging and disability services, with an annual budget of over $2 billion. Under Landgraf’s leadership, Delaware expanded community-based services to help older adults age in place, and people with disabilities live, work and participate in their communities.&nbsp; Landgraf is the former President of AARP Delaware, the former Executive Director of the National Alliance on Mental Illness Delaware, and the former Executive Director of the Arc of Delaware.</p>



<p><strong><u>Roselyn Tso, Nominee for Director of the Indian Health Service, Department of Health and Human Services</u></strong></p>



<p>Roselyn Tso is an enrolled member of the Navajo Nation. Tso began her career with the Indian Health Service (IHS) in 1984. She previously served in various roles in the Portland Area IHS and IHS Headquarters. Currently, Tso serves as the Area Director for the Navajo Area IHS. The Navajo Area IHS delivers health services to a user population of over 244,000 American Indians; the Navajo Nation is one of the largest Indian reservations in the United States consisting of more than 25,000 contiguous square miles and three satellite communities, and extends into portions of the states of Arizona, New Mexico, and Utah. In her leadership position, she was responsible for the implementation of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Act and worked directly with tribes and direct service tribes.</p>



<p>Tso holds a Bachelor of Arts in interdisciplinary studies from Marylhurst University in Portland, Oregon and a master’s degree in organizational management from the University of Phoenix, Portland, Oregon.</p>



<p><strong><u>Patrick Murphy, Nominee for Chair of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Patrick Murphy, a Pennsylvania native, was the first Iraq War Veteran to serve in Congress. He received a Bronze Star for his service in Iraq as paratrooper with the 82nd Airborne Division. While in Congress, Murphy led the signing of two landmark bills into law, including the repeal of Don’t Ask Don’t Tell and the 21st Century GI Bill. As Under Secretary of the Army during the Obama-Biden Administration, Murphy oversaw the management and operation of the Army – a Fortune 10-sized organization and the nation’s second largest employer of over 1.3 million individuals. Murphy led the expansion of the Soldier for Life initiative, which saved $340M in FY16, and helped the Army reach recruitment goals for the first time in five years with over 130,000 millennials hired.</p>



<p>In 2019, Murphy chaired the Cyberspace Solarium Commission which generated more than 100 recommendations for improving the United States’ approach to digital security issues, many of which became law through multiple defense bills and a high-profile infrastructure package. For the last several years, Murphy has been working across the public and private sector to invest in veteran-owned businesses, advocate for stronger healthcare policy, and recruiting young people and veterans to run for public office.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jonathan Woodson, Nominee for Vice Chair of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Jonathan Woodson is the Lars Anderson Professor in Management and Professor of the Practice at the Boston University Questrom School of Business, and holds joint appointments as Professor of Surgery at the School of Medicine, and Professor of Health Law, Policy, and Management at the School of Public Health. He established and led the University-wide Institute for Health System Innovation and Policy.</p>



<p>From 2010-2016, Woodson was the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs and Director of the Tricare Management Activity in the United States Department of Defense (DOD). He was the principal advisor to the Secretary of Defense for all health and force health protection related issues, and ensured the effective execution of the DOD medical mission. He exercised authority, direction, and control over the Defense Health Agency, Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences, Armed Forces Radiobiology Research Institute, Defense Center of Excellence for Psychological Health and Traumatic Brain Injury, and the Tricare Health Plan serving 9.5 million beneficiaries. Woodson holds the rank of Major General, United States Army, Reserve, and is Commander of the United States Army Reserve Medical Command, Pinellas Park, Florida.</p>



<p><strong><u>William Carl Blake, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Carl Blake is the Executive Director for Paralyzed Veterans of America (PVA), a position he has served in since January 2018. He is responsible for exercising administrative control, as directed by the President of PVA, of all offices and functions of the organization, including overseeing all efforts devoted to financial management, development and fundraising, strategic communications, and service programs executed by PVA. Blake previously served as the Associate Executive Director of Government Relations for PVA. He has represented PVA to federal agencies and has frequently testified before committees of the U.S. House of Representatives and Senate.</p>



<p>Blake was raised in Woodford, Virginia. He attended the United States Military Academy at West Point, New York. He received a Bachelor of Science Degree from the Military Academy in May 1998. He was assigned to the 2nd Battalion, 504th Parachute Infantry Regiment (1st Brigade) of the 82nd Airborne Division at Fort Bragg, North Carolina. He graduated from Infantry Officer Basic Course, U.S. Army Ranger School, U.S. Army Airborne School, and Air Assault School. His awards include the Army Commendation Medal, Expert Infantryman’s Badge, and German Parachutist Badge. Blake retired from the military in October 2000 due to injuries suffered during a parachute training exercise. He completed spinal cord injury rehabilitation at the Richmond VA Medical Center in Virginia. Blake received his Master’s in Public Administration from Old Dominion University with a concentration in Nonprofit Management. Blake lives in Fredericksburg, VA, with his wife Venus, son Jonathan, and daughter Brooke.</p>



<p><strong><u>Michael Blecker, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Michael Blecker served in the U.S. Army from 1967 to 1970, with combat infantry service in Vietnam from 1968 &#8211; 1969. Upon finishing law school, he joined Swords to Plowshares in 1976 to help veterans navigate the complex VA disability system. In 1982, he became Executive Director of Swords to Plowshares, and has over the past 45 years guided the agency from its small grassroots origins to one with a continuum of specialized services and an annual budget of over $35 million.</p>



<p>Blecker has a nationwide reputation for dedicated service and as an authority on veterans’ services and veterans’ rights. He is co-founder of the National Coalition for Homeless Veterans and the California Association of Veterans’ Service Agencies. He has served on the Congressional Commission on Service Members and Veterans Transition Assistance, the California Senate Commission on Homeless Veterans, the San Francisco Mayor’s Homeless Planning Committee, the National Agent Orange Settlement Advisory Board, the Agent Orange Information Center, and the Veterans Speakers Alliance. From 2015 to 2016, Blecker served on the federal Commission on Care, examining veteran access to VA care.</p>



<p><strong><u>Christine Hill, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Christine Hill currently serves as the Republican Staff Director for the House Committee on Veterans’ Affairs Subcommittee on Health. Prior to this position, she was the Executive Vice President, Government Affairs for Wounded Warrior Project (WWP). In the Bush Administration, Hill was Senate-confirmed as the Assistant Secretary for Congressional and Legislative Affairs for the Department of Veterans Affairs. Prior to her appointment, Hill was Director, Congressional and Intergovernmental Affairs for the 2005 Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission. Before joining this congressionally mandated commission, Hill was the military legislative assistant to Senator Elizabeth Dole.</p>



<p>A 1983 graduate of the United States Air Force Academy, Hill held numerous positions as a KC-135 instructor navigator and senior standardization/evaluation navigator. During this time, she flew combat support during the U.S. intervention in Panama, and was deployed to Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, flying in support of Desert Storm as the chief of tanker air operations. Following an assignment to Headquarters Air Combat Command, Hill was hand-picked to become the first woman assigned to fly the B-1B Bomber. She completed qualification as both an offensive and defensive systems officer and was the first initial qualification student combat qualified as a weapons system officer and instructor. During this time, she also held various Squadron- and Wing-level leadership positions. Hill concluded her military career at the Pentagon with assignments in Air Force plans and budget, and in the weapon systems division of the Air Force Office of Legislative Liaison. She retired as a Lieutenant Colonel.</p>



<p><strong><u>Joyce Johnson, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Rear Admiral Dr. Joyce M. Johnson, DO, MA is a physician with senior public health leadership experience in the civilian and military sectors. Her last active duty assignment was with the U.S. Coast Guard as Director, Health and Safety and she retired at the rank of Rear Admiral, Upper Half (08). As a physician, she is board certified in Public Health/Preventive Medicine and Psychiatry, and is also a board-certified Clinical Pharmacologist and Certified Addiction Specialist. She is a Doctor of Osteopathic Medicine, earning a D.O. degree; prior to that she earned a master’s degree in Hospital and Health Administration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Based on her previous experiences, Johnson understands the clinical needs of veterans from both provider and patient perspectives, and recognizes the many contributions the VA health care system makes to patients, their families, and the overall community in meeting the needs of America’s veterans. For many years, she was a surveyor for a national accreditation body, surveying both inpatient and ambulatory care facilities. At the Department of Veterans Affairs, Johnson served as a Senior Research Resident, and more recently on has been appointed to the VA Commission on Care, the Advisory Committee on Disability Compensation, and the Advisory Committee on Women Veterans. In addition, Johnson served on the Board and chaired several committees of the Military Officers Association of America (MOAA). Johnson has been awarded eight honorary doctoral degrees, and has extensive on-site disaster relief experience, and has provided clinical care and/or medical consultation on all seven continents.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lucretia McClenney, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Lucretia M. McClenney has dedicated her professional life to our nation’s men and women who have served and are serving in uniformed armed services, and their families. She served with distinction for 30 years in the Army in various medical treatment facilities and staffs worldwide, and retired as a Colonel in November 2001. Immediately following McClenney’s retirement from the Army, she joined the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) as Special Assistant to the Assistant Secretary for Policy, Planning, and Preparedness. She also served as Director of the VA’s Center for Minority Veterans, where she was the principal advisor to the Secretary of the VA on policies and programs affecting minority veterans. As an outcome of her efforts in this role, the VA established an Office of Health Equity to ensure health equity for all veterans.</p>



<p>Her dedication and passion for the health care of veterans led to her selection in 2015 to serve on the congressionally mandated Commission on Care that provided recommendations for transforming veterans’ health care. She served as a consultant with the DOD Vietnam War Commemoration. Currently, McClenney is a member of the Military Officers Association of America (MOAA) Board of Directors, VA’s Former POW Advisory Committee, a Life Member of The ROCKS, Inc., and a Life Member of Alpha Kappa Sorority, Inc. She received a BSN from Murray State University, and an MSN in Psychiatric/Mental Health Nursing from Catholic University. She lives in Alexandria, VA.</p>



<p><strong><u>José Ramos, Nominee for Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>José R. Ramos is the Vice President of Government and Community Relations for the Wounded Warrior Project (WWP). Ramos grew up in El Paso, TX and joined the Navy as a Hospital Corpsman, spending his entire career serving alongside Marines as a platoon “Doc”. He served one tour in Afghanistan and two tours in Iraq. In 2004, while serving as a member of a Sniper Team, he was hit by a rocket and was severely injured. His injuries were nearly fatal and included a left arm amputation, lung contusions, nerve damage to the left leg, bulged discs in the lumbar region, and numerous shrapnel wounds which led to his retirement from service in November 2005. Ramos used adaptive sports through his recovery, running the New York City Marathon, cycling with other injured troops from Washington, D.C. to the Hamptons, N.Y. in seven days, and competed in endurance events as a way of raising awareness for those with disabilities.</p>



<p>In 2007, Ramos was appointed by President Bush to serve on the President’s Commission on Care for America’s Returning Wounded Warriors, tasked to conduct a review of the care America is providing wounded servicemen and women returning from the battlefield. Ramos graduated from George Mason University, <em>summa cum laude</em>, with a B.A. in Government and International Politics and a Minor in Islamic Studies. Earlier in Ramos’ career, he worked at the Center for Strategic and International Studies, sat on the Peer Reviewed Orthopedic Research Program Integration Panel for the Department of Defense, and served as a Special Assistant at the Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Legislative Affairs. Ramos resides in Great Falls, VA with his wife Jodie, their sons Donovan and Luke, and their Labrador Scout.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the President&#8217;s New Digital Assets Executive&#160;Order</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/09/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-presidents-new-digital-assets-executive-order/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 14:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (March 8, 2022) 6:21 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MODERATOR:&#160; Good evening, everyone.&#160; Thank you for joining today&#8217;s press call to discuss President Biden&#8217;s new executive order on ensuring responsible innovation in digital assets. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; As a reminder, this call will be on background, attributed to a senior administration official, and the contents of this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(March 8, 2022)</p>



<p>6:21 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you for joining today&#8217;s press call to discuss President Biden&#8217;s new executive order on ensuring responsible innovation in digital assets.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As a reminder, this call will be on background, attributed to a senior administration official, and the contents of this call are embargoed until tomorrow, Wednesday, March 9th, at 6:00 a.m.&nbsp; By joining the call, you agree to these ground rules.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Prior to this call, I also shared a factsheet that is also under embargo until tomorrow at 6:00 a.m.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For everyone&#8217;s awareness but not for reporting, our speakers today are [senior administration official], [senior administration official], and [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>After we hear from our speakers, we will open up the call for Q&amp;A.&nbsp; And with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks to all of you for joining us late in the day.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ensuring responsible innovation and evolution of the digital asset ecosystem is essential to our national security, financial stability, economic competitiveness, and continued global leadership.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You all know that cryptocurrencies have seen explosive growth in recent years, reaching a $3 trillion market cap last November.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Without oversight, the explosive growth in cryptocurrency use would pose risks to Americans and to the stability of our businesses, our financial system, and our national security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The absence of sufficient oversight can also provide opportunities for criminals and other malicious actors to leverage cryptocurrencies to launder the proceeds of their crimes or circumvent justly-applied sanctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the same time, however, digital assets can also provide opportunities for American innovation and competitiveness, and promote financial inclusion.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Innovation is central to America&#8217;s story and powers our economy, generating jobs and opportunities, creating and building new industries, and sustaining our global competitive edge and leadership.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This innovation is also a critical factor in ensuring the long-term strength of key national security tools, like sanctions and anti-money laundering frameworks as well as other strategic benefits we reap from the role of the United States in the global financial system.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also want to underscore the significant international leadership role the United States has already played in the digital asset ecosystem, just as we have in technological and financial standard-setting throughout our history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States also has the world’s oldest and most comprehensive regulatory framework for digital asset activities, which has enabled us to take leading roles in international fora and supporting key partners in building their own digital asset capacity.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States led global efforts to adopt the first international standards on digital assets during our presidency of the Financial Action Task Force &#8212; FATF.&nbsp; And we continue to drive implementation of those standards.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Under our G7 presidency, we established the G7 Digital Payments Expert Group to discuss Central Bank Digital Currencies, stablecoins, and other digital payment issues.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To reinforce this leadership, the EO directs relevant departments and agencies to initiate research into the merits of a U.S. central bank digital currency, including an assessment of possible risks and benefits to consumers, investors, payment systems, implications for national security, human rights, and financial inclusion.&nbsp; That effort will also lay out the measures that are needed to establish a central bank digital currency, or CBDC, should there be a determination that doing so is in the national interest.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For context, over 100 countries are currently exploring or piloting central bank digital currencies for both cross-border and domestic use.&nbsp; Many of these countries are also working together to set standards for CBDC design and cross-border systems, with implications for domestic and international priorities including the centrality of the U.S. dollar in the global financial system.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This EO will help make sure we have a leadership role and a seat at the table.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now I&#8217;ll turn it over to my colleague.&nbsp; As you just heard, they are [redacted].&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Over to you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Good evening everyone, and thank you again for your time this evening.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, innovation is not only critical for our economic security but also for our national security, enabling us to maintain our technological and economic edge to compete and win in the 21st century.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But innovation must benefit all Americans, and that extends to innovation in the digital asset ecosystem.&nbsp; The benefits and risks of digital asset systems are fundamentally dependent on their design and governance, so we must take steps to ensure this serves Americans’ interests.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This executive order seeks to promote digital asset innovation while balancing their benefits and associated risk, and it does so in several ways.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, the EO establishes a comprehensive federal framework to ensure the United States continues to play a leading role in the innovation and governance of digital assets at home and abroad, consistent with our democratic values and to the benefit of U.S.&nbsp;global competitiveness.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, the EO directs relevant departments and agencies to initiate research into the merits of a U.S. Central Bank Digital Currency, as [senior administration official] mentioned previously.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This research, along with the framework we will develop for international engagement and competitiveness, will help ensure we preserve the critical role of the United States in the global financial system.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is critical for ensuring the strength of U.S.&nbsp;national security tools that we need to combat illicit actors, like rogue states and cybercriminals.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Third, the EO calls for the development of a plan to mitigate the illicit finance and national security risks posed by the misuse of digital assets.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The White House has already demonstrated leadership in this space by aligning departments and agencies to combat misuse of digital assets enabling the rise and spread of ransomware.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The insufficiency of international implementation of anti-money laundering network and frameworks for digital assets is the greatest vulnerability of these ecosystems that criminals are currently exploiting.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Most current digital asset systems were not designed with critical controls in mind like identity, sanctions screening, and revocability of illicit transactions.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Similar to our efforts to secure software development under the cyber executive order, this executive order is a signal to industry on the need to build in the critical protections needed for financial systems so we can leverage these innovative technologies for our benefit.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The U.S. government will be developing action plans and frameworks to drive this objective.<a></a></p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In sum, the executive order recognizes and reinforces U.S. leadership in the global financial system, safeguards the long-term efficacy of critical national security tools like sanctions and anti-money laundering frameworks, ensuring the digital asset ecosystem evolves in a manner consistent with our democratic values and protects businesses, consumers, and the integrity of the global financial system.</p>



<p>This EO is represents a continuation of U.S. leadership on financial and technological standard-setting at home and abroad. We remain committed to working with allies in the broader digital asset community to shape the future of digital assets systems in a manner that&#8217;s inclusive, consistent with our democratic values, and safeguards the integrity of the global financial system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to my colleague, [senior administration official], to follow up and continue.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Over to you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>As [senior administration officials] said, today&#8217;s announcement marks a necessary step forward in our efforts to promote responsible innovation in the digital asset space, leveraging technology, and working with the private sector to help build an economy from the bottom up and the middle out.</p>



<p>Fundamentally, an American approach to digital assets is one that encourages responsible innovation by decisively mitigating the risks, in particular the financial stability and consumer protection risks.</p>



<p>We need to be clear-eyed that certain earlier forms of financial innovation have ended up hurting American families while making a small group of people very rich.&nbsp; That underscores the need for robust consumer and investor protection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As digital assets have grown, investors have poured in.&nbsp; Around 16 percent of adult Americans &#8212; approximately 40 million people &#8212; have ever invested in, traded, or used crypto currency based on recent surveys.&nbsp; But some asset prices are volatile, regularly skyrocketing and sinking with real downsides for investors.&nbsp; Bitcoin, for example, began the pandemic at $7,300, peaked at around $68,000 before falling back down to about $39,000.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has put forward a holistic whole-of-government approach to understand and address not only the macroeconomic risks, but also the micro risk &#8212; that is the risk to each individual consumer, investor, and business that engages with these assets.</p>



<p>I want to emphasize why this executive order is significant in two key ways.&nbsp; First, it reflects an extensive process informed by stakeholders across the federal government and many outside of government.&nbsp; This process has identified key areas of present and future concern, and questions about the potential promise of these assets and their underlying technology.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Chief among those is the need to guard individual consumers, investors, and businesses, as well as the financial system writ large, from the risks posed by the substantial growth in digital assets.&nbsp; This includes the disparate impact risks that may arise from disparities in digital asset ownership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, it recognizes that our assessments of the risks and potential benefits of digital assets must include an understanding of how our financial system does and does not meet the current needs of consumers in a manner that is equitable, inclusive, and efficient.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Antiquated payment infrastructure leaves the United States and its consumers with options that are slow, costly, or altogether inaccessible.&nbsp; That&#8217;s particularly true of cross-border payments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That is why this executive order directs a report on the future of money and payment systems, including discussion of the conditions that drive broad adoption of these assets and the implications for the U.S. financial system and consumers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The executive order also places the highest urgency on research and potential development of the U.S. central bank digital currency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The government alone does not solve these problems, and definitely not a government that stays in its silos.&nbsp; Therefore, we’ll continue to partner with all stakeholders &#8212; including industry, labor, consumer, and environmental groups, international allies and partners &#8212; to identify actions we can take to foster responsible innovation in the digital asset ecosystem, while mitigating the very real risk.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, this executive order signals the beginning, not the conclusion, of this administration&#8217;s work around digital assets.&nbsp; As this ecosystem evolves, so will our approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I will give it back to you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I just am looking at a map that shows nine countries have already started &#8212; you know, launched a currency.&nbsp; There&#8217;s 15 pilots underway; 16 countries have them in development.&nbsp; Is the United States kind of getting to this market and this sector too late?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you are now launching a 180-day study, you know, don&#8217;t you even put it off any further?&nbsp; So how quickly can you go after the &#8212; after these reports come in?&nbsp; And is there a risk of being at a competitive disadvantage to China and others?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Maybe I’ll start on that, Andrea.&nbsp; Thanks for the question.&nbsp; I think the first thing to note from the EO is we&#8217;re placing the highest urgency on the effort to assess the potential benefits and the risks of a digital dollar on payment systems, on financial stability, on national security, on the implications for human rights, and financial inclusion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And these are critical design &#8212; all of these implications lead to critical design decisions.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve got to be very &#8212; very deliberate about that analysis because the implications of our moving in this direction are profound for the country that issues the world&#8217;s primary reserve currency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, look, we can move quickly, but we can also move in a way that&#8217;s smart and that&#8217;s inclusive of the stakeholders both within our government and certainly outside our government.</p>



<p>Oh, I should say also on your second question, you know, on the digital one: I mean, here I want to be &#8212; I want to be very, very direct with my answer.  The primacy of the dollar &#8212; the U.S. dollar &#8212; it&#8217;s underpinned by fundamental advantages that the United States has held for a long time and continues to hold: credible and longstanding commitments to transparency, our rule of law, the contractual obligations and rights that everyone enjoys, the deepest and most liquid financial markets in the world, sound economic governance, and the full independence of our Federal Reserve system.  So those are the institutional features, the competitive advantages that give the dollar its primacy. <br><br>     And really, the dollar’s role has been and will continue to be crucial to the stability of the international monetary system as a whole.  Foreign central bank digital currencies &#8212; I mean, their introduction by themselves do not threaten this dominance. <br><br>     But, you know, we are &#8212; we are constantly assessing and monitoring any developments that relate to a core policy objective of ours, which is to maintain the centrality of the dollar in global financial markets and in the global economy.<br><br>     Q    Hi.  My first question is just logistical.  What is the timeline for some of the reports to be delivered or action to be taken?<br><br>     The second one is: What has your conversation been like with industry in developing this executive order?  You know, how have those conversations gone?  What’s the tenor of them?  And do you expect that they will be on board with the principles that you’ve laid out?<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  So I’m happy to start on that and then invite my colleagues to join.<br><br>     So on the timeframes, the executive order includes various timeframes consistent with the complexity of the particular reports and how much work has been done.<br><br>     So one of the key parts of the executive order is we want to fully leverage innovation while managing the risks.  And that means taking a careful look at both of those components and really bringing together stakeholders so that we make these decisions &#8212; as [senior administration official] noted, these are important decisions and we make them in a way that really sets us up for the long-term benefits and implications.<br><br>     So the EO will have a range of timeframes &#8212; some shorter, some 60 to 90 days; some longer, 180 days &#8212; in order to allow for that.<br><br>     And with regard to the engagement with industry, we’ve done a number of what we call “Crypto Sundays” where we brought in innovators on the technology side, individuals on the financial side to really understand the different elements of cryptocurrencies &#8212; for example, the types of services it will enable, like cross-country remittances &#8212; bringing down the cost of that, enabling the speed of that &#8212; as well as innovation in financial markets and, on the flip side, how the governance and design can be &#8212; and the technology of that can be navigated to ensure we manage some of the risks as well.<br><br>     So we’ve done extensive engagement to both be informed and also to test out ideas in the development, which was extensive, of this EO.<br><br>     Q    Hey.  I wanted to ask about next steps once these reports come in.  Is there a timeline for when you would want to maybe start thinking about regulation on some of these topics?<br><br>     And then my other question is &#8212; you mentioned sanctions at the top of the call.  I don’t see them mentioned in the fact sheet.  But are the sanctions and the concerns that have been raised about crypto being a workaround &#8212; are those going &#8212; is that going to be mentioned in this executive order?<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  [Senior administration official], you want to speak to that?  Or &#8212;<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  I don’t know.  [Senior administration official], do you want to talk about the sanctions aspect?<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah.  Maybe, [senior administration official], if you want to start on regulation and then [senior administration official] and I can do sanctions?<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Sure.  So, look, I &#8212; we don’t want to pre-judge what we’re going to do before we’ve &#8212; the agencies have had time to do their work and produce their reports and analysis that we are asking them to do.<br><br>     That said, I think the entire premise of this executive order and the spirit behind it is that this is a growing area, an area that is presenting increasing risks and also potential opportunities, and that it’s important that we very quickly fully document and understand what those are and move quickly to address them.<br><br>     So my expectation would be that once the reports are finished on the accelerated timeline that the executive order requires that we would move quickly to try to act on the recommendations that they are providing &#8212; that they provide.<br><br>     [Senior administration official], do you want to talk about sanctions?<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Sure.  [Senior administration official], I’ll start on this, and if there’s anything I miss, please add onto mine.<br><br>     So, first thing to say here is the U.S. government has long taken actions, including under law enforcement and existing Treasury authorities to combat the use of cryptocurrency to evade sanctions.  And right now, the administration is driving a priority effort on combatting the misuse of virtual currency.<br><br>     This was launched as part of the U.S. counter-ransomware strategy that has been underway for several months.  And the administration will continue to aggressively combat the misuse of cryptocurrency, including the use of it to evade U.S. sanctions.  And that stance equally applies to the &#8212; to the Russia-Ukraine crises, as it does to any other nation or regime or non-state actor that seeks to undermine U.S. national security.<br><br>     I will say, on Russia, in particular, the use of cryptocurrency we do not think is a viable workaround to the set of financial sanctions we’ve imposed across the entire Russian economy and, in particular, to its central bank.<br><br>     And, [senior administration official], over to you for anything I missed.<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  No, I think you really covered it all, [senior administration official].  We’re building on work that’s been underway over the last six to nine months really to counter use of cryptocurrency as part of ransomware and &#8212; including working with international partners on anti-money laundering.<br><br>     And hopefully, while we don’t see it in the current context in terms of Russia itself, the current crisis is a good opportunity for us to double down on that international work and help our partners build capacity to actually implement that anti-money laundering or cryptocurrency rules that we very much want to have in place.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing the call.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t mean to be facetious here, but I&#8217;d love to know sort of how you characterize the importance of this executive order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It strikes me looking at it that a lot of this is ground that’s been trod before, particularly when it comes to central bank digital currency.&nbsp; We just saw the report &#8212; the initial report from the Board of Governors, the subsequent report from the Reserve Bank of Boston, and it just seems like they&#8217;ve begun to dig into these issues in much the same way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, as you talk about the kind of cross-agency work on cybersecurity, certainly the Deputy Attorney General has talked a lot about the role the Justice Department is going to play looking into these issues, I just wonder if you see this as a reset or something more than that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, I&#8217;ve listened to the CFTC chairman, the FCC chairman talk about what they see as their regulatory role here.&nbsp; And I guess I&#8217;m just struggling, looking at the factsheet, to understand how this advances the work that has been done by the administration thus far.&nbsp; Is it, again, to reset it, or to pull it under one agency or umbrella?&nbsp; Just how would you convey the importance of this to somebody who is wondering what the notional progress is from seeing this EO.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Please go ahead, [senior administration official].&nbsp; I’ll follow you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I’m happy to.&nbsp; And then we’ll work this &#8212; you can tell the close partnership among the three of us on this work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, first, there hadn&#8217;t previously been an organized effort to bring together the expertise and authorities of the entire U.S. government to inform a holistic approach to digital assets.&nbsp; And, in this case really, the partnership &#8212; the White House and specifically the National Security Advisor, the Economic Adviser chair &#8212; they’ll share this effort to ensure that we&#8217;re bringing together our national security and our economic policy in a coordinated way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you&#8217;re correct.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been work done by Treasury, there&#8217;s been work done by financial regulators, but really pulling together the questions around consumer and investor protection, financial stability, and systemic and disparate risk &#8212; bringing that together and then, with a common approach, laying out a coordinated path is really the game changer here.</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;Yeah, I mean, just to add to what you said, I think the implications &#8212; we know the implications of potentially issuing a digital dollar are profound.&nbsp; They&#8217;re extraordinarily wide-ranging.</p>



<p>So, this EO pulls together the expertise from across the U.S. government.&nbsp; It also pulls &#8212; pulls in expertise views and perspectives from a range of stakeholders in our &#8212; in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, this is all about &#8212; this is all about the future of the payments system in this country, the future of credit creation, commercial banking.&nbsp; We know the implications for national security, our ability to show leadership in setting global payment standards for privacy and security, but also reinforcing the efficacy of sanctions or potentially influencing the growth of private cryptocurrencies that we know are growing to a material scale and, in some cases, have facilitated illicit finance and financial stability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of these issues are tied up in the question of whether to issue a digital currency, and, if so, how to do so in a way that advances our strategic objectives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so this &#8212; this is a way to organize ourselves with urgency so that we have a coherent and coordinated view on digital assets and that it&#8217;s articulated at the very highest level of our government.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doing it.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, this is [senior administration official].&nbsp; I would just add to what [senior administration officials] have said: that it&#8217;s notable because this is the President articulating his views about what our interests and concerns are in this space.&nbsp; In fact, that is notable in and of itself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think it&#8217;s also important that &#8212; the emphasis that this document places on potential risks and the need to mitigate those risks.&nbsp; You know, in a world &#8212; we live in a world where, you know, approaching 20 percent of Americans have invested in or traded or used cryptocurrencies.&nbsp; This is not a niche issue anymore.&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s profoundly important that we have the right tools to mitigate the risks to consumers, to investors, and, frankly, to the entire financial system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as [senior administration officials] said, getting &#8212; articulating those interests, getting all the work that has already been happening at agencies, getting that organized, getting the agencies talking with each other as appropriate to adequately address these issues &#8212; all of that is very important.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, folks.&nbsp; Thanks for taking this.&nbsp; I guess &#8212; some of my questions have been answered.&nbsp; I guess I wanted to circle back on, I think, the Crypto Sundays that [senior administration official] mentioned.&nbsp; How many of those did you guys do?&nbsp; And was it only sort of innovators and industry representatives present?&nbsp; Or did you also have, you know, some of the academics who have studied, you know, financial stability risks, consumer protection risks, governance issues that are present in the crypto market?&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Academics and other &#8212; you know, other &#8212; other, I guess, experts and stuff.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, the less I share, you know, how often we work Sundays &#8212; I won’t go into how many Sundays there were, but will go into the question about who was included.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There were &#8212; you know, our goal was noting this is a new space and really wanting to learn from as broad a space as possible and test those ideas.&nbsp; It did include academics, innovators, to your point, as well as individuals from the sector as well.</p>



<p>And I want to emphasize, as well, the points that [senior administration officials] made.&nbsp; You know, you see as well we tasked a number of studies in the EO to emphasize that we &#8212; this is an area needs some deep reflection to ensure that we can move out quickly following that and making some key decisions, both from a policy and an implementation perspective.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I would just add that there&#8217;s also meetings with consumer groups and other groups that are focused on some of those risks and that, you know, we purposefully tried to solicit views from experts and academics who have a diversity of viewpoints about the potential risks and benefits of cryptocurrency.&nbsp; So, we tried to really get the full spectrum of the user.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And I don’t &#8212; I can’t recall, just to be sure &#8212; I think, [senior administration official], you mentioned it just now &#8212; but we also heard quite a bit from those who want to solve the problems associated with financial inclusion.&nbsp; You know, we know as recently as 2020, I think, over 5 percent of American households were unbanked.&nbsp; That’s if not the highest, among the highest percentage among G7 countries.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s a multiple of that share that&#8217;s underbanked.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so we heard quite a bit about the reasons why those who are unbanked or underbanked are facing issues with financial inclusion, and many of them relate to high minimum balances or high fees they have to face in the existing architecture.&nbsp; And so, it was important to hear their perspective and to understand how this effort can help solve that problem.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for taking my questions.&nbsp; The last comment actually was very helpful because I&#8217;m interested in the comments that were made about how the current financial system doesn&#8217;t serve many Americans.&nbsp; And I was hoping you could provide a bit more information from the surveys that you talked about regarding unbanked individuals investing in cryptocurrency.&nbsp; Is there &#8212; are there numbers that you might have regarding that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then one other question.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve heard from sources &#8212; quite a few sources that say that this EO has not a lot to do with the current war in Ukraine, but I am curious about the timing of the executive order and if that was factored in whatsoever to it&#8217;s being released now.&nbsp; Any information on that would also be helpful.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Maybe I&#8217;ll start.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure &#8212; I&#8217;m sure both [senior administration officials] would like to add perspective.</p>



<p>First, on your last question, we&#8217;ve been working on this EO for many, many months, updating well before early November when Russia began to amass troops on Ukraine&#8217;s border.</p>



<p>In terms of the problems we&#8217;re trying to solve &#8212; and I&#8217;ll come to &#8212; I think [senior administration official] should speak to the financial inclusion issue.&nbsp; But, you know, the payment system right now is quite costly in this country and, in some cases, quite slow, especially for payments across borders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, you can look to a number of objective analyses that show Americans pay over, I think, 2 percent of GDP in payment services.&nbsp; And a lot of that has to do with high fees for credit cards.&nbsp; And the primary payment source, which is bank deposits, they tend to get compensated with relatively low interest rates compared to wholesale money market rates, for example.</p>



<p>And, you know, it takes a long time for checks to clear, and wire transfers sometimes take even longer.&nbsp; And so these are problems that are worth solving, worth understanding.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s part of this effort.</p>



<p>You know, you referenced the financial inclusion surveys.&nbsp; A lot &#8212; the numbers I was citing come from the FDIC, and I think they cite that over 5 percent of American households are unbanked and about 18 percent of households are underbanked.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, just to add to what [senior administration official] said.&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, we &#8212; we have a clear problem with lack of access to basic banking services, as [senior administration official] has detailed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our payment system for consumers, in many cases, is quite slow, and it takes a while for a check to actually be deposited into your account.&nbsp; And that delay can end up being quite costly to people who need that payment for &#8212; to pay the rent, or pay utility bills, and so on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, what we are trying &#8212; one of the things that we are trying to do here is to fully understand how can digital assets help, if at all, in solving those problems.&nbsp; I think that just the very fact that they are digital does not, you know, magically solve these problems.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not &#8212; based on what we know so far, it&#8217;s not the case that these assets completely eliminate transaction costs.&nbsp; There are a variety of costs associated with holding and transferring them that resemble some of the problems that we have in our current payment system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the point is, there&#8217;s at least potential here to try to address a very serious problem that mainly affects, you know, lower-income, middle-class Americans.&nbsp; And so we really want to try to get to the bottom of what we can do and how it would be possible to nurture innovation so it does help those folks rather than &#8212; rather than hurt them.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, everyone, for joining our call this evening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a reminder, the contents of this call are under embargo until 6:00 a.m. tomorrow morning, and the contents of this call should be attributed to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p> 6:53 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Ensuring Responsible Development of Digital&#160;Assets</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/09/executive-order-on-ensuring-responsible-development-of-digital-assets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 14:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows: Section 1.&#160; Policy.&#160; Advances in digital and distributed ledger technology for financial services have led to dramatic growth in markets for digital assets, with profound implications for the protection&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows:<br><br>Section 1.&nbsp; Policy.&nbsp; Advances in digital and distributed ledger technology for financial services have led to dramatic growth in markets for digital assets, with profound implications for the protection of consumers, investors, and businesses, including data privacy and security; financial stability and systemic risk; crime; national security; the ability to exercise human rights; financial inclusion and equity; and energy demand and climate change.&nbsp; In November 2021, non‑state issued digital assets reached a combined market capitalization of $3 trillion, up from approximately $14&nbsp;billion in early November 2016.&nbsp; Monetary authorities globally are also exploring, and in some cases introducing, central bank digital currencies (CBDCs).&nbsp;<br>While many activities involving digital assets are within the scope of existing domestic laws and regulations, an area where the United States has been a global leader, growing development and adoption of digital assets and related innovations, as well as inconsistent controls to defend against certain key risks, necessitate an evolution and alignment of the United States Government approach to digital assets.&nbsp; The United States has an interest in responsible financial innovation, expanding access to safe and affordable financial services, and reducing the cost of domestic and cross-border funds transfers and payments, including through the continued modernization of public payment systems.&nbsp; We must take strong steps to reduce the risks that digital assets could pose to consumers, investors, and business protections; financial stability and financial system integrity; combating and preventing crime and illicit finance; national security; the ability to exercise human rights; financial inclusion and equity; and climate change and pollution.<br><br>Sec. 2.&nbsp; Objectives.&nbsp; The principal policy objectives of the United States with respect to digital assets are as follows:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;We must protect consumers, investors, and businesses in the United States. &nbsp;The unique and varied features of digital assets can pose significant financial risks to consumers, investors, and businesses if appropriate protections are not in place.&nbsp; In the absence of sufficient oversight and standards, firms providing digital asset services may provide inadequate protections for sensitive financial data, custodial and other arrangements relating to customer assets and funds, or disclosures of risks associated with investment.&nbsp; Cybersecurity and market failures at major digital asset exchanges and trading platforms have resulted in billions of dollars in losses.&nbsp; The United States should ensure that safeguards are in place and promote the responsible development of digital assets to protect consumers, investors, and businesses; maintain privacy; and shield against arbitrary or unlawful surveillance, which can contribute to human rights abuses.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;We must protect United States and global financial stability and mitigate systemic risk.&nbsp; Some digital asset trading platforms and service providers have grown rapidly in size and complexity and may not be subject to or in compliance with appropriate regulations or supervision. &nbsp;Digital asset issuers, exchanges and trading platforms, and intermediaries whose activities may increase risks to financial stability, should, as appropriate, be subject to and in compliance with regulatory and supervisory standards that govern traditional market infrastructures and financial firms, in line with the general principle of &#8220;same business, same risks, same rules.&#8221; &nbsp;The new and unique uses and functions that digital assets can facilitate may create additional economic and financial risks requiring an evolution to a regulatory approach that adequately addresses those risks.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;We must mitigate the illicit finance and national security risks posed by misuse of digital assets.&nbsp; Digital assets may pose significant illicit finance risks, including money laundering, cybercrime and ransomware, narcotics and human trafficking, and terrorism and proliferation financing. &nbsp;Digital assets may also be used as a tool to circumvent United States and foreign financial sanctions regimes and other tools and authorities.&nbsp; Further, while the United States has been a leader in setting international standards for the regulation and supervision of digital assets for anti‑money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism (AML/CFT), poor or nonexistent implementation of those standards in some jurisdictions abroad can present significant illicit financing risks for the United States and global financial systems.&nbsp; Illicit actors, including the perpetrators of ransomware incidents and other cybercrime, often launder and cash out of their illicit proceeds using digital asset service providers in jurisdictions that have not yet effectively implemented the international standards set by the inter-governmental Financial Action Task Force (FATF). &nbsp;The continued availability of service providers in jurisdictions where international AML/CFT standards are not effectively implemented enables financial activity without illicit finance controls. &nbsp;Growth in decentralized financial ecosystems, peer-to-peer payment activity, and obscured blockchain ledgers without controls to mitigate illicit finance could also present additional market and national security risks in the future. &nbsp;The United States must ensure appropriate controls and accountability for current and future digital assets systems to promote high standards for transparency, privacy, and security &#8212; including through regulatory, governance, and technological measures &#8212; that counter illicit activities and preserve or enhance the efficacy of our national security tools.&nbsp; When digital assets are abused or used in illicit ways, or undermine national security, it is in the national interest to take actions to mitigate these illicit finance and national security risks through regulation, oversight, law enforcement action, or use of other United States Government authorities.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;We must reinforce United States leadership in the global financial system and in technological and economic competitiveness, including through the responsible development of payment innovations and digital assets.&nbsp; The United&nbsp;States has an interest in ensuring that it remains at the forefront of responsible development and design of digital assets and the technology that underpins new forms of payments and capital flows in the international financial system, particularly in setting standards that promote: &nbsp;democratic values; the rule of law; privacy; the protection of consumers, investors, and businesses; and interoperability with digital platforms, legacy architecture, and international payment systems. &nbsp;The United States derives significant economic and national security benefits from the central role that the United States dollar and United States financial institutions and markets play in the global financial system.&nbsp; Continued United States leadership in the global financial system will sustain United States financial power and promote United States economic interests.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;We must promote access to safe and affordable financial services.&nbsp; Many Americans are underbanked and the costs of cross-border money transfers and payments are high. &nbsp;The United States has a strong interest in promoting responsible innovation that expands equitable access to financial services, particularly for those Americans underserved by the traditional banking system, including by making investments and domestic and cross-border funds transfers and payments cheaper, faster, and safer, and by promoting greater and more cost-efficient access to financial products and services. &nbsp;The United States also has an interest in ensuring that the benefits of financial innovation are enjoyed equitably by all Americans and that any disparate impacts of financial innovation are mitigated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(f) &nbsp;We must support technological advances that promote responsible development and use of digital assets.&nbsp; The technological architecture of different digital assets has substantial implications for privacy, national security, the operational security and resilience of financial systems, climate change, the ability to exercise human rights, and other national goals.&nbsp; The United States has an interest in ensuring that digital asset technologies and the digital payments ecosystem are developed, designed, and implemented in a responsible manner that includes privacy and security in their architecture, integrates features and controls that defend against illicit exploitation, and reduces negative climate impacts and environmental pollution, as may result from some cryptocurrency mining.<br><br>Sec. 3.&nbsp; Coordination.&nbsp; The Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs (APNSA) and the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy (APEP) shall coordinate, through the interagency process described in National Security Memorandum 2 of February 4, 2021 (Renewing the National Security Council System), the executive branch actions necessary to implement this order.&nbsp; The interagency process shall include, as appropriate: &nbsp;the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Domestic Policy Council, the Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, the Director of the National Science Foundation, and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.&nbsp; Representatives of other executive departments and agencies (agencies) and other senior officials may be invited to attend interagency meetings as appropriate, including, with due respect for their regulatory independence, representatives of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, and other Federal regulatory agencies.<br><br>Sec. 4.&nbsp; Policy and Actions Related to United States Central Bank Digital Currencies.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The policy of my Administration on a United States CBDC is as follows:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sovereign money is at the core of a well-functioning financial system, macroeconomic stabilization policies, and economic growth.&nbsp; My Administration places the highest urgency on research and development efforts into the potential design and deployment options of a United States CBDC. &nbsp;These efforts should include assessments of possible benefits and risks for consumers, investors, and businesses; financial stability and systemic risk; payment systems; national security; the ability to exercise human rights; financial inclusion and equity; and the actions required to launch a United States CBDC if doing so is deemed to be in the national interest.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;My Administration sees merit in showcasing United States leadership and participation in international fora related to CBDCs and in multi‑country conversations and pilot projects involving CBDCs. &nbsp;Any future dollar payment system should be designed in a way that is consistent with United States priorities (as outlined in section 4(a)(i) of this order) and democratic values, including privacy protections, and that ensures the global financial system has appropriate transparency, connectivity, and platform and architecture interoperability or transferability, as appropriate.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;A United States CBDC may have the potential to support efficient and low-cost transactions, particularly for cross‑border funds transfers and payments, and to foster greater access to the financial system, with fewer of the risks posed by private sector-administered digital assets.&nbsp; A United States CBDC that is interoperable with CBDCs issued by other monetary authorities could facilitate faster and lower-cost cross-border payments and potentially boost economic growth, support the continued centrality of the United States within the international financial system, and help to protect the unique role that the dollar plays in global finance. &nbsp;There are also, however, potential risks and downsides to consider. &nbsp;We should prioritize timely assessments of potential benefits and risks under various designs to ensure that the United&nbsp;States remains a leader in the international financial system.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall submit to the President a report on the future of money and payment systems, including the conditions that drive broad adoption of digital assets; the extent to which technological innovation may influence these outcomes; and the implications for the United&nbsp;States financial system, the modernization of and changes to payment systems, economic growth, financial inclusion, and national security. &nbsp;This report shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section&nbsp;3 of this order.&nbsp; Based on the potential United States CBDC design options, this report shall include an analysis of:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the potential implications of a United States CBDC, based on the possible design choices, for national interests, including implications for economic growth and stability;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;the potential implications a United States CBDC might have on financial inclusion;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;the potential relationship between a CBDC and private sector-administered digital assets;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;the future of sovereign and privately produced money globally and implications for our financial system and democracy;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the extent to which foreign CBDCs could displace existing currencies and alter the payment system in ways that could undermine United States financial centrality;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;the potential implications for national security and financial crime, including an analysis of illicit financing risks, sanctions risks, other law enforcement and national security interests, and implications for human rights; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(vii) &nbsp;an assessment of the effects that the growth of foreign CBDCs may have on United States interests generally.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;The Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Chairman of the Federal Reserve) is encouraged to continue to research and report on the extent to which CBDCs could improve the efficiency and reduce the costs of existing and future payments systems, to continue to assess the optimal form of a United States CBDC, and to develop a strategic plan for Federal Reserve and broader United&nbsp;States Government action, as appropriate, that evaluates the necessary steps and requirements for the potential implementation and launch of a United States CBDC. &nbsp;The Chairman of the Federal Reserve is also encouraged to evaluate the extent to which a United States CBDC, based on the potential design options, could enhance or impede the ability of monetary policy to function effectively as a critical macroeconomic stabilization tool.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Chairman of the Federal Reserve, shall:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;within 180 days of the date of this order, provide to the President through the APNSA and APEP an assessment of whether legislative changes would be necessary to issue a United States CBDC, should it be deemed appropriate and in the national interest; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;within 210 days of the date of this order, provide to the President through the APNSA and the APEP a corresponding legislative proposal, based on consideration of the report submitted by the Secretary of the Treasury under section 4(b) of this order and any materials developed by the Chairman of the Federal Reserve consistent with section 4(c) of this order.<br><br>Sec. 5.&nbsp; Measures to Protect Consumers, Investors, and Businesses.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The increased use of digital assets and digital asset exchanges and trading platforms may increase the risks of crimes such as fraud and theft, other statutory and regulatory violations, privacy and data breaches, unfair and abusive acts or practices, and other cyber incidents faced by consumers, investors, and businesses.&nbsp; The rise in use of digital assets, and differences across communities, may also present disparate financial risk to less informed market participants or exacerbate inequities.&nbsp; It is critical to ensure that digital assets do not pose undue risks to consumers, investors, or businesses, and to put in place protections as a part of efforts to expand access to safe and affordable financial services.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Consistent with the goals stated in section 5(a) of this order:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the heads of other relevant agencies, including, as appropriate, the heads of independent regulatory agencies such as the FTC, the SEC, the CFTC, Federal banking agencies, and the CFPB, shall submit to the President a report, or section of the report required by section&nbsp;4 of this order, on the implications of developments and adoption of digital assets and changes in financial market and payment system infrastructures for United States consumers, investors, businesses, and for equitable economic growth.&nbsp; One section of the report shall address the conditions that would drive mass adoption of different types of digital assets and the risks and opportunities such growth might present to United&nbsp;States consumers, investors, and businesses, including a focus on how technological innovation may impact these efforts and with an eye toward those most vulnerable to disparate impacts.&nbsp; The report shall also include policy recommendations, including potential regulatory and legislative actions, as appropriate, to protect United States consumers, investors, and businesses, and support expanding access to safe and affordable financial services.&nbsp; The report shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the Chief Technology Officer of the United&nbsp;States, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Chairman of the Federal Reserve, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall submit to the President a technical evaluation of the technological infrastructure, capacity, and expertise that would be necessary at relevant agencies to facilitate and support the introduction of a CBDC system should one be proposed.&nbsp; The evaluation should specifically address the technical risks of the various designs, including with respect to emerging and future technological developments, such as quantum computing.&nbsp; The evaluation should also include any reflections or recommendations on how the inclusion of digital assets in Federal processes may affect the work of the United&nbsp;States&nbsp;Government and the provision of Government services, including risks and benefits to cybersecurity, customer experience, and social‑safety‑net programs.&nbsp; The evaluation shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii)&nbsp; &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to the President a report on the role of law enforcement agencies in detecting, investigating, and prosecuting criminal activity related to digital assets.&nbsp; The report shall include any recommendations on regulatory or legislative actions, as appropriate.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;The Attorney General, the Chair of the FTC, and the Director of the CFPB are each encouraged to consider what, if any, effects the growth of digital assets could have on competition policy.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(v)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Chair of the FTC and the Director of the CFPB are each encouraged to consider the extent to which privacy or consumer protection measures within their respective jurisdictions may be used to protect users of digital assets and whether additional measures may be needed.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(vi)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;The Chair of the SEC, the Chairman of the CFTC, the Chairman of the Federal Reserve, the Chairperson of the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Comptroller of the Currency are each encouraged to consider the extent to which investor and market protection measures within their respective jurisdictions may be used to address the risks of digital assets and whether additional measures may be needed.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(vii)&nbsp; &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers, the Assistant to the President and National Climate Advisor, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall submit a report to the President on the connections between distributed ledger technology and short-, medium-, and long-term economic and energy transitions; the potential for these technologies to impede or advance efforts to tackle climate change at home and abroad; and the impacts these technologies have on the environment.&nbsp; This report shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.&nbsp; The report should also address the effect of cryptocurrencies&#8217; consensus mechanisms on energy usage, including research into potential mitigating measures and alternative mechanisms of consensus and the design tradeoffs those may entail.&nbsp; The report should specifically address:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(A)&nbsp; potential uses of blockchain that could support monitoring or mitigating technologies to climate impacts, such as exchanging of liabilities for greenhouse gas emissions, water, and other natural or environmental assets; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(B)&nbsp; implications for energy policy, including as it relates to grid management and reliability, energy efficiency incentives and standards, and sources of energy supply.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(viii)&nbsp; Within 1 year of submission of the report described in section 5(b)(vii) of this order, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall update the report described in section&nbsp;5(b)(vii) of this order, including to address any knowledge gaps identified in such report.<br><br>Sec. 6.&nbsp; Actions to Promote Financial Stability, Mitigate Systemic Risk, and Strengthen Market Integrity.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Financial regulators &#8212; including the SEC, the CFTC, and the CFPB and Federal banking agencies &#8212; play critical roles in establishing and overseeing protections across the financial system that safeguard its integrity and promote its stability.&nbsp; Since 2017, the Secretary of the Treasury has convened the Financial Stability Oversight Council (FSOC) to assess the financial stability risks and regulatory gaps posed by the ongoing adoption of digital assets.&nbsp; The United States must assess and take steps to address risks that digital assets pose to financial stability and financial market integrity.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Within 210 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury should convene the FSOC and produce a report outlining the specific financial stability risks and regulatory gaps posed by various types of digital assets and providing recommendations to address such risks. &nbsp;As the Secretary of the Treasury and the FSOC deem appropriate, the report should consider the particular features of various types of digital assets and include recommendations that address the identified financial stability risks posed by these digital assets, including any proposals for additional or adjusted regulation and supervision as well as for new legislation. &nbsp;The report should take account of the prior analyses and assessments of the FSOC, agencies, and the President&#8217;s Working Group on Financial Markets, including the ongoing work of the Federal banking agencies, as appropriate.<br><br>Sec. 7.&nbsp; Actions to Limit Illicit Finance and Associated National Security Risks.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Digital assets have facilitated sophisticated cybercrime‑related financial networks and activity, including through ransomware activity. &nbsp;The growing use of digital assets in financial activity heightens risks of crimes such as money laundering, terrorist and proliferation financing, fraud and theft schemes, and corruption.&nbsp; These illicit activities highlight the need for ongoing scrutiny of the use of digital assets, the extent to which technological innovation may impact such activities, and exploration of opportunities to mitigate these risks through regulation, supervision, public‑private engagement, oversight, and law enforcement.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Within 90 days of submission to the Congress of the National Strategy for Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of other relevant agencies may each submit to the President supplemental annexes, which may be classified or unclassified, to the Strategy offering additional views on illicit finance risks posed by digital assets, including cryptocurrencies, stablecoins, CBDCs, and trends in the use of digital assets by illicit actors.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;Within 120 days of submission to the Congress of the National Strategy for Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of other relevant agencies shall develop a coordinated action plan based on the Strategy&#8217;s conclusions for mitigating the digital‑asset-related illicit finance and national security risks addressed in the updated strategy.&nbsp; This action plan shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.&nbsp; The action plan shall address the role of law enforcement and measures to increase financial services providers&#8217; compliance with AML/CFT obligations related to digital asset activities.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d)&nbsp; Within 120 days following completion of all of the following reports &#8212; the National Money Laundering Risk Assessment; the National Terrorist Financing Risk Assessment; the National Proliferation Financing Risk Assessment; and the updated National Strategy for Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing &#8212; the Secretary of the Treasury shall notify the relevant agencies through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order on any pending, proposed, or prospective rulemakings to address digital asset illicit finance risks.&nbsp; The Secretary of the Treasury shall consult with and consider the perspectives of relevant agencies in evaluating opportunities to mitigate such risks through regulation.<br><br>Sec. 8.&nbsp; Policy and Actions Related to Fostering International Cooperation and United States Competitiveness.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The policy of my Administration on fostering international cooperation and United States competitiveness with respect to digital assets and financial innovation is as follows:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Technology-driven financial innovation is frequently cross-border and therefore requires international cooperation among public authorities. &nbsp;This cooperation is critical to maintaining high regulatory standards and a level playing field. &nbsp;Uneven regulation, supervision, and compliance across jurisdictions creates opportunities for arbitrage and raises risks to financial stability and the protection of consumers, investors, businesses, and markets. &nbsp;Inadequate AML/CFT regulation, supervision, and enforcement by other countries challenges the ability of the United States to investigate illicit digital asset transaction flows that frequently jump overseas, as is often the case in ransomware payments and other cybercrime-related money laundering.&nbsp; There must also be cooperation to reduce inefficiencies in international funds transfer and payment systems.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;The United States Government has been active in international fora and through bilateral partnerships on many of these issues and has a robust agenda to continue this work in the coming years. &nbsp;While the United States held the position of President of the FATF, the United&nbsp;States led the group in developing and adopting the first international standards on digital assets. &nbsp;The United States must continue to work with international partners on standards for the development and appropriate interoperability of digital payment architectures and CBDCs to reduce payment inefficiencies and ensure that any new funds transfer and payment systems are consistent with United States values and legal requirements.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;While the United States held the position of President of the 2020 G7, the United&nbsp;States established the G7 Digital Payments Experts Group to discuss CBDCs, stablecoins, and other digital payment issues.&nbsp; The G7 report outlining a set of policy principles for CBDCs is an important contribution to establishing guidelines for jurisdictions for the exploration and potential development of CBDCs. &nbsp;While a CBDC would be issued by a country&#8217;s central bank, the supporting infrastructure could involve both public and private participants. &nbsp;The G7 report highlighted that any CBDC should be grounded in the G7&#8217;s long-standing public commitments to transparency, the rule of law, and sound economic governance, as well as the promotion of competition and innovation.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;The United States continues to support the G20 roadmap for addressing challenges and frictions with cross-border funds transfers and payments for which work is underway, including work on improvements to existing systems for cross-border funds transfers and payments, the international dimensions of CBDC designs, and the potential of well-regulated stablecoin arrangements.&nbsp; The international Financial Stability Board (FSB), together with standard-setting bodies, is leading work on issues related to stablecoins, cross‑border funds transfers and payments, and other international dimensions of digital assets and payments, while FATF continues its leadership in setting AML/CFT standards for digital assets. &nbsp;Such international work should continue to address the full spectrum of issues and challenges raised by digital assets, including financial stability, consumer, investor, and business risks, and money laundering, terrorist financing, proliferation financing, sanctions evasion, and other illicit activities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;My Administration will elevate the importance of these topics and expand engagement with our critical international partners, including through fora such as the G7, G20, FATF, and FSB. &nbsp;My Administration will support the ongoing international work and, where appropriate, push for additional work to drive development and implementation of holistic standards, cooperation and coordination, and information sharing.&nbsp; With respect to digital assets, my Administration will seek to ensure that our core democratic values are respected; consumers, investors, and businesses are protected; appropriate global financial system connectivity and platform and architecture interoperability are preserved; and the safety and soundness of the global financial system and international monetary system are maintained.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) In furtherance of the policy stated in section 8(a) of this order:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 120 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall establish a framework for interagency international engagement with foreign counterparts and in international fora to, as appropriate, adapt, update, and enhance adoption of global principles and standards for how digital assets are used and transacted, and to promote development of digital asset and CBDC technologies consistent with our values and legal requirements.&nbsp; This framework shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.&nbsp; This framework shall include specific and prioritized lines of effort and coordinated messaging; interagency engagement and activities with foreign partners, such as foreign assistance and capacity-building efforts and coordination of global compliance; and whole‑of‑government efforts to promote international principles, standards, and best practices.&nbsp; This framework should reflect ongoing leadership by the Secretary of the Treasury and financial regulators in relevant international financial standards bodies, and should elevate United States engagement on digital assets issues in technical standards bodies and other international fora to promote development of digital asset and CBDC technologies consistent with our values.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 1 year of the date of the establishment of the framework required by section 8(b)(i) of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and the heads of other relevant agencies as appropriate, shall submit a report to the President on priority actions taken under the framework and its effectiveness. &nbsp;This report shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall establish a framework for enhancing United States economic competitiveness in, and leveraging of, digital asset technologies.&nbsp; This framework shall be coordinated through the interagency process described in section 3 of this order.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 90 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit a report to the President on how to strengthen international law enforcement cooperation for detecting, investigating, and prosecuting criminal activity related to digital assets.<br><br>Sec. 9.&nbsp; Definitions.&nbsp; For the purposes of this order:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a)&nbsp; The term &#8220;blockchain&#8221; refers to distributed ledger technologies where data is shared across a network that creates a digital ledger of verified transactions or information among network participants and the data are typically linked using cryptography to maintain the integrity of the ledger and execute other functions, including transfer of ownership or value.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The term &#8220;central bank digital currency&#8221; or &#8220;CBDC&#8221; refers to a form of digital money or monetary value, denominated in the national unit of account, that is a direct liability of the central bank.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c)&nbsp; The term &#8220;cryptocurrencies&#8221; refers to a digital asset, which may be a medium of exchange, for which generation or ownership records are supported through a distributed ledger technology that relies on cryptography, such as a blockchain.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d)&nbsp; The term &#8220;digital assets&#8221; refers to all CBDCs, regardless of the technology used, and to other representations of value, financial assets and instruments, or claims that are used to make payments or investments, or to transmit or exchange funds or the equivalent thereof, that are issued or represented in digital form through the use of distributed ledger technology.&nbsp; For example, digital assets include cryptocurrencies, stablecoins, and CBDCs. &nbsp;Regardless of the label used, a digital asset may be, among other things, a security, a commodity, a derivative, or other financial product.&nbsp; Digital assets may be exchanged across digital asset trading platforms, including centralized and decentralized finance platforms, or through peer-to-peer technologies.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e)&nbsp; The term &#8220;stablecoins&#8221; refers to a category of cryptocurrencies with mechanisms that are aimed at maintaining a stable value, such as by pegging the value of the coin to a specific currency, asset, or pool of assets or by algorithmically controlling supply in response to changes in demand in order to stabilize value.<br><br>Sec. 10.&nbsp; General Provisions.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>March 9, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NEC Director Brian Deese and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on New Digital Assets Executive&#160;Order</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/statement-by-nec-director-brian-deese-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-new-digital-assets-executive-order/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to establish the first-ever comprehensive federal digital assets strategy for the United States. The E.O. will help position the U.S. to keep playing a leading role in the innovation and governance of the digital assets ecosystem at home and abroad, in a way that protects consumers, is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to establish the first-ever comprehensive federal digital assets strategy for the United States. The E.O. will help position the U.S. to keep playing a leading role in the innovation and governance of the digital assets ecosystem at home and abroad, in a way that protects consumers, is consistent with our democratic values and advances U.S. global competitiveness.</p>



<p>This E.O. marks an intensification of our efforts to promote responsible innovation in the digital assets space – innovation that works for all Americans, protects our national security interests, and contributes to our economic competitiveness and growth. Fundamentally, an American approach to digital assets is one that encourages innovation but mitigates the risks to consumers, investors, and businesses, broader financial stability, and the environment. We are clear-eyed that “financial innovation” of the past has too often not benefited working families, while exacerbating inequality and increasing systemic financial risk. This history underscores the need to build robust consumer and economic protections into digital asset development.</p>



<p>The approach outlined in the E.O. will reinforce U.S. leadership in the global financial system and safeguard the long-term efficacy of critical national security tools like sanctions and anti-money laundering frameworks. To these ends, the Order identifies the Administration’s policy priorities, both for cryptocurrencies and any future U.S. central bank digital currency, to help guide the evolution of the digital asset ecosystem in a way that is consistent with our values. Governments alone cannot solve these problems, and definitely not a government that operates in siloes. This E.O. is the product of months of work with stakeholders across government, industry, advocacy, academia, and international allies and partners – to identify actions we can take to foster responsible innovation in the digital asset ecosystem. Its implementation will leverage the knowledge and distinct expertise of a broad range of stakeholders across the White House and Executive departments and agencies, and regulatory agencies. We remain committed to working with allies, partners, and the broader digital asset community to shape the future of digital asset systems in a manner that is safe, inclusive, and consistent with our democratic values. As this ecosystem evolves, so too will our approach.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden to Sign Executive Order on Ensuring Responsible Development of Digital&#160;Assets</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-sign-executive-order-on-ensuring-responsible-innovation-in-digital-assets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Outlines First Whole-of-Government Strategy to Protect Consumers, Financial Stability, National Security, and Address Climate Risks Digital assets, including cryptocurrencies, have seen explosive growth in recent years, surpassing a $3 trillion market cap last November and up from $14 billion just five years prior. Surveys suggest that around 16 percent of adult Americans – approximately 40&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Outlines First Whole-of-Government Strategy to Protect Consumers, Financial Stability, National Security, and Address Climate Risks</em></p>



<p>Digital assets, including cryptocurrencies, have seen explosive growth in recent years, surpassing a <a href="https://time.com/6115300/cryptocurrency-value-3-trillion/">$3 trillion</a> market cap last November and up from $14 billion just five years prior. Surveys suggest that around 16 percent of adult Americans – approximately 40 million people – have invested in, traded, or used cryptocurrencies. Over 100 countries are exploring or piloting Central Bank Digital Currencies (CBDCs), a digital form of a country’s sovereign currency.<br><br>The rise in digital assets creates an opportunity to reinforce American leadership in the global financial system and at the technological frontier, but also has substantial implications for consumer protection, financial stability, national security, and climate risk. The United States must maintain technological leadership in this rapidly growing space, supporting innovation while mitigating the risks for consumers, businesses, the broader financial system, and the climate. And, it must play a leading role in international engagement and global governance of digital assets consistent with democratic values and U.S. global competitiveness.<br><br>That is why today, President Biden will sign an Executive Order outlining the first ever, whole-of-government approach to addressing the risks and harnessing the potential benefits of digital assets and their underlying technology. The Order lays out a national policy for digital assets across six key priorities: consumer and investor protection; financial stability; illicit finance; U.S. leadership in the global financial system and economic competitiveness; financial inclusion; and responsible innovation.</p>



<p>Specifically, the Executive Order calls for measures to:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect U.S. Consumers, Investors, and Businesses </strong>by directing the Department of the Treasury and other agency partners to assess and develop policy recommendations to address the implications of the growing digital asset sector and changes in financial markets for consumers, investors, businesses, and equitable economic growth. The Order also encourages regulators to ensure sufficient oversight and safeguard against any systemic financial risks posed by digital assets.<br></li><li><strong>Protect U.S. and Global Financial Stability and Mitigate Systemic Risk </strong>by encouraging the Financial Stability Oversight Council to identify and mitigate economy-wide (i.e., systemic) financial risks posed by digital assets and to develop appropriate policy recommendations to address any regulatory gaps.<br></li><li><strong>Mitigate the Illicit Finance and National Security Risks Posed by the Illicit Use of Digital Assets </strong>by directing an unprecedented focus of coordinated action across all relevant U.S. Government agencies to mitigate these risks. It also directs agencies to work with our allies and partners to ensure international frameworks, capabilities, and partnerships are aligned and responsive to risks.<br></li><li><strong>Promote U.S. Leadership in Technology and Economic Competitiveness to Reinforce U.S. Leadership in the Global Financial System </strong>by directing the Department of Commerce to work across the U.S. Government in establishing a framework to drive U.S. competitiveness and leadership in, and leveraging of digital asset technologies. This framework will serve as a foundation for agencies and integrate this as a priority into their policy, research and development, and operational approaches to digital assets.<br></li><li><strong>Promote Equitable Access to Safe and Affordable Financial Services </strong>by affirming the critical need for safe, affordable, and accessible financial services as a U.S. national interest that must inform our approach to digital asset innovation, including disparate impact risk. Such safe access is especially important for communities that have long had insufficient access to financial services.&nbsp; The Secretary of the Treasury, working with all relevant agencies, will produce a report on the future of money and payment systems, to include implications for economic growth, financial growth and inclusion, national security, and the extent to which technological innovation may influence that future.<br></li><li><strong>Support Technological Advances and Ensure Responsible Development and Use of Digital Assets </strong>by directing the U.S. Government to take concrete steps to study and support technological advances in the responsible development, design, and implementation of digital asset systems while prioritizing privacy, security, combating illicit exploitation, and reducing negative climate impacts.<br></li><li><strong>Explore a U.S. Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC) </strong>by placing urgency on research and development of a potential United States CBDC, should issuance be deemed in the national interest. The Order directs the U.S. Government to assess the technological infrastructure and capacity needs for a potential U.S. CBDC in a manner that protects Americans’ interests. The Order also encourages the Federal Reserve to continue its research, development, and assessment efforts for a U.S. CBDC, including development of a plan for broader U.S. Government action in support of their work. This effort prioritizes U.S. participation in multi-country experimentation, and ensures U.S. leadership internationally to promote CBDC development that is consistent with U.S. priorities and democratic values.</li></ul>



<p>The Administration will continue work across agencies and with Congress to establish policies that guard against risks and guide responsible innovation, with our allies and partners to develop aligned international capabilities that respond to national security risks, and with the private sector to study and support technological advances in digital assets.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden on the Return of American Detainees from&#160;Venezuela</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/08/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-return-of-american-detainees-from-venezuela/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 04:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tonight—two Americans who were wrongfully detained in Venezuela will be able to hug their families once more. We are bringing Gustavo Cardenas and Jorge Fernandez home. Cardenas was arrested in 2017 as part of the so-called CITGO-6, and he has endured five years of hardship and imprisonment at the hands of an unjust system. Fernandez&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Tonight—two Americans who were wrongfully detained in Venezuela will be able to hug their families once more.</p>



<p>We are bringing Gustavo Cardenas and Jorge Fernandez home.</p>



<p>Cardenas was arrested in 2017 as part of the so-called CITGO-6, and he has endured five years of hardship and imprisonment at the hands of an unjust system. Fernandez was arrested last year on spurious charges. These men are fathers who lost precious time with their children and everyone they love, and their families have suffered every day of their absence. I am grateful to Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs Roger Carstens and our entire diplomatic team for their tireless efforts to secure their release and reunite these families.</p>



<p>Unjustly holding Americans captive is always unacceptable. And even as we celebrate the return of Cardenas and Fernandez, we also remember the names and the stories of every American who is being unjustly held against their will—in Venezuela, in Russia, in Afghanistan, Syria, China, Iran, and elsewhere around the world. My Administration will keep fighting to bring them all home.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Supporting Veterans as Part of the Unity&#160;Agenda</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/08/remarks-by-president-biden-on-supporting-veterans-as-part-of-the-unity-agenda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Resource Connection of Tarrant CountyFort Worth, Texas 4:05 P.M. CST    THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; Please, please, sit down.&#160; Thank you.&#160; I don&#8217;t know who’s coming.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160;I want to thank you, Councilwoman Beck.&#160; You know, look, what I said to her on the way out: The thing that bothers me the most when veterans aren’t looked&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Resource Connection of Tarrant County<br>Fort Worth, Texas</p>



<p>4:05 P.M. CST   </p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; Please, please, sit down.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know who’s coming.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank you, Councilwoman Beck.&nbsp; You know, look, what I said to her on the way out: The thing that bothers me the most when veterans aren’t looked out for, because of what we owe them, is every single, solitary veteran deserves to be treated with dignity.&nbsp; They shouldn’t have to ask for a damn thing.&nbsp; It shouldn’t be, “Can you help me?”&nbsp; It’s, “I&#8217;ve got a problem.”&nbsp; And we should say, “How can we help?”<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I thank you for your service.&nbsp; I thank you for all of you who are here for your service.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I hope &#8212; I hope that hearing &#8212; hearing you will inspire more veterans to do exactly what you’re doing: sign up &#8212; sign up for the benefits and support you have earned.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I found with my son, what I found with my friends, what I found with the generation of Vietnam: There’s this notion that you never have to &#8212; you shouldn’t ask for anything.&nbsp; You’re military &#8212; you don’t ask for anything; you just serve.<br>&nbsp;<br>You should be asking.&nbsp; You should be letting us know.&nbsp; You should let us know what is bothering you, what is the problem &#8212; because we owe it to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>It’s great to be here in Fort Worth at the Resource Connection.&nbsp; And I’m able to spend time with Mayor Parker earlier, very briefly.&nbsp; And I want to thank her for the passport into town.&nbsp; And I also want to thank Judge &#8212; Judge Whitley, all &#8212; and all the city and council members &#8212; city council and county council members as well here today.&nbsp; I want to thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I often tell the story: I got elected to the county council in my state. &nbsp;We have a &#8212; we’re like a miniature Illinois.&nbsp; We have one state with 60 percent of the population, so a councilman has a district seven times as big as a House member and three times a big as a state senator.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I did not want to run, but I ran just to show the flag.&nbsp; And, unfortunately, I won.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And they reapportioned me.&nbsp; It was in 1970.&nbsp; I got reapportioned from a four-year term to a two-year term because my &#8212; the opposition party saw more in me than I saw in me.&nbsp; And I was forced into, what we say in public life, “up or out.”&nbsp; And I ended up running for the Senate before I was old enough to be sworn in.&nbsp; I didn’t expect to win that either.&nbsp; And here I am.&nbsp; You’re stuck with me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But &#8212; (applause) &#8212; but the reason I ran for the United States Senate was it was too hard being a county councilman.&nbsp; You’d knock on the door and say, “My name is Joe Biden, Democratic candidate for the county council.”&nbsp; And they’d look at you like &#8212; and you know what they’re thinking.&nbsp; Well, you know part of what they were thinking: “What does county council do?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Well, you affect people’s lives as much as anybody else.&nbsp; And people go, “County council?”<br>&nbsp;<br>Anyway.&nbsp; But I just think that &#8212; Jake, you’re a fighter pilot.&nbsp; You get this stuff.&nbsp; I mean &#8212; you know what I mean.&nbsp; You can smile, Jake.&nbsp; It’s okay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It’s okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Jake is a Republican, but I like the hell out of him.&nbsp; He’s got &#8212; no, I’m serious.&nbsp; This guy is the real deal.<br>&nbsp;<br>The three congressmen you have here &#8212; two of them look like they could &#8212; they really could and did play ball.&nbsp; And the other one looks like he could bomb you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And &#8212; that’s &#8212; it’s a tough group but a good group.<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, I want to thank you and your staffs for welcoming us to town.&nbsp; It’s a one-stop shop connection for people in this county to the services and benefits they need.&nbsp; And that’s important.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’m here today to talk about the critical community it serves: our veterans, their families, caregivers, and survivors.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’m joined today by the bipartisan group of Texas Reps that are here and who care deeply about these issues.&nbsp; Congressman Marc Veasey is &#8212; I want to thank him so much for giving me the passport into his district here.&nbsp; And I want to let them know how proud I am to sign into law the bill to create a national monument to Medal of Honor winners and recipients and the values they represented.&nbsp; It was a very important thing you did.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And, Congressman Colin Allred, I want to thank you for your work in the Veterans Affairs committee in the House of Representatives, particularly your leadership dealing with veterans mental health issues.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Congressman Jake Ellzey, a member of the House Veterans Affairs committee, a veteran himself, served 20 years in the United States Navy and multiple combat tours as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Congressmen, thank you all for being here and for allowing me to be with you and continuing to serve our country.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I’ve often said &#8212; and I mean it sincerely, from the bottom of my heart &#8212; veterans are the backbone, the spine, and sinew of who we are in this country.&nbsp; One percent of you these days &#8212; one percent of you serves all the rest of us.&nbsp; And the 99 percent who aren’t with you deserve to treat you with the dignity and respect in service that you deserve.&nbsp; You’re the best of us, and we owe you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’ve always believed that &#8212; and I’ve said this from the time I was a young senator &#8212; we have many obligations in the United States Senate and the United States Congress, the President of the United States to the American people &#8212; to the elderly, to the poor, to those in need.&nbsp; But we only have one truly sacred obligation, and I mean this &#8212; sacred obligation &#8212; and that is to train and equip those who we send into harm’s way and care for them and their families when they come home.<br>&nbsp;<br>Only a small percentage, as I said, deserve and can claim the title of veteran.&nbsp; More than 1.4 million of them are living here in Texas.&nbsp; That’s about 6.5 percent of your population.&nbsp; And to be a veteran is to have endured the survival &#8212; and survived challenges most Americans will never know.&nbsp; And you have done it, and you’ve done it for all of us.&nbsp; All of us.<br>&nbsp;<br>A week ago, during my State of the Union message in Washington, I spoke about the bipartisan Unity Agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>Four big things that I think all of us &#8212; Democrats, Republicans, and independents &#8212; can agree on and rally around.<br>&nbsp;<br>One is dealing with the opioid epidemic, which is stealing the lives of so many people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Two: mental health for our children in the wake of all that&#8217;s happened because of COVID and all the &#8212; all the consequences.&nbsp; There&#8217;s over a million people out there who are no longer sitting at the kitchen table this morning because of COVID.&nbsp; And people worry about that &#8212; and the kids particularly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Third is ending cancer as we know it, which I&#8217;m confident we can do.<br>&nbsp;<br>And fourth is supporting our veterans &#8212; fully supporting them.<br>&nbsp;<br>These are the issues that unite us because they impact Americans in every single solitary state &#8212; issues that go beyond partisan politics because they’re about people &#8212; about people, our neighbors.<br>&nbsp;<br>Caring for our veterans has been a central focus of my administration since day one.&nbsp; And for the last year, the Department of Veterans Affairs, led by Secretary McDonough, has been the linchpin &#8212; the linchpin of our government-wide push to make life better for American veterans, providing assistance through this pandemic like job training and housing.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re helping lower-income veterans access VA care debt-free.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re expanding access to healthcare services for women veterans and the LGBTQ community veterans.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re implementing a plan to bring down the rate of suicide among service members and veterans.&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s sad to say, but to this day, we average 17 veterans a day commit suicide every single day.&nbsp; More than get killed in combat every single day.&nbsp; It’s an absolute tragedy that demands not only a whole-of-government approach but a whole-of-country working together to deal with this issue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Texas is one of those states particin- &#8212; participating in the Governor&#8217;s and Mayor&#8217;s Challenge to take on this crisis.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as I announced in my State of the Union message, we’re focusing on meeting the specific care and needs for all our veterans who suffer because of their service &#8212; for all our veterans.<br>&nbsp;<br>We learned a horrible lesson after Vietnam.&nbsp; It was harm &#8212; the harmful effects of Agent Orange, which was dropped upon so many thousands of veterans, and the years it took to manifest illnesses in veterans.&nbsp; Because then the veteran had to prove that whatever his problem was was directly a consequence of Agent Orange.<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, we passed a law that I was proud to be a co-sponsor of a long time ago saying that if you were &#8212; if you had Agent Orange drop upon you, it was presumed that the illness you had was a consequence of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And how we were even slower to connect the dots of what&#8217;s happening to those too many Vietnam veterans living in the lurch, unable to access the care they needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>It was only in the past year that we added bladder cancer and conditions of un- &#8212; underactive thyroid and Parkinson&#8217;s to the list of conditions tied to Agent Orange exposure, as science told us more, decades after the exposure took place.<br>&nbsp;<br>It took far too long to reach that decision, in my view.&nbsp; And I refuse to repeat the mistake when it comes to the veterans of our Iraq and Afghans- &#8212; Afghan wars.<br>&nbsp;<br>Not only they &#8212; they faced the dangers on battlefield, but they were breathing toxic smoke in burn pits where they&#8217;re &#8212; near where they were based.&nbsp; I was in and out of Afghanistan and Iraq 23 times.&nbsp; I spent a fair amount of time there as a United States senator and as Vice President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The burn pits that incinerate the wastes of war &#8212; medical and hazardous material, jet fuel, and so much more &#8212; just dug in big pits where &#8212; not far from &#8212; the hooch is not far from where our veterans were sleeping.<br>&nbsp;<br>And when our troops came home, the fittest among them, the greatest fighting force in the history of the world, too many of them were not the same.&nbsp; Headaches, dizziness, numbness, dizziness, cancer.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we know &#8212; we don’t yet know enough about the connection between burn pits and each of these diseases so many of our veterans are now facing.&nbsp; But I’m committed &#8212; I&#8217;m committed that America make the commitment to find out everything we can.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m committed to the families like Danielle Robinson, the widow of Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson, who joined my wife Jill in the Vice Pre- &#8212; in the First Lady&#8217;s box at the State of the Union.<br>&nbsp;<br>Sergeant Robinson was born a soldier.&nbsp; National &#8212; Army National Guard.&nbsp; Combat medic in Kosovo and Iraq.&nbsp; Stationed at the same bases and at around the same exact time as my son Major Beau Biden, United States Army.<br>&nbsp;<br>In Baghdad, Sergeant Robinson was stationed yards from burn pits the size of football fields.<br>&nbsp;<br>And back home in Ohio, Danielle and their little girl waited for him to come home &#8212; to coach the soccer team, to build Legos.&nbsp; But when he finally came home, cancer &#8212; likely caused by prolonged exposure to the burn pits &#8212; ravaged his lungs and his body.<br>&nbsp;<br>A soldier who could bench press 315 pounds, squat 400 pounds, and run two miles in 12 minutes would be bent over in the bathroom, gasping for air.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Danielle, working full-time, turned to become a 24/7 caregiver, scared to leave him alone for even a minute.<br>&nbsp;<br>He was just 39 years old when he was held &#8212; she held his hand as he took his last breath.<br>&nbsp;<br>But Daniel [sic] said he &#8212; Danielle said he never stopped fighting and neither did she.&nbsp; She kept fighting for his memory, in his memory &#8212; for our veterans and their families that are going through the same thing today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Families like hers, like so many of yours &#8212; you’re the reason why we’re doing everything we can.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ve increased funding for VA research to study the health effects of toxic exposure in the military.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re speeding up the process to identify and address adverse impacts of military-related environmental exposures.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re following the science in every case, but we’re also not going to force veterans to suffer in limbo for decades if the science is eve- &#8212; even if it&#8217;s evenly divided.<br>&nbsp;<br>When the evidence doesn’t give a clear answer one way or another, the decision we should favor is caring for veterans while we continue working to learn more &#8212; not waiting, not waiting.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I directed &#8212; I directed the VA to move quickly to review more of the cancers and provide determinations of whether or not they are presumed to be service-connected within 90 days.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, by the way, you saw what happened in the &#8212; what happened when &#8212; at 9/11 when the buildings went down in New York.&nbsp; You saw the thousands of firefighters who, in fact, were &#8212; because of the toxic smoke they inhaled &#8212; finally, finally, because of some of the people in the media and in entertainment insisted that they be compensated for.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, when diseases are so rare that there isn’t enough evidence, we’ll examine other factors as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>And this week, Secretary McDonough is developing a new rule that will add several rare respiratory cancers to the list of presumptive conditions for certain veterans.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also need to know more about which of our veterans may have been exposed to burn pits in the first place or other environmental toxins during their service, to record possible exposures before service members separate from the military.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we’re building a more comprehensive database from the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs to use to track access to exposures.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’re working hard to educate everyone across the VA system about the potential impact of specialized care needed for burn pit exposure, urging veterans to sign up for the VA burn pit registry and to make sure we know about them &#8212; they know about the benefits that may be available to them.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, what I’ve found about veterans as we worked for those who are trying to deal with the mental health problems, is they’re used to always giving &#8212; you don’t think you have a right to ask for anything.&nbsp; You don’t think you have a right to ask.&nbsp; We’re asking you &#8212; asking you to tell us.&nbsp; Tell us where you’ve been.&nbsp; Tell us what your needs are.&nbsp; It&#8217;s nothing to be ashamed of; it’s to be proud of.&nbsp; We owe you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Improving training for VA providers to make sure they’re equipped to diagnose and treat exposures to related conditions.<br>&nbsp;<br>And this year, launching a new wo- &#8212; network of special care &#8212; specialized care providers and call centers to help connect veterans with questions about exposure to care that is consistent, comprehensive, and high quality.<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, these are the kinds of steps that can make a difference in getting the proper care for more patients and providing support for veterans, especially those facing a cancer diagnosis.<br>&nbsp;<br>And every one of you know the earlier cancer is diagnosed, the greater the prospect of dealing with it, the greater the pa- &#8212; the prospect of curing it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It reinforces the new goal of my Cancer Moonshot to cut cancer deaths &#8212; the death rate by 50 percent over the next 25 years at a minimum, to create a more supportive experience for all the patients and families.<br>&nbsp;<br>Secretary McDonough is part of my newly formed Cancer Cabinet.&nbsp; The Department of Veterans Affairs is an essential part of our whole-of-government initiative because we’re going to invest billions of dollars solving this problem &#8212; to turn cancers from death sentences into treatable diseases.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These are all things my administration is moving on.&nbsp; We’re not waiting.&nbsp; We’re not waiting.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But some of the most important next steps need congressional action.&nbsp; Both the United States House of Representatives and the Senate have bills in motion that would extend the eligibility period for VA care for burn pit-related health impacts from 5 years after leaving the military to a minimum of 10 years.&nbsp; That would open enrollment to all veterans who served in Iraq and Afghanistan.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, in February, the Senate passed their bill to do just that, unanimously &#8212; Democrat and Republican.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the House bill that passed just last week would do even more: expanding healthcare, mandating research, reforming the process for determining presumptions, and adding more conditions to the list of presumptive care.<br>&nbsp;<br>Both these bills have bipartisan support.&nbsp; These are bills that unite the American people.&nbsp; These are the bills that will deliver necessary care for our veterans and their families.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let’s get those bills to my desk so I can sign them immediately &#8212; immediately.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, we have a sacred obligation as a nation.<br>&nbsp;<br>I promised Danielle Robinson and I promise all of you here today that we’ll do better.&nbsp; We must.&nbsp; We owe you.&nbsp; We owe you.<br>&nbsp;<br>I can&#8217;t say enough about the veterans community.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a famous expression by a famous English poet who said, “They also serve who only stand and wait.”<br>&nbsp;<br>To every husband and wife of the deployed &#8212; of the deployed husband or wife, to every child with a mom or dad deployed: We owe you.&nbsp; We owe you, because they also serve who only stand and wait.<br>&nbsp;<br>I remember the head of the National Guard in the State of Delaware wife used to say a prayer.&nbsp; When my son got deployed &#8212; my wife was a school teacher who got up earlier than I did to get to school.&nbsp; I&#8217;d get to the train &#8212; the 7:30 train.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d walk downstairs.&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t be &#8212; I&#8217;d just be &#8212; I’d just had shaved and have my trousers on to get a cup of coffee.&nbsp; She&#8217;d be standing over the sink, like many of you have done, looking out the window mouthing a prayer that she was given by the commander’s wife &#8212; a prayer &#8212; a prayer for her son who was in harm’s way.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>All of you did that.&nbsp; All of you do that.&nbsp; All of you worry about that call.&nbsp; So, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Concluding point I’ll make &#8212; and we talked about it, the Congressman and I, on the way down: You know, this is an incredible generation &#8212; the 9/11 generation that fought.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They served in a way, I think, that maybe they&#8217;re right up there with the Greatest Generation, because they not only got deployed once, but sometimes twice, three, four times into harm’s way.&nbsp; They&#8217;d come home and go back, and after knowing that they cleaned off the blood of the seat of that up-armored Humvee that they &#8212; where they lost somebody.&nbsp; And they’d have to saddle up and go back out again.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>An enormous generation.&nbsp; An incredible generation.<br>&nbsp;<br>I was telling the guys on the way down I remember flying into Iraq one of those times, and I went up in the cop- &#8212; the cockpit.&nbsp; And there were, I believe, seven members &#8212; six members: five men and one women &#8212; one woman.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I asked the question of all of them.&nbsp; I said, “How many is this your first tour of duty?”&nbsp; Nobody raised their hand.&nbsp; “Second tour of duty?”&nbsp; Nobody.&nbsp; “Third tour?”&nbsp; Two of them.&nbsp; “Fourth tour?”&nbsp; Two of them.&nbsp; “Fifth tour?”&nbsp; One.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>No other generation has been deployed, redeployed, and redeployed, and redeployed.&nbsp; It takes nothing away from the World War One and World War Two and Vietnam generations.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s one thing to serve and come home and then go back, and go back, and go back.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we owe you.&nbsp; We owe you all, every veteran in here and every family member of a veteran.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops. Thank you for all you do.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>4:25 P.M. CST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Shooting at East High&#160;School</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/08/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-shooting-at-east-high-school/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48683</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday afternoon, as the school day was coming to a close, three students were shot in a drive-by shooting outside East High School in Des Moines, Iowa. One young man—just 15 years old—was tragically killed. Jill and I pray for his family and for everyone impacted by yet another senseless act of gun violence. A&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday afternoon, as the school day was coming to a close, three students were shot in a drive-by shooting outside East High School in Des Moines, Iowa. One young man—just 15 years old—was tragically killed. Jill and I pray for his family and for everyone impacted by yet another senseless act of gun violence.</p>



<p>A half dozen suspects have been arrested for their alleged involvement in the shooting, and we are grateful to Des Moines law enforcement and first responders for their quick work and professionalism.</p>



<p>But these swift arrests cannot obscure the reality that too many families have had to bury a piece of their soul after yet another tragic shooting. It comes less than a month after we marked four years since the shooting at Marjorie Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida, and three months after the shooting at Oxford High School in Oakland County, Michigan. Between these tragedies are shootings that happen every day without making headlines.</p>



<p>Enough. Our young people should be safe in and around school, in their neighborhoods, and in their homes. Every American should be able to visit a house of worship, a grocery store, a night club, or any other place without fear of being gunned down. That too many cannot is a stain on our national character and an urgent call to action.</p>



<p>Last June, I put forward a comprehensive national strategy to reduce gun violence. In carrying out this strategy, I have taken more executive action to reduce gun violence than any other president in their first year in office—more than a dozen necessary actions, from cracking down on gun trafficking and rogue gun dealers, to promoting safe firearm storage, to reining in the proliferation of hard-to-trace “ghost guns” that can be bought online and made at home.  Now, Congress must do its job. As I reiterated in my State of the Union address last week, it is up to Congress to pass proven measures to reduce gun violence—including universal background checks, a ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, and a repeal of the liability shield protecting gun manufacturers who knowingly put weapons of war on our streets. These laws don’t infringe on the Second Amendment, but they will save lives.<br>May God bless the lives that have been lost or forever altered.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden After Air Force One&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/08/remarks-by-president-biden-after-air-force-one-arrival-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 22:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Naval Air Station Fort Worth Joint Reserve BaseWestworth Village, Texas &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, do you have a message for the American people on gas prices? &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; They&#8217;re going to go up.&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; What can you do about it? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Can&#8217;t do much right now. &#160;Russia is responsible.  END]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Naval Air Station Fort Worth Joint Reserve Base<br>Westworth Village, Texas</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you have a message for the American people on gas prices?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to go up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What can you do about it?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Can&#8217;t do much right now. &nbsp;Russia is responsible.</p>



<p> END</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology Anne Neuberger on President&#160;Biden’s Cyber Executive&#160;Order</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/08/statement-by-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-cyber-and-emerging-technology-anne-neuberger-on-president-bidens-cyber-executive-order/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 22:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48671</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President’s Executive Order, Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity, charted a new course for nation’s cybersecurity. And, we have begun implementation of one of the most important components of the Executive Order. As of yesterday, every company that sells software to the government must have a rigorous software security program in place.&#160;The requirement covers traditional commercial&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President’s Executive Order, <em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/12/fact-sheet-president-signs-executive-order-charting-new-course-to-improve-the-nations-cybersecurity-and-protect-federal-government-networks/">Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity</a></em>, charted a new course for nation’s cybersecurity. And, we have begun implementation of one of the most important components of the Executive Order. As of yesterday, every company that sells software to the government must have a rigorous software security program in place.&nbsp;The requirement covers traditional commercial on-premise software, software provided as a service, as well as any included open source software components.</p>



<p>We know Americans are concerned about cybersecurity – we’ve seen the cost of ransomware attacks to businesses of all sizes and the disruption it has caused to critical services in countries around the world. And we know that a foundational part of building cyber resilience is building in security throughout the lifecycle of a product, from the initial design phase through deployment. We buy a car with pre-installed seatbelts and airbags. We should be able to buy software with security baked in. With the implementation of this component of the Executive Order, the federal government is leveraging its procurement power to improve the security of the software that we all use – including software we install in some of our nation’s most critical infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We thank NIST and our private sector partners for their collaboration to develop the Secure Software Development Framework (SSDF) which NIST published last month.&nbsp;The SSDF contains a set of practices that create the foundation for developing secure software, which every company that sells software to the government must now follow. We also thank OMB for working with the private sector over the next 60 days to outline guidance for how companies will attest their compliance with the SSDF, as they sell software to the United States Government.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
