<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 22:50:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris at a Reception to Celebrate AANHPI Heritage&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/17/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-at-a-reception-to-celebrate-aanhpi-heritage-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 22:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rose Garden 4:23 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Ambassador Tai.&#160; It is true, there is something we all know: that we must always honor the mothers, the aunties, the chithis, all of them.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And, of course, the husbands and the fathers and the grandfathers.&#160; (Laughter.) It is good to be with everyone.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rose Garden</p>



<p>4:23 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Ambassador Tai.&nbsp; It is true, there is something we all know: that we must always honor the mothers, the aunties, the <em>chithis</em>, all of them.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And, of course, the husbands and the fathers and the grandfathers.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>It is good to be with everyone.&nbsp; I think this is, Mr. President, one of the biggest groups that we&#8217;ve had since we&#8217;ve been in office, and it&#8217;s quite a beautiful sight to see.</p>



<p>So good afternoon to everyone.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>And as you all know, my mother arrived in the United States at the age of 19, from India.&nbsp; And when I think about the work that we are all doing, the work we are doing as an administration, led by our President, in terms of not only living the values but standing on the shoulders of so many who imagined that we would all be here and who know that when we talk about the beauty of who we are as a nation, as the United States of America, it is represented by all of the people who are here today and all those who are proud that we stand here today together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Joe Biden, Dr. Jill Biden, Mr. Second Gentleman &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and members of our Cabinet, it is good again to be gathered with all of you today and to be joined by the members of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a former member of the caucus, I will take a few moments to talk about a friend to so many of us, a mentor to so many of us, one who helped found CAPAC and became its first chair.&nbsp; And, of course, I&#8217;m talking about the amazing Secretary Norman Mineta, who devoted his career to public service.</p>



<p>For all of those who knew Norm, he worked tirelessly to make our nation stronger, safer, and more just.&nbsp; And in so doing, he inspired a generation of leaders, including me.</p>



<p>Secretary Mineta’s family is here with us today.&nbsp; And from my family to yours, please know that he is deeply missed.</p>



<p>Today, yes, it is a great celebration for so many reasons of so many things.&nbsp; But it is also impossible to ignore that we gather mere days after a horrific act of hate in Buffalo, New York, targeting Black Americans.</p>



<p>And, you know, it was only last year, as the Ambassador said &#8212; only last year that we &#8212; that I was with the President in Atlanta, mourning the murder of eight people, including six who were Asian American women.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, sadly, what I said then remains true now: Racism is real in America. &nbsp;It has always been.&nbsp; Xenophobia is real in America. &nbsp;It has always been.&nbsp; Sexism too.</p>



<p>I said last year and I sadly say again today: We have had people in positions of incredible power in our country scapegoating, people with the biggest pulpits spreading this kind of hate.</p>



<p>This requires &#8212; these moments &#8212; sadly, tragically require us to ask, “Who are we as a nation?&nbsp; And what do we stand for?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is yet again a moment to remember and talk about and reflect on how we treat people and do we live to the greatest and best of our ideals, which means treating people &#8212; all people &#8212; with dignity and respect, remembering the history of our nation and who built our nation and honoring the diversity of all who have contributed to who we are today.</p>



<p>And, of course, that is what this month requires us to do.&nbsp; And I know, looking around at the leaders here, we remember it every day of the year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we also know in tragic moments like this that we are committed collectively to saying: A harm against any one of us, is a harm against all of us, and it is all harm against our nation.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And the President and I, and all of us as leaders, will not be silent.&nbsp; We will not stand by.&nbsp; We must always speak out against violence, against hate crime and discrimination, whenever and wherever it occurs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we must do everything in our power to end this epidemic of hate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We feel great pride, based on good reason and fact and history, in what we celebrate today.&nbsp; And we know that those who allowed us to be here, and paved the path for us to be present at this moment, expect great things from us, including that we are not only clear-eyed but that we are optimistic about our future &#8212; collectively about our future as a nation.&nbsp; That we remain committed to the ideals that make this nation great.&nbsp; That we remain committed to the notion that a harm against any one of us is a harm against all of us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that is an extension of a most profound belief, which is that we are in this together as one nation undivided.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So today we celebrate all those ideals when we celebrate the great people of this nation who have paved a path for so many of us to be where we are today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, finally, to quote then a great American, Norm Mineta &#8212; I quote: “If we will act together, then we are strong enough to withstand any evil, internal or external, that threatens to unravel” &#8212; and this is key &#8212; “this beautiful tapestry that is America.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now it is my great honor to introduce a man who ran for President because he knows that no one should be in this fight alone: President Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You’ve got to admit, I have got good taste in picking people, don’t you?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Way above my pay grade.</p>



<p>Kamala, thank you, and Ambassador Tai; and Doug, the Second Gentleman, out there hiding behind everybody out there, I know. (Laughter).&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, Jill and I are honored to welcome all of you here to celebrate the Asian American, Native Hawaiian, Pacific Islander Heritage Month here in the Rose Garden.</p>



<p>You know, it’s wonderful to see so many friends: U.S. Senator Mazie Hirono.&nbsp; Where &#8212; where’s Mazie?&nbsp; I see &#8212; was told she’s here.&nbsp; I’m looking.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;Mazie, wherever you are, you’re the best.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Tammy Duckworth.&nbsp; Tammy &#8212; Tammy is here, I’m told.&nbsp; Or &#8212; (applause) &#8212; going to be here.&nbsp; No?&nbsp; Any rate &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the Chair of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus, Representative Judy Chu, is here as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there’s several other representatives here today who represent the community in Congress that is growing each election.</p>



<p>As Katherine mentioned, I’m proud to have re-established</p>



<p>the White House Initiative on Asian American, Native Ameri- &#8212; Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islanders.&nbsp; Several members are here today along with members of the community across the administration at every level.</p>



<p>Also joining are mayors and local leaders, and leaders of business and philanthropy, leaders of civil rights, the arts, the fashions and culture.</p>



<p>And this is a reception that follows on the &#8212; the great honor Jill and I, Kamala and Doug had in hosting Team USA, including the Amer- &#8212; the Asian American athletes who so honorably represented America in the Olympics.</p>



<p>Not too long ago, that included one of the most decorated &#8212; the most decorated figure skater in U.S. history &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and also worked on my campaign &#8212; also worked on my campaign and is now my nominee to be Ambassador to Belize: Michelle Kwan.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Michelle, you’re the best, kid.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You’re the best.&nbsp; You do things backward better than most people can do them forward.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you represent a simple truth: There is no single Asian Am- &#8212; as Jill pointed out much more articulately than I have &#8212; there is no single Asian American, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander identity.&nbsp; It doesn’t exist.&nbsp; The diversity of cultures, the breadth and achievement that has shaded and shaped so many, strengthened the fabric of this country in ways that you can’t measure.&nbsp; I don’t think &#8212; I don’t know how you can measure it.</p>



<p>The fastest-growing demographic in the United States that has also gotten us through the pandemic as frontline and essential workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you have powered our economic recovery: An unemployment rate in a community that’s fallen from 6.6 percent since we got in office to 3.1 percent &#8212; for Asian Americans.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Entrepreneurship in the community has risen &#8212; with you all, it’s risen the fastest rate in over a decade.</p>



<p>Where members of the community were once tokenized as villains on the movie screens, you now light them up as superheroes.</p>



<p>And today, I’ll be traveling &#8212; on Thursday, excuse me, I’ll be traveling to the Republic of Korea and Japan to affirm the importance of our Indo-Pacific alliances.&nbsp; Folks &#8212; and to celebrate the indispensable partnerships that are strengthening by the deep family ties and heritage and the values reflected in the AAN- &#8212; NH &#8212; PI &#8212; aye, aye, aye, aye, aye &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; community here in the United States.&nbsp; As they say in Claymont, Delaware, “All youse guys.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But, look, we know that for the generations of progress, racism, harassment, and hate crimes persist, as was pointed out by my friends behind me.&nbsp; And today we know that maybe you are one of them who don’t feel safe walking American streets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A shooting near Atlanta a year ago is still fresh, as been mentioned, in the hearts of so many.&nbsp; And Kamala and I went to vi- &#8212; down to visit.&nbsp; Just as we’ve seen hate crime shootings in Orange County, California; Dallas, Texas, just last week.</p>



<p>Jill and I just got back from Buffalo &#8212; Buffalo, New York &#8212; where another lone gunman with a hate-filled soul shot and killed Black people at a grocery store on a Saturday afternoon.</p>



<p>You know, I probably shouldn’t be saying this now, but I’m going to say it anyway: We have to not only talk about how we’re going to end the hate, but who’s responsible for generating it.&nbsp; Who is responsible for generating it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, I’ve said many times: Hate can have no safe harbor in America.&nbsp; And every person deserves to be treated with dignity and respect.</p>



<p>But, you know, you have folks on television stations talking about the “replacement theory,” scaring the living hell out of people who don’t have a whole lot of emotional stability, taking advantage of &#8212; on the Internet and other means by talking about how we’re going to be “overtaken.”<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why, one year ago, with the help of many of you, I signed into law the bipartisan COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act.&nbsp; And with your continued help &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, with your continued help &#8212; our commitment to advance equality across the board in everything from healthcare, to education, to housing, to LGBTQ rights.</p>



<p>Look, we&#8217;re working to fix our immigration system to reflect our values and the truth that legal immigration defines who we are as a nation &#8212; who we are as a nation.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re so darn strong.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bottom line is we&#8217;re doing the work to make real the promise of America for every American &#8212; a promise that holds that every person is created equal and deserves to be treated equally throughout their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve never fully lived up to that promise, but we&#8217;ve never, ever before walked away from it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never walked away from it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we acknowledge during this month: building a legacy of strength and resilience for people like you and almost all of our forebears.</p>



<p>You know, you were telling the story &#8212; Jill is going to get mad at me for &#8212; it reminded me.&nbsp; I happen to be Irish.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; That’s the problem sometimes with Jill.&nbsp; But anyway, I&#8217;m only joking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; That’s not true.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m teasing.&nbsp; But my mother used to always say on birthdays, “The mother should get the gift, not the child.”&nbsp; So I didn&#8217;t realize it was both Asian and Irish &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; at least in my house.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And speaking of friends, the late Norm Mineta, whom Kamala just spoke about, was one of my close friends &#8212; for real.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you all know, Norm was born in 1931 in San Jose, California, an immigrant &#8212; to immigrant parents from Japan.&nbsp; As an 11-year-old, he spent three years in an incarceration camp, among 120,000 Japanese Americans across the country.</p>



<p>But with every reason to be angry and resentful &#8212; with every reason to be angry and resentful, Norm chose to believe in himself, to believe in America, and to believe in his country.</p>



<p>He served in the United States Army, elected the first Asian American mayor of a major city in his hometown of San Jose.&nbsp; Elected and served two decades as a congressman.&nbsp; We were &#8212; we spent a lot of time together and traveled together, serving with pioneers and dear friends like Danny Inouye and Danny Akaka.&nbsp; They both taught me, by the way, not only about Asian Americans, they taught me that it is “Native Americans,” not “Indian Tribes.”&nbsp; “Native Americans.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Danny was the first guy &#8212; I don’t want to ruin his reputation, God bless his soul &#8212; but Danny was the first guy to convince me to run for president and be my national campaign chairman.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then Norm became the first American of Asian descent to serve as a Cabinet Secretary.&nbsp; Norm passed away earlier this month, as we all know.&nbsp; In the days after, I signed a bill into law naming the U.S. Department of Transportation headquarters in his honor.</p>



<p>Today, we’re honored to be joined by two of his sons, David and Bob.&nbsp; Where are you guys?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Come up here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’re a good man &#8212; you’re both good men.&nbsp; Thank you very, very much.&nbsp; And I want to tell you, he was one of hell of a man.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let’s all follow in the power of Norm’s example.</p>



<p>I thank you all for being here, and I want you to enjoy the rest of the reception.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember, though: This fight that we’re &#8212; for equality, we&#8217;re just starting here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just the wackos who go out there with those guns and get talked into doing something.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the people who fill their brains with false ideas.&nbsp; It’s the people who make them &#8212; convince them, for their power and their prestige and their money, to be able to go out and do these terrible things.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s not who we are.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not who we are.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll be darned, as long as I&#8217;m President of the United States, I&#8217;m going to fight like hell, and we&#8217;re going to expose everybody.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to make sure that this &#8212;</p>



<p>And my &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s a hymn in my &#8212; based on the 91st Psalm, and it says &#8212; in my church &#8212; “May He raise you up on Eagle&#8217;s wings and Bear you on the breath of dawn, and let the sun shine upon you until…”&nbsp; And then it goes on to talk about that we all &#8212; all &#8212; that God will hold you in the palm of his hand.</p>



<p>That’s how we’ve got to think about our fellow Americans.&nbsp; The reason we are strong, the reason we’re who we are is because we’re diverse with so many talents.&nbsp; So many.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know this group will never forget it.&nbsp; But I’m going to spend the rest of my term and as long I’m in office reminding the rest of America they should understand it too.</p>



<p>God bless you all, and enjoy the night &#8212; the day.&nbsp; And thank you for being here.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;</p>



<p>4:41 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to&#160;the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 21:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Andrew G. Biggs, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2024, vice Lanhee J. Chen, term expired. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Stacy Lynn Dean, of the District of Columbia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Andrew G. Biggs, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2024, vice Lanhee J. Chen, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Stacy Lynn Dean, of the District of Columbia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services, vice Kevin W. Concannon.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Alexis Taylor, of Iowa, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Trade and Foreign Agricultural Affairs, vice Ted McKinney.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Calvin Smyre, of Georgia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Commonwealth of The Bahamas.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; David Pressman, of New York, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Hungary.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Heide B. Fulton, of West Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Oriental Republic of Uruguay.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yohannes Abraham, of Virginia, to be Representative of the United States of America to the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Alice Hill, of the District of Columbia, to be Deputy Administrator for Resilience, Federal Emergency Management Agency, Department of Homeland Security, vice Daniel J. Kaniewski, which was sent to the Senate on February 7, 2022.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Calvin Smyre, of Georgia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Dominican Republic, which was sent to the Senate on October 4, 2021.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; William J. Valdez, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security, vice Claire M. Grady, which was sent to the Senate on July 28, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vice President Harris’s Meeting with Prime Minister Mitsotakis of&#160;Greece</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-prime-minister-mitsotakis-of-greece/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis of Greece following his address to a joint meeting of Congress.  The Vice President offered her congratulations on Greece’s 201 years of independence and reaffirmed the strong alliance between the United States and Greece, as well as our shared commitment to democratic values, international&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis of Greece following his address to a joint meeting of Congress.  The Vice President offered her congratulations on Greece’s 201 years of independence and reaffirmed the strong alliance between the United States and Greece, as well as our shared commitment to democratic values, international norms, and the rule of law.  She also thanked the Prime Minister for Greece’s robust support to Ukraine and solidarity in the face of Russian aggression and for Greece’s contributions to Europe’s efforts to diversify its energy supplies. The two leaders also discussed security issues in the Eastern Mediterranean and wider Middle East.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and First Lady Biden Honoring the Lives Lost in Buffalo, New York, and Calling on All Americans to Condemn White&#160;Supremacy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/17/remarks-by-president-biden-and-first-lady-biden-honoring-the-lives-lost-in-buffalo-new-york-and-calling-on-all-americans-to-condemn-white-supremacy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 20:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Delavan Grider Community CenterBuffalo, New York 12:21 P.M. EDT THE FIRST LADY:&#160; I just wanted to say thank you to the families for opening up your hearts to us and for letting us be with you today.&#160; So God bless you, and thank you for allowing us to be with you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; (Applause.) THE&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Delavan Grider Community Center<br>Buffalo, New York</p>



<p>12:21 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; I just wanted to say thank you to the families for opening up your hearts to us and for letting us be with you today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So God bless you, and thank you for allowing us to be with you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; To Majority Leader &#8212; Leader Schumer and Senator Gillibrand and Congressman Higgins.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, Gov, thank you for taking my call when I called.&nbsp; And I’ll never forget what she said.&nbsp; I said, “I’d like to maybe come up if it’s okay.”&nbsp; She said, “This is a big Scranton.&nbsp; Come.&nbsp; Come.”&nbsp; And I think you’re doing a heck of a job.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for your heart as well as your head.</p>



<p>And, Mayor Brown, you’ve been a &#8212; you’ve been wonderful.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And I know this is a lot of &#8212; when a vice presidential or a presidential trip shows up, it&#8217;s &#8212; there’s all kinds of paraphernalia and people, and I know it&#8217;s not easy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank your law enforcement officers for not just what they did in this crisis, but for accommodating us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all the elected officials, and law enforcement officers, first responders, and faith leaders that are here today: Jill and I have come to stand with you.</p>



<p>And to the families: We’ve come here to grieve with you.&nbsp; It’s not the same, but we know a little bit of what’s like to lose a piece of your soul when you lose a son, a daughter, a husband, a wife, a mother, a father.&nbsp; The feeling of having that &#8212; as I said to some of you when we talked privately: You feel like there’s a black hole in your chest you’re being sucked into and you’re suffocating, unable to &#8212; unable to breath.&nbsp; That’s what it felt like, at least to us.&nbsp; And I’m sure some version of that &#8212; it feels that way to you.&nbsp; The anger.&nbsp; The pain.&nbsp; The depth of a loss that’s so profound.</p>



<p>You know, we know it’s hard to believe, and you’re probably not going to believe it, but I can tell you now from our personal experience and many others who we’ve met: The day is going to come &#8212; it will come &#8212; when your loved one brings a smile as you remember him or her &#8212; as you remember her; it’s going to bring a smile to your lip before it brings a tear to your eye.&nbsp; It takes a while for that to happen.&nbsp; It takes a while.&nbsp; It might take more than a season, but our prayer for you is that time comes sooner or later, but I promise you it will come.</p>



<p>As a nation, I say to the families: We remember them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve been reading about them.&nbsp; We visited the memorial where &#8212; the show of the love for them, and you’ve all shown, by the supermarket.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Celestine Chaney, 65 years old.&nbsp; Brain cancer survivor.&nbsp; Churchgoer.&nbsp; Bingo player.&nbsp; Went to buy strawberries to make her favorite shortcake.&nbsp; A loving mother and a grandmother.</p>



<p>Roberta Drury, 32.&nbsp; Beloved daughter and sister.&nbsp; Moved back home to help take care of her brother after his bone marrow transplant.&nbsp; She went to buy groceries for dinner.&nbsp; The center of attention who made everyone in the room laugh and smile when she walked in.</p>



<p>Andrei Mackneil &#8212; excuse me, Andre Mackneil, 53.&nbsp; Worked at a restaurant.&nbsp; Went to buy his three-year-old son a birthday cake.&nbsp; His son <s>celing</s> [celebrating] a birthday, asking, “Where is Daddy?”</p>



<p>Katherine Massey, 72.&nbsp; A writer and an advocate who dressed up in costumes at schools and cut the grass in the park</p>



<p>and helping local elections.&nbsp; The glue of the family and the community.</p>



<p>Margus Morrison, 52.&nbsp; School bus aide.&nbsp; Went to buy snacks for weekly movie night with the family.&nbsp; Survived by his wife and three children and his stepdaughter.&nbsp; The center of their world.</p>



<p>Heyward Patterson, 67.&nbsp; Father.&nbsp; Church deacon.&nbsp; Fed the homeless at the soup kitchen.&nbsp; Gave rides to the grocery store to neighbors who needed help.&nbsp; Putting food in the trunk of others when he took his final breath.</p>



<p>Aaron Salter, 55.  Retired Buffalo police officer for three decades.  Three decades.  Loved electric cars.  A hero who gave his life to save others on a Saturday afternoon.  And had that man not been wearing that vest that he purchased &#8212; bulletproof vest &#8212; a lot of lives would have been saved.  A beloved father and husband.</p>



<p>Geraldine Talley, 62.&nbsp; Expert <s>banker</s> [baker].&nbsp; And known for her warm, gentle personality.&nbsp; A friend to everybody.&nbsp; Devoted mother and grandmother.</p>



<p>Ruth Whitfield, 88.  Beloved wife, mother, grandmother, great-grandmother who sang in the church choir.  A caretaker of her husband, bringing him clean clothes, cutting his hair, holding his hand every day she visited him in the nursing home.  Heart as big as her head.</p>



<p>Pearl Young, 77.&nbsp; A mother, grandmother, missionary of God.&nbsp; Public school teacher who also ran a local food pantry.&nbsp; Loved singing, dancing, and her family.</p>



<p>And all three are injured: Zaire Goodman, 20.&nbsp; Shot in the neck but fighting through it.&nbsp; Jennifer Warrington, 50.&nbsp; Christopher Braden, 55.&nbsp; Both treated with injuries, on a long road to recovery.</p>



<p>Individual lives of love, service, and community that speaks to the bigger story of who we are as Americans.&nbsp; A great nation because we’re a good people.</p>



<p>Jill and I bring you this message from deep in our nation’s soul: In America, evil will not win &#8212; I promise you.&nbsp; Hate will not prevail. &nbsp;And white supremacy will not have the last word.</p>



<p>For the evil did come to Buffalo, and it’s come to all too many places, manifested in gunmen who massacred innocent people in the name of hateful and perverse ideology rooted in fear and racism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s taken so much. &nbsp;Ten lives cut short in a grocery store, three other wounded &#8212; three other wounded by a hate-filled individual who had driven 200 miles from Binghamton &#8212; in that range &#8212; to carry out a murderous, racist rampage that he would livestream &#8212; livestream to the world.</p>



<p>What happened here is simple and straightforward: terrorism.&nbsp; Terrorism.&nbsp; Domestic terrorism.&nbsp; Violence inflicted in the service of hate and a vicious thirst for power that defines one group of people being inherently inferior to any other group.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A hate that through the media and politics, the Internet, has radicalized angry, alienated, lost, and isolated individuals into falsely believing that they will be replaced &#8212; that’s the word, “replaced” &#8212; by the “other” &#8212; by people who don’t look like them and who are therefore, in a perverse ideology that they possess and being fed, lesser beings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I and all of you reject the lie.&nbsp; I call on all Americans to reject the lie.&nbsp; And I condemn those who spread the lie for power, political gain, and for profit.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Because that’s what it is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have now seen too many times the deadly and destructive violence this ideology unleashes.</p>



<p>We heard the chants, “You will not replace us,” in Charlottesville, Virginia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I wasn’t going to run, as the Senator knows, again for President.&nbsp; But when I saw those people coming out of the woods &#8212; of the fields of &#8212; in Virginia, in Charlottesville, carrying torches, shouting “You will not replace us,” accompanied by white supremacists and carrying Nazi banners &#8212; that’s when I said, “No.”&nbsp; “No.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I, honest to God &#8212; those who know me &#8212; Chuck &#8212; you know I wasn’t going to run for certain.  But I was going to be darned if I was going to let &#8212; anyway.  Don’t want to get going. </p>



<p>Look, we&#8217;ve seen the mass shootings in Charleston, South Carolina; El Paso, Texas; in Pittsburgh; last year in Atlanta; this week in Dallas, Texas; and now in Buffalo &#8212; in Buffalo, New York.&nbsp;</p>



<p>White supremacy is a poison.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a poison &#8212; (applause) &#8212; running through &#8212; it really is &#8212; running through our body politic.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s been allowed to fester and grow right in front of our eyes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>No more.&nbsp; I mean, no more.&nbsp; We need to say as clearly and forcefully as we can that the ideology of white supremacy has no place in America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; None.</p>



<p>And, look, failure for us to not say that &#8212; failure in saying that is going to be complicity.&nbsp; Silence is complicity.&nbsp; It’s complicity.&nbsp; We cannot remain silent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our nation&#8217;s strength has always come from the idea &#8212; it&#8217;s going to sound corny, but think about it: What&#8217;s the idea of our nation?&nbsp; That we&#8217;re all children of God.&nbsp; All chil- &#8212; life, liberty, our universal goods &#8212; gifts of God.&nbsp; We didn&#8217;t get it from the government, we got it from &#8212; because we exist, and we’re called upon to defend them.</p>



<p>The venom of the haters and their weapons of war, the violence in the words and deeds that &#8212; that stalk our streets, our stores, our schools &#8212; this venom, this violence cannot be the story of our time.&nbsp; We cannot allow that to happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I&#8217;m not naïve.&nbsp; I know tragedy will come again.&nbsp; It cannot be forever overcome.&nbsp; It cannot be fully understood either.&nbsp; But there are certain things we can do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can keep assault weapons off our streets.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve done it before.&nbsp; I did it when we passed the crime bill last time.&nbsp; And violence went down, shootings went down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can&#8217;t prevent people from being radicalized to violence, but we can address the relentless exploitation of the Internet to recruit and mobilize terrorism.&nbsp; We just need to have the courage to do that, to stand up.</p>



<p>Look, the American experiment in democracy is in a danger like it hasn&#8217;t been in my lifetime.&nbsp; It&#8217;s in danger this hour.&nbsp; Hate and fear are being given too much oxygen by those who pretend to love America but who don&#8217;t understand America.</p>



<p>To confront the ideology of hate requires caring about all people, not making distinctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reverend, the Scripture is seeing that we&#8217;re all part of the Divine.&nbsp; “Love thy neighbor as thyself.”&nbsp; That&#8217;s the America I know, that Jill knows.&nbsp; And most deserve the most &#8212; we &#8212; look, we are the most multiracial, most dynamic nation in the history of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now is the time for the people of all races, from every background, to speak up as a majority in America and reject white supremacy.</p>



<p>These actions we’ve seen in these hate-filled attacks represent the views of a hate-filled minority.&nbsp; We can’t allow them to distort America &#8212; the real America.&nbsp; We can’t allow them to destroy the soul of the nation.</p>



<p>As President of the United States, I travel the world all the time, and other nations ask me &#8212; heads of state and other countries ask me, “What’s going on?&nbsp; What in God’s name happened on January 6th?&nbsp; What happened in Buffalo?&nbsp; What happ-…”&nbsp; They ask.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have to refuse to live in a country where Black people going about a weekly grocery shopping can be gunned down by weapons of war deployed in a racist cause.</p>



<p>We have to refuse to live in a country where fear and lies are packaged for power and for profit.</p>



<p>We must all enlist in this great cause of America.</p>



<p>This is work that requires all of us &#8212; presidents and politicians, commentators, citizens.&nbsp; None of us can stay in the sidelines.&nbsp; We have to resolve here in Buffalo that from the tragedy &#8212; this tragedy &#8212; will come hope and light and life.&nbsp; It has to.&nbsp; And on our watch, the sacred cause of America will never bow, never break, never bend.&nbsp; And the America we love &#8212; the one we love &#8212; will endure.</p>



<p>So, to the families: From your pain, may we find purpose to live a life worthy of the loved ones you lost.</p>



<p>From a hymn based on the 91st Psalm, sung at my church: “May He raise you up on Eagle’s wings and Bear you on the breath of dawn, make you to shine like the sun, and hold you in the palm of His hand.”&nbsp; That’s my wish for us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can do this if we resolve to do it, if we take on the haters and those who don’t even care &#8212; it’s just about profit and politics.</p>



<p>May the soul of the fallen rest in peace and rise in glory.&nbsp; And may God guide the United States of America, now and always.</p>



<p>To the families: As my grandpop used to say when I walked out of his home in Scranton &#8212; he’d say, “Joey, spread the faith.”&nbsp; And my grandma would yell, “No, Joey.”&nbsp; I mean, he said, “Keep the faith.”&nbsp; And my grandma would say, “No, Joey, spread the faith.”</p>



<p>We’re thinking of you.&nbsp; Hold on to each other tightly.&nbsp; Stick together.&nbsp; You’ll get through this.&nbsp; And we’ll make Buffalo and the United States a better place to live than it is today.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p> 12:38 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Air Force One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/17/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 19:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buffalo Niagara International AirportBuffalo, New York 12:56 P.M. EDT Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, what was your message to the families?&#160; What was your message to the families? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; What was the question? Q&#160;&#160;&#160; What was your message to the families, Mr. President? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; My message was: They’re going to be in pain for a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Buffalo Niagara International Airport<br>Buffalo, New York</p>



<p>12:56 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what was your message to the families?&nbsp; What was your message to the families?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What was the question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What was your message to the families, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; My message was: They’re going to be in pain for a long while.&nbsp; But they will get to the point where something &#8212; they’ll open a closet door or they’ll ride by a park or they’ll eat their favorite ice cream, and they’ll think of the person they lost and they’ll smile before they cry.&nbsp; And that’s when they know you’re going to make it.&nbsp; Until then, you’re not sure.&nbsp; But it will happen.&nbsp; It’ll come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you believe that certain members of Congress, the Republican Party, as well as Tucker Carlson, who have echoed the replacement theory, deserve some blame for violent acts like this?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:  I believe anybody who echoes a replacement is to blame &#8212; not for this particular crime.  But it’s if for no purpose &#8212; no purpose except for profit and/or political benefit.  And it’s wrong.  It’s just simply wrong.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What more can you do on guns via executive action?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Not much on executive action.&nbsp; I’ve got to convince the Congress that we should go back to what I passed years ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How are you doing that?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I’m going to try.&nbsp; I’m going to try.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What’s your &#8212; what is your thoughts about next steps in Congress?&nbsp; Do you think there’s an opportunity or a prospect for more movement there?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The answer is going to be very difficult.&nbsp; It’s going to be very difficult.&nbsp; But I’m not going to give up trying.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, is it time for a domestic terrorism statute?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, we have enough laws on the books to deal with what’s going on now.&nbsp; We just have to &#8212; we have to deal with it.</p>



<p>Look, part of what the country has to do is look in the mirror and face the reality.&nbsp; We have a problem with domestic terror.&nbsp; It’s real.</p>



<p>I know you don’t want to hear me &#8212; not you.&nbsp; People don’t want to hear me saying it.&nbsp; They say, “Well, he’s the President.&nbsp; He’s a Democrat.&nbsp; He’s…”&nbsp; But that’s what the intelligence community has been saying; that’s what the military has been saying for a long time.&nbsp; There’s nothing we can do about this.&nbsp; Nothing to do about this.</p>



<p>And, look, there is a lot of people, like this murderer who committed this act, who are just deranged, who are susceptible, who are &#8212; who are just lost and don’t know what to do, and they’re easily taken &#8212; they’re easily sucked in.&nbsp; And it’s got to stop.&nbsp; We have to admit it.&nbsp; I don’t know why we don’t admit what the hell is going on.</p>



<p>Anyway, thank you very much.&nbsp; We’ll get on the plane.</p>



<p>1:00 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre En Route Buffalo,&#160;NY</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/17/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-en-route-buffalo-ny/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 16:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Buffalo, New York 9:07 A.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hello, hello, hello.&#160; Okay.&#160; I’ll try and speak loudly. Good morning.&#160; As you all know, we are headed to Buffalo, where the President and the First Lady will mourn with a grieving city. &#160;During the trip, the President and the First Lady&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Buffalo, New York</p>



<p>9:07 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hello, hello, hello.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I’ll try and speak loudly.</p>



<p>Good morning.&nbsp; As you all know, we are headed to Buffalo, where the President and the First Lady will mourn with a grieving city. &nbsp;During the trip, the President and the First Lady will visit Tops Market memorial where they&#8217;ll pa- &#8212; where they’ll pay their respects to the lives of lost &#8212; to the lives lost in Saturday&#8217;s tragic shooting.</p>



<p>Afterward, the President and First Lady will meet with family members of the victims, law enforcement and first responders, and local leaders at a community center to offer their condolences and comfort to those affected by this tragedy.</p>



<p>After, the President will deliver remarks at the community center.&nbsp; The President will call this despicable act for what it is: terrorism motivated by a hateful and perverse ideology that tears at the sco- &#8212; the soul of our nation.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll call on all Americans to give hate no safe harbor and to reject the lies of racial animus that radicalize and divide us and lead to the act of racist violence we saw on Saturday that took the lives of 10 Americans.</p>



<p>President Biden will call on Congress to take action to keep weapons off war &#8212; weapons of war off our streets and keep guns out of the hands of criminals and people who have a serious mental illness that makes them a danger to themselves or others.</p>



<p>And the President will call on Americans to seek a more perfect union and embraces the diversity that has made us the world&#8217;s strongest and most dynamic nation in history of the world.</p>



<p>We &#8212; we&#8217;re joined on Air Force One by Majority Leader Chuck Schumer, Senator Kirsten Gillibrand, and Congressman Brian Higgins who represents Buffalo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the ground in Buffalo, President Biden will be joined by Governor Kathy Hochul, Buffler [sic] &#8212; Buffalo Mayor Byron Brown, Erie County Executive Mark Poloncarz, and Buffalo City Council President Reverend Darius Pridgen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the &#8212; in his meeting with first responders and local officials, the President will meet with the Buffalo Police Commissioner and De- &#8212; and Buffalo Deputy Fire Commissioner among many other state and local leaders.</p>



<p>We will, of course, share all of the &#8212; all of that in pool notes as we normally do.</p>



<p>Finally, I want to make sure you all saw that, on Thursday, President Biden will welcome the Prime Minister of Sweden and the President of Finland to the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve got a short flight, so I&#8217;m going to just get to it. And, Chris, do you want to kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, the President said earlier when he took office that he wanted to boost efforts against domestic terrorism.&nbsp; Obviously, you know, this attack was carried out despite those efforts to refocus on white supremacy and domestic terrorism.&nbsp; Are there gaps in the administration&#8217;s efforts? &nbsp;And what is being done to boost those efforts now?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I know that &#8212; that Congress, right now, is looking at the Domestic Terrorism Prevention Act.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been &#8212; we&#8217;ve been asked about that, so I just wanted to give an answer on that.&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;re still studying the details of the legislation, but the President has been clear in his commitment to countering domestic terrorism threats.</p>



<p>I talked a little bit about this yesterday, about what we have been doing in particular here in the administration.&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve been working to implement the government-wide National Strategy to Counter Domestic Terrorism President Biden directed his national security team to develop on his first full day in office.&nbsp; Recognize that that has evolved into the most urgent terrorism threat the United States faces today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that works &#8212; that work includes &#8212; just very quickly &#8212; improving information sharing; adding resources to prevent domestic terrorism recruitment; increase our support for federal, state, and local law enforcement in addressing domestic terrorism nationwide; confronting long-term contributor &#8212; contributors to domestic terrorism; and rooting out hate and bigotry to fight gun crime.</p>



<p>As we have talked about, we are going to continue to call &#8212; I said that at the topper &#8212; on Congress to expand background checks, renew our ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, and confirm Steve Dettelbach to head ATF.</p>



<p>I do want to go back to &#8212; a second &#8212; about law enforcement. &nbsp;And I also said this yesterday, but the way that the law enforcement &#8212; local law enforcement reacted and was on top of what happened in Buffalo and the other cities was &#8212; they should be commended.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s what we want to continue to do: provide them the assistance that they need; when this sad events &#8212; these sad events happen, that they&#8217;re able to react in the way that’s saving lives and protecting lives the best that they can.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, on NATO, Turkish President Erdoğan made some pretty strong comments yesterday suggesting that he would not want Finland and Sweden to join the Alliance.&nbsp; With those leaders coming to the White House tomorrow &#8212; or on Thursday, excuse me &#8212; what is the U.S. prepared to do to assuage Turkey’s concerns?&nbsp; Have the Turkish government communicated anything they want from the U.S. in terms of concessions?&nbsp; And what is the U.S. prepared to offer Turkey to reassure them about their &#8212; the Sweden and Finland NATO campaign?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, Secretary Blinken spoke to this on Sunday.&nbsp; He held a press conference in Berlin &#8212; you know, meeting with his counterparts in NATO.<br><br>Look, we &#8212; we are confident that they will reach a consensus as an Alliance and &#8212; on an entry process should they decide to apply.&nbsp; So, that &#8212; we&#8217;re confident that, again &#8212; and Secretary Blinken &#8212; so I&#8217;m just really re-upping what he says: that there will be a consensus as it relates to Turkey and Sweden and Finland of applications.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What gives you confidence in that, given that &#8212; I mean, after Blinken’s comments, Erdoğan’s tone seemed to get even less optimistic or willing to allow them into the Alliance?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, as we know, there&#8217;s a lot of support for Sweden and Finland to &#8212; to join NATO.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that in polling.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that in voice support just across &#8212; across the NATO Alliances.&nbsp; And so, we have every confidence that there will be a consensus.<br><br>There &#8212; there&#8217;s conversations happening.&nbsp; I cannot speak for the Turkey government as what they need or what they&#8217;re looking for.&nbsp; But again, we feel very confident.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; that is something that the &#8212; Secretary Blinken said himself after &#8212; when he was in Berlin recently.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, a question about guns.&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of what the administration&#8217;s intelligence is or view is right now of the potential for copycat attacks and what&#8217;s being done on that?&nbsp; And then I have a follow-up.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have anything to share on any copycat attacks.&nbsp; I know I heard reporting that there was one in Buffalo, I think yesterday.&nbsp; That is something for, like, the local &#8212; clearly, the local &#8212; local enforcement to &#8212; you can go to them and ask them exactly what was happening there.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have anything to share on the federal government side.&nbsp; I laid out what we&#8217;re doing, what we have done in fighting domestic terrorism, but I don&#8217;t want &#8212; I don&#8217;t have more to share.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Further on the issue of guns: Gun prevention groups or gun violence protection groups &#8212; prevention groups, rather &#8212; have been pressing the White House to start an office of gun violence protection.&nbsp; Is that something that President Biden is considering, particularly in light of this most recent attack?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I would have to go back to the team and see if that is something that&#8217;s actually on the table.&nbsp; I have not heard of that.&nbsp; I could understand why that is being requested or asked, especially what we have been seeing these past &#8212; this past weekend.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything more to share or preview or anything to &#8212;</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Just one last follow-up on that, sorry.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just &#8212; what is next then for this administration in terms of next steps on gun violence and gun reform?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, you know, we&#8217;ve said &#8212; you&#8217;ve heard us say this: Our country is facing an epidemic on gun violence that is costing lives every day, as we&#8217;ve seen most recently in Buffalo and other examples.&nbsp; The President is using every tool he can to fight gun violence.&nbsp; He&#8217;s done more through executive action than any President in their first history &#8212; in their first year in office.&nbsp;<br><br>And I &#8212; for example, we heard on Friday how over $10 billion from the Rescue Plan has been spent or committed on ways to fight gun crime.&nbsp; The President wants cities and states to use even more.&nbsp; The Justice Department issued a tough new rule to stem the flow of ghost guns, which are increasingly being found at crime scenes and which are the weapons of choice for terrorists and criminals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there&#8217;s so much more to do, and that&#8217;s why we are calling on Congress to act on what I was talking about: the expanded background checks, renew our ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazine, and confirm our ATF nominee as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, you were talking about the Domestic Terrorism Prevention Act.&nbsp; That &#8212; it’s somewhat broad in what it would do &#8212; increasing resources, what have you.&nbsp; Does the President think &#8212; does the President believe that there should be a domestic terrorism statute that allows prosecutors to charge suspects of mass shooting with domestic terrorism?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So in light of today&#8217;s evolving domestic terrorism threat, we have to consider whether legislation &#8212; legislative reforms could meaningfully and materially increase our ability to protect Americans from acts of domestic terrorism while simultaneously guarding against potential abuse and outreach.</p>



<p>You know, we have asked the Department of Justice as part of our strategy to counter domestic terrorism, as I just laid out, to closely examine whether new legislative authorities that balance safely &#8212; safety and the protection of civil liberties are necessary and appropriate.&nbsp; And this is something they have said they are carefully considering.&nbsp; So, this is still in progress as something that they&#8217;re looking at.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, yesterday, you were asked a couple of times about whether or not certain commentators and media, whether or not certain members of the Republican Party as well should share some blame in amplifying “replacement theory.”&nbsp; It seems like the administration at this point is not calling out by name some of those people that have, in fact, amplified that theory.</p>



<p>Can you walk through the thinking of the President and the White House of why this is not a time and why it&#8217;s not effective to call them out?&nbsp; Or do you feel that it&#8217;s not effective, and will you call them out by name?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the people who spread this filth know who they are, and they should be ashamed of themselves.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to give them or &#8212; give them or their obnoxious ideas they&#8217;re pushing the attention that they desperately want.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the President has already called out this &#8212; this poisonous, false, hateful ideology, including on Saturday and Sunday, saying, “Any act of domestic terrorism, including an act perpetrated in the name of a repugnant white nationalist ideology, is antithetical to everything we stand for in America” and that “We must all work together to address the hate that remains a stain on the soul of America.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Every leader should condemn that hate and certainly not echo it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to focus on what unites us as Americans. That&#8217;s going to be what we&#8217;re focusing on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we should anticipate, in that case, as a follow to this, that we won&#8217;t hear that from the President today either?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  So, I mean, just to reiterate, Jonathan, I&#8217;m not going to give them a platform.  So, I just want to make that very clear. </p>



<p>But we&#8217;re going to make our case directly to the people.&nbsp; We have a vision for this country &#8212; one where we combat hate, racism, and violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We denounce white racism and domestic terror.&nbsp; We hope all will join us in denouncing hate and racism, as well as the conspiracy theories that run rampant online.</p>



<p>For today, as I stated earlier, is I &#8212; the President and the First Lady are going to comfort the grieving victims and the families who lost their loved ones.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to listen to them, he&#8217;s going to talk to them, and he&#8217;s going to be there for them as their President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on a different topic.&nbsp; Over the weekend, there were a number of large demonstrations and rally in defense of abortion rights.&nbsp; The President, of course, has spoken that he supports that as well.&nbsp; Why did he not appear at any of these?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the President and the Vice President were energized to see the many people peacefully gathering this past weekend.&nbsp; The administration continues to do everything possible to protect access to women&#8217;s reproductive rights, including working closely with abortion rights groups, providers, and elected officials, and more.&nbsp; But he was, indeed, gen- &#8212; energized to see what &#8212; folks coming out, peacefully protesting, and speaking out.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Sally.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, just on politics quickly.&nbsp; Does the President have any plans to watch the Pennsylvania returns tonight? &nbsp;Obviously, it&#8217;s his other home state.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a really important primary for both parties.&nbsp; And when can we expect to see more of him on the campaign trail heading into November?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have anything on his schedule on what that&#8217;s going to look like the next several months, going into November.&nbsp; So, as you know, I&#8217;m not going to go into politics from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, obviously, Pennsylvania, as you were saying, Sally, is near and dear to the President &#8212; to President Biden.&nbsp; And he spent a lot of time on the ground there as President talking about his plan to lower costs for the American people there and the need to get something done in Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;s going to continue to take his plan to the people of Pennsylvania and throughout the country.&nbsp; And as you’ve heard President Biden say over and over, “Don&#8217;t compare me to the Almighty.&nbsp; Compare me to the alternative.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Right now, the ultra-MAGA congressional Republicans want to raise taxes on the middle class, take away a woman&#8217;s right to &#8212; to right &#8212; right to reproductive healthcare, and oppose the administration&#8217;s work to keep guns out of the hands of criminals and put more cops on the beat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President isn&#8217;t going to shy away from underscoring the contrast between congressional Republicans and the work he and his administration are doing to lower prices and make our communities safe and stronger.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything for the &#8212; his future role as we go up into November.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just quickly on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, Karine &#8212; and just &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, sorry &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last one, Karine &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Inaudible) follow up.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, just on one other topic. &nbsp;Yesterday&#8217;s Cuba announcement from the administration &#8212; how closely is that related to the Summit of the Americas coming up?&nbsp; And when can we expect to see those formal invitations go out to the nations?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have anything new on the invites just quite yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me just give you a little bit of the announcement yesterday: The Cuban people are confronting an unprecedented humanitarian crisis, and our policy will continue to focus on empowering the Cuban people to help them create a future free from repression and economic suffering.</p>



<p>The President is fulfilling his commitment to the Cuban- American community and their family members in Cuba by facilitating family reunifications, strengthening fam- &#8212; family ties and facilitating educational connections, increasing support for independent Cuban entrepreneurs, ensuring that the remittances flow more freely to Cuban people while not enriching those who perpetrate human rights abuses.</p>



<p>These policy are designed to center on human rights and empowering the Cuban people to determine their own future.&nbsp; And so that is &#8212; that is our focus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know you asked me “Why now?”&nbsp; So the &#8212; following the large-scale protests in July 2021, President &#8212; President Biden directed his national security team to take action in two primary ways.&nbsp; And those are &#8212; those what &#8212; is what I just listed out.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where it came from.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So one quick follow-up on Cuba.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why does the Biden administration feel confident in the safety of the U.S. resources they&#8217;re sending to Cuba with these new steps when these anomalous health incidents haven&#8217;t been solved?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, you know, I get &#8212; I understand the question, but at the same time, we have to make sure that we&#8217;re helping the Cuban people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To your &#8212; to your question, that&#8217;s something that we&#8217;re monitoring, clearly, and just keeping a close eye on.&nbsp; But we also have to make sure that the Cuban people does &#8212; do not suffer.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the U.S. have a plan?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So that’s our focus there.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the U.S. have a plan if those attacks continue in Cuba?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more to share beyond the announcement that we made yesterday.&nbsp; We are going to have our National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, with me at the podium tomorrow.&nbsp; So we can &#8212; that&#8217;s a question you can ask him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I sneak in one more quick one?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just &#8212; do you have an update on when the President will make a decision on student loan relief?&nbsp; And also, I&#8217;m wondering if the administration has assessed whether or not even relief for $10,000 &#8212; what kind of impact that could have on inflation.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So let me start with your first question.&nbsp; We have no policy to announce yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as a reminder, no one has been required to pay a single dime of student loans since the President took office.&nbsp; You know, I will note that the administration’s actions have already provided more than $18.5 billion in targeted debt relief to more than 750,000 borrows [sic] &#8212; borrowers.&nbsp;&nbsp; This is through the Public Service Loan Forgiveness &#8212; borrowers who have a total and permanent disability, borrowers who were misled by their college or university, and borrowers who attended ITT Technical Institutes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, the policy has not been &#8212; we haven&#8217;t announced it yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is your question about inflation:&nbsp; And &#8212; but I do want to state that Jared Bernstein has spoken to this before &#8212; your question, Zolan &#8212; and he&#8217;s mentioned that the impact on inflation by pausing federal loan repayments would be almost negligible, in his words &#8212; something like 0.001 percent.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>&nbsp;9:25 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on Actions to Expand Infant&#160;Formula</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/17/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-actions-to-expand-infant-formula/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 15:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (May 16, 2022) 7:34 P.M. EDT MR. MUNOZ:&#160; All right, good evening.&#160; Happy Monday, everybody.&#160; Thank you for joining us on this call tonight to discuss some updates from the administration on efforts to increase the availability of safe infant formula supply across the United States. As a reminder, this call will be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(May 16, 2022)</p>



<p>7:34 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, good evening.&nbsp; Happy Monday, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us on this call tonight to discuss some updates from the administration on efforts to increase the availability of safe infant formula supply across the United States.</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; It will be embargoed until the conclusion of the call.</p>



<p>At the beginning, we have a few brief remarks and then we can just get into a couple of questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Joining us on the call is [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].&nbsp; And with that, I will kick it to [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, Kevin.&nbsp; As you know, getting more safe infant formula onto shelves across the country is one of the President’s top priorities.&nbsp; We understand how stressful it is for parents trying to feed their children &#8212; I say that as someone expecting my second child in June &#8212; and that’s why this administration has been working for weeks to address the infant formula shortage.</p>



<p>It’s important to remember that this shortage exists because one manufacturer, Abbott Nutrition, closed a facility in Michigan due to safety concerns from the FDA.&nbsp; That facility was a major producer of formula that families in this country rely on.&nbsp; And you have heard from us about our ongoing, 24/7 work to tackle the issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to provide an update tonight on just a couple of very recent developments.&nbsp; First, today, FDA and Abbott agreed on next steps to reopen the Michigan plant that is currently closed.&nbsp; This is a critical step in resolving the shortages that are impacting families across the country today.</p>



<p>Abbott and the federal government signed a formal consent decree that outlines the steps to get the facility reopened and produce &#8212; and producing formula again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The consent decree requires that Abbott retain an independent expert to review the facility’s operation and ensure compliance with the law.&nbsp; It includes requirements for testing products and for promptly notifying the FDA should any contamination be detected.</p>



<p>And the consent decree also requires the implementation of a detailed sanitation plan, an environmental monitoring plan, a new employee training program.&nbsp; So a robust document outlining a key series of basic steps that the parties have agreed to.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, also today, we took another important step with the FDA releasing guidance under which major formula manufacturers can ask to safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market.</p>



<p>Companies will need to apply with the FDA, and FDA is prepared to review applications quickly and respond to them rapidly.&nbsp; FDA will prioritize review of applications that are most likely to be successful and will get the most formula to U.S. shelves as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>FDA is going to be closely evaluating quality and safety and safety history to ensure that only safe product will come to American shelves.</p>



<p>At the White House, we have alerted embassies and retailers and manufacturers to identify potential companies that could make use of the new importation process.&nbsp; And we’ll continue working with folks as we get this process moving.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, I want to highlight that throughout the weekend we’ve been working closely with manufacturers and retailers that are today producing formula for the U.S. market to identify transportation and logistical needs to increase the amount and speed of approved formula that’s being shipped into the country, and to ensure that formula that is being produced here or coming in from abroad is quickly moving from factories to retailers.&nbsp; And we’ve offered logistical support, and we’ll be, you know, continuing to conduct that outreach and identify ways to be helpful.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fourth, we’ve also continued to engage with pediatricians and parents’ groups and other stakeholders to hear from them and to share information about resources and (inaudible) during this time.</p>



<p>So, taken together, the steps we&#8217;re announcing today should continue to make a difference for families.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be working overtime to get more formula on shelves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, back to you, Kevin.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Don&#8217;t be shy &#8212; if you have questions, we have some time.&nbsp; First let&#8217;s go to Spencer Kimball at CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for doing the call.&nbsp; So the FDA said that, you know, it streamlined the process at ports, and imports have increased 300 percent since last year.&nbsp; Can you just say where exactly are the imports coming from &#8212; what companies, what countries?&nbsp; How long does the administration expect the situation to take until supply is kind of normalized?</p>



<p>And then also, in the consent decree, the Justice Department said that products were adulterated.&nbsp; Abbott has denied that.&nbsp; So did the FDA find contaminated baby powder at the facility?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], you want to take the first part of that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So I can take the piece on the consent decree.&nbsp; So, you know, I don&#8217;t want to get into a, like, huge back-and-forth on exactly the findings of facts between the agencies or between the parties here.</p>



<p>The consent decree reflects that there was a history of, you know, product disposal at the facility because of concerns about contamination, and so it&#8217;s consistent with that.&nbsp; But I would refer you to DOJ and to Abbott for, you know, specifics on the terms of the consent decree.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], if you can jump in.&nbsp; I think you&#8217;re best positioned to weigh in on where are you seeing imports are coming from.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And if not, I will (inaudible).</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, it&#8217;s working now.&nbsp; I had trouble unmuting my line, so apologies for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, when we look at our trade data, the sources of imports for formula currently include Ireland, Chile, the Netherlands.&nbsp; You know, as we look at the kind of countries that have health and safety inspection systems similar to our own, may be able to meet that quantity and labeling and nutritional guidance standards that [senior administration official] laid out, we can imagine Australia, New Zealand, the UK also being countries that, you know, product could be imported from.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Alex Alper at Reuters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Can you hear me okay?</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We can.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; I guess &#8212; you know, you mentioned the importance of facilitating transportation.&nbsp; And I was wondering if you could say, you know, what specific transportation help has the White House offered to the companies involved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, just to follow up on something that was mentioned I think late last week, which was the possibility of invoking the DPA.&nbsp; And I wondered if that was still under consideration and how specifically it could help increase production.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; On the &#8212; I can take those questions.</p>



<p>On the transportation side, you know, we&#8217;ve talked to the retailers, we&#8217;ve talked to the manufacturers.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve told them, “Let us know if you&#8217;re having some specific transportation, logistical challenges somewhere in your supply chain where we could offer some help.”&nbsp; Thus far, we&#8217;re still working through those requests, and I have no specific update to report on that side.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we have seen generally during this supply chain crisis &#8212; because we have a Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force that the administration has been running &#8212; that, in some instances, we’re able to help improve communication between all the firms and the logistics industry, and between suppliers and their customers to help speed up the movement of goods through the supply chain.</p>



<p>On the question of the Defense Production Act, here we are continuing to focus on actions we can take to get more supply available as quickly as possible.&nbsp; That is, like, our primary goal.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to look at every option that is on the table there.&nbsp; No additional specific updates to offer you on the DPA there, but I will point you again to the work that the FDA has done today with their new importation guidance.&nbsp; It’s is a really critical and crucial step to quickly increasing supply in the country.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Let’s go to MJ Lee at CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp; Sorry about that.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Hey.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I was wondering if you all could share or know when the last time was that the FDA inspected the Michigan facility that&#8217;s opening up again.&nbsp; And will FDA officials be there throughout the reopening process?&nbsp; And just if you could walk us through how that would work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then just on the new guidance you mentioned for applying to import formula, you said that you hope to go through some of these applications pretty quickly.&nbsp; Do you have a sense of a general timeline for that?&nbsp; Are we talking about days or weeks for approval?&nbsp; And also just what the quantity is that you are estimating.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so on the first question, I would refer you to the FDA.&nbsp; As you know, they&#8217;re an independent scientific entity that conducts, you know, independent inspections and enforcement activities.&nbsp; So I would refer you to them for details on what they can share about when they have been on site and, you know, the schedule there.</p>



<p>On the timing for reviewing applications, FDA, you know, has asked companies to provide them with information that they can review.&nbsp; FDA has made clear that they will prioritize applications that stand a good chance of being successful, that indicate, sort of, clear quality and safety and nutritional adequacy and all of that, and that have potential to move significant products into the United States quickly.</p>



<p>You know, we expect &#8212; well, the process has been designed to move rapidly so that FDA, again, can evaluate those applications that have a clearer chance of success and move forward on those on those quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t have a specific timeline or number of days to give you tonight.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Next question, let&#8217;s go to Alyssa Rosenberg, The Washington Post.</p>



<p>All right, Alyssa, we will come back to you.&nbsp;<br><br>Ben Gittleson, ABC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Along the same lines, I was wondering how soon you expect imports could be actually seen on shelves.&nbsp; I know the previous question was about the application process, but as you&#8217;re planning for supply to become available, if you could give an estimate for parents how long it would take for the imports to actually appear on shelves.&nbsp;<br><br>And then also, the White House had said earlier today that the administration had been contacting suppliers for infant formula manufacturers to let them know that their materials were critical for boosting production, and encouraging them to prioritize the production and delivery.&nbsp; I was wondering if you could provide a little bit more specific detail.&nbsp; Like, what does that actually look like?&nbsp; Are these suppliers within the U.S.?&nbsp; What type of impact will this make and how quickly?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, sure.&nbsp; On the first question, the FDA commissioner said this morning that we are talking about getting products to the shelves in, you know, a matter of weeks.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re talking just a couple of weeks to &#8212; you know, for &#8212; to get some of that imported product into the country and available in U.S. stores.<br><br>I’ll turn to [senior administration official] on the second piece.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, on the second one, you know, I can tell you broadly: You can imagine that a manufacturer of infant formula needs to assemble a range of inputs, whether it&#8217;s specific ingredients, it’s labeling, it’s packaging materials.&nbsp; And so, you know, in a few instances, they identified how it would be helpful to get some of those supplies in quicker, and we were able to contact the suppliers and let them know.&nbsp; And they were &#8212; it was a helpful flag because they were not aware of what that downstream customer was producing and were eager to help make sure that those orders were being sent quickly.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go back to Alyssa.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, sorry about that.&nbsp; So, I &#8212; you know, I just hopped off the FDA call.&nbsp; I&#8217;m hearing from you guys, from them that it&#8217;s going to be a couple of weeks.&nbsp; And what efforts are underway to connect families who can&#8217;t get formula now with the formula they need?&nbsp; Because, clearly, there are families who can&#8217;t wait a couple of weeks.<br><br>I know that, you know, the guidance has referenced trying to identify areas where out-of-stock rates are particularly high and expedite getting formula to retailers there.&nbsp; But can you talk about any resources and efforts that are helping families bridge that couple-of-weeks gap, especially because it could be longer?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, I mean, as you know, we are carefully monitoring data across the country and improving, you know, our ability to understand regional and other variations every minute.&nbsp; As we relayed last week and remains true, we do know that today there is more infant formula coming off of production lines in the U.S. than there was prior to the recall.&nbsp; And similarly, overall sales of infant formula are up 13 percent compared to the pre-recall period.&nbsp;<br><br>So there is infant formula available.&nbsp; At the same time, we are absolutely mindful of how challenging this is, and I think we have a couple of key messages for families.<br><br>One is we want families to talk to their pediatrician and have confidence that it is &#8212; it is generally safe to switch your baby between infant formula products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If there is a brand available in the store &#8212; even if it&#8217;s not your normal product or, you know, a slightly different formulation or a different brand or, you know, powder versus liquid or, you know, any of those differences &#8212; it is &#8212; the formula on U.S. shelves is safe, and it is safe to move your baby between products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We recognize that that&#8217;s scary and can be challenging, but families should have confidence buying whatever is available and providing that to their family.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time, you know, it is not &#8212; it is not safe to provide &#8212; to water down formula or to make your own infant formula at home.&nbsp; And so, we think it is important that families hear those messages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:  All right.  Last question, let&#8217;s go to Meredith Lee.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Can you hear me?</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you could just clarify the timeline for when FDA notified the White House about infant formula shortages at the Michigan plant and potential market disruptions from that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know Karine said today that the administration has been working on this 24/7 since February, but Politico reported that a whistleblower last October flagged food safety concerns to senior FDA officials.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m wondering when the FDA notified the White House about any issues at the Michigan plant and potential shortages stemming from that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not in a position to comment on any internal communication.&nbsp; The recall became public on February 17th.&nbsp; And, you know, we certainly have been very public about our activity in this space since then.&nbsp; But again, I am &#8212; I am not in a position to comment on internal communications that were &#8212; you know, that would have happened prior to that.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Well, thank you, everybody.&nbsp; As a reminder, the call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and the embargo lifts after this.&nbsp; So, thank you for joining tonight.</p>



<p>7:52 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call By Senior Administration Officials On New Cuba&#160;Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/17/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-new-cuba-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 15:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (May 16, 2022) 6:36 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; Thank you so much for calling in this evening.&#160; I know it&#8217;s late, so I won&#8217;t delay and get us started.&#160; Of note, this is a call that&#8217;s on background.&#160; So for just your own edification, we have [senior administration official], who is [redacted].&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(May 16, 2022)</p>



<p>6:36 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you so much for calling in this evening.&nbsp; I know it&#8217;s late, so I won&#8217;t delay and get us started.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of note, this is a call that&#8217;s on background.&nbsp; So for just your own edification, we have [senior administration official], who is [redacted].&nbsp; And we also have [senior administration official] &#8212; and I apologize if I misspelled her name.&nbsp; And she is also joining us for this call.&nbsp; For both of them, please use a “senior administration official” when you refer to them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This call is embargoed until &#8212; at its conclusion, and I will let you know at the end of the call.&nbsp; If you don&#8217;t get a question, but you want to answer one after the fact, feel free to contact me or State Department and we will assist you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I will turn it over to you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [moderator].&nbsp; So good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; And thanks again for jumping on the line.</p>



<p>Today we&#8217;re &#8212; the United States announced a series of measures to increase support for the Cuban people and safeguard our national security interests. </p>



<p>I&#8217;ll say that this is the result of work we&#8217;ve been doing over the last year as a part of the policy review of our Cuba policy.&nbsp; It continues to center on human rights and empowering the Cuban people to determine their own future, and we continue to call on the Cuban government to release all political prisoners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before jumping in, I want to just very quickly review some of the actions that we&#8217;ve been taking since the large-scale protests that took place last July.&nbsp; The President met with the Cuban American community and directed us &#8212; following that meeting &#8212; to take action in two primary areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first is to promote accountability for human rights abuses, for which we have announced several rounds of sanctions targeting those individuals and entities with direct ties to human rights abuses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, he directed us to explore meaningful ways to support the Cuban people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, since then, we&#8217;ve prioritized facil- &#8212; prioritized and facilitated the export of privately sourced or donated goods to the Cuban people, focusing specifically on agricultural and medical exports; facilitated U.S. private sector faith-based organizations and other NGOs to provide humanitarian support; provided guidance to individuals and entities seeking to export to Cuba for the first time; also increased our support for the families of those who were detained; and increased, by $5 million, our support for censorship circumvention technology to support the ability of the Cuban people to communicate to, from, and among each other. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the measures today, again, are practical steps that we&#8217;re taking to address the humanitarian situation and to respond to the needs of the Cuban people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden is also fulfilling his commitment to the Cuban American community and their family members in Cuba by announcing measures in four key areas, which we plan to implement in the coming weeks &#8212; these measures &#8212; willing to support greater freedom and expand economic opportunities for the Cuban people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, diving in, the four areas are: First, we&#8217;re going to reinstate the Cuba Family Reunification Parole Program and continue to increase the capacity for consular services.&nbsp; So as you all saw, we began &#8212; resumed limited immigrant visa processing in early May and are looking to make sure that we staff up so that we can begin processing the full 20,000 immigrant visas out of Havana as quickly as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, we will &#8212; we&#8217;re strengthening family ties and facilitating educational connections for American and Cuban people by expanding authorized travel.&nbsp; And on that, I’ll say specifically authorizing commercial and charter flights to locations beyond Havana.&nbsp; We are reinstating group people-to-people educational travel under a general license, among a number of other measures.&nbsp; We are not reinstating individual people-to-people educational travel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, we are increasing support for independent Cuban entrepreneurs.&nbsp; That includes encouraging commercial opportunities outside the state sector by using their access &#8212; independent Cuban entrepreneurs’ access to the Internet, cloud technology, programming interfaces, e-commerce platforms, and a number of other measures, including access to microfinance and training.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then lastly, we will ensure that remittances flow more freely to the Cuban people while not enriching those who perpetrate human rights abuses.&nbsp; And by that, I mean we are removing the limit on family remittances of $1,000 per quarter per sender/receiver pair.&nbsp; And we’ll authorize donative remittances, which will support Cuban families and independent Cuban entrepreneurs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Donative remittances will particularly be crucial in supporting the Afro-Cuban community on the island.&nbsp; And I will note that right now only one of six Afro-Cubans receives family remittances.&nbsp; We will not remove entities from the Cuba restricted list, so remittances through FINCIMEX will remain prohibited.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Most importantly, we&#8217;re going to continue to elevate the matter of human rights, the treatment of political prisoners, and in particular, we’re going to elevate the issue of labor rights in Cuba as something that &#8212; the issue of labor rights, in general, is something that is a core priority for the Biden-Harris administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, I will now defer to my colleague, who is a versed expert on all the details here, to add additional points.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Nothing for me at the top, but I&#8217;m happy to answer questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I do have a &#8212; I just have a quick question about Senator Menendez, who just released a statement saying that the announcement today “risks sending the wrong message.”&nbsp; And he says he&#8217;s dismayed to learn that the administration will authorize group travel to Cuba.&nbsp; Do you have any reaction?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I mean, what I&#8217;ll say &#8212; and I&#8217;ll allow my colleague to weigh in on this &#8212; is that, certainly, the senator’s concerns about establishing the group people-to-people travel under general license opens the door to tourism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; I think one thing to underscore is that the Treasury Department has the authority to audit groups that are organizing travel.&nbsp; And we will ensure that that travel is purposeful and in accordance with U.S. law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], I don&#8217;t know if there&#8217;s anything else you want to add to that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; We’ll certainly ensure travel is purposeful and in accordance with U.S. law.&nbsp; And we’ll note something that President Biden had said often, which is his belief that Americans are the best ambassadors for democratic values.&nbsp; And facilitating group people-to-people travel will allow for greater engagement between the American people and the promotion of their democratic values.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I wonder if you&#8217;ve reached a decision yet about the Summit of the Americas and whether Cuba will be invited.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So what I&#8217;ll say on that is &#8212; Karen &#8212; is we&#8217;ve not made &#8212; invitations have not gone out, so there&#8217;s not been a decision on that.&nbsp; This &#8212; and these policy measures, as I mentioned, have been long in the works, as you well know, and are seen as completely separate from the conversation of who attends and does not attend the summit.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, thank you very much.&nbsp; I think that &#8212; that was my &#8212; my question was the relationship between this process and the Summit of the Americas, and whether &#8212; for the countries that have expressed concern about attending the summit in the absence of a Cuban invitation, whether that timing is in any way related to the announcement you&#8217;re making today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;&nbsp; No, so the &#8212; I mean, this was always planned for what we&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; It’s a coincidence.&nbsp; But I would say that in the conversations we&#8217;ve had with other leaders, we have laid out also just the level of ambition of the summit agenda as really where the focus should be.&nbsp; And I think the large majority of interlocutors &#8212; and something where Senator Chris Dodd, as special advisor for the summit, has been very active &#8212; I think agree that we should be focusing on addressing a whole host of shared challenges in the region and not blow up the summit over who shows up and who doesn&#8217;t.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; My question goes back to the question before.&nbsp; Why are these changes being announced now?&nbsp; I mean, you say this it’s coincidental, but are these concessions to the Cuban government for the boycott on the Summit of the America?&nbsp; That’s something that people on Capitol Hill actually say right now.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I don’t &#8212; I don’t know what “on the Hill” you’re referring to.&nbsp; But, again, these are actions that we see as in the national interest of the United States.&nbsp; They are focused, they’re practical steps we are taking to find ways to expand support for the Cuban people and to do what all Cuban Americans have been asking for, which is for us to reestablish immigrant visa processing in Havana.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t know if, [senior administration official], if there&#8217;s anything else you want to add?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a time of concerning &#8212; the humanitarian situation in Cuba right now is very concerning.&nbsp; And as the President directed us to find ways to meaningfully support the Cuban people, we assessed that these measures do take steps to do so at a particularly concerning time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you very much for this.&nbsp; I really appreciate it.&nbsp; We know that on the campaign trail President Biden had referred to Trump&#8217;s policies as “failed” and wanted to reverse them.&nbsp; Is this going in the step of reversing what many have seen as a maximum-pressure-style campaign against Cuba?&nbsp; And can we expect more measures such as closer &#8212; closer relations in terms of normalization of relations?&nbsp; Could this move forward based on the reaction from the Cuban side and their attitude moving forward?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, look, I &#8212; thanks for that question.&nbsp; Again, these &#8212; these are steps that, as my colleague mentioned, are intended to help alleviate the humanitarian suffering that prompts out (inaudible) migration from Cuba and also to advance our interest in supporting the Cuban people and ensuring that Cuban Americans and Americans in general are also the best advanced ambassadors for U.S. policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, measures are ones that are a complement to what has been an active effort since July of last year to increase the pressure on human rights abuses in Cuba and to find ways to provide more direct humanitarian support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, the President&#8217;s direction has been to find ways to hold the regime accountable and to support the Cuban people.&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been what has informed this policy outcome.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you very much for doing this.&nbsp; I have actually two questions.&nbsp; The first is: Why keep Guyana processing the visas?&nbsp; Why not change everything coming back to Havana?&nbsp; What is impeding you &#8212; impeaching you to do so?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the second question is: Do you have any plans to change the five-year visa that was before, during the administration &#8212; during the Obama administration?&nbsp; I understand now it&#8217;s only one way.&nbsp; Before that, it was multiple ways for five years.&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to take that?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; At this time, we plan to process immigrant visas &#8212; many immigrant visas out of Georgetown, Guyana, while we are standing up limited immigrant visa processing in Havana.&nbsp; We intend to resume in short order the Cuban Family Reunification Parole Program out of Havana as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the reason we are continuing to process visas out of Guyana is to maximize capacity.&nbsp; We are slowly ramping up capacity in Havana.&nbsp; And as we do so, we do not want to diminish the overall numbers of interviews that we can conduct, and so we&#8217;ll keep the Georgetown option open.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with respect to the question on visa validity for B visas, I do not have anything to share at this time.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; Thanks very much for doing this.&nbsp; In 2017, the Trump administration scaled back our presence in Havana.&nbsp; And as you just said, we&#8217;re going to be increasing our presence.&nbsp; We scaled it back because of concerns about Havana Syndrome.&nbsp; And I was curious what exactly has changed that makes you feel confident that you could put more people in the embassy there.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], you want to take that?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; The President directed us to increase staff at Embassy Havana &#8212; at U.S. Embassy Havana and to do so with an appropriate security posture.&nbsp;<br><br>We have been working over the course of the last several months to put in place a plan to be able to do so.&nbsp; As you know, the top priority of the U.S. government, and Secretary Blinken has said this several times, is the safety and security of U.S. personnel overseas.&nbsp; And we are working closely with all the relevant bureaus in the Department of State and across the interagency as well on plans to investigate and get to the bottom of the anomalous health incidents.&nbsp; And then as we do so, we working to increase staff as an appropriate security posture at U.S. Embassy Havana.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp; Two quick questions.&nbsp; First, just following up on that last one: While you haven&#8217;t come to a conclusion about Havana Syndrome, are you now persuaded that the Cuban government was not responsible?&nbsp;<br><br>And more to the question of the sanctions relief here: Take us a little bit into the logic of not going back to the kind of sanctions relief that the Obama administration, or I should say Obama-Biden administration, had in place at the end of their time in office.&nbsp; And what are you getting from the leverage of holding back on some of the sanctions relief?</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, look, I&#8217;ll answer the second part and then defer to my colleague on the first part.&nbsp; Look, I think, fundamentally, these policies are ones that are designed to advance our own national interests and U.S. national security policy, specifically expanding the ability to process visas outside Havana.&nbsp; And the other is very specific steps and &#8212; specific and practical steps to create bridges to the Cuban people.<br><br>I think that what we&#8217;re going to be doing over the next several months is focusing on implementing these steps and which &#8212; you know, some of which are going to take place faster than others.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to monitor the situation in Cuba and the effects of our actions.&nbsp;<br><br>But I&#8217;ll say that the crackdown by the Cuban regime after the July 11th protests were there for, I think, the world to see.&nbsp; And the sentences that were imposed on people that were just singing in the streets and asking for food and to have a greater say in the future of their country really shows the situation &#8212; the lack of respect for human rights on the island.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something that is at the core of President Biden&#8217;s approach to the Americas and, frankly, the world.<br><br>But these are steps that we thought were designed to get specifically to the Cuban people and that were in our unilateral interest.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And with respect to your question about the anomalous health incidents, I&#8217;ll say that we are working across the interagency and State Department and with allies around the world as well to get to the bottom of the anomalous health incidents.&nbsp; And at this moment, we do not have a conclusion as to the attribution.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) much for doing this.&nbsp; I was hoping you could say when do you anticipate the invites for the summit to go out.&nbsp; And while I&#8217;m just considering this is one of the few times we&#8217;ll probably get to ask you questions about this &#8212; you know, this &#8212; you know, on this (inaudible) &#8212; can you talk any &#8212; a little bit about what goes into making the decisions of who to invite; you know, what are the factors that are being considered?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, I guess the plan is to send the invitations soon.&nbsp; And the &#8212; I guess the rationale is, look, the host has wide discretion.&nbsp; And we’ll &#8212; but we start by looking at the Inter-American Democratic Charter and the criteria that it established for inviting leaders from democratically elected governments.</p>



<p>I think the question of expanding that is one where we consult with our partners in the region.&nbsp; We have these debates about who to invite, but ultimately it is the prerogative of the host to make that decision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, good afternoon.&nbsp; So I have specific questions on the measures.&nbsp; First, do you have a timeline for when you expect the embassy in Havana to be working at full capacity where you think you&#8217;ll be meeting the 20,000 visa quota agreed with the Cuban government?&nbsp; That&#8217;s one.</p>



<p>The other: You say the authorizing of commercial and charter flights.&nbsp; So you expect that the frequencies that were available before the sanctions will be available again?&nbsp; And you said cities different from Havana.</p>



<p>And on the remittances: So you&#8217;re lifting their limit on 1,000 percent [sic] per quarter, but you&#8217;re not excluding the Cuban entity.&nbsp; So how are people going to send the money?&nbsp; And how will this specific measure benefit Afro-Cubans?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Would you like to take to the first question?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And forgive me, can you repeat the first question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How quickly are we going to get up to 20,000 in Havana?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, perfect.&nbsp; I do not have a timeframe at this time, unfortunately.&nbsp; We are working with our colleagues in the State Department and also Department of Homeland Security, which manages the Cuban Family Reunification Parole Program, to determine the pace at which we can increase capacity and visa issuance and parole practicing.</p>



<p>We aim to, and have every intent to, be in compliance with the migration accords.&nbsp; And the recent migration talks that were held last month between the United States and Cuba sought to bring both countries into compliance with their commitments for safe, legal, and orderly migration as enshrined in the migration accords.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On your second question is &#8212; so the implementation of these measures, I think we&#8217;re going to be working to move very quickly to execute on them over the course of weeks and months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when it comes to the question of visa (inaudible) or of remittance processing, certainly providing reassurance to third, kind of, electronic payment companies that there is bipartisan support for electronic payments &#8212; that is something that&#8217;s going to take time but it&#8217;s something we&#8217;re going to focus a lot on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On not removing FINCIMEX from the Cuba restricted list: Cuba is unique in the world at having the military play a role in remittance processing.&nbsp; If they were &#8212; you know, and we&#8217;ve engaged with them to underscore that if there was a civilian entity that could do the processing, that that would be something that would be acceptable, recognizing that what we want to work toward is having electronic payments expand to the extent that that&#8217;s possible.</p>



<p>So the decisions &#8212; the ball is in their court to decide.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, everybody.&nbsp; Well, that was the last question.&nbsp; Thank you so much for attending again.&nbsp; Remember, this is a call on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; And the embargo is now lifted.</p>



<p>Thank you so much.</p>



<p>7:01 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on International Day Against Homophobia, Transphobia and&#160;Biphobia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-international-day-against-homophobia-transphobia-and-biphobia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the International Day Against Homophobia, Transphobia and Biphobia, Jill and I stand in support and solidarity with lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex, (LGBTQI+) people in the United States and around the world. And we join with Americans across the country to reaffirm our commitment to the ongoing work of upholding human dignity&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On the International Day Against Homophobia, Transphobia and Biphobia, Jill and I stand in support and solidarity with lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex, (LGBTQI+) people in the United States and around the world. And we join with Americans across the country to reaffirm our commitment to the ongoing work of upholding human dignity for all people and advancing equality globally.</p>



<p>On this day in 1990, the World Health Organization took the long overdue step of declassifying ‘homosexuality’ as a mental disorder. Since that time, there has been much progress. But we continue to witness disturbing setbacks and rising hate and violence targeting LGBTQI+ people in the United States and around the world. This is wrong. LGBTQI+ people are entitled to all the rights, opportunities, and protections that belong to every human on this planet. LGBTQI+ people are an essential part of families and communities—teachers, first responders, public officials, doctors, lawyers, front-line workers, and friends who enrich and strengthen every single country.</p>



<p>And make no mistake: hateful legislative attacks against members of our own LGBTQI+ community cannot be tolerated in America or anywhere else. They spur discrimination and can stoke violence. And they are rooted in the same ignorance and intolerance that we see around the world. Hate is hate—and all of us have a responsibility to speak out against hate wherever we find it.</p>



<p>The United States leads the world not only by the example of our power, but by the power of our example. That means making commitments— and following through with action, transparency, and accountability. That’s why, last month, we released the first-ever public progress <a href="https://www.state.gov/lgbtqi-human-rights/">report</a> on my Administration’s whole-of-government approach to advance the human rights of LGBTQI+ people globally, from supporting local civil society organizations to standing up for LGBTQI+ human rights at the United Nations, and in our engagement with repressive governments.</p>



<p>By openly reporting on our own progress, the United States hopes to inspire other governments to take similar action to address the needs of their LGBTQI+ communities.</p>



<p>Strong and healthy democracies must ensure LGBTQI+ people can enjoy full participation in society and access all the benefits available to a nation’s citizens. At the first Summit for Democracy, the United States committed to facilitating the participation and leadership of LGBTQI+ community members in democratic institutions, a process we will continue to support.</p>



<p>To the LGBTQI+ community, my administration sees you. We stand with you. And we will continue to defend human rights and dignity, at home and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on the Meeting Between President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Andersson of Sweden and President Niinistö of&#160;Finland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-meeting-between-president-biden-and-prime-minister-andersson-of-sweden-and-president-niinisto-of-finland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Magdalena Andersson of Sweden and President Sauli Niinistö of Finland to the White House.  The leaders will discuss Finland’s and Sweden’s NATO applications and European security, as well as strengthening our close partnerships across a range of global issues and support for Ukraine. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Magdalena Andersson of Sweden and President Sauli Niinistö of Finland to the White House.  The leaders will discuss Finland’s and Sweden’s NATO applications and European security, as well as strengthening our close partnerships across a range of global issues and support for Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
