<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 20:28:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 23, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/23/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-23-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:14 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi everyone.&#160; Happy Friday.&#160; Okay, a couple of notes for you at the top.&#160;Today, the Biden-Harris administration took additional steps to provide stability and relief to homeowners who are still feeling the economic effects of the COVID-19 pandemic.&#160;HUD, USDA, and the VA announced details to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:14 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi everyone.&nbsp; Happy Friday.&nbsp; Okay, a couple of notes for you at the top.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, the Biden-Harris administration took additional steps to provide stability and relief to homeowners who are still feeling the economic effects of the COVID-19 pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>HUD, USDA, and the VA announced details to help people with government-backed mortgages stay in their homes through monthly payment reductions and potential loan modifications.<br>&nbsp;<br>Homeowners could see reductions in their monthly payments of roughly 20 to 25 percent, allowing them to remain in their homes and build long-term equity.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re working hard to get the word out to Americans who may benefit from these new programs.&nbsp; And thanks to the work of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau and today’s actions, most servicers of mortgages are required to provide borrowers information about these options.<br>&nbsp;<br>Homeowners can visit ConsumerFinance.gov/Housing for up-to-date information and more details.<br>&nbsp;<br>Also would note, on our delegation in Haiti, the presidential delegation is safe and accounted for in light of the reported shootings outside of the funeral.&nbsp; They’re on their way back to the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are deeply concerned about unrest in Haiti.&nbsp; In this critical moment, Haiti’s leaders must come together to chart a united path that reflects the will of the Haitian people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We remain committed to supporting the people of Haiti in this challenging time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, a vaccine-sharing update for you:&nbsp; We shipped a record number of doses to a record number of countries this week.&nbsp; Twenty-two million doses went out to 23 countries, including Guatemala, Senegal, Zambia, Niger, Gambia, El Salvador, Honduras, the Central African Republic, Cameroon, Lesotho, Panama, Vietnam, Georgia, Pakistan, Tanzania, Mozambique, Benin, Morocco, Tajikistan, Colombia, Madagascar, Liberia, and Eswatini.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our teams across the government are working to get more and more doses out every day, but this was a record week for our efforts to provide supply to the global community.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, week ahead: On Monday, the President will host an event in the Rose Garden to celebrate the 31st anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act, which the President proudly cosponsored as a senator.&nbsp; While we have much work to do to realize the full aspiration of the ADA, our country has made progress toward its goals of equality of opportunity, full participation, self-sufficiency, and respect for the 61 million Americans with disabilities.<br>&nbsp;<br>Also Monday, the President will welcome Prime Min- &#8212; the Prime Minister of Iraq to the White House.&nbsp; The Prime Minister’s visit will highlight the strategic partnership between the United States and Iraq, and advance bilateral cooperation under a Strategic &#8212; the Strategic Framework Agreement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The visit will also focus on key areas of shared interest, including through education, health, cultural, economic, energy, and climate initiatives.&nbsp; President Biden looks forward to strengthening bilateral cooperation with Iraq on political, economic, and security issues, including joint efforts to ensure the enduring defeat of ISIS.<br>&nbsp;<br>On Wednesday, the President will travel to Pennsylvania and Lehigh Valley &#8212; in the Lehigh Valley area, where he will emphasize the importance of American manufacturing, buying products made in America, and supporting good-paying jobs for American workers.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ll have more details for you over the weekend as things get finalized.<br>&nbsp;<br>Josh, why don&#8217;t you kick us off.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two subject areas.&nbsp; First, an AP-NORC&nbsp; survey found that 45 percent of the unvaccinated say they would definitely not get vaccinated.&nbsp;&nbsp; Another 35 percent say they probably won&#8217;t get vaccinated.&nbsp;&nbsp; Why does this opposition still exist after all the public outreach?&nbsp; And should more governments and employers mandate vaccinations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Josh, I think &#8212; let&#8217;s take a step back first.&nbsp;&nbsp; In December, before the President took office, the percentage of Americans willing to get a shot was in the 30s.&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, over 68 percent of adult Americans have taken a shot.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, what that shows you is that, in a relatively short period of time, we&#8217;ve been able to influence a whole lot of people to change their minds, taken ac- &#8212; take action, get a shot, save their lives and the lives of people around them.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that we&#8217;ve seen some encouraging data over the last couple of weeks.&nbsp; The five states with the highest case rates &#8212; Arkansas, Florida, Louisiana, Missouri, and Nevada &#8212; had a higher rate of people getting newly vaccinated compared to the national average.&nbsp;&nbsp; That is a good sign.&nbsp; This is the second week in a row &#8212; I noted this last week.<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, in the past 10 days, more than 5.2 million Americans have gotten a shot.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, there will be institutions, there will be private-sector companies, and others who make decisions about how to keep their communities safe.&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s certainly appropriate, but I would just note that we&#8217;re going to continue our efforts to go community by community, case by case to convey the accurate information about the efficacy of vaccines.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gotcha.&nbsp; Secondly, the Taliban has said that, as a condition for peace in Afghanistan, Ashraf Ghani has to be removed as President and a new negotiated government formed.&nbsp; Does the administration believe that that&#8217;s in the best interest of the Afghan people and U.S. national security?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the President and the administration supports the leadership of the Afghan people, including Ashraf Ghani.&nbsp; The President was scheduled to speak with him today, I believe, and I don&#8217;t believe there&#8217;s a readout that&#8217;s come out about that call quite yet.&nbsp; It may while we&#8217;re speaking here.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that there are ongoing political negotiations and discussions that we certainly support between Afghan leaders, members of the Afghan government, and the Taliban.&nbsp; And we believe a political solution is the only outcome to lasting peace in Afghanistan, but we will continue to provide support to the government in the form of humanitarian support, security support, training.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll also continue to encourage them to take a leading role in defending and protecting their own people.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Alabama&#8217;s Republican governor says it is &#8220;time to start blaming the unvaccinated folks&#8221; who &#8220;are letting us down.&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp; What do you think about that take?&nbsp; Should the administration be taking a sharper tone against unvaccinated people for putting vaccinated people at risk?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think our role is to place blame, but what we can do is provide accurate information to people who are not yet vaccinated about the risks they are incurring not only among &#8212; on themselves, but also the people around them.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And while, if you are a young person, you may think you&#8217;re Superman or Superwoman and immune from the &#8212; from getting the virus, that is not true.&nbsp;&nbsp; That is not accurate.&nbsp;&nbsp; You can get very sick.&nbsp; You can die from the virus.&nbsp;&nbsp; You can also make your grandparents sick and your parents sick.&nbsp; That is factual information.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re not &#8212; but we&#8217;re not here to place blame or threats; we&#8217;re here to provide accurate information.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; She says that she doesn&#8217;t know what else she can do at this point, that she&#8217;s hit a brick wall with trying to convince people to get vaccinated.&nbsp; Is that a sign that perhaps the federal government should step in and issue mandates?&nbsp; And if not, are you putting the needs of unvaccinated people ahead of the needs of vaccinated people?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think the question here &#8212; one, that&#8217;s not the role of the federal government; that is the role that institutions, private-sector entities, and others may take.&nbsp; That certainly is appropriate.&nbsp; Also, local communities are going to take steps they need to take in order to protect people in their communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will say: We understand her frustration, and we understand the frustration of leaders out there and public voices who are trying to say the right thing, advocate for the efficacy of the virus, save people in their communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>What our role is and what we are going to continue to do is make the vaccine available.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to work in partnership to fight misinformation.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to advocate and work in partnership with local officials and &#8212; and trusted voices to get the word out.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there something to be learned from our neighbors to the north &#8212; Canada?&nbsp; They got a much slower start.&nbsp; They didn&#8217;t have nearly as many vaccines as we did early on.&nbsp; And yet, now they&#8217;ve shot past us, and 70 percent of their population is at least partially vaccinated.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the difference between the two countries?&nbsp; What can we learn from their experience?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say 162 million Americans are now vaccinated.&nbsp; That certainly is a positive step.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the first to say and we have long said that that&#8217;s not enough.&nbsp; We need to ensure more people and more communities are vaccinated.&nbsp; And it is now &#8212; we reached a point where there are some communities, even states, where there are 70 percent, 80 percent, or higher vaccination rates.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Other communities where there&#8217;s 40 percent, 50 percent, or otherwise, that&#8217;s not just a health issue &#8212; it&#8217;s a huge health issue &#8212; it&#8217;s an economic issue.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen how that can impact local communities, as it may lead to shutdowns of different businesses.&nbsp; That can have &#8212; it&#8217;s an economic issue as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, of course, we work in close partnership with our neighbors, but we have 162 million Americans vaccinated.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the world&#8217;s largest provider of vaccines to the global community.&nbsp; That&#8217;s progress, in our view, even as we&#8217;ve said from the beginning there&#8217;s more work to be done.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; About the economics of COVID that you just mentioned: Now that daily doses administered of the vaccine are down below 300,000 for the first time since December, we&#8217;ve heard talk about maybe updating the mask guidance.&nbsp; Do you know if there&#8217;s been any talk here about updating guidance to start shutting businesses down in places that have very low vaccination rates?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; There has not been, no.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then on crime, generally &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Can I note, though, two things &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; just for your public information purposes?&nbsp; One is that, while we have seen &#8212; while we don&#8217;t look at one week of data as an indication of &#8212; as you know, we talk about weekly averages &#8212; we did see larger numbers of unemployment claims in areas where there are lower vaccination rates.&nbsp; We &#8212; it&#8217;s not enough data to draw a conclusion; I&#8217;m just noting it for all of you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that, on the American Rescue Plan, the way we designed that is for the impact and the assistance that we&#8217;re providing to communities across the country to be long-lasting &#8212; not to stop all in July or all in September.&nbsp; It extends far beyond.&nbsp; It was &#8212; that is a lesson learned from the past.&nbsp; And so, there are different components of that package that&#8217;s providing assistance to businesses, to organizations, to communities that is going to be lasting for months to come.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Proceed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on crime: The intersection in D.C. that was shot up last night, only about a mile and a half from here,&nbsp; President Biden had lunch in that neighborhood this summer.&nbsp; What is your message to innocent people who live in cities like this one who might start to get worried about getting caught in the crossfire?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; the message is that the cornerstone of the President&#8217;s comprehensive plan to reduce gun violence is providing communities with the tools and resources they need to reduce gun crime, including in Washington, D.C.<br>&nbsp;<br>And there are a couple of steps specific to Washington D.C.&nbsp; I mean, a lot of us live there or live in the neighboring communities, or know people who are on 14th street or in the neighboring areas.&nbsp; And for people who are not &#8212; who are watching or hearing this who are not from those neighborhoods, there&#8217;s a lot of restaurants there, a lot of foot traffic.&nbsp; This is a pretty popular part of &#8212; of the city many of us live in.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s one of &#8212; D.C. is one of the five areas nationwide where DOJ launched gun trafficking strike forces just yesterday, which are going to for- &#8212; focus law enforcement resources across jurisdictions to keep guns out of the hands of criminals.<br>&nbsp;<br>D.C. is also a part of our 16 City Community Violence Intervention Collaborative, which is helping cities implement evidence-based strategies and which have been shown to reduce violence by as much as 60 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Washington D.C. is also taking advantage of the historic funding that they&#8217;ve gotten through the Rescue Plan to bolster public safety.&nbsp; So, Mayor Bowser&#8217;s budget proposal would invest $59 million from the Rescue Plan to reduce violent crime.&nbsp; It would add 100 new slots to the cadet program and add $14 million for youth safety initiatives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re certainly seeing this and feeling this, even in our community here, and it is one of the cities that DOJ is focused on.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you just mentioned the White House is working with D.C. as part of this collaborative.&nbsp; But just in the last week and a half or so since the mayor of D.C. was here, a six-year-old girl was shot and killed, a Nationals game had to be evacuated, and then there&#8217;s this incident last night where diners are diving for cover.&nbsp; So, at what point would the President maybe reconsider his strategy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say we&#8217;re just implementing our strategy, which is a multi-pronged effort to work in partnership with local leaders &#8212; including Mayor Bowser, who has been a great partner to us in this effort &#8212; to address gun violence that&#8217;s rising in cities across the country, including Washington.&nbsp; And the events of the last week are just examples of that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Secretary Yellen just said, before you came to the podium, that the Treasury Department will need to take extraordinary measures if the debt limit isn&#8217;t raised by August.&nbsp; And she indicated those could run out shortly after lawmakers return, possibly as soon as October.&nbsp; So, does the White House &#8212; are you guys setting a deadline?&nbsp; Before recess, do you want to see that debt limit raised?&nbsp; And what is the White House doing to urge lawmakers to address the debt limit?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This is like the Olympics for Bloomberg, these days.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, I would say &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Reuters.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And Reuters, sorry.&nbsp; And other financial outlets in the room.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me give you just a little bit of context, for those of you who have not seen the letter that just went from Secretary Yellen to the Hill.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is a letter that’s standard practice for Treasury Secretaries when a debt limit is going to be reimposed, which there&#8217;s a timeline coming up at the end of this month.&nbsp; That is diff- &#8212; I&#8217;m not saying you&#8217;re suggesting this &#8212; that is different&nbsp;from defaulting, which has never happened in the history of the United States and would clearly be a catastrophic event.&nbsp; But it is a timeline for the debt limit to be &#8212; to be raised or extended.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, during the previous two administrations, the Treasury Secretary sent nearly 50 letters to the Hill on the debt limit, some of which were very similar in wording and asks and updates to this letter.&nbsp; And raising or suspending the debt limit does not authorize new spending commitments; it simply enables the government to pay for obligations that Congresses and Presidents of both parties have already approved.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And Congress &#8212; finally the last piece of history &#8212; has raised or suspended the debt limit approximately 80 times, which has happened under both Republican and Democratic Presidents &#8212; I will say, just for historical fact, more often under Republican Presidents.<br>&nbsp;<br>But it has happened under both, and it has been supported in a bipartisan way.&nbsp; So, we expect Congress to act promptly to raise or suspend the debt limit and protect the full faith and credit of the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, it is not &#8212; I gave you all the context because it is not out of the ordinary, even though they&#8217;re called “extraordinary measures,” for Treasury Secretaries to present to Capitol Hill steps that they are going to take, even as this is being litigated on Capitol Hill.&nbsp; That was the &#8212; this is what &#8212; that was what this update was to provide.<br>&nbsp;<br>In that letter, she also noted that the period of time that extraordinary measures may last is subject to considerable uncertainty due to a variety of factors, which are exacerbated this year by uncertainty related to the pandemic and calculations about inflows and outflows.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the October timeline that she &#8212; was referenced in there &#8212; or the October 1st date, I should say, was referenced &#8212; was because there&#8217;s a very large reduction in the cash balance on October 1st &#8212; or we&#8217;re projecting that &#8212; due to outflows on that day to meet our obligations to the Department of Defense.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, she was giving a sense of what the timeline looks like, while not &#8212; while also conveying that we can&#8217;t give a sense, at this point, on the length of time for extraordinary measures.&nbsp; We certainly expect Congress to act in a bipartisan manner, as they did three times under the prior administration, to raise the debt limit.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But given that uncertainty, is the White House communicating to congressional leaders that you&#8217;d like to see this debt limit extended before the recess for August?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not here to set a new deadline.&nbsp; I&#8217;m conveying to you the history and conveying to you that we think it&#8217;s clear Congress should act in a bipartisan manner to raise the debt limit as they have in the past.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one more on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework.&nbsp; Is the White House getting involved in this dispute between Democrats and Republicans over transit funding?&nbsp; And are you recommending any solutions as to how that should be resolved?&nbsp; Are you backing Democrats who say it should remain with the 80/20 highway transit split?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, transit funding is obviously extremely important to the President &#8212; the “Amtrak President,” as we may call him.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we believe that &#8212; that members can get this work done and can work through these issues quite quickly.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as you know, the issue is about the balance of funding and how it would be allocated between different forms of infrastructure.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re encouraged by their progress, they&#8217;re having conversations, and we believe they can work through any disagreement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m just going to go to the back because I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m not always good at that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Mike Memoli, do you have a question today?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, Jen.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve&nbsp;talked a lot with &#8212; (laughter) &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You didn&#8217;t raise your hand, but usually have a question.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I often do.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked about &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go to the back, back too.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now everyone is into it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked a lot about this, this week &#8212; the protocols that are in place at the White House &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to ensure the President&#8217;s safety in &#8212; with COVID-19.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve seen over the last few weeks the President has been traveling the country quite a bit.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been engaging in more uncontrolled environments.&nbsp; He went to an ice cream stop.&nbsp; He was on a rope line for almost an hour in Philly last week.&nbsp; He&#8217;s doing a campaign event today.&nbsp; And we &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Best hour he&#8217;s spent probably in probably a while.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given &#8212; I remember well how COVID changed the way he would campaign &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; last year, what &#8212; to what extent is the rise in cases that we&#8217;re seeing in this country leading any discussions behind the scenes about whether the President would continue to engage in this kind of activity in public settings where you can&#8217;t control for people&#8217;s vaccinations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, we&#8217;re always going to abide by public health guidelines.&nbsp; And right now, the public health guidelines continue to be that if you&#8217;re vaccinated &#8212; and we expect them to continue to be &#8212; if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you&#8217;re very much protected from severe illness from the virus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President will continue to be a model in following those guidelines and also engaging with the public in a manner that, one, is his role as President of the United States and is certainly aligned with and appropriate according to those guidelines.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you all know, he has an event later this evening with Governor &#8212; future governor, maybe &#8212; former Governor Terry McAuliffe in Virginia, where he will be certainly engaging with people and &#8212; with people of Virginia who are making decisions about their future leadership.&nbsp; But I expect he&#8217;ll be engaging as he did at events last week.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, nothing has changed about our approach or protocols over the past week or how you&#8217;ve seen him engage at the ice cream shop or at larger crowd events we&#8217;ve had.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then a question about infrastructure.&nbsp; With some key votes coming up, obviously, next week, again, we&#8217;ve seen the President not necessarily engaging in the kind of meetings at the White House with lawmakers on this specific set of proposals in the way we have earlier on in the process.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been meeting more with outside stakeholders.&nbsp; It seems like there&#8217;s an outside-in pressure campaign.&nbsp; But can you give us an update on what his specific conversations might be with lawmakers involved in this process?&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t really heard much about that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has had a range of conversations with lawmakers over the phone.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s always conveyed to his team that if it would be helpful to bring members down here, as he has continued to do, he&#8217;s always happy to do that.&nbsp; The door to the Oval Office is always open.&nbsp; And he is available and will be through the course of the weekend, but also through the coming pivotal weeks as we work to get the infrastructure package across the finish line in the Senate and also the reconciliation bill moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, we&#8217;re going to go all the way to the very back.&nbsp; Todd Gillman, I see you somewhere there.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; So, the Texas Democrats who broke quorum from the legislature have &#8212; they&#8217;re about halfway through their one-month quorum break.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been trying really hard to get into a meeting, even if it&#8217;s a Zoom meeting, with the President.&nbsp; Is he going to meet with them?&nbsp; Is he specifically not meeting with them because of fears that they are spreading COVID?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, he &#8212; the Vice President, who is leading our voting rights effort and our voting rights movement we&#8217;re building across the country, met with these lawmakers last week, as you all know.&nbsp; And the President is very proud of their activism, their vocal support and advocacy for voting rights, but I don&#8217;t have any meetings scheduled for him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And in a kind of similar vein regarding COVID: Will the First Lady be quarantined away from the President when she gets back from Japan?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The First Lady will ca- &#8212; follow all public health guidelines.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe that&#8217;s part of the protocols.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>All right, let&#8217;s go &#8212; let&#8217;s see &#8212; to the middle here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just jumping around today because, you know, trying better.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House have a reaction to Mississippi&#8217;s decision ask the Supreme Court to overturn Roe v. Wade?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly, we are prominent sup- &#8212; or we are supporters &#8212; the President is a supporter of preserving Roe v. Wade.&nbsp; That is our position.&nbsp; In terms of a legisla- &#8212; or a legal reaction, I would point you to the Department of Justice.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let&#8217;s go to you, Patsy.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a question on China.&nbsp; China just announced sanctions &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; against six individuals and an entity in the U.S. in retaliation of sanctions imposed by the Biden administration on Chinese officials over Hong Kong.&nbsp; Do you think that this announcement will complicate or impact any plans for Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman&#8217;s visit to Tianjin?&nbsp; And is the administration concerned on the escalating sanctions &#8212; a potential escalating sanctions war?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I&#8217;m not aware of any changes to her planned trip.&nbsp; And certainly, we discussed not only areas where we agree, but areas where we disagree when we have engagements and diplomatic meetings.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the sanctions, we are aware, of course, of the reports that the PRC has imposed sanctions on several individuals and NGOs, including at least one official from the previous administration.&nbsp; We’re undeterred by these actions and we remain fully committed to implementing all relevant U.S. sanctions authorities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These actions are the latest examples of how Beijing punishes private citizens, companies, and civil society organizations as a way to send political signals and further illustrate the PRC’s deteriorating &#8212; deteriorating investment climate and rising political risk.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These actions would follow the baseless sanctioning in March of two commissioners from the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom.&nbsp; The PRC’s January sanctions on 21 &#8212; 28 U.S. officials and their July 2020 sanctions on U.S. officials and organizations promoting democracy and human rights around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Americans of both parties oppose these outrageous moves to target those who defend universal human rights and fundamental freedoms.&nbsp; And Beijing&#8217;s attempt to intimidate and bully internationally respected NGOs only demonstrate its further isolation from the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I do have another question on vaccine sharing.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s keep going &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to keep going around because &#8212; go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, in the back.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to keep going around so I get to more people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On vaccines.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’ve been asked about the travel restrictions for international travel before &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but I&#8217;m going to try something different.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would the President drop those restrictions if airlines adopted vaccine passports or vaccine mandates?&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve, you know, sort of encouraged businesses to take steps to get everyone vaccinated that they possibly can.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, first, that there are ongoing working groups that are having discussions about how to, hopefully, move forward to a point where there is international travel and is returning something we would all like to see &#8212; not just for tourism, but for families to be reunited.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are a range of topics in those discussions that are ongoing.&nbsp; The President receives regular briefings on them, but we rely on public health and medical advice on when we&#8217;re going to determine changes to be made.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President continued engaging with Chancellor Merkel on the subject?&nbsp; I know they talked about that at the bilateral press conference the other week.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That was raised.&nbsp; He has not had another follow-up conversation with her since that point in time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Why don&#8217;t I go to the young man next to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You know, a lot of parents are concerned about the upcoming school year.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House doing to sort of make sure that we&#8217;re not &#8212; we&#8217;re not doing remote learning again nationwide?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our plan and our objective and our desire and commitment is to push for and ensure 100 percent of schools are open across the country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s also, of course, up to school districts to implement.<br>&nbsp;<br>But from the federal government, the role we have played is by work &#8212; advocating for funding in the American Rescue Plan that can help provide funding for mitigation measures for schools so that they can invest in social distancing opportunities or repairing vents that need to improve ventilation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re also &#8212; we&#8217;ve also put out public health guidance from the CDC that includes specific mitigation measures that schools can take.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And our Secretary of Education has been focused on this issue from the first day he was sworn into office &#8212; working across school districts to share best practices and ensure we can work towards returning kids to in-school learning.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Delta doesn&#8217;t change that, right?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Delta has not changed our public health guidelines, no.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, let&#8217;s go back to the front, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick follow-up on infrastructure.&nbsp; On the transit spending &#8212; we know that&#8217;s important to the President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; is that a red line for him?&nbsp; If that is dropped from this package, would he still support it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not setting red lines here, but we are confident that they can work through the funding issues and that &#8212; the breakdown of funding issues between Democrats and Republicans over the coming days.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one other question just on Alabama, and then I have one on Hunter Biden.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On Alabama, the big concern here &#8212; and the reason why these comments from the governor are so alarming is because of the low vaccination rates.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So, is there some concern from the White House?&nbsp; And does the administration fear that some elected leaders may just get so frustrated and accept this fact that there are just some people in this country that just may not want to get vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I didn&#8217;t hear those comments as accepting the fact.&nbsp; I heard those comments as being frustrated that &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s an effort to protect the citizens in your state and trying to figure out what steps you can take to encourage people to get vaccinated and save their lives and the lives of their loved ones.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We always knew it would be harder as more people got vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the stage we&#8217;re in now.&nbsp; But we also believe that there is still opportunity through a range of approaches and tactics and partnerships with governors and leaders and civic leaders to get more people vaccinated. There a range of factors &#8212; you all &#8212; many of you have reported on &#8212; that are leading individuals in these five states with lower vaccination rates to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Some are &#8212; is the Delta variant; and reporting, frankly; and fears of the transmissibility of the Delta variant.&nbsp; Some is, unfortunately, individuals are experiencing people in their communities, family members who are getting sick and getting hospitalized because of the transmissibility of the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I don’t think we have com- &#8212; complex data quite yet to determine what is leading to the increase in vaccination rates in some of these states, but we think that&#8217;s an encouraging sign.&nbsp; We know it&#8217;s frustrating.&nbsp; We get it.&nbsp; But we have to stay at it to save people&#8217;s lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last, on Hunter Biden: You confirmed yesterday that he will be meeting with prospective buyers, but you also said that he&#8217;s not going to have any conversation related &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not that he&#8217;s meeting with prospective buyers &#8212; that he is attending gallery events that had been prior me- &#8212; prior planned and announced.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There could be prospective buyers there.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s not &#8212; those discussions will be happening with the gallerist.&nbsp; But that is different than meeting with prospective buyers.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If there are prospective buyers there, you said, yesterday, that he is not going to have any conversations related to the selling of art.&nbsp; How can the administration guarantee that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The selling of his art will all happen through galler- &#8212; the gallerist, and the names and individuals will be kept confidential.&nbsp; We will not be aware of, neither will he be aware of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything stopping anyone from directly telling, though, Hunter Biden that they&#8217;re going to purchase his art?&nbsp; And if they do, the American people won&#8217;t know who they are.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He will not know, we will not know who purchases his art.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Jeff.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said yesterday that the 25-person COVID group is quote, &#8220;investigating every aspect of any change.&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp; What specifically are they doing or is he looking for them to do in regards to the Delta variant?&nbsp; What information is he looking for them to bring back to him?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean the CDC &#8212; or discussions with our public health experts?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think what he was conveying, Jeff, is that he gets regular weekly, if not more frequent, updates from his COVID team about what is happening with the virus, the rise of certain variants, including the Delta variant, and certainly steps that they suggest we take as a result.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an ongoing process. That&#8217;s not new.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think he&#8217;s, of course, looking for their updates and guidance on what the spread is, where we&#8217;re seeing the spread, what impacts we&#8217;re having, and any mitigation measures they recommend we take from a public health and data-driven perspective.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On testing specifically, does the President believe that more testing should be done?&nbsp; It&#8217;s fallen some 75 percent or so since November.&nbsp; What specifically do you think should be done or does he think should be done on testing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He relies on the guidance of his health and medical experts.&nbsp; If they are advising that that is a factor, then certainly his role would be to advocate for expanding it if &#8212; in his role as President, but that they obviously provide recommendations publicly as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And final thing here: You said it&#8217;s not your role to place blame, but a President has a remarkable ability to use the bully pulpit, pick up the telephone.&nbsp; It happens all the time with &#8212; with corporations and things.&nbsp; What is he doing specifically with celebrities, perhaps, or with business leaders &#8212; like we saw the NFL this week &#8212; to use his power of the office to try and get some companies or groups to do mandates or make changes?&nbsp; Is he doing anything himself &#8212; reaching out like this?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean, aside from getting &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Aside from public speeches.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; aside from getting enough vaccine to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; make sure every American is vaccinated; and donating more to the world than any other country; and ensuring we&#8217;re expanding accessibility to pharmacies, to community groups; and giving $3 billion to empower local voices to get into local communities to get people vaccinated?&nbsp; I&#8217;d say that&#8217;s a fair amount that he&#8217;s done.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you said, several times, that it&#8217;s not the role of the government to, essentially, you know, talk to private corporations.&nbsp; But a President talks to corporations and leaders all the time, certainly during the Rescue Plan, when he was Vice President.&nbsp; It happened all the time &#8212; talking to private corporations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If a corner is to be turned here on the hesitancy, is there anything that he believes that he personally can do among some different leaders &#8212; not giving a public speech, but that he can do?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think, I referenced the $3 billion because the most powerful and impactful role we&#8217;ve seen across the country, from community to community, is engaging, educating, and empowering those trusted local voices.<br>&nbsp;<br>We know the President, the Vice President, Olivia Rodrigo, who we&#8217;re very grateful to, and others have been out there advocating for the efficacy of the vaccine, and we&#8217;re hopeful that&#8217;s effective.&nbsp; And it can be.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll continue to do that, and we&#8217;ll continue to look to partner with more voices and more creative, you know, well-known individuals to elevate the issue of vaccine &#8212; of the effectiveness of the vaccine.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;ve seen that’s &#8212; that, actually, local voices &#8212; people you may not know, who may not have a Twitter following &#8212; are actually the most powerful people in this fight, and we&#8217;ll continue to empower and fund those efforts.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, Jeff, go ahead.&nbsp; And then, I&#8217;ll go to Karen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Pfizer says the U.S. government is purchasing another 200 million doses of its vaccine &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for children and for potential booster shots.&nbsp; Can you confirm the purchase? &nbsp;And can you say whether the thinking about the need for booster shots is crystallized within the administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First, HHS has all the specifics, but, yes, we have made that purchase.&nbsp; Here&#8217;s the bottom line: We&#8217;ve always prepared for every scenario.&nbsp; The federal government is exercising an option in its contract with Pfizer to purchase these 200 million doses of the Pfizer vaccine to be delivered between the fall of 2021 and the spring of 2022 to prepare for future vaccination needs, including &#8212; as you referenced, Jeff &#8212; vaccines for children under 12 and possible booster shots, if studies show they are necessary.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will note, I have said from the podium many times that we were like Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts, and we were going to prepare for every contingency.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the job of the federal government &#8212; right? &#8212; to ensure we have maximum flexibility.<br>&nbsp;<br>We don&#8217;t know if we&#8217;ll need a booster shot.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to be up to the research that&#8217;s ongoing with the FDA.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a recommendation that&#8217;s currently made.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also don&#8217;t know &#8212; we also can&#8217;t predict what the outcome will be of research on kids under 12.&nbsp; We&#8217;re certainly hopeful.&nbsp; And we don&#8217;t know which vaccine will be most effective, but we want to have maximum flexibility, so this is an effort to provide us with that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And just one on infrastructure.&nbsp; We understand that Senate negotiators are looking at repurposing COVID relief funds for hospitals and nursing homes to pay for the &#8212; parts of the bill.&nbsp; Is that something the White House would support?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s a range of final nitty-gritty discussions between both sides, but I&#8217;m not going to give feedback on each of the discussions from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, Asma, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karen’s turn.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karen, go.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, Karen, sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Apologies.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sort of keying off of what Jeff Zeleny was asking &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the NFL is telling teams that they could potentially forfeit games for a COVID outbreak among unvaccinated players, and the players could lose their pay for any missed games.&nbsp; Does the administration support a policy where players &#8212; or more broadly, employees &#8212; could lose pay if they are unvaccinated and cause a COVID outbreak at their place of work?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I&#8217;m not going to make a sweeping private-sector conclusion here.&nbsp; What I will say is the NFL policy is making clear how they&#8217;re going to proceed with their season.&nbsp; That&#8217;s their role to do.&nbsp; Right?<br>&nbsp;<br>We certainly believe the biggest takeaway is that getting vaccinated is our ticket back to normal, and that vaccines are effective and allow all of us a high degree of protection, importantly, avoid hospitalization or death.&nbsp; So, this provides &#8212; this is guidance they determined &#8212; the NFL &#8212; about how they&#8217;re going to proceed with their season.&nbsp; That is their role to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a new model out from an organization that consults with the CDC, and it&#8217;s predicting that the current surge in cases right now could continue until a peak in mid-October.&nbsp; The daily deaths potentially more than tripling where they are right now.&nbsp; What can the President do right now to prepare Americans for that possibility?&nbsp; He talked so much about the long winter last year.&nbsp; What about a potentially long fall?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think the President&#8217;s role right now is to continue to encourage people to get vaccinated because it is incredibly effective in prodect [sic] &#8212; protecting them from serious illness, from death, from hospitalization from the virus.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the most powerful role he can play at this point in time.<br>&nbsp;<br>George, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Jen.&nbsp; This morning, the Cleveland Indians announced they&#8217;re changing their name to &#8220;Guardians,&#8221; and that&#8217;s already become an issue in the Ohio Senate race.&nbsp; And the former President, just minutes ago, attacked it.&nbsp; Any reaction by the President or the White House?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly support their change of name.&nbsp; We may be on the other side of the President &#8212; former President &#8212; on that front, I would guess.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t seen his tweet, or however he&#8217;s communicating these days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions on the vaccine.&nbsp; First, you had mentioned yesterday that every individual at this White House has been, quote, &#8220;offered&#8221; a vaccine.&nbsp; So, can you clarify, is the administration not mandating vaccines for White House staff?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, we have not mandated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And do you have a count or can you offer any confirmation to us on the percentage of employees who are vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m not going to provide that.&nbsp; I will see if there is more information to provide.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you offer any guidance then on how you&#8217;re confirming vaccination status of employees?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, they&#8217;re vaccinated here in the White House Medical Unit, for the most part.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, Kelly, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll come to you next.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions: One, this administration has long claimed that you&#8217;re trying to be the most transparent in history.&nbsp; If that&#8217;s the case, why won&#8217;t you just release the number of breakthrough cases that you&#8217;ve had of vaccinated staffers?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, first, we&#8217;re in a very different place than we were six to seven months ago as it relates to the virus.&nbsp; And as many medical experts have said &#8212; inside and outside of the government &#8212; those who are vaccinated are protected from serious illness, most are asymptomatic &#8212; if they are individuals who are vaccinated who get the virus.&nbsp; And, you know, we are in a different place in terms of the impact of individuals who may have, as you said, breakthrough cases.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But why not just provide the number?&nbsp; Are you trying to hide something?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, but what is the &#8212; why do you need to have that information?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s a case of transparency, in the interest of the public, knowing &#8212; having a better understanding of how breakthrough cases work here in the White House.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, there are &#8212; the CDC tracks &#8212; and let me give you this information, too: The CDC tracks, across the country, of course, hospitalizations and deaths, as we have seen.&nbsp; They also do a great deal of tracking in cohorts and ensure that &#8212; so, let me give you a little more information on this, which I think &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if it &#8212; hopefully, it&#8217;s of interest.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the way that &#8212; because people have asked this before &#8212; so, the way the CDC is actively tracking breakthrough cases &#8212; there are tens of thousands of people across the country, in course, who are in what we are &#8212; what they call &#8220;cohort studies,&#8221; which the CDC is actively monitoring.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, the CDC has a long-term care facility study where it is getting data from more than 14,000 long-term care facilities.&nbsp; CDC has a healthcare worker study where they monitor vaccinated healthcare workers who got tested &#8212; who get tested with PCR tests every single week.&nbsp; And CDC also collects what they call &#8220;passive surveillance,&#8221; which is where hospitals provide CDC with data when they identify someone who is hospitalized but has been vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>So there&#8217;s a range of means our public health officials are tracking, across the country, across D.C., across any individuals here about who is vaccinated, who is getting the virus, getting hospitalized &#8212; hopefully not; it remains a small percentage.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And following up on the questions about Hunter Biden and his art shows.&nbsp; Are there any specific procedures you can tell us that are being put in place to ensure that these conversations remain, as you say, not about the sales.&nbsp; Will he get ethics training?&nbsp; Will he have to report afterwards about the conversations?&nbsp; Anything specific you can tell us about how you are monitoring this?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think it is certainly a commitment that has been made by all parties involved.&nbsp; He is not involved in the sale or discussions about the sale of his art.&nbsp; And he will not be informed of the sale &#8212; of the sale of his art and who is purchasing that art.&nbsp; That is a commitment that&#8217;s been made, and we expect that all parties would abide by it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask about the CDC tracking &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; because &#8212; and you gave us some information just now, but &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; as of May 1st, they stopped tracking breakthrough cases that did not result in hospitalization or death, with the exception of those kinds of tests that you just described. Should there be a more broader net on breakthrough cases?&nbsp; Would the President support that to get a better picture of breakthrough?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And those White House employees, staff &#8212; EOP, on the campus in any capacity &#8212; who are not vaccinated, are they working here or are they working from home?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, any individual who has chosen not to be vaccinated, same as in the press corps, the public health guidance is to wear a mask.&nbsp; That is the public health guidance that&#8217;s provided to employees as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the &#8212; it is much more expensive than hospitalizations that &#8212; that was what I was trying to convey. &nbsp;What the CDC does is they have these &#8212; they tra- &#8212; actively track breakthrough cases through these cohorts of individuals who are vulnerable populations, who are hi- &#8212; have high risks of exposure. And they, of course, incl- &#8212; as I noted &#8212; long-term care facilities, healthcare workers, and others who would be in those cohorts and categories.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that because the vast majority of individuals who are vaccinated who get &#8212; test positive for COVID may be asymptomatic or have moderate or minimal cases, those are cases we may not know &#8212; we may not know about, right?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But they&#8217;re &#8212; the CDC says, as of May 1st, they stopped tracking breakthrough cases that don’t result in hospitalizations.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They do track through these cohorts, which is a large swath of people who would be vulnerable or on the frontlines of exposure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My periodic question: It’s now past &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; six months.&nbsp; When can we expect to know about a physical exam for the President?&nbsp; And what are the plans for that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is &#8212; absolutely he will have a physical exam.&nbsp; Absolutely you will know about the physical exam.&nbsp; I don’t have a date for you at this point in time.&nbsp; And I expect you will continue to ask, as you should.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, Jen, thank you.&nbsp; This is sort of a rhetorical question &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; following up on vaccinations.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is a shame that people have to get very sick and some people have to die in order to increase the vaccination rate in many parts of this country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But isn&#8217;t that, I guess, a logical order of how this would play out?&nbsp; Or is there a political component to it, do you think?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m following your question.&nbsp; Try again.&nbsp; Or tell me more about what you&#8217;re looking for.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, wouldn&#8217;t it be standard practice that people, if more people are getting sick in a certain area, that the people in that area who are unvaccinated would say, “Gee, I really need to go get vaccinated.”&nbsp; Isn&#8217;t that a logical order for this?&nbsp; Or is there a political component, do you think, that has kept people away from being vaccinated?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think there are a range of reasons we&#8217;ve seen across the country why individuals have not yet been vaccinated.&nbsp; Some of it is misinformation &#8212; a large amount, in our view.&nbsp; Some of it is fear.&nbsp; Some of it is, they may feel, time.&nbsp; Some of it is they&#8217;re young, and they feel they&#8217;re Superman or Superwoman, and they&#8217;re not going to get sick.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That shouldn&#8217;t be; we don&#8217;t want that to be the order of events.&nbsp; It shouldn&#8217;t be that someone should have to know a neighbor who gets sick and hospitalized to motivate them to go to a hospital &#8212; I mean to go to get vaccinated.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t want that to be the case.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have seen anecdotally and through some of your &#8212; all of your reporting that that has been the case in some communities.&nbsp; But certainly, our objective is to communicate to people this is not a political issue, it is not a partisan issue; this is about protecting lives.&nbsp; The virus does not discriminate between political party affiliation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The White House noted yesterday that 40 percent of cases are coming from three states with low vaccination rates: Florida, Texas, and Missouri.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>All three of those states have governors who, in recent weeks, have criticized the White House&#8217;s strategy.&nbsp; One of them is even fundraising off of it, as you are probably aware.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What&#8217;s being done to engage those governors, come up with a common message, common strategy to try and be one team with those governors in terms of fighting this virus?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, our public health experts work with governors from across the country and work with local health officials from across the country in all of these states, especially the ones at this point in time where there are lower vaccination rates and we&#8217;re seeing the Delta variant spread.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this is one of the reasons we rely so much on &#8212; hold on, I’m going to sneeze.&nbsp; Okay, hold on.&nbsp; Okay, maybe it will come back.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; This is wh- &#8212; sorry, (inaudible) &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is why we rely on local messengers and why we rely on trusted voices.&nbsp; Because whether it&#8217;s the President of the United States or the governor, sometimes those aren&#8217;t the people you trust.&nbsp;&nbsp; Sometimes that is too political or partisan for people.&nbsp; We understand that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s why we rely on and we&#8217;re funding and empowering local, trusted voices who aren&#8217;t seen through a political prism.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the West Coast right now, we’re seeing wildfires in Oregon and Northern California.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What steps is the administration taking to combat the current fires and also prevent additional fires this summer?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I appreciate you asking about this because I know this has gotten a lot of attention across the country, and we just haven&#8217;t talked about it a lot.&nbsp; There&#8217;s so much going on.<br>&nbsp;<br>One, the President receives regular reports on the wildfire situation; he&#8217;s quite focused on it.&nbsp; As I think you&#8217;re probably aware but others may not be, the National Wild- &#8212; Wildland Fire Preparedness Level is at a five, which is the highest level due to significant fire activity.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as of today, 2.5 million acres have burned across the United States in the past two weeks alone.&nbsp; The number of large, uncontained fires across the United States has increased by nearly 90 percent.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, right now, what we&#8217;re doing: One, the President is very focused on this and wants regular updates.&nbsp; He&#8217;s regularly met with Western governors, and I expect we&#8217;ll do that again soon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The FEMA Administrator is visiting Idaho, Oregon, and California this week to meet with state, federal, and Tribal partners and emergency groups about worsen &#8212; the worsening wildfire situation, to coordinate response efforts and discuss how the regions are addressing climate change and ongoing resilience work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are also closely coordinating with officials on the frontlines to provide federal assistance as needed, including by recently approving Fire Management Assistance Grants for fire departments in Oregon, California, and Washington, which are where there&#8217;s the collective threat to homes and major communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;re also continuing to monitor the &#8212; monitor these fires from here.&nbsp; Again, the President receives regular updates and he&#8217;s quite focused on this.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Cuba &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Congresswoman Salazar says that the administration could turn the Internet back on for Cubans within minutes.&nbsp; I guess there&#8217;s this technology to allow high-tech balloons to float over Cuba to act as towers.&nbsp; What&#8217;s being done?&nbsp; Or can you provide an update on restoring Internet services to Cuba?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wish it was that easy.&nbsp; We are exploring a range of options.&nbsp; We are quite focused and interested in restoring Internet access to the people of Cuba, which we actually &#8212; which we absolutely believe, and agree, I would say, would provide information, would allow individuals to communicate.&nbsp; And we feel if we can get it done, that would be a great step forward and beneficial to the people of Cuba.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, ma’am.&nbsp; You mentioned at the top that&nbsp; Republicans had also increased the debt ceiling and certainly, you know, spending has been bipartisan for many years.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering what the President&#8217;s long-term view of the country&#8217;s balance sheets are, given that under current long-term CBO estimates, debt is never again expected to dip below 100 percent of gross domestic product, and then, within 30 years, it is projected to hit 202 percent of gross domestic product.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say the President has proposed a way to pay for his proposals, which is something that is a fiscally responsible step some of his predecessors &#8212; the most recent one &#8212; did not do when he worked and advocated to support the passing of $2 trillion in tax cuts that did not bear out the financial benefit he promised and also certainly added to the deficit.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President takes these issues seriously.&nbsp; He is focused on being a President who cares about the future of our &#8212; the next generations.&nbsp; And I think his actions have borne that out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then a quick follow-up:&nbsp; There was a lot of discussion about masking the other day.&nbsp; This administration has always followed CDC guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If the CDC was to say, “We need to return to masking,” would this administration follow suit?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re always going to follow the guidance of our health and medical experts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the vaccine immunity: Given that Pfizer&#8217;s now seeing waning immunity and separate from who is vaccinated and who is not, is the White House looking at models and projections that say, in the next year, as everyone who has been vaccinated could start to lose that immunity, what does that look like for hospitalizations and deaths, et cetera?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would certainly point to our health and medical experts to answer questions about future projections about the impact of waning immunity.&nbsp; I will say that as they look at this data and assess from our &#8212; from the CDC and other public health entities in the government, they certainly talked to private-sector companies like Pfizer, but that&#8217;s only one source of data and engagement.&nbsp; They look at a range of data across the board as they make projections.&nbsp; So we really rely on their broad data and projections as we assess what the future looks like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a follow-up on Afghanistan as well: You mentioned continuing U.S. support.&nbsp; Does that include continuing military support?&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;ve seen a number of airstrikes that the U.S. has launched on Taliban targets over the last 30 days.&nbsp; Could that continue past the end of the military mission at the end of August?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything on that for you.&nbsp; I&#8217;d certainly point to the Department of Defense.&nbsp; But what I&#8217;m &#8212; what I was communicating about was, you know, over the coming weeks, we maintain our authorities, as you know, and we provide &#8212; we’ve provided a range of training and security assistance equipment to the Afghans and the leaders of Afghanistan as we transition to bringing our men and women home.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thanks so much, everyone.&nbsp; Have a great weekend.<br>&nbsp;<br>2:04 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 19:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Presidential Delegation to the funeral of President Moise is safe and accounted for, and those traveling from Washington, D.C. have arrived safely back in the United States.&#160; The United States remains deeply concerned about the situation on the ground in Haiti. We strongly urge all parties to express themselves peacefully, and call on Haiti’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Presidential Delegation to the funeral of President Moise is safe and accounted for, and those traveling from Washington, D.C. have arrived safely back in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States remains deeply concerned about the situation on the ground in Haiti. We strongly urge all parties to express themselves peacefully, and call on Haiti’s leaders to be clear that their supporters must refrain from violence. In this critical moment, Haiti’s leaders must work together and engage in a broad and inclusive dialogue that is reflective of the will of the Haitian people. The Presidential Delegation, led by Ambassador Linda Thomas-Greenfield, and joined by Representative Meeks and Representative Fortenberry, met with senior Haitian officials and civil society leaders and shared this message directly.<br><br>The United States will continue to provide requested assistance, including equipment and training, to the Haitian National Police and the Government of Haiti amid ongoing security challenges. Additionally, the Departments of Justice and Homeland Security are providing investigative assistance to the Haitian authorities at the request of the Government of Haiti, and will keep working closely with our international partners to support the Haitian government as it seeks to hold accountable those responsible for the assassination of President Moïse.<br><br>The United States stands with the people of Haiti in this challenging time.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How the Biden-Harris Administration Is Advancing Educational Equity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/fact-sheet-how-the-biden-harris-administration-is-advancing-educational-equity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As Schools Reopen, Vital PK-12 Investments Will Address Disparities, Build Back Our Schools on a Stronger and More Equitable Foundation, and Enable America to Compete Globally The last year and a half have been extraordinarily challenging for America’s students. As we prepare for the 2021-2022 school year, the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to helping every&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>As Schools Reopen, Vital PK-12 Investments Will Address Disparities, Build Back Our Schools on a Stronger and More Equitable Foundation, and Enable America to Compete Globally</em></p>



<p><br>The last year and a half have been extraordinarily challenging for America’s students. As we prepare for the 2021-2022 school year, the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to helping every school safely open for full-time, in-person instruction; accelerate academic achievement; and build school communities where all students feel they belong. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, President Biden understands that addressing the immediate impact of the pandemic is not enough. For too many Americans—including students of color, children with disabilities, English learners, LGBTQ+ students, students from low-income families, and other underserved students—the promise of a high-quality education has gone unfulfilled for generations. Studies show the <a href="https://www.future-ed.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Gormley_et_al-2017-Journal_of_Policy_Analysis_and_Management.pdf">remarkable benefits of preschool programs</a>, but such programs are too often <a href="https://s3-us-east-2.amazonaws.com/edtrustmain/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/05162154/Young-Learners-Missed-Opportunities.pdf">out of reach</a> for children of color and low-income children. <a href="https://edtrust.org/resource/funding-gaps-2018/">Dramatically unequal funding</a> between school districts means some children learn in gleaming new classrooms, while students just down the road navigate <a href="https://eric.ed.gov/?id=ED498100">unsafe and rundown facilities</a>. Amid a <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">nationwide teacher shortage</a>, high-poverty school districts struggle to attract certified staff and experienced educators. And students of color and children with disabilities face disproportionately high rates&nbsp;<a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/crdc-exclusionary-school-discipline.pdf">of school discipline</a> that removes them from the classroom, with lasting consequences.<br><br><a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/cge">With 53 percent of our public school students</a> now students of color, addressing these disparities is critical for not only all our children, but for our nation’s collective health, happiness, and economic security. Consistent with the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-advancing-racial-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through-the-federal-government/">Executive Order</a>, the Administration is committed to advancing educational equity for every child—so that schools and students not only recover from the pandemic, but Build Back Better. As First Lady Dr. Biden says, “Any country that out-educates us is going to outcompete us.” We will meet the challenges of the coming decades only by harnessing the full potential of every young person.<br><br>Taken together, the unprecedented investments already made in the American Rescue Plan—along with those proposed in the Build Back Better Agenda—will devote historic and vitally-needed resources that unlock opportunity for millions of Americans. These investments in evidence-based approaches will shore up schools struggling with the aftermath of COVID-19, tackle inter-generational educational disparities, address the holistic needs of children, and incentivize states to help our schools rebuild on a stronger and more equitable foundation.<br><br>To support the equitable education of every child at every step, the Administration will:</p>



<ul><li>Safely reopen schools and support students, particularly those disproportionately impacted by the pandemic;<br></li><li>Invest in high-quality early childhood education, including providing universal pre-school for all three and four-year-olds and access to affordable child care;<br></li><li>Address the national teacher shortage by improving teacher preparation, strengthening pipelines for underrepresented teachers, and supporting current teachers;<br></li><li>Upgrade and build new public schools and child care centers;<br></li><li>Expand college and career pathways for middle and high school students;<br></li><li>Make a historic $20 billion investment in high-poverty Title I schools;<br></li><li>Fund additional transformational investments to support the needs of the whole child, including community schools that provide wraparound services like afterschool programs, and hiring more counselors, social workers and school psychologists.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>ADVANCING EDUCATIONAL EQUITY IN THE AMERICAN RESCUE PLAN</u></strong><br><br>The President made clear on <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/21/executive-order-supporting-the-reopening-and-continuing-operation-of-schools-and-early-childhood-education-providers/">Day One of this Administration</a> that safely reopening schools was a national priority, signing an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/21/executive-order-supporting-the-reopening-and-continuing-operation-of-schools-and-early-childhood-education-providers/">Executive Order</a> that launched a comprehensive effort across the White House, Department of Education, and Department of Health and Human Services to safely reopen schools. The Department of Education has worked to support states and school districts in implementing CDC guidance for safe operations, and engaged education leaders across the country to collect and share best practices. The Administration has prioritized K-12 educator, staff, and child care vaccinations, and increased access to and awareness of vaccines among adolescents and their parents.<br><br>States, school districts, and schools are supported in this work by the American Rescue Plan’s historic and needed investment in our schools. This included $130 billion to support the safe reopening of schools and address the academic, social, emotional, and mental health needs of students—including $122 billion through the American Rescue Plan’s Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief Fund (ARP ESSER). This funding is being used to help schools safely operate, implement high-quality summer learning and enrichment programs, hire nurses and counselors, support the vaccination of students and staff, and invest in other measures to take care of students. Thanks to these efforts—combined with the Administration’s aggressive vaccination push and the hard work of state, district, school leaders, educators, and parents—the percentage of K-8 schools offering only remote instruction dropped from 23 percent in January to only 2 percent in May.<br><br>The American Rescue Plan recognizes and addresses <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/20210608-impacts-of-covid19.pdf">the disproportionate impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on underserved students</a>. Districts and states must spend a combined minimum of 24 percent of total ARP ESSER funds on evidence-based practices to address lost instructional time and the impact of the coronavirus on underserved students, such as summer learning and enrichment programs, comprehensive afterschool programs, and tutoring. School and district leaders must ensure that these efforts respond to students’ social and emotional needs as well. ARP ESSER includes a first-of-its-kind maintenance of equity requirement to ensure that high-poverty school districts and schools are protected from funding cuts. The American Rescue Plan also includes additional funding for students with disabilities, students experiencing homelessness, Tribal education, nutrition security, broadband access, and child care for low-income families.<br><br><strong><u>ADVANCING EDUCATIONAL EQUITY IN THE BUILD BACK BETTER AGENDA</u></strong><br><br>The resources in the American Rescue Plan, however, are not enough to address the deep educational inequities that have existed in our country since its founding. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda directly addresses longstanding educational inequities and will revitalize our education system so that students have the opportunities to learn and prepare for jobs in tomorrow’s economy, which includes ensuring the needs of the whole child are addressed.<br><br><strong><u>Make a historic investment to support students in high-poverty schools</u></strong>.<br>To ensure that every student—including those from underserved and under-resourced communities—can learn and thrive, the President’s discretionary budget request provides an additional $20 billion in funding for Title I schools. These investments will help address long-standing funding disparities between under-resourced school districts and wealthier districts:</p>



<ul><li><strong><em>Providing meaningful incentives to examine and address inequalities in school funding systems.</em></strong> There is a <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/overview/budget/budget22/justifications/a-ed.pdf">$23 billion annual funding gap</a> between white and nonwhite districts, and gaps between high- and low-poverty districts as well. A <a href="https://edtrust.org/resource/funding-gaps-2018/">2018 report from The Education Trust</a> found that the highest poverty districts receive 7 percent less per pupil in State and local funding than the lowest poverty districts.<br></li><li><strong><em>Promoting competitive teacher pay.</em></strong> In 2017, public school teachers <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/teacher-pay-gap-2018/">earned 18.7 percent less</a> in weekly wages than their peer group of college educated workers, up from only 1.8&nbsp;percent less in 1994. <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/education-k-12/reports/2014/07/23/94168/mid-and-late-career-teachers-struggle-with-paltry-incomes/">In many states, teachers with ten years of experience who head a household of four may qualify for public assistance.<br></a></li><li><strong><em>Increasing preparation for, access to, and success in rigorous coursework.</em></strong> Black and Native American students <a href="https://sites.ed.gov/underservedyouth/files/2017/01/MS3-Lead-Higher-Initiative-Finding-Americas-Missing-AP-and-IB-Students.pdf">participate in AP coursework at half</a> the national average<strong>.</strong> <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/crdc-course-access-report">While 87% of low-poverty schools provide calculus, only 45 percent of high-poverty schools do.</a> Lack of access to and preparation for success in mathematics and science coursework ultimately has a <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/education-k-12/news/2019/08/28/473876/advancing-racial-equity-career-technical-education-enrollment/">negative impact on the outcomes achieved by Black and Latino students in high-paying, in-demand STEM fields</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Boost early childhood care and education</u></strong><br>The President’s Build Back Better Agenda makes historic investments in our youngest learners, so that every child can succeed, paving the way for the best-educated generation in U.S. history.<br><br><strong><em>Establishing universal preschool</em></strong><br>Preschool is critical to ensuring that children start kindergarten with the skills and supports that set them up for success in school. However, <a href="https://s3-us-east-2.amazonaws.com/edtrustmain/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/05162154/Young-Learners-Missed-Opportunities.pdf">children of color are less likely to have access to high-quality preschool programs,</a><a href="https://nieer.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/NIEER-AchievementGaps-report.pdf%20with%20a%20furtherhttps:/nces.ed.gov/ecls/kindergarten2011.asp">resulting in disparate educational outcomes before students even enter kindergarten</a>. <a href="https://www.future-ed.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Gormley_et_al-2017-Journal_of_Policy_Analysis_and_Management.pdf">Research shows</a> that kids who attend preschool programs are more likely to take honors classes and less likely to repeat a grade, do better in <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/bpea-articles/the-impacts-of-expanding-access-to-high-quality-preschool-education/">math and reading</a>, <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w28756/w28756.pdf?utm_campaign=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_medium=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_source=PANTHEON_STRIPPED">and are more likely to graduate from high school and enroll in college</a>. Impacts are particularly strong for <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w23215/w23215.pdf">children from low-income families</a>, and children with disabilities benefit from inclusive, accessible preschool programs with their peers<a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w23215/w23215.pdf">.</a><br><br>President Biden’s plan would establish a national partnership with states to offer free, high-quality, accessible, and inclusive preschool for all three-and four-year-olds. This will benefit five million children, and save the average family $13,000 a year on preschool tuition. This historic investment in America’s future will prioritize high-need areas first, establishing universal programs in these communities, so that all students can access them, facilitating the creation of diverse classrooms that are best for all students. It will also enable communities and families to choose the setting that works best for them, whether that’s a preschool classroom in a public school, family child care provider or child care center, or a Head Start program. The President’s plan supports low student-to-teacher ratios, high quality standards, and inclusive classroom environments.<br><br><strong><em>Make high-quality child care affordable and accessible</em></strong><br>High-quality early care and education helps ensure that children can take full advantage of education and training opportunities later in life, especially for children from low-income families and children of color, who disproportionately <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/digest/d19/tables/dt19_202.30b.asp">lack access</a> to good child care options and who face <a href="https://rhyclearinghouse.acf.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/docs/18755-Disparities_in_Early_Learning_and_Development%5Bfull%5D.pdf">learning disparities</a> before they even can go to preschool. President Biden’s proposal will ensure that low- and middle-income families can access affordable, high-quality, child care. The most hard-pressed working families would pay nothing, and families earning 1.5 times their state’s median income would spend no more than 7 percent of their income on child care for their young children. The plan will also provide families with a range of inclusive and accessible options to choose from, from child care centers to family child care providers to Early Head Start programs. Child care providers will receive funding to support the true cost of quality early childhood education, which will allow them to provide care that is accessible and inclusive of children with disabilities.<br><br>The President’s investments in child care and preschool will also support early childhood educators, more <a href="https://nwlc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ChildCareWorkersFS.pdf">than nine in ten</a> of whom are women and more than <a href="https://nwlc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ChildCareWorkersFS.pdf">four in ten</a> of whom are women of color. <a href="https://cscce.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/ReportFINAL.pdf">One report found that nearly half</a> rely on public income support programs. The President’s plan establishes a $15 minimum wage for these educators and ensures those with similar qualifications as kindergarten teachers receive comparable compensation and benefits.<br><br>And the President’s proposal will extend the American Rescue Plan’s expanded Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit so that families can instead choose to get a credit for up to half of their child care expenses, saving up to $8,000 per year.<br><br><strong><u>Invest in our teachers.</u></strong> Few people have a bigger impact on a child’s life than a great teacher. Unfortunately, the U.S. faces a <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">large and growing teacher shortage</a>. Before the pandemic, <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">schools needed an estimated additional 100,000 certified teachers</a>, resulting in key positions going unfilled, the granting of emergency certifications, or teachers teaching out of their certification area. Shortages disproportionately impact <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">students of color </a>and rural communities. In schools with the highest percentage of students of color, the percentage of teachers who are uncertified is more than <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/understanding-teacher-shortages-interactive?gclid=EAIaIQobChMIlZbktfGP8AIVg-DICh10CQyXEAAYAiAAEgJgV_D_BwE">three times as large</a> as in schools with the lowest percentage of students of color. The percentage of teachers in their first or second year of teaching is <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/understanding-teacher-shortages-interactive?gclid=EAIaIQobChMIlZbktfGP8AIVg-DICh10CQyXEAAYAiAAEgJgV_D_BwE">70 percent higher</a>. While access to <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/Diversifying_Teaching_Profession_REPORT_0.pdf">teachers of color benefits all students and has a particularly strong impact on students of color</a>, only around <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat11.htm">one in five</a> teachers are people of color, compared to <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator_cge.asp">more than half</a> of public school students.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda will increase support for teacher preparation and invest in Grow Your Own programs and year-long, paid teacher residency programs. These programs have a significant impact on <a href="https://www.aft.org/sites/default/files/ae_spring2017guha_hyler_and_darling-hammond.pdf">student outcomes and teacher retention</a>, and <a href="https://www.aft.org/sites/default/files/ae_spring2017guha_hyler_and_darling-hammond.pdf">are more likely to enroll underrepresented teacher candidates, including candidates of color</a>. The plan would also invest in teacher preparation at Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and Minority-Serving Institutions. The President has also called for increased investments in certifications in high-demand areas like special education and bilingual education, and is urging Congress to invest in programs that leverage teachers as leaders, such as high-quality mentorship programs for new teachers. These investments will improve the quality of new teachers, increase retention rates, and grow the number of teachers of color—all of which will improve student outcomes like <a href="https://mrbartonmaths.com/resourcesnew/8.%20Research/Improving%20Teaching/Teaching%20Experience.pdf">academic achievement</a> and <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/Diversifying_Teaching_Profession_REPORT_0.pdf">high school graduation rates</a>, resulting in <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/Diversifying_Teaching_Profession_REPORT_0.pdf">higher long-term earnings, job creation, and a boost to the economy</a>. As more teachers stay in the profession, districts will <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/the-cost-of-teacher-turnover">save money</a> on recruiting and training, and can invest more in programs that directly impact students.<br><br><strong><u>Expand career pathways for middle and high school students.</u></strong><a href="https://ies.ed.gov/ncee/wwc/interventionreport/671">Strong dual enrollment programs</a> increase college enrollment, and graduation. High-quality career and technical education models have significant positive effects on <a href="https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED570132.pdf">high school graduation, increase college enrollment, and improve wages</a>. The President’s plan would provide more students with access to high-quality career and technical education programs that expand access to computer science; connect underrepresented students to careers in STEM and in in-demand, high-growth industry sectors; that include partnerships with institutions of higher education, employers, and other stakeholders; and that allow students to engage in quality work-based learning opportunities, earn a credential, and/or earn college credit.<br><br><strong><u>Eliminate inequitable school infrastructure conditions</u>. </strong>According to one national study, <a href="https://infrastructurereportcard.org/cat-item/schools/">there is a $38 billion gap</a> between the current infrastructure spending on schools and actual infrastructure needs. The <a href="https://infrastructurereportcard.org/cat-item/schools/">American Society of Civil Engineers gives American school infrastructure a grade of D+.</a><a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/letters/colleague-resourcecomp-201410.pdf">Students of color are more likely to attend schools with rundown and unsafe facilities</a>. <a href="https://ajph.aphapublications.org/doi/pdfplus/10.2105/AJPH.2009.165324">Poor physical school conditions are associated with increased rates of student absenteeism, with one study finding poor ventilation associated with a 10 to 20 percent increase in student absences</a>. While the American Rescue Plan provides critical resources for improving ventilation systems, it does not provide sufficient resources to address all health and safety needs, let alone long-overdue investments to increase energy efficiency, ensure our schools have the technology and labs to prepare students for jobs in tomorrow’s economy, or build new buildings where needed. President Biden’s plan supports investments to upgrade and build new public schools, ensuring that all our children have equal access to healthy learning environments that prepare them for success. It also invests in upgrading child care facilities and increasing the supply of child care in areas that need it most.<br><br><strong><u>Addressing lead in schools</u>. </strong>There is no safe level of lead exposure for children. Lead can slow development and cause learning, behavior, and hearing problems in children, as well as lasting kidney and brain damage. Communities of color are <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nceh/lead/prevention/populations.htm">at a higher risk</a> of lead exposure. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework would make significant investments towards the elimination of all lead pipes and service lines in the country, and reduce lead exposure in our schools and child care facilities, improving the health of our country’s children, including in communities of color.<br><br><strong><u>Increasing broadband access for students and families</u>. </strong>Broadband internet is critical to learning. Yet, by one definition, more than 30 million Americans live in areas where there is no broadband infrastructure that provides minimally acceptable speeds. <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/fact-sheet/internet-broadband/?menuItem=d5edf003-5858-4269-89c5-f2889ecf7951">In urban areas, there is a stark digital divide: a much higher percentage of white families report having a home broadband internet than Black, or Latino families</a>. <a href="https://aipi.asu.edu/sites/default/files/tribal_digital_divide_stimulus_bill_advocacy_04032020.pdf">Native families in their tribal communities also lack sufficient access to high-speed internet.</a><a href="https://msutoday.msu.edu/news/2020/poor-internet-connection-leaves-rural-students-behind"> One Michigan study</a> found that 47 percent of students who lived in rural areas had broadband access at home, compared to 77 percent of those in suburban areas. The last year made painfully clear the cost of these disparities, particularly for students who struggled to connect while learning remotely. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework would make historic investments in building “future proof” broadband infrastructure in unserved and underserved areas, so that we finally reach 100 percent high-speed broadband coverage.<br><br><strong><u>Electrifying school buses for safe student travel</u>. </strong><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4476560/">One study finds</a> that when children ride buses with clean air technologies, they experience lower exposures to air pollution, less pulmonary inflammation, and reduced absenteeism. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework would make a down payment on electrifying our yellow school bus fleet.<br><br><strong><u>Increase support for children with disabilities.</u></strong> All children, including those with disabilities, should be provided the services and support they need to thrive in school and graduate ready for college or a career. The discretionary request provides an historic $2.6 billion increase for Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) grants that support special education and related services for children with disabilities in grades preschool through 12. This funding would, for the first time in eight years, increase the federal share of the cost of providing services to children with disabilities, and is a significant first step toward fully funding IDEA. The discretionary request also includes an additional $250 million for IDEA Part C, which supports early intervention services for infants and toddlers with disabilities or delays, and funds services that have a proven track record of improving academic and developmental outcomes. This increase in funding would be paired with reforms to improve access to these vital services for underserved children, including children of color and children from low-income families.<br><br><strong><u>Prioritize the physical and mental well-being of students.</u></strong> The discretionary request provides $1 billion to increase the number of counselors, nurses, and mental health professionals in schools, prioritizing high-poverty schools.<br><br><strong><u>Support full-service community schools.</u></strong> Community schools play a critical role in providing comprehensive wrap-around services to students and their families, from afterschool to adult education opportunities to health and nutrition services. The discretionary request increases funding for these schools from $30 million to $443 million, an over ten-fold increase.<br><br><strong><u>Foster diverse schools.</u></strong> Schools play vital roles in bringing communities together. But, too many of the nation’s schools are <a href="https://cepa.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/wp19-06-v092019.pdf">still largely segregated by race and class</a>, mirroring their communities. The discretionary request includes $100 million for a new voluntary grant program to help communities develop and implement strategies to build more diverse student bodies. As part of their application, applicants would be required to demonstrate strong student, family, teacher, and community involvement in their plans. Applicants would have flexibility to develop and implement school diversity plans that reflect their individual needs and circumstances, and improve educational opportunities and outcomes for students.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden Administration Announces Additional Actions to Prevent Foreclosures</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/fact-sheet-biden-administration-announces-additional-actions-to-prevent-foreclosures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Across America, a strong economic recovery is taking hold. Since President Biden took office, more than 3 million jobs have been created—600,000 a month on average. The American Rescue Plan is working, jumpstarting the economy and getting Americans back to work. And critically, over two-thirds of adults are vaccinated, with our most vulnerable populations protected&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Across America, a strong economic recovery is taking hold. Since President Biden took office, more than 3 million jobs have been created—600,000 a month on average. The American Rescue Plan is working, jumpstarting the economy and getting Americans back to work. And critically, over two-thirds of adults are vaccinated, with our most vulnerable populations protected at even higher rates. In every state, jobs are up and American workers and families are looking ahead to a brighter future.<br><br>Shortly after taking office, the Biden-Harris Administration extended the foreclosure moratorium and mortgage forbearance enrollment period for homeowners with government-backed mortgages to provide relief to struggling homeowners. On June 24<sup>th</sup>, the Administration extended the foreclosure moratorium for a final, additional month until July 31, 2021 and the forbearance enrollment window through September 30, 2021, and provided up to three months of additional forbearance for certain borrowers. These actions were taken by three federal agencies that back mortgages – the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), and Department of Agriculture (USDA). The Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) provided similar relief for mortgages backed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac.<br><br>This helped ensure that American families did not lose their homes during the pandemic. Those policies prevented foreclosures and allowed some homeowners with government-backed loans to pause their mortgage payments for up to eighteen months. Nearly 7.2 million American households took advantage of forbearance options.<br><br>Thanks in part to President Biden’s strategy to get Americans vaccinated and the economy back on track, the number of American households in forbearance has fallen by more than 50% from its pandemic peak. Today, approximately 1.75 million Americans remain in forbearance. In order to ensure a stable and equitable recovery from the disruptions of the COVID-19 pandemic and prepare for homeowners to exit mortgage forbearance, the Biden-Harris Administration is taking action to keep Americans in their homes and support a return to a more stable housing market. &nbsp;<br><br>Specifically, the Biden-Harris Administration is:<br><br><em>Offering Borrowers Loan Modifications and Payment Reductions that Will Help Them Stay in Their Homes</em><br><br>With over 160 million Americans fully vaccinated and every American offered the opportunity to get vaccinated, along with an improving economy and more Americans getting back to work, many homeowners exiting mortgage forbearance are returning to their pre-pandemic earnings and are no longer facing financial hardship associated with the pandemic. For homeowners who can resume their pre-pandemic monthly mortgage payment and where agencies have the authority, agencies will continue requiring mortgage servicers to offer options that allow borrowers to move missed payments to the end of the mortgage at no additional cost to the borrower.<br><br>However, many homeowners will need deeper assistance due to pandemic-related income loss. For example, due to the economic crisis caused by the pandemic, some homeowners are earning less than they were before the pandemic. Homeowners with government-backed mortgages that have been negatively impacted by the pandemic will now receive enhanced assistance, especially if they are looking for work, re-training, having trouble catching up on back taxes and insurance, or are continuing to experience hardship for another reason. The new steps the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Department of Agriculture (USDA), and Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) are announcing will aim to provide homeowners with a roughly 25% reduction in borrowers’ monthly principal and interest (P&amp;I) payments to ensure they can afford to remain in their homes and build equity long-term. This brings options for homeowners with mortgages backed by HUD, USDA, and VA closer in alignment with options for homeowners with mortgages backed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac.<br><br>Specifically, where agencies have the authority and depending on homeowners’ financial conditions, agencies will require or encourage mortgage servicers to offer borrowers new payment reduction options to help them remain in their home.</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>HUD:&nbsp;</u></strong>The Federal Housing Administration (FHA) announced enhanced loss mitigation tools and simplified a COVID-19 Recovery Modification to help homeowners with FHA-insured mortgages who have been financially impacted by the COVID-19 pandemic. These options will offer borrowers appropriate relief while preserving flexibility for future crises. FHA will require mortgage servicers to offer a no cost option to eligible homeowners who can resume their current mortgage payments. For all borrowers that cannot resume their monthly mortgage, HUD will enhance servicers’ ability to provide all eligible borrowers with a 25% P&amp;I reduction. Based on recent analyses, the Administration believes that the additional payment reduction offered to struggling borrowers will result in fewer foreclosures. To achieve those goals, HUD will implement the following options over the next few months:<br><br><strong>COVID-19 Recovery Standalone Partial Claim:&nbsp;</strong>For homeowners who can resume their current mortgage payments, HUD will provide borrowers with an option to continue these payments by offering a zero interest, subordinate lien (also known as a partial claim) that is repaid when the mortgage insurance or mortgage terminates, such as upon sale or refinance;<br><br><strong>COVID-19 Recovery Modification:&nbsp;</strong>For homeowners who cannot resume making their current monthly mortgage payments, the COVID-19 Recovery Modification extends the term of the mortgage to 360 months at market rate and targets reducing the borrowers’ monthly P&amp;I portion of their monthly mortgage payment by 25 percent. This will achieve significant payment reduction for many struggling homeowners by extending the term of the mortgage at a low interest rate, combined with a partial claim, if partial claims are available.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>These options augment additional COVID protections HUD published last month. These included the foreclosure moratorium extension, forbearance enrollment extension, and the COVID-19 Advance Loan Modification: a product that is directly mailed to eligible borrowers who can achieve a 25% reduction to the P&amp;I of their monthly mortgage payment through a 30-year loan modification.&nbsp; HUD believes that the additional payment reduction will help more borrowers retain their homes, prevent future re-defaults, help more low-income and underserved borrowers build wealth through homeownership, and assist in the broader COVID-19 recovery.</p>



<ul><li><strong>USDA:</strong>&nbsp;The USDA COVID-19 Special Relief Measure provides new alternatives for borrowers to help them achieve up to a 20% reduction in their monthly P&amp;I payments.&nbsp; New options include an interest rate reduction, term extension and a mortgage recovery advance, which can help cover past due mortgage payments and related costs.&nbsp; Borrowers will first be assessed for an interest rate reduction and if additional relief is still needed, the borrowers will be considered for a combination rate reduction and term extension. In cases where a combination of rate reduction and term extension is not enough to achieve a 20% payment reduction, a third option combining the rate reduction and term extension with a mortgage recovery advance will be used to reach the target payment.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>VA:</u></strong>&nbsp;VA’s new COVID-19 Refund Modification provides multiple tools to assist certain borrowers in achieving a 20% reduction in the dollar amount for monthly P&amp;I mortgage payments. In some cases, even larger reductions are possible. One such tool is the new COVID-19 Refund option, where VA can purchase from the servicer a borrower’s COVID-19 arrearages and, if needed, additional amounts of loan principal (subject to an overall cap corresponding to 30% of the borrower’s unpaid principal balance as of the first day of the borrower’s COVID-19 forbearance). Similar to VA’s COVID-19 partial claim option, the COVID-19 Refund will be established as a junior lien, payable to VA at 0% interest. In addition, servicers can now achieve significant reductions in the dollar amount for monthly payments by modifying the loan and adding up to 120 months to the original maturity date (meaning the total repayment term can be up to 480 months).<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>FHFA</u></strong>: HUD, USDA, and VA’s steps bring federal agency options closer in alignment with payment reduction and loan modification options for borrowers with Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac mortgages. FHFA’s existing COVID loss mitigation options provide servicers with homeownership retention tools for borrowers. The tools include a payment deferral option that allows borrowers to resume their pre-COVID monthly payment after deferring up to 18 months of missed mortgage payments into a non-interest-bearing balloon. The missed payments do not have to be repaid until the homeowner sells or refinances the property. Borrowers requiring more significant help may receive a loan modification that targets up to a 20% reduction in their monthly mortgage payments. The Flex Modification (Flex) capitalizes all past due amounts, extends the mortgage up to 40 years and in some cases lowers the interest rate and provides for principal forbearance.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Additional Assistance</strong><br><br>In addition to these new opportunities for borrowers, agencies across the federal government are also taking other steps to support borrowers as our economic and public health recovery continues. &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Homeowner Assistance Fund</u></strong>: In addition, the Homeowner Assistance Fund (HAF), a critical component of President Biden’s American Rescue Plan, provides $9.961 billion to states, D.C., territories, and Tribes for relief to homeowners impacted by the COVID-19 economic crisis. These funds can be used for assistance with mortgage payments, homeowner’s insurance, utility payments, and other specified purposes – and homeowners can access these funds in addition to the payment reduction options discussed above. And they will be integrated into the payment reduction options outlined above – providing additional payment reduction to borrowers who need it and to borrowers whose mortgages are not backed by federal agencies.</li><li><strong><u>Extended Term Option: </u></strong>Finally, the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae) recently announced it is creating a new security product for modified loans that would provide government agencies the flexibility to extend mortgage terms to up to 40 years, if they choose to do so, for borrowers who are behind on their mortgages and would benefit from the monthly payment reduction associated with this option.  Ginnie Mae expects this extended term product will be available for use in late 2021.</li></ul>



<p><em>Giving Borrowers the Information They Need to Understand their Options</em><br><br><strong>These new loan modification and payment reduction options will only give borrowers the relief they need if borrowers have the information to understand their options.</strong></p>



<ul><li>Homeowners can visit <a href="http://www.consumerfinance.gov/housing">consumerfinance.gov/housing</a> for up-to-date information on their relief options, protections, and key deadlines.</li><li>As federal agencies continue working to implement housing assistance for American families, CFPB offers this website as a one-stop shop for homeowners to learn about programs and resources that can help them stay in their homes by reducing the risk of eviction and foreclosure.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Borrowers should contact their servicer or housing counselor as soon as possible to learn more about the options available.</strong></p>



<ul><li>Last month, HUD, VA, and USDA announced steps to ensure that no new foreclosures are filed on mortgages backed by those agencies until borrowers are reviewed for new and improved options to make their monthly payments more affordable.</li><li>In addition, FHFA will continue to work with Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to ensure that borrowers are evaluated for home retention solutions prior to any referral to foreclosure.</li><li>The CFPB finalized a mortgage servicing rule that requires most servicers to meet temporary procedural safeguards before filing foreclosures for most mortgages through the end of the year. The CFPB’s rules also require that mortgage servicers provide information to borrowers about their options.</li></ul>



<p><strong>For borrowers not currently in forbearance, there is still an opportunity to access relief.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>HUD, VA, and USDA announced that they will continue to allow homeowners who have not taken advantage of forbearance to date to enter into COVID-related forbearance through September 30, 2021.</li><li>Homeowners with Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac-backed mortgages who have COVID-related hardships will also continue to be eligible for COVID-related forbearance.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Haiti to Pay Respects upon the Death of His Excellency Jovenel Moïse, Former President of the Republic of Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-republic-of-haiti-to-pay-respects-upon-the-death-of-his-excellency-jovenel-moise-former-president-of-the-republic-of-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Haiti to pay respects upon the death of His Excellency Jovenel Moïse, Former President of the Republic of Haiti The Honorable Linda Thomas-Greenfield, United States Ambassador to the United Nations, will lead the delegation. Members of the Presidential&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Haiti to pay respects upon the death of His Excellency Jovenel Moïse, Former President of the Republic of Haiti</p>



<p>The Honorable Linda Thomas-Greenfield, United States Ambassador to the United Nations, will lead the delegation.</p>



<p><strong><u>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</u></strong></p>



<p>The Honorable Michele J. Sison, U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Haiti</p>



<p>The Honorable Gregory Meeks, Chairman of the House Foreign Affairs Committee</p>



<p>The Honorable Jeff Fortenberry, Member of Congress, U.S. House of Representatives</p>



<p>The Honorable Daniel Foote, Special Envoy to Haiti, U.S. Department of State</p>



<p>The Honorable Juan S. Gonzalez, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere, National Security Council</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before a Meeting With Business and Labor Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/22/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-meeting-with-business-and-labor-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 4:43 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, I’m delighted you’re all here.&#160; I’m meeting with a group of labor and business leaders who &#8212; and this is one of those meetings I’ve been looking forward to. They&#8217;re not here to negotiate with one another.&#160; The good news is they&#8217;ve been here negotiating &#8212; not&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>4:43 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I’m delighted you’re all here.&nbsp; I’m meeting with a group of labor and business leaders who &#8212; and this is one of those meetings I’ve been looking forward to.</p>



<p>They&#8217;re not here to negotiate with one another.&nbsp; The good news is they&#8217;ve been here negotiating &#8212; not negotiating &#8212; supporting what we’re trying to get done on the infrastructure bill.</p>



<p>And I know that we&#8217;re looking for this bipartisan effort to get this infrastructure bill passed.&nbsp; As you all know, and they share my belief that it&#8217;s both in the interest of business and labor to get this done.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and it’s about &#8212; not about energy versus environment, it’s not about business versus labor; it’s all about, basically, a race to the future.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve been traveling the world lately and &#8212; back out where I used to spend a lot of time, in the G7 and meeting with the summits with the Russians, as well as NATO.&nbsp; And I tell you, the rest of the world is looking to see whether we can get something done.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The single-biggest issue &#8212; I know you’ve travelled the world, all of you &#8212; and the fact is that they’re trying to figure out whether we&#8217;re so divided that we can&#8217;t get something done.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I&#8217;m convinced that they&#8217;re convinced now that we have an opportunity to make some real fundamental changes that generate growth in the future.</p>



<p>You know, the days used to be that we were in a position where the United States invested more money in research and development three, four decades ago than any nation in the world.&nbsp; Now we’re number eight.&nbsp; And it used to be that China was &#8212; was number nine, and now they&#8217;re number two.</p>



<p>This is about a race for the 21st century.&nbsp; And you know &#8212; and what we&#8217;re doing here is, in this race for the future, it&#8217;s about connecting Americans &#8212; all Americans, rural and urban &#8212; to high-speed Internet, repairing our roads and our bridges so that we can, in fact, no longer be ranked number 9 or 10 in terms of infrastructure in America.&nbsp; Back to what we used to be &#8212; we used to lead the world.</p>



<p>You know, electrify our school buses and our transit systems.&nbsp; And we’re going to build national charging networks for electric vehicles; eliminate the nation&#8217;s lead service pipes.&nbsp; We got 400,000 home- &#8212;</p>



<p>I mean, there&#8217;s just a whole lot we can do that&#8217;s going to put a lot of people to work.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to improve the life of a lot of people.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to update our power grid &#8212; which, as you saw what happened to Texas last year, there&#8217;s a lot we can do.&nbsp; It’s going to generate &#8212; and, Lonnie, your (inaudible) is going be awful busy, and &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. STEPHENSON:&nbsp; We&#8217;re ready.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going &#8212; we have to win the comp- &#8212; we really do.&nbsp; This is not hyperbole.&nbsp; We have to win the competition for the 21st century.&nbsp; That’s really what&#8217;s at stake, and I think you all know that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the Bipartisan Infrastructure does, in my view.</p>



<p>I want to thank everyone here for supporting it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to get into the details, among all of us, about what we think about what needs to be improved, what can be made better or worse.&nbsp; You know, so, we want everybody to be engaged.</p>



<p>So, thank you all, folks, for being here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to now get down to business.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what conversations have you had with public health officials about possibly changing the mask mandate for vaccinated Americans?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll respond to the COVID question quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We follow the science.&nbsp; What&#8217;s happening now is all the major scientific operations in this country and the 25-person group we put together are looking at all the possibilities of what&#8217;s happening now.</p>



<p>We have a pandemic among the nonvaccinated &#8212; those who are not vaccinated.</p>



<p>If you are vaccinated, you are safe.&nbsp; If you are vaccinated, you have over a 98 percent chance of never catching the virus at all.&nbsp; And if you catch it, you&#8217;re likely to &#8212; overwhelming proof, so far, is you&#8217;re not going to be hospitalized, you&#8217;re not going to be sick, you&#8217;re going to probably have no signs that you had it, and you are not going to die.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a simple proposition.</p>



<p>And what they&#8217;re doing is they&#8217;re going into &#8212; investigating every aspect of any change that could or might take place.</p>



<p>But the vaccines are good against all of the variants that are out there, including the Delta variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you so much for being here.</p>



<p>4:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at Signing of H.R. 1652, the VOCA Fix to Sustain the Crime Victims Fund Act of 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/22/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-h-r-1642-the-voca-fix-to-sustain-the-crime-victims-fund-act-of-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 22:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East&#160;Room&#160; 3:18&#160;P.M. EDT&#160;&#160;(&#8220;Hail to the Chief&#8221; is played.)&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Every time I hear that, I wonder when he&#8217;s coming.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Please, everybody sit down.&#160; Thank you.&#160;Let me begin by doing something no speaker should ever do &#8212; by apologizing.&#160; I got a little tied up in that other office I work in, Pat,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East&nbsp;Room&nbsp;</p>



<p>3:18&nbsp;P.M. EDT&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(&#8220;Hail to the Chief&#8221; is played.)<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Every time I hear that, I wonder when he&#8217;s coming.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Please, everybody sit down.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me begin by doing something no speaker should ever do &#8212; by apologizing.&nbsp; I got a little tied up in that other office I work in, Pat, and I apologize for keeping you waiting because I know you&#8217;re all as equally busy as I am.&nbsp; And I want to thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, I think is a day of hope.&nbsp; And I mean that.&nbsp; A day of hope and healing for victims or crime and organizations that support those victims of crime.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to thank the Vice President and the Second Gentleman, Senators Durbin &#8212; I think he&#8217;s here; I thought I saw him.&nbsp; Senators Durbin and Baldwin and Grassley and Graham and Murkowski.&nbsp; Representatives Nadler and Fitzpatrick and Jackson-Lee and Wagner and Scanlon.&nbsp; And everyone who has helped make possible this moment, including so many of you who are here today that I haven’t mentioned.<br>&nbsp;<br>When someone commits a crime, it’s &#8212; it&#8217;s not enough to bring the predator to justice; we also need to support the victims.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s something that, way back &#8212; 150 years ago, when I was Chairman of the Judiciary Committee, we spent a lot of time working on and setting up victims&#8217; funds.&nbsp; That’s what this Crime Victims Fund does.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In many years of working on the issue, I&#8217;ve visited an awful lot of domestic violence shelters.&nbsp; Every time I&#8217;d go into a city, I would quietly &#8212; before I went to where I was supposed to be &#8212; quietly slip in and spend time in a domestic violence shelter to speak to the people giving the services of people getting the services.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, many times, the body language that you&#8217;d see when you walked in was one of the victims of crime finding themselves almost curled up, Dianne, in a ball.&nbsp; They were still suffering from a serious, serious &#8212; not only physical abuse they received, but, quite frankly, the emotional abuse.&nbsp; And you can see the pain.&nbsp; You can see the pain was still with them, and you wondered when was this going to abate, no matter what we did.<br>&nbsp;<br>According to the CDC &#8212; and I&#8217;m &#8212; I think Senator Feinstein remembers &#8212; I got in trouble because when I was pushing the legislation, way back in those days, I said, &#8220;I&#8217;m convinced that women who are victims of domestic violence suffer from post-traumatic stress no different than a solider being shot at regularly.&#8221;&nbsp; You come home and every time your significant other would come home, if dinner wasn’t ready, they smashed your head against the wall.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no &#8212; there&#8217;s no difference than being shot at.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the CDFE [sic] &#8212; the CDC, two years later, came out and said, &#8220;Survivors can experience mental health problems and such depression and the symptoms of post-traumatic stress syndrome.&#8221;&nbsp; Even before research confirmed it, you could see it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there are economic costs for survivors as well &#8211;medical costs, lost productivity from work, and navigating the court system.&nbsp; That’s why Victims Compensation Program helps victims and their families cover the costs they&#8217;d suffered from the crime.&nbsp; They can &#8212; there can be counseling and medical bills; lost wages because you couldn’t work; paying for temporary housing for a family fleeing abuse; even fixing a broken door kicked down by an abuser.&nbsp; And, you know, the vast majority of children out in the street are the children who are, in fact, the children of abused women.&nbsp; It can also be a long-term support survivors need to heal, every time, in every single sense of the word.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In 2019, these victim compensation funds went directly to over 230,000 victims &#8212; 230,000.&nbsp; These funds also got to states, territories, and Tribes to support thousands of victim services organizations.&nbsp; These organizations have provided services and support to over 13 million survivors.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, by the way, last night, some of you heard me talk about the need for more policing that understands the need for communities and citizens.&nbsp; These funds will also go to law enforcement agencies to support training on how to respond to victims who have experienced trauma.<br>&nbsp;<br>In 1984, I was proud to support the &#8212; the passage of the Victims of Crime Act, and created &#8212; that created this fund.&nbsp; I&#8217;m also proud to sign the law that significantly strengthened it today.&nbsp; This fund doesn&#8217;t take a dime of taxpayers’ money; it uses fines and penalties paid by convicted federal criminals. However, fines from what are called “non-prosecutorial agreements” or defendant &#8212; or “deferred prosecution agreements” did not go into this Victims Crimes Fund in the past.<br>&nbsp;<br>Since there&#8217;s been more and more of these agreements in recent years, the fund is being depleted.&nbsp; That meant dramatic cuts in the funding it could provide for victims and for organizations to support these victims.<br>&nbsp;<br>Between 2017 and today, the amount of money in these funds has gone down 92 percent, which has resulted in a 70 percent reduction in victims assistance programs and grants.&nbsp; This means that, for a lot of victims, the help they need isn&#8217;t there any longer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>When my son Beau was the Attorney General of the state of Delaware, he took pride in getting more support more quickly to victims, especially to protect and care for child victims.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I know that, as the San Francisco DA and the California Attorney General, Vice President Harris expanded support for victims of crime and launched one of the nation&#8217;s first medical centers focused on treating childhood trauma caused by violence in a home or in a community.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This bill is going to allow us to make &#8212; make sure that all the fines and penalties that are from federal cases go into the victims &#8212; the Crime Victims Fund to rebuild this fund, because it&#8217;s badly needed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is going to enable us to provide more help and support to victims of domestic violence, sexual assault, child abuse, trafficking, and other crimes all across America.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In order to provide more access and safety and services for victims of gender-based violence, it&#8217;s long past time to re- &#8212; reauthorize and strengthen the protections through the Violence Against Women Act.&nbsp; Please.&nbsp; Please.&nbsp; You know, you can &#8212; (applause).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know from experience you all can come together in a bipartisan, bicameral way and to pass this bill.&nbsp; We need to do the same thing to reauthorize the Violence Against Women Act without further delay.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, after these changes in the Victims Crime Act passed this week, a leader from one of the state&#8217;s &#8212; state&#8217;s Coalition Against Domestic Violence sent a letter to her national organization.&nbsp; And she wrote about working in the shelter where their ability to serve people rose and fell based on the fundings of victim services.&nbsp; She told the story of a client she lost to domestic violence homicide because the budget cuts left them without space at the shelter or staff needed to help this particular woman.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Upon learning about the law I&#8217;m about to sign today, she wrote, and I quote &#8212; I quote, “I think about her every day.&nbsp; This is going to be truly lifesaving,” end of quote.&nbsp; This is what you&#8217;ve done &#8212; truly lifesaving.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In closing, I want to thank those angels working on the frontlines to help these victims, especially during this pandemic that’s made the work both more difficult, more in demand, and more dangerous.&nbsp; And I want to thank the advocates who mobilized and bring together these important changes in the law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are thousands of people out there who may not know about the work you did to get this bill passed, but they’ll know that they are getting the help they need to put their lives back together and move toward healing and toward justice.&nbsp; I will now have the great honor of signing the bill.&nbsp; And I’d invite the sponsors to come on up and stand with me if you’re willing.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>(The act is signed.)<br>&nbsp;<br>This is one of those deals where what they did is literally, not figuratively, going to change the lives of women and children and some men out there.&nbsp; So, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>3:30 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki and Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, July 22, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/22/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-secretary-of-commerce-gina-raimondo-july-22-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:41 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Happy Thursday.&#160; Okay, we have a special guest.&#160; Happy to welcome back Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo.&#160;&#160;Today, she will be telling us about a new economic development initiative that the Department is launching, thanks to the American Rescue Plan.&#160; She&#8217;ll take a couple of questions.&#160; After that, as always,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:41 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Happy Thursday.&nbsp; Okay, we have a special guest.&nbsp; Happy to welcome back Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, she will be telling us about a new economic development initiative that the Department is launching, thanks to the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; She&#8217;ll take a couple of questions.&nbsp; After that, as always, I&#8217;ll be the bad cop.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, I’ll turn it over to Secretary Raimondo.<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see here.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; So, as the President often says and as we all know, we&#8217;re on the road to recovery.&nbsp; And today, with this announcement, we mark a real step forward in that recovery.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As Jen just said, the President signed the American Rescue Plan into law, intended to get our country back on its feet.&nbsp; And thanks to that law, I&#8217;m thrilled right now to be announcing the launch of a transformative $3 billion economic development initiative that will be running out of the Department of Commerce.&nbsp; I&#8217;m even more excited to say that, starting today, this afternoon, every community in America can begin applying for that funding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We believe that this is the largest local economic development initiative that the Commerce Department has ever made.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a testament to the President&#8217;s commitment to do far more than simply recover, but to build back better and make sure every community and every American is included in our comeback.<br>&nbsp;<br>Everybody ought to benefit from this $3 billion initiative &#8212; from working mothers working to balance multiple jobs; to young adults looking for work; to factory workers or retail workers who lost their job in the pandemic &#8212; many of them mid-career and they&#8217;re wondering, “What happens to me now?&nbsp; What happens to me next?”<br>&nbsp;<br>These funds &#8212; this initiative has been specifically designed to make sure that we are going to be providing high-quality, real jobs for you and for your community.<br>&nbsp;<br>What we saw during the pandemic, and what we all know, is that some people did very well.&nbsp; Those who were doing well did very well.&nbsp; But millions of Americans continue to struggle, and it&#8217;s uneven.&nbsp; Those who continue to struggle &#8212; it&#8217;s been disproportionately women, people of color, communities of color, rural communities, and Tribes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We know 2 million American women dropped out of the labor force since the start of the pandemic, mostly because of lack of affordable childcare and paid leave.&nbsp; So, ensuring that these $3 billion are distributed equity is core to our investment strategy.&nbsp; We know that equity is good for workers, good for business, and good for the economy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As many of you know, I&#8217;m the former governor of Rhode Island, and, as a governor, I saw what good-paying jobs mean to American families and mean to communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This initiative has the potential to create, we believe, 300,000 jobs in the near term, revitalize dozens of communities around America, and drive innovation in unser- &#8212; underserved communities and revitalize depressed economies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The good news is the Department of Commerce&#8217;s Economic Development Agency has been doing this for decades.&nbsp; They have a track record of success.&nbsp; In fact, I saw that, on Monday, when I was in Albany, where EDA’s investment over the last 10 years have helped that city and region become a global semiconductor and bio-science hub.&nbsp; And, in fact, the employment growth rate there has grown by 30 percent in those industries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This initiative that I&#8217;m announcing today will bring that type of transformative growth to communities all over the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, at the end of the day, as the President has so often said, our economy can&#8217;t recover until everybody in every community is included.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I&#8217;d like to briefly describe the components of this $3 billion initiative.&nbsp; It begins with what we&#8217;re calling the “Build Back Better Regional Challenge”.&nbsp; This is a $1 billion challenge for up to 30 regions across the country seeking to revitalize their economies.&nbsp; It&#8217;s designed to focus on innovation and spur projects that grow new industries and scale existing ones.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Secondly is what we&#8217;re calling the “Good Jobs Challenge,” which allocates a half a billion dollars towards industry-led workforce training and apprenticeship programs with a particular focus on women, people of color, and underserved communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>Importantly, we have designed this so that funds can also be used for support services like childcare and transportation while folks are getting trained so we make sure they &#8212; they get to the finish line of the training and get a job.<br>&nbsp;<br>For the hard &#8212; hard-hit communities hit hardest by the loss of travel and tourism, we’re providing $750 million to accelerate the recovery of trarel [sic] &#8212; travel tourism and outdoor recreation.&nbsp; Through the economic adjustment assistance, we&#8217;re offering a half a billion dollars to hundreds of communities across the country to create new jobs, spur economic development, and put Americans back to work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our “Indigenous Communities Commitment” sets aside $100 million to meet the needs of Indigenous communities with everything from broadband to health centers and more &#8212; deliberately designed to be flexible to meet the needs of the community.<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, we are making a $300 million commitment to invest in economic development in coal-affected communities.&nbsp; We believe that this $300 million investment in coal communities is the largest economic development that EDA has ever made in coal communities.&nbsp; And we know that it will enable these communities to recover, diversify their economies, and grow.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, these grants together reflect the values and priorities of President Biden&#8217;s Build Back Better agenda, and they, alongside of the Jobs Plan, will accelerate America&#8217;s economic recovery and help the country continue to get back to work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, spread the word.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll be &#8212; applications go live this afternoon, and we look forward to working with communities around America.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Jeff.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Madam Secretary, two questions.&nbsp; One, can you explain how people can apply for these grants?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And two, on a separate topic:&nbsp; The Commerce Department has a Supply Chain Advisory Committee.&nbsp; Can you give us an update on what you&#8217;re doing about chips and other supply issues?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, as I said, this afternoon, on the EDA website &#8212; the EDA website applications will be live.&nbsp; So we want to get this money out the door as quickly as possible.&nbsp; EDA has six regional offices around the country, which we will be working with.&nbsp; But this is &#8212; I want to clarify: This money is for states, cities, counties, nonprofits, universities &#8212; not for companies.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s coalitions of nonprofits in communities, specifically designed to be locally led and managed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re doing a lot on the chip shortage.&nbsp; I am engaging almost daily with industry.&nbsp; We are working as hard as we can to get the House to pass the CHIPS Act or their version of USICA.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re putting plans in place right now, already, on the team to invest the $52 billion.&nbsp; We need to incentivize the manufacturing of chips in America.&nbsp; And so, we are very focused on putting the pieces in place so that can happen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With regard to the EDA grants, I understand that you&#8217;re going to judge some of these by return on investment.&nbsp; How are you defining ROI, given that that can often exclude priorities like gender and racial equality?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; So, our number one investment priority is equity.&nbsp; And as our team decides which &#8212; these are &#8212; this is a competitive grant process.&nbsp; By the way, I think that the fact of the competition will help communities to come together as a community and put their best ideas forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>In order to qualify to get the money, you have to prove to us that equity &#8212; you&#8217;ll have an equity lens.&nbsp; And whether it&#8217;s job training that you&#8217;re doing, you have to give &#8212; you know, I have to make sure that women, people of color, veterans, people who&#8217;ve been left out will be included in this.<br>&nbsp;<br>So it&#8217;s a lens that we&#8217;re going to take across the $3 billion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, like, whoever does it the best?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Exactly.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Rachel.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What type of &#8212; thank you, Madam Secretary.&nbsp; What type of follow up will there be?&nbsp; You&#8217;re emphasizing equity, but will you be following up to make sure that that money is distributed fairly to the communities that you&#8217;re speaking of that really do need it?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Great question.&nbsp; So, we are deeply committed for this to be transparent.&nbsp; Everything is going to be online.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be on our website.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be a wide-open, transparent process.&nbsp; And we are, at the get-go, putting in place accountability measures.&nbsp; And this is something I am very serious about &#8212; having been a governor, being on the ground.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to track every penny to make sure that it&#8217;s doing what it&#8217;s supposed to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the ROI &#8212; the ROI is jobs. We think we can create, in the short term, hundreds of thousands of jobs, and fundamentally revitalize dozens of communities around America so that, a few years from now, we’ll create 300,000 jobs; 10 years from now, we will have communities that are a beehive of economic activity that, five years ago, were distressed.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nancy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Secretary Raimondo.&nbsp; A few days ago, the U.S. government and governments around the world accused China of malicious cyber activities.&nbsp; Have you gotten any reaction from your Chinese government counterparts about these accusations?<br>And do you believe that the statements alone are going to be enough to change Chinese behavior if they aren&#8217;t paired with punitive measures like tariffs or sanctions?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So I have not had &#8212; to answer your first question, the answer is: No, I have not had any interaction.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Pre- &#8212; President Biden has been very clear on this: There will be consequences.&nbsp; And we will use all tools at our disposable [sic] &#8212; at our disposal in order to protect Americans and American businesses.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tamara.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You mentioned that some of this money would go to communities hit hard by the loss of travel and tourism.&nbsp; Do you have a sense of how big that hit has been and how &#8212; what share of that is because of the public health-related travel bans?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; So, we know that nearly every community in America has been affected.&nbsp; And I want to be clear that, of the $750 million, every state will receive something.&nbsp; So, $500 million is going out as quickly as we can in the next few weeks, and everyone will participate.&nbsp; And then, $200 [million] or so is competitive.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think that it&#8217;s im- &#8212; I think the answer to your question is &#8212; it&#8217;s impossible to answer &#8212; or I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don’t think it&#8217;s possible to figure it out that way.&nbsp; But we do know, about a year and a half ago, we shut down travel and tourism.&nbsp; I lived it in Rhode Island &#8212; you know, Newport, Narragansett, Block Island closed; we shut it down.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re still trying to build back after that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so that&#8217;s what this money is intended to do: to help these communities to get back into the business of tourism and travel.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kelly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How would you assess, Madam Secretary, the work &#8212; worker shortage that many employers are finding &#8212; that they&#8217;re having difficulty getting back up, especially in some of the hospitality and tourist areas?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; It’s &#8212; it is acute.&nbsp; There &#8212; there is &#8212; every business I talk to says that they need to find talent.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t know if I would call it a “shortage,” per se; I would say there&#8217;s a skills gap.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we put so much money of this $3 billion &#8212; you know, a half a billion of $3 billion is just for skill development, apprenticeship, high-quality job training.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I hear all the time is &#8212; from companies &#8212; “We are ready to hire, but people need to have the skills.&nbsp; They need digital skills, cybersecurity skills, data &#8212; you know, data skills, cloud computing skills.”&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what we have to get at the business of.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And by the way, we need to make sure that women and people of color and people in rural areas have those digital skills so they can get those good jobs.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what this is about.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what I hear most often from companies.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kaitlan is going to have to be the last one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Secretary.&nbsp; Last week, the President said he would have an update for us on international travel restrictions in a few days.&nbsp; Do you have any update on that?&nbsp; And do you believe it&#8217;s time for the U.S. to reopen its borders?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; I do not have an update on that except to say a couple of things: International travel is vital, and it&#8217;s vital to commerce.&nbsp; And we are taking a methodical approach based on data and based on science.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My primary message with respect to that and to the American people: Get vaccinated.&nbsp; Like, increasingly, this is a disease of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; Ninety-seven percent of people in hospitals with COVID are unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, if you&#8217;re asking me, you know, what can we do to get our economy back on track &#8212; get vaccinated.&nbsp; Because as more people do that, then we can continue to think about opening travel, going back into the office, et cetera.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, Secretary Raimondo.&nbsp; We appreciate you.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick follow up on training?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; She&#8217;s got to go.&nbsp; Busy day.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; Couple items for you at the top.&nbsp; This afternoon, the President will bring together leaders from both the labor and business community at the White House to talk about the critical need to invest in America&#8217;s economic strength by passing the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>While some of the participants at this roundtable may have sat across the negotiating table in the past, now they&#8217;ve joined together as part of a broad coalition of labor and business leaders backing this plan.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re joined in their support by bipartisan leaders in Washington, governors, mayors, and an overwhelming majority of the American people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I also wanted to note that today the Department of Justice is announcing, or has announced, the launch of five gun trafficking strike forces in regions around the country to combat the uptick in gun crimes that we&#8217;ve seen over the last 18 months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of this announcement, the Attorney General and Deputy Attorney General will visit the headquarters of ATF in Washington before the Attorney General travels to Chicago to meet with the leaders from the Chicago Police Department and attend a listening session with participants in a group that offers innovative programming to reduce gun violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>The regional strike forces we&#8217;ve talked about a bit in the past, but they will leverage existing resources to ensure sustained efforts across city and state boundaries to help stem the supply of illegally trafficked firearms in five key regions: New York, Chicago, Los Angeles, the San Francisco Bay Area/Sacramento region, and Washington, D.C.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this is part of the administration&#8217;s comprehensive crime reduction strategy announced last month by &#8212; at the White House with Attorney General Garland.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to targeting gun traffickers to keep guns out of the hands of criminals, the President&#8217;s plan bolsters local law enforcement efforts by giving them the resources they need to hire more police officers and engage in effective community policing.&nbsp;<br><br>I also wanted to note that, this afternoon, the President will sign H.R. 1652, which will help strengthen and restore funding for the Crime Victims Fund, which has lost billions of dollars over the last five years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This was originally passed in 1984 and &#8212; which established the Crime Victims Fund, which received most of its fundings &#8212; funds through deposits from criminal fines and penalties from convictions in federal cases and does not receive any appropriated funding of taxpayer dollars.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The awards grants the &#8212; this &#8212; the awards grants to states, local governments, and other entities through DOJ Office for Victims of Crime.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, Josh.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Three subjects.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, given the spread of the Delta variant, return to offices, is the administration looking at new mask guidance, as reported by The Washington Post?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know that the head of the CDC, our public health arm, just spoke to this earlier this morning and made clear that there had not been a decision to change our mask guidance.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two, it&#8217;s being reported that President Biden plans to impose sanctions on Cuban officials because of the attacks on protesters.&nbsp; Can you outline the administration&#8217;s goals with regard to those sanctions?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I can confirm for all of you that there will be more from the Department of Treasury and the Department of State later this afternoon on sanctions.&nbsp; And the announcement will be coming from then &#8212; from them.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I &#8212; in terms of our approach to Cuba and what we&#8217;re trying to accomplish, we have, of course, condemned mass detention, sham trials, and disappearances that are attempts to threaten the Cuban people into silence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We continue to call for swift &#8212; the swift release of peaceful protesters who have unjustly been detained.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made clear over the last week that addressing this moment was a priority for the administration and for President Biden, and that he has &#8212; he had asked his team to look into a range of options that would both help the Cuban people, help provide humanitarian assistance, help look into addressing issues like the lack of Internet access, and that also sanctions authority was a part of those considerations.&nbsp; So this is an announcement that will be coming later this afternoon.<br><br>I&#8217;d also note that we&#8217;ll continue to engage closely and coordinate with our international partners, from the OAS to the U.N. and others, to collectively condemn the actions of the Cuban government.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then last, real quick, National Association of Realtors says that home prices are up 24.3 percent from a year ago to $363,300 &#8212; a record.&nbsp; Are home prices too high for an economy that&#8217;s supposed to be growing from the bottom up and middle out?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say the President is quite focused on making sure we&#8217;re doing everything we can to help middle-class families as the economy is recovering and as there are ongoing challenges in our economy that have been longstanding, including supply chain issues, which you and many others are quite familiar with.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as he talked about a little bit last night, there are a range of factors that impact that &#8212; the shortage of lumber that is starting to pick back up has, of course, impacted the building of new homes, which has raised the pri- &#8212; the prices of older homes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, his focus and a big focus of this administration is on addressing supply chain issues to help address some of these skyrocketing prices in the market.&nbsp; But, also, he is focused on providing assistance to renters, to homeowners, and others to get through this period of time in our economy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, today, China rejected a WHO plan for a second phase of an investigation into the origins of the coronavirus, including audits of laboratories and markets.&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s reaction to that?&nbsp; And how will this impact the U.S. dealing with China on this going forward?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first reiterate that we &#8212; the United States supports the WHO plan for phase two, which commits to ensuring these studies are scientific, transparent, expert-led, and free from interference.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have certainly seen the PRC’s comments again rejecting phase two of a WHO study.&nbsp; We’re deeply disappointed.&nbsp; Their position is irresponsible and, frankly, dangerous.&nbsp; Alongside other member stat- &#8212; member count- &#8212; states around the world, we continue to call for China to provide the needed access to data and samples.&nbsp; And this is critical so we can understand to prevent the next pandemic.&nbsp; This is about saving lives in the future.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not a time to be stonewalling.&nbsp;<br><br>I would note that we believe in a multilateral approach; that has not been an approach that has been taken prior to the President taken office &#8212; taking office, and that has been a big focus of his strategy &#8212; strategy as it relates to our engagement with China.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; and that relates to our approach to global health security, which is why we rejoined the WHO on day one.&nbsp; Unfortunately, phase one, as you all know, did not yield the data and access from China that we think is necessary.&nbsp; But our support for a multilateral approach and the phase two plan is because it&#8217;s rigorous and science-based.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But most importantly, it&#8217;s not just the United States calling for this.&nbsp; As a part of our renewed engagement and our efforts to build a coalition of support around the world with allies and partners, we&#8217;re joined by the international community on this &#8212; partners and multilateral organizations who are also calling for and pressuring China to be engaged in the sta- &#8212; the second phase of this discussion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note &#8212; I&#8217;m almost done; there&#8217;s a lot to say about this topic.&nbsp; In Cornwall, which many of you were with us &#8212; with us for that trip, the G7 leaders, together, called for a transparent, evidence-based investigation, including in China.&nbsp; And after the phase one study, we were joined by allies and partners across the world in a joint statement calling for a transparent and independent analysis expressing our concerns over the lack of access and urging momentum.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s clear China isn&#8217;t living up to their obligations.&nbsp; What our focus is on is building this multilateral effort and support for putting pressure on and making clear that it&#8217;s unacceptable and dangerous.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you foresee any consequences for China for this decision?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of any policy process.&nbsp; I will tell you that, again, our approach to China, as it relates to global health security, is going to continue to be in a coordinated fashion with our international partners.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one last one on China.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They also started a new crackdown in Hong Kong, this time on children&#8217;s book authors.&nbsp; Any thoughts on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we have expressed many times before &#8212; unfortunately, because there has been reason to express many times before &#8212; our concerns about the crackdown on freedom of speech, freedom of media, a crackdown on &#8212; on human rights activists in Hong Kong.&nbsp; And we continue to express that.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You mentioned there had not been a decision to change the guidelines on wearing a face mask for fully vaccinated Americans.&nbsp; But have there been any conversations within the administration about possibly changing those guidelines?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we are guided by the science, and we&#8217;re guided by our public health experts.&nbsp; And any decision would come from the CDC.&nbsp; The head of the CDC spoke to this earlier this morning.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So conversations within the administration &#8212; that&#8217;s what the Washington Post was also reporting: There were early conversations in the administration about possibly changing those guidelines.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve seen the reporting, but what I can tell you is that there has been no decision to change our mask guidelines.&nbsp; Any decisions about public health would be driven by the CDC.&nbsp; But, of course, we are engaged with public health experts and the CDC about how to continue to attack the virus.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve never said that battle is over; it&#8217;s still ongoing.<br><br>It would be more concerning &#8212; or should be more concerning to all of you and the American people &#8212; if we were not having those conversations.&nbsp; So, there are certainly conversations about steps we can and should take.&nbsp; But I think Dr. Walensky was quite clear this morning.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one quick follow-up.&nbsp; We heard the CDC Director today warn about the rise in the Delta variant, saying that it&#8217;s spreading with incredible efficiency.&nbsp; At what point would the White House reconsider the protocols for the President and for administration officials?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re guided by the public health guidance and the CDC guidelines, and that&#8217;s what we abide by here.&nbsp; They have not changed those, and so we continue to abide by the guidelines we have announced to all of you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Obviously, there are a lot of parents who are wondering what school is going to look like in the fall.&nbsp; And last night, the President said this, quote, “The CDC is going to say that everyone under the age of 12 should probably be wearing a mask in school.&nbsp; That&#8217;s probably what&#8217;s going to happen.”&nbsp; Has the CDC indicated that that is in fact their position already &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They already &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and how soon could we hear from them about that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They did already announce that several weeks ago as a part of their CDC guidance for schools &#8212; because anybody under 12 is not eligible to be vaccinated, so they would not be vaccinated, and so therefore they should be wearing a mask.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Got it.&nbsp; Also, we now know that Hunter Biden is going to be able to meet with prospective buyers at two art shows where his paintings are going to be on display later this year.&nbsp; How does this square with the goal of keeping him in the dark about the buyers of his art as a means to prevent even the appearance of undue influence?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, this showing that was &#8212; that you&#8217;re referencing was previously public.&nbsp; He&#8217;s not going to have any conversations related to the selling of art.&nbsp; That will be left to the gallerist, as was outlined in the agreement that we announced just a few weeks ago.&nbsp;<br><br>We believe this is a reasonable system that has been established that allows for Hunter Biden to work in his profession within appropriate safeguards.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s not going to discuss anything related to the selling of art.&nbsp; And I would reiterate that the gallerist will be the only person who handles transactions or conversations in that vein and will reject any offer that is out of the ordinary.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Wouldn&#8217;t it be more transparent to just release the names of the buyers so that everyone would know who purchased this art and how much they paid?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t &#8212; we won&#8217;t know who the buyers are; Hunter Biden won&#8217;t know who the buyers are.&nbsp; So, I think the re- &#8212; the origin, I think, of this line of questioning, which is understandable, is about whether this would provide un- &#8212; provide a situation for undue influence.&nbsp; But we won&#8217;t know who they are, so there&#8217;s no scenario where they could provide influence.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Couldn&#8217;t they just announce on social media that they bought a painting?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I think we have set up a system which we feel is appropriate &#8212; has appropriate safeguards.&nbsp; We believe that Hunter Biden, just like any child of a President, should be able to pursue their professions and their passions.&nbsp; And any selling of the art would be through the gallerist.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On schools, first: Now that the Education Department admits they made a mistake in their guide for reopening by in- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; How so?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, they included advice from the Abolitionist Teaching Network, and they came out and said that was not supposed to be in there.&nbsp; Is the administration going to follow up with school districts to make sure that the Abolitionist Teaching Network material is not in lesson plans?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, just to be clear, for the context &#8212; because I know you love context of what &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; you&#8217;re asking about here &#8212; what you&#8217;re referring to is a citation in a report of which there were 1,000 citations.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m quite impressed with your researchers for finding one of a thousand citations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It was an error in a lengthy document to include this citation.&nbsp; This specific site does not endor- &#8212; we &#8212; does not represent the administration&#8217;s view, and we don&#8217;t endorse the recommendations of this group.&nbsp; And I believe it&#8217;s been removed or is in the process of being removed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we are close to the schools reopening.&nbsp; And is there any concern if you don&#8217;t endorse this material that was in there &#8212; citation or not &#8212; that it&#8217;s in lesson plans?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that &#8212; as we &#8212; we said many times before &#8212; we don&#8217;t dictate or recommend specific curriculum decisions from the federal government.&nbsp; That is and will continue to be handled at the local level.&nbsp; And we believe that the American people trust teachers to make those decisions, not government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on masks: A few weeks ago, the President said we were “closer than ever to declaring our independence from a deadly virus.”&nbsp; Is that still the case if you guys are now reportedly considering asking vaccinated people to wear masks again?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, the CDC Director, who oversees decisions along those lines and all of our public health decisions, made clear that that was not a decision that had been made, just a few hours ago.&nbsp; So, I point out that first.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, I would say: What the President was referring to and continues to talk about, as he did last night at a town hall, is that we&#8217;re quite proud of the progress that&#8217;s been made.&nbsp; People over 65 &#8212; more than 80 percent are vaccinated.&nbsp; Almost 70 percent of adults are vaccinated.&nbsp; A hundred and sixty-two million Americans are vaccinated.&nbsp; That is certainly progress.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we are still at war with the virus; we&#8217;ve never said that would be over.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve always said that we&#8217;d be &#8212; continued to &#8212; continuing to focus on ensuring we&#8217;re meeting people where they are and getting them vaccinated, keeping them safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, the President said, in May, &#8220;vaxxed or masked.&#8221;&nbsp; Is &#8212; I think a lot of people got the vaccine because they were hearing him say, &#8220;If you get the vaccine, you don&#8217;t have to wear masks anymore.&#8221;&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And that continues to be CDC guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you can say that that&#8217;s going to be the guidance forever?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I am not the CDC Director.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand, but people don&#8217;t care who tells him to wear a mask.&nbsp; If it&#8217;s the White House &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They should care.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; if it&#8217;s the White House or the CDC, what difference does it make?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Shouldn&#8217;t they care if it&#8217;s a doctor or medical expert or a spokesperson?&nbsp; I think most Americans actually do care.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s the government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Kelly, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a conversation about encouraging people to make the personal choice that Dr. Walensky talked about today &#8212; if they, for example, are vaccinated but live in a state with low vaccination rates or have other considerations?&nbsp; Is part of your messaging going to be encouraging the personal choice piece on mask wearing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that is currently our messaging, right?&nbsp; So I would say that for communities, where there are lower rates of vaccination &#8212; and, as we know, that&#8217;s really concentrated in only a handful of states across the country where most of the cases are coming from, as we&#8217;ve seen the rise in the Delta variant, which is more transmissible, and, if you&#8217;re not vaccinated, it is transferring, no question, more quickly across people &#8212; people should wear masks.&nbsp; And that is something we will continue to encourage leaders and civic leaders and educators and people who are trusted voices in communities to make clear.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And those are vaccinated people you&#8217;re referring to &#8212; to make the personal choice to wear the mask in those high-rate areas?&nbsp; That’s what I&#8217;m asking about.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s not the advice of the CDC at this point in time, so that is not a message we are conveying to people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky said today that it can be a personal choice with the vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Of course.&nbsp; Of course, it can be.&nbsp; And some people make that decision because they are immunocompromised, because they have family members, because they just want an extra layer of protection, and we should all respect that.&nbsp; But it is not proactive guidance that the CDC is providing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last night, the President said, “You&#8217;re not going to get COVID if you have these vaccinations.”&nbsp; Why did he say that when that is not what the science says?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what the science says is that 97 percent of hospitalizations are people who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; So, yes, there are cases of individuals who are vaccinated, to be absolutely clear, who &#8212; who do have &#8212; gotten COVID.&nbsp; It is a very small percentage and a small number of people.<br>&nbsp;<br>And those cases &#8212; vast, vast, vast majority are asymptomatic and they have &#8212; they have minor symptoms, which means that you are largely protected.&nbsp; That was the point he was trying to make last night.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a couple of days since we talked about the breakthrough case on the campus here and that you acknowledged there were additional breakthrough cases.&nbsp; Can you give us, now, the number of breakthrough cases that have occurred during the Biden presidency?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, that our medical experts, our health experts have been conveying from the beginning, as have we, that there would be cases of individuals who are vaccinated who tested positive for COVID.&nbsp; There are 2,000 people who work on the campus, and, of course, that means that, just statistically speaking, there will be people who are vaccinated individuals who get COVID on the campus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I announced yesterday or conveyed yesterday was what our policy would be moving forward.&nbsp; But, no, I don&#8217;t think you can expect that we&#8217;re going to be providing numbers of breakthrough cases, no.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Really?&nbsp; That&#8217;s not transparency to give us a number &#8212; not the names, but a number of these cases?&nbsp; You must have that information.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Kelly, I think, one, we&#8217;re in a very different place than we were several months ago.&nbsp; The vast, vast, vast majority of individuals who are vaccinated who get COVID will have &#8212; will be asymptomatic or have mild cases.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Every individual at this White House has been offered a vaccine, and we have been very clear that we will be transparent with anyone who has had close proximity contact with the President or any of the four principles, as deemed by the White House Medical Unit, with all of you.&nbsp; And if they &#8212; if they approve having their name released, we will also release their names, but we will protect their privacy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That will be our policy moving forward, and we understand and agree that that is in the public interest.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, last night, at the CNN Town Hall, the President was asked by an &#8212; a restauranteur about the worker shortage that the Commerce Secretary just called “acute.”&nbsp; She described it as a “skills gap,” but the restauranteur said that he had, right now, job openings that he can&#8217;t fill.&nbsp; And he asked the President if there&#8217;s anything that his administration can do to help him and his business.&nbsp; The President seemed to struggle with an answer.&nbsp; Is there anything that his administration can do to help that restauranteur or people who are similarly situated with this acute worker shortage?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that we have already implemented &#8212; and the money has gone out the door &#8212; goes &#8212; it continues to go out the door for our Restaurant Restabilization Program &#8212; something that was a part of the American Rescue Plan and helped many, many hundreds of restaurants across the country stay open, reopen.&nbsp; And that was assistance that came from the American Rescue Plan that the President signed into law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think what the President was noting is that, at this point in time, it&#8217;s also a workers’ market.&nbsp; And in some places, it may be that you have to pay more wages in order to attract workers.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have all the details, of course, about his individual circumstance, but we implemented a major program that helped restaurants stay open &#8212; something we strongly supported, we advocated for as a part of the package.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I can ask a follow-up to the question about the President&#8217;s son and the art gallery event.&nbsp; You said that Hunter Biden is not going to discuss anything related to the sale of his art.&nbsp; Is that a promise that has been made in writing?&nbsp; And if so, is that an agreement that could be made available to the public?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m making that clear to all of you now that that is an agreement that has been made as a part of this &#8212; as a part of these events.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it in writing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can check and see if there&#8217;s more detail.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But I think it&#8217;s pretty clear what the agreement is, so I&#8217;m not sure it&#8217;s more complicated than that.&nbsp; But I will see if there&#8217;s more to provide.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; One on masks and then one quick one on the Fed after that.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci told reporters earlier today that there isn&#8217;t enough research to know whether breakthrough cases can result in long COVID.&nbsp; The President has repeatedly told the public that, you know, they should &#8212; they&#8217;re safe from the worst effects of COVID.&nbsp; How can he be sure without this research?&nbsp; And if there&#8217;s even a chance that breakthrough cases can result in long COVID, why not recommend masks more widely?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what the President is referring to &#8212; one, we&#8217;ve seen some interesting polling over the last week &#8212; I believe it was a CBS poll &#8212; that showed that vaccinated people in the country are more fearful about the Delta variant than unvaccinated people.&nbsp; That&#8217;s clearly concerning to us because unvaccinated people should be more fearful.&nbsp; And what the President wanted to convey to people in the country is the impact and effect of getting vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we also know statistically that 97 percent of hospitalizations are for people who are unvaccinated and that the vast majority of cases are asymptomatic or have very mild symptoms, which the health and medical experts will tell you &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re talking about the long-term &#8212; long-term effects here &#8212; right? &#8212; which we don’t know yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s true.&nbsp; There&#8217;s still research about a range of components of the impacts of COVID over the long term, which our health and medical leaders will advise us on.&nbsp; They also have not changed their guidance on masks.&nbsp; That is not a determination that&#8217;s being made by &#8212; from a political standpoint or from anyone in the White House.&nbsp; That is something the CDC and our health and medical experts are advising on, and they look at a range of factors.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on the Fed.&nbsp; Is the President concerned at all that choosing a new Federal Reserve Chairman during a period of economic uncertainty and inflation could complicate economic recovery or spook the markets?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I just have nothing to preview for you in terms of the end of the term next winter.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, you already asked.&nbsp; Go ahead, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On infrastructure, Senator Carper, one of your allies, said that he wants to make sure that the water infrastructure measures that the Senate already passed and the Surface Transportation Reauthorization bill that passed out of his committee are also included in the infrastructure agreement.&nbsp; I know that the bipartisan group said yesterday that they were 99 percent of the way there.&nbsp; I know there are some issues that Republican lawmakers are working out with the White House right now.&nbsp; Are Senator Carper’s concerns also something that the White House is aware of and working on at this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re certainly aware of the concerns that have been expressed, or asks or requests by a range of members.&nbsp; This is typically what happens, as you all know, in this period of time where we&#8217;re very close to a point where there&#8217;s going to be a vote on a motion to proceed.&nbsp; And everybody who has initiatives, who has priorities is going to make their voice heard.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a part of the process.&nbsp; We respect that.&nbsp; So, certainly, we&#8217;re engaged in discussions, as is the leadership.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would also note that &#8212; that we are &#8212; we see clear signs of momentum.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re quite &#8212; we were quite encouraged by the letter &#8212; yesterday&#8217;s letter signed by 11 Republicans and 11 Democrats showing positive signs about being able to go forward soon.&nbsp; And the President is, of course, eager to deliver these economic ben- &#8212; benefits to Americans in red states and blue states that they&#8217;ve long been waiting for.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think there&#8217;s flexibility to add more money to this bill for those measures that were &#8212; got wide support on the Hill, in the Senate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think there was a clear agreement that the President and members of both parties stood outside of the White House and announced just a few weeks ago.&nbsp; Of course, there will be final discussions over the coming days as they work to finalize the bill text.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on the filibuster: The President said last night that getting rid of it would throw the entire Congress into chaos and nothing will get done, and that&#8217;s sort of his justification for not getting rid of it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>With maybe the exception of anything that can kind of be done along party lines and perhaps this infrastructure bill as well &#8212; likely this infrastructure bill &#8212; is anything getting done?&nbsp; Will anything get done, you know, that can&#8217;t just be done through reconciliation, you know, once we get past this infrastructure thing?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And/or if the things that can&#8217;t get done are things like voting rights that are so big &#8212; or dealing with climate or immigration &#8212; is there really any difference between having the filibuster in place and getting rid of it?&nbsp; What&#8217;s sort of the President&#8217;s justification for not getting rid of it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the President doesn&#8217;t make the decision on filibuster rules or parliamentary rules in the Senate; the Senate does.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll leave that to the Senate.&nbsp; It also requires the majority in the Senate to support a rule change.&nbsp; And so, what he was referring to is simply what that process would look like and the fact that there are some in the Senate who have said they would halt all business if that conversation were to happen.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, in some means, he was reporting out what is publicly known about what the process might look like moving forward.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll leave it to all of you to whip count on how many votes there would be for filibuster changes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; and you&#8217;re saying that there is &#8212; that he&#8217;s not engaging on this.&nbsp; He has kept &#8212; continually talked about wanting to move back to the talking filibuster.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he is weighing in on a part of the filibuster (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And &#8212; and he talked about that last night.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And talked about the fact that it shouldn&#8217;t be so easy to be obstreperous &#8212; I think is a word he’s used before I’ve wanted to use in here &#8212; and it shouldn&#8217;t be so easy to prevent legislation from moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll also note that, you know, the President ran for office because he felt that people&#8217;s fundamental rights were being violated by the last President.&nbsp; And voting rights and racial equality is central to what he wants to do as President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So he has already taken a number of steps.&nbsp; He will continue to advocate for the For the People Act &#8212; which every Democrat voted to advance after he worked the phones &#8212; and the John Lewis Voting Rights Act.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He and the Vice President have launched an all-of-government effort to protect and advance voting rights in every way we can through the executive branch after his executive order.&nbsp; And the White House Counsel&#8217;s Office Legislative team, Public Engagement team, and the Domestic Policy team all remain very engaged on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So he is going to use every lever at his disposal.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to elevate these issues, but he does not, alone, make changes to the &#8212; or does not even have a official role in making changes to procedures in the Senate.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Anne.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Delta variant: We heard the President, last night, speak at some length about the effects on individual Americans &#8212; what the consequences are from this new, highly transmissible variant if you&#8217;re not vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wonder to what extent is he worried, are you worried about the effects &#8212; one step beyond that &#8212; on his agenda and the things that he wants to do this fall if we do end up where the trajectory currently is with basically two camps.&nbsp; You have safe, vaccinated Americans, and you have unsafe, unvaccinated Americans.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He has said before he wants to be President for everyone and have an agenda to match.&nbsp; How can that come true, moving into the fall, if you have so many people in this country who are still at risk of hospitalization and death?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So just so &#8212; I&#8217;m just trying to understand your question.&nbsp; How will &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The impact on the agenda &#8212; his agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In what way though?&nbsp; Like his legislative agenda?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I mean, his &#8212; yes.&nbsp; His general agenda for improving the lives of Americans &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; across a variety of spheres, as he&#8217;s talked about, movingly, several times, including last night.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What he wants to do &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, no, I just wanted to make sure I understood your question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, look, I think that he said in the beginning, and he reiterated last night, that getting the pandemic under control, protecting Americans from the spread of the virus has been, continues to be his number one priority.&nbsp; And that he&#8217;s going to govern for all Americans &#8212; Democrats, independents, Republicans, even people who did not vote for him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, one of the reasons that he does &#8212; did an event like the town hall last night, and one of the reasons why he speaks about what the dire impacts are of the spread of the most transmissible version of the virus we&#8217;ve seen to date is because he wants people to be protected.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve seen, in a lot of these states, there has been a &#8212; you know, misinformation traveling.&nbsp; There has been a, in some cases, a political bent of who is and isn&#8217;t getting vaccinated, unfortunately.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We don&#8217;t want this to be a partisan issue.&nbsp; So, he&#8217;s going to keep at it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure on his legislative agenda how that &#8212; I don&#8217;t know how to make that connection, but it will continue to be his priority moving forward.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on Iraq: the Iraqi Prime Minister will be here Monday.&nbsp; In April, the administration said that the U.S. and Iraq have agreed to eventually withdraw U.S. combat forces and that talks would take place beginning then &#8212; toward that end.&nbsp; Can you give us an update on where those talks stand, and whether the President will be able to announce either a date certain or more specific plans about the withdrawal of U.S. combat forces on Monday?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, well, I&#8217;m not going to get too far ahead of the meeting, which won’t surprise you.&nbsp; But I will tell you that &#8212; I will remind you, I should say &#8212; as Prime Minister Kadhimi stated publicly last week &#8212; even with the decreasing need for U.S. forces with a combat role on Iraq, his government is requesting continuing support from the United States and the coalition for training and enabling its forces, logistics, intelligence sharing, and other areas of security cooperation.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve responded to that request and the discussions between our delegations have been extremely constructive and are ongoing.&nbsp; U.S. military forces are in Iraq, at Iraq&#8217;s invitation, to support Iraqi forces in their fight against ISIS.&nbsp; We routinely discuss the activities of U.S. forces in Iraq and evolution of the mission, from the height of the ISIS campaign to today, where ISIS remains a threat but major combat operations have ended and Iraqi capacity has increased significantly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is an ongoing discussion.&nbsp; We &#8212; I would note the Prime Minister&#8217;s comments.&nbsp; Our delegations will continue to discuss.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more to say &#8212; I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;ll have more to say after their meeting.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to ask questions on Tokyo Olympic Games.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First Lady Jill Biden is bound to attend the opening ceremony.&nbsp; The Opening ceremony’s creative director was fired yesterday for &#8212; over the Holocaust joke he made in 1990s.&nbsp; Does White House have any comment on that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly, we support that decision and disagree with his comments &#8212; offensive comments.&nbsp; The First Lady will still plan to attend the Opening Ceremony to support U.S. athletes and represent the U.S. government at the highest level.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Florida Governor DeSantis was talking about mask mandates for kids earlier this morning.&nbsp; And he said, “We&#8217;re not doing that in Florida.&nbsp; We need our kids to breathe.&nbsp; We need our kids to be able to be kids.”&nbsp; He said “It’s terribly uncomfortable for them to do it.”&nbsp; That obviously goes against the CDC guidance &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for kids under 12 who aren&#8217;t vaccinated and what the President said last night.&nbsp; Is that putting kids in Florida at risk?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as a parent myself &#8212; and I know you are one &#8212; if I were a parent in Florida, that would be greatly concerning to me because kids under the age of 12 are not vaccinated; they&#8217;re not eligible yet.&nbsp; As the President said last night, obviously it&#8217;s going to be led by the FDA, but certainly we hope that will be soon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But that puts kids at risk.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not aligned with public health guidelines.&nbsp; We know masks are not the most comfortable thing.&nbsp; I will say, my kids are quite adjusted to them, as I know many kids are.&nbsp; So, certainly, we would have concern about any step that doesn&#8217;t abide by public health guidelines and we think it puts people at greater risk.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President frustrated that in the fall when kids go back to school across the country that there could be very different standards for kids under 12?&nbsp; And is there something that he can do about that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President can speak out, as he did last night, about the risks of the Delta variant that is more transmissible than any variant we&#8217;ve seen to date, about the risk to young people of the spread of COVID, and about the fact that the CDC has put out clear guidelines, clear mitigation steps that can be taken to keep families safe, kids sape &#8212; safe, individuals safe, and then there are a range of steps that people can take.&nbsp;<br><br>I think what&#8217;s notable about the CDC education guidelines is that it made very clear it&#8217;s important for kids to be back in school, and that that&#8217;s important for their mental health.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important for kids to be learning.&nbsp; We don’t want to put kids behind who &#8212; you know, and create some sort of an additional educational gap.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But there are recommendations by the public health experts for a reason; he&#8217;ll continue to elevate them.&nbsp; But ultimately, those decisions will be made by local school districts.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kaitlan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Can you confirm that White House officials are involved in these discussions about whether or not they need to update the mask guidance?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the CDC Director made clear that was not a decision made.&nbsp; We are regularly in touch and have regular meetings with our public health officials, including the CDC, about how to continue to address the virus.&nbsp; That shouldn&#8217;t surprise anyone.&nbsp; On &#8212; those conversations cover a range of topics.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think the most important thing for the public is that there hasn&#8217;t been a decision made.&nbsp; It will always be led with public health guidance.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve made that very clear this morning.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s just unusual that no one will confirm the discussions are actually happening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think because the report on it was a little breathless about what it implied was happening when the CDC Director said that&#8217;s not a decision that&#8217;s been made.&nbsp; And we want to be clear to the public: Nobody is being advised &#8212; who&#8217;s vaccinated &#8212; to wear a mask.&nbsp; That is not what the public health guidelines says.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the White House concerned about the messaging aspect of this, given not having to wear a mask is often a perk of being vaccinated that the White House and other top health officials have touted?&nbsp; So, are you concerned that if there is a change to the mask guidance for vaccinated individuals when they&#8217;re indoors that it would be harder to sell vaccinations, essentially?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there hasn&#8217;t been a change.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s pretty clear now that if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you don&#8217;t wear &#8212; need to wear a mask.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re not vacckinate [sic] &#8212; vaccinated &#8212; that’s a hard word &#8212; you do &#8212; you should wear a mask, according to the public health guidelines.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a prediction that the CDC Director made this morning.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We certainly know that it is important &#8212; even as parents, as Karen was asking about before &#8212; when you have kids, you&#8217;re not wearing a mask.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not wearing a mask at the playground, or I&#8217;m not wearing a mask, you know, indoors; my kids are still wearing masks.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not terribly confusing to people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, you know, we&#8217;ll continue to communicate, convey what the accurate public health guidelines is.&nbsp; Nothing has changed about that.&nbsp; And, of course, we have ongoing discussions about how to keep the American people safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just related to that, is the White House position still the same on vaccine verification?&nbsp; Have there been any conversations about promoting businesses choosing to verify vaccinated status for attending concerts or dining indoors?&nbsp; Is there &#8212; is there any discussion around vaccine verification, or changing the posture?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is not &#8212; our position has not changed, nor do I anticipate it would, on guidance coming from the federal government.&nbsp; It is also entirely appropriate for private-sector entities and universities and hospitals to make decisions about how to keep their community safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If we can go back to the President&#8217;s comment about ending the filibuster, how it would create chaos &#8212; what did that mean exactly?&nbsp; What kind of chaos would be created?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as I answered &#8212; I think it was Jen&#8217;s question, over here, in response to her question &#8212; what the President was speaking to is the fact that it&#8217;s a parliamentary process.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not something you&nbsp;<s>wage</s>&nbsp;[wave] a magic wand to change.&nbsp; It will require the majority of votes in the Senate.&nbsp; There would be debate about that process in the Senate.&nbsp; And there are manys &#8212; many individuals in the Senate who have been clear that they would throw the Senate into chaos and halt all progress.&nbsp; So, I think he was reporting out on what you all have publicly reported on yourself.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, in regards to Senator Carper, since there&#8217;s no room to lose a Democrat in this, what is the White House doing to get him back on board?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that he&#8217;s characterized himself as &#8220;not on board&#8221; with the infrastructure bill that is incredibly popular and supported by the majority of people across the country, but we also understand and recognize that, in the process of legislating, there are periods where people want to have their voice heard &#8212; we support that; have asks they want to make; have components they want to see in legislation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s the part of the messy process of legislating.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what&#8217;s ongoing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re engaged with a range of members, including, of course, Senator Carper and, of course, working closely with Senate leadership as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just following up on Anne&#8217;s question on Iraq.&nbsp; There has been criticism on the part of the administration that there is a lack of clarity on what the U.S. wants to achieve in Iraq.&nbsp; So, can you explain, beyond defeating ISIS or controlling ISIS, what is it exactly that the President wants to do in Iraq, and perhaps a timeline?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I&#8217;m not sure I can say much more than what I said to &#8212; which it was an extensive answer, I will say &#8212; to Anne&#8217;s question, which was that we are in Iraq at the invitation of Iraqi leadership, obviously.&nbsp; And they have asked our military to remain &#8212; to continue to play a role in &#8212; their government is requesting continuing support from us and the coalition for training and enabling their forces &#8212; its forces, logistics, intelligence sharing, and other areas of security cooperation.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the Prime Minister spoke to last week.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also noted that we are in ongoing discussions with them.&nbsp; The Prime Minister is going to be here next week, but I don&#8217;t think I have much more to preview for you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you clarify what is the President&#8217;s latest position on his proposal to partition Iraq, or soft partition Iraq, that he has supported in the past?&nbsp; Can you give us clarification on what&#8217;s his latest position on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think he&#8217;s made that proposal in any recent time, but he&#8217;s looking forward to the meeting with the Prime Minister.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick question on Guantanamo Bay.&nbsp; I heard you say, last week &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that the goal is to close the detentions facility there.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess 39 detainees remain.&nbsp; What are the next steps that the administration is taking to close Guantanamo Bay?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would point you to the Department of Defense and their leadership on this effort.&nbsp; I &#8212; there are 39 detainees who remain at Guantanamo Bay; 10 are eligible for transfer, of course; 17 are eligible for a Periodic Review Board; 10 are involved in the military commissions process; 2 detainees have been convicted.&nbsp; So, I would point you to the Department of Defense, and they can outline more specifically.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; I got to go because we got to go see the President.<br>&nbsp;<br>All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) breaking news (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not going anywhere.&nbsp; We&#8217;re here, Brian.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>1:32 P.M.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 1652</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/22/bill-signed-h-r-1652/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 20:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24805</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, July 22, 2021, the President signed into law: H.R. 1652, the “VOCA Fix to Sustain the Crime Victims Fund Act of 2021,” which requires funds collected from deferred prosecution and non-prosecution agreements to be deposited into the Crime Victims Fund; increases the crime victim compensation formula grant to provide eligible programs with 75&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, July 22, 2021, the President signed into law:<br><br>H.R. 1652, the “VOCA Fix to Sustain the Crime Victims Fund Act of 2021,” which requires funds collected from deferred prosecution and non-prosecution agreements to be deposited into the Crime Victims Fund; increases the crime victim compensation formula grant to provide eligible programs with 75 percent of the amounts awarded during the preceding year; allows states to waive a requirement that programs promote victim cooperation with law enforcement; and allows or requires states to waive matching requirements for grant funds under certain circumstances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawal Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/22/nominations-and-withdrawal-sent-to-the-senate/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24799</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Andrew Philip Hunter, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Air Force, vice William Roper. &#160; &#160; &#160;Jonathan Kanter, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Attorney General, vice Makan Delrahim, resigned. &#160; &#160; &#160;Thomas R. Nides, of Minnesota, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Andrew Philip Hunter, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Air Force, vice William Roper.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jonathan Kanter, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Attorney General, vice Makan Delrahim, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Thomas R. Nides, of Minnesota, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the State of Israel.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Graham Scott Steele, of California, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Treasury, vice Bimal Patel, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Tom Udall, of New Mexico, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to New Zealand, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Independent State of Samoa.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Tamara Cofman Wittes, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Michael T. Harvey.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>     Andrew Philip Hunter, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Army, vice Bruce D. Jette, which was sent to the Senate on July 20, 2021.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
