<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 15:12:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on the President’s Trip to The Middle&#160;East</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/14/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-the-presidents-trip-to-the-middle-east/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 15:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (June 13, 2022) 8:01 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:  Good evening, everyone.  This call will be on background attributable to a senior administration official.  For your awareness, not for reporting, on the line is [senior administration official].  The contents of the call will be embargoed until 8:00 a.m. tomorrow, June 14th. And, [senior administration official], I&#8217;ll&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br> <br>(June 13, 2022)</p>



<p>8:01 P.M. EDT<br><br>MODERATOR:  Good evening, everyone.  This call will be on background attributable to a senior administration official.  For your awareness, not for reporting, on the line is [senior administration official].  The contents of the call will be embargoed until 8:00 a.m. tomorrow, June 14th.<br><br>And, [senior administration official], I&#8217;ll hand it over to you to get started.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks.  And thank you for joining this call to a preview the President&#8217;s trip to the Middle East later next month.<br><br>My opening here is about 15 minutes or so, maybe a little longer.  There&#8217;s a lot of information, and so I wanted to get it all out there.  I point out at the top that this trip has been in the works for some time.  <br><br>We&#8217;ve long recognized the importance of the President visiting this vital region in a manner similar to the Summit of ASEAN leaders here at the White House, the President&#8217;s visit to South Korea and Japan and convening the Quad Summit, the Summit of the Americas last week, and the G7 and NATO summits next week.<br><br>So this visit to the Middle East region, where the President will engage with nearly a dozen of his counterparts in three stops &#8212; Israel, the West Bank, and Saudi Arabia &#8212; is part of this clear sequence of global engagements at an important moment and demonstrates, we believe, the return of American leadership to bring countries together to address common threats and challenges, something the United States can uniquely do, and with new frameworks that aim to harness unique American capabilities to enable partners to work more closely together, which is essential to a more secure, prosperous, and stable Middle East region over the long term.<br><br>This comparative advantage of ours &#8212; bringing countries together, building and strengthening coalitions and alliances &#8211;atrophied under the last administration.  We&#8217;ve worked to restore it.  And as I think we&#8217;ve seen since Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine, the United States and President Biden personally has begun to revitalize our unique strength in building alliances and coalitions through diplomacy and highest-level engagement.<br><br>In the Middle East region, the topic of this call, I’d point to the vote last week at the IAEA Board of Governors in Vienna, where 30 countries condemned Iran&#8217;s lack of compliance with safeguard obligations, a resounding vote clearly isolating Iran, whereas a year and a half ago, it was the United States that was isolated internationally on this important issue.<br><br>So while there&#8217;s a great deal of work to do, this historic visit to the Middle East comes against that larger backdrop, both globally and in the Middle East region itself. <br><br>So now some details on the trip.  The President will visit the Middle East region from July 13th to July 16th with stops in Israel, the West Bank, and Saudi Arabia, and engagements with nearly a dozen counterparts from across the region and beyond.  The first stop is Israel.  This will be President Biden&#8217;s first visit to the country as President, and it comes nearly 50 years after his first visit to Israel as a young senator. <br><br>As the President often says about Israel, he learned as a young boy from his father that if Israel did not exist, then we would need to invent it.  He has a lifelong connection to the country, and his charge to all of us is to make sure we&#8217;re doing all we can to strengthen Israel&#8217;s security, prosperity, and integration into the larger region, both now and over the longer term.<br><br>One of the first foreign crises of the presidency was the Israeli-Hamas war in May of last year.  The President&#8217;s personal relations with leaders in the region and his very hands-on diplomacy helped end that war, one that had all the ingredients to last for months, in 11 days.  He has since remained deeply engaged with Israeli and other regional leaders to help maintain the peace.<br><br>Our administration also worked with the Congress to secure $1 billion to replenish the Iron Dome Missile Defense System after the Gaza conflict.  And in March, earlier this year, the Congress passed an NDAA with the largest funding package for Israel in U.S. history, with a particular focus on missile defense and security assistance. <br><br>While in Israel, the President will likely visit an area where these defensive systems are utilized, as well as discuss new innovations between our countries that use laser technologies to defeat missiles and other airborne threats.<br><br>In meetings with Israeli leaders, the President will reaffirm the ironclad U.S. commitment to Israel’s security and new areas of deepening cooperation in technology, climate, commerce, trade, and other sectors. <br><br>The visit will also focus on Israel&#8217;s increasing integration into the region, both through the Abraham Accords with UAE, Morocco, and Bahrain; through deepening ties between Israel, Jordan and Egypt; and also an entirely new groupings of partners, including Israel, India, UAE, and the United States &#8212; what we call I2U2.<br><br>We consider these initiatives central to our strategy of empowering partners and encouraging them to work more closely together, which will lead to a more stable region and also to Israel&#8217;s security and prosperity over the longer term.  Secretary Blinken, just last month in the Negev, in southern Israel, met with counterparts from Abraham Accord partners UAE, Bahrain and Morocco, together with Jordan and Egypt, highlighting these deepening regional partnerships.<br><br>Importantly, some of these new partnerships reach beyond the Middle East, and in this regard, the President will hold a virtual summit with the I2U2 heads of state for discussions of the food security crisis and other areas of cooperation across hemispheres where UAE and Israel serve as important innovation hubs. <br><br>The President looks forward to this unique engagement with Prime Minister Bennett of Israel, with Prime Minister Modi of India, and President Mohammed bin Zayed of the UAE. <br><br>He will also, of course, hold side meetings and engagements, which we will preview in the run-up to the trip.<br><br>I note, finally, for the Israel portion that the President will be in Israel at the start of the Maccabiah Games, which brings Jewish athletes from around the world to Israel for an Olympics-like competition.  And he may have an opportunity to meet some of the athletes, and we&#8217;re pleased that this joyous event, the first since 2017, happens to overlap with the President&#8217;s historic visit to Israel.<br><br>The President will also visit the West Bank to meet with President Mahmoud Abbas and other Palestinian leaders.  The President, of course, has known Abbas for decades, and he looks forward to reaffirming his lifelong commitment to a two-state solution and to discuss the ways in which we might rekindle a new political horizon that can ensure equal measures of freedom, security, prosperity, and dignity to Israelis and Palestinians alike.  <br><br>Of course, when we entered office nearly a year and a half ago, ties between the U.S. government and the Palestinians had been nearly severed.  We&#8217;ve worked to restore those ties, and we now have regular engagements with the Palestinian leadership.<br><br>Jake Sullivan visited Ramallah shortly before the new year.  My State Department colleague Barbara Leaf was there just this past Saturday.<br><br>And we&#8217;ve provided over half a billion dollars in support, including humanitarian, economic, and security assistance for the Palestinians since April of last year. <br><br>The President&#8217;s visit is a culmination of these contacts but also the start of what we hope will be new and reinvigorated dialogue, both between the United States and the PA, but also between the PA regional capitals and, most importantly, Israelis. <br><br>Following the visits to Israel and the West Bank, the President will fly directly from Israel to Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, where he will participate in a summit of the Gulf Cooperation &#8212; GCC+3 &#8212; the GCC+3 &#8212; so the leaders of Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Oman, UAE, Bahrain, and Qatar, plus Iraq, Jordan, and Egypt. <br><br>The President will also hold bilateral meetings with the Saudi hosts and other counterparts. <br><br>We are grateful that Saudi Arabia, which holds the rotating presidency of the GCC in 2022, will host this important summit bringing together nine heads of state from across the region to meet the President at the invitation of King Salman. <br><br>The President will discuss a range of bilateral regional and global issues in Jeddah.  These include support to the U.N.-mediated truce in Yemen, which has led to the most peaceful period there since the war began seven years ago.  <br><br>He will also discuss means for expanding regional, economic, and security cooperation, including new and promising infrastructure and climate initiatives, as well as deterring threats from Iran, advancing human rights, and ensuring global energy and food security. <br><br>The President also looks forward to outlining an affirmative agenda for America&#8217;s engagement in this vital region, making clear that the United States is fully committed to supporting the territorial defense of our partners against threats from Iran or elsewhere, and doing so in new integrated and innovative ways, while also combining these strong deterrent capabilities with proactive diplomacy to de-escalate tensions and wars wherever possible.  <br><br>One of those wars, of course, is Yemen.  And from the earliest days of our administration, we have sought to de-escalate and ultimately end this terrible conflict.  Intensive U.S. engagement and diplomacy in the region, including with Saudi Arabia in particular, helped facilitate the first durable truce in Yemen in nearly six years.  That truce, as I mentioned, is now in its ninth week, after having been extended just last week.  <br><br>For the first time since the war began more than seven years ago, civilian flights are flying from Sana&#8217;a to Cairo and Oman.  And Yemen itself has a new government under new leadership that seems determined to establish a durable peace.  <br><br>This will require a great deal of work going forward, and I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;ll be an important topic of discussion between the President and other leaders. <br><br>That brings me to Saudi Arabia.  From the earliest days of our administration, we made clear that U.S. policy demanded recalibration in relations with this important country but not a rupture.  And that is because we have important interests interwoven with Saudi Arabia, and engagement is essential to protecting and advancing those interests on behalf of the American people. <br><br>Saudi Arabia has been a strategic partner of the United States for nearly 80 years, and the President considers Riyadh an important partner on a host of regional and global priorities that we are working on.  <br><br>Since entering office, the President has had two constructive conversations with King Salman.  And senior officials from across our national security team have been engaged with the Saudis regularly on a host of issues from climate, to energy security, to new openings for regional cooperation, to human rights, to ending the war in Yemen, containing Iran, supporting our maritime defense, among many other topics. <br><br>And these engagements do deliver results.  Only 10 days ago, of course, we welcomed the announcement from OPEC Plus, where Saudi Arabia is the leading producer and exporter, to raise its plant supply increases this summer by 50 percent, as well as the important renewal of the Yemen truce.  These are welcomed moves, and we anticipate more of them over the coming months. <br><br>At bottom, the President believes strongly that at this particular moment in the world with interests at stake for the for the United States and the American people, visiting Saudi Arabia for a summit of leaders from across the Middle East region and to discuss face to face with those leaders, including the Saudis, how we move forward as partners is a smart thing to do at the right time, and offers opportunity for significant gains both for the United States, for Saudi Arabia, for the Middle East region, and for advancing our strategy towards a more stable, more peaceful, and more integrated region, which ultimately benefits the American people and the world. <br><br>I will not get ahead &#8212; on this call, I will not get ahead of some of the initiatives that are underway or that may be announced before or during the visit.  But I will say that this visit is the culmination of months of diplomacy, bilateral and multilateral, and also sets the stage for what we hope to get done through the rest of this year and through 2023 as well. <br><br>So with that, I&#8217;m happy to take a few questions.<br><br>Q    Thank you so much.  Thank you, [senior administration official], for doing this.  This is Nadia Bilbassy of Al Arabiya.  If you remember, during the Obama administration, there were mechanisms where they had a similar summit &#8212; as you just mentioned, this one will be analogous to the Asia and the Americas Summit &#8212; where President Obama met with the GCC countries and they discussed the U.S. and regional interest. <br><br>So will this new summit &#8212; will it establish to a mechanism similar to that, adding Iraq, Jordan, and Egypt permanently where it&#8217;s held every year, in an Arab capital?  And will be the main focus, in addition to very serious issues, of course, is countering Iran?<br><br>And one quick technical question: Will the President meet Mahmoud Abbas in Bethlehem or in Ramallah? <br><br>Thank you so much.<br><br>Q    Well, thanks, Nadia, for great questions.  Look, I think it&#8217;s a much different time than six, seven years ago.  And I think this unique gathering of leaders in Jeddah and of the President flying directly from Israel to Jeddah, I think it offers some unique opportunities to discuss some important issues in the world, some of which I laid out, but obviously, containing Iran and energy security.<br><br>I think the President will discuss some pretty innovative initiatives we have ongoing in CENTCOM, in the Red Sea; some unique naval task forces, which we&#8217;ll discuss on the security side; but also the economic integration.  Again, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of anything, but there&#8217;s some really important infrastructure and climate projects that are being done across borders by capitals who are cooperating with each other in really new and promising ways.<br><br>So the Middle East is much different than it was six, seven years ago, and I think we&#8217;re looking &#8212; really looking forward in trying to build on some of the opportunities in ways that can benefit both the region but, most importantly, the United States and the American people. <br><br>And I don’t &#8212; it’s likely to be in Bethlehem, Nadia, but I don’t want to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to discuss the specific meetings, details, or anything like that.  We’ll have more details as the trip approaches. <br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q    Hey there.  Thanks for doing the call.  I &#8212; two quick questions.  One, you just said &#8212; you said it’s likely to be in Bethlehem.  I didn&#8217;t quite hear what you said.  <br><br>And, secondly, on the trip to Jeddah, is it to be assumed that the President will have a bilat, then, with MBS?  And then, can we assume &#8212; I mean, what do we say about if the Khashoggi issue comes up during that meeting?  Does he intend to bring it up during that meeting, or is it an attempt to leave it in the past at this point?<br><br>And then, anything else you tell us about who he’ll meet with?  Will he meet individually with each of these nine leaders there or only as a group?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah, so the President, I think, will have meetings with leaders.  I would just say he&#8217;ll see over a dozen leaders on this trip, and so that includes King Salman and the leadership from our Saudi hosts for the GCC+3 Summit.  So, yes, we can expect the President to see the Crown Prince.<br><br>And I would just note that our teams have been quite constructively engaged over the last five or six months on Yemen and a host of things that I laid out in the introduction.  So I think that answers your question, Peter.<br><br>But, you know, I&#8217;m not going to get into specific meetings or the tick-tock of the visit.  Obviously, one reason &#8212; I know there&#8217;s been a lot of speculation on when the visit will be announced.  One reason is simply we&#8217;re scheduling a lot with a lot of different leaders from all across the region, so to nail everything down takes time.  But we&#8217;re now in a place where we feel this has come together in a very constructive way for everyone involved, and the President is looking forward to it. And I think we have a lot of work to get done over these four days in the Middle East.<br><br>Q    Thanks.  Will there be any particular asks on human rights during the trip, as some lawmakers, including many Democratic allies, have made of the President as a condition of the trip? <br><br>And then secondly, have the Saudis made any commitments, as a condition of the trip, on energy? Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  So I think the first question follows up on something Peter asked; I don&#8217;t think I fully addressed.  Look, human rights is always a part of the conversation in our foreign engagements, and I think it&#8217;s what makes the United States unique.  I think it&#8217;s what makes our administration unique.  And I think if you look at our record, including in the human rights region, I think we&#8217;re the first administration that reprogrammed FMF funding from Egypt; we&#8217;ve taken a number of other measures.<br><br>I&#8217;ll also say, though, a lot of these conversations we do hold them behind closed doors, and we think engagement &#8212; and that is the best way to get results.  <br><br>But our administration is not overlooking any contact that took place before we entered office.  And, of course, early on, we issued an extensive report about the Khashoggi murder.  That, of course, was not new news.  That was a report from the U.S. government that was issued years earlier that had been bottled up.  And we promised to issue it, and we did.<br><br>At the same time, we instituted the so-called “Khashoggi ban” to make sure that any country that seeks to use tools of repression against people abroad who criticize their government will pay a price.  We&#8217;ve used it multiple times.  So we imposed sanctions or visa restrictions on over 70 Saudi individuals and entities, including the Saudi Royal Guard’s Rapid Intervention Force.  This, of course, was all done over a year ago. </p>



<p>&nbsp;I think it&#8217;s very important also, though, of course, to emphasize, as we did then, that while we recalibrate relations, we&#8217;re not seeking to rupture relations, because Saudi Arabia has been a strategic partner of the United States for eight decades.&nbsp; And we share a host of interests with Saudi Arabia, from containing Iran, to counterterrorism, to helping protect its territory where, importantly, 70,000 Americans live and work.&nbsp; And I just think that&#8217;s an important fact.&nbsp;<br><br>I mean, Saudi Arabia has faced hundreds of missiles and UAVs over the last 18 months, many of them targeting areas where Americans live and work.&nbsp; And so we have been engaged very deeply and very constructively with the Saudis to help defeat those threats, and that&#8217;s something, obviously, that is going to continue.<br><br>So, yes, human rights is always a part of our conversation; there’s no doubt it will be part of the meetings the President has in the region, both in the stop in Jeddah and also, of course, in the stop in Israel.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a very important topic of our conversation with the Israelis as well, and the Palestinian Authority.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing the call.&nbsp; I just want to follow up on what you were just talking about regarding the Khashoggi ban.&nbsp; And I know you don&#8217;t want to go into any of the specific meetings, but can you just address the criticism that is already being made that engaging more directly with the Saudi leadership could inadvertently be interpreted as allowing them to sort of get off the hook for what happened and sort of reinforce some of the problematic tendencies around that event?&nbsp;<br><br>And how can the United States think about perhaps engaging with the Crown Prince while he&#8217;s still the Crown Prince &#8212; he’s not the leader of the country just yet &#8212; and without doing that?&nbsp; Anything just to sort of talk about that angle would be helpful.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so I think &#8212; look, the &#8212; as I think as we said before, the President is not going to change his views on human rights; he made that clear.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s also made clear that as President of the United States, it&#8217;s his job to “bring peace, if I can.”&nbsp; I think that was his direct quote.&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to try to do.<br><br>And he focuses our entire national security team on getting things done for the American people.&nbsp; And if he determines it&#8217;s in his interest to engage with any particular leader, and if such an engagement can deliver results, then he&#8217;ll do so.<br><br>I just would point again to our engagement over &#8212; you&nbsp;know, a lot of it is not above the surface until something actually happens, such as the truce in Yemen.&nbsp; I mean, the truce in Yemen is a clear example of where our engagement with the Saudis delivered results.&nbsp; And, obviously, we have more to do. Our Special Envoy, Tim Lenderking, is (inaudible) this every single day, together with Hans Grundberg, the UN Envoy.<br><br>But ending the Yemeni war was a priority for the President from the earliest days of the administration.&nbsp; And we explained, at the time of the Khashoggi ban, we issued the report that one reason we&#8217;re going to remain engaged with Saudi Arabia is because it is our priority to try to end this war.&nbsp; And I have to say the Saudi Crown Prince played a critical role in securing the extension of the truce &#8212; that was in place since April &#8212; just last week; Khalid bin Salman, who was in town last week, similarly.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I cannot speak to what happened in the Yemen war years ago. We&#8217;re focused on what&#8217;s happened on our watch.&nbsp; And this truce has brought about one of the most peaceful periods since the terrible war began seven years ago, saving thousands of lives, and it&#8217;s the type of example of how our engagement is important.<br><br>And I mentioned the 70,000 Americans who live and work in Saudi Arabia under threat from missiles and drones, not to mention the energy security piece, which, of course, is a pressing issue and, of course, will be a topic of engagement during the summit.<br><br>So I think, Missy, it&#8217;s a fair question, and I think &#8212; but if you just look at the breadth and the totality of interests we have with the countries that the President will be engaging on this very important visit to the Middle East, I think it speaks for itself why he believes very strongly and has given the charge to all of us to do all we can to work with these countries, to encourage them to work together cooperatively using unique American attributes and enablers wherever we can, including diplomatic enablers, to try to forge a more stable region.<br><br>And that takes a lot of work, and it takes presidential engagement. And I think his engagement here over four days in July, with about a dozen leaders, we think there&#8217;s significant opportunity not only to deliver some immediate results, but to really set the foundation for a more integrated, more cooperative, more stable region down the line.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think the President&#8217;s engagement is essential to that &#8212; and I would just finish from where I began &#8212; as you saw in&nbsp;the ASEAN Summit, and his trip to Asia and the Quad Summit and Summit of the Americas, and now the trip to the Middle East for a very important summit with about a dozen leaders from across the region.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; To everyone, as a reminder, this call was on background attributable to a senior administration official.&nbsp; The embargo will be lifted at 8:00 a.m. tomorrow.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s it.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp; Have a good night.<br><br>8:25 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre En Route Philadelphia,&#160;PA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/14/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-en-route-philadelphia-pa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 14:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 9:00 A.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  Hey, everybody.  Okay, so good morning.  Thanks for joining us to &#8212; sorry &#8212; thanks for joining us so bright and early.  I have one quick thing at the top. As you all know, today, at the &#8212; I’m going to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>9:00 A.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  Hey, everybody.  Okay, so good morning.  Thanks for joining us to &#8212; sorry &#8212; thanks for joining us so bright and early.  I have one quick thing at the top.</p>



<p>As you all know, today, at the &#8212; I’m going to put this down so you guys can hear me.&nbsp; Today, at the 29th AFL-CIO Convention in Philadelphia, the President will contrast his economic vision that works &#8212; that works out from Scranton &#8212; that looks out from Scranton, with one that looks down from Wall Street.</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s economic vision builds the economy from the middle out and the bottom up, not top down.&nbsp; The President will outline the strength of the economy, including historically low &#8212; low unemployment rates as a result of his American Rescue Plan and bipartisan infrastructure law.&nbsp; And he will say there is more work to do, and tackle &#8212; and tackling inflation is his top priority.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;ll lay out the stark choice: Ask the wealthy to pay their fair share, as he is proposing, or put Medicare, Social Security, and Medicaid on the chopping block every five years, which is what congressional Republicans are proposing.</p>



<p>As you all know, traveling with us today are Representative Brendan Boyle, Mary Gay Scanlon, and Donald Norcross.&nbsp; And greeting the President on the ground will be Philadelphia Mayor Jim Kenney.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; With that, Darlene, you want to kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, it doesn&#8217;t sound like there&#8217;s &#8212; from your topper, it doesn&#8217;t sound like there&#8217;s any news in the President&#8217;s speech today.&nbsp; Will there be any news in the remarks?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t want to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going &#8212; like I said, he&#8217;s going to make the stark contrast.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to talk about the work that he has been doing on behalf of the American people.</p>



<p>As we’ve said before, his priority as it relates to the economy is tackling inflation.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of him.&nbsp; I’ll let him &#8212; I’ll let him speak to what he&#8217;s going to be discussing today or in his remarks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In a statement earlier today announcing the trip to Saudi Arabia and Israel, the White House statement did not mention a meeting with MBS, whereas the Saudi statement did.&nbsp; Is there a reason the White House did not mention this?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, just for folks who are not aware, yes, a statement was put out &#8212; I put out a statement this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just for a little bit &#8212; to give you a little &#8212; folks a little bit of what the statement says.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to, clearly, read through the whole thing, but President Biden will visit the Middle East region from July 13th to 16th to reinforce the United States’ ironclad commitment to Israel&#8217;s security and prosperity and attend a Summit of the Gulf Cooperation Council plus Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan, known as the GCC+3.</p>



<p>He will also meet with counterparts from across the region to advance U.S. security, economic, and diplomatic interests.</p>



<p>The visit to the Middle East region culminates months of diplomacy and follows the President&#8217;s meeting with ASEAN leaders at the White House, his travel to the Republic of Korea and Japan, and the Quad Summit, his hosting of the Summit of the Americas last week in Los Angeles, and his visit next week to Europe for G7 and NATO.</p>



<p>But to your question, look, you know, the President is going to see over a dozen leaders on this trip, including King Salman and the leadership from our Saudi hosts for the GCC+3 Summit.&nbsp; Yes, we can expect the President to see the Crown Prince as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just a quick question on the S&amp;P yesterday slipping into bear market territory.&nbsp; I mean, there are growing fears of the economy heading into a recession.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering how concerned is the President about, sort of, growing fears of the U.S. economy slipping into a recession?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, we are closely watching.&nbsp; We know that families are concerned about inflation in the stock market.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that we are aware of.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we know that this is &#8212; what we&#8217;re seeing right now is &#8212; what we&#8217;re facing are global challenges: Putin’s price hike, inflation, coming out of a once-in-a-generation global pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The American people are well positioned, we believe, to face these challenges because of the &#8212; because of &#8212; because of what the President has done this past year and a half on dealing with the economy &#8212; a historic, economic &#8212; economic place that we’re in with more than 8 million jobs since President Biden took office.&nbsp; Seventeen states have historical &#8212; historically low unemployment.</p>



<p>So, all of these things matter.&nbsp; But, yes, we are watching it closely, and we understand what this &#8212; how this feels for the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he having &#8212; is he having meetings, perhaps, you know, to discuss sort of this &#8212; this &#8212; the growing forecasts that are coming out of &#8212; you know, from economists about the economy?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any meetings to read out for you at this time.&nbsp; Clearly, this President has made inflation a priority &#8212; an economic priority.&nbsp; <a></a><a>You&#8217;ve heard from him for the past several months on it.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll hear from him about it today.&nbsp; So this is something that is at top of mind.</a></p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The market drop has caused a tremendous loss of wealth.&nbsp; Is the President more concerned about the loss of wealth or the inflation?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we know that higher prices are having a real effect, again, on people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; And so that matters, and that is something that the President really is keen on.&nbsp; And we are incredibly focused on doing everything we can to making sure the economy is working for the American people.<br><br>You&#8217;ll hear him talk about that specifically today, as I read out in the topper.&nbsp; But, you know, the economic &#8212; again, his economic plan has led to the strongest job market in American history.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s &#8212; thanks to the American Rescue Plan, unemployment is at historic lows.<br><br>So, these are global challenges that we&#8217;re facing.&nbsp; We believe that we&#8217;re in a good place to fight inflation.&nbsp; We know what the American people are feeling.&nbsp; This is, again, an &#8212; a top economic priority for the President.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Saudi portion of the trips, I wanted to ask you about that, if I may.&nbsp; Is this a last-ditch effort, a Hail Mary attempt to lower oil and gas prices that we&#8217;re facing right now?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I mean, look, we&#8217;ve &#8212; I was asked this &#8212; a similar question yesterday &#8212;</p>



<p>(A nearby interior door opens.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Watch out behind you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.<br><br>So, look, while energy security is one important issue, it&#8217;s hardly the only one.&nbsp; Saudi Arabia is the chair of OPEC-Plus, as you all know, and it&#8217;s the largest exporter.&nbsp;<br><br>Of course, we discuss energy with Saudi &#8212; the Saudi government, and we welcome its &#8212; its leadership in achieving a consensus amongst the group of &#8212; to increase planned supply increases by 50 percent last week.<br><br>But, look, Saudi Arabia has been a strategic partner of the United States for nearly 80 years.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no question that important interests are interwoven with Saudi Arabia, notably the recent extension of truce in Yemen, which has saved countless of lives.<br><br>So, there is an array of agenda, a long list of things to talk &#8212; to &#8212; to have a conversation about that&#8217;s going to be on the agenda.<br><br>But as the President has said many times, he is &#8212; he looks forward to leader-leader conversation and &#8212; as it relates to having a strategic partnership.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, so when the President does see MBS on his trip, does he plan to address Khashoggi’s murder with him directly?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The President &#8212; as you know, human rights is always part of the conversation in our foreign &#8212; our foreign engagements.&nbsp; So that will always be the case.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t ma- &#8212; it does- &#8212; regardless of who he&#8217;s meeting with.<br><br>We are not &#8212; what we &#8212; I want to say: We&#8217;re not overlooking any conduct that happened before the President took office.&nbsp; We issued an extensive report on Khashoggi and issued a Kha- &#8212; the so-called Khashoggi Ban.<br><br>So it&#8217;s important to also emphasize that while we collab- &#8212; re-collaborate relationships, we are not looking to rupture relationships as well.<br><br>But human rights &#8212; you know, human rights issues, human rights conversation is something that the President brings up with many leaders and plans to do so.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, there was a report in Axios this morning that the President favors lifting tari- &#8212; Chinese &#8212; tariffs on China on consumer goods.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you can confirm if that&#8217;s true, but also talk about &#8212; I mean, he&#8217;s going to meet with unions today who have pretty steadfastly opposed lifting tariffs.&nbsp; Is he going to speak about tariffs and his decision-making process here with the members of the Union?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I’ll say this: We have said from the beginning some Trump tariffs were irresponsible and do not advance our economic or national security and instead raise costs for families and businesses.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve said many times that, you know, we&#8217;re discussing this and working to align these haphazard tariffs and our priorities to safeguard the interest of our workers and critical industries; boosting American workers, wages, and creating jobs; securing the resilience of our supply chains; sustaining our technology edge; and advancing our national security.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have anything to share about what &#8212; where the President &#8212; what the President&#8217;s decision has &#8212; is, at this time.&nbsp; As you know, this is something that we&#8217;re discussing internally.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick housekeeping note: We’ve had a couple incidences in gaggles, including under the wing today, where staff members have been touching camera equipment and microphones.&nbsp; So, I was just wondering if we can get a commitment for you to talk to people about how that can&#8217;t happen during that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I mean, absolutely.&nbsp; Look, we want to make sure that there&#8217;s transparency, that you are &#8212; you are &#8212; you all are able to hear the President, directly from the President.&nbsp; We know that&#8217;s important not just for you, but for us as well.<br><br>As the plane lands &#8212; I &#8212; I was not out &#8212; I was not outside when &#8212; to the &#8212; to what you&#8217;re discussing or bringing up right now.&nbsp; But we understand how important it is for all of you to hear directly from the President.&nbsp; So, thank you for letting us know.<br><br>All right, guys.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>9:10 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on President&#160;Biden’s Travel to Israel, the West Bank, and Saudi&#160;Arabia </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/statement-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-president-bidens-travel-to-israel-the-west-bank-and-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will visit&#160;the Middle East&#160;region from&#160;July 13-16&#160;to reinforce the United States’ iron-clad commitment to Israel’s security&#160;and prosperity and attend a Summit of the&#160;Gulf Cooperation Council plus Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan (known as the GCC+3). &#160;He will also meet with counterparts from across the region, to advance U.S. security, economic, and diplomatic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will visit&nbsp;the Middle East&nbsp;region from&nbsp;July 13-16&nbsp;to reinforce the United States’ iron-clad commitment to Israel’s security&nbsp;and prosperity and attend a Summit of the&nbsp;Gulf Cooperation Council plus Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan (known as the GCC+3). &nbsp;He will also meet with counterparts from across the region, to advance U.S. security, economic, and diplomatic interests.</p>



<p>The President will begin his travel in Israel, where he will meet with Israeli leaders to discuss Israel’s security, prosperity, and its increasing integration into the greater region. &nbsp;The President will also visit the West&nbsp;Bank to consult with the Palestinian Authority&nbsp;and to reiterate his strong support for a two-state solution,&nbsp;with&nbsp;equal measures of security, freedom, and opportunity for the Palestinian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President will then travel to Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, which is the current chair of the GCC and the venue for this gathering of nine leaders from across the region, at the invitation of&nbsp;King Salman&nbsp;bin&nbsp;Abdulaziz&nbsp;al-Saud.&nbsp;The President appreciates King Salman’s leadership and his invitation.&nbsp; He looks forward to this important visit to Saudi Arabia, which has been a strategic partner of the United States for nearly eight decades. &nbsp;</p>



<p>While in Saudi Arabia, the President will&nbsp;discuss&nbsp;a range of bilateral, regional, and global issues.&nbsp; These include support to the&nbsp;UN-mediated truce&nbsp;in Yemen,&nbsp;which has led to the most peaceful period there since war began seven years ago.&nbsp; He will also discuss means for expanding regional economic and security cooperation, including new and promising infrastructure and climate initiatives, as well as deterring threats from Iran, advancing human rights,&nbsp;and&nbsp;ensuring global energy and food security.&nbsp;&nbsp;The President looks forward to outlining his affirmative vision for U.S. engagement in the region over the coming months and years. &nbsp;</p>



<p>This visit to the Middle East region culminates months of diplomacy and follows the President’s meeting with ASEAN leaders at the White House, his travel to the Republic of Korea and Japan, the Quad Summit, his hosting of the Summit of the Americas last week in Los Angeles, and his visit next week to Europe for the G7 and NATO Summits.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Summit of the Americas Agriculture Producers&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/13/summit-of-americas-agriculture-producers-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 23:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55459</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Argentina, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and the United States affirm the important role that we as major agricultural and agricultural input exporters can play to strengthen global food security.&#160; At a time when nearly one in three people around the world does not have access to adequate, affordable, and nutritious food, supply disruptions further interrupt&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Argentina, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and the United States affirm the important role that we as major agricultural and agricultural input exporters can play to strengthen global food security.&nbsp; At a time when nearly one in three people around the world does not have access to adequate, affordable, and nutritious food, supply disruptions further interrupt trade in grain, corn, cooking oil, and key agricultural inputs such as seeds, fertilizer, and refined fuels.&nbsp; At the same time, climate change has intensified severe weather events and made them more frequent.&nbsp; The resulting change in precipitation patterns around the world threatens crop yields, making farming more challenging, especially as the world emerges from the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; High energy and fertilizer prices are an additional constraint, making agriculture more difficult to practice profitably and increasing world food prices for consumers, further exacerbating global food insecurity.</p>



<p>We, as major producers and exporters of food and other agricultural inputs affirm the need to take near-term actions with the goal of stabilizing food prices and sustainably maximizing agricultural yields. as well as building more resilient, safe, and sustainable global food systems for the future. We stand with the other over 80 countries that have endorsed the Roadmap for Global Food Security Call to Action released at the U.S.-chaired Global Food Security Ministerial Meeting held at the United Nations on May 18 and urge those countries that have not yet endorsed the Roadmap to do so.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>In order to meet these goals, the aforementioned countries affirm that they plan to:</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Promote best practices to boost crop yields, agricultural production, and trade:&nbsp; We intend to work with farmers around the world to take steps to improve sustainable crop yields and enhance sustainable agricultural production.&nbsp; All exporting countries benefit from the use of effective practices and approaches, including:&nbsp; the use of high-yield crops and resilient seeds; double-cropping; seasonal soil rotation; integrated management of pests and diseases; pesticide productivity; vertical farming; fertilizer innovations and efficiencies; better irrigation use and techniques to improve the water footprint; new and innovative practices and technologies to support sustainable agriculture; greater access to precision agriculture technology and innovative financial tools, such as agricultural credit and crop insurance to guaranteed affordable credit access; and innovative storage techniques to reduce post-harvest loss before crops are sold on the world markets. Over the long-term, we intend to increase efforts to support the transformation of unsustainable agriculture inputs and food systems to make them more sustainable, resilient to shocks, financially and socially inclusive, and accessible to large, medium and smallholder farmers without distinction, according to national capacities and priorities.&nbsp; Countries intend to strengthen both physical infrastructure and logistical supply chain supports, as well as build on existing innovations for food cultivation, storage, and distribution to increase access to affordable, nutritious, and healthy food.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Maximize food supplies and improve trade and transportation of food&nbsp;within world&nbsp;markets:&nbsp; A steady and predictable flow of diverse agricultural exports from major producing countries onto the global market can help maintain price stability, reduce shocks, and project calm over commodity markets.&nbsp; Conversely, panic about shortages and price spikes, hoarding and excessive stockpiling, and export bans can create a vicious cycle that contribute to global food insecurity.&nbsp; We intend to maintain or expand the fair and open trade of agricultural commodities, in line with existing domestic policies and international obligations and standards.&nbsp;&nbsp;We will work towards the objective of substantial progressive reductions in support, resulting in fundamental reform.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Calibrate sanctions, where applicable, and work to avoid other restrictions, like export bans, to limit the impact on trade in agricultural commodities and avoid disrupting markets.&nbsp; We intend to ensure that our countries’ domestic sanctions regimes do not inappropriately target food and to take all appropriate actions to avoid export bans and other economic restrictions that could unduly interfere with the free flow of agricultural commodities around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Provide humanitarian assistance to the most vulnerable:&nbsp; Countries within available resources intend to make new, additive financial or in-kind donations to key humanitarian organizations providing immediate life-saving humanitarian assistance, including cash, food and nutrition supplies, health and nutrition programming, water and sanitation, and humanitarian protection to the most vulnerable populations &#8211; whether inside or outside of their borders &#8211; to prevent malnutrition or famine.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Support increased access to fertilizers and their inputs (synthetic and organic based), including through production inside countries, as a part of their efforts toward food security.&nbsp; Subject to available resources, we intend to increase fertilizer production including with a focus on the development of climate-smart and versatile alternatives, coupled with integrated soil management and fertilizer efficiency techniques, such as 4R fertilizer management, to prevent shortages.&nbsp; Use of these soil management techniques combined with alternative fertilizer choices is critical to optimize global supplies of fertilizer and reduce single-source fertilizer producer dependency, increasing competition among fertilizer producers will also help stabilize production costs in supply chains and increase crop yields to vulnerable food markets.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Optimize use of fertilizers, enhancing sustainability of water resources and biodiversity:&nbsp; We intend to promote innovative techniques, such as precision agriculture, that enable farmers to optimize the balance between fertilizer and water use per ton of food produced through crop, season, and alternative techniques.&nbsp; We also intend to promote the use of high-value and -yield crops and seeds to maximize renewable energy sources from non-food crops, feedstocks, formulations, uses, and crop data to better manage agricultural risks and shortages in advance of critical planting seasons, reduce soil erosion, and enhance sustainable biodiversity.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Food insecurity is a rising global problem that does not respect international borders.&nbsp; It is also historically associated with poverty and social, economic, and political instability.&nbsp; As countries that serve as major food exporters and homes to farmers that feed the world, it is both in our interest and a core part of our values to take these steps to prevent hunger, malnutrition, and poverty around the world, as well as to make investments in more resilient and inclusive global agriculture and food systems, that support rural development and contribute to peace in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Congressional Passage of Ocean Shipping Reform&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/13/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-congressional-passage-of-ocean-shipping-reform-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 23:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lowering prices for Americans is my top priority, and I applaud the Congress for passing the Ocean Shipping Reform Act on a bipartisan basis, which will help lower costs for American retailers, farmers and consumers. I want to thank Senator Klobuchar, Senator Thune, &#160;Rep. Garamendi, and Rep. Dusty Johnson for their leadership and helping drive&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Lowering prices for Americans is my top priority, and I applaud the Congress for passing the Ocean Shipping Reform Act on a bipartisan basis, which will help lower costs for American retailers, farmers and consumers. I want to thank Senator Klobuchar, Senator Thune, &nbsp;Rep. Garamendi, and Rep. Dusty Johnson for their leadership and helping drive forward this important legislation.</p>



<p>In my State of the Union address, I called on Congress to address ocean carriers’ high prices and unfair practices because rising ocean shipping costs are a major contributing factor to increased costs for American families. During the pandemic, ocean carriers increased their prices by as much as 1,000%. And, too often, these ocean carriers are refusing to take American exports back to Asia, leaving with empty containers instead. That’s costing farmers and ranchers—and our economy—a lot of money.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This bill will make progress reducing costs for families and ensuring fair treatment for American businesses—including farmers and ranchers. I look forward to signing it into law.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, June&#160;13, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/13/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:42 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hey, good afternoon, everyone. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Hello. MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hello, hello.&#160; You guys will be very excited: I do not have anything at the top for all of you.&#160; So we’re going to go straight to questions. Darlene, want to kick us off? Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Thanks.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:42 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hey, good afternoon, everyone.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hello, hello.&nbsp; You guys will be very excited: I do not have anything at the top for all of you.&nbsp; So we’re going to go straight to questions.</p>



<p>Darlene, want to kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Yep, I would.&nbsp; On the gun framework that was announced over the weekend, can you talk a little bit about what specifics the White House would like to see as the lawmakers sit down and try to turn this into a bill?&nbsp; Specifics on what you want regarding access to juvenile records, red-flag laws, and redefining which gun sellers now have to do expanded background checks.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, the text is now going to be written, so we&#8217;re going to allow the negotiators to go through that process.</p>



<p>What &#8212; what we do believe and what the President has said is this is a historic agreement, and it&#8217;s the most significant legislation that we have seen to reduce gun violence since more than 20 years.&nbsp; And so it&#8217;s a bipartisan.&nbsp; The President is pleased to see this as a step forward.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we know, you know, this is about saving lives.&nbsp; And so the President is going to &#8212; wants to see Congress act.&nbsp; He wants to see this on his desk as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And &#8212; and that&#8217;s &#8212; and that&#8217;s going to be our focus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As it &#8212; as it relates to his involvement in any of this, his team continues to talk to Congress on a regular basis, as we have been, as they have been this past several weeks.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue talking to negotiators on the Hill, to congressional members and staff on the Hill.&nbsp; And &#8212; and we will continue to have those conversation.&nbsp; But we want to &#8212; the President wants to see this on his desk to sign as soon as possible.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the White House weigh in at all in terms of the final legislative language and text and specific things that you would like &#8212; you, the White House, would like to see?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any specifics on &#8212; on any &#8212; any, you know, pieces of the legislation and our involvement there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we will say is we want to see this move quickly.&nbsp; The President wants to see this move quickly.&nbsp; This is about saving lives.&nbsp; And we think &#8212; again, this is a step &#8212; a step forward in getting that done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, legislating is &#8212; when you think about legislating, it&#8217;s about negotiating.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about getting to a place where both sides can come to an agreement.&nbsp; And this is a bipartisan handshake, a framework, as you all know.&nbsp; And we want to &#8212; we&#8217;re pleased by that, and we want to get that done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other question.&nbsp; Over the weekend, before the President left Los Angeles, he was asked whether he had decided to go to Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; And his answer was, “No, not yet.”&nbsp; And there was a follow-up question, and then he said, “That&#8217;s the reason I&#8217;m going.”&nbsp; So, can you settle it?&nbsp; Is he going?&nbsp; Is he not going?&nbsp; Just tell us.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t have anything to announce for you today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When will you?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me just say this: When the President is ready to make that announcement, that&#8217;s when we will.</p>



<p>But we continue to plan for a trip to Israel and Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; This would be an opportunity for the President to engage with leaders from across the Middle East region.&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t have anything to announce for you today.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, if you think about the focus &#8212; what the focus would be, and the agenda, it’s on delivering results for the American people.&nbsp; That is what the President &#8212; when he has these leader-leader conversation, that is the number one priority: those strategic partnership with those leaders and making sure that it indeed delivers for the American people.</p>



<p>And so, in this &#8212; in this particular case, if this were to happen or when we are ready to announce, if and when we are ready to announce, it’s &#8212; it’s &#8212; would be about &#8212; about diplomacy &#8212; leading through diplomacy to bring stability to the Middle East region, which he has talked about himself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but again, I don&#8217;t have anything to &#8212; any further &#8212; anything further to preview at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Last week, you said that when the President met with the parents in Uvalde, they told him they just wanted to see some action, that they wanted to see if Congress can, quote, “put their politics aside and come in a bipartisan way and deliver something.”&nbsp; Does this agreement that was announced yesterday deliver on what those parents in Uvalde were telling the President that they wanted to see?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me just make clear: What he heard and all of you may have heard from the folks in the community as well is to do something.&nbsp; And so the President has called on Congress to do something.&nbsp; They are doing something.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, does this framework has everything that the President wants or that everything that the President has called for?&nbsp; It does not.&nbsp; And the President is going to continue to fight for &#8212; for &#8212; for the renew our ban on assault weapons; for, you know, making sure that we confirm Steve Dettelbach to lead ATF &#8212; right? &#8212; which is something that we &#8212; we believe is going to happen.&nbsp; And so &#8212; expanding background checks to keep guns out of the hands of criminals.</p>



<p>So there are things that he wants to continue to see done.</p>



<p>But &#8212; but, you know, again, this is about saving lives, and this is what&#8217;s important right now.&nbsp; And this is a step towards that direction.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said &#8212; you said repeatedly now for several weeks that the President was going to give lawmakers time and space.&nbsp; And in the statement, he said yesterday, as you just said, that it didn&#8217;t do everything that he thinks is needed.&nbsp; If he had gotten involved, is there something now, where we are at this point in the conversation and negotiations &#8212; if he had gotten off the sidelines, is there one thing that could have ended up in the agreement that he would have liked to have seen?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I disagree with the framing of that question.&nbsp; The President has been involved.&nbsp; He has been involved since, I would say, day one of his administration &#8212; the first couple of days that he&#8217;s walked into his administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what I mean by that is the executive actions that he took very early on and &#8212; the most executive actions than any president at this time of his presidency, when it comes to dealing with a public health epidemic, which is gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so he put that forward.&nbsp; He did everything at the time that he can from his perch in making sure that we &#8212; we deal with this epidemic.&nbsp; He has said if there&#8217;s anything more he can do on the executive action side, he will take a look, his team will take a look.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;s talked about it &#8212; most recently State of the Union and also the first joint address.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So he has been vocal.&nbsp; He has been talking about this.&nbsp; And he also did a primetime &#8212; a primetime delivery to the American people that, as you all know, that was about almost two weeks ago.&nbsp; So he has been involved, and to say that he is not &#8212; he hasn&#8217;t been is just not true.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I meant in the negotiations.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I meant in the negotiations with this bipartisan group.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But &#8212; no, but I’m &#8212; but more broadly, he has been involved.&nbsp; And he had Chris Murphy here just last week to &#8212; to get a &#8212; to get a download on the negotiations from him directly.&nbsp; And I think that shows involvement, and that shows him wanting to make sure that we push this forward.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; On Saudi Arabia briefly, just to circle back on Darlene’s question: The President seemed to say over the weekend that his trip would not focus on energy.&nbsp; You said just now that any trip to the region will focus on delivering results for the American people.&nbsp; If that&#8217;s the case, why not make energy a major topic of the of the trip, considering gas prices are such a big part of what Americans care about?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me &#8212; let me first say: There &#8212; there&#8217;s no trip to announce at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he’s been talking about (inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying that there&#8217;s nothing to preview for you at this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I will say this: You know, to view engagement with Saudi Arabia and energy security as asking for oil is simply wrong and a misunderstanding of both the complexity of that issue and our multifaceted discussions with the Saudis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That said, Saudi Arabia is the chair, as you know, of OPEC Plus and its largest exporter.&nbsp; Of course, we discuss energy with the Saudi government, as we do with oil producers around the world.&nbsp; And we welcome its leadership in achieving a consensus amongst the group members last week.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just briefly on Afghanistan, if you could: Nearly half of Afghan &#8212; Afghans are starving or don&#8217;t have enough food.&nbsp; Is the administration considering doing more to send direct aid to Afghanistan, not just the United Nations, even if that means recognizing the Taliban?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I don&#8217;t have anything further on what else we might be doing, as ai- &#8212; for aids &#8212; as aid to the people of Afghanistan.  As you know, we have announced humanitarian aid that go directly to the people and not to &#8212; not to the government.  But I don&#8217;t have anything further to share on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you sort of in a rock-and-a-hard-place position here?&nbsp; If the President were to go to Saudi Arabia, would you not see a benefit in embracing the idea that with gas prices at record levels, of course you would speak to the Kingdom and its role in OPEC Plus in trying to increase supply?&nbsp; So why not embrace that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because if you&#8217;re going to go to Saudi Arabia, wouldn&#8217;t that be a benefit for the President to try to deliver on that, even though there are some political downsides to doing that domestically as well?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think what we&#8217;re trying to say is that there are more complexities to that issue, and it&#8217;s multifaceted &#8212; discussions with Saudi Arabia.&nbsp;&nbsp; And it is an array of agenda &#8212; of agenda that we would &#8212; we would potentially be talking about.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I want to be careful because we don&#8217;t have &#8212; I don&#8217;t have &#8212; we don&#8217;t have a trip to preview for you at this time.&nbsp; But I also &#8212; you know, as I said, Saudi Arabia is the chair of OPEC and is the largest exporter.&nbsp; So we talk to them like we do with any other oil producers around the world.&nbsp; So that is &#8212; there&#8217;s no difference there.&nbsp; But &#8212; but again, I don&#8217;t want to go into &#8212; go into specifics.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on the surface, understanding no trip has been announced yet &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; we’ll get there when we get there &#8212; but the idea that the President would engage with Saudi and not talk about oil production and gas prices when Americans are at the highest level they&#8217;ve been in a long time just doesn&#8217;t make sense to me.&nbsp; It would seem the White House would embrace that as one of the many complex issues you would deal with with Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve all been covering Saudi Arabia&#8217;s relationship, which has been fraught on many levels with the United States for a long time, so we know there are many issues.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you&#8217;re not avoiding saying he&#8217;s going to be dealing with &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, what I &#8212; what I did say is: Of course, he will be &#8212; they will discuss energy with the Saudi government.&nbsp; I think what I&#8217;m trying to say is to look at this trip as it being only about oil is not &#8212; it would be simply wrong to do that.&nbsp; So we just wanted to be very clear on that &#8212; on that regard.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; President Biden once bragged about the stock market hitting “record after record after record on my watch.”&nbsp; How about now?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Meaning the stock market &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All the gains from President Biden&#8217;s time in office have been wiped out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, we are watching &#8212; we&#8217;re watching closely.&nbsp; We know families are concerned about inflation and the stock market.&nbsp; That is something that the President is &#8212; is really aware of.&nbsp; And so, look, we face global challenges.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked about this.&nbsp; This is &#8212; we&#8217;re not the only country dealing with what we&#8217;re seeing at the moment as it relates to inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, Putin &#8212; Putin&#8217;s price hike, inflation, coming &#8212; coming out of a once-in-a-generation global pandemic &#8212; all of those things play a factor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know &#8212; but the thing &#8212; the way that we see this is that the American people are well positioned to face these challenges because of the economic historic gains that we have made under this President &#8212; under this President in the last 16 months.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, as you say that Americans are well positioned to weather this stock market decline, what is the President&#8217;s message to somebody who might want to retire but their 401(k) is getting wiped out?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we know &#8212; we know that the &#8212; that high prices are having a real effect on people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; We get that.&nbsp; And we are incredibly focused on doing everything that we can to make sure that the economy is working for every &#8212; American people.&nbsp; But we are coming out of the strongest job market in American history, and that matters.&nbsp; And that &#8212; a lot of that is thanks to the American Rescue Plan, which only Democrats voted for that &#8212; Republicans did not &#8212; and it led to this economic boom &#8212; this historic economic boom that we&#8217;re seeing with jobs.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Didn’t it also lead to historic inflation?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; That is not &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That is &#8212; that is &#8212; that is not &#8212; that is not how we&#8217;re seeing the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, the President came in &#8212; we have to remember what the President walked into.&nbsp; When he walked into this administration, the economy was at a standstill. &nbsp;Schools were closed. Businesses were shutting down.&nbsp; Twenty million people were on unemployment insurance benefits.&nbsp; That is what he walked into.&nbsp; And he took action.&nbsp; He got the American Rescue Plan done.&nbsp; Democrats &#8212; only Democrats voted for it.&nbsp; And it helped turn the economy around, including getting more than 200 million people vaccinated, having a comprehensive vaccination plan that &#8212; that was not in place when he walked into the administration.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, quickly, is the President running for reelection?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; He has &#8212; first of all, let&#8217;s &#8212; let&#8217;s reset for a second.&nbsp; I cannot talk about elections.&nbsp; I cannot be a political analyst from here or &#8212; you know, or the midterms or anything like that, or including 2024.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President, as you know, has been asked that question many times, and he has answered it.&nbsp; His answer has been pretty simple, which is: Yes, he&#8217;s running for reelection.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I can&#8217;t say more than that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, thank you.&nbsp; Back on the discussions about the gun framework.&nbsp; You said he spoke with Senator Murphy.&nbsp; You say negotiators continue to talk to people here at the White House.&nbsp; Has the President himself spoken with any of the Republicans engaged in the negotiations?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I hear the question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; any calls to preview or read out to you at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he &#8212; I know he was flying this morning during the latest January 6th hearing.&nbsp; But has he had a chance to go back and watch any of it, or is somebody keeping him updated on developments?&nbsp;&nbsp; What does he make of it all?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So as you know, the President is very busy today, and so he won&#8217;t be catching it blow by blow but he&#8217;ll get updates from &#8212; from his staff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know who’s been giving him the updates?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a person to &#8212; to share with who&#8217;s been giving his up- &#8212; an update.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has he been briefed on the arrests of the 31 men found inside a U-Haul truck near a Pride event in Idaho on Saturday?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, he&#8217;s been &#8212; yes, he&#8217;s been briefed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; We’ll move on then.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Karine.&nbsp; I wanted to switch gears to Brexit for a moment.&nbsp; Britain, I guess, vo- &#8212; Boris Johnson&#8217;s party published today plans to override some of the post-Brexit trade rules for Northern Ireland.&nbsp; I know Blinken told Foreign Secretary Truss that &#8212; to continue good-faith negotiations with the EU to resolve &#8212; reach a solution that preserves the Belfast/Good Friday Agreement.&nbsp; But I know that Boris Johnson characterized the changes as “relatively trivial,” and I wanted to know if the White House agreed with that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the U.S. priority remains protecting the gains of the Belfast/Good Friday Agreement and preserving peace, stability, and prosperity for the people of Northern Ireland.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have welcomed the provisions in the EU-UK Trade and Cooperation Agreement and the Northern Ireland Protocol as a way to manage the practical challenges of preserving distinct EU and UK markets while preventing the return of customs infrastructure on the land border.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We recognize there have been challenges over the implementation of the Northern Ireland Protocol.&nbsp; We urge the UK and the EU to return to talks to resolve these differences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We support a strong and close EU-UK partnership.&nbsp; Transatlantic peace, security, and prosperity are best served by a strong UK, a strong EU, and the closest possible relationship between the two.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And if I could just follow up quickly. Will this become an impediment to the U.S.-UK trade dialogue talks in Boston or a potential future U.S.-UK trade deal?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I don&#8217;t believe it will be.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just back on the Saudi issue for a second.&nbsp; Does President Biden believe that Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman was responsible for Kamal &#8212; Jamal Khashoggi’s death?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;ve spoken to this before.&nbsp; I think he was asked this question directly recently last week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, look, the President is focused on getting things done for the American people; that is engagement, leader and le- &#8212; leader-to-leader engagement around the world.&nbsp; He takes that very seriously.&nbsp; And he takes delivering for the American people very seriously.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>If he determines that the interests of the United States to engage with a foreign leader and that such an engagement can deliver results, then he&#8217;ll do so.&nbsp; And so, as we &#8212; as you have heard her say &#8212; as you have heard us say, Saudi Arabia has been a partner to the United States for more than 80 years &#8212; an important partner on a host of initiatives that we are working on, both in the region and around the world.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the question that I asked though, does he believe that MBS was responsible for Khashoggi’s death?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we issued &#8212; when the President &#8212; when the President walked &#8212; came into office, you know, the murder of Jamal Khashoggi was something that we and so many others around the world took very, very seriously.&nbsp; He &#8212; he issued an extensive report on Khashoggi’s murder.&nbsp; And we instituted the so-called “Khashoggi ban” to make sure that any country that seeks to use tools of repression against people abroad who criticize their government will pay a price.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve used it multiple &#8212; multiple times since.&nbsp; And we imposed sanctions or visa restrictions on over 70 Saudi individuals and entities, including the Saudi Royal Guard’s Rapid Intervention Force.</p>



<p>As we emphasized then, it was also important to reorient but not rapture [rupture] relations with Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; So we took that incredibly seriously, and the po- &#8212; the President spoken to this before, and I&#8217;m going to just let his word stand.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he believe &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I&#8217;m &#8212; I’ve already answered the question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, regarding all the trapped agriculture exports in Ukraine, there&#8217;s been some reporting that there was a cable sent from the Biden administration kind of warning African nations to not buy grain from Russia under the pretenses that it may be stolen from Ukraine.&nbsp; Is the White House warning African nations like Senegal to not buy any grain from Russia right now?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I can&#8217;t speak to the wire that you&#8217;re speaking of right now.&nbsp; But what I can say is: We are working with other countries to prevent the sale of grain that has likely been stolen from &#8212; from Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would there be any consequences for nations if they do buy grain from Russia at this time (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a hypothetical that I&#8217;m just not going to answer from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I have one more question?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Recently, the family of Emad Sharghi told CBS &#8212; he&#8217;s an American Iranian citizen who was detained in Iran four years ago.&nbsp; His family told our colleague, Margaret Brennan, that they&#8217;ve requested a meeting with the President numerous times but has not received a response from the White House.&nbsp; Their latest request was a couple of weeks ago.&nbsp; They also haven’t received requests from the State Department.&nbsp; Is there any update on when this meeting may take place?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update for you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check with the team.&nbsp; That is also a question for State Department, as they handle those types of engagements, situations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, the President is committed to bringing home U.S. nationals that are being held abroad.&nbsp; And that is a commitment that he has made to the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President think the Fed is running the risk of hiking rates too quickly as it tries to tame inflation?&nbsp; There are some reports suggesting that there&#8217;s going to be a larger rate hike than we expected on Wednesday.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The President believes &#8212; as you heard from him directly multiple times and even in his op-ed most recently &#8212; that the Federal Reserve is &#8212; needs to have their independence.&nbsp; And he leaves &#8212; he wants to give them their space to make their own decision &#8212; monetary decision on how to deal with inflation.&nbsp; They have made that &#8212; the Fed has made that a priority.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, that is what the President believes, and I&#8217;ll leave it as that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more follow-up question.&nbsp; The U.S. Ambassador to Beijing, Nick Burns, said over the weekend that the U.S.-China relationship is at its lowest moment since 1972, given the aggressive comments by China&#8217;s Defense Minister on Taiwan.&nbsp; Is the &#8212; does the President have any plans to speak with President Xi Jinping?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me just say this, since you asked a question about &#8212; about China: The National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, met today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission in Luxembourg.&nbsp; The meeting was about four and a half hours long.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This meeting, which followed their May [March] 18th phone call, included candid, substantive, and productive discussion of a number of regional and global security issues, as well as key issues in U.S.-China relations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sullivan understood the importance of maintaining open lines of communication to manage competition between our two countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To your question on a POTUS &#8212; POTUS-Xi meeting, Nancy: Interactions are planned at a range of officials across the U.S. government, but nothing to announce on a POTUS-Xi meeting at this time.</p>



<p>As you know, they last talked on the phone, as I just mentioned, on March 18th.&nbsp; We will continue to maintain open lines of communication with China.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q    But what about even just a phone call?  Not even &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, just building on Nancy, does the President want to talk to Xi Jinping by the end of the year?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to preview.&nbsp; As you know, and I said this moments ago, leader-to-leader conversations and communication is important to the President as we deal with, you know, important issues across &#8212; across the globe.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything for you right now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Roe vs. Wade: When the President was in California, he spoke to Jimmy Kimmel, and he said that there were some executive orders under consideration if Roe v. Wade was overturned.&nbsp; Can you share a little bit about what is being considered?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this time.&nbsp; Yes, I remember &#8212; I was there.&nbsp; I remember the President saying that.&nbsp; We just don&#8217;t have anything to share at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there any, like, specific areas where the administration feels that they &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, the team &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; have had some space?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The team is looking into it; we just don&#8217;t have anything for you at this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more.&nbsp; At the Summit of the Americas, the Argentine President, Alberto Fernández, he &#8212; he invited Biden to speak at the next Plenary of CELAC, where he&#8217;s the pro tem president.&nbsp; Is that an invitation that the President is considering?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have anything to &#8212; to preview or announce at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, I had a question about China and tariffs.&nbsp; With inflation still an issue, there has been some pressure on President Biden to lift some of the tariffs on China, but it&#8217;s also meeting some resistance from union members.&nbsp; As he heads tomorrow to the AFL-CIO, what does he want to see done as it relates to China and tariffs?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, the President has asked his team to look at that particular issue.&nbsp; He will make a decision on that; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of it.&nbsp; So that is going to be for the President to &#8212; to speak to when he&#8217;s &#8212; when he&#8217;s ready.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the timeframe on that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a timeframe.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to follow up on MBS: I heard you mention the report, but does the President believe that MBS is responsible for Khashoggi’s death?&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t hear you, sort of, engage with that part of the question.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, the President has talked about that.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been asked about words that &#8212; comments that he&#8217;s made during the campaign.&nbsp; He &#8212; he stands by those comments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I&#8217;m trying to say is that &#8212; you know, the President said this last week: He&#8217;s not going to change his view on human rights, and he&#8217;ll &#8212; let me quote him right now: “But as President of the United States, my job is to bring peace if I can, and that&#8217;s what I&#8217;m going to try to do.”&nbsp; And that&#8217;s how he answered the question when he was &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know, but that’s a generalized statement.&nbsp; I mean, this is a very specific question about what he believes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, we put &#8212; we put measures in place &#8212; we put out a report last year on that particular &#8212; the serious nature of what happened, and we take that very, very seriously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has spoken to it himself.&nbsp; And, you know, I&#8217;m going to leave his words &#8212; as he has said himself, leave his words stand.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; I want to follow up first on the Chinese goods and tariffs question.&nbsp; How quickly does the White House anticipate it would take for Americans to feel the effects on the price of goods if it lifts tariffs on some of these products?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, the President hasn&#8217;t made a decision on that.&nbsp; So I &#8212; that&#8217;s a hypothetical that I actually can’t &#8212; can&#8217;t answer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House feel that it would have a significant effect on inflation?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I mean, that is a decision that is going to be put together and &#8212; by his team.&nbsp; And the President is going to make a decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; that&#8217;s a hypothetical I literally cannot answer.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one last thing.&nbsp; On the January 6th hearings, based on the evidence that lawmakers have presented so far, does the President believe that Attorney General Merrick Garland should prosecute former President Donald Trump?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, the President has said this before in voicing his support for the vital work of the bipartisan January 6th Select Committee.&nbsp; And as Kevin McCarthy said just days after the attack, “We cannot sweep this under the rug.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>We agree all Americans should watch and remember the horrors of one of the darkest days in our history.&nbsp; But this is up to the Department of Justice.&nbsp; This is the Department of Justice.&nbsp; And the President has been very clear.&nbsp; The Department of Justice is inde- &#8212; is independent.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President chose Attorney General Garland because of his loyalty to the law and our Constitution, and to restore the independence and integrity of the Justice Department.&nbsp; And this &#8212; that&#8217;s exactly what the Attorney General is doing.&nbsp; So we leave it up to the Department of Justice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President spoken to Senator Schumer since the agreement on guns was reached?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a call to read out for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the arrests in Idaho over the weekend, what was the President&#8217;s reaction when he was briefed?&nbsp; And what, if anything, has the administration done in response?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s still under investigation.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to that from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’ll go to some people I haven&#8217;t gone to.&nbsp; No one up here.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; A question on gas prices.&nbsp; They hit the &#8212; an average of over $5.00 this weekend.&nbsp; So I was wondering: Is the administration reconsidering the idea of a federal gas tax holiday?&nbsp; And what other things are you guys thinking about are on the table?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, don&#8217;t have anything new for you.&nbsp; We don’t have anything new for you to announce on gas prices or the gas tax.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as you know, gas prices are up nearly $2.00.&nbsp; And that has been the case &#8212; per gallon.&nbsp; That has been the case since Putin started to threaten the borders of Ukraine with &#8212; with the troop enforcement at the border.</p>



<p>The U.S. is on track to produce a record amount of oil next year.&nbsp; We&#8217;re releasing a record 1 million barrels of oil per day from the Stra- &#8212; Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; That has been for six months.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve rallied our partners to join us, releasing an additional 240 million barrels of oil.&nbsp; And that has been because of the President&#8217;s &#8212; President&#8217;s leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also expanded access to E-15, which will lower prices for thousands &#8212; thousands of gasoline stations, including people, families in the Middle East.&nbsp; So that was an important move.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I mentioned before, we welcomed the production increase announced by OPEC Plus to increase global supply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if the President had not taken these actions, we would not have been able to blunt the &#8212; to blunt what we&#8217;re seeing now &#8212; the prices.&nbsp; It would have been even worse.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; but as far as anything new to share, we don&#8217;t have anything new to share on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me ask you: The President expressed some real frustration with Exxon last week.&nbsp; Is he reaching out to these CEOs?&nbsp; Is there talk about having a meeting with them?&nbsp; Is there anything like that on the table?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, in just the first three months of this year &#8212; just to give you a little bit of why the President made those comments last week &#8212; Exxon made $8.8 billion in profits.&nbsp; That&#8217;s triple what they made during the same year &#8212; the same time last year and the most they&#8217;ve made in nearly a decade.</p>



<p>Those record profits aren&#8217;t because they produce more oil.&nbsp; In fact, Exxon produced less oil this quarter than any quarter this &#8212; since 1999.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Oil companies making their largest profits in years have a choice: to put money into producing and refining oil or to put in &#8212; to put it into the pockets of wealthy sha- &#8212; stakehol- &#8212; shareholders while American families suffer at the pump.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Exxon made that choice.&nbsp; They made the choice.&nbsp; This quarter, Exxon announced that it is tripling its buybacks to $30 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, look, we&#8217;re on track, as I just mentioned, to &#8212; to reach record levels of production next year.&nbsp; But oil companies also need to do their part as well.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the President was &#8212; was very, very clear about what he said last week.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; A couple of questions, please.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So as the Ukraine war drags on and the food cris- &#8212; the resulting food crisis is clearly not going away &#8212; it’s only just getting worse &#8212; there seems to be pressure growing in Europe from some of the U.S. allies to get Ukraine to a point where they&#8217;re going to make some kind of deal with the Russians, or at least some sort of ceasefire &#8212; anything &#8212; primarily for the food situation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So ahead of the President&#8217;s trip to Europe this month, would you say his emphasis remains on helping Ukraine fight, or is it starting to shift into a place where the U.S. is going to be asking Ukraine to find a way to stop it?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I mean, the President has been very clear: Nothing about Ukraine without Ukraine.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; That &#8212; I mean, he&#8217;s been very clear about that.&nbsp; He wrote an op-ed in the New York Times, saying &#8212; reiterating those comments.</p>



<p>We are going to continue to assist Ukraine in helping to defend their democracy.&nbsp; Again, you know, we&#8217;ve said this many times is &#8212; this is Putin&#8217;s war.&nbsp; This is Putin&#8217;s aggression &#8212; unprovoked aggression onto another country’s sovereignty.&nbsp; This is Putin&#8217;s war to end and not Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ukraine needs to defend its country, and they have done that in &#8212; in an incredibly impressive of way.&nbsp; And, you know, we hoped that it would end with negotiations.&nbsp; But right now, we don&#8217;t see that coming from the Kremlin.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we want to make sure we put Ukraine in the strongest possible place so that if that time comes, they can do that.</p>



<p>When it comes to grain exports and what you&#8217;re asking me about food insecurity, this is a priority for the President.&nbsp; He&#8217;s spoken to this.&nbsp; You know, again, Russia has been repeatedly damaging grain storage facilities in Ukraine, stealing Ukrainian grain, and actively blocking the export of food from Ukrainian ports, increasing world hunger.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russia could immediately cease its war in Ukraine, which is devastating global food security, and allow the free flow of Ukrainian food and agricultural exports.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick domestic one, please.&nbsp; Most presidents, I&#8217;m guessing, would say they don&#8217;t pay attention to the polls.&nbsp; But does President Biden feel any concern that his approval rating is, really, pretty amazingly low and consistently low?&nbsp; I believe today it went under &#8212; the average went under 40 percent for the first time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The President is focused on delivering for the American people.&nbsp; That&#8217;s his focus right now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, thank you.&nbsp; Inflation has been above 5 percent for an entire year now.&nbsp; Why did the President wait until almost December to decide who would be leading the Federal Reserve?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The President has taken &#8212; taken the economy as a whole and inflation very seriously, especially these past several months, in making sure that he does everything he can when it comes to &#8212; as we know, inflation is &#8212; is increasing &#8212; is increasing costs in two important areas for the American people: food and gas.&nbsp; I have listed out the things that the President has done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, that &#8212; you know, that hasn&#8217;t changed.&nbsp; It has been a priority.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we see the economy in a &#8212; in a strong &#8212; stronger place than it&#8217;s been &#8212; a historic place than it&#8217;s been in decades.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the President is going to continue to do that &#8212; to do that work.&nbsp; We do have a Federal Reserve &#8212; you know, the Chair and others in place.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to leave that and make sure that they&#8217;re independent, leave the work to them.&nbsp; They have the strongest tools in dealing with inflation.&nbsp; They have made this a priority.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to leave it to them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The experts now suggest that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to move on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank &#8212;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Over the weekend, a crisis pregnancy center in Oregon was firebombed.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the fourth one so far.&nbsp; And then, last weekend, of course, a would-be- assassin was arrested outside the home of Justice Kavanaugh.&nbsp; I know that the administration condemns violence and you&#8217;ve said as much several times previously, but I&#8217;m wondering: Is there anything that the President is doing to cool passions before the Dobbs decision drops?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You mean in &#8212; with &#8212; as it relates to abor- &#8212; the decision?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I want it to be really clear: You know, the Department of Justice, as it relates to Kavanaugh, has U.S. Marshals providing support to the Supreme Court Marshal.&nbsp; And the President supports legislation to fund increased security for court and judges.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it is how &#8212; it has now been reported that the marshals our administration assigned to help protect judges were instrumental in the person not accomplishing the horrible deed that he set out to do.&nbsp; This is the threat that we saw against Kavanaugh.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we have taken this very seriously.&nbsp; Like you said, we have condemned &#8212; condemned it.&nbsp; The President has, and we will continue to do so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Any int- &#8212; intimidation or threats against judges is something that we take very seriously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, one of the reasons &#8212; again, one of the reasons the &#8212; the act did not happen last week was because the Department of &#8212; DOJ took that very seriously from the beginning when we were &#8212; when we were hearing the threats and the intimidation and put U.S. Marshals there.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, with regard to some of the arson that we&#8217;ve been seeing around the country?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s something, clearly, the DOJ is looking into.&nbsp; And, you know, they&#8217;ve taken that very seriously.&nbsp; We have seen an uptick of that type of arson and bombing and &#8212; or attempt to bomb, as we saw just recently over the weekend.&nbsp; And so, again, that&#8217;s for &#8212; DOJ is taking that very seriously, and they&#8217;re going to continue to do so.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one quick follow-up.</p>



<p>(An aide sneezes.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Bless you, Chris.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen was asked about some of these protests that were occurring outside of Supreme Court justices’ home &#8212; homes, and she reiterated that the administration wants them to remain peaceful.&nbsp; But does the President believe that there should be any type of protesters picketing outside of judges’ homes when there&#8217;s a case pending before them?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, we have not weighed in on where people should or should not protest.&nbsp; We have said that all Americans have the right to peacefully protest, whatever their point of view, but that &#8212; but that attempts at intimidation and violence are totally unacceptable and that they need to be condemned at any time they happen, regardless of who does it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you.&nbsp; The President signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill on November 15th of last year for supply chains &#8212; (phone alarm goes off) &#8212; time is not up yet.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Time is up, Ed.&nbsp; Your time is up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We heard at that that point &#8212; that &#8212; “wait until year, and then the sli- &#8212; supply chains will start to work themselves out.”&nbsp; Well, it’s June &#8212; seven months later &#8212; and we&#8217;re still waiting for supply chains to work themselves out.&nbsp; So what&#8217;s happening?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me just say that we&#8217;re funding major new initiatives on the docks and on-dock rail systems &#8211;the Port of Long Beach &#8212; to move goods more quickly.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re making those investment right now.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>An example that I want to give because the President was just at a port in Los Angeles, as you know &#8212; the Port of Los Angeles, to be specific &#8212; and announced May cargo volumes.&nbsp; There, he announced that May cargo volumes landed at approximately 970,000 container units, the third-best month in ports in a 115-year history.&nbsp; The port set a new record, averaging 12,000 units loaded off and back on each vessel, and half-shelved [on-shelf] availability is at 89 percent, just a tick below pre-pandemic.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we have seen the investments are &#8212; are out there.&nbsp; And we have seen some improvements.</p>



<p>Q    But when is relief coming?  Because when he signed it, inflation was 6.8 percent.  It’s now 8.6 percent.  So when is that relief coming?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, we&#8217;re going to continue to expand capacity of our ports, and that&#8217;s going to be thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re &#8212; again, we&#8217;re seeing investments now.&nbsp; I just gave an example of how we saw an uptick &#8212; uptick in the, you know, container units, which is very important as we&#8217;re talking about supply chain and what the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law has been able to do.&nbsp; And we think we&#8217;ll continue to see that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask you &#8212; can I ask you a question on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I was calling him and then we can &#8212; yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, can I ask you a question on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So there&#8217;s a coalition of civil rights groups that have been calling for President Biden to sign an executive order that would do essentially what H.R. 40 is &#8212; which is create a commission to study enslavement in the United States and consider reparations.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>They&#8217;ve renewed these calls in the aftermath of the Buffalo shooting, saying that this is a symptom of the U.S. &#8212; their inability &#8212; the failure to respond or have &#8212; to, sort of, reparatively respond to this issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I saw &#8212; I talked to members of the Congressional Black Caucus, including Congresswoman Sheila Jackson Lee.&nbsp; They are in support of President Biden signing this order, given the inability to get H.R. 40 passed in Congress in this session and probably not in the next session.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know you were asked about reparations previously, earlier this month, in relation to the California Reparations Task Force &#8212; that President Biden&#8217;s position has not changed on this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, considering the fact that President Biden did sign an executive order that created a commission to study reforming the Supreme Court, would he sign an executive order to create a permission for reparations?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; look, again, the President&#8217;s position has not changed on this.&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve been asked this question many times.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t checked in with him on this new &#8212; kind of, new ask from congressional members because &#8212; as it&#8217;s connected to Buffalo.&nbsp; But the President&#8217;s position just hasn&#8217;t changed.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more for you to share on that.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; You can go.&nbsp; I &#8212; I &#8212; sorry.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I accidently &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s okay.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, President Zelenskyy has been pressing for a quick Ukraine submission into the European Union.&nbsp; Does the President Biden support granting Ukraine accelerated path to the EU?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s not up to us.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not part of the EU &#8212; the European Union.&nbsp; That is something that the members have to decide.&nbsp; We&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to inject ourselves in something that we just don&#8217;t belong to.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more, please.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Ukrainian officials warned that without a rapid increase in military assistance, Ukraine faces a defeat in a crucial region of Donbas.&nbsp; Is President Biden willing to respond to those demands?&nbsp; And is the President satisfied with military assistance for Ukraine from U.S. Allies in Europe, especially France and Germany?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, you know, we &#8212; as it relates to our Allies, we have seen them get involved in their own way.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s up to them on how they want to assist Ukraine.&nbsp; But we have seen a coalition when it comes to NATO Allies, when it comes to our European partners in coming together in a way to help Ukraine.&nbsp; And that &#8212; a lot of that is because of this President&#8217;s leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I know that you&#8217;re &#8212; you&#8217;re talking about a specific area in the east &#8212; right? &#8212; that people have been talking about.&nbsp; You know, it &#8212; I don&#8217;t want to &#8212; I don&#8217;t want to speculate with hypo- &#8212; hypotheticals on what might happen there.&nbsp; I know the city has been under fierce assault and Ukrainians have been fighting bravely under constant bombardment and difficult conditions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Zelenskyy has described the fighting as “severe” as Ukrainian forces battle Russian’s forces “for every meter.”&nbsp; We are continuing to surge security assistance to Ukraine to help them defend that area of the Donbas.&nbsp; So that is something that we&#8217;re doing every day.&nbsp; There&#8217;s security assistance going into Ukraine on a daily &#8212; on a daily clip, if you will.</p>



<p>Secretary Austin will be in Europe this week holding the next round of meetings of the Ukraine &#8212; Ukraine Contact Group, where he will host ministers of defense and chiefs of defense from dozens of countries and ask them to continue to provide weapons and equipment as well.&nbsp; So that also answers your question about getting others to get involved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh &#8212; oh, we’re done?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do one more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I &#8212; can I ask you a question on &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, my gosh, who do I want to go to?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk by reporters.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, you in the corner.&nbsp; I haven’t ever called on you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank &#8212; thank you, Karine.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, in the back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So I have two questions on baby formula.&nbsp; So, first, what is the White House &#8212; what is the latest update the White House has received on the current infant formula situation across the country?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, let me see if I have anything new for you on that because I think it&#8217;s been a couple of days since we have asked &#8212; been asked that question.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new.&nbsp; I know we made some announcements last week, I don’t &#8212; I just don&#8217;t have them in front of me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if you want to come back, and we&#8217;ll &#8212; we&#8217;ll talk through the things that we have been able to do in the past &#8212; what &#8212; the most recent activities that we&#8217;ve done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a second question.&nbsp; So, House Appropriations Chairwoman Rosa DeLauro sent a letter to the HHS Inspector General asking the FDA to &#8212; or asking the Inspector General to investigate the FDA’s recent policy to use enforcement discretion for certain importation of infant formula.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; but she expressed concerns that the rapid pace that they&#8217;re making these approval decisions, with only nine full-time staff members.&nbsp; So is the President confident that the FDA is being able to make these decisions to make sure infant formula that is being imported is safe and &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, first, I haven&#8217;t seen the letter.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s number one.&nbsp; So, can&#8217;t really speak to the letter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re asking me if the President has confidence in the FDA: He does.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:27 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/13/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 21:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to Belarus that was declared in Executive Order 13405 of June 16, 2006, which was expanded in scope in Executive Order 14038 of August 9, 2021, is to continue in effect beyond June 16, 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The actions and policies of certain members of the Government of Belarus and other persons, and the Belarusian regime&#8217;s harmful activities and long-standing abuses, continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.  Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13405 with respect to Belarus.        </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 13, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/13/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 21:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On June 16, 2006, by Executive Order 13405, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions and policies of certain members&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On June 16, 2006, by Executive Order 13405, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions and policies of certain members of the Government of&nbsp;Belarus and other persons to undermine Belarus&#8217;s democratic processes or institutions, manifested in the fundamentally undemocratic March 2006 elections; to commit human rights abuses related to political repression, including detentions and disappearances; and to engage in public corruption, including by diverting or misusing Belarusian public assets or by misusing public authority.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On August 9, 2021, by Executive Order 14038, I expanded the&nbsp;scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13405, finding that the Belarusian regime&#8217;s harmful activities and long-standing abuses aimed at suppressing democracy and the exercise of human rights and fundamental freedoms in Belarus &#8212; including illicit and oppressive activities stemming from the August 9, 2020, fraudulent Belarusian presidential election and its aftermath, such as the elimination of political opposition and civil society organizations and the regime&#8217;s disruption and endangering of international civil air travel &#8212; constituted an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.</p>



<p>The actions and policies of certain members of the Government of Belarus and other persons, and the Belarusian regime&#8217;s harmful activities and long-standing abuses, continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13405, which was expanded in scope in Executive Order 14038, must continue in effect beyond June 16, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1&nbsp;year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13405.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 13, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the North&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/13/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-north-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 21:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to North Korea that was declared in Executive Order 13466 of June 26, 2008, expanded in scope in Executive Order 13551 of August 30, 2010, addressed further in Executive Order 13570 of April 18, 2011, further expanded in scope in Executive Order 13687 of January 2, 2015, and under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13722 of March 15, 2016, and Executive Order 13810 of September 20, 2017, is to continue in effect beyond June 26, 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The existence and risk of the proliferation of weapons-usable fissile material on the Korean Peninsula; the actions and&nbsp;policies of the Government of North Korea that destabilize the Korean Peninsula and imperil United States Armed Forces, allies, and trading partners in the region, including its pursuit of nuclear and missile programs; and other provocative, destabilizing, and repressive actions and policies of the Government of North Korea, continue to constitute an unusual and&nbsp;extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States. &nbsp;</p>



<p>For this reason, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 with respect to North Korea.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 13, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to North&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/13/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-north-korea-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 21:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On June 26, 2008, by Executive Order 13466, the President declared a national emergency with respect to North Korea pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United&#160;States constituted by the existence and risk&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On June 26, 2008, by Executive Order 13466, the President declared a national emergency with respect to North Korea pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United&nbsp;States constituted by the existence and risk of the proliferation of weapons-usable fissile material on the Korean Peninsula.&nbsp; The President also found that it was necessary to maintain certain restrictions with respect to North&nbsp;Korea that would otherwise have been lifted pursuant to&nbsp;Proclamation 8271 of June 26, 2008, which terminated the exercise of authorities under the Trading With the Enemy Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. App. 1<em> et seq.</em>) with respect to North Korea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On August 30, 2010, the President signed Executive Order 13551, which expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States posed by the continued actions and policies of the Government of North Korea, manifested by its unprovoked attack that resulted in the sinking of the Republic of Korea Navy ship <em>Cheonan</em> and the deaths of 46 sailors in March&nbsp;2010; its announced test of a nuclear device and its missile launches in 2009; its actions in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1718 and 1874, including the procurement of luxury goods; and its illicit and deceptive activities in international markets through which it obtains financial and other support, including money laundering, the counterfeiting of goods and currency, bulk cash smuggling, and narcotics trafficking, which destabilize the Korean Peninsula and imperil United States Armed Forces, allies, and trading partners in the region.</p>



<p>On April 18, 2011, the President signed Executive Order 13570 to take additional steps to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 and expanded in Executive Order 13551 that would ensure implementation of the import restrictions contained in United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1718 and 1874 and complement the import restrictions provided for in the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 <em>et</em><em>seq</em>.).</p>



<p>On January 2, 2015, the President signed Executive Order 13687 to expand the scope of, and to take further steps with respect to, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, as expanded in Executive Order 13551, and addressed further in Executive Order 13570, to address the threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States constituted by the provocative, destabilizing, and&nbsp;repressive actions and policies of the Government of North Korea, including its destructive, coercive cyber-related actions during November and December 2014, actions in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1718, 1874, 2087, and 2094, and commission of serious human rights abuses.</p>



<p>On March 15, 2016, the President signed Executive Order 13722 to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, as modified in scope and relied upon for additional steps in subsequent Executive Orders, to address the Government of North Korea&#8217;s continuing pursuit of its nuclear and missile programs, as evidenced by its February 7, 2016, launch using ballistic missile technology and its January 6, 2016, nuclear test in violation of its obligations pursuant to numerous United Nations Security Council resolutions and in contravention of its commitments under the September 19, 2005, Joint Statement of the Six-Party Talks, that increasingly imperils the United States and its allies.</p>



<p>On September 20, 2017, the President signed Executive Order&nbsp;13810 to take further steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, as modified in&nbsp;scope and relied upon for additional steps in subsequent Executive Orders, to address the provocative, destabilizing, and&nbsp;repressive actions and policies of the Government of North&nbsp;Korea, including its intercontinental ballistic missile launches&nbsp;of July 3 and July 28, 2017, and its nuclear test of&nbsp;September&nbsp;2, 2017; its commission of serious human rights abuses; and its use of funds generated through international trade to support its nuclear and missile programs and weapons proliferation.</p>



<p>The existence and risk of the proliferation of weapons-usable fissile material on the Korean Peninsula and the actions and policies of the Government of North Korea continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, expanded in scope in Executive Order 13551, addressed further in Executive Order 13570, further expanded in scope in Executive Order 13687, and under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13722 and Executive Order 13810, must&nbsp;continue in effect beyond June 26, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 with respect to North Korea.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 13, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
