<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:18:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces 10 Key&#160;Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/06/president-biden-announces-10-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 10 individuals to serve in key roles: David R. Gilmour, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Equatorial Guinea Scott Miller, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Swiss Confederation and to the Principality of Liechtenstein Marc R.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 10 individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>David R. Gilmour, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Equatorial Guinea</li><li>Scott Miller, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Swiss Confederation and to the Principality of Liechtenstein</li><li>Marc R. Stanley, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Argentine Republic</li><li>Sam Bagenstos, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Melissa Dalton, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Homeland Defense and Global Security Affairs, Department of Defense</li><li>Alexia Latortue, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for International Markets, Department of the Treasury</li><li>Brent Neiman, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary / Designated Assistant Secretary for International Finance and Development, Department of the Treasury</li><li>Alice Albright, Nominee for Chief Executive Officer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation</li><li>Todd Harper, Nominee for Chairman of the National Credit Union Administration</li><li>Owen Hernstadt, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors, Export-Import Bank</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>David R. Gilmour, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Equatorial Guinea</u></strong></p>



<p>David R. Gilmour, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the Chargé d’Affaires a.i. at the U.S. Embassy in N’Djamena, Chad.&nbsp; He is a former U.S. Ambassador to the Togolese Republic.&nbsp; He has served in the Bureau of African Affairs at the Department of State as Deputy Assistant Secretary for Central Africa, Director of East African Affairs, and Director of Public Diplomacy for Africa.&nbsp; He was Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. embassies in Panama and Malawi, and Counselor for Public Affairs at the U.S. Mission in Geneva.&nbsp; Other overseas assignments include Australia, Costa Rica, South Africa and Cameroon.&nbsp; He is the recipient of numerous awards, including Partnership Excellence Award from the Secretary of State’s Office of Global Partnerships.&nbsp; Gilmour received a B.A. from Saginaw Valley State University in Michigan, and an M.A. from the University of Texas at Austin.&nbsp; He speaks French and Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Scott Miller, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Swiss Confederation and to the Principality of Liechtenstein</u></strong></p>



<p>Scott Miller is an LGBTQ rights activist and philanthropist.&nbsp; As co-chair of the Gill Foundation’s board of directors, Miller directs the foundation’s national giving strategy to advance LGBTQ equality, including public education campaigns to ban conversion therapy and end discrimination against LGBTQ Americans.&nbsp; At the foundation, Miller also oversees local efforts to ensure equal opportunity for all Coloradans, including generous support for K-12 STEM education at numerous Colorado public schools.&nbsp; During the pandemic, Miller led efforts to provide over 5.6 million meals to tens of thousands of his fellow Coloradans to alleviate food insecurity.&nbsp; Together Miller and his husband, Tim Gill, are among the top contributors to LGBTQ equality issues in the United States.&nbsp; Previously, Miller served as an account vice president at UBS Wealth Management in Denver, Colorado.&nbsp; Miller earned a Bachelor of Science degree with honors in business administration from the University of Colorado Boulder.&nbsp; Upon graduation, he started his career as a management consultant for Accenture, followed by work as an event planner for global clientele.</p>



<p><strong><u>Marc R. Stanley, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Argentine Republic</u></strong></p>



<p>Marc R. Stanley is President of the Stanley Law Group and a board-certified civil trial lawyer in Dallas, Texas.&nbsp; A former president of the Texas Trial Lawyers Association and the Dallas Trial Lawyers Association, Stanley has served in leadership positions in dozens of local and national charitable and civic organizations throughout his career.&nbsp; He was a Council Member of the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum in Washington, D.C. and a Member of the Board of Visitors at the United States Air Force Air University at Maxwell Air Force Base in Montgomery, Alabama.&nbsp;&nbsp; He served for four years as Chairman of the Texas Public Finance Authority and was Co-Chair of the Mayor’s Complete Count Outreach Committee for the U.S Census (City of Dallas).&nbsp; Stanley earned a B.B.A. at George Washington University, and a J.D. at the University of Texas-Austin.&nbsp; He is the recipient of numerous awards, including the Tikkun Olam Award by the Jewish Council for Public Affairs.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sam Bagenstos, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of Health and Human Services</u></strong></p>



<p>Samuel R. Bagenstos currently serves as General Counsel to the Office of Management and Budget.&nbsp; He is on leave from his position as the Frank G. Millard Professor of Law at the University of Michigan Law School.&nbsp; From 2009 to 2011, Bagenstos served as a political appointee in the Obama-Biden Administration&#8217;s Department of Justice, where he was Principal Deputy Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights.&nbsp; Pursuant to an appointment by Governor Gretchen Whitmer, he chaired the Michigan Employment Relations Commission from 2019 to 2021.&nbsp; An expert in civil rights law, Bagenstos wrote the leading law school casebook on disability rights law and has engaged with state Medicaid systems as a lawyer, advocate, and consultant to promote community-based services for individuals with disabilities.&nbsp; He has argued four cases in the Supreme Court of the United States, including key matters under the Americans with Disabilities Act as well as Young v. UPS, a case that established new protections for pregnant workers.&nbsp; A graduate of the University of North Carolina and the Harvard Law School, Bagenstos clerked for Judge Stephen Reinhardt on the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit and Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg on the Supreme Court of the United States.</p>



<p><strong><u>Melissa Dalton, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Homeland Defense and Global Security Affairs, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Melissa G. Dalton is currently the Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Strategy, Plans, and Capabilities at the U.S. Department of Defense. She is responsible for advising the Secretary of Defense and other senior defense leaders on national security and defense strategy; the forces, contingency plans, and associated posture necessary to implement the defense strategy; nuclear deterrence and missile defense policy; and security cooperation plans and policies. Prior to her appointment to the Biden-Harris Administration in January 2021, Ms. Dalton was a senior fellow and deputy director of the Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) International Security Program and director of the Cooperative Defense Project. Her CSIS research focused on reinforcing the principled foundations of U.S. defense strategy and military operations, including the responsible role of the U.S. military in Defense Support of Civil Authorities. Prior to joining CSIS in 2014, Ms. Dalton served for a decade as a career civil servant in the Bush and Obama Administrations at DoD. Her assignments included senior advisor for force planning, special assistant to the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy, policy adviser to the commander of the International Security Assistance Force in Kabul, Afghanistan, and country director for Lebanon and Syria in the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy. She also served as an intelligence analyst at the Defense Intelligence Agency.</p>



<p><strong><u>Alexia Latortue, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for International Markets, Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Alexia Latortue is Deputy Chief Executive Offer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation where she helps shape MCC’s strategic vision, oversees the agency’s operations to deliver on programmatic priorities and leads the team. Ms. Latortue has over 20 years of experience in international development, with a focus on development finance, policy and making markets work for all people. Her work has covered private sector development, financial systems development, climate, infrastructure and economic inclusion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ms. Latortue was previously Managing Director for Corporate Strategy and a member of the Executive Committee of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD). Prior to joining the EBRD, she served as the Obama-Biden Administration as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for International Development Policy at the Department of the Treasury, advancing inclusive growth and poverty reduction internationally through the multilateral development banks. Previously, Ms. Latortue spent 10 years with the World Bank where her last assignment was Deputy CEO of CGAP, a unit dedicated to advancing financial inclusion. She began her career with Development Alternatives, Inc.</p>



<p>Ms. Latortue earned a M.A. from the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy at Tufts University and a B.S. from Georgetown University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Brent Neiman, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary / Designated Assistant Secretary for International Finance and Development, Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Brent Neiman is the Edward Eagle Brown Professor of Economics at the University of Chicago’s Booth School of Business. His teaching and research focus on international macroeconomics, finance, and trade. He is a co-founder of the Global Capital Allocation Project and serves as the director of the Initiative on International Economics at the Becker Friedman Institute and a co-director of the Initiative for Global Markets at Chicago Booth. He is a research associate at the National Bureau of Economic Research, a research fellow at the Center for Economic Policy Research, and is an associate editor of The American Economic Review, The Quarterly Journal of Economics, and The Journal of International Economics.</p>



<p>Neiman previously served as the staff economist for international finance on the White House Council of Economic Advisers and has worked at the Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago, at McKinsey and Company, and at the McKinsey Global Institute. He earned a Bachelor of Science in Economics and a Bachelor of Applied Science from the University of Pennsylvania. He earned a master’s degree in mathematical modelling from Oxford University, where he was a Thouron Scholar, and received his PhD in economics from Harvard University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Alice Albright, Nominee for Chief Executive Officer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation</u></strong></p>



<p>Alice Albright serves as the Chief Executive Officer of the Global Partnership for Education, a multilateral partnership and fund dedicated to improving education outcomes for the most marginalized children in low income countries. Before joining GPE, Ms. Albright served in the Obama-Biden Administration from 2009 to 2013 as the Executive Vice President &amp; Chief Operating Officer of the Export-Import Bank of the United States. From 2001 to 2009, Ms. Albright served as the Chief Financial and Investment Officer for the Global Alliance for Vaccines and Immunization. While there, Ms. Albright led GAVI&#8217;s innovative finance efforts, including the launch the International Finance Facility for Immunization, a program to enhance GAVI&#8217;s ability to finance the purchase of vaccines. Previously, Ms. Albright worked as a banker with a focus on emerging markets and held a variety of positions at Citicorp, Bankers Trust Company, JP Morgan, and the Carlyle Group.</p>



<p>Ms. Albright has served on a number of boards and working groups in the development, education, and gender arenas. Currently, she serves on the UK’s G7 Gender Equality Advisory Council, the Board of Williams College, and the UNESCO Institute of Statistics. She is a member of the Council on Foreign Relations. She has been decorated as an Officier de L’Order de L’Etalon by President Kabore and a Commandeur, Ordre National du Lion by President Macky Sall.</p>



<p>Ms. Albright graduated from Williams College with a BA in History, with honors, and received an MIA from Columbia University&#8217;s School of International and Public Affairs. She is also a Chartered Financial Analyst.</p>



<p><strong><u>Todd Harper, Nominee for Chairman of the National Credit Union Administration</u></strong></p>



<p>Todd Harper has specialized in financial services policy during his more than 25 years of government service and has led the NCUA Board as Chairman since January 2021. He also chairs the interagency Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council. Mr. Harper joined the NCUA Board in April 2019 and is the first NCUA staffer to become a Board Member and Chairman. From 2011 to 2017, he led the agency’s Office of Public and Congressional Affairs and served as the chief policy advisor to two NCUA Chairmen. Previously, as staff director for the Subcommittee on Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises in the U.S. House of Representatives, Mr. Harper contributed to the efforts after the financial crisis to enact the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act. As legislative director to former Congressman Paul E. Kanjorski of Pennsylvania, he also worked on bipartisan legislation concerning credit union capital rules, terrorism risk insurance, auditing standards and subprime mortgage lending. A member of the LGBTQ community, Mr. Harper earned an M.P.P. from Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Government and a B.S. with high distinction in business analysis from Indiana University’s Kelley School of Business.</p>



<p><strong><u>Owen Hernstadt, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors, Export-Import Bank</u></strong></p>



<p>Owen Herrnstadt is the Chief of Staff to the International President and Director of Trade and Globalization at the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers. As Chief of Staff, he assists in running one of the largest manufacturing and transportation unions in the United States. As Director of Trade and Globalization, he develops policy for international trade, economic investment, international labor standards, and human rights matters. He also teaches employment and labor law at the Georgetown University Law Center and has taught international employment and labor at American University’s Washington College of Law.</p>



<p>Mr. Herrnstadt is a member of the Council on Foreign Relations, Independent Mexico Labor Expert Board, U.S. Export-Import Bank Federal Advisory Committee, and the U.S. State Department Federal Advisory Committee on International Economics. He also served as Co-Chair of the State Department’s Stakeholder Advisory Board on OECD Guidelines and  as Chair of the Board of Directors of the Baltimore Branch of the Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond. He has testified, written articles and made presentations on labor and employment law, international employment and labor law, corporate social responsibility, trade, manufacturing policy, human rights, and industrial relations in the U.S. and abroad.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Export Control&#160;Regulations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/08/06/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-export-control-regulations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice, stating that the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13222 of August&nbsp;17, 2001, in light of the expiration of the Export Administration Act of 1979, is to continue in effect for 1 year beyond August 17, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Export Control&#160;Regulations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/08/06/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-export-control-regulations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On August 17, 2001, the President issued Executive Order&#160;13222 pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.).&#160; In that order, the President declared a national emergency with respect to the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States related to the expiration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On August 17, 2001, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13222 pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.)</em>.&nbsp; In that order, the President declared a national emergency with respect to the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States related to the expiration of the Export Administration Act of 1979, as amended.&nbsp; Because the implementation of certain sanctions authorities, including sections 11A, 11B, and 11C of such Export Administration Act of 1979, consistent with section 1766(b) of Public Law 115-232, the Export Control Reform Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 4601 note), is to be carried out under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, the national emergency declared on August 17, 2001, must continue in effect beyond August 17, 2021.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13222, as amended by Executive Order 13637 of March 8, 2013.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>August 6, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Bills Signed: H.R. 208, H.R. 264, H.R. 772, H.R.&#160;1002</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/06/press-release-bills-signed-h-r-208-h-r-264-h-r-772-h-r-1002/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 16:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26441</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, August 6, 2021, the President signed into law: H.R. 208, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 500 West Main Street, Suite 102 in Tupelo, Mississippi, as the Colonel Carlyle &#8220;Smitty&#8221; Harris Post Office; H.R. 264, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 1101&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, August 6, 2021, the President signed into law:<br><br>H.R. 208, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 500 West Main Street, Suite 102 in Tupelo, Mississippi, as the Colonel Carlyle &#8220;Smitty&#8221; Harris Post Office;<br><br>H.R. 264, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 1101 Charlotte Street in Georgetown, South Carolina, as the Joseph Hayne Rainey Memorial Post Office Building;<br><br>H.R. 772, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 229 Minnetonka Avenue South in Wayzata, Minnesota, as the Jim Ramstad Post Office; and<br><br>H.R. 1002, the &#8220;Debarment Enforcement of Bad Actor Registrants Act of 2021 or the DEBAR Act of 2021,&#8221; which authorizes the Attorney General to issue an order to prohibit any person from being registered to manufacture, distribute, or dispense controlled substances under certain circumstances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meetings with Landlords and Tenant&#160;Advocates</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/06/readout-of-white-house-meetings-with-landlords-and-tenant-advocates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 13:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling and Special Assistant to the President for Housing and Urban Policy Erika Poethig, along with other Biden-Harris Administration officials, held virtual listening sessions with groups representing landlords and tenant advocates to discuss state and local disbursement of emergency rental assistance funds and ways to protect&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling and Special Assistant to the President for Housing and Urban Policy Erika Poethig, along with other Biden-Harris Administration officials, held virtual listening sessions with groups representing landlords and tenant advocates to discuss state and local disbursement of emergency rental assistance funds and ways to protect renters from eviction.</p>



<p>Administration officials communicated the need for landlords to accept rental assistance before pursuing evictions. They also received feedback on strengths and weaknesses of state and local rental assistance programs as well as ways the Administration can work with governors and mayors to expedite the release of rental assistance funds. Landlords also offered their feedback on how grantees might speed delivery and increase access to rental assistance.&nbsp; In their discussions with tenant advocates, Administration officials also heard about the challenges renters are facing in accessing emergency rental assistance funds. They also shared examples of where evictions are proceeding and ways to promote eviction diversion strategies.</p>



<p>In both meetings, Administration officials reiterated the commitment made by President Biden that his Administration will not rest—nor should state and local governments—until emergency rental assistance dollars reach Americans in need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The meetings with these groups are part of continued engagement by the Administration to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/fact-sheet-companies-non-profits-government-agencies-answer-biden-harris-call-make-combined-commitment-to-alert-tens-of-millions-of-americans-to-emergency-rental-assistance/">raise awareness among tenants and landlords</a> on available resources and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initiatives-to-promote-housing-stability-by-supporting-vulnerable-tenants-and-preventing-foreclosures/">increase the pace of distribution</a> of the billions in emergency rental assistance that is available to state and local governments to prevent evictions and make landlords whole.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Health Center Week,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/08/06/a-proclamation-on-national-health-center-week-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 13:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26413</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; In 1965, our Nation launched its first community health centers to improve the lives and well-being of Americans regardless of their ability to pay.&#160; These health centers were a&#160;key component of President Lyndon B. Johnson&#8217;s &#8220;Great Society&#8221; series of policy initiatives to eliminate poverty and racial injustice, and today serve as the bedrock on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In 1965, our Nation launched its first community health centers to improve the lives and well-being of Americans regardless of their ability to pay.&nbsp; These health centers were a&nbsp;key component of President Lyndon B. Johnson&#8217;s &#8220;Great Society&#8221; series of policy initiatives to eliminate poverty and racial injustice, and today serve as the bedrock on which our public health system was built.&nbsp; Today, health centers are one of the largest health care providers in the country and provide high-quality affordable, accessible, and value-based primary health care services to 29 million Americans each year &#8212; approximately 1 in 11 people across the country.&nbsp; They have also been a vital part of our Nation&#8217;s response to the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; Over&nbsp;the course of National Health Center Week, we recognize the&nbsp;importance of federally-supported health centers and the role they play as a beacon of strength, service, and care in our&nbsp;communities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Health centers integrate medical, dental, and behavioral health care services into a single &#8220;health home&#8221; and consistently yield strong patient outcomes.&nbsp; Health centers also&nbsp;play a critical role in reducing racial and ethnic, geographic, socioeconomic, and other health disparities in the&nbsp;United&nbsp;States.&nbsp; They are invaluable to ensuring that our&nbsp;Nation&#8217;s underserved populations, especially individuals and&nbsp;families living in poverty, rural communities, and communities of color are able to receive the care they need&nbsp;and&nbsp;deserve. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our Nation&#8217;s recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic is stronger because of our health centers, and the tireless, dedicated health center employees who continue to deliver critical services such as COVID-19 testing, treatment, and prevention services on the front lines. &nbsp;As we ramped up the distribution of COVID-19 vaccines over the past several months, health centers, through the Health Center COVID-19 Vaccine Program, have vaccinated and built vaccine confidence in millions of Americans from hard-hit and high-risk communities. &nbsp;Two-thirds of individuals vaccinated at health centers so far identify as racial and ethnic minorities. &nbsp;Health centers have also offered greater flexibility during the pandemic by expanding telehealth services to those in need.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I believe that health care in America should be a right, not a privilege. &nbsp;No one should have to lay awake at night staring at the ceiling wondering what they are going to do to&nbsp;get the care they need or to pay the bills if a family member gets sick.&nbsp; That is why I&nbsp;will&nbsp;do everything in my power to&nbsp;ensure&nbsp;that&nbsp;all Americans&nbsp;have access to&nbsp;the&nbsp;quality, affordable health care&nbsp;they deserve &#8212; and the peace of mind it&nbsp;brings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In support of that goal, my Administration is committed to&nbsp;expanding health centers and increasing access to their life-saving services. &nbsp;That is why we invested more than $7.6 billion to help health centers prevent and respond to COVID-19 and improve health care services &#8212; including over $1 billion for major infrastructure and renovation projects at health centers across the country through the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; I&nbsp;am also committed to doubling the Federal investment in community health centers to further expand access to care and&nbsp;make strides in our pursuit of health equity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During National Health Center Week, we recognize the importance of health centers and their staff who heal and strengthen our local communities. &nbsp;We salute their dedication and service.&nbsp; As our Nation builds back better, we commit to working together to bring about a stronger, healthier Nation for&nbsp;all.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim the week of August 8 through August 14, 2021, as&nbsp;National Health Center Week.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this sixth day of August, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/08/05/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-48/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 11:13 A.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning.&#160; And thanks for joining us.&#160; Dr. Walensky, Dr. Fauci, Dr. Murthy, and I will keep our comments brief this morning, so we can get to your questions. I’ll start with an update on the progress we&#8217;re making in our fight against the pandemic.&#160; Driven by the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:13 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; And thanks for joining us.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, Dr. Fauci, Dr. Murthy, and I will keep our comments brief this morning, so we can get to your questions.</p>



<p>I’ll start with an update on the progress we&#8217;re making in our fight against the pandemic.&nbsp; Driven by the more transmissible Delta variant, cases are continuing to rise.&nbsp; These cases are concentrated in communities with low vaccination rates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, over the past seven days, Florida and Texas have accounted for about one third of new cases and more than one third of new hospitalizations nationwide.</p>



<p>In seven states alone &#8212; Florida, Texas, Missouri, Arkansas, Louisiana, Alabama, Mississippi &#8212; states with some of the lowest vaccination rates account for about half of new cases and hospitalizations in the past week, despite making up less than a quarter of the U.S. population.</p>



<p>Vaccinations are the very best line of defense against COVID and the Delta variant, and we’re doing everything we can to keep getting shots in arms.&nbsp; And we are seeing results.</p>



<p>Over the past 24 hours, we’ve recorded 864,000 vaccinations &#8212; the highest in a day since July 3rd &#8212; and, importantly, 585,000 first shots &#8212; that&#8217;s the highest since July 1st.</p>



<p>For the fourth week in a row, we have increased the daily average number of Americans newly vaccinated, and importantly, we’re seeing the most significant increases in states with the highest case rates.</p>



<p>We have more than doubled the average number of people newly vaccinated each day over the past three weeks in the states with the highest case rates.&nbsp; In fact, Louisiana, Arkansas, Missouri, Alabama, Oklahoma, and Mississippi are now vaccinating people at a pace not seen since April.</p>



<p>And other states that have been lagging in vaccinations are also picking up their pace.&nbsp; Tennessee has seen a 90 percent increase in first shots over the past two weeks.&nbsp; Oklahoma, an 82 percent increase.&nbsp; And Georgia, a 66 percent increase in first shots over the past two weeks.</p>



<p>Clearly, Americans are seeing the impact of being unvaccinated and unprotected.&nbsp; And they respond by doing their part, rolling up their sleeve, and getting vaccinated.</p>



<p>In addition to getting more shots in arms, we are spurring action on vaccination requirements.&nbsp; Last week, the President announced new vaccination requirements for all federal workers and federal contractors.&nbsp; And he called for strong vaccination requirements from the private and public sectors to help protect lives and keep our economy strong.</p>



<p>Already, we&#8217;re seeing momentum in vaccination requirements across the country.&nbsp; Businesses know vaccinations are a way to keep their workers and customers safe, and to keep their doors open.</p>



<p>And today, Yelp is announcing a new feature that allows consumers to search for businesses with fully vaccinated workers or businesses that require proof of vaccination to enter the business.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Small businesses across the country are stepping up.&nbsp; A recent study shows that half of America’s small businesses are likely to require their employees to be vaccinated.</p>



<p>Just this week, Saffron, a family-owned business in New Orleans, announced their staff is 100 percent vaccinated and they are requiring vaccinations or a negative test for all their customers.&nbsp; Tuesday was Saffron’s first night of service under their new rules, and the owner said the community response has been overwhelmingly positive.</p>



<p>At the same time, nearly 650 colleges and universities are already requiring on-campus employees and students to be vaccinated.&nbsp; And yesterday, leaders of America’s historically Black medical schools decided to mandate COVID-19 vaccines for all of their medical students.</p>



<p>Nationwide, over 100 hospital and healthcare systems, including the Department of Veterans Affairs, are requiring vaccinations for their healthcare workers.&nbsp; In fact, just this week, more than 30 healthcare employers, including Kaiser Permanente &#8212; one of the country’s largest &#8212; announced vaccination requirements for their healthcare workers.</p>



<p>So, America’s businesses, large and small; universities and medical schools; and many other institutions are stepping up on vaccination requirements.</p>



<p>And our message is quite simple: We support these vaccination requirements to protect workers, communities, and the country.</p>



<p>As we double down on getting more Americans vaccinated, we&#8217;re also stepping up our work to help states experiencing rising cases due to the Delta variant.&nbsp; Our COVID-19 Surge Response Teams are now working with 16 states to address their specific needs.</p>



<p>We have deployed hundreds of federal personnel to provide in-person support to address a range of needs, from increased testing, to getting shots in arms through mobile vaccination clinics, to encouraging more physicians to use antibody treatments, to helping states address hospital capacity issues.</p>



<p>Let me close with this: From the beginning, we have known that the virus is unpredictable.&nbsp; And we have been relentless &#8212; relentless &#8212; in our efforts to get people vaccinated.&nbsp; Our whole-of-government response will continue its relentless efforts to end this pandemic and deliver progress each and every day.</p>



<p>With that, let me turn it to Dr. Walensky.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; And thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; To keep things brief, I will simply give you an overview of the data and the state of where we are as a country.</p>



<p>Yesterday, CDC reported 103,444 &#8212; -45 new cases of COVID-19.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is about 89,463 cases per day.&nbsp; This represents an increase of 43 percent from the prior seven-day average.</p>



<p>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 7,348 per day, an increase of about 41 percent from the prior seven-day period.</p>



<p>And seven-day average daily deaths have also increased to 381 per day, an increase of more than 39 percent from the previous seven-day period.&nbsp; We saw 614 new deaths reported to CDC on Tuesday.</p>



<p>Eighty-three percent of our counties in the United States are experiencing moderate or high transmission with Delta variant continuing to be the predominant circulating virus.&nbsp;<br><br>Across the board, we are seeing increases in cases and hospitalizations in all age groups.&nbsp; Those at highest risk remain people who have not yet been vaccinated.&nbsp; Now is the time to get vaccinated.&nbsp; We know these vaccines are working and we know they save lives.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; I’d just like to spend a minute or two addressing a concern that I continue to hear regarding the speed with which the vaccines were developed.&nbsp; And this is usually among people who have a degree of vaccine hesitancy or reluctance to get vaccinated.<br><br>It really relates to two things that have gone on that people need to appreciate.&nbsp; One is the logistics and the investment in resources that was made, and others is the decades of basic and clinical research that antedated the development of the vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>What about the logistics and the resources?&nbsp; Generally, when you develop a vaccine &#8212; the thing that usually takes years to do &#8212; you do it in a sequential fashion.&nbsp; In other words, in order not to waste money, as it were, you do something preclinical, phase one, phase two, phase three, and then you start manufacturing the product.&nbsp; You do that sequentially because if the first one doesn&#8217;t succeed, you don&#8217;t want to go to the second, third, and fourth step.<br><br>Because of the wise investment in Operation Warp Speed &#8212; and we give credit to the Trump administration for doing this, particularly Secretary Alex Azar, who was an important component of that &#8212; what you did was make an investment to prepare for phase two and phase three, even before you knew that phase one worked or not, and to start manufacturing.&nbsp;<br><br>So when you do that, you make a major investment in resources.&nbsp; If the vaccine doesn&#8217;t work, you&#8217;ve lost a lot of money; if the vaccine does work, you save a lot of time.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what happened.&nbsp;<br><br>In addition, we had the clinical trial sites that we had built decades earlier for HIV and influenza, which were used to do the clinical trials.&nbsp;<br><br>And third, unfortunately for us, but fortunately for the vaccine trials, we were in the middle of the summer surge when the phase three trials were initiated.&nbsp;<br><br>So, next comes the decades of basic and clinical research, both in platform technology and immunogen.&nbsp; It didn&#8217;t start in January of 2020 when the sequence was put on a public database.&nbsp;<br><br>The data &#8212; the experiments on mRNA approach, which was funded predominantly by the NIH and also industry was involved, started decades earlier to develop an mRNA molecule that could be used as an immunogen for a vaccine.&nbsp; In addition, the vector-based approach, such as the one that J&amp;J did, was again done 10 or 20 years earlier with HIV.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the now very, very elegant work of the development of an immunogen that would be highly immunogenic to get the kind of high efficacy and effectiveness that we got was work done at the NIH Vaccine Research Center and by many of our grantees over the previous, literally, one to two decades.&nbsp;<br><br>So when people say, “I&#8217;m concerned that this went too fast,” it did not go too fast.&nbsp; It was a major investment, both in the logistics, the resources, and the clinical and basic research.&nbsp;<br><br>So I&#8217;ll hand it now back to you, Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Let me hand it over to Dr. Murthy.&nbsp; Dr. Murthy.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Well, thanks so much, Jeff.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s great to be with all of you again this morning.&nbsp;<br><br>I think we all know as cases have risen across the country due to the Delta variant, there are Americans who are wondering what this really means for them and their families.&nbsp; And today I want to emphasize one fact that remains true, and that is that the vaccines are working against the Delta variant.&nbsp; They are highly effective at preventing severe disease, hospitalization, and death.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re also effective at reducing the overall risk of infection.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, a recent study in the New England Journal of Medicine found that two doses of the mRNA vaccines are 88 percent effective against symptomatic COVID-19 infection with the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>So, breakthrough infections in fully vaccinated people are the exception, not the rule.&nbsp; And when they do happen, the vast majority are mild and asymptomatic &#8212; mild or asymptomatic.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, this reflects the reality that we have the most effective tool we need to keep us safe and end this pandemic, and that is a vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>And recognizing the importance of continuing to push our efforts to vaccinate the nation, yesterday, we brought together the six living former surgeons general of the United States &#8212; from the Clinton, Bush, Obama, and Trump administrations &#8212; to discuss our public health COVID-19 response, with equity being at the forefront of our conversation.&nbsp;<br><br>It was a historic meeting for a historic moment.&nbsp; And these former surgeons general are public health leaders who have been friends, mentors, and partners to me in my years as Surgeon General.&nbsp; And we spoke about their concerns about health misinformation, about the importance of ensuring that communities of color and rural areas aren&#8217;t left behind in the vaccination effort, and the power also of engaging trusted community-based organizations in vaccinations.&nbsp;<br><br>We will continue to work together in the months ahead to ensure we continue to increase vaccination rates across the country with equity as our guide.&nbsp;<br><br>And finally, this gathering of surgeons general reflected the diversity of our nation, and it was emblematic of what we have to do together to defeat the virus.&nbsp; As SGs, we came together from different backgrounds, serving under different political administrations to work together on a path toward ending this pandemic.&nbsp; And we all share the belief that science and public health are what will help us protect our nation from this pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>So thanks for your time today.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll turn it back over to Jeff for Q&amp;A.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Doctors.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go ahead and open it up for questions.&nbsp; First question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; First question, let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett at ABC News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; We know that boosters are still under consideration, but there&#8217;s more openness to acting on them for immunocompromised people faster, so can you tell us when can immunocompromised people expect those boosters will be available? &nbsp;And are there any updates?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci?</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yes, thank you for that question.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve said, and continue to say, immunocompromised individuals are vulnerable.&nbsp; The reason is that it is clear now from the observational data that was made that they do not make, in general, with some exceptions, but in general, do not make an adequate response that we felt &#8212; feel would be adequately protected.&nbsp; So, in this regard, it is extremely important for us to move to get those individuals their boosters.</p>



<p>And we are now working on that, and we&#8217;ll make that be implemented as quickly as possible because, for us and for the individuals involved, it is a very high priority.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Weijia at CBS.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for taking my question.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky have both warned that the virus may mutate and perhaps into a strain that is powerful enough to evade the vaccine.&nbsp; Is there any way to gauge how long before the virus overtakes the vaccine?&nbsp; And so we understand what that means for the vaccine, is there a way to tweak it in that situation in order to give us protection?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Why don’t we start with you, Dr. Fauci, and then Dr. Walensky if you have anything to add?</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yes, there is a very, very longstanding tenet in virology that viruses cannot mutate unless they replicate.&nbsp; And so, the easiest way to prevent the scenario that you&#8217;re proposing could happen would be to get as many people vaccinated as quickly as we possibly can to not allow the virus to continue to circulate in the community, giving it ample time to mutate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, not every mutation is going to result in a functional change, but every once in a while, you do get a series or a constellation of mutations that do that, and you get a functional change the way we have seen with the Delta variant, which functionally changed because it became significantly more able to transmit.</p>



<p>We have within our power to prevent that.&nbsp; And you prevent it by not allowing the virus to freely circulate, finding vulnerable targets.&nbsp; You protect the vulnerable targets, who are unvaccinated people, by vaccinating them.&nbsp; And when you do so, you do a very, very strong blocking of the evolution of variants that could be problematic.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Sharon LaFraniere at New York Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Many experts say that the falling antibody levels that Pfizer and, today, Moderna cite as evidence that booster shots are needed is not convincing because people may still be protected even with those.&nbsp; If that&#8217;s so, what is the right signal?&nbsp; Is it vaccinated people ending up sick enough to be in hospitals, and can the government wait for that kind of evidence before making a decision?</p>



<p>And then, secondly, I wanted to ask: What are the chances that the Delta variant will burn out, so to speak, here in a month or so, like in India and the UK?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, first.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, you know, we’re going to make the decision about booster shots based on a compilation of evidence, one of which will most definitely be the immune responses, as you know.&nbsp; But that is not necessarily known to be a perfect correlate &#8212; the antibody responses.&nbsp; Our immune system also has T cell responses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is going to be a combination of evidence, both of neutralizing antibody data, as well as clinical trial data, as well as our cohort data that monitor the safety and &#8212; or the effectiveness of our vaccines in many different populations across the country &#8212; tens of thousands of people, essential workers, healthcare providers, long-term care facilities, people who&#8217;ve been vaccinated early in the process. &nbsp;And it will be a combination of all of that evidence that helps inform our booster strategy.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, the question of the case count and quote &#8212;</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Go ahead, please.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Right, so, what you&#8217;re asking is, when are we going to turn around this acceleration that we&#8217;re currently experiencing with Delta.</p>



<p>There are two ways you do that.&nbsp; You do it in the immediate sense, right now, by mitigation.&nbsp; And mitigation are the kinds of things you&#8217;ve heard from the recommendations of the CDC regarding masking, by regarding avoiding situations &#8212; crowded situations where you can have the increased capability of the virus to spread.</p>



<p>The ultimate endgame of all this is vaccination.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we continue to harp on that in a very, very proactive way; that if we continue to vaccinate and we get that 93 million people who are eligible for vaccinations, who have not been vaccinated &#8212; if we do that, in the immediate, intermediate, and long term, and do the mitigation right now, we will turn the Delta surge around.&nbsp; I will guarantee you that that will happen, if we do what I just outlined.</p>



<p>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Kaitlan Collins, CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Several of you and the President have repeatedly cited figures saying that 99 percent of those who die from COVID-19 are unvaccinated and 95 percent, around that, are hospital- &#8212; who are hospitalized are unvaccinated.&nbsp; With the Delta variant, do you still stand by these numbers, and do you have government data to back them up?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yes, thank you for that question, Kaitlan.&nbsp;&nbsp;So those data were data that were from analyses in several states from January through June and didn&#8217;t reflect the data that we have now from the Delta variant.&nbsp; We are actively working to update those in the context of the Delta variant.</p>



<p>I do want to reiterate, though, that based on the data we&#8217;re seeing &#8212; and we don&#8217;t have fully updated numbers &#8212; universally, as we look at our hospitalizations and as we look at our deaths, they are overwhelmingly unvaccinated people.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Tamara Keith at NPR.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s some reporting out there that the working groups that are looking at reopening some international travel are making plans to require vaccination for international visitors.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering how that would work &#8212; whether it would be simply an attestation with federal workers, or whether there would be a more rigorous form of vaccine verification.</p>



<p>And on vaccine verification: You talk about that restaurant and other businesses that are requiring their customers be vaccinated.&nbsp; How are these businesses supposed to do vaccine verification?&nbsp; Is it Wild West out there, or is &#8212; are there guidelines?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t I take the first question on travel, and, Dr. Murthy, vaccine verifications.</p>



<p>In terms of travel &#8212; and I&#8217;m glad you ask that question &#8212; the administration certainly understands the importance of international travel.&nbsp; And given where we&#8217;re &#8212; where we are today, as Dr. Walensky showed us earlier, on the prevalence of the Delta variant, the United States will maintain the existing travel restrictions at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, we do have, as you alluded to, agency working groups that are developing plans for when we do open travel, how do we do it in a consistent and safe way.&nbsp; And part of that planning is a phased approach that foreign nationals traveling to the United States may &#8212; there&#8217;s still policy work being done here &#8212; may need to have some type of a vaccine requirement, but that&#8217;s not a decision at this point.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the paths that&#8217;s being looked at and considered, but there are &#8212; there are alternative paths being looked at, at the same time.</p>



<p>So, the interagency working groups are currently developing a policy process, and we will be ready when it is the right time to consider reopening travel.&nbsp; And that&#8217;ll be guided, as always, by the science and the public health.</p>



<p>Dr. Murthy.</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And let me just ask: Can you repeat this specific question you had on the verification?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; I have &#8212; I had to &#8212; I had trouble unmuting myself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; It’s okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The question is: You guys have talked about restaurants or other private businesses having only vaccinated customers.&nbsp; How is a mom-and-pop shop supposed to know how to do vaccine verification?</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Yeah, it&#8217;s good question.&nbsp; Well, the good news is that we have seen a significant movement in the private sector to develop, essentially, vaccine verification efforts.</p>



<p>We know this is not something that the federal government is leading, but we are happy to see the private sector leading and taking initiative on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, I think as more &#8212; this is going to be increasingly important because we know that more institutions are considering vaccine requirements.&nbsp; We certainly have seen that in the healthcare system.&nbsp; The vaccine requirements for healthcare workers is being adopted by more and more institutions, and we expect that that will continue.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR: &nbsp;Maureen Groppe at USA Today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about the federal assistance being offered to states that are hit hard by COVID.&nbsp; At the &#8212; one of the White House briefings this week, Jen was asked if the offers had been accepted in Florida and Texas, and she called that a, quote, “discussion.”</p>



<p>Is there any update on that &#8212; on whether Florida and Texas want any of the help that the administration is offering?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; We are working with 16 states, and I believe there are conversations with Florida.&nbsp; I know there are conversations with the state of Florida, and I believe there are some conversations with Texas too.&nbsp; But that &#8212; let me &#8212; let me come back and verify that.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re working with 16 states at this point on testing, on increased vaccination through mobile clinics, the increased use of therapeutics, also assessing and helping out on hospital capacity.&nbsp; So, 16 states across a whole range of areas.</p>



<p>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, we have time for one more question.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll go to Meg Tirrell at CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; This is a question for Dr. Walensky, I think.&nbsp; Last week, in the slides, we saw from the CDC &#8212; the CDC noted that Delta may cause more severe disease than older strains and cited some evidence from other countries.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: Does CDC think the data show it does cause more severe disease?&nbsp; And also, how are you looking at the risk it poses to children?&nbsp; Do you see more severe disease from Delta for them?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you for that question, Meg.&nbsp; Certainly, in that slide deck, there were some early preliminary studies that suggest that Delta may potentially cause severe disease.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We continue to monitor this not just in adults, but also in children.&nbsp; But I do want to highlight a couple of things that continue to confound some of the data, and that is we have enormous burden now of disease, so exposures are much higher.</p>



<p>And the mitigation strategies that were used last summer, even in the winter, have not been employed in many of these areas that we are having surges right now.</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s &#8212; we&#8217;re working to understand the differences between exposures and as well as the severity of disease, and working to confirm those preliminary data that might suggest so.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good.&nbsp; Well, thank you, and look forward to briefing early next week.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>11:40 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/COVID-Press-Briefing_5August2021_for-transcript-1.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/COVID-Press-Briefing_5August2021_for-transcript-1.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the President and Vice President’s Meeting with Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/readout-of-the-president-and-vice-presidents-meeting-with-asian-american-native-hawaiian-and-pacific-islander-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the President and Vice President met with 13 Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AA &#38; NHPI) leaders representing the rich diversity of the AA &#38; NHPI communities to discuss a wide range of issues, including the Administration’s Build Back Better Agenda. The conversation focused on the importance of combating the rise in anti-Asian hate crimes, economic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the President and Vice President met with 13 Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AA &amp; NHPI) leaders representing the rich diversity of the AA &amp; NHPI communities to discuss a wide range of issues, including the Administration’s Build Back Better Agenda. The conversation focused on the importance of combating the rise in anti-Asian hate crimes, economic opportunity, commitment to equity, protecting the sacred right to vote, and immigration reform. During the meeting, the President and Vice President reiterated their promise to work together to ensure the needs of the diaspora of the AA &amp; NHPI communities are heard, uplifted and met. The meeting also commemorated nine years since the horrific 2019 Sikh Temple mass shooting in Oak Creek, Wisconsin. The President and Vice President restated their support for a pathway to citizenship for Dreamers, farm workers, TPS holders, and essential workers through reconciliation, pledging to work with the AA &amp; NHPI community on immigration reform. The President and Vice President acknowledged the AA &amp; NHPI community record turnout in civic engagement and vowed to continue working to strengthen our democracy and the protection of voting rights.</p>



<p><em>AA &amp; NHPI Leaders:</em></p>



<ul><li>Seema Agnani, Executive Director, National Coalition for Asian Pacific American Community Development (National CAPACD)</li><li>Christine Chen, Executive Director, Asian and Pacific Islander American Vote (APIAVote)</li><li>Quyen Dinh, Executive Director, Southeast Asia Resource Action Center (SEARAC)</li><li>Satjeet Kaur, Executive Director, Sikh Coalition</li><li>Kiran Kaur Gill, Executive Director, Sikh American Legal Defense and Education Fund (SALDEF)</li><li>Kūhiō Lewis, President &amp; CEO, Council for Native Hawaiian Advancement (CNHA)</li><li>Neil Makhija, Executive Director, Indian American Impact</li><li>Gregg Orton, National Director, National Council of Asian Pacific Americans (NCAPA)</li><li>Tavae Samuelu, Executive Director, Empowering Pacific Islander Communities (EPIC)</li><li>Chiling Tong, President &amp; CEO, Asian/Pacific Islander American Chamber of Commerce and Entrepreneurship (National ACE)</li></ul>



<ul><li>Alvina Yeh, Executive Director, Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA)</li><li>Sung Yeon Choimorrow, Executive Director, National Asian Pacific American Women’s Forum (NAPAWF)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Signing of H.R. 3325, Awarding Congressional Gold Medals to Those Who Protected the U.S. Capitol on January&#160;6</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/05/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-h-r-3325-awarding-congressional-gold-medals-to-those-who-protected-the-u-s-capitol-on-january-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rose Garden 5:18 P.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Thank you, Vice President Harris.&#160;&#160;Folks, not even during the Civil War did insurrectionists breach the Capitol of the United States of America, the citadel of our democracy &#8212; not even then.&#160; But on January the 6th, 2021, they did.&#160; They did.&#160;&#160;A mob of extremists and terrorists launched&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rose Garden</p>



<p>5:18 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Thank you, Vice President Harris.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, not even during the Civil War did insurrectionists breach the Capitol of the United States of America, the citadel of our democracy &#8212; not even then.&nbsp; But on January the 6th, 2021, they did.&nbsp; They did.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>A mob of extremists and terrorists launched a violent and deadly assault on the People’s House and the sacred ritual to certify a free and fair election.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It wasn’t dissent.&nbsp; It wasn’t debate.&nbsp; It wasn’t democracy.<br>&nbsp;<br>It was insurrection.&nbsp; It was riot and mayhem.&nbsp; It was radical and chaotic.&nbsp; And it was unconstitutional.&nbsp; And maybe most important, it was fundamentally un-American &#8212; an existential threat and a test of whether our democracy could survive, whether it could overcome lies and overcome the fury of a few who were seeking to thwart the will of the many.<br>&nbsp;<br>But while the attack on our values and our votes shocked and saddened the nation, our democracy did survive.&nbsp; It did.&nbsp; Truth defeated lies.&nbsp; We did overcome.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s because of the women and men of the U.S. Capitol Police, the Washington D.C. Metropolitan Police Department, and other law enforcement officials who we honor today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Speaker Pelosi, who led the effort in the House; Senators Klobuchar and Blunt, the co-sponsors of the legislation in the Senate; and to all my colleagues &#8212; Pat Leahy and House members as well that are here: Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, I&#8217;m signing into law the bill you sent me that awards the Congressional Gold Medal to the United States Capitol Police, the Washington D.C. Metropolitan Police Department, and other law enforcement for their service in defense of our democracy on January the 6th.<br>&nbsp;<br>To all of them, on behalf of a grateful nation, thank you, thank you, thank you for protecting our Capitol.&nbsp; Maybe even more importantly, for protecting our Constitution and saving the lives of duly elected members of the Senate and the House and their staffs.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In these moments when we&#8217;re still debating &#8212; these were tragic hours back then &#8212; you stood in the breach.&nbsp; You did your duty &#8212; a duty to defend the Constitution of the United States against all enemies, foreign and domestic.&nbsp; The events that transpired were surprising but not your character or your courage, Chief, and all your men and women.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I didn’t grow up with any of you, but I know you.&nbsp; You’re just like all the women and men I grew up with &#8212; particularly, at that time, it was men &#8212; in Scranton and Claymont, places where &#8212; the neighborhood I lived in &#8212; you became a cop, a firefighter, or a priest.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I wasn’t qualified for any of them &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; so here I am.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>But, look, all kidding aside, I got to know you.&nbsp; You&#8217;re the same ones, after a ballgame in a visiting field, that come walking out of the gym if you won, and you may get jumped by the other team or their supporters.&nbsp; You may be all by yourself &#8212; the only one standing there when you watch six people jump one of our teammates.&nbsp; What the hell would you do?&nbsp; You&#8217;d jump in.&nbsp; You&#8217;d jump in, knowing you&#8217;re going to get the hell beat of you too.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Police officers are not what you do; it&#8217;s who you are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I got to know you after 36 years in the Senate, 8 years as Vice President.&nbsp; You&#8217;re always there.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s not a joke.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not some hyperbole to suggest “duty, honor, service.”&nbsp; That&#8217;s who you are.&nbsp; That&#8217;s who your dad was.&nbsp; It&#8217;s who your dad was.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And America owes you a debt we can never fully repay.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I know receiving this award is bittersweet.&nbsp; On that day, more than 140 law enforcement officers suffered physical injuries, an untold number suffering emotional toll.&nbsp; Fifteen of you were hospitalized and others were lost forever.&nbsp; May their souls rest in peace and rise in glory.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know each time you put on that shield in the morning or whenever you show for work, your families wonder whether they’re going to get a call that day &#8212; a call they don&#8217;t want to receive &#8212; hoping you come home safely.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it breaks my heart.&nbsp; It breaks the heart of the nation to remember that you were assaulted by thousands of violent insurrectionists at the Capitol of the United States of America.<br>&nbsp;<br>Jill and I would never have thought we&#8217;d have to join you in the Capitol Rotunda not once, but twice.&nbsp; Once to hiron [sic] &#8212; to honor Officer Brian Sicknick, who lost his life.&nbsp; And a second time to honor Officer Billy Evans, who lost his defending the Capitol as well.&nbsp; Both gave the full measure of their devotion to the country at the United States Capitol.<br>&nbsp;<br>Their families are here today.&nbsp; I know from similar &#8212; (applause) &#8212; yes, we should clap for the families.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I know, like others may know, from personal experience, getting that phone call.&nbsp; It&#8217;s nice to be honored and have those who you lost remembered, but it&#8217;s tough to be here because it brings back everything like it happened 10 minutes ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I offer you not only our condolences, but recognize your courage, the courage of your children.&nbsp; And you have our most profound gratitude.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, the fallen, in my view, are casualties of a struggle, literally, for the soul of America &#8212; a struggle that they didn&#8217;t start, a struggle we didn&#8217;t seek, and a struggle that, by the grace of God, we&#8217;ll win.<br>&nbsp;<br>As I said, I know this is a bittersweet moment.&nbsp; As proud of Brian and Billy as you are, it still brings back pain &#8212; the moment it happened.<br>&nbsp;<br>And also, we also offer our prayers to the families of the Capitol Police Officer, Howard Liebengood.&nbsp; Those who have been around a while, we knew his dad.&nbsp; We knew his dad well.&nbsp; He was Secretary of the United States &#8212; Sergeant of Arms of the United States Senate.<br>We also pray for the families of the Metro Police Officer, Jeffrey Smith.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For anyone out there facing trauma, for anyone still struggling, please know there is help available.<br>&nbsp;<br>My fellow Americans, the tragedy of that day deserves the truth above all else.&nbsp; We cannot allow history to be rewritten.&nbsp; We cannot allow the heroism of these officers to be forgotten.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have to understand what happened &#8212; the honest and unvarnished truth.&nbsp; We have to face it.&nbsp; That’s what great nations do, and we are a great nation.<br>&nbsp;<br>In the past weeks and months, we’ve heard the officers themselves &#8212; some of whom are here today &#8212; describe what happened: the threats, the violence, the savageness.<br>&nbsp;<br>When asked what he was fighting for, Officer Hodges, who is here today, stated it eloquently &#8212; one word: &#8220;Democracy.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>My fellow Americans, let’s remember what this was all about.&nbsp; It was a violent attempt to overturn the will of the American people; to seek power at all costs; to replace the ballot with brute force; to destroy, not to build.<br>&nbsp;<br>Without democracy, nothing is possible.&nbsp; With it, everything is.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, my fellow Americans, we must all do our part to perfect &#8212; perfect and to preserve our democracy.&nbsp; It requires people of goodwill and courage to stand up to the hate, the lies, the extremism that led to this vicious attack.<br>&nbsp;<br>It requires all of us working together &#8212; Democrats, Republicans, independents &#8212; on behalf of the common good to restore decency, honor, and respect for our system of government.<br>&nbsp;<br>And above all, it requires all of us to remember who we are at our best as a nation, as we see in the law enforcement officers who are here today &#8212; the best of our nation.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Congressional Gold Medal awards today will be housed in four locations.&nbsp; Two medals will be displayed at the U.S. Capitol Police Department in Washing- &#8212; and the Washington D.C. Metropolitan Police Department so that every morning, as you officers walk by, seeing those medals, they&#8217;ll remember the heroism of their colleagues and the importance of their work.<br>&nbsp;<br>The third medal will be displayed at the Smithsonian Museum with a plaque honoring all law enforcement that protected the Capitol on January 6th, so all visitors can understand what happened that day.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the fourth one will be displayed at the Capitol itself, to remind all who served and currently serve there and all who visit the honor and the service of those who protect and preserve all of us.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will now ask Speaker Pelosi, if she&#8217;s able &#8212; not able, willing &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and Senator Klobuchar and Senator Blunt, Chief Contee and Chief Manger, and the other officers here today to join me as I sign this bill into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops and all those who serve watch over our democracy.<br>&nbsp;<br>(The bill is signed.)<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>5:40 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Strengthening American Leadership on Clean Cars and&#160;Trucks</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/05/remarks-by-president-biden-on-strengthening-american-leadership-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 3:26 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Please, everybody, sit down &#8212; please, please, please.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; AUDIENCE MEMBERS:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I &#8212; before I begin, let me start with something &#8212; I apologize &#8212; more somber.&#160; I &#8212; I learned a couple of hours ago, when my staff came in,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>3:26 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Please, everybody, sit down &#8212; please, please, please.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBERS:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I &#8212; before I begin, let me start with something &#8212; I apologize &#8212; more somber.&nbsp; I &#8212; I learned a couple of hours ago, when my staff came in, that a close friend of mine &#8212; and I think of many of you as well &#8212; Rich Trumka died today from a heart attack.</p>



<p>The reason I was a few minutes late coming out &#8212; and I apologize for that &#8212; I was talking to his wife and to his son, who called.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He wasn&#8217;t just a great labor leader, he was a friend.&nbsp; And he was a friend of yours too, Debbie, I think.&nbsp; And he was someone I could confide in.&nbsp; And you knew whatever he said he&#8217;d do, he would do.&nbsp; It was simple, Tommy; you knew him well as well.&nbsp; He was always there.</p>



<p>He was an American worker.&nbsp; Always fighting for working people, protecting their wages, their safety, their pensions, and their ability to build a middle-class life.</p>



<p>I’ve also believed that the middle class built America, but I know who built the middle class: unions.&nbsp; Unions built the middle class.&nbsp; There is no doubt that Rich Trumka helped build unions all across this country.</p>



<p>My heart goes out to Barbara and Rich Jr. and the grandkids.&nbsp; And I might point out that, you know, I used to always kid him &#8212; he was from soft coal country; I was from hard coal country.&nbsp; We used to have this thing about &#8212; you know, he used to be president of the United Mine Workers and that&#8217;s how he got started.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, let&#8217;s &#8212; let me now turn to today’s events &#8212; event.</p>



<p>I want to thank Bernie for the introduction and for being part of the best autoworkers in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, Ray Curry, President of the UAW.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re here, Ray, I was in with you &#8212; it&#8217;s good to see you, pal.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I also want to thank the leaders of the “Big Three” companies for being here today.&nbsp; Mary Barra &#8212; she&#8217;s with General Motors.&nbsp; She &#8212; I want to tell you &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I think she&#8217;s one of the reasons we&#8217;re here today.&nbsp; We had a long discussion on a Zoom call with a bunch of labor leaders and other &#8212; other major business leaders, and she made a commitment and she&#8217;s keeping it.&nbsp; Thank you very much, Madam Chair.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jim Farley of Ford.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, my dad was in the automobile business.&nbsp; He sold Fords for a while, but mostly General Motors projects for &#8212; products.&nbsp; But you see that sucker over there?&nbsp; Zero to sixty in 4.1 seconds.&nbsp; It&#8217;s all electric.&nbsp; I tell you what.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to say publicly, I have a commitment from Mary when they make the first electric Corvette, I get to drive it.&nbsp; Right, Mary?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not kidding.&nbsp; And my entire Secret Service detail went, &#8220;Oh my God.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go.&#8221; &nbsp;</p>



<p>And Mark Stewart of Stellantis.&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, I &#8212; Mark, we used to have one of your big plants in my state.&nbsp; And as &#8212; as the man I&#8217;m about to recognize &#8212; you know, a special thanks to all the member of Congress here, but I want to pay particular recognition to my chairman, my buddy &#8212; we served together for years &#8212; Tommy Carper.&nbsp; Tom.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know that &#8212; I kid my Michigan friends, but, you know, I &#8212; I just want you to know &#8212; say to Senators Heinrich and Markey and Whitehouse and Padilla and, you know, Duckworth &#8212; and I&#8217;m leaving some folks out, I&#8217;m sure.&nbsp; Representative Kathy Castor.&nbsp; You know, and the Michigan delegation that&#8217;s here today: Debbie Stabenow; Senator Gary Peters; Congresswoman Debbie Dingell, who is automobiles; and Dan Kildee.</p>



<p>But I want you all to know &#8212; I remind the Michigan delegation of this: It used to be, when I was first got elected, Deb &#8212; and I used to tell your husband this well &#8212; we had a higher percentage of autoworkers in Delaware than any state in the Union, including &#8212; including Michigan.&nbsp; Now, the fact we that we had a very small population and we &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and we had almost 100,000 autoworkers in our states, counting the Autolite and others had something to do with it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I &#8212; I just want to be very straightforward.&nbsp; You know, UAW “brung me to the dance,” as they say.</p>



<p>And I also know we’re missing someone truly special and a dear friend of all of us &#8212; Senator Carl Levin, who passed away last week.&nbsp; Carl and I served together for 30 years in the United States Senate together.&nbsp; He was one of the most &#8212; and I think all my colleagues who knew him will attest to this &#8212; one of the most honorable people, most decent people I’ve not only served with but I’ve ever known.<br><br>He was a tireless champion of the American worker and the iconic American automobile industry.&nbsp; And so he embodied everything that his beloved Michigan and our country represents: respect, dignity, pride –- pride in the nation and pride in what we built.</p>



<p>And so, today, labor and industry, state and local leaders are all working together to write the next chapter of the American story.</p>



<p>As I’ve said before, we’re in competition with China and many other nations for the 21st century.&nbsp; To win, we’re going to have to make sure the future will be made in America.</p>



<p>You know, back in May, I toured the Ford plant, as I mentioned &#8212; a state-of-the-art facility in Dearborn &#8212; where the UAW workers like Bernie are building the first-ever all-electric Ford 150 [F-150].&nbsp; And as I said, the best part is, I got to drive it.&nbsp; It’s incredible, just like the other vehicles that are behind me today.&nbsp; They’re a vision of the future that is now beginning to happen, a future of the automobile industry that is electric &#8212; battery electric, plug-in hybrid electric, fuel cell electric.&nbsp; It’s electric, and there’s no turning back.</p>



<p>The question is whether we’ll lead or fall behind in the race for the future.&nbsp; It’s whether we’ll build these vehicles and the batteries that got them to where they are in the United States &#8212; here in the United States, or we’re going to have to rely on other countries for those batteries.&nbsp; Whether or not the jobs to build these vehicles and batteries are good-paying union jobs &#8212; jobs with benefits, jobs that’s going to sustain continued growth of the middle class.&nbsp; They have to be.&nbsp; They have to be made here in America.</p>



<p>Right now, China is leading the race, and is one of the largest and fastest-growing electric vehicle markets in the world.</p>



<p>And a key part of the electric vehicle &#8212; to state the obvious &#8212; is the battery.&nbsp; And right now, 80 percent of the manufacturing capacity for these batteries is done in China.</p>



<p>And here’s the deal: It’s not that China batter- &#8212; it’s not China’s battery technology that’s much more innovative than anyone else’s.&nbsp; Remember, our national labs in America, our universities, our automakers led in the development of this technology.&nbsp; We led in the development of this technology.&nbsp; And there’s no reason why we can’t reclaim that leadership and lead again.&nbsp; But we just have to move, and we have to move fast.</p>



<p>You know, when Barack and I were in office &#8212; President Obama and I were in office &#8212; that’s what we were doing.&nbsp;<br><br>In 2009, the automobile industry was flat on its back.&nbsp; We were told that we’d never be able to sell American-made cars at the same rate as we did before.&nbsp; But we didn’t listen to the naysayers.&nbsp; We even had some &#8212; in all &#8212; in both parties who didn’t think we should, quote, “bail out” the industry, if you remember.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, we bet on the American worker.&nbsp; And we extended a lifeline.&nbsp; And they stepped up and made sacrifices to do it, and they saved more than &#8212; we saved more than a million jobs in the process.</p>



<p>Working with the auto industry, we set fuel efficiency standards and provided incentives for folks to buy fuel-efficient vehicles.</p>



<p>Through the Recovery Act, we made the largest investment in clean energy and battery technology ever made.&nbsp; And then the previous administration came along into office, and they rolled back the standards we set.</p>



<p>Despite bipartisan support for consumer incentives, they also let the federal tax credit expire, penalizing autoworkers who were, at the time, selling the most electric vehicles in the world &#8212; in the United States.</p>



<p>They announced infrastru- &#8212; when we &#8212; they announced infrastructure week, they did it for every week for four years, and not once got anything done.&nbsp; Not once.</p>



<p>Folks, the rest of the world is moving ahead, and we’ve just got to step up: government, labor, and industry working together &#8212; what you&#8217;re seeing here today.&nbsp; We have a playbook, and it’s going to work.</p>



<p>Today, I’m announcing steps we’re taking to set a new pace for electric vehicles.</p>



<p>First, I&#8217;m following through on the campaign commitment to reverse the previous administration’s short-sighted rollback of vehicle emissions and efficiency standards.&nbsp; I’m doing so and &#8212; with the support of the auto industry &#8212; the automobile industry.</p>



<p>Today, the Environmental Protection Agency and the Department of Transportation are unveiling proposals to do just that.</p>



<p>These agencies are beginning to work on the next round of standards for a broad class of vehicles &#8212; for cars, SUVs,&nbsp;pick-up trucks, medium- and heavy-duty vehicles.</p>



<p>Importantly, we have announcements today from automakers representing nearly the entire auto industry market who have pos- &#8212; who have positioned around the ambition that of 40 to 50 percent of all vehicles sold by 2030 in America being electric.</p>



<p>This is a big deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But to unlock the full potential, we have to keep investing in our workers and our manufacturing capacity.&nbsp; And that’s what our Build Back Better plan is all about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s about leveraging once-in-a-generation investments and a whole-of-government effort to lift up American autoworkers</p>



<p>and strengthen &#8212; and strengthen the American leadership</p>



<p>in the world in the clean car technology &#8212; trucks &#8212; not just cars, but trucks as well, and buses.</p>



<p>You know, that’s why, today, I’m signing an executive order setting out a target of 50 percent of all passenger vehicles sold by 2030 will be electric and set into motion an all-out effort.</p>



<p>That’s why, along with the members of Congress here today,</p>



<p>we’re working around the clock on the Build Back Better plan, which does three critical things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One, it transforms our infrastructure.&nbsp; We’re going to put Americans to work modernizing our roads, our highways, our ports, our airports, rail, and transit systems.</p>



<p>You know, that included putting IBEW members and other union workers to work installing a national network of</p>



<p>500,000 charging stations along our roads and highways and at our homes and our apartments.</p>



<p>Two, we’re going to boost our manufacturing capacity.&nbsp; The Build Back Better plan invests in new rooted [sic] facilities &#8212; excuse me, new and retooled facilities; and employs workers</p>



<p>with good-paying wages, good jobs.; and grants &#8212; the grants that kickstart new battery and parts production; loans and tax credits to boost manufacturing of these clean vehicles.</p>



<p>And our Build Back pletter [sic] &#8212; Build Back Better plan</p>



<p>makes the largest investment in research and development in generations.</p>



<p>This will help innovate, manufacture, and build the supply chains for batteries, semi-conductors, and those small computer chips that electric trucks and cars that are going to be even more reliant upon as we move forward.</p>



<p>Never again should we be in the situation we face today with a semiconductor shortage.&nbsp; And we know these kinds of federal investments &#8212; we know that they work.</p>



<p>It was the Defense Department and NASA that got the modern semi-conductor industry on its feet decades ago.&nbsp; Our own Department of Energy pioneered and transformed the battery industry where Barack and I &#8212; when we went into off- &#8212; when we were in office.</p>



<p>And with the help of the Recovery Act grants and loans, battery prices dropped 85 percent because we were forward-looking.</p>



<p>We need that same mindset today.</p>



<p>Thirdly, support of consumers and fleets.&nbsp; That means purchasing incentives for consumers to buy clean vehicles,</p>



<p>union-made right here in America, like the ones championed by Debbie Stabenow and Ron Wyden in the Senate, which provides</p>



<p>$7,500 basic credit, $2,500 credit for vehicles made in America, and an additional $2,500 credit for union-made vehicles.</p>



<p>That means spurring demand by converting the federal government’s enormous fleet of vehicles &#8212; we have over 600,000 vehi- &#8212; a lot of vehicles &#8212; 600,000, I should say &#8212; into an all American-made clean vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that’s what we’re going to do.&nbsp; As we &#8212; as we roll out and get rid of the existing fleet, we’re going to support the electric transit system as well and the electric school buses.</p>



<p>Look, and there’s one other thing we have in our playbook that will help us outcompete other nations: The American worker.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;The American worker.&nbsp; I really believe this, and I know you guys do too.&nbsp; American workers are our ace in the deck.</p>



<p>Now, I know many of you watching at home are like the folks I grew up with in Scranton and Claymont, Delaware.&nbsp; They feel left out, left behind in an economy and in an industry that’s rapidly changing.&nbsp; I get it.&nbsp; I understand it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we’re going to leave no one behind.&nbsp; Nearly 90 percent of the jobs created in our infrastructure plan do not require a bachelor’s degree.&nbsp; And when we invest in our infrastructure, we’re going to buy American products, American materials, and services from American businesses made in America, by American workers.</p>



<p>And we’re going to do everything in our power to encourage and protect the right of workers to unionize and collectively bargain.&nbsp; The bottom line is, we are proposing a blue-collar blueprint to rebuild America.</p>



<p>That’s what it’s going to be.&nbsp; And we need automakers and other companies to keep investing in America.&nbsp; We need them not to take the benefits of our public investments and expand electric vehicles and battery manufacturing production abroad.&nbsp; We need you to deepen your partnership with the UAW, continue to pay good wages, support local communities across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why I’m so proud the UAW is standing here today as well.&nbsp; It’s why I am proud that the three largest employers are sitting here and their sights are set not only on electric vehicles, but on expansion &#8212; expanding union jobs, expanding the middle class.&nbsp; It matters.</p>



<p>You know, in the spring, I kept my commitment to convene leaders of all the major economies in the world on &#8212; it was not in person, but we did it &#8212; we did it on a Zoom call with a whole bunch of folks &#8212;&nbsp; including the heads of state of China, India, Japan, the European Union &#8212; for a meeting hosted in the White House on the most consequential issues facing the world, and the agreement was, it’s the climate crisis.</p>



<p>And I made clear &#8212; I made clear what I’ve long believed when I think of &#8212; when I think of the climate crisis: Beyond the devastation to the lives and livelihoods and the health of our very planet, when I hear “climate,” I think “jobs” &#8212; good-paying union jobs.</p>



<p>I wanted the world to see there was a consensus that all &#8212; that we’re at an inflection point in world history.&nbsp; If we act to save the planet, we can also come out of it better.&nbsp; We can create millions of good-paying jobs that generate significant economic growth and opportunity, to raise the standard of living for people not only here, but around the world.</p>



<p>But I also wanted to put the world on notice: America is back.&nbsp; America is back.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’re in the competition for the 21st century &#8212; the future that will be built right here in America.</p>



<p>Let me close with this: Our economy is recovering.&nbsp; In six months, we’re seeing the fastest job growth on record at this point in any administration in history, the fastest economic growth in nearly 40 years.&nbsp; And we’ve shown each other and the world that there’s no quit in America.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; And that it’s never, ever, ever been a good bet to bet against America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are the United States of America.&nbsp; There is not a single, solitary thing &#8212; nothing &#8212; beyond our capacity to get done, if we and when we do it together.&nbsp; But we have to act.&nbsp; And that’s what we are doing today.</p>



<p>And again, I want to thank the CEOs of the automobile companies, and I also want to thank all the autoworkers.&nbsp; Thank you all for being here today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now I am going to sign the executive order, but I’d like to invite my congressional colleagues to come up &#8212; if they’re willing to stand behind me here when we do this &#8212; and others who know they’re supposed to come on up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>Now, when I sign &#8212; it’s so bright &#8212; when I sign this executive order, usually I am able to give a pen to all the folks who are a part of it.&nbsp; I’ve got one pen, but I’m going to make sure you each &#8212;</p>



<p>SENATOR STABENOW:&nbsp; Uh-oh.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>REPRESENTATIVE KILDEE:&nbsp; We’re going to fight for it.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You each are going to get a pen &#8212; I promise you.</p>



<p>This is an executive order strengthening America’s leadership in clean cars and trucks.&nbsp; And again, let me start off by thanking the CEOs, as well as the UAW.&nbsp; You all &#8212; all you elected are the reason why it’s happening, man.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>(The executive order is signed.)</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>(The President rides in an electric vehicle.)</p>



<p>(The President returns and answers questions from the press.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When was the last time you drove?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How did it feel, Mr. President?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you like it better than the Lightning, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It feels great, because, you know, you sit there &#8212; first of all, you don’t hear a thing.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Number one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I try?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s not mine yet.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What do you think about these breathalyzers that are going in the cars nowadays?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Pardon me?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The bill that’s coming up, making breathalyzers for vehicles in a couple of years mandatory?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s a good idea, by the way.&nbsp; I think.&nbsp; I think that’s a good idea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tell me why.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because in large part it just helps the driver, because lots of times people have a couple of drinks and don’t realize (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s thousands of cars in lots around the country lacking chips, Mr. President.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know they are.&nbsp; That’s why we’re &#8212; we’re going to invest billions of dollars in bringing chip manufacturing to the United States &#8212; a bipartisan effort that we’ve gotten done.&nbsp; It’s going to work.&nbsp; Because we can’t afford &#8212;&nbsp;we &#8212; for example, we got the chairman of the board of Ford here somewhere &#8212; they had to slow down production because of the lack of chips.&nbsp; It’s a gigantic, gigantic issue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a response to Governor DeSantis who was using your words about “don’t be in the way,” and he’s saying, “I am in the way” to block too much interference from the federal government?&nbsp; Your response, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Governor who?&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; DeSantis.</p>



<p>(Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s my response.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How did California’s 2019 framework influence the executive order that you signed today?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I think the framework was really helpful.&nbsp; And the reason I say that is that, you know, initially, the industry was opposed to it.&nbsp; And we literally sat over in the EEOB and I had five of the largest corporations in America, with Mary Barra representing General Motors down the street.&nbsp; And you’ve been there with me when I’ve done this.&nbsp; And five major labor unions.</p>



<p>And when it was all over, Mary Barra called and said, “I’m going to withdraw the suit against California.”&nbsp; They were suing California.&nbsp; To say, “You can’t have a higher standard than the rest of the nation,” which was what, you know, the last President did.&nbsp; He lowered the (inaudible) standard.</p>



<p>And she said, “I’m going to get &#8212; I’m going to drop the suit, and I’m going to go electric.”&nbsp; And we got the IBEW involved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the biggest thing that’s happening here is there’s a realization, on the part of both labor and business now, that this is the future.&nbsp; We can’t sit by.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Think about the battery technology.&nbsp; Most of that research and development occurred with United States taxpayers’ dollars from the Department of Energy, the DOD, here in the United States.&nbsp; And we didn’t take advantage of it.&nbsp; We didn’t move on it.&nbsp; China moved, and China now owns the market.&nbsp; So we just got to get back in the game.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How is the eviction moratorium constitutional, sir?&nbsp; How is it constitutional?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How is the eviction moratorium constitutional, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think it is.&nbsp; But there’s a call &#8212; there are a number of constitutional scholars &#8212; I spoke to a lot of constitutional scholars.&nbsp; Let me explain the last &#8212; the last time why I did what I did.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My greatest concern is &#8212; I have three concerns.&nbsp; One, we have $45 billion sitting in the state treasuries right now that were designed specifically to help landlords be able to not have to go bankrupt so that they &#8212; and keep those renters who couldn’t afford to pay their rent because of the pandemic, because of unemployment being as bad as it was since the Great Depression.</p>



<p>We gave it to the states and localities to be able to keep renters in their homes, as well as &#8212; as well as being able to continue to keep their business going.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Court ruled by &#8212; and made it very clear &#8212; the Supreme Court said, “You can&#8217;t do that.&nbsp; You don’t have the authority to do that.”&nbsp; And &#8212; although it was a 5-to-4 decision.&nbsp; I got on the phone and contacted a number of constitutional scholars I&#8217;ve relied on for years, beyond my own team, and there was a split.&nbsp; And the consensus of the folks that I have used the most said, “We think it is &#8212; you have the authority to do it, but, in this court, who knows.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last point I’ll make: So, what I decided to do, I did not tell the CDC.&nbsp; I made a commitment to you all I would not tell the CDC what they should do, and I would not tell the Justice Department who they should prosecute.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve kept that commitment.</p>



<p>So I asked the CDC to go back and take another look at was there anything possible and check with the legal scholars as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Now, wait a minute.&nbsp; They went back and they concluded that if we had a completely different (inaudible) &#8212; we did not try to continue the existing moratorium; it was a different moratorium with another rationale.&nbsp; The rationale was that because of the COVID spread of the virus so rapidly, that &#8212; and the Delta COVID &#8212; what happened was they said: All those &#8212; all those counties that, in fact, are in a situation where they are in that red zone, that they &#8212; we should hold for another month &#8212; or I think they said two months &#8212; the ability to evict people from those facilities.&nbsp; And I said, “Okay, thank you.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I went ahead and did it, but here&#8217;s the deal: I can&#8217;t guarantee you the Court won&#8217;t rule if we don&#8217;t have that authority, but at least we&#8217;ll have the ability, if we have to appeal, to keep this going for a month at least &#8212; I hope longer than that.&nbsp; And in the process, by that time, we&#8217;ll get a lot of (inaudible).</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>4:00 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
