<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 20:23:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the National Parent Teacher Association&#8217;s 125th Anniversary&#160;Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-national-parent-teacher-associations-125th-anniversary-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 19:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gaylord National Resort &#38; Convention CenterFort Washington, Maryland 10:14 A.M. EDT THE FIRST LADY: &#160;Thank you. &#160;Thank you so much. &#160;Thank you. &#160;Where are you, Delaware? &#160; AUDIENCE MEMBER: &#160;Right here! THE FIRST LADY: &#160;(Laughs.) &#160;Please, thank you. &#160;Thank you so much.&#160; I don&#8217;t know why she was so nervous. &#160;She should just think of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Gaylord National Resort &amp; Convention Center<br>Fort Washington, Maryland</p>



<p>10:14 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY: &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;Thank you so much. &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;Where are you, Delaware? &nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER: &nbsp;Right here!</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY: &nbsp;(Laughs.) &nbsp;Please, thank you. &nbsp;Thank you so much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t know why she was so nervous. &nbsp;She should just think of me like her English teacher. &nbsp;(Laughter.) &nbsp;</p>



<p>And thank you, President King. &nbsp;Anna, you know, I’m so grateful for your leadership. &nbsp;And President-elect Johnson, as a &#8212; (applause) &#8212; as a fellow Delawarean, I’m proud that you are representing our state.</p>



<p>So, good morning.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE: &nbsp;Good morning!</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY: &nbsp;Wow. &nbsp;I love that. &nbsp;I love that energy this early in the morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m honored to be with all of you today. &nbsp;For 125 years, the PTA has been an incredibly effective champion for our nation’s students.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;You’ve worked to create child labor laws and kindergarten classes, and better public health services. &nbsp;And I have been grateful for the chance to partner with you to better support military kids through Joining Forces. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe that your success can be traced back to your roots &#8212; the values of your three founding mothers: Alice, Phoebe, and Selena. &nbsp;See, I read your website. &nbsp;You didn’t know that, did you? &nbsp;(Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>They believed that children deserve better than the status quo. &nbsp;And they understood that the best way to win that change was by harnessing the love, passion, and persistence of the people who care most about our kids &#8212; their parents and educators. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like your founders and many of you here, I am both a mother and a teacher. &nbsp;So, I know how personal your fight is, and I know how powerful this partnership can be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that’s why I’ve been frustrated by those who have tried to divide us in these last few years. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;From reopening schools to class curriculum, we’ve been told that parents and teachers are at odds. &nbsp;</p>



<p>But as I visit schools and meet with families, that’s not what I’ve seen.</p>



<p>I’ve seen parents and educators working more closely than ever, finding new ways to support students through the challenges of virtual learning.</p>



<p>I’ve seen teachers and counselors who check in on struggling parents, and families calling for better pay for our educators. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as my husband worked to get the American Rescue Plan passed and as we got millions of Americans vaccinated and made sure that schools could reopen safely, parents and educators were our best advocates and closest partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is no divide between those who love our students and those who teach them, because we all do! &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Parents, we know that we are our children’s first teachers. &nbsp;And, educators, we choose this path because we love what we do and who we teach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together, we can lead the change that our children need. &nbsp;In fact, right now, we must.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Because even as our schools are reopened, we know that recovery isn’t always the same as healing. &nbsp;Our students are still wrestling with the aftershocks of this pandemic &#8212; the isolation, anxiety, and sorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I hear it so much: Parents who are worried that their kids are having a hard time, you know, catching up after learning virtually. &nbsp;Educators who tell me that they’re burned out. &nbsp;Students who are dealing with the trauma of loss and grief.</p>



<p>Joe and his team are working hard to ensure that students have the mental health and academic support they need and to keep them safe. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;Because safety is always on our minds and especially right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Three weeks ago, Joe and I stood before the 21 crosses at Uvalde. &nbsp;I touched the pictures of the bright, beautiful faces that would never again laugh or open birthday presents or tell their parents that they loved them. &nbsp;And I laid down white roses on a sea of colorful flowers, the offerings of a town broken by grief, just as I had done in Buffalo, New York, one week before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a teacher, I’ve imagined that scene in my own classroom again and again. &nbsp;You know, at the start of each semester &#8212; I&#8217;m sure all of you in here who are teachers do this &#8212; you explain to your students of the first day a path &#8212; a pathway to get out if a shooter comes into the school so that they&#8217;re prepared.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I explain it to my students because, you know, they need to know what they should do if the worst happens. &nbsp;And though I now go to work with the Secret Service, I have often wondered over the years &#8212; and it’s true; you know, this is my thirty- &#8212; I think I&#8217;m going into my 38th year of teaching. &nbsp;(Laughs.) &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I wondered over the years if my students would be the next heartbreaking headline. &nbsp;All of you in here who are in the classroom know this. &nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Congress did not act after Columbine, after Sandy Hook, after Parkland. &nbsp;Nothing changed. &nbsp;And nothing will change unless we change it. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; Joe has called on Congress to pass commonsense gun safety reform &#8212; (applause) &#8212; things that the majority of Americans want. &nbsp;And a bipartisan group of senators have come up with a plan to address gun violence. &nbsp;And it would be the most significant gun safety legislation to pass Congress in decades, and with bipartisan support.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;There are no excuses. &nbsp;It’s up to Congress to act. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;And they represent the will of the people. &nbsp;And that’s why we need the people to speak up &#8212; parents and teachers, all of us. &nbsp;We need to fight now for the lives of our children and for the safety of our schools.</p>



<p>So let me say again: This partnership of parents and educators is powerful. &nbsp;You, together, are powerful. &nbsp;Because you have to be. &nbsp;Because when it comes to mental health or learning resources or safe schools, you see what’s at stake every day in the eyes of the people you love.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Your children need you to act, and I know you would do anything for your kids. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So thank you, all of you, for being here. &nbsp;Thank you for showing up for your children and for students across this country. &nbsp;Thank you for using your voice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together, we can change our future. &nbsp;We can. &nbsp;And we have to protect our children and make our schools work for everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, PTA, I am honored to stand with you. &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;END &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;10:24 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration’s Progress Addressing the Infant Formula&#160;Shortage</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administrations-progress-addressing-the-infant-formula-shortage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 19:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, June 17th, Vice President Harris will travel to Dulles International Airport to announce the arrival of over 14,000 pounds of Kendamil infant formula—the equivalent of more than 200,000 8-ounce bottles of formula—that will be used to add more supply to shelves. This shipment is the latest through the Biden-Harris Administration’s Operation Fly Formula,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, June 17<sup>th</sup>, Vice President Harris will travel to Dulles International Airport to announce the arrival of over 14,000 pounds of Kendamil infant formula—the equivalent of more than 200,000 8-ounce bottles of formula—that will be used to add more supply to shelves. This shipment is the latest through the Biden-Harris Administration’s <strong><u>Operation Fly Formula</u></strong>, a multi-agency partnership through which the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) ship infant formula so it can get to store shelves faster.&nbsp;<br><br>By this week’s end, Operation Fly Formula will have delivered the equivalent of 13 million 8-oz bottles since its inception—4 million of which were delivered this week alone. The shipment that the Vice President announces on Friday was donated by United Airlines and constitutes just one of ten international shipments of baby formula facilitated through Operation Fly Formula for the week of June 13<sup>th</sup>, which also include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>June 13:</strong> A United Airlines flight arrived at Dulles International Airport from London Heathrow carrying Kendamil infant formula.</li><li><strong>June 14:</strong> Two United Airlines flights arrived at Dulles International Airport from London Heathrow carrying Kendamil infant formula.</li><li><strong>June 15:</strong> A United Airlines flight arrived at Dulles International Airport from London Heathrow carrying Kendamil infant formula.</li><li><strong>June 16:</strong> A flight arrived in Columbus, OH, from Melbourne, Australia, carrying Bub’s Australia infant formula. And, a flight arrived in Louisville, Kentucky from Switzerland carrying medical specialty infant formula from Nestlé.</li><li><strong>June 18:</strong> A United Airlines flight will arrive at Dulles International Airport from London Heathrow carrying Kendamil infant formula.</li><li><strong>June 19:</strong> Two United Airlines flights will arrive at Dulles International Airport from London Heathrow carrying Kendamil infant formula.</li></ul>



<p>Operation Fly Formula represents just one component of the Biden-Harris Administration’s multi-pronged approach to ensuring families are able to access safe baby formula. While there is more work to do, these successes have meant more product on shelves and fewer families in need.<br><br><u><em><strong>Additional Actions Taken to Get Formula Back on Shelves and Increase the Supply of Infant Formula Quickly and Safely</strong></em></u><em><br></em><br>The Administration is executing an all-of-government approach to produce more infant formula and get it on the shelf. The federal government—including the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), Department of Agriculture (USDA), Department of Justice (DOJ), Department of Transportation (DOT), U.S. Trade Representative (USTR), Department of Homeland Security (DHS), Department of Commerce (DOC), Department of Defense (DoD), and the White House—has worked around the clock to address the shortfall in infant formula production while the Sturgis plant remains offline. The recent actions described below build upon the prior actions taken by FDA and USDA to address this shortage at its earliest stages.</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Invoking the Defense Production Act:</u></strong> To ensure that manufacturers have the necessary ingredients to make safe, healthy infant formula here at home, President Biden has invoked authorities under the Defense Production Act (DPA). The DPA empowers the government to require suppliers to direct needed resources to infant formula manufacturers before any other customer who may have ordered that good. The Administration has already invoked this authority to direct firms to prioritize and allocate the production of key infant formula inputs like raw materials, formula ingredients and bottling and packaging materials. This will continue to help manufacturers increase production and speed up supply chains. To date, the President’s invocation of the DPA has resulted in three priority orders:<ul><li>Abbott Nutrition receiving priority orders of raw materials like sugar and corn syrup for infant formula, enabling a planned 25% increase production so they can manufacture at 100% capacity.</li><li>Reckitt receiving priority orders for consumables like single-use products such as filters, which Reckitt expects will allow the company to expand production by 40%.&nbsp;</li><li>Cargill Inc. receiving priority on materials such as corn products, sweeteners, and oils to maximize production of formula.&nbsp;</li></ul></li><li><strong><u>Cutting Red Tape to Increase Imports:</u></strong> The FDA is cutting red tape to increase the supply of safe, high-quality formula through increased imports. The FDA, with import inspection support from USDA and Customs and Border Protection (CBP), is encouraging infant formula manufacturers worldwide to take advantage of these flexibilities, and will continue to actively work with USDA, the UK, Australia, New Zealand, Singapore, and European authorities to expedite entry for products made abroad, and FDA. The Administration has thus far approved nine applications, representing over 210 million 8-ounce equivalent bottles eligible and committed for import, including:<ul><li>Bubs Australia will provide at least 1.25 million cans of several varieties of its infant formula from Melbourne, Australia, which will make at least 27.5 million 8-ounce bottles.</li><li>Kendal Nutricare will provide at least 58 million bottle-equivalents of its routine infant formula from the UK.</li><li>Nestle will provide approximately 33 million bottle-equivalents of Gerber Good Start Gentle formula from Mexico.</li><li>Nutricia (Danone) will provide 5 million bottle-equivalents of its Neocate Infant DHA/ARA specialty formula from the UK.</li></ul></li><li><strong><u>Facilitating WIC Waivers for Families in Need:</u></strong> Earlier this month, the President called on WIC state agencies that were not yet taking full advantage of the of flexibilities available in WIC to act immediately to adopt any waivers that could help those they serve. Since then, all 50 states have acted, allowing greater flexibility for WIC families to get the formula they need. &nbsp;Additionally, thanks to Congress’ quick action, USDA will also have added flexibility to waive rules and allow WIC participants to purchase multiple brands of formula during supply chain disruptions or other crises. This new legislation will also require formula companies to demonstrate they have a plan in place to respond to an infant formula recall, including how they would prevent shortages.</li><li><strong><u>Getting the Abbott Facility Reopened Safely:</u></strong> This past February, the largest infant formula manufacturer in the country—Abbott Nutrition—initiated a voluntary recall of several lines of powdered formula. This came after concerns about bacterial contamination at Abbott’s Sturgis, Michigan, facility after four infants fell ill and two died. The Sturgis plant closed as a result of the contamination. Since then FDA has entered into a consent decree with Abbott to ensure its facility can reopen safely. FDA is working with Abbott to ensure that the product manufactured at the Sturgis plant is safe for families.&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Cracking Down on Price Gouging:</u></strong><strong> </strong>The DOJ is engaging with state attorneys general to encourage them to use their powers to monitor and address price gouging in the infant formula market, and urging them to devote more resources to monitoring predatory behavior in the market for infant formula, which states like New Jersey have recently announced. In addition, following President Biden’s call for the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to use all its available tools to monitor and investigate reports of illegal and predatory conduct, the FTC launched an inquiry into the ongoing shortage for infant formula including examining deceptive, fraudulent, or otherwise unfair business practices that take advantage of families.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before a Conversation on Historic Investments to Remove and Replace Lead&#160;Pipes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-a-conversation-on-historic-investments-to-remove-and-replace-lead-pipes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 19:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Community Empowerment AssociationPittsburgh, Pennsylvania THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, let me just start by saying thank you all for the &#8212; for this meeting and for this conversation.  Secretary Fudge and I have been &#8212; together with Administrator Regan from the EPA &#8212; have been working on this issue for quite some time, thinking about it deeply&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Community Empowerment Association<br><em>Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, let me just start by saying thank you all for the &#8212; for this meeting and for this conversation. <br> <br>Secretary Fudge and I have been &#8212; together with Administrator Regan from the EPA &#8212; have been working on this issue for quite some time, thinking about it deeply in terms of the significance and the seriousness of it and the impact in terms of what we&#8217;re doing to fix it. <br> <br>In fact, the Administrator and I have been on what we call a roadshow &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; going around the country, talking about lead pipes. <br> <br>And so, it&#8217;s good to be back in Pittsburgh.  And it&#8217;s good to be back with you, as leaders, to think about how we can continue to get the word out about the rights that people in the community have to expect this is going to be handled with a sense of urgency, with a sense of speed, and also to talk about why it is important in terms of &#8212;<br> <br>You know, there are, I think, three principles at play, really.  You know, there&#8217;s the piece that is about equity &#8212; right? &#8212; which is literally different communities are &#8212; are dealing with this differently based on what resources they have.  And that shouldn&#8217;t be the case. <br> <br>It&#8217;s an issue that is obviously about public health, in terms of the harm. <br> <br>And then there&#8217;s the issue, because of the harm that is &#8212; that makes it an issue, that’s also about education, meaning: Can our babies learn if they&#8217;re drinking toxic water?  Right?<br> <br>So that&#8217;s why they&#8217;re here: to have this conversation with you and &#8212; and to highlight the work that that the Secretary and the Administrator are doing through the agencies and on behalf of our administration to finally deal with this issue in a substantial way and see it through in terms of what we know can be done when we prioritize it.<br> <br>So, with that, I thank you all.  And we&#8217;ll begin our discussion now. <br> <br> END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration’s Historic Investments to Remove and Replace Lead&#160;Pipes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-biden-harris-administrations-historic-investments-to-remove-and-replace-lead-pipes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 19:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55837</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Community Empowerment AssociationPittsburgh, Pennsylvania 1:51 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone.  Good afternoon.  Kim, I want to thank you for that.  We had a wonderful conversation with Hanna, who I think is out here &#8212; there&#8217;s Hanna &#8212; and Gwendolyn.  And I just want to thank the leaders here in Pittsburgh, in Pennsylvania, for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Community Empowerment Association<br><em>Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</em></em></p>



<p>1:51 P.M. EDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone.  Good afternoon.  Kim, I want to thank you for that.  We had a wonderful conversation with Hanna, who I think is out here &#8212; there&#8217;s Hanna &#8212; and Gwendolyn.  And I just want to thank the leaders here in Pittsburgh, in Pennsylvania, for the work that you’ve been doing on this issue. <br><br>I’m honored to be traveling with Secretary Marcia Fudge, with Administrator Michael Regan to highlight the work that is happening in local communities like Pittsburgh, which are models of what can and will happen around the country.<br><br>In large part, the work that we are doing is in response to the advocacy that has been coming out of leaders, like the leaders here in Pittsburgh, for years, who have been demanding that we prioritize this as an issue, have been demanding that we put the resources in that are reflective of a priority, and that we do the work in a way that is collaborative with local leaders, local elected officials, with community leaders, knowing that the work that we do together will have profound impact when we are coordinated.<br><br>So I want to thank everyone who was here for the work that you have been doing for years.  We came to Pittsburgh to talk about you here in your backyard, but then to talk about you around the country as a model of what can be done around the country.<br><br>So, Secretary Fudge, Administrator Regan, I want to thank you for traveling with me.  Congressman Lamb, thank you for your leadership.  I&#8217;ve seen you and Congressman Doyle, the work that you do in Washington, D.C., representing the people of this district so, so well and so strongly.  And again, Kim, thank you for that.<br><br>So, basically, we come at this issue from probably an obvious perspective, which is that we believe, the President &#8212; President Joe Biden and I, our administration &#8212; we all believe that all people have a right to be able to drink clean water, that all people have a right to breathe clean air.<br><br>So we approach this from that perspective, which is that we as a society and certainly as a government must ensure that that right is real and that it is protected.<br><br>On the issue, then, of lead pipes, we know that up to 10 million homes in our country have lead pipes that are feeding the water that flows in their home.  We know that when it comes to lead paint, we&#8217;re looking at at least 24 million homes that have lead paint.  And those are the numbers that have been reported.<br>One of the things that, Kim, that we talked about was there are plenty of folks who live in homes, whether they&#8217;re renters or owners, that may be unaware that there is lead in their paint or in the pipe.<br> <br>And so, again, that highlights the importance of what&#8217;s happening here in Pittsburgh, which it is not only about addressing the issue in terms of amelioration and mitigation, but addressing the issue in terms of doing the first step, which is public education about the seriousness of the issue and the need, then, to address the harm that the issue creates.  And to do that, what we must do as government and together, collectively, to allow homeowners to become aware if their paint contains lead or their pipes are flowing with lead, in terms of the water that then goes into their home.<br> <br>So the work we are doing together includes public education; it includes speaking loudly about what we must do to let people know about their rights and about the harm.<br> <br>So, the harm &#8212; let&#8217;s talk about that.  We talked with, for example, Gwendolyn, who runs a childcare center, about the realities of lead poisoning that includes creating developmental issues for our children; learning disabilities can result from drinking toxic water.  And it&#8217;s basically poison, when we talk about lead in water or in paint.<br> <br>We have talked about what it means in terms of the harm to adults.  It can increase blood pressure.  It can decrease kidney function.  These are real harms that are created because of the lead in paint or in pipes.<br> <br>So then there is the issue that is about public education.  And part of that is, again, about what we will do with the $50 billion that the President, that our administration, together with our Congress members &#8212; and these two Congress members, in particular &#8212; what we have done to put $50 billion into the amelioration of lead in paint and in pipes.<br> <br>That money will go to a number of things: public education; it will go toward what the local governments can do to facilitate testing, at-home tests, things of that nature; and it will go to the removal, then, of lead pipes.<br> <br>Let&#8217;s think about why this is important and why government has a responsibility here.  Lead pipes existed in many communities.  But the disparities exist when a particular community and the members of that community don&#8217;t have the personal resources, the private resources to remove the lead pipes.<br> <br>So there are communities that have the resources, individuals that have the resources to do it on their own.  But if you&#8217;re working three jobs, if you&#8217;re working minimum wage, if you&#8217;re barely getting by month to month, then you probably cannot afford the work that needs to get done to remove the lead.  That&#8217;s where government has a responsibility to kick in and help put the resources in so that we can remove the lead, understanding there are three issues that are at play here.<br> <br>One issue is the issue that is about equity.  All people have a right to drink clean water.  And so this should not be a function of how much money you have to pay to remove the lead from the pipes. <br> <br>It is an issue of public health.  We have talked about the damage to children, to adults, from drinking water that has lead. <br> <br>And then, three, this is an education issue.  This is literally an issue about the education of our children, because we know there&#8217;s a direct correlation between lead pipes and learning ability or disabilities based on the toxins that are present in that water.<br> <br>So I am proud to be joined with these leaders.  And I&#8217;m proud to be with you today to uplift the work that you are doing here in this community.  I thank you for that work.<br> <br>And again, this is a model of what we will be continuing to do around the country.  And again, this is an example of where community leadership influences what happens at the highest levels of our government.  And I do believe that, in that way, this is a success story in terms of the dedication and the commitment that we all have to getting this job done and seeing it through.<br> <br>And here in Pittsburgh, you, I think, are ahead of your timelines in terms of what you expect to get done to meet your timeline goals. <br> <br>And for the President and I, it is our full intention with our Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan to remove all lead pipes within 10 years.<br> <br>So with that, I thank you all, and let us continue to do the good work that we know will result in generational impact for the better.<br> <br>Thank you.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END                 1:59 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Marine One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 17:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 10:59 A.M. EDT Q    Mr. President, have you made a decision about how you will handle the Khashoggi killing when you go to Saudi Arabia? THE PRESIDENT:  The same way I’ve been handling it.  I’m not going to meet with &#8212; I’m not going to meet with MBS; I’m going to an international&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>10:59 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>Q    Mr. President, have you made a decision about how you will handle the Khashoggi killing when you go to Saudi Arabia?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The same way I’ve been handling it.  I’m not going to meet with &#8212; I’m not going to meet with MBS; I’m going to an international meeting.  And he’s going to be a part of it, just like there were people part of the discussion today.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, how concerned are you about the three Americans who are reportedly missing in Ukraine?  Have you been briefed?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I have been briefed.  We don’t know where they are.</p>



<p>But I want to reiterate: Americans should not be going to Ukraine now.&nbsp; I’ll say it again: Americans should not be going to Ukraine now.&nbsp; They should not be going to Ukraine.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What will the consequences be for oil companies if they don’t boost supplies?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, look, one of the things that has happened is that the price of gasoline exceeds the price based on the barrel of oil costs right now.&nbsp;&nbsp;So if you get &#8212; based on what a barrel of oil costs on average, it should not be this high.&nbsp; They’re making exorbitant profits &#8212; number one.</p>



<p>Number two, I’ve contacted them &#8212; my team has &#8212; to ask what their plans are and to give any suggestions they have.&nbsp; They have over 9,000 leases &#8212; 9,000.&nbsp; They can drill until they’re &#8212; until (inaudible) won’t have it.&nbsp; But they’re not doing it &#8212; number two.</p>



<p>Number three, I think we’re going to be in a position where we’re going to &#8211;</p>



<p>Oh.&nbsp; (The First Lady approaches the President.)</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; We got to go!</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) two billion people in India are waiting for you to visit India.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ve been to India twice, and I’ll be back to India.&nbsp; And my relations are very good.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>11:01 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the Major Economies Forum on Energy and&#160;Climate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-major-economies-forum-on-energy-and-climate/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 16:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55801</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[8:34 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, John.&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; And thank you for, whatever time zone you’re in, making the time to be here.&#160; I appreciate it very much.&#160;You know, we’re meeting today at a moment when &#8212; where there’s urgent global issues impacting all of our nations, demand our immed- &#8212; and they&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>8:34 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, John.&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; And thank you for, whatever time zone you’re in, making the time to be here.&nbsp; I appreciate it very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, we’re meeting today at a moment when &#8212; where there’s urgent global issues impacting all of our nations, demand our immed- &#8212; and they all demand our immediate action and our close cooperation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Russia’s brutal and unprovoked assault on its neighbor, Ukraine, has fueled a global energy crisis and has sharpened the need to achieve long-term, reliable energy security and stability.<br>&nbsp;<br>And with Russia’s war driving up inflation worldwide, threatening vulnerable countries with severe food shortages, we have to work together to mitigate the immediate fallout of this crisis.<br>&nbsp;<br>In the United States, I’m using every lever available to me to bring down prices for the American people.&nbsp; And our nations are working together to stabilize global energy markets, including coordinating the largest release from the global reserve &#8212; from global oil reserves in history.<br>&nbsp;<br>But the critical point is that these actions are part of our transition to a clean and secure long-term energy future. And the good news is climate security and energy security go hand in hand.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, back in March, the European Commission &#8212; with President von der Leyen leading the effort &#8212; and I announced the U.S.-EU Task Force on Energy Security to help the EU rapidly reduce its dependence on Russian gas and reduce the EU’s overall demand for gas by ramping up clean energy technologies.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ll bolster our energy security and improve the affordability and reliability of energy around the world and reduce our greenhouse gas emissions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Because we cannot &#8212; we cannot afford to let the critical goal of limiting global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius slip out of our reach.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the science tells us that the window for action is rapidly narrowing &#8212; rapidly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Glasgow was just the kickoff for a decade of ambition, action, and innovation.&nbsp; And we look toward COP27.&nbsp; We have to &#8212; we have to dedicate ourselves, as we look forward to it, to delivering on existing goals and undertaking additional efforts to boost our progress.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I urge these countries that &#8212; those countries that have not yet gone to set a 2030 emissions target to align with the Paris temperature goal, to strengthen their targets for COP27.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, we need new initiatives to accelerate our progress toward our goals and bolster our resilience.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here’s what the United States is proposing to maximize efficiency and reduce emissions across the energy, transportation, and agricultural sectors.&nbsp; I hope that many of you will &#8212; will join us in these efforts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>First, we should build upon the success of the Global Methane Pledge &#8212; now more than 115 countries strong.&nbsp; To do that, we’re announcing the Global Methane Pledge Emer- &#8212; excuse me &#8212; Energy Pathway to ramp up the speed at which we reduce methane leaks from the oil and gas sector, and also helping bridge our energy needs.<br>&nbsp;<br>Each year, our existing energy system leaks enough methane to meet the needs for the entire European power sector.&nbsp; We flare enough gas to offset nearly all of the EU’s gas imports from Russia.&nbsp; And so, by stopping the leaking and flaring of this super-potent greenhouse gas, and capturing this resource for countries that need it, we’re addressing two problems at once.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, we’re investing in innovation and hastening the scale-up of new technologies like carbon capture and advanced nuclear and clean hydrogen.&nbsp; The International Energy Agency says we need 90 billion dollars’ worth of demonstration projects for this decade.&nbsp; And thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that was passed here in the United States, we’re stepping up with a $21.5 billion contribution toward this goal.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, we’ve launched a multibillion-dollar effort to create hydrogen hubs all around the country.&nbsp; And using the Defense Production Act, in our system, to boost the manufacturing of electrolyzers, which are used to produce clean hydrogen.&nbsp; We’ve done &#8212; we’re doing both these things.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our Department of Energy also just issued a loan guarantee to construct one of the world’s largest clean hydrogen storage facilities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I challenge us, together, to hit the full $90 billion target by the Global Clean Energy Action Forum that the U.S. is hosting in September in Pittsburgh.<br>&nbsp;<br>Third, Russia’s war is driving up prices of gas &#8212; everybody knows that &#8212; hurting people in all our countries.&nbsp; It’s an immediate problem that I suspect all of you and I know I’m working every day.<br>&nbsp;<br>Over the long run, we can remove the pain of volatile gas prices and reduce transportation emissions by putting more zero-emission cars on the road.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In the United States, we’re building a nationwide network of 500,000 electric vehicle charging stations.&nbsp; We’re strengthening our supply chains for the critical materials that go into those batteries.&nbsp; And we’ve set a goal of ensuring that half of all passenger cars sold in the United States in 2020 will be zero &#8212; 2030, I should say &#8212; will be zero emission.&nbsp; I urge all of you to join us in a similar goal.<br>&nbsp;<br>Fourth, if ocean-based shipping were a country, it would be the eighth-largest emitter in the world.&nbsp; It’s critical we do more to promote zero-emission fuels and green shipping corridors in this sector.&nbsp; And it seems to me we ought to be able to do that.&nbsp; That’s why the United States and Norway are launching the Green Shipping Challenge to fully decarbonize shipping by 2050.<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, Russia’s war in Ukraine is worsening food insecurity, in part due to the skyrocketing price of fertilizer. Fertilizer production relies on natural gas, but more than 50 percent of nitrogen fertilizers are lost globally every year due to waste.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So today, the United States is launching a new Global Fertilizer Challenge.&nbsp; Let’s aim to raise at least $100 million toward increasing fertilizer efficiency and developing alternatives by COP27.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And to keep strengthening our adaptation efforts, this year, the United States is going to partner with Egypt on the Adaptation in Africa event to deliver concrete initiatives that are going to improve people’s lives and build resilience in &#8212; to a changing climate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These are all achievable goals, in my view.&nbsp; And if we all commit to doing our part, we’ll get it done.&nbsp; And if we do, we’ll unlock an incredible opportunities for all our people around the world: more growth, more innovation, more good-paying jobs that support working families, greater food security for communities around the world, and we’ll finally break our dependence on the volatile energy markets and high gas prices.<br>&nbsp;<br>So thank you all again for taking the time to &#8212; this morning, today, tonight &#8212; whatever the timeframe it is &#8212; for what &#8212; and joining us.&nbsp; So let’s keep this challenge &#8212; let&#8217;s keep doing what we &#8212; what we&#8217;ve been doing.&nbsp; Challenge ourselves to do more, because we can.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you all so very much for listening.&nbsp; I&#8217;m anxious to hear what you all have to say.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, John.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>8:42 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on FDA Authorization of the First COVID-&#8288;19 Vaccines for America’s Youngest&#160;Kids</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/statement-by-president-biden-on-fda-authorization-of-the-first-covid-19-vaccines-for-americas-youngest-kids/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 15:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today is a day of huge relief for parents and families across America. Following a rigorous scientific review, the Food and Drug Administration has authorized the first COVID-19 vaccines for kids under the age of five. As early as next week, pending recommendations from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), parents will finally be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today is a day of huge relief for parents and families across America. Following a rigorous scientific review, the Food and Drug Administration has authorized the first COVID-19 vaccines for kids under the age of five. As early as next week, pending recommendations from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), parents will finally be able to get their youngest kids the protection of a safe and effective COVID-19 vaccine.<br><br>We are the first country to protect our youngest children with COVID-19 vaccines, offering safe and highly effective mRNA doses to children as young as six months old. My administration secured vaccine doses for America’s youngest children and now with FDA’s authorization, we will begin shipping millions of vaccine doses for kids to thousands of locations parents know and trust—including pediatricians’ offices, children’s hospitals, and pharmacies. As doses are delivered, parents will be able to start scheduling vaccinations for their youngest kids as early as next week, with appointments ramping up over the coming days and weeks.<br><br>Thanks to my administration and partners across the country, we have come a long way in our fight against COVID these past 17 months. The vaccines, treatments and other tools my Administration has made widely available are protecting the American people from serious illness, keeping them out of the hospital, and bringing down daily deaths due to COVID-19 by 90 percent.<br><br>Today’s decision will help build on this progress, giving parents much-needed relief and peace of mind and helping our nation continue to move forward safely. We look forward to hearing from the CDC on its recommendations.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Launches the Talent Pipeline Challenge: Supporting Employer Investments in Equitable Workforce Development for Infrastructure&#160;Jobs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-launches-the-talent-pipeline-challenge-supporting-employer-investments-in-equitable-workforce-development-for-infrastructure-jobs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 14:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is kicking off a summer-long Talent Pipeline Challenge to fill high quality jobs that will help rebuild our infrastructure and supply chains here at home, and continue our transition from a historic economic recovery to steady and stable growth in the years ahead. This is a nationwide call to action for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is kicking off a summer-long Talent Pipeline Challenge to fill high quality jobs that will help rebuild our infrastructure and supply chains here at home, and continue our transition from a historic economic recovery to steady and stable growth in the years ahead. This is a nationwide call to action for employers, education and training providers, states, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, and philanthropic organizations to make tangible commitments that support equitable workforce development in three critical infrastructure sectors: Broadband, Construction, and “Electrification” (EV Charging Infrastructure and Battery Manufacturing). These commitments will complement the Federal government’s investment in workforce development and help ensure there are trained workers who are ready to meet the demands of implementing the historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, as the country transitions from a historic economic recovery to stable and steady growth that works for working people.</p>



<p><strong>Employers. </strong>The Talent Pipeline Challenge will encourage employers to partner with and hire skilled workers from at least one training provider in each region in which the employer has operations, such as a registered apprenticeship program or a community college with a diverse student population. As part of this pledge, employers can partner with national or regional intermediaries or training providers to build, scale, or support local training models to recruit, train, or hire workers in their sector. Training partnerships will build on pathways to quality jobs for women, people of color, and underserved workers— including those from rural and Tribal communities and communities with persistent poverty. As part of this goal:</p>



<ul><li>Employers and training providers are encouraged to include a community-based organization working with women and under-represented groups in the training partnership.</li><li>Employers already partnered with a registered apprenticeship program may consider investing in a quality pre-apprenticeship program that sends its graduates directly into a registered apprenticeship program.</li><li>Employers are encouraged to invest in the resources and supports like tuition assistance, child care, transportation costs, and emergency aid that are often barriers for workers to participate in training.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Training Providers. </strong>The Talent Pipeline Challenge will encourage training providers, unions, and other intermediaries, including labor-management skills programs, community colleges, industry associations, philanthropic organizations, and worker centers, to commit to:</p>



<ul><li>Partner with employers to create or bring to scale skills training programs, coupled with wraparound services like transportation assistance and child care, that will prepare workers for in-demand jobs.</li><li>Help to recruit regional and local employers from the three infrastructure sectors into the Talent Pipeline Challenge—including through regional convenings.</li><li>Work with employer partners to identify, recruit, and support local women and workers of color so they will be employed in infrastructure jobs, including workers from communities with persistent poverty, and rural and Tribal communities.</li><li>Provide grant funding for employer-training-provider partnerships and to defer costs of advanced skills training, particularly for underserved workers.</li></ul>



<p><strong>State and Local Governments. </strong>The Talent Pipeline Challenge is calling on state, local, Tribal, and territorial governments to commit to:</p>



<ul><li>Use federal funding to invest in workforce development efforts in these critical sectors, including:<ul><li>American Rescue Plan (ARP) State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds toward job training and other assistance to workers negatively affected by the pandemic.</li></ul><ul><li>Bipartisan Infrastructure Law grant funding, where possible and legally permissible, to support workforce development aligned to project labor needs.</li></ul><ul><li>State Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA) Reserve dollars to fund place-based labor-management partnerships in infrastructure sectors, with apprenticeships and pre-apprenticeship opportunities.</li></ul></li><li>Serve as a regional convenor of employers, training, and community partners to identify workforce needs and develop a regional workforce training plan.&nbsp;</li><li>Make a model employer commitment, prioritizing hiring of workers and small businesses in their community for state and local projects and developing diverse hiring goals.</li><li>Encourage contractors, where permissible under applicable law, to use local/economic hiring preferences to expand the diversity of the talent pool and build local talent.</li><li>Adapt career and technical education plans (i.e., Perkins State Plan) to meet new workforce needs created by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Administration Actions to Support Infrastructure Workforce Development</strong></p>



<p>The Administration is undertaking a wide range of actions to support workforce development related to the three industries highlighted in the Talent Pipeline Challenge. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law includes over $800 million in dedicated funding for job training, as well as additional investments where agencies may encourage the use of the funds for training.&nbsp; Agencies are including, where possible, workforce development as an allowable activity in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law programs and identifying funds both within the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, like funds from large federal-aid highway investments, and through other funding streams— like ARP’s State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds and Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA) funding — that can be invested in workforce training programs. The Department of Labor (DOL) is working to align federal workforce investments in registered apprenticeships and workforce programs at community colleges to meet infrastructure workforce needs. The Administration will also work to support state and local partnerships seeking to leverage WIOA funding to support workforce training as well as wrap-around services.</p>



<p><strong><em>ADDITIONAL DETAILS:</em></strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><strong>Administration Actions to Support Infrastructure Workforce Development</strong></p>



<p>Specific actions include:</p>



<ul><li>DOL announced an additional $50 million in Strengthening Community Colleges Training grants available to support the development and expansion of high-quality workforce training programs at community colleges. These grants will enable community colleges – individually or collectively – to proactively address equity gaps and meet the skills development needs of local employers and workers, including for infrastructure-related fields.</li><li>The Department of Commerce’s (DOC) Internet for All program’s Notice of Funding Opportunities (NOFOs) prioritize high labor standards and protections, as well as workforce development initiatives, to ensure there is a trained, diverse workforce ready to support the programs. In particular, the Broadband Equity, Access, and Deployment (BEAD) NOFO makes workforce development an eligible use of grant funds, and requires a highly-skilled workforce, which can be fulfilled through use of graduates of registered apprenticeships or other joint labor-management training programs. The NOFO also requires Eligible Entities to develop a plan for ensuring an available and highly skilled workforce in order to receive their funds.</li><li>The Department of Energy (DOE), in consultation with DOL, is providing $5 million to support a national battery workforce sectoral strategy, leading to national training standards and industry-recognized credentials.</li><li>DOE’s Solar Energy Technology Office, with Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding, is supporting quality pre-apprenticeships for clean energy construction careers.</li><li>DOL is developing, in collaboration with the Department of Transportation (DOT), DOE, and DOC, guidance that will encourage federal agencies and workforce system stakeholders —like American Job Centers (AJCs) and workforce boards, industry associations, worker centers, unions, and employers—to partner on infrastructure projects, share labor market information and expertise, and to shape workforce development activities to reflect proven strategies and practices that deliver sustainable, equitable outcomes.</li><li>In March, DOT and DOL signed a memorandum of understanding (MOU) that will help facilitate efforts between the two agencies on workforce and job quality. The MOU will leverage the individual and combined resources and expertise of both agencies to ensure the actions necessary to meet common goals related to expanding equitable access to quality jobs for workers and communities in the development and modernization of American infrastructure. </li><li>In March, DOT released the NOFO for the Low and No Emissions Bus program. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides the first-ever dedicated investment in our transit workforce to support the transition to clean technologies like battery electric buses. Five percent of grants under the program – up to $280 million over five years – will be used to fund workforce development training, including registered apprenticeships and other labor-management training programs, to train and upskill transit workers to maintain and operate zero emission vehicles and related charging infrastructure.</li><li>Last week, DOT and DOE released their proposed minimum standards for EV Charging. The standards emphasized strong workforce standards such as the Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP) to increase the safety and reliability of chargers while creating and supporting good-paying, highly skilled union jobs in communities across the country.</li><li>Over the course of the summer, the Administration will collaborate with employers and other critical stakeholders to encourage action on new or existing workforce efforts. Agencies will also highlight best practices to address infrastructure talent pipeline needs.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>COMMITMENTS UNDERWAY:</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Wilmington, Delaware is leveraging the Fiscal Recovery Funds from ARP to expand their Howard High School of Technology workforce development program – funding high school and adult job training in construction, plumbing, HVAC, and more. The city has also committed to using their local workforce for ARP funded neighborhood revitalization projects and is assisting local contractors in obtaining information and participating in ARP-funded projects. Wilmington is connecting graduates from the Howard High School training program to jobs with local employers working on local revitalization projects, and soon Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funded infrastructure projects – helping residents get access to these good jobs and helping employers access the talent they need to successfully complete these government projects.   </li><li>Washington D.C. is expanding its D.C. Infrastructure Academy with Fiscal Recovery Funds from ARP to meet the need for skilled infrastructure professionals. The Infrastructure Academy offers high-quality training in infrastructure jobs under one roof and gives D.C. residents the opportunity to gain skills and secure good infrastructure jobs. The program recruits, trains, screens, and supports job placement of residents to fulfill the needs of the D.C. infrastructure industry, matching graduates to infrastructure jobs with leading companies in these high-demand fields.</li><li>Since 2012, the Electrical Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP) has trained and certified thousands of electricians throughout the country in the installation of electric vehicle supply equipment. 1,200 qualified electricians from populations traditionally underrepresented in the field have received scholarships to complete the program. Both IBEW and The Superior Group, a national electrical and technology construction and engineering firm headquartered in Columbus, Ohio, are partnering with EVITP to increase the number of certified electricians to meet growing demand.<ul><li>IBEW will aim to have a total of 10,000 EVITP certified electricians by August.</li></ul><ul><li>The Superior Group will increase the number of EVITP certified electricians in its ranks by 50. Additionally, The Superior Group is committed to attracting more than 100 potential new employees from underserved communities in Central Ohio by the end of 2022.</li></ul></li><li>Solely owned by a Black woman for 30 years, McKissack &amp; McKissack is a national architecture, engineering, program, and construction management firm. McKissack &amp; McKissack offers tuition assistance, technical lectures, reimbursement for membership fees, professional development programs, licenses, and certifications, and other opportunities that grow employee skills and increase individual earning power. It strives for these initiatives to attract and retain talent— especially from underserved communities.</li><li>Siemens, which will produce one million EV chargers by 2025, is taking a number of steps to build the pipeline of workers to fill the jobs that will be created. Siemens is developing technical training pathways and building talent pipelines with more than 100,000 academic institutions nationwide. They are also investing $37 million annually in employee training programs. And, Siemens recently started an apprenticeship program at their expanded manufacturing facility in Spartanburg, South Carolina.</li><li>The Building Pathways Building Trades Pre-Apprenticeship Program, launched in 2011 by the Building and Construction Trades Council of the Metropolitan District, prepares women, people of color, and other underserved Boston metro area residents to enter a union Registered Apprenticeship program – an effective “learn and earn” model providing pathways to the middle class. In addition to creating opportunities to access and prepare for building trades apprenticeships and family-sustaining careers in the construction industry, Building Pathways also educates middle and high school students about career opportunities in the building trades. Building Pathways has prepared and placed hundreds of Boston area residents for careers in union construction, with graduates comprised of over 90 percent people of color and over 55 percent women.</li><li>Wilson Community College in Wilson, North Carolina will pilot the Fiber Broadband Association’s Optical Telecom Installation Certification program. The program was designed with industry professionals to fill an existing fiber technician skills gap, and consists of 144 hours of combined class and lab instruction, provided through Wilson Community College. The program will eventually include a 2,000-hour apprenticeship at Greenlight Community Broadband and other regional broadband partners. The Fiber Broadband Association plans to replicate this model with community colleges and providers across the country. </li><li>The philanthropic community has also stepped up to support these efforts. The Families and Workers Fund has committed $1 million in aligned funding to help advance good jobs and diverse talent pipelines. This funding will focus on building the capacity of community-based nonprofits to scale innovative models for helping workers achieve economic mobility and career advancement and to participate in federal funding opportunities.  Additionally, philanthropies are committing $250,000 to train workers in EVITP, including $150,000 from the Hewlett Foundation, which is committed to enhancing broad public benefits of the clean energy transition.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Father&#8217;s Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/17/a-proclamation-on-fathers-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 14:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55748</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every year on Father&#8217;s Day, we honor the men who help shape our character through their love, guidance, and devotion.  Dads and father figures across the country sacrifice so much to support their families and to ensure that their children can lead fulfilling lives.  &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; I remember my own father, who instilled in me some of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>     Every year on Father&#8217;s Day, we honor the men who help shape our character through their love, guidance, and devotion.  Dads and father figures across the country sacrifice so much to support their families and to ensure that their children can lead fulfilling lives. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I remember my own father, who instilled in me some of the most important values that guide me to this day.&nbsp; He taught me to treat all people with dignity, and that there is no higher calling than to be a good parent.&nbsp; He informed the way that I raised my own children &#8212; and how they continue to raise theirs.&nbsp; Just like my father, dads all over our country help teach their kids a sense of right and wrong that stays with them their entire lives.&nbsp; We owe these wonderful fathers a great deal of respect and gratitude.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For many of us, Father&#8217;s Day is an opportunity to pause and remember the fathers, stepfathers, father figures, grandfathers, brothers, and children that we have lost &#8212; but who are never gone.&nbsp; Too many of us know a dad who was lost too soon or a father who has lost a child.&nbsp; The pain runs deep, but we draw strength from knowing that our loved ones will always remain with us.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Like so many Americans, I am thankful for the precious time I have had both as a son and as a father.&nbsp; The unique challenges of the last few years have reminded us to cherish the time we have with our dads &#8212; learning more from them, showing them more gratitude, and showering them with more love.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration is dedicated to supporting our Nation&#8217;s fathers and families.&nbsp; We provided historic funding to help parents access child care during the pandemic, and we continue to fight for lower costs and higher quality child care for the long term. &nbsp;We are working to ensure that parents can access paid leave as they welcome a new child or care for a sick loved one. &nbsp;Additionally, we are working tirelessly for safer communities so that all fathers can raise their children in flourishing neighborhoods.&nbsp; From my own personal experience as a&nbsp;single dad, I know how critical support is when raising a family. &nbsp;That is why we remain committed to helping single parents ensure that their children have equal opportunities to thrive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Father&#8217;s Day, we pay tribute to the dads, stepdads, grandfathers, and father figures who lift us up on their shoulders so that we can reach our full potential.&nbsp; We express our gratitude for all that they sacrifice on our behalf. &nbsp;We honor the contributions they make every day to strengthen their families and our Nation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, in accordance with a joint resolution of the Congress approved April 24, 1972, as amended (36 U.S.C. 109) do hereby proclaim June 19, 2022, as Father&#8217;s Day.&nbsp; I&nbsp;direct the appropriate officials of the Government to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on this day.&nbsp; Let us honor our fathers, living and deceased, and show them the love and gratitude they deserve.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this seventeenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Juneteenth Day of Observance,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/17/a-proclamation-on-juneteenth-day-of-observance-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55751</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; After the Union Army captured New Orleans in 1862, slave owners in Confederate states migrated to Texas with more than 150,000 enslaved Black persons. &#160;For 3 years, even after President Abraham Lincoln issued the Emancipation Proclamation, enslaved Black Americans in Texas remained in brutal bondage, immorally and illegally deprived of their freedom and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; After the Union Army captured New Orleans in 1862, slave owners in Confederate states migrated to Texas with more than 150,000 enslaved Black persons. &nbsp;For 3 years, even after President Abraham Lincoln issued the Emancipation Proclamation, enslaved Black Americans in Texas remained in brutal bondage, immorally and illegally deprived of their freedom and basic dignity.&nbsp; On June 19, 1865 &#8212; over 2 years after President Lincoln declared all enslaved persons free &#8212; Major General Gordon Granger and Union Army troops marched to Galveston, Texas, to enforce the Emancipation Proclamation and free the last enslaved Black Americans in Texas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Those who were freed from bondage celebrated their long-overdue emancipation on June 19.&nbsp; Today, our Nation commemorates Juneteenth: &nbsp;a chance to celebrate human freedom, reflect on the grievous and ongoing legacy of slavery, and rededicate ourselves to rooting out the systemic racism that continues to plague our society as we strive to deliver the full promise of America to every American.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This Juneteenth, we are freshly reminded that the poisonous ideology of racism has not yet been defeated &#8212; it only hides.&nbsp; Our Nation continues to mourn the 10 lives senselessly taken in Buffalo, New York, and grieve for the families who have lost a piece of their soul.&nbsp; As we confront the awful reality of yet another gunman massacring innocent people in the name of hatred, racism, and fear, we must meet this moment with renewed resolve.&nbsp; We&nbsp;must stand together against white supremacy and show that bigotry and hate have no safe harbor in America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Juneteenth is a day to reflect on both bondage and freedom &#8212; a day of both pain and purpose.&nbsp; It is, in equal measure, a&nbsp;remembrance of both the long, hard night of slavery and subjugation, as well as a celebration of the promise of a brighter morning to come. &nbsp;On Juneteenth, we remember our extraordinary capacity to heal, to hope, and to emerge from our worst moments as a stronger, freer, and more just Nation. &nbsp;It is also a day to&nbsp;celebrate the power and resilience of Black Americans, who have endured generations of oppression in the ongoing journey toward equal justice, equal dignity, equal rights, and equal opportunity in America.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last year, I was proud to sign bipartisan legislation establishing Juneteenth as our newest Federal holiday, so that all Americans can feel the power of this day, learn from our history, celebrate our progress, and recognize and engage in the&nbsp;work that continues. &nbsp;Great nations do not ignore their most painful moments &#8212; they face them. &nbsp;We grow stronger as a country when we honestly confront our past injustices, including the profound suffering and injustice wrought by slavery and generations of segregation and discrimination against Black Americans.&nbsp; To heal, we must remember.&nbsp; We must never rest until the promise of our Nation is made real for all Americans.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The emancipation of enslaved Black Americans was not the end of our Nation&#8217;s work to deliver on the promise of equality &#8212; it was only the beginning.&nbsp; On Juneteenth, we recommit to our shared work to ensure racial justice, equity, and equality in America.&nbsp; We commemorate the centuries of struggle and progress led by abolitionists, educators, civil rights advocates, lawyers, activists, trade unionists, religious leaders, public officials, and everyday Americans who have brought our&nbsp;Nation closer to fulfilling its promise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As my good friend, the late Congressman Elijah Cummings, said, &#8220;Our children are the living messengers we send to a future we will never see.&#8221;&nbsp; Together as a Nation, let us continue our work together to build a country we are all proud to pass along to our children &#8212; one where the foundational promises and ideals of America ring true for every child and every family.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 19, 2022, as Juneteenth Day of Observance. &nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to acknowledge and condemn the history of slavery in our Nation and recognize how the impact of America&#8217;s original sin remains.&nbsp; I call on every American to celebrate the emancipation of all Black Americans and commit together to eradicate systemic racism and inequity that can never be tolerated and must always be fought against.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this seventeenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
