<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 19:48:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President-Elect Gustavo Petro of&#160;Colombia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-elect-gustavo-petro-of-colombia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 19:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke with President-elect Gustavo Petro today to congratulate him and Vice President-elect Francia Marquez on their election. President Biden commended the Colombian people for holding free and fair elections and reaffirmed U.S. support for Colombia. He underscored that he looks forward to working with the President-elect to continue strengthening bilateral&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke with President-elect Gustavo Petro today to congratulate him and Vice President-elect Francia Marquez on their election. President Biden commended the Colombian people for holding free and fair elections and reaffirmed U.S. support for Colombia. He underscored that he looks forward to working with the President-elect to continue strengthening bilateral cooperation, including on climate change, health security, and implementation of the 2016 Peace Accord. President Biden also welcomed the opportunity to discuss bilateral security and counternarcotics cooperation. They discussed the importance of mutual respect and partnership as the foundation of the U.S.-Colombia relationship, and agreed to have their teams follow up and engage directly on shared interests.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Prescription of Method of Designating a Member of the Military Sentencing Parameters and Criteria&#160;Board</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/21/memorandum-on-the-prescription-of-method-of-designating-a-member-of-the-military-sentencing-parameters-and-criteria-board/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 19:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE SUBJECT:       Prescription of Method of Designating a Member of the Military Sentencing Parameters and Criteria Board By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;539E(e)(4)(B) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, Public Law&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Prescription of Method of Designating a Member of the Military Sentencing Parameters and Criteria Board</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;539E(e)(4)(B) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, Public Law 117-81, 135 Stat. 1541, 1700 (2021), I hereby order as follows:</p>



<p>(1) &nbsp;If the chief trial judges designated under article 26(g) of the Uniform Code of Military Justice, 10 U.S.C. 826(g), do not include a trial judge of the Navy, then the Judge Advocate General of the Navy shall designate as a voting member of the Military Sentencing Parameters and Criteria Board (Board) either the Chief Judge of the Department of the Navy or a Navy trial judge assigned to the Navy and Marine Corps Trial Judiciary.</p>



<p>(2) &nbsp;If the chief trial judges designated under article 26(g) of the Uniform Code of Military Justice, 10 U.S.C. 826(g), do not include a trial judge of the Marine Corps, then the Staff Judge Advocate to the Commandant of the Marine Corps, in consultation with the Judge Advocate General of the Navy, shall designate as a voting member of the Board a Marine Corps trial judge assigned to the Navy and Marine Corps Trial Judiciary.</p>



<p>This memorandum constitutes the regulations provided for in subsections (ii) and (iii) of section 539E(e)(4)(B) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.                                </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden to Nominate Dr. Arati Prabhakar to Lead Office of Science and Technology&#160;Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/president-biden-to-nominate-dr-arati-prabhakar-to-lead-office-of-science-and-technology-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 17:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Former Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency and National Institute of Standards and Technology leader would make history as the first woman, immigrant, or person of color confirmed to head OSTP Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate Dr. Arati Prabhakar to serve as Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Former Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency and National Institute of Standards and Technology leader would make history as the first woman, immigrant, or person of color confirmed to head OSTP</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate Dr. Arati Prabhakar to serve as Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), and once confirmed to this position, also as Assistant to the President for Science and Technology. In this capacity, Dr. Prabhakar will be the President’s Chief Advisor for Science and Technology, a co-chair of the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology, and a member of the President’s Cabinet.</p>



<p>“Dr. Prabhakar is a brilliant and highly-respected engineer and applied physicist and will lead the Office of Science and Technology Policy to leverage science, technology, and innovation to expand our possibilities, solve our toughest challenges, and make the impossible possible,” said President Biden. “I share Dr. Prabhakar’s belief that America has the most powerful innovation machine the world has ever seen. As the Senate considers her nomination, I am grateful that Dr. Alondra Nelson will continue to lead OSTP and Dr. Francis Collins will continue to serve as my acting Science Advisor.”<br><br>Prabhakar has been unanimously confirmed by the Senate before, to lead the&nbsp;National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), and was the first woman to hold that role. She later served as director of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA), the birthplace of breakthrough technologies like stealth aircraft and the Internet.</p>



<p>If confirmed to lead OSTP, Prabhakar would become the third Asian American, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander to serve in President Biden’s Cabinet, joining Vice President Kamala Harris and U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai. Today’s nomination is historic, with Prabhakar being the first woman, immigrant, or person of color nominated to serve as Senate-confirmed director of OSTP.</p>



<p><strong><u>Dr. Arati Prabhakar, nominee to serve as Director, Office of Science and Technology Policy</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Arati Prabhakar has led two different federal R&amp;D agencies and worked with startups, large companies, universities, government labs, and nonprofits across a wide variety of sectors to create powerful new solutions for critical challenges. She is an engineer and applied physicist with extensive management and leadership credentials.</p>



<p>Prabhakar served as director of DARPA, the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, from 2012 to 2017. At DARPA, she oversaw teams that prototyped a system for detecting nuclear and radiological materials before a terrorist can build a bomb, that developed tools to find human trafficking networks in the deep and dark web, and that enabled complex military systems to work together even when they were not originally designed to do so. She also established a new office to spur novel biotechnologies. Under her leadership, DARPA kick-started the development of a rapid-response mRNA vaccine platform, making possible the fastest safe and effective vaccine development in world history in response to COVID-19.</p>



<p>Prabhakar was unanimously confirmed by the U.S. Senate to lead the&nbsp;National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), taking the helm at age 34 as the first woman to lead the agency. At NIST, which she led from 1993 to 1997, she helped take from early seed stage to national scale the Manufacturing Extension Partnership to boost the competitiveness of small- and mid-size manufacturers, and the Advanced Technology Program to stimulate early-stage advanced technology development. She also reinforced NIST’s long-time mission in measurement science and technology that underpins commerce and high-quality manufacturing.</p>



<p>Between her Federal leadership roles, Prabhakar spent 15 years in Silicon Valley, helping bring R&amp;D to deployment as a company executive and as a venture capitalist. Her work included components for consumer electronics and semiconductor process technology. In 2019, she founded Actuate, a non-profit organization bringing new actors to the table to develop solutions to the challenges of climate, health, trustworthy data and information technology, and opening access to opportunity for every person.</p>



<p>Prabhakar’s family immigrated from India to the United States when she was three years old – first to Chicago and then settling when she was age 10 in Lubbock, Texas, where she went on to get her electrical engineering degree from Texas Tech University. She was the first woman to earn a Ph.D. in applied physics from the California Institute of Technology, where she also earned an M.S. in electrical engineering. She started her career in the legislative branch as a Congressional Fellow at the Office of Technology Assessment.</p>



<p>She is a fellow of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers and a member of the National Academy of Engineering, and was a fellow at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Bill Signed: S. 1097, S. 2520, and S.&#160;3823</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/21/press-release-bill-signed-s-1097-s-2520-and-s-3823/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 16:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, June 21, 2022, the President signed into law: S. 1097, the &#8220;Federal Rotational Cyber Workforce Program Act of 2021,&#8221; which establishes a Federal rotational cyber workforce program for the Federal cyber workforce; Thank you to Senators Peters, Hoeven, and Rosen and Representatives Khanna and Mace for their leadership. S. 2520, the &#8220;State and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, June 21, 2022, the President signed into law:<br><br>S. 1097, the &#8220;Federal Rotational Cyber Workforce Program Act of 2021,&#8221; which establishes a Federal rotational cyber workforce program for the Federal cyber workforce;</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Peters, Hoeven, and Rosen and Representatives Khanna and Mace for their leadership.<br><br>S. 2520, the &#8220;State and Local Government Cybersecurity Act of 2021,&#8221; which requires the Department of Homeland Security to increase collaboration with State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments on cybersecurity issues;</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Peters, Portman, and Rosen, and Representative Neguse for their leadership.<br><br>S. 3823, the &#8220;Bankruptcy Threshold Adjustment and Technical Corrections Act,&#8221; which raises certain bankruptcy threshold limits and makes technical corrections to the Bankruptcy Administration Improvement Act.</p>



<p>&nbsp;Thank you to Senators Grassley, Durbin, Whitehouse, and Cornyn, and Representatives Neguse and Cline for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Changes to U.S. Anti-Personnel Landmine&#160;Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/fact-sheet-changes-to-u-s-anti-personnel-landmine-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing important policy changes to U.S. Anti-Personnel Landmine policy. After conducting a comprehensive policy review, the United States is joining the vast majority of countries around the world in committing to limit the use of anti-personnel landmines (APL).These changes reflect the President’s belief that these weapons have disproportionate impact on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing important policy changes to U.S. Anti-Personnel Landmine policy. After conducting a comprehensive policy review, the United States is joining the vast majority of countries around the world in committing to limit the use of anti-personnel landmines (APL).These changes reflect the President’s belief that these weapons have disproportionate impact on civilians, including children, long after fighting has stopped, and that we need to curtail the use of APL worldwide. They also complement longstanding U.S. leadership in the clearance of landmines and other explosive remnants of war.<br>&nbsp;<br>The new commitment announced today will align U.S. APL policy outside of the Korean Peninsula with the key requirements of the Ottawa Convention – the international treaty prohibiting the use, stockpiling, production, and transfer of APL – which has more than 160 parties, including all of our NATO Allies. This means that United States will:</p>



<ul><li>Not develop, produce, or acquire APL;</li><li>Not export or transfer of APL, except when necessary for activities related to mine detection or removal, and for the purpose of destruction;</li><li>Not use APL outside of the Korean Peninsula;</li><li>Not assist, encourage, or induce anyone, outside of the context of the Korean Peninsula, to engage in any activity that would be prohibited by the Ottawa Convention; and</li><li>Undertake to destroy all APL stockpiles not required for the defense of the Republic of Korea.</li></ul>



<p>Additionally, the United States will undertake diligent efforts to pursue materiel and operational solutions to assist in becoming compliant with and ultimately acceding to the Ottawa Convention, while ensuring our ability to respond to contingencies and meet our alliance commitments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The new policy announced today represents a further step to advance the humanitarian aims of the Ottawa Convention, and to bring U.S. practice in closer alignment with a global humanitarian movement that has had a demonstrated positive impact in reducing civilian casualties from APL.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Even as the United States takes this further step, the unique circumstances on the Korean Peninsula and the U.S. commitment to the defense of the Republic of Korea preclude the United States from changing anti-personnel landmine policy on the Korean Peninsula at this time.&nbsp; As the United States commits to continuing our diligent efforts to pursue material and operational alternatives to APL, the security of our ally the Republic of Korea will continue to be a paramount concern.<br><br><strong>World Leader in Humanitarian Mine Action</strong><br><br>The United States is the world’s single largest financial supporter of steps to mitigate the harmful consequences of landmines and explosive remnants of war around the world, including through land clearance and medical rehabilitation and vocational training for those injured by these weapons.&nbsp; Since the United States Humanitarian Mine Action Program was established in 1993, the United States has provided over $4.2 billion in aid in over 100 countries for conventional weapons destruction programs. Through this assistance, the United States has:</p>



<ul><li>Helped 17 countries become free from the danger of landmines;</li><li>Provided assistive devices and other rehabilitation services to over 250,000 people in 35 countries through the U.S. Agency for International Development-managed Leahy War Victims Fund.</li></ul>



<p>This vital U.S. assistance has helped post-conflict countries consolidate peace and set the stage for reconstruction and development.  Clearance efforts and victim assistance programs return land and infrastructure to productive use and assist in the rehabilitation and reintegration into society of survivors of mine and explosive remnants of war incidents.<br> <br>Further information on U.S. humanitarian demining and conventional weapons destruction programs can be found in the State Department’s annual To Walk the Earth in Safety report.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on Changes to U.S. Anti-Personnel Landmine&#160;Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-changes-to-u-s-anti-personnel-landmine-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing an important step to limit the United States’ use of anti-personnel landmines. At the President’s direction, the United States will align its policy concerning use of these weapons outside of the Korean Peninsula with key provisions of the Ottawa Convention, the international treaty prohibiting the use, stockpiling, production, and transfer of anti-personnel landmines. Additionally, the President will prohibit the development, production,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing an important step to limit the United States’ use of anti-personnel landmines. At the President’s direction, the United States will align its policy concerning use of these weapons outside of the Korean Peninsula with key provisions of the Ottawa Convention, the international treaty prohibiting the use, stockpiling, production, and transfer of anti-personnel landmines. Additionally, the President will prohibit the development, production, and acquisition of anti-personnel landmines prohibited under the Ottawa Convention, and will direct the Department of Defense to undertake diligent efforts to pursue alternatives to anti-personnel landmines that would be compliant with and ultimately allow the United States to accede to the Ottawa Convention, while ensuring our continued ability to respond to global contingencies. <br> <br>The world has once again witnessed the devastating impact that anti-personnel landmines can have in the context of Russia’s brutal and unprovoked war in Ukraine, where Russian forces’ use of these and other munitions have caused extensive harm to civilians and civilian objects. President Biden is committed to continuing the United States’ role as the world’s leader in mitigating the harmful consequences of anti-personnel landmines worldwide.  Since 1993, the United States has invested more than $4.2 billion in more than 100 countries to promote international peace and security through conventional weapons destruction programs.  We will continue this important work as we take another step to reclaim American leadership on the world stage.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: BIDEN-HARRIS ADMINISTRATION ANNOUNCES NEW PAY RAISES &#038; SUPPORTS FOR WILDLAND FIREFIGHTER WORKFORCE FROM BIPARTISAN INFRASTRUCTURE&#160;LAW</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-new-pay-raises-supports-for-wildland-firefighter-workforce-from-bipartisan-infrastructure-law/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our nation’s wildland firefighters safeguard vital benefits for communities across the nation: protecting our nation’s critical infrastructure, defending lives and private property from the risk of catastrophic wildfire, preserving forests so they can help us combat climate change, and protecting landscapes that contain cultural and natural resources of significance and value to Tribes, provide habitat&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Our nation’s wildland firefighters safeguard vital benefits for communities across the nation: protecting our nation’s critical infrastructure, defending lives and private property from the risk of catastrophic wildfire, preserving forests so they can help us combat climate change, and protecting landscapes that contain cultural and natural resources of significance and value to Tribes, provide habitat to fish and wildlife, and serve as a source of drinking water for more than 60 million people. Investing in our wildland firefighting workforce is a matter of national security as there are more than 460 million acres of land at moderate to very high risk from wildfire this year, and the number of acres burned in 2021 is the highest on record.</p>



<p>For decades, Federal wildland firefighters have faced the challenges of longer, more severe fire years with pay that has lagged behind their counterparts. Shifting development patterns, land and fire management decisions, and climate change have turned fire “seasons” into fire “years” in which increasingly destructive fires are exceeding available Federal firefighting resources.&nbsp; Federal firefighters also lack an official, uniform occupational series and a clear path for career advancement through the Federal government.</p>



<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing a series of bold steps to increase pay, create new mental wellness and health supports, and establish a new wildland fire management job series for federal firefighters.&nbsp; These unprecedented actions on behalf of the wildland firefighter workforce are funded by $600 million from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. These measures are a significant step forward that will deliver an immediate, temporary pay raise to Federal wildland firefighters across the nation, and sets Federal agencies on a path to continue working with stakeholders towards an updated, competitive, and equitable pay structure, along with a support system that will address the many challenges that have plagued our wildland firefighter workforce for decades.</p>



<p><strong>INCREASING PAY<br></strong><br>Under <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-acts-to-address-the-growing-wildfire-threat/">President Biden’s 2021 initiatives</a> to support federal wildland firefighters and ensure they receive a minimum of $15 per hour, more than 11,300 firefighters received pay increases last year at a cost of $24.3 million.&nbsp; This increase in the minimum wage was a critical first step for the dignity and respect of all Federal employees.&nbsp; Over the coming summer months, the Administration is implementing a new set of temporary pay increases that will put retroactive pay (from October 1, 2021) into wildland firefighter pockets increasing their bi-weekly pay, up to the lesser of $20,000 or 50% of their annual base salary through September 2023.&nbsp; The Federal agencies will begin processing these payments in the coming weeks, with additional payments to occur throughout July and into August.&nbsp; The $600 million in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law serves as a bridge for two years as the Administration works with Congress on longer-term reforms.</p>



<p><strong>CREATING NEW SUPPORTS FOR FIREFIGHTERS<br></strong><br>During a visit to the National Interagency Fire Center (NIFC) last week, Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland announced the establishment of an interagency wildland firefighter health and wellbeing program. Wildland firefighters work in incredibly stressful environments that can take a significant toll on their overall health and wellbeing, as well as on those who love them. Standing up a targeted interagency effort to provide trauma-informed mental health care is critical. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law directs the Departments of the Interior (DOI) and Agriculture (USDA) to increase focus on wildland firefighters’ physical and mental wellbeing.&nbsp; The newly established joint DOI- U.S. Forest Service program will address mental health needs, including post-traumatic stress disorder care for permanent, temporary, seasonal and year-round wildland firefighters at both agencies, along with addressing environmental hazards to minimize on-the-job exposure for wildland firefighters. The joint program will also connect existing efforts and establish year-round prevention and mental health training for wildland firefighters and create critical incident stress management staffing response. &nbsp;The Forest Service along with each of DOI’s wildland fire management bureaus — the Bureau of Indian Affairs, Bureau of Land Management, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, and National Park Service — will also add staffing capacity specifically to focus on mental health and employee support efforts for firefighters.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law also provides increased support to the Joint Fire Science Program, an interagency partnership with USDA’s U.S. Forest Service that funds wildfire science research projects. A total of $3.1 million will be used to support research towards a better understanding of firefighter mental health, landscape resiliency, and other climate-related studies on the beneficial uses of prescribed fire, carbon storage, and greenhouse gas and smoke emissions.</p>



<p><strong>IMPROVING RECRUITMENT AND RETENTION<br></strong><br>Because the pay increase under the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is temporary, the Biden-Harris Administration supports a new firefighter pay structure that is both sufficiently competitive and equitable to address longstanding nationwide recruitment and retention challenges and consider the longer work shifts, pressures and risks associated with these jobs. The Administration is committed to working with Congress to secure much needed investments and to grow this critical workforce.&nbsp; The costs in firefighter turnover brought about by not having an adequately compensated and supported firefighting workforce will far exceed the amount needed to invest in them.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>ESTABLISHING NEW WILDLAND FIRE MANAGEMENT OCCUPATIONAL SERIES<br></strong><br>The U.S. Office of Personnel Management (OPM) has taken the necessary step of creating the Wildland Fire Management occupational series established under the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. No such series has existed for 50 years.&nbsp; The new occupational series better identifies Federal firefighters with the work they do. It defines the duties of wildland firefighters and is responsive to the calls of firefighters and their unions to provide opportunities for career advancement.&nbsp; It also gives a boost to recruiting, as agencies can now post clear job opportunity announcements that specifically target people interested in wildland firefighting jobs.&nbsp; And it will help with retention, as our wildland firefighter workforce will benefit from a clear career path with detailed requirements for advancement, providing wildland firefighters with a job title and description that more accurately reflects their contributions.</p>



<p>Agencies will implement the new series in the coming months, though current Federal firefighters will be able to choose whether to opt-in to the new Wildland Fire Management series or stay in their current occupations.  Once fully implemented, the series will provide a solid foundation for recruitment and retention, further strengthening our wildland firefighter workforce and contributing to the fire safety of communities across our Nation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Increasing Federal Firefighter&#160;Pay</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-increasing-federal-firefighter-pay/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55929</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s an old expression that God made man – and then he made a few firefighters. Firefighters are some of the bravest men and women among us, and the backbones of our communities, protecting our homes, businesses, schools, and families from catastrophe.&#160; Federal firefighters used to get paid $13 an hour – but that ended&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>There’s an old expression that God made man – and then he made a few firefighters. Firefighters are some of the bravest men and women among us, and the backbones of our communities, protecting our homes, businesses, schools, and families from catastrophe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Federal firefighters used to get paid $13 an hour – but that ended in my administration. Last summer, we bumped up wildland firefighter pay to $15 an hour, a critical first step.&nbsp;I also fought for and secured historic investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to give America’s federal firefighters the pay, respect, and dignity they deserve.&nbsp;Today, my administration is announcing additional steps to increase pay for our nation’s federal firefighters, as well as expanding access to mental health support and creating more career pathways in wildland firefighting. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Today’s new steps, already paid for by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, will temporarily put back pay into firefighter’s pockets, increasing their bi-weekly checks by up to 50% of their annual base salary for two years. But we know there is more work to do, especially as climate change fuels more wildfires. I will do everything in my power, including working with Congress to secure long-term funding, to make sure these heroes keep earning the paychecks – and dignity – they deserve.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Intent to Appoint Marilynn Malerba as Treasurer of the United&#160;States</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/president-biden-announces-intent-to-appoint-marilynn-malerba-as-treasurer-of-the-united-states/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint Marilynn Malerba as Treasurer of the United States. Malerba, who is the Chief of the Mohegan Tribe, will be the first Native American to hold the position. The Treasurer of the United States directly oversees the U.S. Mint, the Bureau of Engraving and Printing, Fort Knox, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint Marilynn Malerba as Treasurer of the United States. Malerba, who is the Chief of the Mohegan Tribe, will be the first Native American to hold the position.</p>



<p>The Treasurer of the United States directly oversees the U.S. Mint, the Bureau of Engraving and Printing, Fort Knox, and is a key liaison with the Federal Reserve. Chief Malerba will also serve as a senior advisor to the Secretary of the Treasury in the areas of community development and public engagement.</p>



<p><strong>Marilynn Malerba</strong></p>



<p>Marilynn Malerba is the Chief of the Mohegan Tribe, a lifetime appointment made by the Tribe’s Council of Elders. Prior to becoming Chief, she served as Chairwoman of the Mohegan Tribal Council, and served in Tribal Government as Executive Director of Health and Human Services. Preceding her work for the Mohegan Tribe, Malerba had a lengthy career as a registered nurse, ultimately serving as the Director of Cardiology and Pulmonary Services at Lawrence &amp; Memorial Hospital. Additionally, Malerba currently serves as a member of the Treasury Tribal Advisory Committee. This seven-member committee advises the Secretary of the Treasury on significant matters related to the taxation of Indians, the training of Internal Revenue Service field agents, and the provisions of training and technical assistance to Native American financial officers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on World Refugee Day&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/20/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-world-refugee-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 13:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55909</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, on World Refugee Day, I join people around the world in recognizing the strength, resilience, and humanity of the millions of refugees forced to flee violence, persecution, and war.  This is also a moment to honor the incredible generosity of host communities, the private sector, and state and local government across the United States&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, on World Refugee Day, I join people around the world in recognizing the strength, resilience, and humanity of the millions of refugees forced to flee violence, persecution, and war.  This is also a moment to honor the incredible generosity of host communities, the private sector, and state and local government across the United States who work tirelessly to welcome refugees and provide them with essential support.  We also laud the bravery and dedication of humanitarian workers who show up, time and again, to provide life-saving assistance in challenging and often hazardous conditions.</p>



<p>As a result of Russia’s war against Ukraine we recently reached a grim milestone:&nbsp; According to the UN Refugee Agency, more than 100 million people are now forcibly displaced, more than at any other time in history.&nbsp; On this day, we&nbsp;reaffirm our&nbsp;commitment to work with the international community to&nbsp;achieve&nbsp;sustainable, long-term solutions to support refugees—including through resettlement.&nbsp; We also recommit to engaging in diplomatic efforts to address the root causes of displacement and bring an end to the&nbsp;ongoing&nbsp;conflicts that drive refugees to seek safety across borders.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States&nbsp;will do our part to ensure that those who have sought refuge here have access to the life-saving assistance they deserve, including healthcare and shelter, and opportunities to pursue livelihoods and education that allow them to rebuild their lives with dignity and hope for a brighter tomorrow. We will also continue to support vulnerable refugee populations such as women, children, lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and intersex (LGBTQI+) persons, and persons with disabilities.</p>



<p>As Americans, protecting and welcoming refugees is part of who we are.  Our nation of immigrants was founded by individuals fleeing religious persecution.  As we lead the world in responding to the needs of refugees, we honor our past, enhance our economic and social fabric, and exemplify our highest values.  We do this because it’s the right thing to do, but helping refugees is also good foreign policy, contributing to making the world more stable and secure, which benefits us all.   This is why the United States is the largest single provider of humanitarian assistance worldwide and why I raised our annual refugee admissions cap to 125,000 for Fiscal Year 2022.  My Administration is working as quickly as possible to rebuild the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program, to improve processing times, and to expand our domestic capacity to welcome refugees so that we are better positioned to reach this ambitious goal.  We have already demonstrated, by welcoming more than 80,000 Afghans to our country over the past year, and by committing to provide temporary safe haven to tens of thousands of Ukrainians, that we will lead by example.  Those who find refuge on our shores enrich our communities, as they always have, and bring a determined and entrepreneurial spirit that makes our country stronger.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
