<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 22:27:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 7,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/07/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-7-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 22:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:35 P.M. EDT&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  Okay.  A couple of items for you at the top. Obviously, this is a tremendously historic day in the White House and in the country, and this is a fulfillment of a promise the President made to the country.&#160; His time on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:35 P.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  Okay.  A couple of items for you at the top.</p>



<p>Obviously, this is a tremendously historic day in the White House and in the country, and this is a fulfillment of a promise the President made to the country.&nbsp; His time on the Judiciary Committee was defining for him and gave him historically exceptional preparation for what we would consider a smooth process characterized by heavy engagement with both parties in the Senate during both the advice and consent phases.</p>



<p>He promised to choose a successor in the mold of Justice Breyer, as Republicans and Democrats called for, and after thorough consideration, as you know, chose Judge Jackson.</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s outreach &#8212; Justice Jackson, I guess we can now call her.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s outreach continued at this stage, calling senators in both parties early about his choice.&nbsp; Out of the gate, he proved he had chosen someone in the tradition by immediately getting endorsed by the Fraterni- &#8212; Fraternal Order of Police and Judge Thomas Griffith, followed by a procession of leading conservative legal minds and additional law enforcement organizations.</p>



<p>As we&#8217;ve talked about in here a bit, she began her prep work immediately, starting the day after she was announced, and promised to meet with anyone who wanted to and honored it, meeting with 97 senators over the course of her consultations.</p>



<p>She further displayed her work ethic, extraordinary credentials, and character when she testified for over 20 hours and answered the most QFRs of any SCOTUS nominee ever.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also functioned seamlessly with the Judiciary Committee and leadership, and we were conscientious about being a good resource to Republicans.&nbsp; Senator Jones and the additional staff brought on during the process made invaluable contributions essential to success.</p>



<p>I also wanted to highlight that on UI data that was released today, as you can see in here, the comparison between January of 2021 and March, now that we are in, of 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the last four weeks, fewer Americans filed initial claims for unemployment insurance than any time in recorded history.&nbsp; Since President Oba- &#8212; Biden took office, our economy has added 7.9 million jobs; that&#8217;s more jobs created on average per month than any other President in history.&nbsp; And last month, the unemployment rate fell to 3.6 percent, down from 6.7 percent when the President took office about 15 months ago.</p>



<p>This historic job growth is a direct result of the American Rescue Plan, which funded our vaccination strategy, reopened schools, and helped grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out.</p>



<p>Last item for you before we get to your questions: Across the country, as we&#8217;ve talked about a bit in here, Republican elected officials are engaging in a disturbing, cynical trend of attacking vulnerable transgender kids for purely partisan, political reasons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today in Alabama, instead of focusing on critical kitchen-table issues like the economy, COVID, or addressing the country&#8217;s mental health crisis, Republican lawmakers are currently debating legislation that, among many things, would target trans youth with tactics that threatens to put pediatricians in prison if they provide medically necessary, lifesaving healthcare for the kids they serve.</p>



<p>Just like the extreme government overreach we&#8217;ve seen in Texas, where politicians have sent state officials into the homes of loving parents to investigate them for abuse &#8212; just to harass and intimidate the LGBTQI+ community &#8212; today&#8217;s vote in Alabama will only serve to harm kids.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But Alabama&#8217;s lawmakers and other legislators who are contemplating these discriminar- &#8212; discriminatory bills have been put on notice by the Department of Justice and the Department of Health and Human Services that laws and policies preventing care that healthcare professionals recommend for transgender minors may violate the Constitution and federal law.</p>



<p>To be clear, every major medical association agrees that gender-affirming healthcare for transgender kids is a best practice and potentially lifesaving.</p>



<p>All of this begs an important question: What are these policies actually trying to solve for?&nbsp; LGBTQI+ people can&#8217;t be erased or forced back into any closets, and kids across our nation should be allowed to be who they are without the threat that their parents or their doctor could be imprisoned simply for helping them and loving them.</p>



<p>President Biden has committed in both words and actions to fight for all Americans and will not hesitate to hold these states accountable.</p>



<p>I would also note, since I&#8217;ve had a rotation of fabulous colleagues in here today: Today we have Vedant Patel here.&nbsp; You may all know him.&nbsp; Any of you who work on immigration and climate issues know him very well.&nbsp; I often joke with him that we give him the easy assignments.&nbsp; We did not.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just because he&#8217;s super talented.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vedant &#8212; I’ll say about him: He&#8217;s a beautiful writer.&nbsp; He&#8217;s a fast writer.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if that means he could be a wire reporter.&nbsp; I think he has a very promising career in government ahead of him.&nbsp; But I just wanted to highlight Vedant and his amazing contributions and everything he does to help me, help all of us, help the President every day.</p>



<p>With that &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perfect.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got &#8212; I’ve got three things.&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Ukraine&#8217;s foreign minister at NATO made very clear that his country needs more weapons and needs them fast.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if it&#8217;s time for the U.S. and other allies to not just provide defensive weaponry but actually provide offensive weapons.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me give you a sense of where we are.&nbsp; As of now, we have provided &#8212; committed to providing $1.7 billion of weapons, of security assistance to Ukraine since the beginning of this conflict; more than $2 billion since the President took office.&nbsp; There are transfers of systems nearly every single day.</p>



<p>I would note we just announced, two days ago, $100 million in Javelins, which are a critical weapon that the Ukrainians have been using effectively to fight the Russians, push back the Russians, and defend their country.</p>



<p>I would also note that as it relates to the type of systems and materiel we are providing: For every Russian tank in Ukraine, the United States will have or has provided 10 anti-tank systems.&nbsp; If you factor in contributions from allies, we&#8217;re almost at 90 to 1.&nbsp; That means one tank &#8212; Russian tank, 10 anti-tank systems to fight them back.&nbsp; For every Russian armored vehicle in Ukraine, the United States will have provided about three anti-armor systems.&nbsp; If you factor in contributions from allies, it&#8217;s about 25 to 1.</p>



<p>The way this works &#8212; and it’s the last thing I&#8217;ll say and get to your next question &#8212; the way that it works is that the Ukrainian leaders request a range of assistance.&nbsp; They often provide us lists.&nbsp; We go through that list; we determine what we can provide.&nbsp; We provide a vast, vast majority of what they&#8217;re requesting.&nbsp; If we don&#8217;t have access to it &#8212; sometimes it&#8217;s Russian-made military equipment &#8212; we work with our allies and partners to see what they can provide.</p>



<p>And our focus as our &#8212; as Department of Defense officials have conveyed on the Hill when they&#8217;ve testified this week, has been providing &#8212; providing what they are trained on and what we know is effective in fighting this war.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve already seen, to date, that the use of this security assistance has been central and essential in effectively fighting the war as they have done.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Mara.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you saying that that’s sufficient, that you feel that you&#8217;ve given them enough?&nbsp; I mean, what do you mean by those metrics?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I provided them because I think it&#8217;s interesting or compelling &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; to understand &#8212; right? &#8212; the range and the significance and the totality of the type of assistance we&#8217;ve provided.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have not stopped nor are we stopping providing additional security assistance.&nbsp; We have announcements nearly every couple of days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just think that, to me, was interesting and compelling to better understand the significance and the broad scope of the assistance we’ve provided.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you’re saying there&#8217;ll be no letup in your efforts to provide them with more?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, I don&#8217;t think I conveyed that in any &#8212; in any way.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; That’s fine.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to kind of follow up on that: The Secretary of State yesterday, in a Russian-language Telegram channel, said, quote, “[W]e&#8217;re looking at other systems &#8212; some of them larger, more sophisticated &#8212; that may be useful going forward…”&nbsp; Is he talking about the systems that allies might have that we&#8217;re trying to backfill?&nbsp; What was, for clarity’s perspective, was he trying to say there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, partly, yes, because there are systems, of course, we have access to.&nbsp; We have the best military in the world.&nbsp; We have a range of systems we have access to that we have been providing and we will continue to provide.</p>



<p>There are certain systems, as you&#8217;ve noted &#8212; the S-300 is one of them, of course &#8212; where they have requested.&nbsp; We have to continue to work with allies and partners on what systems and equipment they have access to and they would have the capacity to provide.&nbsp; Sometimes that means backfilling systems.&nbsp; And there is also systems and &#8212; weapons systems that they may request that we may not talk about because, for operational reasons and their own process, it wouldn&#8217;t be to their benefit to do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he’s potentially talking about U.S. systems that we just aren&#8217;t necessarily aware of at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s &#8212; he&#8217;s talking about &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to detail always every type of system or every type of weapon we&#8217;re going to work with allies to provide or provide.&nbsp; We have provi- &#8212; we have detailed it quite extensively from here, but we&#8217;re not going to detail everything &#8212; we haven&#8217;t &#8212; over the course of time for operational purposes.&nbsp; But what he was conveying is that we&#8217;ll continue to work with our partners and allies in meeting the needs and the requests that the Ukrainians have put forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, Germany&#8217;s foreign intelligence service briefed a parliamentary committee over there that it had intercepted radio communications of Russian soldiers talking about killing civilians.&nbsp; Is the U.S. either aware of that intelligence, or does it have any intercepts of its own that show something similar?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have seen the reports, but I don&#8217;t have anything more on those reports or the intelligence.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I guess the President obviously tested negative today.&nbsp; And according to CDC guidelines &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yesterday.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, yesterday.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaker Pelosi was not considered a close contact, but it seems like a very close call.&nbsp; I know you said that he had a second booster and that he&#8217;s following CDC guidelines.&nbsp; But given the importance of his role and his age, is the White House considering any stricter measures to keep him safe: more mask wearing, fewer big venue events, more outdoor events?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, when you say it&#8217;s a “close call,” I&#8217;m not sure what you mean by that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Close call in the sense that they were in two events at the White House together; within two days, she tested positive.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, sure.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, for clarity purposes, what &#8212; the way a “close contact” is defined &#8212; it&#8217;s not arbitrary.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not something made up by the White House.&nbsp; It&#8217;s CDC guidelines.&nbsp; And how they define it is being within six feet for a cumulative total of 15 minutes over a 24-hour period.&nbsp; That &#8212; they were not.&nbsp; All of their interactions were publicly available; I think you saw them.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s how that assessment is made.</p>



<p>In terms of additional testing or anything along those lines, those assessments would be made by the President&#8217;s doctor.&nbsp; He was tested last evening and tested negative.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have incredibly stringent protocols here at the White House that we keep in place to keep the President safe, to keep everybody safe.&nbsp; Those go over and above CDC guidelines, and that includes ensuring that anyone who is going to be around the President is tested.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Every member of the staff is on a regular testing protocol.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re going to see him in person, whether you&#8217;re traveling with him or you&#8217;re meeting in the Oval Office, you will be tested.&nbsp; If you &#8212; we try to do socially distanced meetings when necessary.&nbsp; For those employees who test positive, they are required to isolate, of course, in alignment with CDC guidance, and must test negative before returning to work.&nbsp; That is also a step that goes over and above.</p>



<p>But we are going to continue to follow the protocols.&nbsp; And I would remind you and reiterate that we also put out a plan just a month ago that made clear that while COVID-19 will continue to be with us and we will see cases rise and fall, as we are seeing them rise now &#8212; to be expected, given the transmissibility of BA.2 &#8212; we can now &#8212; we now have steps to go back to many of our normal routines in alignment with what the CDC continues to recommend.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And given the fact that there has been this uptick among, you know, people who have been following CDC guidelines, are there plans to revisit those guidelines or edit them in some way, given the uptick?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That would be up to the CDC.&nbsp; But again, I think when they put out these guidelines, they made clear that it was about looking at data on hospitalizations and even deaths.&nbsp; And what we have a plan to address, and I would note &#8212; I have it with me, because we really like COVID props this week &#8212; right here.&nbsp; We have copies for anyone who would like a copy.</p>



<p>And this is a 100-page preparedness plan that we put out that &#8212; meant to protect against and treat COVID, prepare for new variants, prevent shutdowns, vaccinate the world.</p>



<p>We expected there to be ups and downs and increases.&nbsp; And with a transmissible &#8212; a variant that’s as transmissible as BA.2, that’s what we&#8217;re seeing at this point in time in the White House, in &#8212; among the press corps, among the general public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the most important message we&#8217;re sending to the public is that we have steps in place that we can take to continue to address it.&nbsp; And even as we&#8217;re continuing to fight COVID, we can, for the most part, return to our normal routines.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And quickly, on another topic.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Congress voted to remove most-favored-nation trade status for Russia and Belarus and ban oil imports.&nbsp; Does President Biden plan to sign &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A hundred to zero.&nbsp; Right?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Exactly.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes, this is something the President supports, had called for, and certainly plans to sign it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back on COVID, you just said that anyone who is around the President is tested.&nbsp; Does that apply just to Executive Office employees, or is that true also of any members of Congress or invited guests who are here at the White House meeting with the President?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; If they are individuals who have a meeting with the President.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I was referring to: our own protocols.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, if you&#8217;re at an event, obviously there are assessments made on a case by case.&nbsp; But if somebody is going to be in close proximity, standing next to him, sitting next to him on a stage, that would be obviously different than a broad group of attendees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And given, sort of, the uptick in cases that we&#8217;ve seen here at the White House, on the Hill &#8212; there seems to be, you know, cases going around within the political world here in Washington &#8212; and the fact that sometimes you do go beyond the CDC-recommended guidelines, is there any plan just to test the President daily for the next few days or week or so?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That would be a decision made by his doctor, but that is not deemed to be necessary at this point.</p>



<p>Q    And on another topic: A Service agent from the First Lady&#8217;s detail was placed on administrative leave after they associated with and were provided gifts from two men who were pretending to be Homeland Security Investigations agents.  Is the First Lady aware of this?  Is the President aware of this? How concerned are they?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any comment from here.&nbsp; I&#8217;d point you to the Secret Service and others investigating.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, just &#8212; do you have any further guidance on what these two men were after or who they may have been working with?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s being investigated, and I would point you to the proper agencies for any further comment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Back on COVID, it&#8217;s pretty clear that vaccines and boosters are not going to prevent you from getting COVID, but we know from science that masking does.&nbsp; Given you yourself saying, you know, how transmissible BA.2 is, are there any conversations happening here on campus, at the White House, to reinstate a mask mandate?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We would continue to follow CDC guidance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not what they&#8217;re recommending, given we are in a yellow zone at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are individuals who are masked because they are close contact, and that is part of our protocols &#8212; they have had a close contact.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s part of our protocols.&nbsp; And individuals who may decide to mask because they have health issues in their family, personally.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something we also certainly support.&nbsp; But we would always abide by CDC guidance and go beyond it if necessary.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And given what you&#8217;ve said about the plan in place and about living with COVID, is the end goal not to stop the spread anymore?&nbsp; Is it just to stop severe cases?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Or are you still trying to stop the spread?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Of course, we&#8217;re trying to stop the spread, and we have the means to address that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re also, though &#8212; I would point you to the 100-page plan we put out just a month ago, where it made clear that we will continue to see COVID &#8212; COVID will continue to be with us; we will see cases rise and fall.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We now know how to protect ourselves from hospitalization and death, which is hugely important.&nbsp; We know how &#8212; how much getting vaccinated, getting boosted can protect you.&nbsp; And we know, here in the White House, of course, 99 percent of people are vaccinated; many, many people are boosted.&nbsp; And so, we have policies that also go even beyond.</p>



<p>What is most important right now, as we&#8217;re looking broadly to the country, is the fact that we are very concerned about the failure of Congress to continue to fund our COVID response &#8212; the fact that we have needed to, therefore, end our program for the uninsured.&nbsp; We are not going to be able to make purchases of a broad scope of boosters; of Evusheld, which is a treatment for immunocompromised &#8212; or preventative treatment for immunocompromised.&nbsp; That when we get to the end of June, our testing capacity will be at risk of collapsing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as we&#8217;re looking broadly beyond the White House of how we&#8217;re planning, that is our greatest, biggest concern at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And just one more on the news of the day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You just talked about how historic today was for Judge Jackson to be confirmed, but no reporters were allowed in the room, no TV cameras were allowed in the room to help record that history.&nbsp; Can you help us understand that decision?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, today was meant to be a private moment between the President and Judge Jackson.&nbsp; And we made a decision late in the process that we would have some photographers &#8212; some of your colleagues in the news media &#8212; in the room to capture it for history.&nbsp; Those photos have been used by networks &#8212; including, likely, your network &#8212; over the course of the last hour.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this was meant to be a private moment.&nbsp; Tomorrow, as we&#8217;ve announced, we have an event &#8212; a moment in history &#8212; where, certainly, the President will be speaking.&nbsp; We will have a range of guests.&nbsp; It will be an outside event.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be marking it in that way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; How can you guys say that President Biden was not a close contact with Speaker Pelosi when there is video of the Speaker kissing him?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, the way that it is defined is by the Center for Disease Control &#8212; the CDC.&nbsp; And their definition of it is 15 minutes of contact within a set period of time within six feet.&nbsp; It did not meet that bar.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It does not mean that no one will get COVID around the world who does not have a close contact.&nbsp; It just means we are defining, for all of you, whether the President and their interaction met the definition of the CDC of a close contact.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Half the Cabinet was there on Tuesday.&nbsp; At least two additional Cabinet members &#8212; Raimondo and Garland &#8212; already have COVID.&nbsp; Is there a threat that this is going to be a national security problem if the Cabinet comes to the White House and starts getting infected with COVID?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think, Peter, we can assess where they &#8212; where they got COVID or where they &#8212; where they acquired COVID &#8212; or whatever the right way to say that is.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that it was Tuesday.&nbsp; There are other events obviously that have happened over the course of the last week as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They are all boosted.&nbsp; They are all &#8212; many of them are able to work from home, as many staff and even reporters are, who are &#8212; who are vaccinated and boosted.&nbsp; And they all have a talented and experienced team who is stepping into their shoes where needed in the office.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When the last President wanted to host a big event for a Supreme Court nominee here at the White House, some folks got COVID and then-former Vice President Biden called it a “super spreader event.”&nbsp; So is there any risk that this event tomorrow for a Biden Supreme Court, now, Justice is going to be a super spreader event?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one, at that point in time, vaccines weren&#8217;t available.&nbsp; People were not vaccinated.&nbsp; It certainly puts us in a different space.&nbsp; This event is also going to be outside tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on a different topic, when Title 42 expires next month, what is the plan for the 18,000 migrants a day that are going to cross?&nbsp; Do you want them to get jobs here?&nbsp; Is there something else that you want these 18,000 a day to be doing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know where you&#8217;re basing your specific numbers on, Peter.&nbsp; But what I would tell you &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Eighteen thousand &#8212; I&#8217;ve got it right here: “Earlier this week, the Department gave reporters an estimate that up to 18,000 migrants could be apprehended at the border each day if Title 42 were to be lifted.”&nbsp; That’s from ABC News.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, “up to.”&nbsp; And we’ll see what happens.&nbsp; And, obviously, we&#8217;re taking steps to convey that this is not the time to come.&nbsp; Individuals who come to the border &#8212; this is what would happen: CBP and ICE would work together to ensure that anyone who enters the country without authorization is put into immigration proceedings as quickly as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>CBP has been working with ICE to ensure individuals awaiting processing in the interior of the country monitor und- &#8212; would be monitored under the Alternatives to Detention program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know that, to date, nearly 80 percent of non-citizens waiting in the interior under prosecut- &#8212; prosecutorial discretion have either received a notice to appear or are still within their window to report.&nbsp; That is what would happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, I would note the Department of Homeland Security also put together a preparedness plan to continue addressing irregular migration that involves surging personnel and resources to the border, improving border processing, implementing mitigation measures, and working with other countries in the hemisphere to manage migration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those are all steps that they&#8217;re working to do in order to implement when we get to that point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the last one on this: Now that the Texas governor is saying that he&#8217;s going to start busing border crossers to Washington, D.C., when they get here, are you guys going to help them find a place to stay and something for them to do?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not aware of what authority the governor would be doing that under.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s pretty clear this is a publicity stunt.&nbsp; His own office admits that a migrant would need to voluntarily be transported and that he can&#8217;t compel them to.&nbsp; Because again, enforcement of our country&#8217;s immigration laws lies with the federal government, not a state.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You don’t think people want to visit Washington, D.C.?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, listen, I don&#8217;t know, but I know that the governor of Texas or any state does not have the legal authority to compel anyone to get on a bus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, is there pressure to avoid saying that President Biden has a &#8212; had a close contact given his position and the demands of his schedule?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; We announced yesterday the Vice President had a close contact.&nbsp; And if there is 15 minutes that he spends with somebody in person within six feet and they test positive for COVID, then that would be a close contact.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, given, you said, it’s not &#8212; it doesn’t necessarily take 15 minutes to get COVID &#8212; right?&nbsp; So it could take less than that.&nbsp; Obviously, he was around Nancy Pelosi and many others.&nbsp; Are you doing anything differently?&nbsp; Is there anything being done differently, given that circumstance for the President?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He was tested last night and tested negative.&nbsp; And if his doctor deems he should be tested more frequently, he certainly could do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if just, for example &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But, again, the CDC guidelines are in place. And the CDC specifics on what a close contact and how it&#8217;s defined are in place for a reason: to give everybody clear, data-driven guidance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is clear, but it&#8217;s not always accurate, right? Because it doesn&#8217;t take 15 minutes to get COVID, and this is more transmissible &#8212; this latest variant &#8212; than other variants in the past.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t necessarily require that much time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, yesterday we were in the State Dining Room.&nbsp; The President was face to face with many individuals, right up in their mugs, for extended periods of time because he was enjoying this moment &#8212; a chance to visit with folks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, for clarity, not everybody in that room was tested in advance of arriving.&nbsp; Correct?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, some of those people who may have been further back but ultimately had, I don’t know, five minutes &#8212; we watched for an hour, literally &#8212; in the room may not have been with him for 15 minutes, but could have been in his face having not been tested for an extended period of time.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, if individuals are within six feet of him for 15 minutes or more, that&#8217;s considered a close contact.&nbsp; No one in there was, that I&#8217;m aware of.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ketanji Brown Jackson tested negative before her visit today, I trust.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more details on Ketanji Brown Jackson’s testing protocols.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me ask you about the Secret Service very quickly, if I can.&nbsp; Does the President maintain confidence in the Director of the Secret Service, James Murray?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen?&nbsp; Jen?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me just get some clarity.&nbsp; Is it your sense that Judge Jackson will ascend to the bench sooner than the end of the term?&nbsp; Because our understanding was that Justice Breyer was going to retire at the end of the term.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates on that, but &#8212; or any changes to that, no.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I want to give you a chance to respond.&nbsp; Jonathan Swan did an interview with Mitch McConnell this morning, in which he &#8212; Swan asked McConnell whether, if the Republicans should take the Senate in the midterm elections and another vacancy should occur while this President is still in office, whether a Republican-controlled Senate would hold a hearing on another Biden nominee.&nbsp; He refused to answer that question.&nbsp; Do you have a response to that?&nbsp; And what do you think it says about the health of our constitutional system?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think given it&#8217;s a day where, with bipartisan support, we have a new &#8212; we are about to have a new member of the Supreme Court &#8212; a historic and eminently qualified member of the Supreme Court &#8212; and she did get three Republicans supporting her &#8212; that is a good sign and something we should take a moment to celebrate.</p>



<p>Certainly, we don&#8217;t anticipate or predict &#8212; I have no prediction of an additional opening, but we would certainly expect and call for all members of the Senate to operate as professionally as the President and our team did in this case, which is ensuring that there was advice and consent, that she met &#8212; that the &#8212; our nominee met with 97 senators.&nbsp; That&#8217;s obviously a great number from the other party.&nbsp; That is how we would conduct ourselves, and we would expect the same in response.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The CDC aside, and distance, et cetera &#8212; has the President expressed any surprise or amazement that there&#8217;s a number of cases around him?&nbsp; And has he asked for people to stay away?&nbsp; What&#8217;s his &#8212; just his kind of human-level response to what&#8217;s going on?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not at all?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, he&#8217;s &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He&#8217;s completely &#8212; he&#8217;s completely nonplussed by the fact that a growing number of people around him are getting COVID?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have anticipated that there would be rising numbers of COVID cases.&nbsp; It is not the numbers, in here, where it was around Omicron.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know if it was among the press corps.&nbsp; It certainly wasn&#8217;t among the general public.</p>



<p>He knows there are a number of steps and precautions that we put in place and we take to protect him and protect the Vice President and other senior members of the team.&nbsp; That includes testing for anybody who goes to see him.&nbsp; That includes social distancing in meetings whenever possible &#8212; a step we take &#8212; an additional precautionary step we take in order to protect him and protect other senior members of the White House.</p>



<p>Q    And just a second question, if I can.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any ongoing or future &#8212; near-future conversations with China on the Russia situation?&nbsp; Or has the U.S. just concluded China is not going to budge on its position, which is to not really get involved and try to push them off?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There will be ongoing conversations with China, I would expect, including our expectation that they abide by sanctions and that they not provide material support to Russia.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have anything to predict in terms of which channel it will happen through next, but certainly I would expect there will be ongoing and continued conversations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a follow-up on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can I ask whether it&#8217;s the view of the President&#8217;s position that if he gets COVID, he&#8217;ll have a mild case because he has the second booster, given his age and given his health profile?&nbsp; Do you expect it not to be a serious case if he were to get it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that is what we see statistically and through &#8212; as we look at health analysis and data.&nbsp; But, obviously, you know, we would &#8212; he would be treated by his doctor.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to make a prediction of that at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is it fair for us to conclude that the event tomorrow &#8212; was a factor in it being outside and being tomorrow, given outside it’s raining today &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s supposed to be a beautiful day.&nbsp; That is a big factor.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it fair to say COVID risk was part of the calculus in deciding how to mark this confirmation?&nbsp; Did you &#8212; is that part of the reason it&#8217;s outside?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would tell you that the biggest factors are actually that &#8212; and we would’ve had events outside earlier in the week too, had the weather allowed.</p>



<p>It is that time of year, and certainly we do know that it is better to have events outside when you can have them outside.&nbsp; It is meant to be &#8212; it is supposed to be a beautiful day.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not a weatherperson, but that is what everything is telling us.&nbsp; And also, we want to be able to invite a large number of people, and this would enable us to do that.&nbsp; So, those are the biggest factors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there&#8217;s no question, Josh, that that also is true statistically, or (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the CDC is actually a little less clear on the link between the two clauses that you&#8217;re linking. &nbsp;And they talked about, &#8220;Was this person less than six feet away from someone?&#8221; &nbsp;Yes, in President Biden&#8217;s case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then they asked &#8212; they say to consider the time spent with someone starting two days before. &nbsp;So that includes both the ACA event and yesterday&#8217;s event.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, separately, they say, “Have they been in the presence of someone with confirmed or suspected COVID for a total of 15 minutes or more over a 24-hour period?”</p>



<p>As far as we know, Speaker Pelosi might&#8217;ve left right after the event.&nbsp; That was about 14 minutes yesterday.&nbsp; And they spent about 45 minutes the day before.&nbsp; So, is the White House position &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But she wasn&#8217;t &#8212;</p>



<p>Q    &#8212; but she was, like, seven feet away.  She was, you know, as far as you.  So, is it the White House position that President Biden &#8212; 14 minutes, seven feet away from Speaker Pelosi &#8212; is not a close contact, but 15 minutes, six feet away would have been a close contact?</p>



<p>And I ask by way of saying: Was there a discussion of whether to treat him as a close contact to anybody?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he is tested regularly.&nbsp; As you know, he was tested yesterday.&nbsp; He will be tested again soon.&nbsp; He&#8217;s tested typically a couple of times a week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If he is a &#8212; if he were a close contact, the only difference &#8212; or I don&#8217;t even know that it would be a difference; it would be a five &#8212; a five-day te- &#8212; a test five days after your contact.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) he&#8217;d have to wear a mask for 10 days in public.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And if he is a close contact, that is what exactly he will do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And, Jen, sorry &#8212; on the broader COVID question:&nbsp;It looks like that bill has stalled now.&nbsp; What are the short-term consequences of not having new funding in place?&nbsp; Is there a risk that you can&#8217;t proceed with previously announced funding, namely of Pfizer&#8217;s pill, Paxlovid?&nbsp; And when do you think the shipments of the monoclonal antibodies will run out?&nbsp; They were supposed to run out in May, but you’ve been shipping fewer of them.&nbsp; How long will the cupboard last on the monoclonals without any money?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I may have to check on that specific component for you, Josh, and I&#8217;m happy to do that.&nbsp; I mean, what we do know is that, by the end of June, the testing capacity will be at risk.&nbsp; Our testing capacity will be at the risk of &#8212; risk of collapsing, at least from the federal government and what we can provide.</p>



<p>We know that we can&#8217;t buy any additional treatments beyond those that have already been paid for and contracted, of course, including preventative treatments for immunocompromised.&nbsp; Those treatments, as you know, often take six months to manufacture, so we&#8217;d also be losing out on supply that we intended to purchase for September through January. &nbsp;And, of course, the uninsured fund is already closed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I can certainly check on the next purchase of monoclonals and if we &#8212; if we have any ability to purchase that as planned.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the difference if a bill passes three weeks from now versus having &#8212; if it had passed this week?&nbsp; Do those three weeks matter?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we would be able to have the funding, hopefully, to reopen some of our uninsured programming.&nbsp; We&#8217;d be able to get ahead and plan ahead for purchases of testing &#8212; to ensure we had testing capacity; to make sure we could place some orders for treatment &#8212; preventative treatments for the immunocompromised.&nbsp; It just delays the process.</p>



<p>And as we know, they&#8217;re going on a two-week recess right now.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Jen.&nbsp; Thanks. &nbsp;I appreciate it.&nbsp; I have a non-COVID question, I swear. &nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But first I want to &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You can ask me a COVID question too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp; I just want to be specific about tomorrow.&nbsp; Are folks who are attending going to be required to take any additional steps &#8212; you know, other than it being outside and all that stuff &#8212; but testing by senators for example, or, you know, distance kept by the President?&nbsp; Is there going to be anything above and beyond just being outside?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not that I&#8217;m aware of.&nbsp; But it being outside is certainly an important component here.&nbsp; And typically, individuals who are going to be in close proximity, like on the stage or something, they would be tested.&nbsp; But there are protocols that are evaluated on a case by case as we have events.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a question on Puerto Rico &#8212; non-COVID &#8212; I swore, right?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s a million-people-plus without power there.&nbsp; A lot of people criticizing that the federal government has not done enough to fix the grid there &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; after recent hurricanes.&nbsp; I wonder what &#8212; you know, is the President read in on this?&nbsp; Are there any actions that the President is planning to do there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Let me check.&nbsp; I know we&#8217;ve provided a broad range and a significant amount of financial assistance, but let me &#8212; let me check and see where that &#8212; what the status is at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I also ask you about the Amir Locke &#8212; the case involving Amir Locke &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and the officers that are not charged in that case?&nbsp; Is the President read in on that?&nbsp; And is there any &#8212; does he have any thoughts on, like, the no-knock warrants?&nbsp; I think you addressed this in February a little bit, but I wonder if there&#8217;s been any action or movement or further conversation about it.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me give you &#8212; I mean, so, first, like so many across the nation &#8212; and obviously this news is a reminder of how we&#8217;ve all mourned the tragic death of Amir Locke.&nbsp; And our thoughts and prayers continue to be with his family.</p>



<p>The President is committed &#8212; and, of course, he is aware of.&nbsp; And I would point you to the Department of Justice for any specifics about next legal actions.&nbsp; But the President is committed to ensuring fair, impartial, and effective policing, keeping our communities safe.&nbsp; Those goals go hand-in-hand, and we can achieve them, in part, by building trust between the police and communities they serve.</p>



<p>So, to go to your other questions: In September, the Attorney General issued a new policy imposing restrictions on the use of no-knock warrants, chokeholds, and carotid restraints by federal agents.</p>



<p>President Biden also continues to call on Congress to pass comprehensive police reform legislation.&nbsp; But since Republicans refuse to support the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act, we are looking at additional steps we can take.&nbsp; We are continuing to look at them on executive action to advance police reform, obviously something we put a pause on while that was being negotiated.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have an update on the timing of that, but that is something we are continuing to look at to build on, of course, the actions taken by the Department of Justice.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Jen.&nbsp; You noted that Vice President Kamala Harris is considered a close contact.&nbsp; CDC guidance says to wear a mask.&nbsp; Today, she was presiding over the vote for Ketanji Brown Jackson and didn’t wear a mask.&nbsp; I guess, does the White House have a response to that?&nbsp; Was that a breach of protocol?&nbsp; Or, I guess, what made it different that she didn&#8217;t have to wear a mask?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t seen &#8212; I obviously watched most parts of the vote, but I know that she was alone, up &#8212; kind of on the dais for the vast majority of that.&nbsp; And, of course, she has been wearing a mask otherwise.&nbsp; But beyond that, I haven&#8217;t &#8212; I haven&#8217;t done any further analysis.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more question, sort of on immigration.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are reports that there has been an increased number of Ukrainian refugees heading to this &#8212; that are at the southern border &#8212; around 2,000 in Tijuana.&nbsp; I guess I was wondering, what are the administration&#8217;s plans to kind of address a rise of Ukrainian refugees that might come to the southern border?</p>



<p>You know, the State Department hasn&#8217;t really outlined the specifics on how they want to, you know, address allowing 100,000 Ukrainian refugees to the U.S.&nbsp; So, I guess, is there any other preparations that are being made in addition to whatever expected rise of migrants coming to the border once Title 42 ends?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I would say that we are still working through the policy process that, hopefully, we&#8217;ll have more to say on soon about what specific mechanisms Ukrainians can apply who wish to come to the United States, even though we know the vast majority have made clear they would like to stay in neighboring countries, which is why we&#8217;re providing the most humanitarian assistance of any country in the world to support those efforts that neighboring countries are &#8212; have undertaken to host refugees.</p>



<p>There are very good questions, I&#8217;m sure you have, about family reunification, prioritization, and whether there will be prioritization for individuals who fear persecution and things along those lines.&nbsp; Those are all important questions that are being discussed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we are still implementing Title 42 at the border for anyone who comes to the border.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working toward implementation of the lifting of Title 42 next month. &nbsp;And we would apply the policy to everybody.&nbsp; But obviously &#8212; coming from any country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, obviously, there would be these programs &#8212; and we&#8217;d have more details before then, for sure &#8212; that Ukrainians who are eligible would be able to apply for.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; The first one is: &#8220;Budget Day&#8221; in Ottawa today.&nbsp; And up to $8 billion in new money will go to defense purpose, which will be bring Canada&#8217;s defense contribution to approximately 1.5 percent of the GDP; not yet to the 2 percent.&nbsp; Does the administration wish Canada would do more, considering the actual war in Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we applaud that increase, and we applaud Canada&#8217;s efforts and support for &#8212; in standing up against the invasion of Ukraine by President Putin and the Russians.&nbsp; And they are an important partner and continue to be.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my second question, it goes back to the aid &#8212; the aid you detailed at the beginning of the briefing to the Russian military, all sorts of &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Ukrainian military.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Ukrainian &#8212; yeah, Ukraine military, of course.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; I just want to verify again: You referred to, you know, that they &#8212; there are requests coming to you, and you go through the list, and sometimes you need old Soviet equipment.&nbsp; Are the MiG-29s in &#8212; still in the list?&nbsp; And is the administration considering transferring those Polish planes to Ukraine (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our policy has not changed, but other countries, of course, could make that determination and decide to do it, and we certainly wouldn&#8217;t stand in the way.&nbsp; But our policy has not changed.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, when &#8212; so when President Biden continued the pause on student loan payments &#8212; repayments, he said that that pause will provide a “continued lifeline as we recover and rebuild from the pandemic.”&nbsp; You said today you want to stop the spread of COVID.&nbsp; So, my question is: If we&#8217;re still recovering from the pandemic, why then is Title 42 going to be re-lifted?&nbsp; Is there a revis- &#8212; a revisit that you can look at that?&nbsp; And have we just recovered from the border, then &#8212; does that mean?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me see if I can unpack &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; a few things in there.&nbsp; First, on the announcement about the extension of student loan pau- &#8212; the student loan pause: What I said yesterday is also that what we look at is the impact of the pandemic on the economic recovery.&nbsp; And even though the economy has &#8212; is very strong &#8212; look at the UI data from today; look at the jobs data from last Friday &#8212; we certainly know that costs are continuing to impact people across the country, including students who have &#8212; who have &#8212; or former students who have student loan payments they need to make.</p>



<p>And the President is going to look for every way he can lower costs for the American people, whether that is the “family <s>fix</s> [glitch]” that he announced with former President Obama earlier this week or the announcement about the pause on student loan payments. </p>



<p>The decision about Title 42 is a decision made by the CDC &#8212; a public health decision.&nbsp; It’s not immigration authority or policy, it&#8217;s a public health decision, and we respect the authority given to them by Congress to make that determination.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And one more.&nbsp; The President said that sanctions were not a deterrent on Russia going into Ukraine.&nbsp; Yesterday, Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen is saying that the U.S. would use all its sanction tools should China move towards Taiwan.&nbsp; So, is that message a deterrent or not?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have sanctioned China in the past, as you know, for human rights abuses.&nbsp; And we have sanctioned a range of countries, certainly, around the world.&nbsp; I would say sanctions have a range of purposes, including putting consequences in place.&nbsp; And where we are, as it relates to the war in Ukraine, is also making it much more difficult for President Putin to fund this war, and that is a huge priority to us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have any predictions about future sanctions.&nbsp; I would leave that at the comments of the Treasury Secretary.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But given how &#8212; given how intertwined our economies are, could we really do sanctions on China like we are on &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is assessment that the Department of Treasury would have to make, but I don&#8217;t have a prediction beyond what the Secretary of Treasury said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; This week, you’ve been critical of Republicans trying to add amendment votes onto the COVID funding bill, specifically regarding Title 42.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, you said they decided to move the goalposts and that the White House is questioning whether Republicans are acting in good faith or if they&#8217;re just playing politics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But Democratic senators Mark Kelly, Kyrsten Sinema, Joe Manchin, Maggie Hassan, and Jon Tester are joining Republicans in this effort.&nbsp; Does the White House have the same criticism we&#8217;ve heard about Republicans?&nbsp; Does that apply to these Democratic senators as well?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, regardless of who&#8217;s standing against this, our larger point here is: If we do not have treatments, vaccines, or tests that the American people need, Americans will die from COVID and &#8212; whether they support or oppose the administration on immigration or childcare, environt- &#8212; environmental rules &#8212; anybody.</p>



<p>And so, our point: It’s not political.&nbsp; The vast majority of people who are opposing this moving forward are Republicans; that is a fact.&nbsp; But our point here is that there is an urgency to move forward.&nbsp; We can have a range of debates about a range of issues we have disagreements on; that&#8217;s fine &#8212; immigration, childcare, environmental rules. &nbsp;We welcome that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the way, the President put forward an immigration bill his first day in office.&nbsp; If Republicans want to work on immigration, come on down to the White House; we&#8217;re happy to work with you on it.</p>



<p>But right now, this is a game of politics, and we need to get this funding, otherwise people in the country are going to die.&nbsp; That&#8217;s our larger point.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick follow-up on Vice President Harris.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; She was a close contact.&nbsp; Tomorrow, during the event or if there&#8217;s any reception behind the scenes, will she be required to wear a mask indoors?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; She&#8217;ll follow CDC protocols in any of her events.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; The congressional approval from the confirmation vote today tells us that Senator Rand Paul cast his vote from the GOP cloakroom.&nbsp; He was in casual clothes, without a suit jacket or tie, so he was unable to come onto the floor. There are reports, I think, two other Republican senators may have done similar.&nbsp; Is that an appropriate way to vote on a historic occasion like this?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will tell you, I&#8217;m not spending a lot of time, nor is the President, thinking about the dress code of Rand Paul today.&nbsp; We&#8217;re thinking about the historic confirmation of an eminently qualified Black woman to serve on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Not really worried about his khakis.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if I &#8212; if I may as well: We&#8217;ve enjoyed your shout-outs to members of your team.&nbsp; I wonder if this means you&#8217;re now working on notice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, what?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Whether you&#8217;re now &#8212; is that an American phrase? &#8212; whether you&#8217;re now working on notice, on your &#8212; on your way out.&nbsp; Is it underway?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; I think I&#8217;m &#8212; I &#8212; it’s &#8212; I don&#8217;t know that it&#8217;s an American phrase.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I &#8212; I have &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Excuse my Briticism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, no, I &#8212; I love the Britishness and the accent, not to put you on notice of sorts.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I think it is simply a reflection of my appreciation for the incredible people on my team that I get to work with every day.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve shouted them out in the past before.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve ma- &#8212; I&#8217;ve presented them with sashes to wear &#8212; all sorts of embarrassing things.&nbsp; And I think working in the White House, just like being a reporter &#8212; people think you have glamorous se- &#8212; glamorous setups back there.&nbsp; I&#8217;m here to confirm that is not the case.&nbsp; But our team works their tails off.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot going on.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just simply an effort to recognize that.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have nothing to announce about &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Final question, Jen.&nbsp; Jen, final question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that is: What is this administration’s response to Israel for their role as mediator in this Russia-Ukraine crisis?&nbsp; And I have a follow-up question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, we certainly support the efforts of a range of leaders to &#8212; that &#8212; who are hoping to play a diplomatic role here.&nbsp; And there are a number of leaders around the world who have also had engagements with Russians and engagements with the Ukrainians, and we just ask that they all engage closely with Ukrainians as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; To help Europe develop energy independence from Russia, would the Biden administration drop its opposition to the EU EastMed pipeline being developed by Israel, Cyprus, and Greece?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think there&#8217;s going to be decisions made by European leaders about how to reduce their &#8212; any level of dependence they have on Russian oil.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve seen a number of leaders this week announce their intention to ban oil imports from Russia.&nbsp; But I would remind you that pipelines are a means of moving oil; it&#8217;s not a means of production.&nbsp; But I’d point you to the European leader to speak to that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks so much, everyone.</p>



<p>3:19 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden on the UN Vote Suspending Russia from the Human Rights&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-un-vote-suspending-russia-from-the-human-rights-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50748</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I applaud the overwhelming vote today in the General Assembly of the United Nations to kick Russia off the UN Human Rights Council. This is a meaningful step by the international community further demonstrating how Putin’s war has made Russia an international pariah. The United States worked closely with our Allies and partners around the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I applaud the overwhelming vote today in the General Assembly of the United Nations to kick Russia off the UN Human Rights Council. This is a meaningful step by the international community further demonstrating how Putin’s war has made Russia an international pariah.</p>



<p>The United States worked closely with our Allies and partners around the world to drive this vote because Russia is committing gross and systemic violations of human rights. Russian forces are committing war crimes. Russia has no place on the Human Rights Council. After today’s historic vote, Russia will not be able to participate in the Council’s work or spread its disinformation there as the Council’s Commission of Inquiry investigates Russia’s violations and abuses of human rights in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The images we are seeing out of Bucha and other areas of Ukraine as Russian troops withdraw are horrifying. The signs of people being raped, tortured, executed—in some cases having their bodies desecrated—are an outrage to our common humanity. Russia’s lies are no match for the undeniable evidence of what is happening in Ukraine. That’s why nations in every region condemn Russia’s unprovoked and brutal aggression against Ukraine and support the brave people of Ukraine in their fight for freedom. And we will continue to work with responsible nations around the world to gather evidence to hold Russia accountable for the atrocities being committed, increase the pressure on Russia’s economy, and isolate Russia on the international stage.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 20:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50738</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Robin Meredith Cohn Hutcheson, of Utah, to be Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration, vice Raymond Martinez. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Jaime E. Lizárraga, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Securities and Exchange Commission for a term expiring June 5, 2027, vice Allison Herren Lee, term expiring. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Vincent Garfield Logan,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Robin Meredith Cohn Hutcheson, of Utah, to be Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration, vice Raymond Martinez.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Jaime E. Lizárraga, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Securities and Exchange Commission for a term expiring June 5, 2027, vice Allison Herren Lee, term expiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Vincent Garfield Logan, of New York, to be a Member of the Farm Credit Administration Board, Farm Credit Administration, for a term expiring May 21, 2026, vice Dallas P. Tonsager, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Mark Toshiro Uyeda, of California, to be a Member of the Securities and Exchange Commission for the remainder of the term expiring June 5, 2023, vice Elad L. Roisman, resigned.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Carla Ravi Koppell, of New York, to be an Assistant Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Michelle A. Bekkering, which was sent to the Senate on September 21, 2021.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;David Weil, of Massachusetts, to be Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division, Department of Labor, vice Cheryl Marie Stanton, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-63/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 19:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Sharon Beth Lewis, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2022, vice Alan L. Cohen, term expired.      Sharon Beth Lewis, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sharon Beth Lewis, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2022, vice Alan L. Cohen, term expired.</p>



<p>       Sharon Beth Lewis, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2028.   (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Patricia Hart Neuman, of the District of Columbia, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for a term of four years, vice Robert D. Reischauer, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Patricia Hart Neuman, of the District of Columbia, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund for a term of four years, vice Robert D. Reischauer, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Patricia Hart Neuman, of the District of Columbia, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund for a term of four years, vice Robert D. Reischauer, term expired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Senate transmitting the Extradition Treaty between the Government of the United&#160;States of America and the Government of the Republic of&#160;Albania</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/a-message-to-the-senate-transmitting-the-extradition-treaty-between-the-government-of-the-united-states-of-america-and-the-government-of-the-republic-of-albania/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 19:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50732</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE&#160;SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES: &#160; &#160;With a view to receiving the advice and consent of the Senate to ratification, I transmit herewith the Extradition Treaty between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of Albania (the &#8220;Treaty&#8221;), signed at Tirana on December 22, 2020.&#160;&#160;I also transmit,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE&nbsp;SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp;With a view to receiving the advice and consent of the Senate to ratification, I transmit herewith the Extradition Treaty between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of Albania (the &#8220;Treaty&#8221;), signed at Tirana on December 22, 2020.&nbsp;&nbsp;I also transmit, for the information of the Senate, the report of the Department of State with respect to the Treaty.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;The Treaty would replace the extradition treaty between the United States and Albania, signed at Tirana on March 1, 1933.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Treaty follows generally the form and content of other extradition treaties recently concluded by the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp;It would replace an outmoded list of extraditable offenses with a modern &#8220;dual criminality&#8221; approach, which would enable extradition for such offenses as money laundering, cyber-related crimes, and other newer offenses not appearing on the list.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Treaty also contains a modernized &#8220;political offense&#8221; clause and provides that extradition shall not be refused based on the nationality of the person sought.&nbsp;&nbsp;Finally, the Treaty incorporates a series of procedural improvements to streamline and expedite the extradition process.</p>



<p>   I recommend that the Senate give early and favorable consideration to the Treaty, and give its advice and consent to ratification.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"> JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>        April 7, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden for World Health Day&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/statement-from-president-joe-biden-for-world-health-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 17:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For too many families, in too many places, worrying about health problems and access to health care is a daily reality.&#160;&#160;So today, on World Health Day, let us reaffirm our commitment to building a future that is safer, more equitable, and healthier,&#160;for families here and abroad. Since day one of my Administration, we have renewed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For too many families, in too many places, worrying about health problems and access to health care is a daily reality.&nbsp;&nbsp;So today, on World Health Day, let us reaffirm our commitment to building a future that is safer, more equitable, and healthier,&nbsp;for families here and abroad.</p>



<p>Since day one of my Administration, we have renewed U.S. leadership in global health, starting here at home. As we vaccinated 255 million Americans and fought COVID-19, we also lowered health care costs and enrolled a record breaking 14.5 million people; expanded postpartum coverage in several states; released a new Overdose Prevention Strategy; and launched a national strategy to treat mental health and physical health concerns equally. </p>



<p>On the global stage, we have led an ambitious campaign with our allies and partners to fight COVID-19, strengthen global health systems, and finance future pandemic preparedness. We have already shipped more than 516 million COVID-19 vaccines to countries around the world, with no strings attached, and we have pledged another 700 million by the end of this year. But we have to keep up the fight. More work lies ahead, and Congress must continue funding our fight against COVID-19, at home&nbsp;<em>and</em>&nbsp;abroad.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>While we focus on COVID-19, we have also reinvigorated our efforts and our investments to&nbsp;address core global health challenges. We’re doubling down on our commitment to meet our 2030 goals to end the AIDS epidemic. We’re boosting efforts to fight tuberculosis and malaria, including through our $2 billion commitment to the Global Fund and by rallying contributions from around the world. We’re working to reverse the alarming downward trend in global life expectancy and the impacts of the climate crisis by making foundational investments in childhood vaccinations, maternal and reproductive health, and basic nutrition. And it’s why the United States&nbsp;joined the Universal Health Coverage Group of Friends – a coalition of countries dedicated to strengthening health systems and expanding access to health coverage around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This pandemic has spotlighted the critical role and bravery of health and care workers. That’s why I’ve asked my Administration to develop a global health workforce plan, to accelerate our contributions to the Sustainable Development Agenda and investments in health and care workers.</p>



<p>Our&nbsp;health and security at home are irrevocably connected to the health and security of people everywhere. On this World Health Day, let us recommit to making sure that all people can access the health care they need.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration’s Commitment to Global Health in the FY 2023 President’s&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-commitment-to-global-health-in-the-fy-2023-presidents-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 17:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States Government is proud to be the largest donor for global health and supporter of research and cooperation worldwide. As we work to end the COVID-19 pandemic, we remain committed to investing in global public health, science partnerships and collaboration, strengthening health systems and institutions, advancing global health security, and accelerating efforts towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States Government is proud to be the largest donor for global health and supporter of research and cooperation worldwide. As we work to end the COVID-19 pandemic, we remain committed to investing in global public health, science partnerships and collaboration, strengthening health systems and institutions, advancing global health security, and accelerating efforts towards achieving universal health coverage and the objectives of the Sustainable Development Agenda. The President’s Budget for Fiscal Year (FY) 2023 requests mandatory and discretionary funding totaling over $17 billion for the Department of State (State) and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and over $11 billion for the Department of Health and Human Services to advance U.S. leadership in global health, including health system strengthening; HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis; maternal and child health; family planning and reproductive health; nutrition; global health security, and pandemic and other biological threat preparedness, and neglected tropical diseases.</p>



<p>We continue to lead the global community toward a safer, more equitable future.&nbsp;&nbsp;Investments in global health advance U.S. foreign policy interests by protecting Americans at home and abroad, promoting economic progress and recovery, and supporting the rise of capable partners to better solve regional and global problems.<br>Over the last year, the Biden-Harris Administration has renewed U.S. leadership in global health, and the FY 2023 Budget will continue to advance global health priorities on the following:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Strengthening health systems, including the global health workforce.&nbsp;</strong>The FY 2023 Budget prioritizes sustained investment across health programs to support health system resilience and strengthening. The Budget provides $1 billion in mandatory funding for State and USAID to support and protect the global health workforce as part of the Administration’s increased prioritization and investments in human resources for health.&nbsp;&nbsp;These resources are intended to support the Administration’s launch of a new Global Health Worker Initiative, which complements the Domestic Health Worker Initiative launched by the Administration last year.&nbsp;&nbsp;In addition, the FY 2023 Request includes $10 million for USAID to establish a Health Resilience Fund (HRF) to support cross-cutting health systems strengthening in countries emerging from crisis. The HRF will provide flexible, no-year funding to ensure basic health services are accessible to those most in need and to build more resilient health services and systems in order to prevent worse outcomes from ongoing health crises. The FY 2023 Request also includes over $265 million in discretionary funding for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) for partnerships that build critical health system capacity for global immunizations and the fight against parasitic diseases and malaria.<br></li><li><strong>Supporting enhanced global leadership on addressing HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis.</strong>&nbsp;The Budget includes $4.37 billion for State to support U.S. President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) bilateral programs and the global AIDS response. Funds will continue to save lives, prevent millions of HIV infections, and help countries build a strong foundation to prevent, detect, and respond to other health threats, including COVID-19. Across 55 countries, PEPFAR invests in strengthening local health systems’ ability to respond to HIV. The FY 2023 Budget also includes $2 billion to support the Global Fund’s seventh replenishment for an intended pledge of $6 billion over three years, to save lives and continue the fight against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria, as well as $780 million for the U.S. President’s Malaria Initiative to continue the fight against malaria. Finally, the FY 2023 Budget requests $350 million for USAID to support programs combatting tuberculosis around the world.<br></li><li><strong>Strengthening multilateral global health institutions:</strong>&nbsp;Funding requested in FY 2023 will support efforts to strengthen our partnerships with multilateral global health institutions, including the World Health Organization and the United Nations Children’s Fund.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Building global health security and pandemic preparedness capacities.</strong>&nbsp;The FY 2023 President’s Budget includes nearly $750 million for USAID, and over $1.5 billion in mandatory and discretionary funding for CDC, to expand global health security capacity building to additional partner countries, strengthen global disease detection, bolster our commitment to the multilateral Global Health Security Agenda, and accelerate progress toward improved prevention, detection, and response to infectious disease threats. Funding through USAID would support $250 million for Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator multilateral organizations, and $590 million in discretionary and mandatory funding to replenish USAID’s Emergency Reserve Fund for Contagious Infectious Diseases (ERF).&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Financing for global health security and pandemic preparedness.&nbsp;</strong>The Budget includes $4.75 billion in mandatory and discretionary funding for State to establish a new financial intermediary fund (FIF) at the World Bank focused on global health security and pandemic preparedness. This catalytic, fit-for-purpose financing mechanism is critical to filling major gaps in the world’s ability to prevent, detect, and respond to infectious disease threats and future pandemics at the national, regional and global levels.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Budget also provides $500 million over five years for the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations (CEPI) to support innovations in science and technological capabilities to shorten the cycle for development of safe, effective, and globally accessible vaccines for pathogens with pandemic potential.<br></li><li><strong>Building global medical countermeasure readiness, research and development,</strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong>advancing capacity to conduct variant and strain surveillance</strong>&nbsp;through support for global innovations in vaccine and therapeutics policy development, program design, and effective monitoring of the viral strains that are circulating globally to detect the emergence of significant variants. The Budget includes $5.9 billion in mandatory funding for CDC for this effort which would expand and strengthen multi-pathogen and molecular laboratory capabilities, bioinformatics systems, and data modernization to detect and monitor respiratory and other high-consequence pathogens.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Advancing biosafety and biosecurity in the United States and globally to prevent biological incidents.&nbsp;</strong>The Budget supports applied research and innovation in biosafety and biosecurity, which will expand capabilities to identify and minimize safety and security risks in the design and development of biotechnology. It also enables CDC and USAID to expand efforts to strengthen biosafety and biosecurity practices and globally.<br></li><li><strong>Leading global threat detection innovations</strong>&nbsp;through a globally connected network of public health surveillance systems that optimizes disease prevention and health promotion as we strengthen surveillance initiatives to provide necessary actionable data before, during, and after a pandemic. The Budget includes $2.47 billion in mandatory funding for CDC to will include enhancements to domestic sentinel surveillance programs, expansion of domestic and global wastewater surveillance, and investments in global genomic surveillance approaches as well as global respiratory disease surveillance platforms. CDC will transition and sustain genomic surveillance capacities initially developed for COVID-19 to support additional priority pathogens.<br></li><li><strong>Sustaining commitments in global maternal and child health.</strong>&nbsp;As the largest donor to both maternal health and voluntary family planning programs, including the provision of life-saving health care services in crisis settings, the United States will continue its efforts to make pregnancy and childbirth safer by strengthening health systems to provide women with integral health services, including increased access to maternal health care and voluntary family planning.&nbsp;The FY 2023 Budget includes $879.5 million for USAID to continue the United States’ sustained commitment to ensure that critical health services continue to prevent child and maternal deaths globally. This includes $290 million for a contribution to Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, to reach children with cost-effective vaccines to accelerate progress towards preventing child deaths. In addition, $25 million is requested for USAID to support&nbsp;the implementation of the U.S. Government’s Strategy Advancing Protection and Care for Children in Adversity and USAID’s Child Blindness Program to reduce childhood blindness and improve eye health.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights.</strong>&nbsp; In the last year, the Administration has taken several legislative and policy steps to advance sexual and reproductive rights around the world, starting with President Biden’s issuance of a Presidential Memorandum on Protecting Women’s Health at Home and Abroad in his first days in office, which revoked the expanded Mexico City Policy and directed agencies to resume funding to the United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) in support of its essential work to prevent maternal deaths, expand access to voluntary family planning, and prevent and respond to gender-based violence around the world.&nbsp; Under the leadership of Secretary Blinken, the Department of State has returned to reporting on sexual and reproductive health issues in its Annual Country Reports on Human Rights. The Administration continues to advance sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR) for all, in support of accelerating progress toward universal health coverage and gender equality. The FY 2023 Budget provides $597 million to continue support for critical SRHR programs globally, as well as a $56 million contribution to the United Nations Population Fund. As the largest bilateral donor to family planning, the United States will continue to lead globally by advancing SRHR in multilateral fora and with bilateral partners. Funds will support increased access to SRHR services.<br></li><li><strong>Continuing to demonstrate strong global leadership on nutrition.</strong>&nbsp;Given increased rates of global malnutrition, and expected further impacts on global food security from Russia’s unprovoked further invasion of Ukraine, the United States will accelerate efforts to support global nutrition, particularly for vulnerable populations. The FY 2023 Budget includes $150 million for USAID for global health nutrition programs, in addition to over $1 billion in State and USAID economic and development assistance, $1.7 billion in emergency food aid via Food for Peace Title II, and humanitarian assistance to support food security and nutrition globally.<br></li><li><strong>Supporting efforts to address neglected tropical diseases.</strong>&nbsp;The FY 2023 Budget includes $114.5 million to continue USAID’s long-standing and effective public-private partnerships with pharmaceutical companies to focus on ending the most prevalent neglected tropical diseases (NTD). Over the past 15 years, USAID has leveraged $27.6 billion in donated medicines, resulting in the delivery of more than 2.8 billion treatments to approximately 1.4 billion people. This funding will also support USAID in achieving its goal to eliminate at least one NTD as a public health problem within 5 years in 15 countries, and to expand private sector partnerships.<br></li><li><strong>Leading the global COVID-19 response.</strong>&nbsp;The Biden Administration has submitted an urgent request to Congress for $5 billion to accelerate near-term COVID-19 global response.&nbsp;&nbsp;Without additional funding to support getting shots into arms, U.S. agencies will have to cut short efforts to turn vaccines into vaccinations across the globe.&nbsp;&nbsp;Leaving large unvaccinated populations worldwide will increase the risk of new, emerging deadly variants that could evade our current vaccines and treatments.&nbsp;&nbsp;Without additional funds, the Administration would be unable to extend Global VAX surge support to 20+ additional under-vaccinated countries that will need intensive support this year to get shots in arms. This will devastate our ability to ensure those countries can effectively deploy safe and effective vaccines. U.S. agencies will also be unable to provide life-saving supplies, tests, therapeutics, oxygen, and humanitarian aid to countries still struggling to manage a continuing COVID-19 disease burden.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Unprecedented IEA Release Following President&#160;Biden’s SPR&#160;Announcement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-unprecedented-iea-release-following-president-bidens-spr-announcement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 17:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week, President Biden announced a historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve of 1 million barrels a day for six months and said it would be in coordination with other countries releasing tens of millions of additional barrels on the market. Today after around the clock diplomacy by the United States and our allies&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Last week, President Biden announced a historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve of 1 million barrels a day for six months and said it would be in coordination with other countries releasing tens of millions of additional barrels on the market. Today after around the clock diplomacy by the United States and our allies and partners, the International Energy Agency announced a historic collective release with member countries outside of the United States releasing an additional 60 million barrels.&nbsp;Together&nbsp;with the United States’ commitment, this&nbsp;will add&nbsp;a combined global amount of 240 million barrels.&nbsp;It is both the largest release from the United States and the largest release from other IEA countries in history, and will support American consumers and the global economy.</p>



<p>Today’s announcement is another result of President Biden’s unwavering focus on doing everything in his power to help American families who are paying more out of pocket as a result of Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine. Since Putin accelerated his military build-up around Ukraine this past winter, gas prices have increased by nearly a dollar per gallon because less oil is getting to market, and the reduction in supply is raising prices at the pump for Americans. We will continue to take every action we can to increase supply in the immediate term so families can pay for gas while at the same time working with the international community to achieve energy independence that reduces demand for oil and bolsters our clean energy economy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden on Unemployment Insurance&#160;Claims</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-unemployment-insurance-claims-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Americans are getting back to work at a historic pace, with fewer America is back to work. Over the last four weeks, fewer Americans filed initial claims for unemployment insurance than at any time in our nation’s recorded history. Our economy added 7.9 million jobs since I took office – more jobs created on average&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Americans are getting back to work at a historic pace, with fewer America is back to work. Over the last four weeks, fewer Americans filed initial claims for unemployment insurance than at any time in our nation’s recorded history. Our economy added 7.9 million jobs since I took office – more jobs created on average per month than under any other President in history. That’s millions of families with a little more breathing room and the dignity a job provides. This historic job growth is a direct result of the American Rescue Plan, which funded our vaccination strategy, re-opened schools, and helped grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out. While we have more work to do to combat Putin’s Price Hike and lower costs for families, today’s data demonstrate that America is on the move again and the economy is uniquely well-positioned to overcome the global challenges brought on by the pandemic and Putin’s War of Choice.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 6,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/06/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-6-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 23:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:15 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; Okay, a couple of items for you at the top.&#160;&#160;On his first day in office, President Biden directed the Department of Education to pause federal student loan repayments through September of that year.&#160; He has since extended it twice, today being the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:15 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay, a couple of items for you at the top.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On his first day in office, President Biden directed the Department of Education to pause federal student loan repayments through September of that year.&nbsp; He has since extended it twice, today being the third extension.&nbsp; Millions of Americans were struggling, of course, at that time to stay afloat.&nbsp; Because of the pause in repayments, 41 million Americans were able to breathe a little easier during some of the toughest days of the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, as America &#8212; America is stronger than we were a year ago and we will be stronger a year from now than we are today.&nbsp; However, as our administration recognized in recently extending the COVID-19 national emergency, we are still recovering from the pandemic and the unprecedented economic disruption it caused &#8212; which, of course, is the root reason for this extension.<br>&nbsp;<br>In order to enable Americans to continue to get back on their feet after two of the hardest years this nation has ever faced, we have announced, earlier today, of course, the plan to &#8212; the extension of the pause on federal student loan repayments through August 31st of this year.&nbsp; That additional time will assist borrowers in achieving greater financial security and support the Department of Education’s efforts to continue improving student loan programs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Also would note &#8212; one note on the COVID funding bill.&nbsp; We have made clear for months about our funding needs.&nbsp; And at every step of the way, we&#8217;ve provided the details that Republicans have asked for, even when they&#8217;ve asked for &#8212; has changed in real time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I have a little prop here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to call him “Vanna” over here.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; This is Kevin Munoz.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is 385 pages of information we have given to Capitol Hill and briefed them on how COVID funding has been spent, what we need, what the needs are.&nbsp; These are the kind of details we have provided and constantly briefed members on the Hill to make clear to them what the impact will be if we do not get this funding.&nbsp; You can have access to this for a prop if you would like it as well.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll make copies for you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; But unfortunately, as we&#8217;ve gone through before, going back to January &#8212; while we&#8217;ve worked, going back to January, with members of Congress &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; on the funding needs, we&#8217;ve hosted dozens of briefings, we&#8217;ve held more than three dozen conference calls, we&#8217;ve shared more than a dozen funding tables &#8212; all available 385 pages.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve also given Congress a full accounting of every dollar that&#8217;s been spent on the COVID medical response and a full accounting of the entire American Rescue Plan, which, as you all know, goes well beyond the direct medical needs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve also provided all the specifics of planned additional funding: how it will be deployed against the additional purchase of monoclonals and pills and vaccine &#8212; vaccines.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And unfortunately, even after Senate leadership agreed upon a &#8212; on a pared down bipartisan bill, Senate Republicans decided to move the goalposts yet again and force amendment votes on something completely independent of our COVID response needs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And at this point, we &#8212; the question we have is whether Republicans are acting in good faith to provide the resources we need to save American lives or if they are just playing politics.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The virus is not waiting for Republicans in Congress to get their act together.&nbsp; We know BA.2 is here.&nbsp; We know that it is more transmissible.&nbsp; We know that it is leading to increased cases, and we know we&#8217;re already seeing an impact on our resources.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The program that reimbursed doct- &#8212; doctors, pharmacists, and other providers for vaccinating the uninsured had to end yesterday due to a lack of funds.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>America&#8217;s supply of monoclonal antibodies that are effective at keeping people out of the hospital will run out as soon as late May.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And our test-manufacturing capacity will begin ramping down at the end of June.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re going to continue to work closely with Congress to drive to a solution, because the President knows that we can&#8217;t afford inaction in this moment.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to require politicians stopping &#8212; to stop skirting their responsibility to the American people.&nbsp; COVID is not over, and we have an obligation to protect our country, the American people, and make sure we&#8217;re taking steps to prepare.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, last thing: Last night, as you may have all seen, we announced the authorization of an additional $100 million in security assistance &#8212; the Department of Defense announced &#8212; to Ukraine through presiden- &#8212; through presidential drawdown authority.&nbsp; This package will meet Ukraine&#8217;s urgent need for additional Javelin anti-armor systems, which we&#8217;ve been providing to Ukraine and they have been using effectively to defend their country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Javelins have been one of the most effective weapons the Ukrainians have been &#8212; have deployed in combating Russian tanks and Russian armored vehicles.&nbsp; They were critical in the defense of Kyiv and other areas, and we want to ensure we continue to get them in the Ukrainians’ hands.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also continue to work with our allies and partners to provide Ukraine with additional capabilities and expect to have more to announce in the coming days.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Kevin has been out here before, so I have already embarrassed him in the past, and I will keep it short.&nbsp; But Kevin, as many of you know, is our COVID spokesperson.&nbsp; Kevin only recently turned 26, which means he can barely rent a car.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But he is &#8212; he can now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; I can now.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But he &#8212; he has become an expert.&nbsp; He is stalwart.&nbsp; He works 20 hours a day.&nbsp; And he is indispensable.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;m very grateful to Kevin and happy he&#8217;s out here to provide the prop but also to provide all of you with many, many answers on a daily basis.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, with that, Zeke.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You just mentioned that COVID isn&#8217;t over.&nbsp; We just saw the President give remarks to a very large crowd indoors.&nbsp; I was hoping you’d speak a little bit to how the President views, sort of, what &#8212; when it is safer to be going to such large gatherings.&nbsp; Is that the sort of thing he’s trying to model for the rest of the American public?&nbsp; That the risks for most people from COVID now are lesser than they were a year or two ago before vaccines and treatments?&nbsp; Is that sort of behavior now &#8212; it&#8217;s not something that should be stigmatized or &#8212; and should be embraced?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I think what the President is doing is he is following CDC protocols and models, and that&#8217;s exactly what we would recommend the rest of the country do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That includes getting vaccinated; getting boosted; getting an extra booster if you are eligible, as the President did just last week; and obviously taking any steps or precautions that the CDC recommends to keep yourself safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And obviously, in Washington, D.C., we remain in a yellow zone, and the President follows those protocols as needed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just an update: He said &#8212; did he say when the last &#8212; the last time the President tested for COVID?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I suspected you would ask this.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve asked this question, and I will get you an answer to that as quickly as possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, he is tested on &#8212; he has a regular testing cadence &#8212; is usually tested a couple times a week.&nbsp; We will venture to get to that as soon as possible after the briefing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And on a different topic, the U.S. today sanctioned a number of Russians, including Vladimir Putin’s daughters, as well as some other senior officials.<br>&nbsp;<br>I was hoping you’d might be able to speak a little bit about sort of the &#8212; the administration’s thinking about when are family members of Russian oligarchs and Russian government officials, sort of, fair game for sanctions and how you’ve weighed and (inaudible) distinction between minors and adults, in this case, with, sort of, you know, collective punishment or trying to prevent them from harboring assets with, you know, people who are not necessarily involved in the decision-making in Ukraine but have, sort of, maybe benefited from that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve seen a pattern over time of President Putin and Russian oligarchs stash assets and resources in the bank accounts and &#8212; of their family members.&nbsp; And so, this was an effort to get at those assets, and that&#8217;s why these individuals were sanctioned.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so there’s no &#8212; but why the distinction, then, between minors and adults?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we look at where assets may be stored and stashed and make a decision and an assessment on what&#8217;s appropriate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The New York Times has a verified video that appears to show a group of Ukrainian soldiers killing captured Russian troops outside a village just west of Kyiv.&nbsp; Has the White House seen these videos?&nbsp; Do you have a response?&nbsp; Is this something you&#8217;re investigating?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have seen the video; I don&#8217;t have any confirmation or validation of the video or the report.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so far, the administration &#8212; or the U.S. has spent about $2 billion since the beginning of this invasion.&nbsp; Obviously, you know, you&#8217;ve said the U.S. is committed to doing everything it can to help Ukraine in this fight.&nbsp; But if General Milley is correct in what he said yesterday &#8212; that this really could go on for several years &#8212; are these numbers sustainable over the long term?&nbsp; Can you keep up at this pace?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first &#8212; just to reiterate what General Milley said and the President has also been clear &#8212; that there are tough days ahead for the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a likely scenario where there &#8212; this could go on for some time.&nbsp; And even as they have moved their forces and they&#8217;ve retreated from Kyiv &#8212; they retreated from the north and the west, and they&#8217;re consolidating forces in the east and in the Donbas.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve warned that we&#8217;re entering a new phase of the conflict that could last for some time.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean it will look exactly the same or the needs or the resources will be exactly the same.&nbsp; And that is something we will continue to assess in our conversations with the Ukrainians, as well as with our allies and partners around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And right now, just to note, obviously, our focus is on amping up and providing a range of military assistance of &#8212; the $100 million for Javelins is a good example of that &#8212; as they are in an active fight every single day against the Russian military.&nbsp; Also, humanitarian and economic assistance.&nbsp; And there will be different needs that will come about over the course of time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s something we are, of course, committed to continuing to support: their recovery from this, their continued fight from this.&nbsp; But I can&#8217;t make an assessment about sustaining because, obviously, this war and the needs will change over the course of time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if this is a really protracted, prolonged conflict, given what the Treasury Secretary said today &#8212; sort of warning of the enormous economic repercussions of this war for the whole world &#8212; what does this mean for the economy in the U.S. for the next year or two?&nbsp; Can you just give us sort of a big picture of what Americans should be bracing for?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as we&#8217;ve made decisions about putting sanctions in place, we&#8217;ve continued to do that through the prism of maximizing the impact on Russia, on the Russian economy while minimizing the impact on the West and the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, there are areas where there has been an impact, including on the price of gas.&nbsp; And you saw the Federal Reserve convey today the impact of the Russian invasion on inflation.&nbsp; And we know that to be the case.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what we&#8217;re trying to do is mitigate those impacts.&nbsp; And obviously, not just the announcement of the Strate- &#8212; release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, but the announcement by the IE &#8212; IEA today is the largest release that they have ever done in history.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And all of these are part of our collective effort to impact &#8212; to mitigate the impacts on the American people over the course of time.&nbsp; Even the length of time of the release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve &#8212; meant to be a stopgap measure or kind of a bridge measure, to get to the point where oil companies could produce more &#8212; is intended to have a mitigation impact over the course of time.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I &#8212; what we&#8217;re doing is anticipating and trying to step &#8212; take steps to reduce the impact on the American people over time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up on that IEA question: Do you have a detail or figure of how much oil has been released of the 180 million barrels to date?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to get that for you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure that our team may have that, but I don&#8217;t have that in front of me.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask &#8212; President Biden today told union members, “Amazon, here we come.”&nbsp; Was he endorsing the efforts of union &#8212; of workers to unionize Amazon facilities?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What he was not doing is sending a message that he or the U.S. government would be directly involved in any of these efforts or take any direct action.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What he was conveying is that &#8212; is his longtime support for collective bargaining, for the rights of workers to organize, and their decision to do exactly that in this case &#8212; something that he has long supported broadly over the course of his career.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just back to the issue of the sanctions that are being imposed on Putin’s children and, obviously, sanctions against him as well.&nbsp; Does the U.S. have a rough estimate, at this moment in time, of how much of his assets are tied up versus what he still might have access to?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an assessment to offer from here on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But we know that &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen attempts and efforts to stash assets in the accounts and resources of his children.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A senior administration official, earlier today, was raising the question of Putin’s endgame &#8212; that, at some point, he would presumably recognize that this war has been a failure for him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Given some of the scenes that we&#8217;re seeing in places like Bucha and Mariupol, does the U.S. believe that he is any closer to realizing that reality today versus a week ago, a month ago?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, remember, the scenes we&#8217;re seeing in Bucha are from events and atrocities that didn&#8217;t happen yesterday.&nbsp; They happened some time ago.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And there will be more of those &#8212; which our Secretary of State and our National Security Advisor have also predicted, unfortunately &#8212; because there are a lot of areas of the country where Russia has invaded and committed atrocities &#8212; no doubt &#8212; which we have not yet had visual access to.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say that I can&#8217;t make an assessment for you from here on what is in President Putin&#8217;s mind.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we do know is that because of the impact of the economic sanctions, including the ones we have taken today, and steps we&#8217;ve taken over the course of time, we have seen an unquestionable, significant impact on Russia&#8217;s economy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that has led to this question now, as a result of the decision around whether or not they would be able to make a bond payment earlier this week, that they will have to decide whether they are going to spend down dollars and resources they have to avoid default or whether they&#8217;re going to spend that money &#8212; continue to spend that money in funding the war.&nbsp; And that is a part of our objective &#8212; is to force them into a place where they are making that decision.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;ve seen Russia&#8217;s economy collapse by 15 percent, wiping out the gains made in the last 15 years.&nbsp; Inflation is spiking up to 15 percent.&nbsp; Russia is set to lose its status as a major economy.&nbsp; And our objective is to implement those consequences to make it much more difficult for President Putin to fund the war &#8212; and we&#8217;re seeing the direct impacts of that already &#8212; and to make it clear that this was a strategic blunder.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re already seeing those impacts on the economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>How that impacts him and &#8212; you know, that &#8212; that is not something I can predict in terms of getting into his mind.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the administration&#8217;s current assessment of what Putin&#8217;s endgame is?&nbsp; And does the administration believe that that may have shifted since the beginning of the invasion?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; I would say that, one, while they have moved their troops around and repositioned, we have not made &#8212; and they haven&#8217;t made many airstrikes in the last 24 hours, according to Department of Defense and their briefing, which you may have seen, or their backgrounder &#8212; we also know that, you know, their goal remains weakening Ukraine as much as possible.&nbsp; And we should be under no illusion that that objective hasn&#8217;t changed, even as their tactics have changed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The President today, as he was talking about his vow to stand by Ukrainians, added a line: “And, by the way, if I&#8217;ve got to go to war, I&#8217;m going with you guys.”&nbsp; Can you clarify what that meant?&nbsp; Is &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has no intention of sending boot &#8212; troops to the ground or fighting a war between &#8212; with the U.S. forces against Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That was a reflection of his long love for labor unions, and members of labor unions, and the building and trades workers who were there, and people that he would always love to be in the foxhole with &#8212; not an indication of a change in U.S. policy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Got it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also referred to that heated exchange we saw that involved Secretary Austin.&nbsp; And he said, with regard to Ukrainian troops, “We&#8217;ve trained them and we&#8217;ve given them the weapons.”&nbsp; Can you clarify what he meant by “We have trained them”?&nbsp; What training was he talking about?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there was some, some time ago &#8212; training.&nbsp; And we have provided them, obviously, a range of weapons over time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What point he was making is one Secretary Austin made yesterday: Without the extensive military assistance that we have been providing the Ukrainians &#8212; the security assistance &#8212; over the course of the last several weeks and even months before that &#8212; $1.6 billion worth, maybe a little higher now after the $100 million last night &#8212; they would not have been able to effectively fight back as they have.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And how it has basically worked is: They have requested a range of assistance.&nbsp; We go through and see what we are able to provide.&nbsp; We often work with partners and allies to provide assistance we don&#8217;t have access to here.&nbsp; And then we expedite the delivery of that over the course of time, whether that is Javelin, Stingers, or a range of materials that are &#8212; the U.S. military has determined they&#8217;re not only trained on but has been effective in fighting this war.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Aside from the physical resources, what training was he talking about?&nbsp; What was the latest training the U.S. troops have done?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s not new training to report out to you.&nbsp; What he was really emphasizing and the important part here is what Secretary Austin was also talking about, is the military equipment that has been provided that has allowed them to fight this war.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And one more &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on sanctions.&nbsp; You said a couple times now that, you know, the U.S. sanctioned Putin’s daughters because there&#8217;s reason to believe Putin has stashed his wealth with them.&nbsp; Does that mean that the U.S. has some information about where the billionaire daughters are stashing their wealth?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more to provide to you from here.&nbsp; We make assessments about where to implement financial sanctions to get close to not only the assets of President Putin, but those around him.&nbsp; And we have seen a long pattern of using relatives and family members to stash wealth.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; First, on immigration: Our team in Texas is that saying that you guys are starting to give smartphones to border crossers, hoping that they&#8217;ll use the phones to check in or to be tracked.&nbsp; I &#8212; which part of that is supposed to deter people from crossing illegally into the states?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think you of all people &#8212; since you&#8217;ve asked me a range of questions on this topic over time &#8212; would recognize that we need to take steps to ensure that we know where individuals are and we can track &#8212; and we can check in with them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The alternatives to detention programs &#8212; is what we utilize &#8212; has three unique forms of technology to monitor participants enrolled in the program:<br>&nbsp;<br>Telephonic, which is one of them, which is uses a participant’s voice to create a biometric voice print during the enrollment process.&nbsp; And when the participant has a check-in call, their voice is compared to the voice print.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SmartLink, which is another option, enables participant monitoring via smartphone or tablet using facial-matching technology to establish identity.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Global Positioning System monitoring is of a participant’s location and movement history, using satellite technology through an ankle bracelet.&nbsp; This is all part of our effort, as individuals come into the United States and individuals who are entering who will proceed to immigration proceedings, to monitor and track where they are.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the telephonic, though, any concern by folks around here that these migrants will take the phones and just<br>toss them?&nbsp; And then &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Do you have a record of people throwing phones away?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m just asking if that&#8217;s a concern.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our concern is ensuring that individuals who irregularly migrate to the United States proceed through our process of, you know, of course, being monitored, but also participating in &#8212; in hearings to determine whether or not they will be able to stay.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that nearly 80 percent of non-citizens released at the border from DHS custody under prosecut- &#8212; prosecutorial discretion have either received a notice to appear or are still within their window to report.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, actually, the vast, vast majority of people are appearing.&nbsp; In part, we have these monitors and monitoring systems in order to do that effectively.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On another topic, was it common for President Biden to do favors for Hunter Biden&#8217;s international business partners like writing college recommendations for their kids?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen the report.&nbsp; I have no confirmation or comments on a report about whether or not the President, when he was a private citizen, wrote a college recommendation letter for an individual.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A college recommendation letter, though, from, at the time, a former Vice President would be a big deal.&nbsp; So, do we know what the President might have gotten in return for doing a favor like that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I have no confirmation of any recommendation letter the President wrote when he was a private citizen &#8212; by the way, not serving in public office.&nbsp; That&#8217;s even in the report.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he&#8217;s the President now, and you&#8217;re his spokesperson.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; And he was not the President at the time of this report.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s evidence that the President, at one point, was officemates with Hunter and his brother Jim here in D.C.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not accurate.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That is not accurate?&nbsp; So, when Hunter Biden is emailing a landlord, “Please have keys made available for new officemates &#8212; Joe Biden, Jill Biden, Jim Biden,” that &#8212; you&#8217;re disputing it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They were not officemates, no.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They were not officemates.&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Great.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On student loans, briefly &#8212; and you were sort of asked about this yesterday, but I just wanted to come back to it.&nbsp; So, as people plan for the future, should borrowers expect that after August 31st, they&#8217;ll have to repay their loans?&nbsp; Or is there another &#8212; is there a chance that it could be further extended after August 31st?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue to assess.&nbsp; And what we look at &#8212; while, of course, the economy is in a better state than it is &#8212; than it was a year ago, and it&#8217;s &#8212; we have a strong recovery, we also understand that there are a range of impacts that are still longer lasting because of the pandemic, including the impacts on costs and inflation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this is part of the President&#8217;s effort to help alleviate that, as was fix &#8212; as was the “family glitch” announcement of yesterday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;ll make an evaluation.&nbsp; The Department of Education will look at that and a range of factors as we get closer to that timeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has the President, at this point, ruled out a possible executive-level cancellation on a widescale of student debt?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has not ruled out, but I don’t have any update on that.&nbsp; And I would note that, again, he would encourage Congress to send him a bill cancelling $10,000 in student debt, something that he talked about looking forward to signing on the campaign trail.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just really briefly, on the G20 &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Secretary Yellen said today that they may not &#8212; that the U.S. might not attend meetings if Russians are there.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is she implying that these would just be individual meetings, or would it be a kind of broader-scale boycott of the G20 in Bali?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; She &#8212; I think they have later clarified she was referencing at the ministerial level and, more specific, meetings.&nbsp; I would point you to them of the more specifics.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President has also said &#8212; he said on the trip that he did not think Russia should be a part of the G20, you know, meeting.&nbsp; And I would note it&#8217;s seven months away, which is a lifetime in our &#8212; in our lives.&nbsp; But it wasn&#8217;t an indication of plans for us to boycott or not attend.&nbsp; It was just, “It shouldn&#8217;t be business as usual,” which is something the President has also said.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, is it a priority of the President to try to identify the Russian units that carried out the atrocities in Bucha?&nbsp; Is that something that the U.S. may be able to do?&nbsp; And is it something the President wants to have happen?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will continue to assist in every way possible with these efforts to track down data, additional information, and contribute to the international effort to do exactly that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May I ask, if I can, a couple of other questions that made news today?&nbsp; A judge has just issued the first outright acquittal of a defendant charged in the January 6th Capitol riot.&nbsp; This was a New Mexico man, Matthew Martin.&nbsp; He was acquitted on some misdemeanor charges by the judge.&nbsp; This man had claimed that he thought police allowed him into an entrance near the Capitol Rotunda.&nbsp; Does the White House have any view now that that case has been adjudicated?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any specific comment on that case.&nbsp; We continue to support the efforts of the January 6th commission and all of the members in trying to get to the bottom of what happened that day to prevent it from happening in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me go back to one last question as it relates to what&#8217;s happening in Russia.&nbsp; The U.S. still doesn&#8217;t have an ambassador to India, but it appears increasingly clear that Los Angeles Mayor Garcetti doesn&#8217;t have the votes right now to be confirmed.&nbsp; How does the lack of an ambassador to India impact our ability &#8212; America&#8217;s ability to pressure India not to work with Russia in providing any aid or assistance?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, while our preference is always to have a confirmed ambassador on the ground &#8212; it’s an incredibly important diplomatic position &#8212; we also engage with countries through a range of channels.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And obviously, our Deputy National Security Advisor was just in India recently in the last few weeks conveying clearly what the consequences of violating sanctions would be and what the mechanisms are; and also making clear that we do not think India should accelerate or increase imports of Russian energy and other commodities, even as obviously those decisions are made by individual countries; and also making clear that we stand ready to support India as &#8212; in any efforts to diversify its imports and serve as a reliable supplier, even as they&#8217;re only importing about 1 to 2 percent of their oil from India.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we have a range of ways to communicate and engage. &nbsp;And obviously, sending our Deputy National Security Advisor is an example of that.&nbsp; But clearly our preference would be to have a confirmed ambassador.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President still support that nomination?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He does.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Russian ruble has been on the rise.&nbsp; Viktor Orbán in Hungary said today that he&#8217;d be happy to pay for Russian gas in rubles and that he&#8217;s happy to buy more Russian gas.&nbsp; Is there anything the U.S. can do about this?&nbsp; Are you engaging Hungary on this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would &#8212; I would first say, in terms of the ruble, the reason &#8212; it&#8217;s important to note that the Russian Central Bank is making extreme policy decisions to artificially prop up the ruble.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s not actually on the rise.&nbsp; It is being artificially propped up by limitations that they are putting in place, including barring banks from selling dollars to customers; Russian brokerages are not allowing foreign clients to sell securities; exporters are being forced to sell 80 percent of their dollar revenues and buy rubles.&nbsp; So, they are essentially manipulating it on their end.<br>&nbsp;<br>As it relates to Hungary &#8212; I mean, slightly a different question, but our &#8212; you know, obviously, there was the recent election, as you noted, of Viktor Orbán.&nbsp; I would note that our &#8212; Hungary is a NATO Ally, continues to be. &nbsp;We continue to cooperate on a range of bilateral and shared global interests, including on NATO defense and on humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; They&#8217;re currently hosting forces from an Army Stryker infantry troop as part of a NATO battle group.&nbsp; We regularly conduct joint training exercises with them, and we will continue to work to strengthen our partnership with Hungary.<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, reliance on the ruble is a decision individual countries will make, and we&#8217;ve obviously made our views clear on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you have engaged Hungary on this question?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is not what I conveyed.&nbsp; I just conveyed they’re a NATO Ally.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we go back to the sanctions?&nbsp; As they were announced this morning, the Sberbank and the Alfa Bank sanctions, I believe, exclude energy.&nbsp; They’re full blocking sanctions excluding energy.&nbsp; Similarly, the SOE sanctions coming tomorrow also will not affect the energy sector.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak to that balancing act?&nbsp; Is that because you&#8217;re worried about the domestic impact here in the U.S. on the price of natural gas, price of gasoline? &nbsp;Or is that because the Europeans asked you to sort of carve that out?&nbsp; Why &#8212; or why is that still sort of a bridge too far for the U.S. on these sanctions?&nbsp; They&#8217;re not really full blocking sanctions if they’re excluding energy.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I mean, I would say they’re quite extensive, given Sberbank is the largest bank in Russia and Alfa Bank is the largest private bank in Russia.&nbsp; So, in total, we’ve now fully blocked more than two thirds of Russia’s banking sector.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These conversations and discussions, obviously, are done in coordination with our European allies and partners.&nbsp; And we continue to assess how we can maximize the impact while minimizing the impact on other economies, including, of course, the gloi- &#8212; the global oil marketplace.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve taken steps, of course, banning oil imports.&nbsp; A number of countries, including Poland, in Europe have announced their intention to take steps, but that&#8217;s up to individual countries to make.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s part coordination, assessment with other countries and our allies about the impacts.&nbsp; But I would still say it&#8217;s quite a significant step, given they&#8217;re the largest bank in Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is it accurate then to say that this was done because of the Europeans saying, “Hey, you know, this would be too (inaudible)?”<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, this is &#8212; but we do update them and brief them on the steps we take and why.&nbsp; And we look at the impacts on &#8212; on how things will impact the United States, how they will impact a range of our allies as we make decisions about sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And very quickly on the central bank actions propping up the ruble &#8212; do you have any sense of how long they&#8217;re able to keep that up?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an assessment from here at this point in time on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On immigration: With the lifting of Section 42, there are a lot of Democrats, particularly Democratic senators, up for reelection who worry that you don&#8217;t have a plan to either stop the spring surge of undocumented immigrants or handle it.&nbsp; What do you say to those Democrats?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that Title 42 is not an immigration measure, it&#8217;s a public health measure and one that Congress has given the CDC authority to make a decision about.&nbsp; And we respect that and think that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s absolutely right.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the President proposed an immigration bill in his first day in office.&nbsp; And we would certainly welcome efforts of anybody to work with us on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>But as we&#8217;re implementing this over the course of the next five weeks, if I&#8217;m doing my math correctly, we&#8217;ve also surged resources from the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; And we will continue to take additional steps to implement and make clear that this is not the time to come, that there are &#8212; there will still be significant measures put in place for anyone who tries to irregularly migrate to the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you feel that you &#8212; I mean, what&#8217;s your goal, and what do you expect &#8212; what impact do you expect to have on the spring surge with those kinds of measures?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would really point you to the Department of Homeland Security to make any projections of that, because we have not made any projections of what it will mean in terms of the ending of Title 42 either.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I know that you&#8217;ve talked about the stringent measures you&#8217;ve taken to keep the President safe from COVID that go beyond the CDC guidelines, but that&#8217;s such a visual contrast between that and the President showing up maskless in front of people at some of these events.&nbsp; So how do you make sure that you keep that protection bubble around him?&nbsp; I’m sure you feel like you’re asked to explain this ad nauseum.&nbsp; But &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, it’s okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the bubble is looking pretty porous lately.&nbsp; So how do you keep that, sort of, enforced?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, that we continue to<br>take measures that go beyond what the CDC protocols are.&nbsp; That includes ensuring that everybody who&#8217;s going to see the President in a meeting is tested in advance &#8212; or if you&#8217;re traveling with the President, you&#8217;re tested in advance.<br>&nbsp;<br>When possible, we take steps to socially distance in circumstances, which certainly the Oval Office and other meeting spaces in the White House allow for.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If an individual in the White House is a close contact, they are asked to or required to, I guess you could say, wear a mask for 10 days after that exposure.&nbsp; And they are also tested regularly following.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I would say we take additional measures that go beyond what the CDC protocols and requirements are to ensure that we&#8217;re doing everything we can to keep principals safe &#8212; the President, the Vice President, and others, of course, in the building.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was everyone tested before the East Room event tomorrow &#8212; everyone who was there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s not at public events.&nbsp; I&#8217;m talking about at meetings.&nbsp; But again, I can check on the protocols for public events.&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you changed any protocol surrounding him in recent days as more people are &#8212; in the administration contract this virus?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve continued to implement stringent and strict protocols.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that even as we&#8217;re looking at, with BA.2 &#8212; a very transmissible variant, as we all know, and our public health officials have told us.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen an increase in cases &#8212; right? &#8212; in the country, in the region, among the press corps, and certainly in the White House.&nbsp; And &#8212; but it is not, at this point, what we saw during Omicron.<br>&nbsp;<br>And what &#8212; the steps we have taken here, including policy put in place to ensure that “return to work” was part of our policies in the federal government, are meant to ensure that can continue to be the case.&nbsp; And even while we have individuals who are out with COVID, everyone here is required to be tested, highly recommended to be boosted.&nbsp; People who are out because of that &#8212; the vast, vast majority have mild cases and are continuing to work from home.<br>&nbsp;<br>And obviously, we are continuing to implement the “return to work” policy and feel we have the measures necessary to do that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what&#8217;s the clearest version of the message that you&#8217;re trying to send to Americans about living with this virus, even as infection rates rise &#8212; I mean, that it&#8217;s not the end of the world if you get it if you&#8217;re boosted?&nbsp; I mean, is that the message you send through the President, who&#8217;s maskless in front of hundreds of people &#8212; that this isn&#8217;t the end, that we have to live this way?&nbsp; Is that the clear version of the message?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our recommend- &#8212; well, the message we&#8217;re sending is to follow the CDC protocols and guidance for where you live.&nbsp; The President does that.&nbsp; He did an event in Washington, D.C., today where it does not require mask wearing.&nbsp; There are other parts of the country, as you know, where he&#8217;s traveled and he has worn a mask where that has been the recommendation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our protocols also here &#8212; and we would certainly project this to the American people &#8212; are that getting vaccinated and getting boosted &#8212; and if you are immunocompromised or you’re over certain age, getting your next booster &#8212; is certainly a way to help protect yourself.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the President has done and every member of the senior staff and White House staff has done and will continue to do, although some of us are teasing the people who are over 50 that were not old enough yet.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s a si- &#8212; that&#8217;s a sidebar.&nbsp; When we are, we will be doing that as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it is &#8212; it is to follow the protocols and to recognize that the statistics show you are significantly more likely to be hospitalized and even to die if you are not vaccinated, if you are not boosted.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, yes, we are living with COVID-19.&nbsp; We are continuing to fight it.&nbsp; And our biggest message right now is that we need the resources from Congress to continue to have the &#8212; to ensure we have programs for the uninsured, that we can provide treatments for immunocompromised, that we can make sure that we have testing mechanisms and booster mechanisms.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re at serious risk of those programs not being able to continue.&nbsp; Some haven&#8217;t, obviously.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Karen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, just to follow up on something you said to Mara on the Title 42 question.&nbsp; You said that the administration will be taking additional steps to make clear this is not the time to come.&nbsp; That was, of course, a pretty explicit message from the President and others last year: “Do not come.”&nbsp; Is that still the message on May 24th?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, a follow-up to that: As the U.S. moves to end Title 42 in May, are there discussions now or is there any update you can give us on ending the testing requirement for reentry into the U.S. for people traveling here?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update on that at this point in time.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something we will continue to evaluate.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; I have a follow-up on sanctions and energy.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The European Union said yesterday that they are paying Russia, every day, a little more than $1 billion for gas and oil.&nbsp; How long can this go on, in the President&#8217;s view, without undermining the collective effort to punish Russia?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that we continue to believe that it&#8217;s up to individual countries to make assessments about what additional measures they will be put in place.&nbsp; While we are focused on continuing unity with our NATO Allies and partners and our European partners, it does not mean that it is always identical, and different countries have to make their own assessments.<br>&nbsp;<br>What we&#8217;ve also tried to do is take steps to ensure there are other options to reduce dependence, even if it&#8217;s a small percentage.&nbsp; And if there&#8217;s a vari- &#8212; varying, as you all know, degree of reliance for these countries you&#8217;re referencing on Russian oil.&nbsp; And some of them have taken steps to convey they want to reduce or end their dependence or import of Russian oil, and that&#8217;s something certainly we&#8217;d support and play any constructive role in helping &#8212; to helping expedite.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a follow-up &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll come around to you in a second.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow up on the question about Hungary, are there any plans to engage with them about this particular topic of paying in rubles at any level in the coming days or weeks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check with the State Department to see if there&#8217;s any plans for engagement about it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, Jen.&nbsp; Again, an American Catho- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You talked about the increasing picture of Russia&#8217;s economy.&nbsp; Over the years, public reporting has shown that white supremacists and other domestic extremists have developed an affinity for Russia.&nbsp; Is there any concern that as the Russian economy continues to degrade, that Russia might try and inspire domestic extremists, domestic terrorists to commit acts of violence on American soil in retaliation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s an interesting and scary question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any prediction or assessment of that, nor have I heard a prediction or assessment of that from our national security experts or the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check with them and see if there&#8217;s anything on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, again &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right, Jen.&nbsp; So, an American Catholic nun has been abducted &#8212; it happened Monday night &#8212; by gunmen in Burkina Faso, in Western Africa.&nbsp; Her name is Sister Suellen Tennyson.&nbsp; She was doing missionary work there.&nbsp; Is the White House aware of that, by any chance &#8212; her abduction?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check with our national security team and the State Department.&nbsp; Obviously, they would have purview over any steps to bring Sister &#8212; tell me her name again.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sister Suellen Tennyson.&nbsp; And she was working in Burkina Faso, in Western Africa.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sister Tennyson back, who clearly was doing incredible work &#8212; humanitarian work, it sounds like &#8212; on behalf of the people in Burkina Faso.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will check with the State Department and see if there&#8217;s any updates on this specific case.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Okay, go ahead, Patsy.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I want to follow up on what you said yesterday about the lack of global COVID funding.&nbsp; And you explained it essentially means that the U.S. cannot turn the doses that you already have into shots in arms.&nbsp; And I believe that the U.S. has already purchased 1.2 billion doses that it’s pledged.&nbsp; And out of that, there is about 680 million that haven&#8217;t been delivered.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, my question, then, is: What will happen to those doses?&nbsp; I know, like, possibly you already have funding for delivery &#8212; the cold chain storage, training people, and so on.&nbsp; But what happens to the rest of it when you are unable to turn those vaccines into vaccinations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not quite there yet.&nbsp; And our hope is that we will be able to turn them &#8212; vaccines into vaccinations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But as you know, it&#8217;s not just an issue of vaccine doses.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the know-how, it&#8217;s the capacity, it&#8217;s the tools and mechanisms to be able to store, deliver, implement getting shots into arms in a number of these countries, which is why a number of countries haven&#8217;t even been able to accept the doses that we&#8217;ve been able to offer &#8212; because of that know-how.&nbsp; And that is part of the program that is so essential to fund through USAID and other of our international bodies to do exactly that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re not quite at that point.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to press for international funding, just like we are going to continue to press for domestic funding, because we feel it&#8217;s important and imperative that we continue to be the arsenal of vaccines around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us a sense on how you want to do that?&nbsp; Is the goal to push for a separate package on global COVID funding?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of where we are.&nbsp; Obviously, it was disappointing, to say the least, that the package did not move forward despite an agreement on that yesterday afternoon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what I&#8217;m here to convey is that this funding, domestically and internationally, is imperative, it&#8217;s urgent, and we&#8217;re going to continue to press for all of it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I have one more question on Daleep Singh’s visit to India &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; which was also partly to go on a listening tour for the Build Back Better World that was actually scheduled to be formally launched early this year.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So if you can give us an update on that.&nbsp; Why has it not launched yet?&nbsp; And at this point, do you feel that it is &#8212; with the projects &#8212; with the listening tours, with the pilot projects that are being planned, is it robust enough to be introduced to the world as a viable alternative to China&#8217;s Belt and Road Initiative?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As you know, the President has used his own time to talk about Build Back Better World and how important it is to our efforts to rebuild infrastructure without the strings attached around the world.&nbsp; And that speaks to our commitment to it.&nbsp; And obviously, our Nat- &#8212; Deputy National Security Advisor taking a trip himself, having a discussion about it is a reflection of our commitment to that and our efforts.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you a follow-up question on COVID-19?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The WHO Director-General is in D.C. &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Earlier this morning at the Monitor Breakfast, NEC Director Brian Deese mentioned a classified briefing that took place earlier today between lawmakers, Jake Sullivan, and others about, quote, “escalating vulnerabilities” around semiconductors.&nbsp; Can you tell us more about this meeting?&nbsp; And was it an effort to get Congress to hurry up on the reconciliation of the two related bills?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak to the specifics of a classified briefing.&nbsp; What I can tell you is that we can &#8212; remain committed to supporting efforts to get you USICA passed, which includes significant funding for chips manufacturing and production, which, as we know, is a big hindrance to our ability to manufacture a range of &#8212; a range of items in the United States, including cars and others, that rely on chips.&nbsp; And this bill has a great deal of funding for it.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think it was a reminder &#8212; and more details that I can&#8217;t get into from here on &#8212; on how important addressing that shortage and being able to produce them at home are, moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, as the administration sort of collects this evidence for potential war crimes trials against Russian officials, does the U.S., does the administration have a preferred venue for where that type of trial might take place?&nbsp; That &#8212; there are obviously a few avenues available to the international community.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are.&nbsp; And there &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of precedent and &#8212; that has used different venues.&nbsp; So at this point, that determination has not been made.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we are doing &#8212; and I think I would point you first to our Attorney General&#8217;s comments earlier today about the role of the Department of Justice in this effort moving forward.&nbsp; But we have supported a range of efforts, including the efforts by the Ukrainian Special Prosecutor to gather information and the work of the war crimes unit under the Ukrainian Prosecutor General &#8212; sorry, Prosecutor General, not Special Prosecutor &#8212; and a team of international prosecutors who are working with them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also &#8212; in the last few weeks, we helped establish investigations for the U.N. Human Rights Council and the OSCE of possible violations by Russia.&nbsp; And we welcome the investigation opened by the ICC Prosecutor.<br>&nbsp;<br>So there has been different ways that war crimes &#8211;unfortunately, there are past instances and examples &#8212; have been investigated and tried in the past.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to support all of these efforts, but there hasn&#8217;t been a determination yet about what mechanism it will take.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has this effort changed at all the thinking of the administration as it relates to the relationship between the U.S. and the ICC?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we are not a member of the ICC, as you know.&nbsp; That hasn&#8217;t changed.&nbsp; We have supported and contributed data and information to ICC investigations in the past.&nbsp; There was &#8212; we supported the U.N. Security Council&#8217;s referral of Libya to the ICC back in 2011.&nbsp; And if you look back to 2004, we also provided data and information to the ICC investigation of Darfur.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there is past precedent, even as we have not been members of the ICC.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; A couple of follow ups. &nbsp;When the President said that the U.S. was training Ukrainians, was he talking about training that had occurred during his administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any other additional details.&nbsp; What he was really making a point about is what Secretary Austin said yesterday, which is that without the extensive and robust military assistance we have provided, the Ukrainians would not have been able to as effectively fight and push back on the Russian invasion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then he said, “Amazon, here we come.”&nbsp; You said that he was generally expressing his support for the right to unionize.&nbsp; Moments later, though, news broke that the SEC was beginning an investigation of Amazon.&nbsp; Was that a coincidence?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No relation.&nbsp; SEC is an independent agency.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gotcha.&nbsp; Was he aware that there was an investigation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not that I&#8217;m aware of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, one final one.&nbsp; This administration has sent everything from medical supplies to laser-guided rockets to the Ukrainians right now.&nbsp; While this administration is making them more lethal, is the thought that we are bolstering their defensive capabilities?&nbsp; Or is the administration confident that we are bolstering their offensive capability to, in fact, you know, expel Russia from their borders?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, their country is being invaded, so it&#8217;s all defensive.&nbsp; They&#8217;re defending their sovereign country and the territorial integrity of Ukraine using these weapons systems that the Department of Defense has long categorized as defensive systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>You wouldn&#8217;t go invade another country with a lot of these systems &#8212; the vast majority of these systems.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not how you would go about it.&nbsp; And obviously, that is not what they&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; They&#8217;re trying to protect their own people, their own cities, their own innocent civilians who are being invaded by a foreign power.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let me do one more in the back because I never get to the Huffington Post, and I &#8212; today is the day.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; There was a recent report that the President had expressed some frustration that the former President had not been charged.&nbsp; Without getting into the details of that, there are lots of people being charged with obstructing an official proceeding, meaning the January 6th certification.<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, the former President was doing that openly and his administration was doing it.&nbsp; Why wouldn&#8217;t you charge him?&nbsp; And why hasn&#8217;t the President come out and said that if that&#8217;s the case?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; first, I&#8217;ve never heard the President say those words &#8212; or say that phrase that was reported.&nbsp; And I know Ron Klain said something similarly, so I don&#8217;t know &#8212; we each spend a lot of time with him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I would say that the President, from the beginning, has felt strongly that the Justice Department and the Attorney General must operate independently, and any decisions about prosecution need to be made independently.&nbsp; And that is the strength of our system, even as the former guy ignored that and former-President Nixon ignored it as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President does not want to be in that category of how you approach the separation of the White House and the Department of Justice.&nbsp; And &#8212; and he thinks that will even strengthen our systems as they&#8217;ve been weakened over the last few years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, thanks so much.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br>&nbsp;<br>All right, everybody.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>4:02 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
