<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 19:23:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 19:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Richard Trumka Jr., of Maryland, to be a Commissioner of the Consumer Product Safety Commission for a term of seven years from October 27, 2021, vice Robert S. Adler. &#160; &#160; &#160;Alvin Harlyn Warren, of New Mexico, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Richard Trumka Jr., of Maryland, to be a Commissioner of the Consumer Product Safety Commission for a term of seven years from October 27, 2021, vice Robert S. Adler.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Alvin Harlyn Warren, of New Mexico, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for National and Community Service for a term expiring October 6, 2023, vice Hyepin Christine Im, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;James A. Diossa, of Rhode Island, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation for a term expiring October 3, 2024, vice Harvey M. Tettlebaum, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Terrence Keith Wright, of Delaware, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation for a term expiring May 29, 2025, vice John J. Faso, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Rahul Gupta, of West Virginia, to be Director of National Drug Control Policy, vice James W. Carroll Jr.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jeffry Lane Flake, of Arizona, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Turkey.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Kent Doyle Logsdon, of Pennsylvania, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Moldova.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Atul Atmaram Gawande, of Massachusetts, to be an Assistant Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Alma L. Golden.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Gabriel Camarillo, of Texas, to be Under Secretary of the Army, vice James E. McPherson.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Chester John Culver, of Iowa, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation, vice Charles A. Stones.</p>



<p>     Alan F. Estevez, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security, vice Mira Radielovic Ricardel, resigned.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden to Mark the Day That Tens of Millions of Families Will Get Their First Monthly Child Tax Credit Relief Payments Thanks to the American Rescue Plan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/15/remarks-by-president-biden-to-mark-the-day-that-tens-of-millions-of-families-will-get-their-first-monthly-child-tax-credit-relief-payments-thanks-to-the-american-rescue-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 19:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:27 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Well, for you &#8212; anybody under the age of 13 &#8212; this has got to be boring, boring, boring for you.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Right?&#160; Well, I’ll tell you what, we have to work something out here so that when this is over, your parents, your uncles, your aunts &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:27 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Well, for you &#8212; anybody under the age of 13 &#8212; this has got to be boring, boring, boring for you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Well, I’ll tell you what, we have to work something out here so that when this is over, your parents, your uncles, your aunts &#8212; whoever you’re with &#8212; they owe you some ice cream or something for this.&nbsp; You know?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Folks, it’s a pleasure to be here.&nbsp; I’m going to take a sip here.&nbsp; (Drinks water.)&nbsp; And this &#8212; I believe this is actually a historic day &#8212; a historic day in the sense that we continue to build an economy that respects and recognizes the dignity of working-class families and middle-class families.&nbsp; It&#8217;s historic and it&#8217;s our effort to make another giant step toward ending child poverty in America.&nbsp; I think this will be one of the things that the Vice President and I will be most proud of when our terms are up.<br><br>Beginning this morning, nearly all working families &#8212; that is people making under $150,000 as families or an individual making under $120,000 &#8212; $125,000 who have children, are raising children in America, they’re going to receive their first monthly &#8212; first monthly tax cut payment.&nbsp; That payment &#8212; that payment from the expanded Child Tax Credit that we signed into law as part of my &#8212; our American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s one of the largest-ever single tax cuts for families with children, and it&#8217;s a reflection of our belief that the people of this country who need a tax cut aren&#8217;t the folks at the top.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve got plenty of tax cuts.&nbsp; They’re doing just fine.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s the people in the middle, the folks who are struggling, who are just looking for a little bit of &#8212; my dad would say, “a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp; A little bit of breathing room.<br><br>This has the potential to reduce child poverty in the same way that the Social Security reduced poverty for the elderly.&nbsp; And by the way, you think of monthly payments &#8212; you get a Social Security check &#8212; those who you know get Social Security, they get it monthly.&nbsp; Well, this will be &#8212; unless you want it in one lump sum, this would be a monthly payment for childcare &#8212; for &#8212; excuse me, for your children, a tax cut.&nbsp;<br><br>And here&#8217;s how the tax credit works: For every child under the age of six, a parent will get $3,600 a year.&nbsp; For every child 6 to 17, they&#8217;ll get $3,000 per year.&nbsp; For example, a middle-class family with two young children would expect to receive $7,200 a year to help raise their children.&nbsp; This will be the &#8212; they&#8217;ll get the first half of this $3,600 starting today.&nbsp; Today.&nbsp; Today.&nbsp; And it’ll be paid out at $600 a month between now, July, and December.&nbsp; And then they’re going to get the rest of the payment next spring around Tax Day.<br><br>Now, if you file taxes electronically, you can go to your bank account today &#8212; today &#8212; and you&#8217;ll see a payment that says “Child CTC.”&nbsp; Let me say that again: payments of $300 for each child under the age of 6, $250 for each child between the ages of 6 and 17 on a monthly basis between now &#8212; between July and December.&nbsp;<br><br>If you don’t file electronic- &#8212; your taxes electronically, as you did last year, you can expect to receive a check in the mail beginning today or a few days from now.&nbsp; And you’ll get this payment on the 15th of every month for the rest of this year.&nbsp;<br><br>And if you’re not required to file taxes at all in the past &#8212; you haven’t filed because you didn’t owe any taxes, then you can go to: ChildTaxCredit.gov.&nbsp; Let me say it again: ChildTaxCredit.gov.&nbsp; And you will give you &#8212; they’ll give you clear information and a link to help you sign up for the first time.&nbsp; This can be lifechanging for so many families.&nbsp;<br><br>Because of the way the tax credit was structured before the American Rescue Plan, more than 26 million children from the hardest-pressed working families didn’t get any full payment for the Child Credit &#8212; for childcare &#8212; for Child Tax Credit.&nbsp; Half of all Black and Hispanic children in America never received the full tax credit.&nbsp; We’ve changed all that.<br><br>In technical terms, we’ve made this tax cut fully refundable.&nbsp; In plain English, it means instead of families who need help the most getting the le- &#8212; getting the least, the hard-working &#8212; the hard-working families will get this on a month- &#8212; full monthly basis.&nbsp;<br><br>Ninety-seven percent of the children receiving this credit come from working families.&nbsp; And the other 3 percent includes kids being raised by retired grandparents or by someone with a serious disability.<br><br>And by the way, this credit doesn’t start to phase out until a couple is making $150,000 or a single parent is making <s>$112,000</s> [$112,500].&nbsp; It begins to phase out then.&nbsp; This is a middle-class tax cut.&nbsp; When I came up &#8212; when I decided I wanted this in the legislation, I referred to it in the way it really is: It’s a middle-class tax cut.&nbsp; It’s just like the wealthy get tax cuts for a lot of things, this is a tax cut for your children &#8212; having children.<br><br>And this can make it possible for a hardworking parent to say to his or her child, “Honey, we get &#8212; you can get your new braces now.&nbsp; We can get you a tutor to help you in that math class you’re having trouble with.&nbsp; We can get you the sports equipment you need to sign up to &#8212; for your first team you’re going to play on.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>People have written me to tell me they’ll use the money to buy their kids new shoes, to send them to summer camp, to cover afterschool care when school starts up again.&nbsp;<br><br>You know &#8212; and to give you a sense of how transformative this is:&nbsp;This would be the largest-ever one-year decrease in child poverty in the history of the United States of America &#8212; as we begin now. &nbsp;Historic reductions in child poverty among white, Black, and Latinos, and AAPI communities. &nbsp;It’s not even close. &nbsp;The benefits will be felt for years.<br><br>Studies have shown &#8212; (a baby cries) &#8212; that tax relief that helps children &#8212; that’s okay, don’t worry about it.&nbsp; It’s okay to let him cry, or her, whichever &#8212; that helps children and can lead to better health, better school performance, and better future earnings.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, research from Columbia University in New York found that for each dollar this tax cut costs, it returns eight dollars in benefit down the line.&nbsp; Eight dollars would have to be spent other ways.&nbsp; It’s a gigantic help.&nbsp; It’s an eight to one return.&nbsp;<br><br>Your head, your heart, and your budget all lead to the same place.&nbsp; This is the right thing to do, and it’s the smart thing to do.<br><br>Today, these tax cut payments are arriving automatically.&nbsp; But it didn’t happen automatically &#8212; the result of the work that people who did this, advocating for this for a long, long time.&nbsp; And we finally got it passed in my American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to particularly thank those who have been fighting for this for years: Congresswoman Rosa DeLauro from Connecticut.&nbsp; She has been a champion for this issue.&nbsp; Congressman Richie Neal and &#8212; and Torres.&nbsp; And Senators Bennet, Brown, and Booker.&nbsp; And Ron Wyden.&nbsp;<br><br>You’ll probably hear from our Republican friends &#8212; all who voted against this &#8212; but they’ll tout the success as it helps working families in their states and their districts.&nbsp; But in the coming days, we’re also going to hear from them saying, “I want to now extend this tax…”&nbsp; It’s only for one year now.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s all I could get it for, for the first time.&nbsp; And so, I want to extend it into the future now.&nbsp; I have another piece of legislation that will be voted on soon, saying we’re going to continue this.<br><br>To the people who say we can’t afford to give the middle class a break, I say: We can afford it by making people at the top and the big corporations &#8212; over 50 of which paid no taxes last year at all &#8212; to finally just &#8212; just start paying their fair share.&nbsp; I’m not going to gouge them.&nbsp; Just pay their fair share.&nbsp; Because people who are working hard and paying taxes deserve a break.<br><br>That’s why &#8212; excuse me for all these terms I’m using, but my Build Back Better agenda, which still needs to be voted on in the Congress, keeps this tax cut for working families in place for years to come.&nbsp; We shouldn’t let taxes go up on working families.&nbsp; We shouldn’t let child poverty continue to stain the conscience or drag down our economy.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I say to my colleagues in Congress: This tax cut for working families is something we should extend, not end, next year.<br><br>And I say to all of you watching: Make sure your family, friends, and community know about this tax cut.&nbsp; Send to them, as I said, ChildTaxCredit.gov to learn more about the difference this is going to make in their lives.<br><br>Let me close with this: I signed the American Rescue Plan less than two months after taking office on January 20th.&nbsp; Four months later, we’ve implemented the fir- &#8212; we’ve implemented the first-ever automatic monthly payment for any major tax credit ever, as the Vice President was talking about, beyond Social Security, which was a long time ago.<br><br>This groundbreaking effort is similar to what we did in our &#8212; what I called our “war-time effort” to vaccinate Americans against COVID-19, to mobilize the whole country.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re proving &#8212; we’re proving that democracy can deliver for people, and deliver in a timely way &#8212; saving lives, improving lives, helping fuel a recordsetting recovery, giving working families a fighting chance again.&nbsp;<br><br>I received an email today from a mother in Washington State.&nbsp; She’s a young teacher who had just received her payment.&nbsp; She wrote, and I’m quoting, “My family has been living hand to mouth to put me through school so I can follow my passion of molding young minds…&nbsp; This first CTC payment has come at the exact moment when we need it most.&nbsp; These payments may seem small to some, but they are lifechanging for my family, for us.”&nbsp;<br><br>Millions of children and their families &#8212; starting today, their lives are about to change for the better.&nbsp; And our country will be better off for it as well.&nbsp;<br><br>This is a really good day.&nbsp; And parents are going to be able to tell your kids when they’re 25-years-old that you were there the day this happened; we talked about it.&nbsp; We are showing once again that there’s nothing beyond the capacity &#8212; our capacity as Americans to get done when we do it together.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I want to thank you.&nbsp; God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; And kids, thank you for being so polite while I was speaking.&nbsp; You’re very, very nice.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>See you all.&nbsp; Bye bye.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>12:39 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How the Build Back Better Framework Will Support Women’s Employment and Strengthen Family Economic Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/fact-sheet-how-the-build-back-better-framework-will-support-womens-employment-and-strengthen-family-economic-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite the progress our nation has made over the last four months, there remain two million fewer women in the workforce than there were before the pandemic struck – taking a toll on our economy and on millions of families across the country. Thirty years of progress in women’s labor force participation has been eroded;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Despite the progress our nation has made over the last four months, there remain two million fewer women in the workforce than there were before the pandemic struck – taking a toll on our economy and on millions of families across the country. Thirty years of progress in women’s labor force participation has been eroded; millions of women are still struggling to return to the workforce.&nbsp;And while the pandemic has exacerbated this reality, many of the challenges facing women aren’t new. Historically, women have typically held jobs with lower wages and fewer benefits and protections. Women of color are even more likely to work in jobs that have lower wages and few benefits and protections.<br><br>Our economic recovery depends on addressing longstanding discrimination and barriers that have hampered women—including women of color—from fully participating in the labor force. One economist finds the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/11/perspectives/biden-build-back-better/index.html">President’s plan</a>, and especially its investments in the care economy, would increase labor force participation by almost a full percentage point—with even greater gains for women—and boost the economy’s real GDP growth by 10 to 15 basis points in the long-term. Increasing women’s labor force participation is also critical to supporting America’s working families, including the over 4 in 10 mothers – disproportionately women of color – who are sole or primary breadwinners for their families, contributing significantly to their families’ total earnings.<br><br>When women are better off, we’re all better off. The Build Back Better Agenda rests on our commitment to ensuring every American is given a fair shot to get ahead in this country. It will strengthen our families, our communities, and our nation by making bold and necessary investments in women’s employment and ensure a broad and deep recovery – one on which the success of the entire U.S. economy rests. Our economy cannot reach its full potential when half of the population is forced to leave their jobs, cut back on their hours, or unable to access good jobs. These issues are not simply women’s issues. They are issues that affect all families, our economy’s stability and growth, and our nation’s competitiveness.<br><br><strong><u>Supporting Women’s Caregiving Needs</u></strong></p>



<p>Too many American women struggle with the high costs of raising children, caring for a sick family member, providing long-term care for people with disabilities or older adults, and addressing the myriad other caregiving challenges. Although professional care is costly for families, caregivers themselves &#8211; <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat18.htm">disproportionately women of color &#8211;</a> remain some of the <a href="https://equitablegrowth.org/working-papers/the-wages-of-care/">most underpaid workers</a> in the country, often having to rely on public income supports to get by. And, many American women fill the gap in professional caregiving options by providing unpaid care to their loved ones, often causing them to reduce working hours, choose lower-paying jobs, or leave the labor force entirely.<br><br>In&nbsp;part&nbsp;due to the <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w18702">lack of family friendly policies</a>, the United States has fallen behind its competitors in the share of women in the labor force. The United States is one of the only countries in the world that does not guarantee paid leave &#8212; <a href="https://www.bls.gov/ncs/ebs/benefits/2020/employee-benefits-in-the-united-states-march-2020.pdf">95 percent of the lowest wage workers</a>, who tend to be <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/meet-the-low-wage-workforce/#:~:text=Low-wage%20workers%20comprise%20a%20substantial%20share%20of%20the,the%20most%20likely%20to%20be%20raising%20children%20%2843%25%29.">predominately&nbsp;women&nbsp;</a>and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nationalpartnership.org/our-work/resources/economic-justice/paid-leave/paid-family-and-medical-leave-racial-justice-issue-and-opportunity.pdf">workers of color</a>, lack any access to paid family leave. Only 57 percent of children under six years old have parents who report there are good choices for child care where they live. And, <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/system/files/pdf/265126/LTSSOlAmRB.pdf">high costs</a> and increasing <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=AtYpDwAAQBAJ&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;source=gbs_ViewAPI#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false">shortages</a> of care for disabled and elderly people leave many to rely on unpaid caregiving – more than one in six adult women are unpaid eldercare providers. <a href="https://www.aarp.org/content/dam/aarp/livable-communities/old-learn/health/metlife-study-of-caregiving-costs-to-working-caregivers-2011-aarp.pdf">One study</a> estimates that women who leave the labor force early to care for elderly parents lose $330,000 [1]&nbsp;in lifetime wages and Social Security benefits.<br><br>Research shows <a href="http://oro.open.ac.uk/50547/1/care_economy_en.pdf">investments in the care economy</a> would increase employment, especially for women, reducing the gender employment divide. Not only would this support women’s economic security, it would lead to a more robust and equitable economy. The President’s Build Back Better plan:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Creates a National Comprehensive Paid Family and Medical Leave Program</strong>.&nbsp;The program will ensure workers receive partial wage replacement to take time to bond with a new child; care for a seriously ill loved one; deal with a loved one’s military deployment; find safety from sexual assault, stalking, or domestic violence; heal from their own serious illness; or take time to deal with the death of a loved one. This program guarantees twelve weeks of annual paid parental, family, and personal illness/safe leave, and also ensures workers get three days of bereavement leave per year. The program will provide workers up to $4,000 a month, with a minimum of two-thirds of average weekly wages replaced, rising to 80 percent for the lowest wage workers. In California, one study&nbsp;found that the state’s paid leave law increased new mothers’ likelihood of working a year after the birth of their child by <a href="https://equitablegrowth.org/factsheet-what-does-the-research-say-about-the-economics-of-paid-leave/">18 percentage points</a>. In addition <a href="https://journals.lww.com/greenjournal/Citation/2021/04000/Association_Between_Rhode_Island_s_Paid_Family.26.aspx?context=LatestArticles">recent</a> <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32134836/">research</a> shows that in the short term, paid family leave policies are associated with positive health outcomes including <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w25902">better maternal physical health</a>, infant mortality, improved infant attachment and childhood development. Paid family leave encourages men and women to take <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/pam.21894">time off</a>. This is crucial in an economy in which <a href="https://www.thirdway.org/report/the-fatherhood-bonus-and-the-motherhood-penalty-parenthood-and-the-gender-gap-in-pay">fatherhood increases men’s wages</a> and motherhood decreases women’s (by four percent per child), exacerbating the gender wage gap.<br></li><li><strong>Guarantees access to high-quality, affordable child care for low- and middle-income families and offers universal free preschool to all three- and four-year old children</strong><strong>.</strong>&nbsp;President Biden’s Build Back Better plan offers free, high-quality preschool to all three- and four-year old children, fully covers the cost of high-quality child care for young children for the most hard-pressed working families, and ensures that families earning up to 1.5 times their state’s median income will pay no more than 7 percent of their income for all children under age five. This is estimated to increase labor force participation of these parents, and especially women, by up to 20 percent. The President’s plan would also make permanent the dramatic expansion of the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit (CDCTC) enacted in the American Rescue Plan. With this expanded credit, families can receive up to half of what they spend on child care for children under age 13, up to a total of $4,000 for one child or $8,000 for two or more children. In addition to reducing the cost of child care and freeing up money for other spending, child care and preschool programs also increase mothers’ incomes, as mothers continue working and earn more over time.<br></li><li><strong>Expands Access to Long-Term Care Services under Medicaid. </strong>In addition to caring for children, families feel the financial burden of caring for aging relatives and family members with disabilities, and there is a financial strain for people with disabilities living independently to ensure that they are getting care in their homes. At the same time, hundreds of thousands of people who need better care are unable to access it, even though they qualify under Medicaid. Aging relatives and people with disabilities deserve high-quality care that meets their unique needs and personal choices. President Biden is calling on Congress to put $400 billion toward expanding access to quality, affordable home- or community-based care. One <a href="https://scholar.harvard.edu/files/kshen/files/caregivers.pdf">recent study</a> finds that for every 2.4 to 3 women whose parent receives formal home care through Medicaid, one additional daughter works full-time.<br></li><li><strong>Boosts compensation of child care and home care workers.</strong> About nine in ten care workers are women, and nearly <a href="https://nwlc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ChildCareWorkersFS.pdf">five in ten</a> child care workers are women of color. As of 2020, the median <a href="https://www.bls.gov/ooh/personal-care-and-service/childcare-workers.htm">child care worker</a> made $12.24 per hour and the median <a href="https://www.bls.gov/ooh/healthcare/home-health-aides-and-personal-care-aides.htm">home health and personal care aide</a> made $13.02 an hour. On average, child care workers make <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/child-care-workers-arent-paid-enough-to-make-ends-meet/">23 percent below</a> workers who do not work in child care. The President’s plan would ensure child care and preschool teachers are paid at least $15 an hour and comparable to kindergarten teachers if they have similar credentials. The President’s plan to expand HCBS under Medicaid will support well-paying caregiving jobs that include benefits and the ability to collectively bargain. Investment in higher labor standards for care workers improve these jobs and supporting the economic security of women who fill them, help close the gender pay gap, and attract more workers to the care industry.<br></li><li><strong>Addresses Maternal and Infant Health Disparities</strong>. The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to tackling health disparities that are rooted in bias and systemic racism. America’s maternal mortality rates are among the highest in the developed world, and they are especially high among Black women and Native American women— regardless of their income or education levels. The Build Back Better proposal would make health insurance for women who buy it on their own more affordable by making the American Rescue Plan’s premium reductions permanent, saving women $600 a year. It also includes a $3 billion investment to improve maternal and infant health outcomes. Growing and diversifying the perinatal workforce, improving data collection to better understand the causes of maternal death and complications from birth, and investing in community-based organizations are priorities of this Administration.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Strengthening Family Economic Security</u></strong></p>



<p>When households do not have enough income, they are forced to make impossible trade-offs between paying for rent, education, healthcare, and food. These choices have consequences and limit the investments made in oneself and one’s children. The Build Back Better agenda makes significant investments to increase household stability and economic security.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Supports the construction or rehabilitation of over 1 million affordable rental housing units in building and small towns across the country. </strong>Before the pandemic, HUD estimated that nearly 5 million female-headed households that didn’t receive federal housing assistance paid more than half their income in rent or lived in severely inadequate units. The Build Back Better plan would bolster funding for successful housing subsidy programs to produce and preserve housing that is affordable for very- and extremely-low income renters.<br></li><li><strong>Addresses longstanding public housing capital needs.</strong> Nearly two million people across the country live in public housing. Approximately 75 percent of households living in public housing units are headed by women, and 33 percent of all households are headed by women with children. Nearly half of the nearly 1 million units of public housing are over 50 years old and many contain lead paint, mold, and other health hazards. The President’s plan calls for a transformative investment of $40 billion to rehabilitate and preserve public housing, addressing residents’ critical health and safety concerns. This is not just a safety issue but a racial justice issue, as approximately three in four public housing residents are people of color.<br></li><li><strong>Extends the Expanded Monthly Child Tax Credit</strong>. The Build Back Better proposal would extend the Child Tax Credit (CTC) expansion first enacted in the American Rescue Plan – increasing the credit from $2,000 per child to $3,000 per child six-years-old and above, and from $2000 to $3,600 per child for children under six. This means a monthly payment of&nbsp;$300 per month per child under 6 and $250 a month for each child six and older. Parents can use this tax credit on everything from diapers, to putting more food on the table, to paying the rent or mortgage. An <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/american-rescue-plan-act-includes-critical-expansions-of-child-tax-credit-and">estimated 66 million children</a> (90 percent) and their parents will benefit from this tax credit expansion including 9 million Black children and 18 million Latino children.<br></li><li><strong>Supports nutrition security</strong>. Nutrition insecurity has a negative and lasting impact on a child’s ability to learn and can put children at higher risk for diseases such as diabetes, heart disease, and high blood pressure. However, provide adequate nutrition can be an incredible financial burden for parents. The Build Back Better plan will expand free meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year. Additionally, the plan will invest more than $25 billion so that the families of all 29 million children eligible for free and reduced-price school meals will receive a $75 per child per month benefit to purchase nutritious foods during the summer.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Expanding Education, Training, and Job Opportunities for Women</u></strong></p>



<p>The&nbsp;Build Back Better agenda will ensure that the economy is built on a foundation of equity, by strengthening the education and workforce pipeline for more women to obtain high-quality in-demand jobs. These workforce development investments are based on evidence-based approaches to supporting workers, including women and people of color. Some of these approaches include wraparound services –such as child care and transportation – income supports, counseling, and case management, paired with high-quality training and effective partnerships between educational institutions, unions, and employers. These investments will ensure jobs have fair and equal pay, safe and healthy workplaces, and that workplaces are free from racial, gender, and other forms of discrimination and harassment. They will also help more women enroll in college, reduce their need to rely on student debt, and ensure they have the supports they need to complete their training program, certificate or degree.<br><br>The President’s Build Back Better plan:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protects the health, safety and rights of working women.</strong>&nbsp;This includes jobs with fair and equal pay, safe and healthy workplaces, and workplaces free from racial, gender, and other forms of discrimination and harassment. In addition to a $10 billion investment in enforcement as part of the plan’s workforce proposals, the President is calling for increased penalties when employers violate workplace safety and health rules. President Biden is also calling on Congress to ensure all workers have a free and fair choice to join a union by passing the Protecting the Right to Organize (PRO) Act. Unions benefit women’s wages;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/union2.t02.htm">in 2020</a>, the median weekly earning of full-time workers 16+ was $1,067 for women who are members of unions, $1,057 for women who are represented by unions, and $862 for non-union women. His plan also ensures domestic workers receive the legal benefits and protections they deserve and tackles gender pay inequities.<br></li><li><strong>Invests in gender equitable workforce development programs and creates new career pathways for women.</strong> As more Americans <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/CLF16OV">rejoin</a> the workforce or <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/carolinecastrillon/2021/05/16/why-millions-of-employees-plan-to-switch-jobs-post-covid/?sh=13afaf2b11e7">seek out new opportunities</a> in a changing economy, we must ensure workers have ready access to the skills they will need to succeed, and improve racial and gender equity. This includes registered apprenticeships and pre-apprenticeships, creating one to two million new registered apprenticeships slots, and making these opportunities accessible to underserved populations, including women and people of color, through successful pre-apprenticeship programs, such as Women in Apprenticeship and Non-Traditional Occupations grants that help to expand pathways for women to enter and lead in all industries. It also includes sector-based training programs that provide millions of workers, including women and people of color, with in-demand training that leads to high-quality jobs in high-growth and critical industries and sectors including information technology, clean energy, public health, home care and child care, manufacturing and infrastructure. The President’s plan also creates a new subsidized jobs program that will invest in the creation of hundreds of thousands of subsidized employment opportunities for workers adversely affected by the economic crisis, especially public assistance recipients, long-term unemployed individuals and the underemployed. These investments also include the creation of career pathway programs in middle and high schools, prioritizing increased access to computer science and high-quality career and technical programs that connect underrepresented students to STEM and in-demand sectors through partnerships with both institutions of higher education and employers.<br></li><li><strong>Increases the affordability of, access to, and student success in education beyond high school. </strong>Women constitute <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/ipeds/TrendGenerator/app/build-table/2/2?rid=1&amp;cid=13">more than half</a> of all college students. At the same time, <a href="https://iwpr.org/iwpr-issues/student-parent-success-initiative/parents-in-college-by-the-numbers/">a number of women in higher education are raising children while pursuing a certificate or degree, often at community colleges. More than 20 percent</a> of all college students are parents; of those, over 70 percent are mothers and 43 percent are single mothers. Only <a href="https://iwpr.org/iwpr-issues/student-parent-success-initiative/investing-in-single-mothers-higher-education-state/">8 percent</a> of single mothers who entered college between 2013 and 2017 earned a degree or certificate within six years, compared to 49 percent of women students who were not parents. Additionally, women are more likely to face financial barriers while in college. They are about <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/fastfacts/display.asp?id=900">seven percentage points</a> more likely to take out federal loans than men, and have more federal student loan debt on average. Increased financial support for college <a href="https://direct.mit.edu/edfp/article/15/1/164/10312/Does-Broad-Based-Merit-Aid-Improve-College">can</a> <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0047272720301171?via%3Dihub">boost</a> completion rates. Increased financial support for college can boost completion rates. The President’s $109 billion plan will ensure that first-time students and workers wanting to reskill can enroll in a community college to earn a degree or credential for free. The President is calling for a $39 billion investment in tuition subsidies to increase affordability at Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and Minority-Serving Institutions. The plan also increases the maximum Pell Grant award by approximately $1,500 and allows DREAMers to access Pell Grants. This will support the 43 percent of women in college who rely on Pell to afford their higher education goals. Finally, the President is proposing a bold $62 billion grant program to invest in completion and retention activities at colleges and universities that serve high numbers of low-income students, particularly community colleges, which can be used for student support services that include child care.<br></li><li><strong>Advances equity in research and development and science, technology, engineering, and math</strong>. Discrimination leads to less innovation: one study found that innovation in the United States would quadruple if women, people of color, and children from low-income families invented at the same rate as other groups. Persistent inequities in access to R&amp;D dollars and to careers in innovation industries prevents the U.S. economy from reaching its full potential. The President’s plan includes $10 billion in new grants to HBCUs and MSIs, in addition to, funding for research infrastructure (ex. labs) and funding for equity in STEM education.<br></li><li><strong>Helps small businesses, including women-owned businesses and minority business enterprises, access capital and scale through over $30 billion in investments</strong><strong>.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden is calling on Congress to invest in federal programs that empower small firms to participate in federal research and other research and development initiatives that have the potential for commercialization. His plan will also support new grantmaking through the Minority Business Development Agency that will help small businesses owned by people of color access private capital. And, it will enable small businesses to drive the economic recovery by investing in the Small Business Administration’s 7(a) loan program and Small Business Investment Company program.<br></li><li><strong>Invests in teachers. </strong>For too long, we have underinvested in our teachers, <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/clr">76% of whom</a> are women. From teachers in training to veteran teachers, the President’s plan invests $9 billion in teachers, addressing teacher shortages, recruiting more teachers of color, improving teacher preparation and supporting teachers. The plan would invest in innovative and effective teacher training programs like residencies, that provide future teachers with a year of experience before they take charge of a classroom, double the annual scholarship for future teachers from $4,000 to $8,000 per year, and help schools leverage their expert teachers as mentors supporting new and struggling teachers, or as leaders in other areas, and compensate them for this work. All of these policies will disproportionately benefit women.</li></ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" />



<p>[1] The study, which uses data from 2008, finds a loss of approximately $274,044 in 2008 dollars. This number is adjusted for inflation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Distributes First Monthly Payments of the Expanded Child Tax Credit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-distributes-first-monthly-payments-of-the-expanded-child-tax-credit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, tens of millions of American families will begin to see their first monthly Child Tax Credit payments. The Department of Treasury estimates that $15 billion were distributed today to tens of millions of working families with 60 million children. For the 86% of families using direct deposit, they will receive their child payment today,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, tens of millions of American families will begin to see their first monthly Child Tax Credit payments. The Department of Treasury estimates that $15 billion were distributed today to tens of millions of working families with 60 million children. For the 86% of families using direct deposit, they will receive their child payment today, July 15<sup>th</sup>, and the 15<sup>th</sup> of every month for the rest of 2021. It will show up in their bank accounts described as “ChildCTC.” Others will receive their check in the mail today or in the coming days.</p>



<p>The American Rescue Plan is providing the <strong><u>largest-ever</u></strong> Child Tax Credit – increasing from $2,000 per child to $3,000 for each child between the ages of 6 and 17, and to $3,600 for each child under the age of 6. This historic increase will provide middle-class families with critical tax relief and will lift millions of children out of poverty.</p>



<p><strong><u>Major Tax Cut for Middle Class Working Families:</u> </strong>Nearly all middle-class families will receive the expanded child tax credit, to help them meet the costs of raising children with the security and dignity they deserve. And because monthly payments start today, they won’t have to wait until tax season for tax relief that millions of families need now.</p>



<ul><li><em><u>Full Payment for Most Families</u></em>. All families will get the full Child Tax Credit if they make up to $150,000 for a married couple or $112,500 for a family with a single parent (also called Head of Household). Eligible families will receive monthly payments of the Child Tax Credit <em><u>automatically</u></em> if they filed taxes in the last two years.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em><u>$7,200 for Typical Family with Young Children</u></em>: For a married couple earning a combined $60,000 per year with two children under age 6, their Child Tax Credit will equal $7,200, providing an <strong><em><u>additional $3,200 tax cut</u></em></strong> in 2021 thanks to the expansion<strong><em>.</em></strong></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>The first monthly Child Tax Credit ever:</u></strong> Today, <strong><em>four months</em> </strong>after the American Rescue Plan was signed into law, tens of millions of families with nearly 60 million children are receiving the first-ever <strong><em>monthly payments</em></strong> of the Child Tax Credit<strong><em>.</em></strong> This reflects the swift implementation efforts of the White House, Treasury, and the IRS.</p>



<ul><li><em><u>$250-$300 a Month Per Child</u></em>: Starting today, working families will receive monthly payments of $250 for each child ages 6 to 17 and $300 for each child under 6 years old.</li><li><em><u>Helping Working Families Meet the Costs of Raising Children</u>:</em> Tens of millions of working families will be able to rely on these monthly payments to help with the costs of raising their children – from putting food on the table, to covering the costs of school supplies, new clothes, and unexpected expenses.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Over 97 percent of Families Receiving the 2021 Child Tax Credit are Working</u></strong><strong>: </strong>The Treasury Department estimates that <strong><em><u>over 97 percent</u></em></strong><strong><em> </em></strong>of families that will receive the expanded Child Tax Credit are working familieswith wages or self-employment income. And for the families that don’t have income, many of those are seniors taking care of grandchildren or people with serious disabilities and health issues.</p>



<p><strong><u>More than 26 million Children from Hard-Pressed Families will now get a full Child Tax Credit:</u></strong> Treasury estimates that the hard-pressed low-income families of over 26 million children that previously would have gotten a smaller Child Tax Credit than families with higher earnings, will now receive the full expanded Child Tax Credit. Prior to the American Rescue Plan, researchers found that over half of Black and Hispanic children were in families ineligible for the full Child Tax Credit because of too little earnings.</p>



<p><strong><u>A Historic Reduction in Child Poverty</u>: </strong>The expanded Child Tax Credit is the main driver in experts’ projections that the American Rescue Plan could cut child poverty by around half. Even by the most conservative estimates, the Child Tax Credit alone is projected to reduce child poverty by a multiple of any <a href="http://www.cbpp.org/sites/default/files/atoms/files/1-27-21pov-data.xlsx">previous year</a>.</p>



<p><strong><u>Administration-wide effort to help sign up additional children and their families:</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Simplified non-filer portal</u>:</strong> The Child Tax Credit has been around for more than twenty years, but there has never been a tool to help non-filers claim the credit. Thanks to the implementation efforts of the White House, Treasury, and the IRS, the first-ever non-filer portal for the Child Tax Credit was launched by the IRS in June.</li><li><strong><u>ChildTaxCredit.gov:</u> </strong>The White House launched <a href="https://childtaxcredit.gov/">ChildTaxCredit.gov</a> – a one-stop-shop in English and Spanish for user-friendly information on the Child Tax Credit, including a step-by-step guide to using the non-filer portal in multiple languages.</li><li><strong><u>Working with Major Non-Profit Organizations and Community Groups that Fight for Children: </u></strong>For months, the White House has worked closely with children’s advocacy groups, women’s organizations, committed faith-based organizations, and other nonprofit organizations in an on-going collaborative effort to find the most effective strategies for signing-up families who aren’t receiving the credit, through creating awareness, developing navigator and trusted messenger sign-up strategies, and working to improve website accessibility.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Investment with a high return:</u></strong> Studies show that children whose families get more in refundable credits do <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/up-front/2021/03/11/new-child-tax-credit-could-slash-poverty-now-and-boost-social-mobility-later/">better in school</a> and <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/prancotamamnta.104.116?seq=1">score higher on standardized tests</a>, are more likely to <a href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/full/10.1086/697477">graduate high school</a> and <a href="https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/pol.20160298">attend college</a>, and <a href="https://www.census.gov/library/working-papers/2020/adrm/CES-WP-20-35.html">make more money</a> as adults. These children are also less likely to face the early onset of disabilities and health issues like <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/income-support-associated-with-improved-health-outcomes-for-children-many">diabetes</a> that can represent key barriers to employment later in life. In fact, research from Columbia University <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/605978841a7c672eaed64ec6/1616476294180/Child-Allowance-CBA-brief-CPSP-March-2021.pdf">shows</a> that each $1 invested in the Child Tax Credit returns over $8 to society in improved health for children and their parents, better educational outcomes and higher future incomes, and reduced crime and criminal justice costs.</p>



<p><strong><u>Extending the new Child Tax Credit for years to come:</u></strong> The American Rescue Plan’s expanded Child Tax Credit is only for 2021. This is a historic investment that will lift children and working families out of poverty. That’s why President Biden believes that we should extend the new Child Tax Credit for years and years to come. He is proposing that we do so in his American Families Plan and Build Back Better agenda.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Michigan Disaster Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-michigan-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Michigan and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, flooding, and tornadoes from June 25 to June 26, 2021. The President&#8217;s action makes Federal funding available to affected&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Michigan and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, flooding, and tornadoes from June 25 to June 26, 2021.</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s action makes Federal funding available to affected individuals in the counties of Washtenaw and Wayne.</p>



<p>Assistance can include grants for temporary housing and home repairs, low-cost loans to cover uninsured property losses, and other programs to help individuals and business owners recover from the effects of the disaster.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Scott A. Burgess as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Damage assessments are continuing in other areas, and more counties and additional forms of assistance may be designated after the assessments are fully completed.</p>



<p>Residents and business owners who sustained losses in the designated counties can begin applying for assistance by registering online at <a href="http://www.DisasterAssistance.gov">http://www.DisasterAssistance.gov</a> or by calling 1-800-621-FEMA(3362) or 1-800-462-7585 (TTY) for the hearing and speech impaired.&nbsp; The toll-free telephone numbers will operate from 7:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m. (local time) seven days a week until further notice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on Two Million Americans Signing Up for Health Coverage and Launching the “Summer Sprint to Coverage” Campaign</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-two-million-americans-signing-up-for-health-coverage-and-launching-the-summer-sprint-to-coverage-campaign/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24017</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I ran for President, I promised the American people that I would build on the historic foundation of the Affordable Care Act to ensure that every American has access to quality, affordable health care. As part of that promise, just weeks after taking office, my Administration opened a special enrollment period through HealthCare.gov to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>When I ran for President, I promised the American people that I would build on the historic foundation of the Affordable Care Act to ensure that every American has access to quality, affordable health care. As part of that promise, just weeks after taking office, my Administration opened a special enrollment period through HealthCare.gov to provide all Americans the opportunity to sign up for health insurance.<br> <br>Five months later, the results are clear: two million Americans have signed up for the peace of mind that health insurance brings. That’s two million more Americans who can sleep soundly at night, no longer having to worry whether their family would lose everything due to a heart attack, a cancer diagnosis, or an accident. This milestone is in addition to our progress expanding access to health insurance through vital programs like Medicaid and the Children’s Health Insurance Program, which now cover more than 81 million Americans.<br> <br>I pledged to lower the cost of health care — and that’s exactly what we did with my American Rescue Plan. Thanks to the law, nine million Americans who buy their coverage through the Affordable Care Act have lower premiums, saving families an average of $50 per person per month — that’s $2,400 per year for a typical family of four. In fact, four out of five people can now find a quality plan with a premium of $10 or less per month. And my Build Back Better agenda will expand on these efforts and make health care more affordable — including by adding dental, vision, and hearing coverage to Medicare; closing the Medicaid coverage gap for low-income Americans; and making the premium reductions in the American Rescue Plan permanent.<br> <br>With 30 days to go until the opportunity for special enrollment closes and more affordable quality plans, now is the time to sign up for health coverage. Today, my Administration is launching a final 30-day “Summer Sprint to Coverage” campaign to help people and communities across America who still need health insurance sign up for it. I encourage everyone who is not yet covered to visit HealthCare.gov and sign up by August 15. If you already have coverage, help get your friends, family, neighbors, and others in your community signed up as well.<br> <br>More than a decade after the landmark passage of the Affordable Care Act, as we emerge from a once-in-a-century pandemic, we are on our way to truly making health care a right and not a privilege. I urge Congress to do its part by passing the critical health care reforms in my Build Back Better agenda — and I urge all Americans to get covered today.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Atomic Veterans Day, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/15/a-proclamation-on-national-atomic-veterans-day-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 16, 1945, the United States detonated the world&#8217;s first nuclear device in Alamogordo, New Mexico.&#160; Better known by&#160;its code name, &#8220;Trinity,&#8221; the successful test of the first atomic bomb brought forth a new age of science that changed the lives of many of those who served in our Armed Forces, and forever altered&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 16, 1945, the United States detonated the world&#8217;s first nuclear device in Alamogordo, New Mexico.&nbsp; Better known by&nbsp;its code name, &#8220;Trinity,&#8221; the successful test of the first atomic bomb brought forth a new age of science that changed the lives of many of those who served in our Armed Forces, and forever altered the nature and the risks of war.&nbsp; Just weeks later, the world witnessed the horrors of nuclear destruction at Hiroshima and Nagasaki, which marked the end of World War II but opened our eyes to the truth that a nuclear war must never be fought.</p>



<p>Many brave men and women have risked their lives in service to our Nation, but few know the story of our &#8220;Atomic Veterans&#8221; &#8212; American military service members who participated in nuclear tests between 1945 and 1962, served with United States military forces in&nbsp;or around Hiroshima and Nagasaki through mid-1946, or were held as prisoners of war in or near Hiroshima or Nagasaki. &nbsp;These veterans served at testing sites like the Bikini Atoll and witnessed the destructive power of nuclear weapons firsthand. &nbsp;On National Atomic Veterans Day, we recognize and honor the contributions of America&#8217;s Atomic Veterans for their sacrifice and dedication to our Nation&#8217;s security, and recommit to supporting our Atomic Veterans and educating ourselves on the role&nbsp;these patriots played in our national story.</p>



<p>Atomic Veterans served our Nation with distinction, but their service came at a great cost.&nbsp; Many developed health conditions due to radiation exposure, yet because they were not able to discuss the nature of their service, they were unable to seek medical care or disability compensation from the Department of Veterans Affairs for their illnesses.&nbsp; Decades later in 1996, the United States Congress repealed the Nuclear Radiation and Secrecy Agreements Act, allowing Atomic Veterans to tell their stories and file for benefits.&nbsp; By then, thousands of Atomic Veterans had died without their families knowing the true extent of their service.</p>



<p>Our Nation has one truly sacred obligation:&nbsp; to properly prepare and equip our troops when we send them into harm&#8217;s way, and to care for them and their families when they return from service.&nbsp; As Commander in Chief, I am committed to fulfilling our obligation to the Atomic Veterans and their families, and ensuring that all of our Nation&#8217;s veterans have timely access to&nbsp;needed services, medical care, and benefits.</p>



<p>On this National Atomic Veterans Day, our country remembers the service and sacrifices of Atomic Veterans.&nbsp; Their heroism and patriotism will never be forgotten and we always honor their bravery and devotion to duty.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim July 16, 2021, as National Atomic Veterans Day.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this day with appropriate ceremonies and activities that honor our Nation&#8217;s Atomic Veterans whose brave service and sacrifice played an important role in the defense of our Nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fifteenth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Official Working Visit of Chancellor Merkel of Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/15/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-official-working-visit-of-chancellor-merkel-of-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23891</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (July 14, 2021) 2:53 P.M. EDT SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Hi, everyone, and thanks for joining this afternoon.&#160; Today’s call will be embargoed until 5:00 a.m. tomorrow, July 15, and the contents will be attributed to a “senior administration official.”&#160; With that, I will turn it over to our speaker, [senior administration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(July 14, 2021)</p>



<p>2:53 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Hi, everyone, and thanks for joining this afternoon.&nbsp; Today’s call will be embargoed until 5:00 a.m. tomorrow, July 15, and the contents will be attributed to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; With that, I will turn it over to our speaker, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And hi, everybody.&nbsp; Thanks for joining this afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow, as you know, German Chancellor Angela Merkel will be at the White House for an official working visit, which we very much see as one that will affirm the deep and enduring bilateral ties between our two countries.&nbsp; This is very much a forward-looking visit which will address our robust partnership on shared global challenges.&nbsp; And as we look forward, we’ll be looking for ways to continue strengthening cooperation between our countries in the months and years ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s also fair to say that, over the course of her long and distinguished tenure, Chancellor Merkel has been a true friend to the United States, a strong advocate for the transatlantic partnership, for multilateral cooperation, as well as for our shared priorities.&nbsp; In their meeting, I expect that President Biden will convey gratitude for her leadership role in Europe and around the world as she prepares to depart the German political stage following their elections this September.</p>



<p>In terms of the schedule: In the morning, Vice President Harris will host Chancellor Angela Merkel for a working breakfast at the Vice President’s Residence.&nbsp; Then in the afternoon at the White House, the President and Chancellor Merkel will have a one-on-one meeting, an expanded bilateral meeting, followed by a press conference.</p>



<p>And in the evening, President Biden will host Chancellor Merkel for a small dinner with a range of individuals who have long been strong supporters of Germany and the bilateral relationship, which will further demonstrate the close and continuing ties between our countries.</p>



<p>In terms of what is on the agenda in their bilateral meeting, as I said, this is very much a working visit and we expect them to discuss the full range of policy issues in our bilateral relationship.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’ll address the threat of climate change, including the need for progress between the Leaders’ Meeting this spring and COP26 in Glasgow this fall.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I expect them to discuss the COVID-19 pandemic, including their shared desire to provide access to vaccines around the world, and to shore up global health security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I expect that they will discuss the full range of shared security challenges, including Afghanistan, Libya, and the Sahel.</p>



<p>I expect the leaders also will discuss shared ways to respond to regional challenges, including addressing Russian cyberattacks and territorial aggression; countering China’s rising influence, non-market economic practices, and human rights abuses, including forced labor; support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and also bolstering the Euro-Atlantic aspirations of the Western Balkan countries.</p>



<p>And then, finally, their commitment to shoring up democracy at home and defending human rights, democratic institutions, and the rule of law around the world.</p>



<p>To make a few general points on the bilateral relationship, Germany is one of our staunchest allies.&nbsp; That relationship has long been built on shared values of freedom, democracy, human rights, and rule of law.&nbsp; There is also extensive cultural and economic ties between our countries.</p>



<p>As I think you all know, the Biden administration has an overarching goal of revitalizing the transatlantic relationship, which includes increasing cooperation with NATO and raising the level of ambition with the EU &#8212; two goals that I think the President was able to make good progress on during his trip to Europe last month, where, of course, he had the opportunity to engage with Chancellor Merkel on the margins of the G7 in Cornwall, as well as their shared participation in the NATO Summit.&nbsp; And our relationship with Germany, of course, is a very important foundation for all of that.</p>



<p>On the economic side: Germany is our largest trading partner in Europe, and the U.S. is Germany’s largest export market.&nbsp; We’re also a major source of foreign investment in each other’s economies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the security side, the U.S. cooperates closely with Germany in NATO to ensure the prosperity and security of citizens on both sides of the Atlantic.&nbsp; Germany has approximately 36,000 active duty U.S. service members, with President Biden announcing earlier this year the additional deployment of 500 troops, as well as halting the planned withdrawal by the previous administration of U.S. forces from Germany.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Germany is also an essential hub for training, operations, and logistics for U.S. and Allied forces operating in Europe, Africa, and the Middle East.&nbsp; Our troops served together, of course, in Afghanistan for nearly two decades.&nbsp; We also cooperate in the counter-ISIS campaign, with both U.S. and German troops on the ground in Iraq as part of the NATO training mission.</p>



<p>And as I mentioned earlier, we also, of course, have close cultural and people-to-people ties.</p>



<p>Finally, I want to touch briefly on the deliverables that you can expect to see coming out on Thursday: We’re expecting the two leaders to release the Washington Declaration, which will outline their common vision for cooperation to confront policy challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this document is likely to lay out the broad principles and values that are shaping our relationship and that we believe are going to be guiding principles for the relationship in the months and years ahead as we continue to confront the shared challenges that we both face in terms of our shared commitment to democratic principles, values, and institutions, and human rights; common dedication to upholding the international rules-based order and an open world without spheres of influence; our joint efforts to build strong and equitable market economies that cultivate resilience and demonstrate that democratic leadership delivers for the world; and, of course, the importance of transatlantic cooperation.</p>



<p>We’re also working on developing other initiatives that will solidify areas of our bilateral relationship that we can continue to strengthen and develop in the years ahead, including a Futures Forum, which will bring together Germans and Americans from a wide range of sectors to be able to analyze and propose solutions to global problems going forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our two governments will also look at developing an economic dialogue to further strengthen this part of our bilateral relationship, and we’ll also look at launching a climate and energy partnership, which will enable us to work together to address climate change, transformational energy technologies, and support for energy transitions in emerging economies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, looking very much forward to the Chancellor being here tomorrow, expect a very robust discussion between the two leaders on the full range of policy priorities, and are looking forward to releasing and announcing deliverables that are very much focused on strengthening and continuing to deepen the bilateral ties between our countries as well as our peoples.</p>



<p>So, let me stop there and take some questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Everyone, thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; I’m going to try to squeeze in two if it&#8217;s possible.&nbsp; First, on Nord Stream: Do you anticipate any breakthroughs with Chancellor Merkel or her team on the Nord Stream issue?&nbsp; And if not, could we anticipate any consequences with regard to the Biden administration&#8217;s position on that?&nbsp; Or does the administration sort of bite its tongue, for lack of a better expression, and wait to work with Merkel&#8217;s successor and pick up these discussions?&nbsp; So if you could talk about how that will work.</p>



<p>And then, if I could just throw in a really Wall Street Journal-ly question: The U.S. Commerce Department, last week, released a redacted report regarding the Trump administration&#8217;s auto tariffs, and this was something that made Germany very, very nervous.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a lot of information on that, and I&#8217;m wondering if that issue is going to come up and whether or not auto tariffs are even remotely on the table with this administration.&nbsp; Anything you can give us on that would be awesome.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, to take your second question first, I&#8217;m not personally tracking the Commerce report, so would defer on that to my press colleagues if there&#8217;s anything they want to follow up and share on, on that specific issue.</p>



<p>On the Nord Stream issue, as you know, we&#8217;ve been engaging for a while now with the German government at multiple levels on our concerns about Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; This has included engagement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, by the Secretary of State in their conversations with the German government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do expect that President Biden will raise his longstanding concerns with Chancellor Merkel during their meeting about Russia&#8217;s geopolitical project and about the importance of developing concrete mechanisms to ensure that energy is not used as a coercive tool against Ukraine, our Eastern Flank allies, or any other country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We believe that the sanctions waivers that we announced in May have given us diplomatic space to be able to work with Germany, to have these conversations, to try and find ways to address the negative impacts of the pipeline.&nbsp; Our teams have been discussing these concerns.&nbsp; I expect that they will continue discussing these concerns.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are not anticipating any sort of formal announcement or deliverable coming out of the leaders’ meetings tomorrow on Nord Stream.&nbsp; But like I said, the teams have been having very productive conversations on this set of issues and expect that those will continue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration officials].&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this call.&nbsp; I wanted to, I guess, ask you on &#8212; just a quick follow-up on Nord Stream, and then I have another question.</p>



<p>On Nord Stream, German officials have said they expect this to be resolved in August.&nbsp; You know, there have been some hints that it could come sooner than that.&nbsp; Can you &#8212; since we’re on background here, can you &#8212; or maybe even just off the record &#8212; can you say why you weren&#8217;t able to figure this out before this visit?&nbsp; It seems like, you know, that that&#8217;s usually a big goal.</p>



<p>And then I have a separate question.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Go ahead with your separate question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So the second question has to do with another point of contention, which is the German position on the WTO waiver.&nbsp; There have been protests, balloons, big banners all over D.C.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been protests in other cities.&nbsp; Do you &#8212; I know that the President is a strong proponent of the waiver, but do you anticipate this factoring into the discussion?&nbsp; Or do you think it will just be the, sort of, like, “We agree to disagree, and let&#8217;s focus on the things we have in common”?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sorry, I missed a part of what you said.&nbsp; I heard the balloons and the banners and the waiver.&nbsp; Which &#8212; which specific waiver?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The WTO waiver for intellectual property &#8212; right? &#8212; that is being considered at the WTO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Sorry, is this the &#8212; sorry, the TRIPS waiver or is this a different &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah, yeah.&nbsp; TRIPS waiver.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Lots of &#8212; lots of protests, so I just wanted to ensure I was &#8212; I was tracking the right question.</p>



<p>Look, I, you know &#8212; I take your point on the Nord Stream discussions.&nbsp; I mean, like I said, our teams have been having very robust conversations on this.&nbsp; You know, I think there&#8217;s &#8211;there&#8217;s a lot of aspects that we want to work through.&nbsp; There&#8217;s things that we want to discuss in terms of the energy components of this, the impact that it has potentially on Eastern Flank allies, on Ukraine, and really believe that that the waivers that we were able to use in in this case have provided the space for this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I wouldn&#8217;t read too much into the timing of this.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s something that we&#8217;ve continued to have good discussions on.&nbsp; I think you&#8217;re &#8212; you know, the August timeframe I think people are tracking on is when the next report by the State Department is due to Congress.&nbsp; But I think we&#8217;re not anticipating having anything to announce that at this visit in particular, but do believe that we are having very productive conversations with the German government.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue having those conversations with them in the days ahead.</p>



<p>On the TRIPS waiver, you know, I think the President has been very clear about his position on a waiver.&nbsp; He supports it, given the extraordinary circumstances that call for extraordinary measures.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re encouraged that our announcement in May has encouraged other countries to be able to put additional proposals and ideas on the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think, at the same time, we know that a waiver alone won&#8217;t result in the scale and the speed that we need to make enough vaccines to end the pandemic.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re continuing to ramp up our own efforts, including with the private sector, to expand vaccine manufacturing and distribution around the world.</p>



<p>And I think that this broad goal is very much one that President Biden and Chancellor Merkel share in terms of their joint commitment to COVAX, the contributions that the United States, that Germany, the EU, and other countries made at the G7&nbsp; &#8212; and do expect that they will continue to have conversations about how we can ensure the widest distribution of vaccines on a very rapid timeframe to a number of countries around the world as the best and most effective way of ultimately ending the pandemic.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Another Nord Stream-related question: After tomorrow, President Biden will have met with the main Nord Stream 2 proponents &#8212; President Putin and Chancellor Merkel &#8212; but not with the main opponents &#8212; President Zelensky of Ukraine.&nbsp; I was just wondering, what is the thinking on sequencing and not meeting with Zelensky first?&nbsp; And Zelensky (inaudible) his White House meeting would be taking place in July after the invitation was extended. &nbsp;Is that meeting still planned to happen in July?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I &#8212; so thank you for the question.&nbsp; You know, I think there has been a lot of engagement at different levels of the U.S. government not only with Germany, but also with Ukraine.&nbsp; The President did have a phone call with President Zelensky right before his trip to Europe before he met with President Putin.&nbsp; They were able to discuss the situation of Russia&#8217;s continued aggression against Ukraine, also an opportunity to discuss Nord Stream and some of those broader issues.</p>



<p>So the President did actually have conversations with Zelensky before he went to Europe, before he saw Merkel on the margins of the G7, and before he met with President Putin there as well.&nbsp; When &#8212; and Chancellor Merkel, it&#8217;s worth flagging, has also been engaging with President Zelensky who was in Berlin earlier this week.&nbsp; And so we very much support the conversations that the Germans and the Ukrainians are having directly about Ukraine&#8217;s concerns about Nord Stream and stuff that the Germans might be prepared to take in response to that.</p>



<p>When the President spoke with President Zelensky earlier this summer, he invited him to visit Washington this summer.&nbsp; We never specified what month that was going to take place and are still anticipating a visit by President Zelensky to the White House this summer, but don&#8217;t have a date to announce at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; Hello, thank you for doing this.&nbsp; So I have question &#8212; earlier you said the meeting is going to also talk about the challenges coming out from China.&nbsp; And China remains to be Germany&#8217;s biggest trade partner in 2020.&nbsp; I know Biden administration has, you know, proposed about the supply chain (inaudible) by forced labor, human rights abuse, protect intellectual property.&nbsp; However, with that such big amount of trade partnership between China and Germany, how can President Biden convince Chancellor Merkel to work with the United States to face the challenge from China?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I thank you very much for the question.&nbsp; I &#8212; like I said, I think China very much is going to be part of the agenda between the two leaders tomorrow.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s frankly been something that we have been actively discussing with our European allies over the first six months of the administration.&nbsp; And I think we really saw the fruits of that diplomatic engagement during the President&#8217;s trip to Europe last month, where there was signs of increasing convergence among our allies in &#8212; and partners at the G7. &nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, President Biden, Chancellor Merkel agreed with other leaders on the importance of responding to China&#8217;s non-market practices, the need to speak out against human rights abuses.&nbsp; The communiqué coming out of the G7 also addressed the need for action against forced labor practices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the NATO Summit, there was agreement, for the first time ever, on the security challenge from China, including plans to include China in the new strategic concepts that allies are going to be working on over the next year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then at the U.S.-EU summit, leaders launched the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council, which will enable us to deal with a wide range of issues &#8212; including emerging technologies, competition policies &#8212; and very much expect that dealing with China&#8217;s non-market practices, economic abuses, et cetera will be part of those conversations.</p>



<p>I think we&#8217;ve consistently been very clear that we need to engage China from a position of strength, which includes our alliances and partnerships.&nbsp; And Germany, of course, is one of our closest alliances.&nbsp; And frankly, we think, to your specific question on economics, that it actually makes economic sense for us to work together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S.-EU trade and investment relationship is the largest in the world.&nbsp; As I noted, the U.S. and German relationship is also very significant.&nbsp; And we think that we&#8217;re going to be much more effective in terms of harnessing the power of that transatlantic relationship, that bilateral relationship to set the global rules of the road on issues that we care about.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; That concludes our call.&nbsp; Reminder that this is on background, attributed to an “SAO.&#8221;&nbsp; And the contents of this call are embargoed until tomorrow morning at 5:00 a.m.</p>



<p>Have a good afternoon.</p>



<p>3:15 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 14, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/14/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-14-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:43 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; All right.&#160; So I have a special guest with me today.&#160; Joining us in the briefing room is actress and multiplatinum recording singer/songwriter, Olivia Rodrigo, who traversed red lights and stop signs to see us.&#160; If you know her music, you&#8217;ll get&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:43 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; So I have a special guest with me today.&nbsp; Joining us in the briefing room is actress and multiplatinum recording singer/songwriter, Olivia Rodrigo, who traversed red lights and stop signs to see us.&nbsp; If you know her music, you&#8217;ll get that dad joke there.&nbsp; And we just want to thank you for using your platform and your voice for elevating the important issue of young people getting vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She&#8217;s here today to meet with the President and Dr. Fauci later this afternoon, but she agreed to come say a quick hello to all of you first.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you, Olivia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. RODRIGO:&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; First, I want to say I am beyond honored and humbled to be here today to help spread the message about the importance of youth vaccination.&nbsp; I&#8217;m in awe of the work President Biden and Dr. Fauci have done, and was happy to help lend my support to this important initiative.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s important to have conversations with friends and family members, encouraging all communities to get vaccinated, and actually get to a vaccination site, which you can do more easily than ever before, given how many sites we have and how easy it is to find them at Vaccines.gov.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, Jen, for having me today.&nbsp; And thank you all for helping share this important message.&nbsp; It&#8217;s so appreciated it.&nbsp;&nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you, Olivia, so much for joining us.&nbsp; Good luck with your great day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; A couple of other items &#8212; a little less exciting, also very important &#8212; for all of you.&nbsp; This afternoon, the President will be joined by a bipartisan group of governors and mayors from around the country, representing communities from Vermont to Arizona, to discuss the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and his Build Back Better agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The framework has received support from across the political spectrum, including, yesterday, from a bipartisan group of 369 mayors from all 50 states and a letter organized by the U.S. Conference of Mayors, the bipartisan leadership of the National Governors Association, and a coalition of 20 leading business and labor groups &#8212; labor groups.</p>



<p>During the meeting, the President will underscore the broad, bipartisan sup- &#8212; public support for generational investments in our economy and middle class that will create millions of jobs and help us outcompete the rest of the world in the 21st century.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;ll also note some of the areas where Democrats and Republicans were able to come together in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, including money to remove lead pipes, expand universal access to high-speed Internet, boost transit options, and rebuild roads and bridges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;ll also thank the leaders for their work on a range of important issues across the country and reiterate his commitment to being a partner to them moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today &#8212; this is a separate announcement &#8212; we&#8217;ll begin shipping 1.5 million doses of Moderna to Sri Lanka &#8212; our first doses to this country.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll be shipping more doses throughout the week.&nbsp; And as always, I will share updates with you as those are available.</p>



<p>We announced this in our week ahead, but just to give you guys a little bit more context on the APEC meeting that the President will be participating in remotely on Friday: He will be participating in the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation &#8212; or APEC &#8212; Leaders’ Virtual Retreat, where leaders will discuss ending the COVID-19 pandemic, supporting the global economic recovery, hosted by the Prime Minister &#8212; Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>His participation demonstrates U.S. leadership in the Indo -Pacific region and his commitment &#8212; the United States’ commitment to multilateral institutions.&nbsp; As the President&#8217;s first engagement with many of the APEC leaders, particularly those in Southeast Asia, he will also emphasize the importance he places on the region, as well as his vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll provide an update to leaders on what the United States is doing to serve as an arsenal of vaccines for the region and to support all those suffering from COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, he&#8217;ll also advance an economic agenda that promotes our shared prosperity, leverages the economic potential in the region, and builds inclusive and resilient economies.</p>



<p>Last piece for all of you: Today, the Department of Health and Human Services announced that more than 2 million people have signed up for health coverage during the Biden-Harris administration&#8217;s special enrollment period, which opened on February 15th.&nbsp; Americans have until August 15th to go to Healthcare.gov, sign up for coverage, and take advantage of the lower premiums made possible by the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>Today&#8217;s announcement demonstrates the need to expand access to affordable healthcare, which is why the President is proposing to extend the Rescue Plan’s premium subsidies and lower the cost of healthcare for Americans across the country.</p>



<p>With that, Zeke.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the topic of youth vaccinations: Tennessee&#8217;s former top vaccination official says the state has stopped all outreach to minors on vaccinations &#8212; not just COVID-19 vaccinations &#8212; because of the political pressure.&nbsp; Does the White House, the President have a response to that?&nbsp; And is there something the White House can do to fill the gap there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First of all, thank you for the question, Zeke. We, of course, have seen the reporting and coverage of this iss- &#8212; this issue.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to comment specifically on a personnel step.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me take it &#8212; this opportunity to say that the Delta variant poses a threat to Americans of all ages.&nbsp; We continue to see young people hit by the virus as we vaccinated so many of the &#8212; our elderly and most vulnerable.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been crystal clear that we stand against any effort that would politicize our country&#8217;s pandemic response and recovery from COVID-19.</p>



<p>So even as we&#8217;ve seen, unfortunately, personnel decisions made in other parts of the country as well over the past several months along these lines, we&#8217;re going to continue to work with partners in states like Tennessee and in states across the country to ensure that we are pushing back against misinformation; that we are conveying accurately that the vast majority &#8212; 99.5 percent of people &#8212; who are going to hospitals are not vaccinated; and ensuring we&#8217;re using every tool at our disposal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ll also note for you that, this week, the th- &#8212; our Surgeon General &#8212; tomorrow, actually &#8212; he&#8217;s going to come to the briefing room tomorrow to talk about &#8212; he will discuss health and misinformation in the United States, as well as our efforts to work with communities and get out information about COVID-19 vaccines.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On a different subject: We&#8217;ve seen the Taliban continue make gains in Afghanistan.&nbsp; And we saw the administration announced earlier about SIV visas.&nbsp; How large is the pop- &#8212; the universe of people who would qualify for these visas?&nbsp; And does the White House believe that there&#8217;s enough in &#8212; within the statutory cap right now in that program for all those who helped the United States in Afghanistan to come to the U.S?&nbsp; Does Congress need to do more to lift that cap?&nbsp; What is the timetable for, sort of, getting everyone in Afghanistan who wants to leave and come to the U.S. out of Afghanistan?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, you had a couple of questions in there, so let me try to address all of them.&nbsp; First, we&#8217;re working closely with Congress to change the authorization legislation so that we can streamline the process of approving these visas.&nbsp; Obviously, we have a number of authorities.&nbsp; We want to make sure we&#8217;re working to expedite and work as efficiently as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we announced today also is that we are launching what we are calling “Operation Allies Refuge” to support relocation flights for interested and eligible Afghan nationals and their families who have supported the United States and our partners in Afghanistan, and are in the SIV application pipeline.</p>



<p>In terms of the specific numbers, I&#8217;m not going to be able to provide those to you for operational and security reasons, but I can confirm that flights out of Afghanistan for SIV applicants who are already in the pipeline will begin in the last week of July and will continue.&nbsp; And our objective is to get individuals who are eligible relocated out of the country in advance of the removal &#8212; of the withdrawal of troops at the end of August.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on a different topic: An American journalist, Danny Fenster, has been in prison in Myanmar for months now.&nbsp; His family has raised considerable alarm about his health situation &#8212; that he&#8217;s showing signs of a potential COVID-19 exposure and is not getting treatment there.&nbsp; Has the President been briefed on his condition?&nbsp; And what has the White House engagement been to try to get him free and returned to United States?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, we take the detainment of individuals &#8212; Americans and journalists &#8212; around the world very seriously, and we work through a range of channels to raise concerns.&nbsp; Obviously, the situation on the ground in Myanmar is quite concerning and quite challenging.&nbsp; But we do work with international partners to raise issues, including these, through every channel that we have at our disposal.</p>



<p>I would say the &#8212; the most appropriate channel to raise specific issues and to move forward on action is through the State Department, given their diplomatic role in the world.&nbsp; But in terms of the President&#8217;s awareness, he certainly is kept abreast of the detainment of individuals around the world.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update on his awareness of this particular case.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The compromise &#8212; the $3.5 trillion reconciliation bill.&nbsp; Is the President satisfied with the level of funding?&nbsp; Is he happy with it?&nbsp; Is he &#8212; does it fund his priorities?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, Steve, I would say first that, last night, when the agreement was announced by the Budget Committee &#8212; which, again, we acknowledge is just a step in the process.&nbsp; Now it needs to move forward and obviously needs support of all Democrats in order to move it forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s one of the reasons that the President is up on Capitol Hill as we speak &#8212; or headed up to Capitol Hill if he hasn&#8217;t departed yet, I should say &#8212; as we speak.&nbsp; Because we recognize that that&#8217;s the next natural step in the process in moving his agenda forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as Senator Sanders said last night, “This is the most significant piece of legislation passed since the Great Depression.&nbsp; I&#8217;m delighted to be a part of helping to put it together.”&nbsp; We agree with that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we&#8217;ve seen come out as the current framework is reflective of the President&#8217;s priorities, both what was in his budget, what was in his American Families Plan, and also what was what &#8212; what were the components that were left out of &#8212; out of the bipartisan agreement that was in the American Jobs Plan.</p>



<p>We certainly recognize there are additional steps to come, as we said.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he&#8217;s up on the Hill.&nbsp; And we feel this is working exactly as it should: The President of the United States proposes a bold agenda, as he did back in March; Congress works out a path forward, works out an agreement on where things look.&nbsp; That’s what’s happening now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now he’s going to engage, he’s going to advocate with members, he’s going to advocate with the American people and communicate and sell the package about why it needs to move forward.&nbsp; So that’s exactly what’s happening.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, on Cuba: What is the status of the review of the Trump-era policy?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, I would say, Steve, that &#8212; and you and others who’ve covered this certainly know that, one, first, I will confirm, of course, we’re still reviewing our Cuba policy with an eye toward its impact on the political and economic wellbeing of the Cuban people.&nbsp; The nature of the kinds of changes that were made by the previous administration, like redesignated &#8212; redesignating Cuba as a state sponsor of terror, carries significant statutory restrictions.&nbsp; We’ve been running a thorough policy process on these and other issues with support for democracy and human rights always at the core of our work.</p>



<p>Now there’s no question that the protests over the weekend and the events of the last several days are significant event &#8212; significant events.&nbsp; And it was the largest protest we’ve seen in Cuba in a long time.&nbsp; That will obviously have an impact on how we proceed.&nbsp; So, we will see how things develop in the days ahead and develop our policy responses accordingly.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t want to do it as one-offs.&nbsp; We want to look at it, as we have been, with a comprehensive approach in mind.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Are there must-haves &#8212; what are the must-haves for the President in this reconciliation package as it moves forward?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I’m not going to negotiate further from here &#8212; or at all from here.&nbsp; Obviously, as I note &#8212; as I just noted, Senator Sanders, the Chairman of the Budget Committee, noted the historic nature of this package that has been agreed to by the Budget Committee.&nbsp; We agree with that.</p>



<p>This package currently represents and is aligned with the President&#8217;s priorities, including what was &#8212; been outlined in his budget &#8212; which is quite public, out in a blueprint &#8212; as well as the American Families Plan, which is &#8212; includes key components of investing in our workforce, in childcare, and in the next generation.</p>



<p>We also understand that this is a process.&nbsp; There are steps to go.&nbsp; He is going to continue to advocate.&nbsp; He is going to continue to talk with, engage with members just as he is today.&nbsp; And we know that there can be changes as things move forward.&nbsp; But it is certainly aligned with the priorities he’s outlined publicly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So Senator Padea saying that it&#8217;s his &#8220;understanding&#8221; &#8212; I want to get this right &#8212; &#8220;and expectation&#8221; that a pathway to citizenship would be included in this package.&nbsp; He says it could be just a matter of months if all the necessary steps are taken.&nbsp; Is that a correct assessment from this White House&#8217;s point of view?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we have said in the past that we would &#8212; we certainly want to see an immigration bill passed through Congress.&nbsp; There are a range of mechanisms to do that.&nbsp; We will let Congress determine how they should &#8212; how they want to move that forward.&nbsp; And certainly there are a number of advocates &#8212; advocates, in terms of people who are elected officials who support that as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of additional contents of what would be in the package, I would refer you to the Senate.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is this one of those mechanisms that the White House would support?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Does the White House have a reaction to the charges that were filed against Iranian nationals, including the Iranian intelligence officials for a plot to kidnap an activist on U.S. soil?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; First off, this is a law enforcement matter, of course.&nbsp; Hence, the announcement came out of there.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re not going to weigh in on the specific allegations in the indictment.</p>



<p>Overall, though, we categorically condemn Iran’s dangerous and despicable reported plot to kidnap a U.S. citizen on U.S. soil.&nbsp; We will forcefully defend U.S. citizens and U.S. interests.&nbsp; That includes law enforcement actions like the one announced yesterday, as well as the actions the President has taken to defend U.S. forces in the region from Iranian-backed militant groups.&nbsp; It also includes our diplomatic effort to constrain Iran&#8217;s nuclear program &#8212; one of our most important and urgent actions.</p>



<p>But it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s actions to attempt to silence the voices of those peacefully working to address the situation, both inside of Iran and outside of Iran, that are appalling.&nbsp; We’ll continue to speak out against that, and obviously law enforcement authorities will take appropriate steps.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what kind of impact, if any, will this have on Iranian nuclear talks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it still remains we are &#8212; we have never assessed Iran to be a good actor in the world, not just by this &#8212; this plot to kidnap a U.S. &#8212; a person who is residing in the U.S., but their activities in the region, which we have had great concern about and the President has taken retaliatory actions for.</p>



<p>But at the same time, we still see it in U.S. interests and in our national interests, to engage in ongoing discussions so that we have &#8212; can have greater visibility into Iran’s path to acquiring a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we will continue to pursue those talks, pursue the diplomatic path forward, which we think is in our interests and continues to be constructive.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on another topic: The President gave a very impassioned speech yesterday about voting rights, calling on Congress to pass sweeping voting rights legislation, but the political reality there remains the same, which is that the Senate is unlikely to pass anything unless the filibuster rules are changed.&nbsp; Is he giving Congress a certain amount of time, a window to act before he changes his position on the filibuster?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think what you saw &#8212; heard the President deliver yesterday &#8212; and what many people on the outside heard &#8212; was an impassioned case for why voting is a fundamental right in this country, and why we should use every lever at our disposal to advocate for it and ensure people have access.</p>



<p>One of those is certainly legislation &#8212; something he will continue to push for and advocate for.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s asked his Vice President, and she has agreed, to serve as the point person on moving that forward.</p>



<p>We do hard things.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t accept that there isn&#8217;t a path forward.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to engage with leaders in Congress about not just the For the People Act, but also the John Lewis Voting Rights Act, something &#8212; voting rights has been supported in a bipartisan manner quite a bit in the past.</p>



<p>In terms of the filibuster, it is a legislative procedural process.&nbsp; That is up to the Senate to determine the path forward on.&nbsp; And I will leave it all to you to determine what the vote count and the whip count is there.&nbsp; But there is not the majority to support that.&nbsp; And we &#8212; I know we&#8217;ve focused on one or two, but it&#8217;s certainly more than that, of individuals who oppose changes to the filibuster because of the history.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; About voting rights and these Texas lawmakers who have come to Washington.&nbsp; Do you know any &#8212; of any examples from his 36 years in the Senate that Joe Biden just hopped on a train and left town to avoid a vote that he knew he was going to lose?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Welcome back.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Look, I think that the President’s view is that these Texas legislators were making a statement through action in opposition to efforts in their state to oppose restrictions on people&#8217;s fundamental rights and their rights to vote in their state.&nbsp; That is why they departed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Pre- &#8212; the Vice President met with these legislators yesterday, and the Vice President &#8212; and the President, I should say, certainly applauds their actions and their outspoken opposition to states &#8212; to efforts to put in place restrictive measures in their state.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And maybe it is funny to think about it that way, but the President is talking about this as the most serious assault on democracy’s since the Civil War.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think anything about &#8212; I don&#8217;t think anything about this is funny.&nbsp; I think what is important to note, though, here is that there are 28 states, including Texas, where there are laws in place or in process to make it harder to vote.&nbsp; And it requires bold action, it requires bold voices to speak out against that and make sure people understand their rights.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what&#8217;s happening here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So does the candidate &#8212; who&#8217;s now President &#8212; who told people he was going &#8212; he knew how to make deals with Republicans &#8212; he&#8217;s meeting with Republicans today &#8212; does he think that the best way to prevent something bad from happening &#8212; that he thinks is bad &#8212; from happening in Texas is for these lawmakers to be hiding out in a different state or for them to go back and sit down at the table?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President fundamentally believes you should work together in areas where you can find agreement, as he is on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework that is going to help rebuild roads and rails and bridges around our country, and also that you should be outspoken where you have concerns about affronts to democracy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what he did yesterday, and that&#8217;s what these legislators are doing now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just quickly on Cuba: DHS Secretary Mayorkas is warning people there, “If you take to the sea, you will not come to the United States” &#8212; why is that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think it&#8217;s important to understand the context of what the Secretary was conveying yesterday, which is just that it is still the case that it is not &#8212; the way to come to the United States is not through &#8212; through processes of trying to come to the border without going through an asylum process or coming by sea without going through an asylum application process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are certainly programs that &#8212; through which that some of them have been &#8212; have not been reinstated, I should say, that were in place &#8212; put in place by the Trump administration that are being reviewed, as he said yesterday.&nbsp; That would apply to the individuals and people of Haiti and the people of Cuba as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those have not been reinstated.&nbsp; They&#8217;re being reviewed.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the Secretary said yesterday.&nbsp; What he was reiterating is that this is not the time to travel irregularly.&nbsp; It&#8217;s dangerous.&nbsp; People can lose their lives, as they have in the past.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as the administration tries to figure out the root causes of migration to the country, don&#8217;t we know that the reason people want to leave Cuba is because they don&#8217;t like communism?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, as you&#8217;re trying to figure out, like, what the processes are for these people who want to leave Cuba, is &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I’m not sure what your question is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You guys have spent a lot of time &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Why are people leaving Cuba?&nbsp; Or what is the process for them getting here?&nbsp; I can explain either of them, but you tell me.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Do you think that people are leaving Cuba because they don&#8217;t like communism?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;ve been pretty clear that we think people are leaving Cuba &#8212; or not &#8212; leaving Cuba or protesting in the streets, as well, because they are opposed to the oppression, to the mismanagement of the government in the country.&nbsp; And we certainly support their right to protest.&nbsp; We support their efforts to speak out against their treatment in Cuba.</p>



<p>I will say, separately, an important question is also: What happens when people are seeking protection or what happens when they are attempting to flee?&nbsp; In the past, as I noted, we&#8217;ve had several humanitarian programs, such as Family Reunification Parole Programs for both Haiti and Cuba.&nbsp; Those were policies or pol- &#8212; processes that were in place prior to the Trump administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Though have not &#8212; those have not been turned back on, as Secretary Mayorkas said yesterday.&nbsp; He also said we&#8217;re assessing the status of those parole programs.&nbsp; Haitian and Cuban nationals in the United States with a fear of return for &#8212; for &#8212; to their home countries may be eligible for protection, such as asylum, under U.S. law.&nbsp; Haitian nationals already in the United States may be eligible for Temporary Protected Status.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But migrants interdicted in the Caribbean, who manifested in fear, are referred to USCIS for protection screening.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what happens.&nbsp; Those who do not manifest in fear or who are not found to have a credible fear following the screening are repatriated to their country of origin.&nbsp; Those found to have a well-founded fear of persecution or torture are not brought to the United States; they are referred to a third country for resettlement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m sharing all of that with you so people understand what the process is when they&#8217;re trying to make what a treacherous journey is and a challenging journey where people can lose their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But certainly, we have said many times &#8212; and I will reiterate here &#8212; that we support not &#8212; not just the &#8212; the role of peace &#8212; of protest and peaceful protest.&nbsp; We stand with the Cuban people in their call for pre- &#8212; freedom from both the pandemic and from decades of oppression and economic suffering to which they have been subjected by Cuba&#8217;s authoritarian regime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was hoping you could tell us more about Olivia Rodrigo&#8217;s visit here today.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; What was the intended target of the message?&nbsp; When will we see the video that we believe she made?&nbsp; And &#8212; just more about the strategy of having her here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, she&#8217;s meeting with the President and Dr. Fauci later this afternoon.&nbsp; And I &#8212; in terms of when a video product will go out, I&#8217;ll have to check on that and see what the editing process looks like.&nbsp; You all may have a better sense of that than I may.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But she&#8217;s here because we recognize and understand &#8212; she offered to come, of course, so that is an important component of it &#8212; that we need to use &#8212; we need to reach people, meet people where they are.&nbsp; And speaking to young people &#8212; people who are under the age of 18 &#8212; many of whom, as we&#8217;ve seen across the country, are huge Olivia Rodrigo fans; hearing from her that &#8212; that getting vaccinated is a way to keep yourself safe, a way to ensure you can see your friends, a way you can ensure you can go to concerts, a way you can ensure that you can live a healthy life &#8212; and is &#8212; is an important part of what we&#8217;re trying to do here.&nbsp; So, she&#8217;s playing an important role in that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of when the video is, I&#8217;m not sure.&nbsp; But I will say, not every 18-year-old uses their time to come do this, so we appreciate her willingness to.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In other news of popular interest, there&#8217;s a rally today at the Lincoln Memorial.&nbsp; And I &#8212; this follows on a question I asked you a couple weeks ago about the White House&#8217;s position on conservatorships.&nbsp; Have &#8212; has there been a decision on that here as to whether the President feels there&#8217;s a federal role in governing these relationships?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new on that for you.&nbsp; Understand the interest and the question.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to return to Cuba, will we hear from the President this week?&nbsp; He said the other day that he would speak out on that.&nbsp; And secondly, is it &#8212; is his position still that he feels that the Trump policies were a failure, didn’t effect change?&nbsp; Is that still his policy?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I would say: One, in terms of whether you’ll hear from him, he says that often, as you know. And what he means is he speaks out publicly nearly every day at events; sometimes you all ask questions.&nbsp; If there&#8217;s an update to provide on what we&#8217;re doing, on what our policies are, certainly he’ll provide that.&nbsp; Is there a planned speech or trip?&nbsp; Not at this time.</p>



<p>In terms of our policies: Again, I would say, Alex, that we are continuing to review our policies.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been an ongoing process to review the policies that were put in place by the prior administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also recognize that this was a significant event over the last couple of days, the largest protest in a long time that we saw in Cuba &#8212; people speaking out &#8212; Cuban people speaking out, calling for freedom from both the pandemic and from decades of repression.&nbsp; That&#8217;s significant.&nbsp; And, of course, that will play a role as we consider and factor in what our policies will be moving forward.</p>



<p>I would also note, though, that we will do that through the prism of what will help the people of Cuba, not what will help pad the pockets of the regime.&nbsp; And that is challenging circumstance, given the control of the of the regime currently on the people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does President Biden endorse Senator Schumer&#8217;s bill on marijuana?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spoken in the past about the President&#8217;s views on marijuana.&nbsp; Nothing has changed.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no new endorsements of legislation to report today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just for clarity, housekeeping: Did you &#8212; maybe I missed it &#8212; will the President meet with the Texas Democratic legislators?&nbsp; And if so, when?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President asked the Vice President to meet with the legislatures &#8212; legislators yesterday.&nbsp; She was happy to do that.&nbsp; She did that.&nbsp; He supports, of course, their voicing of their strong views.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He still plans to meet with them?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any int- &#8212; any plans to preview for you at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has he spoken to them in any form &#8212; by phone?&nbsp; Did he call into that at some point when the media left?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He did not.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let me ask you, if I can, about a couple other questions &#8212; one as it relates to the dark websites that are linked to REvil.&nbsp; We saw that the ransomware gang REvil &#8212; those websites were no longer operating as of yesterday.&nbsp; Is the U.S. behind the targeted attacks on REvil or the computer servers that have hosted those ransomware attacks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more for you on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do &#8212; is there any indication that they &#8212; REvil &#8212; has adapted to preempt a possible attack?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We just don&#8217;t have anything more for you on REvil’s absence currently from the environment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me see if there&#8217;s something else you can answer then, perhaps.&nbsp; On Afghanistan: We know that Operation Allies Refuge and the announcement that this is going to begin for those who are already in the pipeline, as they describe it, in the last week of July &#8212; they can&#8217;t talk, it said in the note that was provided by a senior White House official &#8212; they wouldn&#8217;t say anything more specifically about the timing of it, but where are these Afghan nationals and their families?&nbsp; Where will they be going?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, Peter, for operational and security purposes for the individuals that were relocating, we&#8217;re not going to be providing details of that at this time.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t foresee that necessarily changing.&nbsp; Once it is in a place where their security is &#8212; is affirmed, then we will, of course, provide information, as we have on the timing, as we have on the &#8212; what the operation looks like.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So on that basis then, as a security issue then, how many Afghan nationals and family members does the U.S. assess have been killed in the course of the last several months in Afghanistan, in the absence of their departure from that country so far?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any assessment of that, Peter.&nbsp; I would say that the reason that we are taking these steps is because these are courageous individuals.&nbsp; We want to make sure we recognize and value the role they&#8217;ve played over the last several years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are working on several fronts here &#8212; both working with Congress, using our authorities &#8212; relocating individuals who have played roles as translators and others supporting U.S. efforts in Afghanistan.&nbsp; So that should be seen as significant.</p>



<p>I would also note, because I didn&#8217;t note it earlier, that we have Ambassador Tracey Jacobson &#8212; a three-time Chief of Mission in Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, and Kosovo &#8212; is leading the State Department coordination unit that will deliver on the President&#8217;s commitment under Operation Allies Refuge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The unit also includes representatives from the Departments of Defense and Homeland Security.&nbsp; Russ Travers, who’s Department of Homeland Security Advisor &#8212; the Deputy Homeland Security Advisor and former head of the National Counterterrorism Center is coordinating the interagency policy process on the operation as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the Homeland Security Advisor is traveling in Uzbekistan &#8212; is that something you (inaudible)?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, I &#8212; I can.&nbsp; I cer- &#8212; she is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; She has or she is?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; She is &#8212; let&#8217;s see &#8212; she is en route or she is there.&nbsp; She is, I believe, there now.&nbsp; She&#8217;s leading a U.S. delegation to a high-level international conver- &#8212; conference.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be discussing the promotion of prosperity, security, regional connectivity.&nbsp; While she&#8217;s there, obviously, security in Afghanistan and the region and all of our initiatives and priorities will be a part of the discussion.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the $3.5 trillion package that was unveiled last night: How does the President view that topline number?&nbsp; There&#8217;s some in the party that balked at higher spending, of course.&nbsp; Or is it too low?&nbsp; How does the President kind of view that number right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, as I said a little bit earlier, the step forward, announced last night, is a significant step forward, I should say, in our view and the President&#8217;s view.&nbsp; And we recognize there&#8217;s still a path forward, steps forward that need to be taken.&nbsp; Because while it &#8212; while this was an important step in the &#8212; in the committee, we obviously need every member of the Democratic Caucus to support this endeavor moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I&#8217;d also note that, as Senator Sanders said last night, “This is the most significant piece of legislation passed since the Great Depression, and I&#8217;m delighted to be part of ha- &#8212; of help &#8212; having helped put it together.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, yesterday was a major breakthrough for middle-class families, in the President&#8217;s view.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on voting rights, civil rights leaders and activists have characterized the President&#8217;s reluctance to mention a filibuster as a lack of urgency on the issue.&nbsp; I mean, what do you say to those critics that say that&#8217;s a lack of urgency that he hasn&#8217;t yet pushed senators to support abandoning or modifying the filibuster to get this legislation passed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first that the President delivered a major speech yesterday on voting rights &#8212; which received a great deal of attention and many accolades from a lot of supporters/advocates out there in the country as well &#8212; because he wants to stand with them and is committed to standing with proponents of access to voting rights across the country in this fight and this effort moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He also talked in his speech, as you know, about not just his commitment to the For the People Act, but also about what levers from the federal government he will continue to use &#8212; whether it was the executive order he signed into law just a few months ago or steps the Department of Justice are also taking.&nbsp; But this is going to be a cause of his presidency.&nbsp; The fact that he delivered a speech yesterday elevating the issue, educating people on the issue, making sure people understood their rights should be seen as representative of his commitment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a follow-up on that please, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Well, hold on.&nbsp; I’ll come &#8212; oh, go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you’ve gotten close to this, but I want to make sure I&#8217;m clear.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President going to this lunch &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; should we take that as an indication that you don&#8217;t think you have all 50 Democrats signed on to this framework?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, as you all know, if there were enough votes for each of these priorities, there would be a vote and it would have happened.&nbsp; So, I will say that he&#8217;s headed up to the Hill because it&#8217;s the next natural step.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, as I said earlier, he knows that, as President, you lay out a bold agenda, or certainly that&#8217;s your objective; members of Congress negotiate the details; and then it&#8217;s his role to continue to engage in selling both packages to members and the Senate and to the public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think you can expect you&#8217;re going to see him doing that until both pieces of legislation are passed.&nbsp; So, going back home to the Senate &#8212; where he spent 36 years &#8212; and speaking with, engaging with Democrats in the Senate, answering their questions is certainly a part of that effort of selling the package.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a sequencing question related to that, which is: The &#8212; Speaker Pelosi had said that the &#8212; that part two needs to pass in order for the part one bipartisan infrastructure thing to be taken up in the House.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if it is the White House&#8217;s view that this framework &#8212; if this budget resolution were to pass the Senate, is that then enough for the House to take up the bipartisan infrastructure package? Or is that not enough?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President expects to sign both pieces of legislation into law.&nbsp; They&#8217;re on a dual track, as he long said they would be on, and we&#8217;re going to leave it to leaders in the Senate and House to determine the sequencing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, one more crack on the filibuster thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the Vice President yesterday, when she was asked about changing it to have a carveout for voting rights, said, “I&#8217;m certainly having conversations with folks.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Is the President also having conversations?&nbsp; Or is he sort of yielding completely on the idea of changing the filibuster, given that yesterday he compared the current state of democracy as in peril, comparing it to the Civil War?&nbsp; So w- &#8212; is he talking to people about this legislative tool that could be changed?&nbsp; Is he having conversations?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, of course, the President and Vice President have conversations about a range of issues, including members who raise concerns &#8212; or their advocacy for changing filibuster rules.&nbsp; Some also advocate against, as you well know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what the Vice President was acknowledging was that some members have raised filibuster reform with her &#8212; as won&#8217;t surprise any of you &#8212; and members have also raised it with the President.&nbsp; But they&#8217;ve raised it on different sides as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;And ultimately, it&#8217;s a legislative process, one that the President is &#8212; no longer gets a vote on.&nbsp; It&#8217;s up to them to vote on what their processes will be moving forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But as he is having conversations, is he advocating any particular way?&nbsp; Is he expressing an opinion to &#8212; in those conversations?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, they both heard from members who have points of view on the future of the filibuster, as won&#8217;t surprise any of you.&nbsp; That is what the Vice President was referring to.&nbsp; And the President also has, of course, been a part of those conversations.&nbsp; But his position, I&#8217;ve stated to all of you publicly, is what his position is privately as well.</p>



<p>Did you have a question, Kaitlan, or no?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, I do.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m not just here for fun.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m just kidding.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, I know.&nbsp; But I didn’t &#8212; I didn’t know.&nbsp; You didn’t raise your hand.&nbsp; I didn’t want to skip you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; He met with Senator Sanders earlier this week, who wanted this $3.5 trillion number, initially, to be a lot higher than it is.&nbsp; There are other moderate members who wanted it to be a lot lower than it is.&nbsp; So, does he plan to meet with people like Senator Manchin on this, one-on-one, as well?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I expect the President will continue to be deeply engaged with a range of members &#8212; Senator Sanders, Senator Manchin, others in the Senate &#8212; as they work to move this legislation forward.&nbsp; And it is certainly a significant step, a big breakthrough last night in the agreement that was announced.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President will be the first to tell you, though, that he knows there are a number of steps ahead, and there will be continuing discussions, negotiations.&nbsp; There are components of this that could certainly change, but it was a big breakthrough &#8212; a big breakthrough for middle-class families.&nbsp; And certainly, he would ech- &#8212; echo the comments made by Senator Sanders.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on vaccine misinformation, Ron Klain, the Chief of Staff, said recently that it would be a policy decision whether or not the administration went after regulating companies, like Facebook, on things like vaccine misinformation.&nbsp; So what is the administration&#8217;s stance on that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; we believe that all of us &#8212; social media companies, platforms where a lot of this misinformation travels &#8212; the media, state and local officials &#8212; it&#8217;s important for everybody to step up and spread the word about the vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a report that will be coming out that, again, our Surgeon General Vivek Murthy will be coming to the briefing room tomorrow to talk about.&nbsp; And certainly, the pushback against disinformation &#8212; information that is, you know, literally a matter of life and death &#8212; is something that is going to be a continued focus of this administration.</p>



<p>You are right that, obviously, decisions to regulate or hold to account any platform would certainly be a policy decision.&nbsp; But in the interim, we&#8217;re going to continue to call out disinformation and call out where that information travels.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President have plans to speak with Mark Zuckerberg at all about this?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s no plans that I&#8217;m aware of.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; A group of senators is urging the President to postpone a pause in federal student loan payments until next March.&nbsp; I’m just wondering: What is the President&#8217;s current thinking about the timeline for reinstating those payments?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s a certain timeline, I think, that&#8217;s required because I think they expire in the fall, if I&#8217;m correct.&nbsp; So, obviously, it would be in advance of that period of time, but I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of where he will land.&nbsp; I want to give him the space to make a decision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I have another question on climate: The EU, today, said it will impose a carbon border tax, which could affect U.S. imports, which could complicate the President&#8217;s plan to present, sort of, a unified front later this fall in Glasgow.&nbsp; Is the administration concerned about how the carbon border tax will affect exports to Europe?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This is a very question that I suspect that someone would ask me about today.&nbsp; And I actually did not talk to our team about it, so let me get something &#8212; I’m sure it’s of interest to others &#8212; and I&#8217;ll get back to you after the briefing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, thanks.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So, as we speak, outside, right now, there&#8217;s solidarity protests with the Cuban people right outside the fences of the White House.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been seeing this all across the country, here.&nbsp; And Democratic lawmakers in South Florida have actually called on Biden to come down to Miami to give a speech.&nbsp; You all are reviewing your policies, but is there a way that you believe &#8212; either to answer these calls &#8212; that you can more forcefully show support for the Cuban people in that way?&nbsp; Or is there anything in the works?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Through a speech?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; It &#8212; it’s been asked.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, certainly I understand that, but I would say that I think what is most important to the Cuban people is understanding that the United States stands with them and their call for freedom from both the pandemic and from the decades of repression and economic suffering to which they have been subjected &#8212; subjected by Cuba&#8217;s authoritarian regime.</p>



<p>And also, I would just note that, again, it is a policy process that has been under review.&nbsp; There were a number of policies that were put in place by the prior administration.&nbsp; We want to do that in a comprehensive and not a one-off manner.&nbsp; We want to do it through the prism of what is going to help the Cuban people directly and help incentivize a change in behavior, if that is possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly, the events, the protests, the reaction, the continued oppression of the Cuban people weighs in on our decision-making process.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any speech or visit to preview for you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then &#8212; so then, on policy changes: On the campaign trail, Biden promised that he would reinstate the Cuban Family Reunification Parole Program.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; can you give us a readout, maybe, on where that process has gone so far in these comprehensive reviews or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is, again, an ongoing review.&nbsp; Of course, the events and the protests and the reaction and the continued oppression of the Cuban people will weigh in on our &#8212; will be a factor in the &#8212; our decision-making process.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Can you give us a preview of the President&#8217;s Child Tax Credit event tomorrow?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the message going to be?&nbsp; Is he bringing real people to the White House to highlight this?&nbsp; Just, what’s it going to look like?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, that is our intention.&nbsp; “Real people,” as we call them here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I will say &#8212; I will say that there are tens of millions of families across the country who will benefit from the Child Tax Credit that has been extended thanks to the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; Also, it&#8217;s something that he has advocated for and will continue to push for.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s broad support for, in Congress, extending further than that.</p>



<p>But tomorrow, we&#8217;re marking the fact that these checks &#8212; or these direct deposit payments &#8212; because we&#8217;re in 2021 &#8212; will start going out directly to people&#8217;s bank accounts.&nbsp; We have seen projections that the Child Tax Credit, the implementation &#8212; or the extension of Child Tax Credit could reduce &#8212; could cut child poverty in half.&nbsp; And this is just extra money that&#8217;s going into people&#8217;s bank accounts who need help the most.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the President felt it was important to elevate this issue to make sure people understand this is a benefit that will help them as we still work to recover from the pandemic and the economic downturn.</p>



<p>Go ahead, April.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, yesterday, in Philadelphia, after the speech, Reverend Al Sharpton said it was a momentous speech.&nbsp; He said the President talked on race, but what was missing was the word “filibuster” in what he was going to do.&nbsp; Also, after the speech, we talked to NAACP President Derrick Johnson who said that he was concerned that there was no path forward and there was no sense of urgency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m going back to that other question, but giving you a little bit more specifics as to what people said.&nbsp; Can you address that about the path forward, the filibuster, and the sense of urgency?&nbsp; The President talked about equating this moment to the Civil War, but where was the urgency in moving it forward &#8212; the path forward &#8212; and also the issue of the filibuster that&#8217;s holding this whole thing up?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, April, I&#8217;d also say that the president of the Southern Poverty Law Center said that “President Biden accurately characterized the anti-democracy actions by state legislators and others following January 6th.”&nbsp; And President Biden&#8217;s speech today, ultimately, “was a needed call to action for [this] multiracial coalition of democracy defenders” in this country to rise to the urgency of the moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The president of UnidosUS said, “I commend the President for asserting the importance of voting rights, especially as we&#8217;re seeing numerous states enact voting rules that are restrictive and discriminatory for Black and brown communities.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President pr- &#8212; delivered this speech yesterday because he knows that there is still not enough information out there, not enough empowerment, not enough engagement with people across the country about what their rights are, on what is happening in states across the country that is oppressing and silencing their right to have their voices heard.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he delivered the speech.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; part of our focus is continuing to press for the For the People Act &#8212; he will continue to do that &#8212; and the John Lewis Voting Rights Act.&nbsp; And he will stand with civil rights leaders, who were just here at the White House last week, to have a conversation about how they can work together to move this forward.&nbsp; He&#8217;s also not going to wait on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He &#8212; obviously, the Department of Justice has already took &#8212; take action in Georgia.&nbsp; They will make decisions about taking action to fight against these oppressive laws around the country.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to implement the executive order.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to fund efforts around the country to educate and inform citizens.&nbsp; So, he delivered the speech to make sure people knew what their rights are and to make sure people knew what he was doing to fight against efforts to oppress.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what about the pathway forward, though, from this administration?&nbsp; What do you &#8212; I mean, you&#8217;re telling the coalition groups to go out and act.&nbsp; The President said that yesterday.&nbsp; But what is the path forward?&nbsp; What is the formula that this administration has to making sure that H.R.1 is passed and then H.R.4 comes behind it &#8212; H.R.1 and S.1 are passed, and then H.R.4 moves forward?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don’t have details on a legislative strategy to outline for you here.&nbsp; We are going to continue to work with leaders in the Senate, leaders in the House, who, as you know, are huge advocates for moving these pieces of legislation forward.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to lift up and empower voices across the country to ensure that people understand &#8212; who have a vote &#8212; how important this is to citizens across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more question &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I got to keep going, April.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; I got to keep going because I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m going to run out of &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to run out of time.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A two-part question about why the President is up on the Hill right now.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The three and a half trillion-dollar price tag of the infrastructure proposals and the reconciliation bill with the human infrastructure elements to it may give pause to some Republicans who would otherwise support the so-called “traditional” infrastructure bipartisan bill.&nbsp; Is the President worried about that at this point?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the second part of my question is: It brings up the scenario that if the “traditional” bill is not going to be approved in the Senate, it can be pushed into the reconciliation bill, possibly.&nbsp; Is the President going to think about that and talk about that?&nbsp; I know I&#8217;m getting way ahead of the process, you&#8217;re going to tell me.&nbsp; But is there &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; is that a possibility?&nbsp; So, tell me, if you want.&nbsp; But was that a possibility?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly the President is going to continue to advocate for a dual track of these pieces of legislation moving forward.&nbsp; To &#8212; you are right.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of that process.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I will say that the President was in the Senate for 36 years.&nbsp; He&#8217;s the first to say that &#8212; and he knows well that voting for one measure you support never means you have to vote for a different measure.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not how legislation works.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly, he said from the beginning that &#8212; and he&#8217;s been clear for months, as had &#8212; as his Republican colleagues have acknowledged for months &#8212; that we are proceeding on two tracks to pass his economic agenda: one is the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework; the other is the Build Back Better reconciliation package where there was a significant breakthrough last night, led by the Budget Committee and Chairman Sanders.</p>



<p>So, a couple weeks ago, everyone said this was dead, it wasn&#8217;t going happen, no possibility.&nbsp; They&#8217;re both moving forward.&nbsp; The Senate Majority Leader says he wants to bring them both up for a vote, and we&#8217;re going to work closely with him to get that done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he want to talk to some Republicans?&nbsp; Does he want to run into some Republicans while he’s in the hallway there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He may, as you know how Capitol Hill works.&nbsp; It could be wild and crazy up there.&nbsp; But &#8212; but he is going to continue to engage, of course, with Republicans on moving his agenda forward.</p>



<p>Today is an opportunity to speak with Democrats about both pieces of his legislation &#8212; both pieces of legislation they support &#8212; many of them support &#8212; about moving them forward.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a quick question on COVID.&nbsp; A question on &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question on Cuba, and then a question on COVID after that.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given the lack of Internet access in Cuba, how is the administration monitoring the situation, the crackdown on protesters?&nbsp; And if the administration determines that there is violence against protesters, what options are at the President&#8217;s disposal?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say we continue to call for the swift release of pe- &#8212; those peaceful protesters who have been unjustly detained.&nbsp; Again, we stand with the Cuban people and their call for freedom from both the pandemic and from decades of repression.</p>



<p>The protests in Cuba, as you all know, have largely stopped because of the regime’s violent crackdown and retaliatory measures against Cubans exercising their fundamental and universal rights.&nbsp; This is unacceptable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, we will continue to call for a change in approach, and we will continue to review our own policies about what is possible and work with our partners around the world in a coordinated fashion as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on vaccinations, you’ve talked before about going county by county.&nbsp; What do &#8212; what does the administration think is driving some of the variation of vaccination rates between counties?&nbsp; Looking at Kansas and Missouri, for example: Missouri has more than 30 counties where there&#8217;s less than 25 percent of the population vaccinated; Kansas &#8212; right next door, culturally similar &#8212; only has 2 counties in that case.&nbsp; What accounts for variation between states, between counties?&nbsp; Is it local officials?&nbsp; Is it state officials?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t make a sweeping assessment of that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s different in county to county and in state to state.&nbsp; We also recognize, looking at the data, that there are portions of the population, demographics, including people under the age of 27, who have a much lower vaccination rate.&nbsp; Hence, we are quite focused on communicating directly with those people.&nbsp; Hence, our special guest today about why it&#8217;s important to get vaccinated, why these vaccines are safe, why they can still kill you even if you are under the age of 27.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need to be clear and direct about our messaging.&nbsp; There is misinformation out there.&nbsp; Sometimes that&#8217;s traveling on platforms.&nbsp; Sometimes that&#8217;s traveling, unfortunately, out of the mouth of elected officials.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s really case by case, but the most important thing we can do is not see this as a partisan issue because, certainly, the virus is killing people, whether they&#8217;re Democrats or Republicans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re vaccinated, you&#8217;re protected.&nbsp; 99.5 percent of people who are going to hospitals are not vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a pretty clear statistic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Olivia Rodrigo is here today.&nbsp; Why would you invite Olivia Rodrigo, who&#8217;s only 18 years old?&nbsp; She&#8217;s super popular, obviously.&nbsp; She has a line of fans outside of this White House gate right now.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure she does.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And they made &#8212; they told me to make sure I get in a question for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So my question for them and the rest of the young people in this country is: What is it that Olivia Rodrigo is tasked with while she&#8217;s here?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the goal of having her voice involved in this conversation?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m saying this in the context of youth numbers being very low right now.&nbsp; Reports are saying that those who are eligible, even though you lowered &#8212; we &#8212; the government lowered the rate of eligibility, those young people are not getting shots.&nbsp; So, I imagine that her being here today has something to do with that, but I would like you to go on record to explain her goal.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I think I answered a similar question earlier.&nbsp; But I would say that, certainly, a voice of someone like Olivia Rodrigo, who is a popular recording artist and someone who has legions of fans &#8212; some of them are outside the White House &#8212; and her willingness to play a role in making sure people understand &#8212; young people understand they are not immune from getting COVID, they are not immune from getting very sick from COVID; and that it&#8217;s important to know that the vaccine is safe, it&#8217;s effective, and it&#8217;s accessible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly, her willingness to use her voice and her platform to speak directly to young people is quite powerful, and we&#8217;re grateful for hi- &#8212; for her time and effort.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) crime prevention meeting on Monday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The administration is encouraging cities to use COVID funding to hire police.&nbsp; But cops are walking off the job, applications to training academies are down, recruitment and morale is a real problem.&nbsp; Is the administration going to take a lead with these cities to help improve recruitment and morale for local departments?&nbsp; And if so, what would that look like?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one, I would say that a number of cities have actually used funding from the American Rescue Plan to rehire police and to make sure that they have our funding &#8212; their COPS program &#8212; something the President has supported throughout his career.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also have just started a strike force to work from the Department of Justice with about a half a dozen cities around the country to crack down on illegal gun trafficking &#8212; another way that we are working with cities to ensure we are being an effective partner from the federal government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the President has proposed a great deal of &#8212; an increase in funding for law enforcement in his federal budget that can be used to keep cops on the beat to ensure that we are supporting local community.&nbsp; So those are all steps that he&#8217;s taking and he&#8217;s proposing in action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if people don&#8217;t want to be cops, what does &#8212; does this really matter &#8212; freeing up these funds?&nbsp; I mean, that&#8217;s &#8212; we want &#8212; everybody wants better cops, better policing, more diverse policing.&nbsp; Is just freeing up these funds going to be enough to do it?&nbsp; Or does the White House need to do more?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think the President has been clear that he supports and advocates for and supports funding and has proposed funding to ensure that local communities and local police departments have the support and the resources they need.&nbsp; At the same time, he&#8217;s also been an advocate and looks forward to signing a police reform bill into law.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to ask you a question about a gender equity issue that I hope you could weigh in on.&nbsp; You may be familiar with five-star safety ratings.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the measure for cars, trucks, vans &#8212; how well they perform in crash tests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it turns out, based upon an investigation that Gray Television has done, that testing is not done for women drivers.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just a male crash-test dummy that is put behind the wheel of an automobile, not a female crash-test dummy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since our investigation, bipartisan legislation has been introduced in both the House and the Senate to correct this gender inequity.&nbsp; I was hoping that you could weigh in on this issue, number one. And could you support that type of legislation?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I do know that NHTSA, who oversees this effort, does use female crash-test dummies in some of their safety testing and uses data to determine where to use which sized and gendered dummies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They also use computer simulation, in addition, to enhance their research and fund the Global Human Body Model Consortium, which has developed simulation models for a variety of occupants, including men and women, but also children, the elderly, and more.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s another way they rely on data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But otherwise, I would refer you to NHTSA, who would have more additional information.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any announcements about support for legislation at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would like to turn it back to immigration &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for just a moment.&nbsp; I know that President Biden has previously said that his administration is going to work to address illegal immigration in Central America by addressing root causes of it, including corruption.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering, with what we&#8217;re seeing right now in Cuba and Haiti &#8212; I think that was just that that can be a very long and tricky process that can lead to very dangerous situations.&nbsp; Do you think that that throws any sort of wrench into the administration’s, kind of, plan to address illegal immigration in Central America in that way?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think so.&nbsp; But tell me more about your question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, really, I&#8217;m just asking, you know, given what we&#8217;re seeing in Cuba and Haiti, it&#8217;s clear that trying to address these issues &#8212; while I think everyone would agree that&#8217;s important &#8212; leads to potentially, you know, a lot of unrest.&nbsp; Do &#8212; does that give anybody pause in the Biden administration for addressing illegal immigration in Central America in that way?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, Jen, one more question, if I may, on this &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Operation Allies Refuge.&nbsp; I know you won&#8217;t divulge the third countries &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that these people will go to.&nbsp; But can you confirm that Guam, which is U.S. territory, has been ruled out now as a waystation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to rule in or rule out any places.&nbsp; I certainly understand the interest.&nbsp; This is a big priority for the President.&nbsp; As we have information we can provide to all of you, we will provide it.&nbsp; We &#8212; obviously, the security and safety of the individuals who are relocating is of utmost focus and concern.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Yamiche.&nbsp; Go ahead, Yamiche.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; A question about Haiti and one on COVID.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Haiti, does the President support halting deportations to Haiti?&nbsp; The Haiti Caucus in the House has written a letter calling for him to halt deportations of Haitians.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not spoken with him or our team about that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m certainly happy to check for you, Yamiche.&nbsp; But did you have another Haiti question?&nbsp; Or you said you had another one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; The other Haiti question I have is: Is there a timeline for when the United States plans to respond to this request for troops and military assistance in Haiti?&nbsp; And then could you talk a little bit about what the United States is weighing if you can&#8217;t give a timeline?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that, you know, we have a very large diplomatic presence on the ground.&nbsp; Our ambassador &#8212; our ambassador, Sison, has been very involved and deeply engaged in efforts on the ground.&nbsp; We have more than 100 American citizens who are working on the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also responded to a number of their specific requests in terms of personnel and aid and assistance on the law enforcement front as they are working to move the investigation forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of additional considerations or considerations of requests for troops, that is still an ongoing review.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the COVID, I want to ask you something about &#8212; we saw, in Tennessee &#8212; the Tennessee Department of Health, it halted all adolescent vaccine outreach not just for coronavirus vaccines &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but all vaccines.&nbsp; I wonder what this administration makes of that move.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve talked about taking the politics out of vaccinations.&nbsp; How do you do that when you have a state like Tennessee now halting vaccine outreach in this way?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, Yamiche, that I still am not going to comment on a personnel decision or pol- &#8212; or &#8212; in that way, which I know was a significant part of the reporting here &#8212; an important one.&nbsp; Certainly, any effort to that prevents accurate information &#8212; information based on di- &#8212; data, on science as it relates to the COVID-19 vaccine or any other vaccine is of concern to the federal government.&nbsp; Because we have seen, as we&#8217;ve talked about a bit in this briefing, lower rates of vaccination, as it relates to COVID, specifically, among young people.&nbsp; That puts young people at risk, puts young people in danger for illness and even death in this case.</p>



<p>So, we will continue to work with local health authorities. We will continue to work with local trusted voices in order to get the message out and the word out, and get accurate information out.&nbsp; But any effort to repress or not share that information is risking people&#8217;s lives.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And (inaudible) you said that you&#8217;re going to get back on the deportations of Haitians.&nbsp; But is it under consideration at all?&nbsp; Is that something that the President is open to doing &#8212; to halt deportations?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to speak out of turn here.&nbsp; I will see if there&#8217;s anything to report out on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, in the very back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions on Afghan interpreters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you said you don&#8217;t want to give a specific number of people that will get evacuated, but there&#8217;s a lot of confusion on the ground, fear on the ground.&nbsp; Is it going to be all SIV applicants?&nbsp; Is it going to be just people who have cleared the first step?&nbsp; One interpreter there told me this week, “If I&#8217;m left behind, I will 100 percent been killed by the Taliban.”&nbsp; So what details can you give us for that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, as we&#8217;ve announced in the past, the focus is on applicants who are already in the pipeline.&nbsp; That is what will be &#8212; begin the last week of July.&nbsp; We, though, have a range of contingencies, and we are continuing to work to ensure that we can help as many of these bold and courageous individuals as we possibly can.&nbsp; But those are the individuals &#8212; the translators &#8212; who are in the pipeline already, who will be the first focus of relocation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more question.&nbsp; We’re hearing that the flights will happen only outside &#8212; out of Kabul, but there are a lot of interpreters that don&#8217;t live in Kabul.&nbsp; They may not be able to get there.&nbsp; Are you going to help them get there safely?&nbsp; They&#8217;re threatened by the Taliban, and they often don&#8217;t go outside.&nbsp; So advocates are wondering how they&#8217;re going to get to those flights.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a &#8212; it’s a great question.&nbsp; We, obviously, want to help advoc- &#8212; interpreters and applicants who may not be living directly near the airport.&nbsp; I will see if there&#8217;s more from the State Department, in terms of the operational component of this, that we&#8217;re able to share.&nbsp; But certainly, we keep that in mind.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Chris.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So going back &#8212; I know this was partially asked &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but going back to this question on decriminalizing marijuana at the federal level.&nbsp; So I just remembered, during the campaign &#8212; since then, the President has spoken about mass incarceration and reducing the levels.&nbsp; Is he encouraged that this is coming back to the Senate?&nbsp; I know you won’t speak specifically about endorsing the bill, but is he glad to see that this is resurfacing and that there will be a debate over it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; I have not spoken with him about this specific piece of legislation.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Okay, go ahead.&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp; Last one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about the &#8212; what about the issue of decriminalizing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, that remains his position.&nbsp; And certainly, he would be encouraged by steps to implement that, but I have not spoken with him in recent days about marijuana or legislation &#8212; go ahead &#8212; on this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Special Envoy Kerry is in Moscow right now.&nbsp; He met Foreign Minister Lavrov, I think, yesterday.&nbsp; He held talks with his Russian counterpart, and he held a phone conversation with &#8212; (clears throat) &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry &#8212; with President Putin.&nbsp; Is he delivering any additional messages?&nbsp; Is he talking about climate only or something on top of that as well?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the other point, very quickly: Deputy Foreign Minister Ryabkov has announced that strategic stability talks will take place before the end of the month.&nbsp; Any announcements from your side?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The former Secretary of State, my former boss, the Special Envoy &#8212; he&#8217;s got a lot of titles &#8212; his purview is on climate.&nbsp; That is what the focus of his conversations and discussions are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of strategic stability talks, I don’t have anything in terms of a timeline.</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; Have a great day.</p>



<p>1:43 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before a Meeting with Bipartisan Governors and Mayors to Discuss the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/14/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-meeting-with-bipartisan-governors-and-mayors-to-discuss-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 3:52 P.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT: Well, we’re going to talk about infrastructure and how we’re going to have to widen this room so you all can get in. (Laughter.)&#160;I want to thank you for being here, all of you, to discuss an issue that has been always bipartisan for the longest time. When I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>3:52 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: Well, we’re going to talk about infrastructure and how we’re going to have to widen this room so you all can get in. (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank you for being here, all of you, to discuss an issue that has been always bipartisan for the longest time. When I got here 180 years ago, it was a bipartisan issue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Mayors and governors more than anyone else knows what it means to be accountable to people, and you have to solve problems every single day in your communities. And &#8212; and there’s no &#8212; there are no Democratic roads or Republican bridges.<br>&nbsp;<br>But &#8212; you know, but there are families in need of shorter commute times, safer commutes; kids that need to be able to drink clean drinking water that doesn’t have lead in it; and communities need to have reliable transit systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we have a chance to solve these problems &#8212; a bipartisan chance to solve these problems. It would create millions of jobs, literally &#8212; not &#8212; not $7-an-hour jobs or even $15-an-hour jobs, but jobs of prevailing wages, making $46, $50 an hour with benefits. And, you know, a chance for America to put ourselves in a position where we can begin to win the second quarter of the 21st century, because our infrastructure, relative to the rest of the world, is moving &#8212; we’re falling behind.<br>&nbsp;<br>I found it disturbing to find out that they ask if you name &#8212; I think it was the 25 best airports in the world &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE: Yes, sir.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: &#8212; the United States wasn’t mentioned. There wasn’t a single U.S. entry.<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; but fixing the broken today is okay, but we got to build for tomorrow. There’s a lot we’re going to do. And press is tired of hearing me say this because I’ve been talking about infrastructure for a while now. Hopefully, it won’t be like the last team in here &#8212; once a week and not get anything done.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we’re going to get something done. And that’s why I think that my Build Back Better agenda is all about not just building back, but build back better than what we &#8212; what we inherited.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Mayors and Governors, you know how to get this done and what we have to do. It’s time to stop talking about it and time to get you the resources. But what I want to talk about today is what you need most and what you think will work the best.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so that’s what we’re going to be talking about and &#8212; and hopefully, we’re going to get a lot done.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you all for coming in.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Do you need to do more work on the payfors, Mr. President? Are the payfors intact?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: He’s talking about &#8212; I went up and spoke to the &#8212; the &#8212; Democratic caucus today, and we put together a plan that dealt with infrastructure. And it’s a bipartisan plan. I think we’re in good shape. There may be some slight adjustments to the &#8212; of the payfors. And that’s going to get down to what the &#8212; what the Congress wants to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ve laid out how I think we’d pay for it. And we have an agreement. We have an agreement. There may be slight changes; I’m not sure what may happen, exactly how &#8212; but it’s going to be paid for. And that’s what we&#8217;re going to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you all very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Mr. President, any concern that having two tracks here will disrupt the bipartisan agreement that was worked out?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: No, I think it’s the only way to get it done is having two tracks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>3:56 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
