<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 20:38:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 20:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Daniel B. Maffei, of New York, to be a Federal Maritime Commissioner for a term expiring June 30, 2027.&#160; (Reappointment) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Catherine J.K. Sandoval, of California, to be a Member of the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board for a term of five years, vice Kristen Marie Kulinowski, term&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Daniel B. Maffei, of New York, to be a Federal Maritime Commissioner for a term expiring June 30, 2027.&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Catherine J.K. Sandoval, of California, to be a Member of the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board for a term of five years, vice Kristen Marie Kulinowski, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Douglas J. McKalip, of the District of Columbia, to be Chief Agricultural Negotiator, Office of the United States Trade Representative, with the rank of Ambassador, vice Gregory Doud.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jessica Davis Ba, of the District of Columbia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Cote d&#8217;Ivoire.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Robert J. Faucher, of Arizona, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Suriname.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kenneth Merten, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Bulgaria.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWAL SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Maria Duaime Robinson, of Massachusetts, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Office of Electricity), vice Bruce J. Walker, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Labor Leaders on Health Care and Workers’&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-labor-leaders-on-health-care-and-workers-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 20:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with labor leaders—including nurses and teachers—on access to health care and workers’ rights. Participants shared their experiences of union women advocating and organizing for health care, including reproductive health care. They also discussed the challenges posed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with labor leaders—including nurses and teachers—on access to health care and workers’ rights. Participants shared their experiences of union women advocating and organizing for health care, including reproductive health care. They also discussed the challenges posed by extreme state laws that restrict access to critical reproductive health services and the direct impact these restrictions have on women in the workforce including impact on negotiated health care benefits.</p>



<p><br>Senior Administration officials underscored the President’s commitment to reproductive rights and thanked participants for their leadership and efforts to protect access to reproductive health care in their communities. The Administration also committed to continued engagement and collaboration with these labor leaders.<br> <br>Participants included:<br>Jessica Blue, Registered Nurse, SEIU 1199<br>Elise Bryant, President, Coalition of Labor Union Women<br>Karla Hernández-Mats, President, United Teachers of Dade<br>Paula Herbart, President Michigan Education Association<br>Deborah Burger, President, National Nurses United</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at CEO Summit On Progress Made Addressing the Root Causes of&#160;Migration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/08/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-ceo-summit-on-progress-made-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[InterContinental Los Angeles DowntownLos Angeles, California 11:05 A.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Well, first, I want to thank the Chamber of Commerce for organizing this CEO Summit and for bringing together so many leaders from business across the hemisphere.  We gather today in pursuit of a shared goal: to build a prosperous and inclusive future&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>InterContinental Los Angeles Downtown<br><em>Los Angeles, California</em></em></p>



<p>11:05 A.M. PDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Well, first, I want to thank the Chamber of Commerce for organizing this CEO Summit and for bringing together so many leaders from business across the hemisphere. <br> <br>We gather today in pursuit of a shared goal: to build a prosperous and inclusive future for the people of the Western Hemisphere.  This is a priority for President Joe Biden and me &#8212; a priority, I know, that everyone here shares.<br> <br>The economies of the Western Hemisphere are deeply intertwined.  And the work we do to strengthen these ties directly impacts the American people. <br> <br>Our neighbors in the Western Hemisphere comprise the largest market for American goods.  The region accounts for nearly 50 percent of all American exports.  And when we have resilient and secure supply chains that are close to us, disruptions will be less frequent, more goods will be available, and prices will come down. <br> <br>From Canada to Chile, a prosperous region benefits all our economies and creates more opportunities for our people. <br> <br>Here&#8217;s how I see it: To realize a more prosperous future for our hemisphere, public-private partnerships are essential &#8212; partnerships that combine the private sector and its experience and expertise with the reach and capacity that only governments can provide. <br> <br>By working together, we can unleash growth and opportunity that far exceeds what either the public or the private sector would achieve on its own. <br> <br>I want to offer a scenario.  Imagine what could happen when governments and companies collaborate. <br> <br>So, picture this.  Imagine a woman in Honduras who lives in a small rural town.  She&#8217;s a single mother.  She has two children.  She does not have a formal education and has never had steady work.  Instead, she takes on an odd job here or there.  She often lays awake at night, worried about whether she can put enough food on the table, wondering if her children can break the cycle of poverty that is all too common where she lives. <br> <br>Then, let&#8217;s imagine a beverage company announces new investments sourcing coffee from her hometown in western Honduras.  Imagine that the company then offers her a job cultivating that coffee.  Imagine an international aid program provides lunch for her children at school, improving their nutrition and their health; that a financial company helps her open a bank account in the form of a digital wallet.  Imagine that she now has some disposable income, and she saves, and she starts moving up the economic ladder. <br> <br>And then, a telecommunications company makes an investment and connects her town to the Internet, and she gains access to new information and online tools that will help her really reach into her imagination about what she can achieve.  And so, she then starts to think about an entrepreneurship based on her vision for herself and her community. <br> <br>Imagine that USAID provides her with a grant to establish her own eco-tourism business and that she accesses credit for the first time, and she hires employees, and her business grows, and she thrives. <br> <br>This story illustrates what I believe is possible when governments and business truly integrate our approach.  This scenario is, then, our vision for millions of people as part of our strategy to address the root causes of migration from Central America. <br> <br>Last year, I began work to lead this effort.  And I approached this task with three basic principles.  First, I do believe most people don&#8217;t want to leave home.  They don&#8217;t want to leave their grandmother.  They don&#8217;t want to leave the place where they worship and the community that they&#8217;ve always known. <br> <br>And so, when they do, it is usually for one of two reasons: They are fleeing harm, or to stay means they simply cannot satisfy their basic needs or the needs of their family. <br> <br>The second principle that is informing our call to action and this approach is my and our belief that governments alone cannot address this issue.  We must partner with the private sector if we are to have lasting impact and if we are to maximize our capacity.<br> <br>Third, I believe that to attract meaningful investment, part of our agenda and strategy must include a priority that is to combat corruption, promote the rule of law, reduce violence, and empower women.<br> <br>So, these are the guiding principles that inform our Root Causes Strategy.  And this Strategy is aligned with the importance that many of the of the leaders here know and live &#8212; the importance of paying attention to a good return on investment, consistency and predictability, a skilled workforce, and a reliable infrastructure.<br> <br>As part of this strategy, last year I launched the Call to Action focused on northern Central America and encouraged companies and civil society to deepen their commitment in the region and to expand collaboration, to invest, and to contribute to long-term development.<br> <br>In particular, I’d like to change &#8212; or thank the Chamber of Commerce, the Partnership for Central America, and the 40 companies and organizations that have made commitments thus far.  These are long-terms efforts, and we are making progress.<br> <br>Yesterday, I announced we have now generated more than $3.2 billion.  This investment is on track to generate tens of thousands of jobs.  It will help more than 10 million people access banking services and credit.  And 2 million people already have been connected to the Internet, with millions more to follow.<br> <br>In parallel, we are taking the steps that only government can.  Our administration has made tackling corruption a top policy priority.  This work incorporates an understanding that rule of law, consistency, and stability are necessary for economies to thrive.<br> <br>Another pillar of our Strategy is to train, protect, and empower women and to address gender-based violence.  I think we all know protecting the safety and security of women is the right thing to do and empowering women drives economic growth.<br> <br>Experts and top universities are now in the midst of studying our Call to Action as an innovative model of public-private partnership &#8212; a model for development efforts in other regions. <br> <br>It is apparent to me that the best approach entails the full involvement of the private sector, governments, and civil society.  And, of course, the idea of a public-private partnership is not new.<br> <br>But what I believe distinguishes the Call to Action is the integration of so many efforts in one ecosystem.  This ecosystem includes some companies that are even competitors with one another.  This ecosystem also includes civil society organizations and the convening power of the United States government and our ability to scale.<br> <br>The Call to Action brings all of these sectors together to collaborate, coordinate, and share lessons learned.<br> <br>Yesterday, in fact, I met with several business executives who made new commitments as part of this initiative.  We discussed how powerful it is to see how each investment &#8212; each investment fits into the larger picture.  In corporate speak: We identified many synergies.<br> <br>And this coordination allows us to address the full spectrum of needs in a given region under one integrated plan.  Together, we are creating an ecosystem of opportunity.<br> <br>And any good public policy, of course, must then be designed with an eye for replication.  I believe truly that our approach can indeed be applied elsewhere on other issues, in other parts of our hemisphere, and even by other governments.<br> <br>When I think about all the challenges we face in the Western Hemisphere, I know that they will require new and innovative coalitions between the public and private sectors.  One size does not fit all, of course.<br> <br>But think about it: Economic inequality in our hemisphere is among the worst in the world.  Women and girls in our hemisphere face far too many barriers and far too few opportunities. <br> <br>Many countries in the region are still struggling to recover from the pandemic.  Health systems are strained.  The climate crisis is mounting.  And we continue to see corruption, migration flows, and democratic backsliding, and violence.<br> <br>These issues affect all of us.  And the solutions then must involve all of us. <br> <br>I believe there is untapped potential for us to partner in these areas and so many more &#8212; in the area of clean energy, food security, health, supply chains, infrastructure, and more.<br> <br>Later today, President Joe Biden will officially open the Summit of the Americas to lay out his ambitious vision for shared prosperity in our hemisphere, now and into the future.<br> <br>Our ongoing partnership with the private sector will play a crucial role in realizing this vision.<br> <br>And I urge all of the leaders here to consider what you can continue to do to partner within the context of the vision I know we share. <br> <br>Needless to say, each of you here has the power to act to help solve some of the most pressing challenges of our time.<br> <br>Our partnership can create new opportunities for individuals to not only succeed but to thrive.<br> <br>For companies, it can create new opportunities to grow and to innovate.<br> <br>And for our hemisphere as a whole, it can create new opportunities to connect and to prosper. <br> <br>I look forward to partnering with all of you in the months and the years ahead.  I thank you for your leadership.  And I look forward to the work we will do. <br> <br>Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END                11:19 A.M. PDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Andrzej Duda of&#160;Poland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Andrzej Duda of Poland.  Following President Biden’s trip to Poland in March, the leaders reaffirmed their shared commitment to further strengthening our bilateral security and economic cooperation. They also discussed their ongoing support for the people and government of Ukraine in response to Russian aggression. President Biden&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Andrzej Duda of Poland.  Following President Biden’s trip to Poland in March, the leaders reaffirmed their shared commitment to further strengthening our bilateral security and economic cooperation. They also discussed their ongoing support for the people and government of Ukraine in response to Russian aggression. President Biden underscored the U.S. commitment to the security of Poland and NATO’s eastern flank, sending his best wishes for a successful Bucharest Nine (B9) Summit later this week.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials Previewing the 9th Summit of the Americas Economic&#160;Deliverables</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/08/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-previewing-the-9th-summit-of-the-americas-economic-deliverables/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you so much, and good morning, everyone.&#160; Thank you for joining us today.&#160; And for those of you in California already, I hope you have a nice cup of coffee in your hand, appreciate the early wake-up call.&#160; Before I turn it over to my colleagues to outline today&#8217;s deliverables, I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you so much, and good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us today.&nbsp; And for those of you in California already, I hope you have a nice cup of coffee in your hand, appreciate the early wake-up call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before I turn it over to my colleagues to outline today&#8217;s deliverables, I just wanted to remind everyone of the ground rules.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And we will lift the embargo today at 11:00 a.m.&nbsp; Eastern.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You should have received &#8212; if not, it’s going out momentarily &#8212; a factsheet that&#8217;s also currently under embargoed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we really &#8212; we’ll have [senior administration official] kick off the call and then have [senior administration official] outline today&#8217;s econ deliverable, and then we&#8217;ll go over to questions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, [senior administration official]?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everybody, for joining us this morning.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve said, the President is very much looking forward to hosting the Ninth Summit of the Americas this week.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s already been a fairly active pace of activity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The theme yesterday, Tuesday, was on building strong and inclusive democracies, and you saw the Vice President announce $3.2 billion now in commitments from the private sector for nortern Central America women&#8217;s empowerment initiative.&nbsp; The Secretary of State announced deliverables on independent journalism and the digital agenda for transformation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, when the President arrives, the theme will be investments in the region&#8217;s health and prosperity.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll let my colleagues speak to the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Thursday, we&#8217;re going to focus on energy security and climate-smart recovery.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ll see meetings that the President and Vice President will have with the Caribbean and others to focus on this issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then lastly, on Friday, the focus is going to be on collaborative migration, where the President is going to meet with leaders to announce an unprecedented partnership on addressing migration challenges that are affecting all of us in the hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that is the focus.&nbsp; And today, I will turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk about the economic deliverables for today.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And thank you all for joining this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, today in Los Angeles, President Biden will announce a new economic agenda for the hemisphere, based on a vision of a region that is secure, middle class and democratic with the announcement, as [senior administration official] mentioned, of what we&#8217;re calling the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it really is a fitting counterpart to the last time the U.S. hosted the Summit of the Americas 28 years ago, when then-President Bill Clinton really outlined an economic vision for that time that effectively laid the tracks for the next three decades of U.S. economic policy that followed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think today&#8217;s unveiling is a necessary update in matching that in scale and ambition, and really taking account of all the ways the world has changed and all the things that the region needs now to effectively run hard at the opportunities and address the challenges that the region has.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, a bit on the “what.”&nbsp;&nbsp; This historic agreement will be instrumental to deepening our economic cooperation, really focusing on the largest drivers of middle-out growth.&nbsp; And we think, going back actually to yesterday&#8217;s themes of democracy, we see this as really a necessary part of the foundation for shoring up democracy in the region.&nbsp; Because I think &#8212; hopefully, it&#8217;s obvious, but they&#8217;re saying that we see democracy as not simply the right of people to choose their leaders, but the agency to shape the kind of economy we live in and the values that that economy serves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think you will see three very clear through-lines of this effort.&nbsp; One is really building it, customizing it to run hard, fast, quickly, effectively at a set of challenges that we have today.&nbsp; I think that certainly the supply chain crisis that we&#8217;re still in the middle of stands out as high on that list.&nbsp; And what will be a new kind of supply chain negotiation really meant to make the supply chains in the hemisphere resilient to unexpected shocks, I think, will be a centerpiece of this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we will really think hard about innovation in both the public and private sectors, precisely to enable governments to better address society&#8217;s most pressing challenges.&nbsp; This goes as much to the “how” of effective public administration as to the “what,” mindful that the best way that people can claim agency over their economy is through their governments.&nbsp; And so, really thinking about how to make governments deliver better will be, I think, really key to a lot of this work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally is just, I think, another instantiation of what has been a through-line of the Biden administration&#8217;s work across its international economic style of really tethering, much more closely than I think previous administrations have, our efforts on climate to our efforts on international trade and economic engagement so that we create a better set of politics around climate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you&#8217;ve seen that borne out in President Biden&#8217;s efforts domestically, when he says, “When I think climate, I think good jobs.”&nbsp; That is, I think, no less true in other countries.&nbsp; And so I think part of the idea here is to take that same logic on the road, multi-lateralize it as part of our international economic engagements.</p>



<p>So, just a few more highlights of what this kind of negotiation will feature and the “how” of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Following the conclusion of the summit, the U.S. will hold initial consultations with partners in the hemisphere and arrange U.S. stakeholders on the following areas.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll just hit them briefly, and then we can take questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first is really reinvigorating regional economic institutions and mobilizing investment.&nbsp; Together, we will reinvigorate the hemispheres (inaudible) flagship economic institution and the Inter-American Development Bank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there, we are looking at the possibility of future capital for IDB Invest &#8212; that&#8217;s the private sector investment arm of the IDB &#8212; as well as looking at a lot of the global multilateral development banks and making sure that they are adequately indexing our own hemisphere, mindful that the acute inequality that so many of the countries in the hemisphere face creates a kind of bimodal tendency in these countries that on average has them appear to be middle income in ways that, frankly, mask a whole lot of need for a whole lot of the populations of these countries that can often have the result of putting them last in line for the kind of supports and financial stabilization that a lot of the global (inaudibles) and multilateral banks can offer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I think just thinking hard about a set of measures that would make sure that we are adequately weighting the need in our own hemisphere with all the institutions that we can bring to bear.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, is really that body of work I mentioned earlier on &#8212; making more resilient supply chains in our hemisphere.&nbsp; I think we now know that our economic security rests on supply chains that are more diverse and secure and reliable and sustainable than, I think, the last 40 years of prioritizing a kind of narrow-minded efficiency that turned out to have been too fragile at the risk of other values like resilience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I think this work will really focus on helping our hemisphere reduce overt dependence and concentrations on certain countries and do the nearshoring and co-investment to run hard at those investments that make good economic and security sense for us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third would be what we&#8217;re calling “updating the basic bargain.”&nbsp; We are mindful that we have a generation of leaders in the region who pretty much (inaudible) are prioritizing a set of public investments in innovation and in the work of government to make life better and fairer for their respective citizens.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes, a lot of that work is necessarily domestic facing.&nbsp; But in many cases, I think it happens to be the kinds of things that tools with U.S. (inaudible), like the Development Finance Corporation and like a newly revamped Inter-American Development Bank, can do good work on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This looks like investments and cooperation in areas like education, health, unemployment, retirement, childcare, women&#8217;s economic empowerment, as well as the kinds of reforms that make those investments enduring, by which I mean helping these countries mobilize the domestic revenue through a set of tax reform measures and anti-corruption measures that will ultimately sustain them over time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fourth is the climate work that I mentioned earlier, advancing clean energy jobs and decarbonization in ways that hopefully create virtuous cycle politics as well as faster progress on decarbonization.&nbsp; And I think we will obviously build this out together with partners.&nbsp; But roughly, I think it hangs together as a negotiation through our ability to develop a financing mechanism to support a set of new asks on things like the percentage of renewables in the grids of these countries and a set of measures on deforestation and a range of other things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, ensuring sustainable and inclusive trade.&nbsp; I think we know that, after the last two years of the pandemic, that we&#8217;ve seen the important role that digital technologies and services play in our economy and the continued importance of trade that is really putting workers and families at the center.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And here, I expect that we will focus on the sort of customs facilitation &#8212; when you look actually at the region&#8217;s sort of container dwelling times, import and customs clearance times, they&#8217;re actually lagging behind many other regions in the world.&nbsp; And as we get into year two or two and a half of a supply chain crisis, I think if you ask a lot of CEOs, they would point to anything we could do to bring these customs and trade facilitation times down is really incredibly valuable and overlooked set of wins that we can probably get at quickly, depending on how we design the negotiation around this.</p>



<p>Beyond that, it&#8217;s advancing transparency and good regulatory practices, pursuing high standards in the digital economy, responsibly supporting emerging technologies, building resilience in energy and food supply chains.&nbsp; Knowing that we are probably in the early days of a food security crisis handed to us by Russia&#8217;s war of choice in Ukraine, it feels incredibly important to do as much as we can as quickly as we can to shave down the worst effects of that food security crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think there&#8217;s also been a number of innovations in areas like labor standards and &#8212; especially on incentivizing corporate accountability, as well as environmental standards &#8212; that a lot of our existing FTAs in this region, because they are some of our oldest, just have not benefited from that thinking.&nbsp; And so, this will also create a venue for us to bring in those kinds of commitments as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, I will stop and look forward to your questions.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for taking questions.&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you elaborate on how countries will be approached and what countries will be invited to negotiate this?</p>



<p>And then similarly, I wonder if you can elaborate on the structure. &nbsp;Will this be like IPEF, where countries opt into particular pillars and it&#8217;s structured to be more flexible? Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And, yes, we are seeing this as effectively the beginning of a conversation that we want to have with, obviously, a set of countries in the region, really beginning with our most likeminded economic partners and &#8212; as well as U.S. stakeholders ranging from friends in Congress to labor and industry stakeholders &#8212; over the next, I would say, two to three months, aiming to, I think, really launch the beginning of formal negotiations once each of these five pillars I just outlined are scoped and we have a sense of country participation across them.&nbsp; That probably looks like a ministerial in early fall.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on your question about structure and design and its proximity to IPEF, we are imagining sort of a flexible structure that does, again, begin with a set of our most likeminded trading partners in the region but, I think, could be opened over time &#8212; and is quite standards based once we have a sense of what those standards are &#8212; through the three-month process that I just described, that would be flexible in the sense of countries being able to join just one, just two, three, four, or all five of these pillars.&nbsp; So, in that sense, I think there is some similarity to the structural mechanics of IPEF.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I actually think the comparison with IPEF is not quite right.&nbsp; So if I could softly push back in a couple of ways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One, I think, in IPEF, you are &#8212; here, we are beginning with a set of, as I mentioned, likeminded partners where I think by and large we already have existing FTAs.&nbsp; And so, I think that just changes the kind of starting posture of this conversation from that of the partners that we&#8217;re dealing with in the Indo-Pacific and in IPEF.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s probably the largest difference.&nbsp; This really is about kind of updating a foundation laid by the several FTAs that we have in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And second is when &#8212; you know, when you go through the pillars that I mentioned, two fifths of them are totally bespoke to the hemisphere &#8212; I think, appropriately so: the (inaudible) reinvigorating regional economic institutions, as well as the updating the basic bargain work that would be, we think, clear demand signals for from the region itself and areas that we think just, again, are quite well suited to the hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, the through-lines that do exist are, frankly, just a reflection of this administration&#8217;s top priorities.&nbsp; It would be, I believe, a little bit head scratching for us to attempt an update of our economic approach to the hemisphere in the scope that we&#8217;re doing here and not include something on climate or supply chain.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for taking the question.&nbsp; I was wondering if there is any money associated with what you&#8217;re announcing today, any U.S. dollar commitments?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think that we are looking at making some commitments around a potential expansion of IDB and IDB Invest &#8212; really the IDB Invest piece &#8212; that has certain procedural hoops that we need to jump through.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t want to prejudge the &#8212; that we would ultimately be successful there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if that does run its course, that would, I think, come with new resources.&nbsp; And I think this is really the beginning of a signal that the President himself is sending about the direction of travel for the kind of economic policy and priorities there that he wants, and I think he would expect to see that reflected in the upcoming budget cycles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for taking the question.&nbsp; You said: Following the conclusion of the summit, the U.S. will hold initial consultation with partners in the hemisphere.&nbsp; Can you talk &#8212; elaborate on that please and talk about what discussions have been held up to now on the contents of this and how you see that going forward?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, again, we&#8217;re not announcing this in ways that has country participation today attached to it.&nbsp;&nbsp; That, I think, will evolve over the next two to three months, as I think we are prioritizing a set of countries that really are our most likeminded.&nbsp; I would leave it to [senior administration official], if he&#8217;d like, to kind of elaborate there, but I think that is exactly the work that we expect to get into, effectively starting today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have, I think, done some very notional conversations with some of these countries as part of our broader brainstorming around the summit to make sure that the notional contours of what we have put out will be well received, just to make sure that we are in the right universe.&nbsp; And I think we do have that comfort that this is something that the region will quite appreciate and we will see a fair bit of uptake for and likely quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I&#8217;ll leave it at that.&nbsp;&nbsp; But, [senior administration official], I don’t know if you want to try to answer that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the first thing I would say is that: In the development of this partnership, we&#8217;ve been consulting with experts and have been talking to governments, even formally through our embassies, to get their feedback, because we have our own concept of what this is based on a recognition of everything [senior administration official] laid out as some of the core challenges of the region and the foundation established by our free trade agreements as being something that has informed U.S. policy over the last 30 years but has not addressed some of these, I think, issues &#8212; inequality issues related to climate and a number of other pillars that [senior administration official] listed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, what we want to do is really frame out a concept that (inaudible) receive widespread support from the countries of the region.&nbsp; And then identify, I think, a core set of countries that will help us set a very high ambition to this.&nbsp; And then have an open architecture where countries will self-select whether they&#8217;re ready really to do this.&nbsp; If not, we&#8217;re not negotiating a trade agreement that would go to Congress, but rather building on existing agreements to actually promote a race to the top.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And I would add, I think, on a pretty ambitious timeline.&nbsp; I think we are building this on the presumption that there are quick gains to be had and inroads to be cut on some of our most acute challenges that we have &#8212; again, that we are in the midst of.&nbsp; And I start with the fact that, again, we do have so many FTAs with a lot of the countries that we would expect to be the inaugural members of this, point one.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, the U.S.’s overall average tariff rate is, as you know, seen as 2.5 percent. I think (inaudible) an undertaking that would be many, many years that we&#8217;re attempting to sort of (inaudible) the ability to run hard at things like the supply chain crisis, improvements that we think we can score on, shaving off the worst effects of the food security crisis, advance on climate, efforts around securing high standards and digital trade where there are no tariffs, our customs and trade facilitation, as I mentioned earlier &#8212; a few of the areas that we think that we could just manage some real wins for the bottom lines of American workers and families as well as countries in the region &#8212; that the ability to run quickly will be an added bonus for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think then it comes to ensuring we can do this in a way that is enduring domestically, which obviously serves all of our interests.&nbsp; And I think that really goes to the kind of consultations that we expect and intend to have with both parties in Congress and a range of U.S. stakeholders in making sure that we develop something that really does put U.S. workers and families at the center and shows that we can pursue those gains for our domestic stakeholders while we are also pursuing a set of geopolitical imperatives in the hemisphere &#8212; that those two things can and should happen simultaneously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, I was wondering if you could just give a little bit of a preview of President Biden&#8217;s remarks on this initiative and whether he&#8217;ll emphasize rising trade flows between the region and China, which is now the largest trading partner for many of these countries, and how that will be discussed in his remarks.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I want to like leave some space for him to make some headlines here as well, so I&#8217;m not going to get into the specifics of his actual remarks &#8212; other than, to your question on the China angle in particular, I don&#8217;t expect that to be a large feature of this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think, frankly, the best antidote to China&#8217;s inroads in the region is to ensure that we are fording our own affirmative vision for the region economically.&nbsp; And we think that that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important that we do lay down a really ambitious, regionally comprehensive, updated vision for the kind of economic partnership we want to have and lead in our hemisphere and use the summit to do that. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I think in that vacuum is where China has made the recent inroads that it has.&nbsp; And so I think we do ourselves both economic service as well as advancing our geostrategic gains by just putting out an affirmative vision that I think these countries will see the clear value proposition in, especially given the way that a lot of China&#8217;s recent efforts through (inaudible) and some of its debt-trap diplomacy have really backfired, including in this instance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thank you so much, everyone, for joining today&#8217;s background call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just as a reminder, this is under embargoed until 11:00 a.m. this morning, and you may attribute the contents of the call to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And then also, thank you so much.</p>



<p>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&#160; Doug McKalip, Nominee for Chief Agricultural Negotiator at the United States Trade Representative Kenneth Merten, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Bulgaria Jessica Davis Ba, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Doug McKalip, Nominee for Chief Agricultural Negotiator at the United States Trade Representative</li><li>Kenneth Merten, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Bulgaria</li><li>Jessica Davis Ba, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Côte d’Ivoire</li><li>Robert J. Faucher, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Suriname</li><li>Catherine J.K. Sandoval, Nominee for Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board</li><li>Daniel B. Maffei, Nominee for Commissioner of the Federal Maritime Commission</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Doug McKalip, Nominee for Chief Agricultural Negotiator at the United States Trade Representative</u></strong></p>



<p>Doug McKalip is in his 29th year of federal service as an agriculture policy leader and trade expert. Since March 2021, he has served as Senior Advisor to the Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack on all agricultural matters relating to trade, national security, animal and plant health regulations, and a wide portfolio of domestic and international issues. McKalip formerly served in a leadership capacity in the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, Biotechnology Regulatory Services. He served as a Senior Advisor to the Secretary of Agriculture from 2015 to September 2016, and also as Acting Chief of Staff. McKalip was Senior Advisor for Agriculture and Rural Affairs at the White House Domestic Policy Council, where he counseled President Barack Obama on issues involving farm, ranch, and rural policy. He served as the Director of the White House Rural Council and coordinated the Executive Branch-wide response to the 2012-2013 drought. McKalip has served in a variety of other roles at USDA, including as Confidential Assistant to the Secretary, and Director of Legislative and Public Affairs for the National Resources Conservation Service at USDA.</p>



<p>McKalip has a Master’s in Public Policy from the American University in Washington D.C. and a Bachelor’s degree in Political Science from the University of Pittsburgh.&nbsp;He is a graduate of the Executive Fellows Program at Harvard Kennedy School of Government (2020), a Fellow in the California Agricultural Leadership DC Exchange (2018), and a graduate of the Federal Executive Institute in Charlottesville, VA (2005).&nbsp;He was also a participant in the Student Council for U.S. Affairs at the United States Military Academy at West Point.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kenneth Merten, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Bulgaria</u></strong></p>



<p>Kenneth Merten is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Career Minister.&nbsp;He recently served as Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim of the U.S. Embassy in Haiti. Previously, he was the Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of Global Talent Management and prior to that he was a Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs. Merten has also served as Ambassador to Croatia, Ambassador to Haiti, and as Deputy Executive Secretary of the Department of State.&nbsp;Among his other assignments, Merten was the Economic Counselor at the U.S. Embassy in Paris, France, the Executive Assistant in the State Department’s Bureau of Economic and Business Affairs and a Senior Watch Officer in the State Department Operations Center. Merten earned his B.A. degree from Miami University in Oxford, Ohio, and his M.A. degree from American University in Washington, D.C.&nbsp; He is the recipient of multiple awards including the Grande Croix of Honor from the government of Haiti for Earthquake support, the Ryan Crocker Award for Outstanding Leadership in Expeditionary Diplomacy, and the CORE Shandling Humanitarian Award. He speaks Haitian Creole, French, German and Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jessica Davis Ba, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Côte d’Ivoire</u></strong></p>



<p>Jessica Davis Ba is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Counselor.&nbsp;She most recently served as Senior Coordinator and Special Advisor for Africa in the Office of the Vice President. Previously, Davis Ba served as the Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim of the U.S. Embassy N’Djamena, Chad and prior to that she was the Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Mission to the African Union and U.S. Deputy Permanent Representative to the UN Economic Commission for Africa in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. Among her other assignments, Davis Ba served as Deputy Program Director at the U.S. Embassy in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, as Special Assistant in the State Department Operations Center, and as Deputy Director, International Narcotics and Law Enforcement at the U.S. Embassy in Baghdad, Iraq. Her earlier assignments include serving as Deputy Counselor for Economic Affairs and Regional Labor Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Nairobi, Kenya and as Political/Economic Officer for the Somalia Affairs Unit in the U.S. Embassy in Nairobi. Davis Ba earned her B.A. from the University of Pennsylvania and her M.A. from the University of Pennsylvania’s Annenberg School for Communication.&nbsp;She speaks French and Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Robert J. Faucher, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Suriname</u></strong></p>



<p>Robert J. Faucher is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor. Faucher has served as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations (CSO) since 2019, including being the Acting Assistant Secretary for CSO throughout 2021.&nbsp;He was previously Director for the Office of Western European Affairs in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs. Previously, Faucher held positions as Director in the offices of United Nations (UN) Political Affairs and UN Specialized and Technical Agencies in the Bureau of International Organization Affairs.&nbsp;Faucher joined the Foreign Service in 1985 and served as the Deputy Chief of Mission at U.S. Embassies in Belgium, Ireland, Suriname and Luxembourg.&nbsp;His other overseas postings include the Netherlands, the U.S. Mission to the European Union, and the United Kingdom.&nbsp;His prior Washington service includes Deputy Office Director in the Office of European Union Affairs, Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs; Special Assistant in the Bureau of Intelligence and Research; and Attorney Advisor for the Middle East and South Asia in the Legal Adviser’s Office.&nbsp;Born in Landstuhl, Germany, Faucher grew up in Arizona, and holds B.A. and J.D./M.B.A. degrees from Arizona State University, an L.L.M. degree in European Union Law from Edinburgh University, and an M.S. degree in National Security Studies from the National Defense University’s National War College.&nbsp;He speaks Dutch and French.</p>



<p><strong><u>Catherine J.K. Sandoval, Nominee for Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Catherine J.K. Sandoval is a tenured Law Professor at Santa Clara University (SCU) who teaches and conducts research on energy, communications, antitrust, and contract law. A regulatory and legal expert for more than thirty years and a safety leader for more than two decades, her interdisciplinary work advances infrastructure safety, reliability, access, and equity. She directs three institutes at SCU Law. Sandoval served a six-year term as a Commissioner of the California Public Utilities Commission (CPUC), appointed by Governor Brown and unanimously confirmed by the California State Senate. During her prior federal service, she served as Director of the Federal Communications Commission’s (FCC), Office of Communications Business Opportunities. Former California Governor Davis appointed her to serve as Undersecretary and Senior Policy Advisor for Housing, and previously as Staff Director of California’s Business, Transportation, and Housing Agency. In that capacity she worked with law enforcement including the California Highway Patrol to respond to infrastructure vulnerabilities and hazardous incidents.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sandoval hails from a trailer park, the barrio of East Los Angeles, and then Montebello, California, and became the first in her family to earn a B.A. degree. She was the first Latina selected as a Rhodes Scholar, the first tenured Latina Law Professor at SCU Law, and the first Latinx CPUC Commissioner. She served as a law clerk to Judge Dorothy W. Nelson of the Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals. She earned a B.A. from Yale University, a Master of Letters from Oxford University, and a J.D. from Stanford Law School.</p>



<p><strong><u>Daniel B. Maffei, Nominee for Commissioner of the Federal Maritime Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Daniel Benjamin Maffei, of New York, is an experienced public servant who serves as Chairman of the Federal Maritime Commission since being appointed to the position by President Biden in 2021.&nbsp;Under his Chairmanship, the Commission has reinvigorated its enforcement efforts, prioritized helping U.S. export shippers, and established several new initiatives to address supply chain congestion and efficiency challenges.</p>



<p>Maffei’s career in government spans more than 20 years. He was twice elected to the U.S. House of Representatives for the 24th Congressional District of New York with assignments to the House Armed Services Committee, House Financial Services Committee, and the House Judiciary Committee. His earlier public service includes working for the Democratic staff of the House Ways and Means Committee and as the Press Secretary for U.S. Senators Daniel Patrick Moynihan and Bill Bradley. Maffei has substantial experience teaching and researching at universities and think tanks. In addition to his career as a public servant, Maffei has worked in the private sector as an independent consultant and as a broadcast journalist. He earned his Bachelor’s degree from Brown University and his Master’s degrees from Columbia University and Harvard University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on  Delegation of Authority Under the European Energy Security and Diversification Act of&#160;2019</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/08/memorandum-on-delegation-of-authority-under-the-european-energy-security-and-diversification-act-of-2019/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegation of Authority Under the European Energy Security and Diversification Act of 2019 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to&#160;the Secretary of State&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegation of Authority Under the European Energy Security and Diversification Act of 2019</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to&nbsp;the Secretary of State the functions and authorities vested in the President by section 2004(e)(1)(C) of the European Energy&nbsp;Security and Diversification Act of 2019 (22 U.S.C. 9563(e)(1)(C)) (the &#8220;Act&#8221;). &nbsp;The delegation in this memorandum shall apply to any provision of any future public law that is the same or substantially the same as the provision referenced in this memorandum. &nbsp;Any reference in this memorandum to the Act shall be deemed to be a reference to such Act as amended from time to time.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House and President pro tempore of the Senate regarding the War Powers&#160;Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-and-president-pro-tempore-of-the-senate-regarding-the-war-powers-report-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 18:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Mr. President:) I am providing this supplemental consolidated report, prepared by my Administration and consistent with the War Powers Resolution (Public Law 93-148), as part of my efforts to keep the Congress informed about deployments of United States Armed Forces equipped for combat. MILITARY OPERATIONS IN SUPPORT OF UNITED STATES COUNTERTERRORISM&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Mr. President:)</p>



<p>I am providing this supplemental consolidated report, prepared by my Administration and consistent with the War Powers Resolution (Public Law 93-148), as part of my efforts to keep the Congress informed about deployments of United States Armed Forces equipped for combat.</p>



<p>MILITARY OPERATIONS IN SUPPORT OF UNITED STATES COUNTERTERRORISM EFFORTS</p>



<p>In furtherance of counterterrorism efforts, the United States continues to work with partners around the globe, with a particular focus on the United States Central and Africa Commands&#8217; areas of responsibility. &nbsp;In this context, the United&nbsp;States has deployed forces to conduct counterterrorism operations and to advise, assist, and accompany security forces of select foreign partners on counterterrorism operations. &nbsp;In the majority of these locations, the mission of United States military personnel is to facilitate counterterrorism operations of foreign partner forces and does not include routine engagement in combat.&nbsp; In many of these locations, the security environment is such that United States military personnel may be required to defend themselves against threats or attacks, and, to that end, the United States may deploy United States military personnel with weapons and other appropriate equipment for force&nbsp;protection. &nbsp;Specific information about counterterrorism deployments to select countries is provided below, and a classified annex to this report provides further information.</p>



<p>Military Operations Conducted Pursuant to the 2001 Authorization for Use of Military Force and in Support of Related United&nbsp;States Counterterrorism Objectives</p>



<p>Since October 7, 2001, United States Armed Forces, including Special Operations Forces, have conducted counterterrorism combat operations, including against al-Qa&#8217;ida and associated forces. &nbsp;Since August 2014, these operations have included targeting the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS), also known as the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), which was formerly known as al-Qa&#8217;ida in Iraq. &nbsp;In support of these and other overseas operations, the United States has deployed combat‑equipped forces to several locations in the United&nbsp;States Central, European, Africa, Southern, and Indo‑Pacific Commands&#8217; areas of responsibility. &nbsp;Such operations and deployments have been reported previously, consistent with&nbsp;Public Law 107-40, Public Law 107-243, the War Powers Resolution, and other statutes. &nbsp;These ongoing operations, which the United States has carried out with the assistance of numerous international partners, have been successful in seriously degrading ISIS capabilities in Syria and Iraq. &nbsp;If necessary, in response to terrorist threats, I will direct additional measures to protect the people and interests of the United States. &nbsp;It is&nbsp;not possible to know at this time the precise scope or the duration of the deployments of United States Armed Forces that are or will be necessary to counter terrorist threats to the United&nbsp;States.</p>



<p><strong>Afghanistan.</strong> &nbsp;No United States Armed Forces are in Afghanistan. &nbsp;The United States has relocated counterterrorism capabilities outside Afghanistan and remains postured to address threats to the United States homeland and United States interests that may arise from inside Afghanistan.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Iraq and Syria.</strong> &nbsp;As part of a comprehensive strategy to defeat ISIS, United States Armed Forces are working by, with, and through local partners to conduct operations against ISIS forces in Iraq and Syria and against al-Qa&#8217;ida in Syria to limit the potential for resurgence of these groups and to mitigate threats to the United States Homeland. &nbsp;A small presence of United States Armed Forces remains in strategically significant locations in Syria to conduct operations, in partnership with indigenous ground forces, to address continuing terrorist threats emanating from Syria. &nbsp;United States Armed Forces in Iraq continue to advise, assist, and enable select elements of the Iraqi security forces, including Iraqi Kurdish security forces. &nbsp;United States Armed Forces also provide limited support to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization mission in Iraq. &nbsp;United States Armed Forces, as part of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS, remain present in Iraq at the invitation of the Government of Iraq.</p>



<p><strong>Arabian Peninsula Region. &nbsp;</strong>A small number of United States military personnel are deployed to Yemen to conduct operations against al-Qa&#8217;ida in the Arabian Peninsula and ISIS. &nbsp;The United&nbsp;States military continues to work closely with the Republic of Yemen government and regional partner forces to degrade the terrorist threat posed by those groups.</p>



<p>United States Armed Forces, in a non-combat role, continue to provide military advice and limited information to the Saudi-led Coalition for defensive and training purposes only as they relate to territorial defense. &nbsp;Such support does not involve United States Armed Forces in hostilities with the Houthis for the purposes of the War Powers Resolution.</p>



<p>United States Armed Forces are deployed to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia to protect United States forces and interests in the region against hostile action by Iran and Iran-backed groups. These forces, operating in coordination with the Government of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, provide air and missile defense capabilities and support the operation of United States military aircraft. &nbsp;The total number of United States forces in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia is approximately 2,733.</p>



<p><strong>Jordan. &nbsp;</strong>At the request of the Government of Jordan, approximately 2,833 United States military personnel are deployed to Jordan to support Defeat-ISIS operations, to enhance Jordan&#8217;s security, and to promote regional stability.</p>



<p><strong>Lebanon. &nbsp;</strong>At the request of the Government of Lebanon, approximately 98 United States military personnel are deployed to Lebanon to enhance the government&#8217;s counterterrorism capabilities and to support the counterterrorism operations of Lebanese security forces.</p>



<p><strong>Turkey. &nbsp;</strong>United States Armed Forces remain deployed to Turkey, at the Turkish government&#8217;s request, to support Defeat-ISIS operations and to enhance Turkey&#8217;s security.</p>



<p><strong>East Africa Region. &nbsp;</strong>United States Armed Forces based outside Somalia continue to counter the terrorist threat posed by ISIS and al-Shabaab, an associated force of al-Qa&#8217;ida, in Somalia. &nbsp;Since the last periodic report, United States forces conducted one airstrike against al-Shabaab in defense of our Somali partner forces, and remain prepared to conduct airstrikes against ISIS and al-Shabaab terrorists. &nbsp;United States military personnel conduct periodic engagements in Somalia to train, advise, and assist regional forces, including Somali and African Union Mission in Somalia forces, during counterterrorism operations. &nbsp;On May 16, 2022, I announced my decision to reestablish a persistent military presence in Somalia, to enable&nbsp;a more effective fight against al-Shabaab. &nbsp;Over the next&nbsp;several weeks and months, United States Armed Forces will reposition from locations within Africa to return to Somalia.&nbsp; United States Armed Forces are deployed to Kenya to&nbsp;support counterterrorism operations in East Africa. &nbsp;United&nbsp;States military personnel continue to partner with the Government of Djibouti, which has permitted use of Djiboutian territory for basing of United States Armed Forces. &nbsp;United&nbsp;States military personnel remain deployed to Djibouti, including for purposes of staging for counterterrorism and counter-piracy operations in the vicinity of the Horn of Africa and the Arabian Peninsula, and to provide contingency support for embassy security augmentation in East Africa, as necessary.</p>



<p><strong>Lake Chad Basin and Sahel Region. &nbsp;</strong>United States military personnel in the Lake Chad Basin and Sahel Region continue to conduct airborne intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance operations and to provide support to African and European partners conducting counterterrorism operations in the region, including by advising, assisting, and accompanying these partner forces. &nbsp;Approximately 773 United States military personnel remain deployed to Niger.</p>



<p><strong>Cuba. &nbsp;</strong>United States Armed Forces continue to conduct humane and&nbsp;secure detention operations for detainees held at Guantanamo&nbsp;Bay, Cuba, under the authority provided by the 2001&nbsp;Authorization for the Use of Military Force (Public Law&nbsp;107-40), as informed by the law of war. &nbsp;There are 37&nbsp;such&nbsp;detainees as of the date of this report.</p>



<p><strong>Philippines. &nbsp;</strong>United States Armed Forces deployed to the Philippines are providing support to the counterterrorism operations of the armed forces of the Philippines.</p>



<p>MILITARY OPERATIONS IN EGYPT IN SUPPORT OF THE MULTINATIONAL FORCE AND OBSERVERS</p>



<p>Approximately 598 United States military personnel are assigned to or are supporting the United States contingent of the Multinational Force and Observers, which have been present in&nbsp;Egypt since 1981.</p>



<p>UNITED STATES AND NORTH ATLANTIC TREATY ORGANIZATION OPERATIONS IN KOSOVO</p>



<p>The United States continues to contribute forces to the Kosovo Force (KFOR), led by the North Atlantic Treaty Organization in cooperation with local authorities, bilateral partners, and international institutions, to deter renewed hostilities in Kosovo. &nbsp;Approximately 561 United States military personnel are among KFOR&#8217;s approximately 4,000 personnel.</p>



<p>UNITED STATES ARMED FORCES IN NORTH ATLANTIC TREATY ORGANIZATION COUNTRIES</p>



<p>With approximately 17,000 additional United States Armed Forces deployed in recent months to reassure our allies and to deter further Russian aggression, approximately 90,000 United States Armed Forces personnel are deployed to North Atlantic Treaty Organization countries in Europe.</p>



<p>I have directed the participation of United States Armed Forces in all of the above-described operations pursuant to my constitutional and statutory authority as Commander in Chief and as Chief Executive (including the authority to carry out Public Law 107-40, Public Law 107-243, and other statutes), as well as my constitutional and statutory authority to conduct the foreign relations of the United States. &nbsp;Officials of my Administration and I communicate regularly with congressional leadership, relevant congressional committees, and other Members of Congress with regard to these deployments, and we will continue to do so.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Air Force One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/08/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 17:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George’s County, Maryland 12:02 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I’ve got a brief statement I’m going to make if I can.&#160; I think the voters sent a clear message last night: Both parties have to step up and do something about crime, as well as gun violence.&#160; And I sent, as you recall&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Andrews<br>Prince George’s County, Maryland</p>



<p>12:02 P.M. EDT</p>



<p><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ve got a brief statement I’m going to make if I can.&nbsp; I think the voters sent a clear message last night: Both parties have to step up and do something about crime, as well as gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I sent, as you recall &#8212; with the first major bill we passed, we gave the states and localities billions of dollars &#8212; billions of dollars they have &#8212; and I encouraged them to use it to hire police officers and reform their police departments.&nbsp; Very few have done it.</p>



<p>In addition to that, I sent to Congress a request for $300 million in this year&#8217;s budget to deal with hiring cops, to retrain cops, as well as to make sure they are adequately dispersed around the communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s time they move.&nbsp; It&#8217;s time to states and the localities spend the money they have to deal with crime, as well as retrain police officers, as well as provide for more community policing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s time to get on with doing that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what I think the message last night from the American public was in all the primaries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>12:03 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Announces the Americas Partnership for Economic&#160;Prosperity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-the-americas-partnership-for-economic-prosperity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the opening ceremony of the Summit of the Americas, President Biden will announce the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity, a historic new agreement to drive our hemisphere’s economy recovery and growth, and deliver for our working people. Accounting for 31.9 % of global GDP, the Western Hemisphere is one of the most dynamic economic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>At the opening ceremony of the Summit of the Americas, President Biden will announce the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity, a historic new agreement to drive our hemisphere’s economy recovery and growth, and deliver for our working people. Accounting for 31.9 % of global GDP, the Western Hemisphere is one of the most dynamic economic regions in the world, and the United States’ ties with the rest of the hemisphere are broad and deep. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Still reeling from the disproportionate impact of the COVID-19 pandemic, Latin America and the Caribbean has seen the deepest economic contraction of any region in the world. Income inequality is widening, millions of people are being cast back into poverty, and global inflation – made worse by Putin’s war in Ukraine – is straining families’ budgets.&nbsp; The Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity will rebuild our economies from the bottom up and middle out.</p>



<p>Together with partners, we deepen our economic cooperation, focusing on the largest drivers of middle-out growth, and shaping new tools for the challenges facing us today and, in the decades, to come. We will strengthen our supply chains to be more resilient against unexpected shocks. We will foster innovation in both the public and private sectors, so governments can better address society’s most pressing challenges, and businesses can enhance their productivity. And we will tackle the climate crisis by growing climate-related industries that will give rise to high-quality jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a high-standards approach that is built on shared values, this partnership will support U.S. business and workers and support hemispheric recovery, resilience, and stability across the Americas. Following the conclusion of the Summit of the Americas, the United States will hold initial consultations with partners in the hemisphere and stakeholders on the following areas of focus: &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Reinvigorating Regional Economic Institutions and Mobilizing Investment</strong>. To deliver on our aspirations, we will work to pivot our public institutions and financing mechanisms to leverage far greater levels of private investment.&nbsp; We will together reinvigorate the hemisphere’s regional economic institutions, such as the Inter-American Development Bank, including through reforms to drive climate ambition, social inclusion and private sector development with the possibility of future capital for IDB Invest, and ensure international financial and economic institutions adequately prioritize the region. We will also work to support countries that are host to large numbers of migrants or refugees, or who want to make ambitious reforms in line with the Partnership’s goals.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Making More Resilient Supply Chains.</strong> Our economic security rests on supply chains that are diverse, secure, transparent, and sustainable. We recognize the importance of diversifying and rebalancing our supply chains to minimize disruption risks.&nbsp; As we work to create resilient supply chains, we will prioritize development of our workforce and take steps to ensure supply chains are transparent and free of exploitative labor conditions.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Updating the Basic Bargain. </strong>Public investments and innovations in public administration can make life better and fairer for our respective citizens.&nbsp; We will explore how to broaden participation in the formal economy, including tax and anti-corruption measures, as well as cooperation and infrastructure investments in areas such as migration, education, health, unemployment and retirement, childcare, and women’s economic empowerment.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Creating Clean Energy Jobs and Advancing</strong>&nbsp;<strong>Decarbonization and Biodiversity</strong>. In line with our climate goals and to support good jobs, we will work together to accelerate clean energy technology, more sustainable forest conservation and management, and low emission and resilient agricultural practices. We will work to decarbonize our economies, enhance biodiversity, and build resilience to climate impacts.&nbsp; We will deepen cooperation on technologies and best practices, mechanisms to increase public and private investment, and explore technical assistance to advance quality infrastructure and programming.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ensuring Sustainable and Inclusive Trade.</strong> The pandemic has only underscored the importance of secure and resilient regional trade flows, as well as the growing role that digital technologies and services play in our economies. We will focus on how to better cooperate on customs facilitation, advance transparency and good regulatory practices, pursue high standards on the digital economy, responsibly support emerging technologies, build resilience in our energy and food supply chains, advance strong labor and environment standards, and incentivize corporate accountability and a race to the top to foster regional economic development.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
