<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 16:46:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Oklahoma Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/30/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-oklahoma-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 16:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Oklahoma and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, tornadoes, and flooding from May 2 to May 8, 2022. The President’s action makes Federal funding available to affected&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Oklahoma and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, tornadoes, and flooding from May 2 to May 8, 2022.</p>



<p>The President’s action makes Federal funding available to affected individuals in the counties of Adair, Cherokee, Muskogee, Okmulgee, Pottawatomie, Seminole, and Tulsa.</p>



<p>Assistance can include grants for temporary housing and home repairs, low-cost loans to cover uninsured property losses, and other programs to help individuals and business owners recover from the effects of the disaster.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Roland W. Jackson as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>Residents and business owners who sustained losses in the designated counties can begin applying for assistance by registering online at <a href="http://www.DisasterAssistance.gov">http://www.DisasterAssistance.gov</a> or by calling 1-800-621-FEMA(3362) or 1-800-462-7585 (TTY) for the hearing and speech impaired.&nbsp; The toll-free telephone numbers will operate from 7:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m. (local time) seven days a week until further notice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in Press Conference &#124; Madrid,&#160;Spain</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/30/remarks-by-president-biden-in-press-conference-madrid-spain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 16:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Institución Ferial de MadridMadrid, Spain 2:56 P.M. CEST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Thank you.&#160; If you have a seat, please sit down.&#160; You’d think someone else walked in the room.&#160; Thank you very much for taking the time to be here. I think we can all agree that this has been a historic NATO&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Institución Ferial de Madrid<br>Madrid, Spain</p>



<p>2:56 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; If you have a seat, please sit down.&nbsp; You’d think someone else walked in the room.&nbsp; Thank you very much for taking the time to be here.</p>



<p>I think we can all agree that this has been a historic NATO Summit.&nbsp; Some of the folks have been covering me for a while.&nbsp; About a year and a half ago, when the first G7 meeting took place in England, I talked about the need for us to reconsider the makeup of NATO, how it functioned, and come up with a different strategy for the &#8212; for NATO and how we work together.&nbsp; And &#8212; and in addition to that, we also talked about the G7 taking on additional responsibilities.</p>



<p>And before the war started, I told Putin that if he invaded Ukraine, NATO would not only get stronger but would get more united.&nbsp; And we would see democracies in the world stand up and oppose his aggression and defend the rules-based order.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re seeing today.</p>



<p>This summit was about strengthening our Alliance, meeting the challenges of our world as it is today and the threats we&#8217;re going to face in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last time NATO drafted a new mission statement was 12 years ago.&nbsp; At that time, it characterized Russia as a partner, and it didn&#8217;t even mention China.&nbsp; The world has changed, changed a great deal since then.&nbsp; And NATO is changing as well.</p>



<p>At this summit, we rallied our Alliances to meet both the direct threats that Russia poses to Europe and the systemic challenges that China poses to a rules-based world order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve invited two new members to join NATO.&nbsp; It was a historic act.&nbsp; Finland and Sweden, two countries with a long tradition of neutrality and choosing to join NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some of the American press will remember when I got a phone call from the leader of Finland saying could he come and see me.&nbsp; And he came the next day and said, “Will you support my joining &#8212; my country joining NATO?”</p>



<p>We got on the telephone, and he suggested we call the leader of Switzerland &#8212; “Switzerland,” my good &#8212; my goodness.&nbsp; I’m getting really anxious here about expanding NATO.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Of Sweden.&nbsp; And what happened was we got on the phone, and she asked if she could come the next day to want to talk about joining NATO.</p>



<p>Allies across the board are stepping up, increasing defense spending.&nbsp; A majority of them are on track for the first time to exceed our 2 percent of GDP commitment that they made.&nbsp; They agreed to spend 2 percent of the GDP on defense.</p>



<p>Look, for example, Germany: Germany has committed to spending 2 percent going forward, and announced a special fund for its military of more than $100 billion.&nbsp; Slovakia, the Czech Republic, and the Netherlands have announced they will also meet their 2 percent commitments.&nbsp; Poland, Romania, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania are doing more than 2.5 percent, some as high as 3 percent.</p>



<p>Together, we’re deploying more assets and capabilities to bolster our Alliances across all domains &#8212; land, air, sea, cyber, and space.</p>



<p>We &#8212; we’ve reaffirmed that our Article 5 commitment is sacred.&nbsp; And an attack on one is an attack on all, and we will defend every inch of NATO territory.&nbsp; Every inch of NATO territory.</p>



<p>For our part, the United States is doing exactly what I said we would do if Putin invaded: enhance our force posture in Europe.&nbsp; We’ll station more ships in here, in Spain.&nbsp; We’re stationing more air defense in Italy and Germany; more F-35s in the United Kingdom; and, to strengthen our eastern flank, new permanent headquarters for the Army Fifth Corps in Poland.&nbsp; In addition, an additional brigade combat team positioned in Romania, and additional rotational deployments in the Baltic countries.</p>



<p>Things are changing to adapt to the world as we have it today.&nbsp; And all this is against the backdrop of our response to NATO&#8217;s &#8212; to Russia&#8217;s aggression and to help Ukraine defend itself.</p>



<p>The United States is rallying the world to stand with Ukraine.&nbsp; Allies and partners around the globe are making significant contributions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secretary Austin just brought together more than 50 countries &#8212; more than 50 countries &#8212; pledging new commitments, and this is a global effort to support Ukraine: nearly 140,000 anti-tank systems, more than 600 tanks, nearly 500 artillery systems, more than 600,000 rounds of artillery ammunition, as well as advanced multiple launch rocket systems, anti-ship systems, and air defense systems.</p>



<p>And again, the United States is leading the way.&nbsp; We provided Ukraine with nearly $7 billion in security assistance since I took office.&nbsp; In the next few days, we intend to announce more than $800 million more, including a new advanced Western air defense system for Ukraine, more artillery and ammunition, counter-battery radars, additional ammunition for the HIMARS multiple launch rocket system we&#8217;ve already given Ukraine and more HIMARS coming from other countries as well.</p>



<p>We also welcomed, for the first time, our partners in the Indo-Pacific to participate in the NATO Summit.&nbsp; As I indicated to Putin, this would be &#8212; his action would cause worldwide response, bringing together democratic allies and partners from the Atlantic and the Pacific to focus on the challenges that matter to our future and to defend the rules-based order against the challenges, including from China.</p>



<p><a>In the G7 in Germany, we also launched what started off to be the Build Back Better notion, but it&#8217;s morphed into the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment, to offer developing and middle-income countries better options to meet their urgent infrastructure needs.&nbsp; Because when the United States and G7 countries put skin in the game, it helped bring &#8212; it helps bring millions of dollars up to &#8212; before it’s all over &#8212; up to possibly a trillion dollars of private sector money off the sidelines &#8212; $600 billion in just the next few years.</a></p>



<p>Unlike China, these projects will be done transparently and with very high standards.&nbsp; For example, the U.S. government just facilitated a new partnership between two American firms and the government of Angola to invest $2 billion building a significant solar project in Angola.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a partnership to help Angola meet its climate goals and energy needs while creating new markets for American technologies and good jobs in Angola.&nbsp; As you heard me say before: When I think “climate,” I think “jobs.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the G7 also said we&#8217;d work together to take on China&#8217;s abusive and coercive trade practices and rid our supply chains of products made with forced labor.</p>



<p>We tasked our teams to work on the details of the price cap on Russian oil to drive down Putin&#8217;s revenues without hurting Americans and others at the gas pump.</p>



<p>We’ll seek to use the funds from the tariffs on Russian goods to help Ukraine rebuild.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re committed &#8212; we&#8217;ve committed more than $4.5 billion &#8212; more than half of that from the United States &#8212; to address food insecurity and the immediate crisis caused by the Russian war.</p>



<p>At every step of this trip, we set down a marker of unity, determination, and deep capabilities of the democratic nations of the world to do what need be done.&nbsp; Putin thought he could break the transatlantic Alliance.&nbsp; He tried to weaken us.&nbsp; He expected our resolve to fracture.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s getting exactly what he did not want.</p>



<p><a>He wanted the <s>Findalization</s> [Finlandization] of NATO.&nbsp; He got the NATOization of Finland.</a></p>



<p>Just think about this: That&#8217;s what he thought.&nbsp; Now <s>NATO</s> [Finland] and Sweden are closer than ever to joining.&nbsp; And this will occur.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re more united than ever.&nbsp; And with the addition of Finland and Sweden, we’ll be stronger than ever.&nbsp; They have serious militaries, both of them.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to increase the NATO border by 800 miles along the Finnish-Russian border.&nbsp; Sweden is all in.</p>



<p>The point is: We&#8217;re meeting the goals I set out when we first &#8212; the first G7 meeting.&nbsp; We&#8217;re moving to a place that reflects the realities of the 20- &#8212; the second quarter of the 21st century.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re on the verge of making significant progress.</p>



<p>Now, I&#8217;d be happy to take your questions.&nbsp; And the first question, I&#8217;m told, is Darlene Superville from the Associated Press.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Two questions, please.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Of course.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; “America is Back” was your motto at the first NATO Summit last year.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve come to this summit here and the one in Germany after the U.S. Supreme Court overturned constitutional protections for abortion, after the shootings in Buffalo and Texas, at a time of record inflation, and as new polling this week shows that 85 percent of the U.S. public thinks the country is going in the wrong direction.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How do you explain this to those people who feel the country is going in the wrong direction, including some of the leaders you&#8217;ve been meeting with this week, who think that when you put all of this together, it amounts to an America that is going backward?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They do not think that.&nbsp; You haven&#8217;t found one person &#8212; one world leader to say America is going backwards.&nbsp; America is better positioned to lead the world than we ever have been.&nbsp; We have the strongest economy in the world.&nbsp; Our inflation rates are lower than other nations in the world.&nbsp; The one thing that has been destabilizing is the outrageous behavior of the Supreme Court of the United States on overruling not only Roe v. Wade, but essentially challenging the right to privacy.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been a leader in the world in terms of personal rights and privacy rights, and it is a mistake, in my view, for the Supreme Court to do what it did.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I have not seen anyone come up to me and do anything other than &#8212; nor have you heard them say anything other than, “Thank you for America&#8217;s leadership.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve changed the dynamic of NATO and the G7.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I &#8212; I can understand why the American people are frustrated because of what the Supreme Court did.&nbsp; I can understand why the American people are frustrated because of inflation.&nbsp; But inflation is higher in almost every other country.&nbsp; Prices at the pump are higher in almost every other country.&nbsp; We&#8217;re better positioned to deal with this than anyone, but we have a way to go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the Supreme Court &#8212; we have to change that decision by codifying Roe v. Wade.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There were some comments by some of your counterparts after the U.S. Supreme Court ruling.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my second question is: G7 leaders this week pledged to support Ukraine, quote, “for as long as it takes.”&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if you would explain what that means to the American people &#8212; “for as long as it takes.”&nbsp; Does it mean indefinite support from the United States for Ukraine?&nbsp; Or will there come a time when you have to say to President Zelenskyy that the United States cannot support his country any longer?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We are going to support Ukraine as long as it takes.</p>



<p>Look at the impact that the war on Ukraine has had on Russia.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve had to renege on their national debt for the first time since the beginning &#8212; almost well over 100 years.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve lost 15 years of the gains they made in terms of their economy.&nbsp; They&#8217;re in a situation where they&#8217;re having trouble because of my imposition of &#8212; of &#8212; dealing with what can be exported to Russia, in terms of technology.&nbsp; They can&#8217;t even &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re having &#8212; they&#8217;re going to have trouble maintaining oil production because they don&#8217;t have the technology to do it.&nbsp; They need American technology.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re also in a simi- &#8212; similar situation in terms of their weapons systems and some of their military systems.&nbsp; So they&#8217;re paying a very, very heavy price for this.</p>



<p>And just today, Snake Island is now taken over by the &#8212; by the Ukrainians.&nbsp; So we are going to stick with Ukraine and all of the Alliance is going to stick with Ukraine as long as it takes to, in fact, make sure that they are not defeated by &#8212; by Ukraine &#8212; I mean, excuse me, in Ukraine by &#8212; by Russia.</p>



<p>And, by the way, think of this: Ukraine has already dealt a severe blow to Russia.&nbsp; Russia, in fact, has already lost its international standing.&nbsp; Russia is in a position where the whole world is looking and saying, “Wait a minute, all this effort &#8212; you tried to take the whole country.&nbsp; You tried to take Kyiv.&nbsp; You lost.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve tried to take the Donbas and all of it.&nbsp; You haven&#8217;t done that yet.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The generic point is that we&#8217;re supplying them with the capacity &#8212; and the overwhelming courage they&#8217;ve demonstrated &#8212; that, in fact, they can continue to resist the Russian aggression.&nbsp; And so, I don&#8217;t know what &#8212; how it&#8217;s going to end, but it will not end with a Russian defeat of Ukraine in Ukraine.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m supposed to go down the list here.&nbsp; Jim, the New York &#8212; Jim Tankersley, the New York Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you.&nbsp; This week, you and the G7 allies introduced a plan for an oil price cap for Russian exports &#8212; which is not yet filled out &#8212; and, obviously, is a response to the high price of gasoline in the United States and around the world.&nbsp; Are you confident that that cap would bring down prices for American drivers?&nbsp; And how long is it expect &#8212; fair to expect American drivers to continue to pay a premium because of this war?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me hear the &#8212; the second part of the question was, “Would it bring down the price?”</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will it bring down prices.&nbsp; And the war has pushed prices up.&nbsp; They could go as high as $200 a barrel, some analysts think.&nbsp; How long is it fair to expect American drivers and drivers around the world to pay that premium for this war?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; As long as it takes so Russia cannot, in fact, defeat Ukraine and move beyond Ukraine.&nbsp; This is a critical, critical position for the world.&nbsp; Here we are.&nbsp; Why do we have NATO?</p>



<p>I told Putin that, in fact, if he were to move, we would move to strengthen NATO.&nbsp; We would move to strengthen us &#8212; strengthen NATO across the board.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, let me explain the price &#8212; I suggested a while ago that what we should consider doing is putting a cap on the amount of money that we would pay for &#8212; the world would pay for Russian oil, and that we would not &#8212; there would &#8212; we would not provide &#8212; the West &#8212; provides insurance &#8212; would not insure Russian ships carrying oil.&nbsp; We would not provide insurance for them, so they would have great difficulty getting customers.</p>



<p>The point is that we&#8217;ve said to them, “Here&#8217;s the deal: We&#8217;re going to allow you to have a profit on what you make but not the exorbitant prices that you&#8217;re charging for the oil now.”&nbsp; We&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve delegated a commission &#8212; a group of our &#8212; (inaudible) sherpa &#8212; our national security people to sit down and work out that mechanism.&nbsp; We think it can be done.&nbsp; We think it can be done, and it would drive down the price of oil, and it would drive down the price of gasoline as well.</p>



<p>In addition &#8212; in addition, at home, I have also called for changes.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve &#8212; I&#8217;ve released a million barrels of oil per day from our oil reserve, and in addition to getting other nations to move forward a total of 240 million barrels of oil to release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; Number one.</p>



<p>Number two, I&#8217;ve asked Congress would they, in fact, go and end the &#8212; temporarily end the tax on gasoline at the pump.</p>



<p>And thirdly, to ask the states to do the same thing.</p>



<p>If we do these things, it&#8217;s estimated we could bring down, tomorrow, if they &#8212; if Congress agreed and the states agreed, we could bring down the price of oil about a dollar a gallon at the pump, in that range.&nbsp; And so, we could have immediate relief in terms of the reduction of the &#8212; of the elimination of &#8212; temporary elimination of the gas tax.</p>



<p>And so I think there&#8217;s a lot of things we can do and we will do.&nbsp; But the bottom line is: Ultimately, the reason why gas prices are up is because of Russia.&nbsp; Russia, Russia, Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reason why the food crisis exist is because of Russia &#8212; Russia not allowing grain to get out of Ukraine.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s the way in which I think we should move, and I think it would have a positive impact on the price at the pump as well.</p>



<p>Jordan Fabian, Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; I also have two questions for you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Of course.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; The first one is on Turkey.&nbsp; What assurances, if any, did you make to President Erdoğan about his request for new F-16 jets for his military?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What I said was &#8212; I said back in December, as you&#8217;ll recall, we should sell them the F-16 jets and modernize those jets as well.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not in our interest not to do that.&nbsp; And I indicated to them that I&#8217;ve not changed my position at all since December.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there was no quid pro quo with that; it was just that we should sell.&nbsp; But I need congressional approval to be able to do that, and I think we can get that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my second question is on your trip to Saudi Arabia, which is coming up next month.&nbsp; As we just discussed, Americans are paying almost $5.00 a gallon nationally, on average, for gas.&nbsp; So, do you expect to ask the Crown Prince or the King to increase oil production?&nbsp; And if so, how will you balance that with your desire to hold them accountable for their human rights abuses?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, first of all, that&#8217;s not the purpose of the trip.&nbsp; The purpose of the trip &#8212; my &#8212; first of all, I&#8217;m starting off on that trip in Israel.&nbsp; And the Israelis are &#8212; believe it&#8217;s really important that I make the trip.&nbsp; And in addition to that, what we&#8217;re trying to do is that the G- &#8212; it’s the Gulf States plus three.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;m sure &#8212; it’s in Saudi Arabia, but it&#8217;s not about Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; It&#8217;s in Saudi Arabia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so there&#8217;s no commitment that is being made or &#8212; I&#8217;m not even sure; I guess I will see the King and the Crown Prince, but that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s not the meeting I&#8217;m going to.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll be part of a much larger meeting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we&#8217;re talking about in dealing with that trip is that, before I go, I&#8217;m, as I said, going to Israel to meet with Israeli leaders to affirm the unbreakable bond Israel and the United States have.&nbsp; And part of the purpose is &#8212; the trip to the Middle East &#8212; is to deepen Israel&#8217;s integration in the region, which I think we&#8217;re going to be able to do and which is good &#8212; good for peace and good for Israeli security.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why Israel leaders have come out so strongly for my going to Saudi.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the overall piece here is we&#8217;re also going to try to reduce the deaths and &#8212; in the war that&#8217;s occurring in Yemen.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a whole range of things that go well beyond anything having to do with Saudi in particular.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if you were to see the Crown Prince or the King, would you ask them to increase oil production?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m not going to ask them.&nbsp; I’m going to ask &#8212; there&#8217;s &#8212; all the Gulf States are meeting.&nbsp; I’ve indicated to them that I thought they should be increasing oil production, generically &#8212; not to the Saudis particularly.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;re going to &#8212; I hope we see them, in their own interest, concluding that makes sense to do.</p>



<p>And, you know, they have real concerns about &#8212; about what&#8217;s going on in Iran and other places in terms of their security as well &#8212; all of them.</p>



<p><a><s>Tarina</s></a> [Tarini], the Wall Street Journal.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to keep the trend and also ask two questions, if that&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; One on the summit and one domestic question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the summit, you just said that there would be another round of security assistance for Ukraine.&nbsp; After hearing President Zelenskyy’s assessment that the war needs to end before the winter, are you changing your calculation in terms of the pace of the assistance and what kind of assistance you&#8217;re sending to Ukraine?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I &#8212; the war could end tomorrow, by the way, if Russia stops its irrational behavior.&nbsp; So, you know, when the war will end, I hope it ends sooner than later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But for it to end, they have to be in a position where the Is- &#8212; the Ukrainians have all that they can reasonably expect, we can reasonably expect to get to them, in order to perva- &#8212; provide for their physical security and their defenses.</p>



<p>And so, one does not relate to the other.&nbsp; They need &#8212; we&#8217;re going to be providing another &#8212; well, I guess I&#8217;ll announce it shortly, but another $800 billion &#8212; $800 million in aid for additional weaponry, including &#8212; you know, weapons, including air defense system, as well as offensive weapons.&nbsp; I have a whole list I&#8217;d be happy to give to you.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s the next tranche that’s going to occur.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the domestic question, sir: What further specific executive actions are you considering in response to the Roe ruling?&nbsp; And would you declare a public health emergency as several Democrats are calling on you to do?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll be happy to go in detail with you on that, on the &#8212; I&#8217;m having a meeting with a group of governors when I get home on Friday.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll have announcements to make then.</p>



<p>But the first and foremost thing we should do is make it clear how outrageous this decision was and how much it impacts not just on a woman’s right to choose &#8212; which is a critical, critical piece &#8212; and on privacy generally.&nbsp; On privacy generally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I&#8217;m going to be talking to &#8212; to the governors as to what actions they think I should be taking as well.&nbsp; And &#8212; but the bi- &#8212; most important thing to be clear about is we have to change &#8212; I believe we have to codify Roe v. Wade into law.&nbsp; And the way to do that is to make sure that Congress votes to do that.&nbsp; And if the filibuster gets in the way &#8212; it&#8217;s like voting rights &#8212; it should be we provide an exception for this &#8212; the exce- &#8212; the &#8212; require an exception to the filibuster for this action to deal with the Supreme Court decision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hang on.&nbsp; I got one more here.&nbsp; Kelly O&#8217;Donnell, NBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Well, you just made some news saying you would support changing the filibuster rules to codify abortion rights broadly across the country.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Right to privacy, not just abortion rights.&nbsp; But, yes, abortion rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you describe for us, sir &#8212; many Americans are grappling with this.&nbsp; What is your sense today about the integrity and the impartiality of the Supreme Court?&nbsp; Should Americans have confidence in the Court as an institution?</p>



<p>And your views on abortion have evolved in your public life.&nbsp; Are you the best messenger to carry this forward when Democrats &#8212; many of them, many progressives &#8212; want you to do more?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Yeah, I am.&nbsp; I&#8217;m the President of the United States of America.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; That makes me the best messenger.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I really think that it&#8217;s a serious, serious problem that the Court has thrust upon the United States not just in terms of the right to choose, but in terms of the right to who you can marry, the right &#8212; a whole range of issues relating to &#8212; to privacy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I have written, way back, a number of law review articles about the Ninth Amendment and the &#8212; and the Fourteenth Amendment and why that privacy is considered as part of a constitutional guarantee.&nbsp; And the &#8212; they&#8217;ve just wiped it all out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I&#8217;m the only President they got, and I feel extremely strongly that I&#8217;m going to do everything in my power which I legally can do in terms of executive orders, as well as push the Congress and the public.</p>



<p>The bottom line here is: If you care &#8212; if the polling data is correct, and you think this decision by the Court was an outrage or a significant mistake, vote.&nbsp; Show up and vote.&nbsp; Vote in the off-year and vote, vote, vote.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we&#8217;ll change it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, guys, I &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, just a quick one.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, there&#8217;s no such thing as a quick one.&nbsp; I&#8217;m out of here.&nbsp; Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>3:23 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Health Sector Leaders Join Biden Administration’s Pledge to Reduce Greenhouse Gas Emissions 50% by&#160;2030</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/fact-sheet-health-sector-leaders-join-biden-administrations-pledge-to-reduce-greenhouse-gas-emissions-50-by-2030/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56550</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Health Sector Steps Up to Protect Public Health and Lower CostsToday, the Biden-Harris Administration announced that 61 of the largest U.S. hospital and health sector companies responded to the Administration’s Health Sector Climate Pledge, committing to reduce greenhouse gas emissions 50% by 2030. The new commitments represent over 650 hospitals and thousands of other providers&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Health Sector Steps Up to Protect Public Health and Lower Costs<br></em><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration announced that 61 of the largest U.S. hospital and health sector companies responded to the Administration’s <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/04/22/hhs-launches-pledge-initiative-mobilize-health-care-sector-reduce-emissions.html">Health Sector Climate Pledge</a>, committing to reduce greenhouse gas emissions 50% by 2030. The new commitments represent over 650 hospitals and thousands of other providers across the country, and include plans to strengthen resilience to climate change, protect public health, and lower costs. The health care sector accounts for 8.5% of U.S. emissions, so these bold commitments advance President Biden’s goal to reduce nationwide greenhouse gas emissions 50-52% in 2030 and reach net-zero emissions in 2050.<br>Today, historic commitments are being made across the health care industry, including:</p>



<ul><li>Two of the five largest US private hospital and health systems (Ascension and CommonSpirit Health) and the largest US public health system have pledged to halve their carbon emissions by 2030.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Leading health sector suppliers like Pfizer and AstraZeneca have stepped up to achieve net-zero emissions ahead of the 2050 pledge timeline.</li><li>Major medical associations, including America’s Essential Hospitals, the American Association of Medical Colleges, and the National Academy of Medicine, have committed to taking climate action.</li></ul>



<p>The full list of the 61 organizations is outlined below.</p>



<p>President Biden sees action on climate change as a public health priority. Studies show that the increasingly dangerous consequences of climate change are affecting public health, through more frequent and intense severe weather, extreme heat, and threats to food and water security. The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to using every available tool to protect public health, while moving full-speed ahead with our mission to tackle the climate crisis, to create jobs, grow the clean energy economy, and lower costs for families.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration launched the <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/04/22/hhs-launches-pledge-initiative-mobilize-health-care-sector-reduce-emissions.html">Health Sector Climate Pledge</a> on Earth Day 2022 through the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). Since then, over 650 private and public hospitals and health centers, along with pharmaceutical companies, medical device-makers, suppliers, and group purchasing organizations have signed the pledge, joining more than 200 federal hospitals and health facilities from HHS, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and the Military Health System. These organizations are also developing climate resilience plans for facilities and communities, including plans to support individuals and communities most vulnerable to the impacts of climate change. Today, the White House and HHS are re-opening the Health Care Sector Pledge until October 28<sup>th</sup>, 2022 to build on these historic commitments ahead of the United Nations Climate Conference in November.</p>



<p><em>Private Sector Pledge Signers</em></p>



<p>61 organizations have signed the pledge, representing a large share of the US health sector, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Health Systems, Hospitals and Other Providers</strong><br><ul><li>Providence Health, HealthPartners, Kedren Health, CommonSpirit Health, University Medical Center of El Paso, NYC Health + Hospitals, Boston Medical Center, Baystate Health, Stanford Children’s Health, Stanford Health Care, Atrium Health, Cherokee Health Systems, University of California Health, Northwell Health, Rush University System for Health, Northern Arizona Healthcare, Hackensack Meridian Health, UW Medicine, RWJBarnabas Health, Sun River Health, NYU Langone Health, Ascension, Henry Ford Health, Mass General Brigham, Boston Children’s Hospital, Tufts Medicine, Southcoast Health, Children’s National Hospital, Mount Sinai Health System, Kaiser Permanente, Keck Medicine of USC, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Montefiore, Seattle Children’s, Valley Children’s Healthcare, University of Nebraska Medical Center and Nebraska Medicine, Advocate Aurora Health, Gillette Children’s, University of Utah Health, Steward Health Care System, DaVita<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Other Industry Organizations</strong><br><ul><li>Philips, AstraZeneca, Owens &amp; Minor, NewGen Surgical, Chiesi Group, Pfizer, AmerisourceBergen, Excellus Health, Blue Shield of California, Vizient, Aspirus, Anthem, WCM Waste and Compliance Management<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Associations, Nonprofits and Technical Assistance Organizations</strong><ul><li>National Academy of Medicine, Association of American Medical Colleges, the Joint Commission, Health Care Without Harm, American College of Physicians (NJ), Kimball Sustainable Healthcare, Mazzetti</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><em>Leading by Example to Advance Health &amp; Climate Goals</em></p>



<p>Last year, the Administration established the <a href="https://www.bing.com/search?q=ocche+at+hhs&amp;cvid=a82857c4043e4517b778c450e385f0e4&amp;aqs=edge..69i57j0j69i60l3.2674j0j1&amp;pglt=43&amp;FORM=ANNTA1&amp;PC=U531">Office of Climate Change and Health Equity</a> at HHS to identify and address health disparities exacerbated by climate impacts. Since then, the Administration has invested over <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/fact-sheet-white-house-announces-additional-385-million-to-lower-home-energy-bills-for-american-families/">$8 billion in the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP)</a> to help low-income Americans manage energy costs in the face of extreme weather.</p>



<p>The VA has made substantial progress implementing its 2021 Climate Action Plan, including incorporating climate resilience requirements into construction standards, assessing the adequacy of critical supply stockpiles to align with projected climate change impacts, and developing agency wide strategies to address mission risk amplified by climate change. Within its medical centers, VA has also successfully initiated efforts to transition to zero-emission vehicles, is accelerating efforts to increase energy and water efficiency, and is expanding upon existing and new sources of carbon-pollution free electricity.</p>



<p>Today, the Administration is announcing a series of new resources to support the health sector in transitioning to clean energy, reducing emissions, and building climate resilience:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Federal Health Sector Emissions Reduction Resources.</strong> HHS, with contributions from the Department of Energy (DOE), the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and the Department of Agriculture (USDA), is launching the “Accelerating Healthcare Sector Action on Climate Change and Health Equity” webinar series to provide education and training on sustainable infrastructure financing, climate emergency preparedness, and emissions tracking from the health sector supply chain.<br></li><li><strong>Federal Health Network on Decarbonization Best Practices.</strong> The VA, Military Health System, and Indian Health Service are launching a coalition to exchange best practices on emissions reduction and climate resilience with a plan to share their learning with private-sector organizations.<br></li><li><strong>National Research Forum on Climate Impacts and Heart Health.</strong> HHS is launching <em>The Million Hearts Climate Change &amp; Cardiovascular Disease Collaborative (CCC)</em>, a national forum for health care organizations to learn about climate change and the effects of air pollution on cardiovascular health, and to review evidence-based interventions to address those threats.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Health Sector Emissions Assessment Toolkit.</strong> HHS’s Agency for Health Care Research Quality (AHRQ) will release a suite of resources to facilitate consistent measurement and reporting of health facility emissions data and to provide guidance on transitioning to greener models of care delivery.<br></li><li><strong>Federal Funding for Climate Smart Health Facilities.</strong> The Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) launched the Green Mortgage Insurance Premium which will provide incentives for ongoing care facilities to implement energy and water efficiency upgrades. This program will lower costs for renovation and rehabilitation of facilities and increasing the safety of the populations they serve.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><em>Private Health Care Systems Leading the Way</em></p>



<p>Private health care systems are taking up the mantle on climate action – going beyond the HHS Health Care Sector Climate Pledge to achieve even greater progress on climate resilience:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Tackling Super-Polluting Medical Gases:</strong> Providence Health, Advocate Aurora Health, and Children’s National Hospital have committed to reduce emissions from medical anesthetic gases used in surgical procedures by over 75% &#8212; keeping these dangerous greenhouse gasses from being vented into the environment. AstraZeneca and Chiesi Group are tackling emissions from fluorinated gases used in common devices like inhalers, with the goal of reducing their carbon footprint by at least 90%.<br></li><li><strong>Investing in Clean Energy:</strong> Blue Shield of California, NYC Health + Hospitals, AmerisourceBergen, Kaiser Permanente, Children’s National Hospital and others have constructed on-site solar arrays and other clean energy generation sources to reduce emissions and provide direct benefits for surrounding communities. Kaiser Permanente has added over 44 MW of on-site solar generation – enough to power 9,600 homes, while the energy from Children’s National Hospital will benefit communities through a solar program that will lower utility costs for 325 families by up to $500 a year.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Achieving Carbon Neutrality:</strong> Seattle Children’s Hospital, Philips, Kaiser Permanente, and Blue Shield California have all surpassed their pledge commitment and already achieved carbon neutrality.<br></li><li><strong>Building Climate Resilience in Vulnerable Communities:</strong> Valley Children’s Healthcare, University of Utah, and CommonSpirit Health have developed and implemented detailed climate resilience plans that put the focus on communities most vulnerable to the impacts of climate change, because the cascading impacts on health such as poor air quality from wildfires, extreme heat, and increased instances of vector-borne diseases are hitting those communities first.<br></li><li><strong>Increasing Transparency on Climate Costs-Impacts: </strong>Vizient, AstraZeneca, and DaVita are leading the charge to ensure that company costs and accounting include risks to organizations from climate impacts through the Task Force of Climate Related Financial Disclosure. These actions will ensure that companies make climate-smart investments with information about how climate can disrupt health care supply chains, damage facilities or impact energy supply.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves South Dakota Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/29/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-south-dakota-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 20:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of South Dakota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe storm, straight-line winds, tornadoes, and flooding on May 12, 2022. Federal funding is available to State, tribal, eligible&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of South Dakota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe storm, straight-line winds, tornadoes, and flooding on May 12, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to State, tribal, eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storm, straight-line winds, tornadoes, and flooding in the counties of Aurora, Beadle, Bon Homme, Brookings, Clay, Codington, Day, Deuel, Grant, Hamlin, Hanson, Hutchinson, Kingsbury, Lake, McCook, Miner, Minnehaha, Moody, Roberts, and Turner and the Flandreau Santee Sioux Tribe of South Dakota and the Sisseton-Wahpeton Oyate of the Lake Traverse Reservation.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Alana B. Kuhn as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the State and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Names Twentieth Round of Judicial&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/29/president-biden-names-twentieth-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing two new federal judicial nominees, both of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. This is President Biden’s twentieth round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his seventh slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing two new federal judicial nominees, both of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>This is President Biden’s twentieth round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his seventh slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 107.</p>



<p>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies. And he has won confirmation of the most lower court judges for the first year of a presidency since the Kennedy Administration.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Circuit Court Press Bio</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Justice Tamika Montgomery-Reeves: Candidate for the United States Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Justice Tamika Renee Montgomery-Reeves has served as a Justice on the DelawareSupreme Court since 2019. Justice Montgomery-Reeves served as a Vice Chancellor on the Delaware Court of Chancery from 2015 to 2019.  Prior to joining the bench, Justice Montgomery-Reeves was a partner at Wilson Sonsini Goodrich &amp; Rosati in Delaware, where she worked from 2011 to 2015.  From 2007 to 2011, Justice Montgomery-Reeves was an associate at Weil Gotshal &amp; Manges LLP in New York. Justice Montgomery-Reeves served as a law clerk for Chancellor William B. Chandler III on the Delaware Court of Chancery from 2006 to 2007. She earned her J.D., <em>cum laude</em>, from the University of Georgia School of Law in 2006 and B.A., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from the University of Mississippi in 2003.   </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>District Court Press Bio</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Judge Frances Kay Behm: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Michigan</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Frances Kay Behm has served as a judge for the Genesee County Circuit and Probate Courts since 2009. Judge Behm was previously a solo practitioner from 2008 to 2009. From 1997 to 2008, Judge Behm was an associate at Winegarden, Haley, Lindholm, &amp; Robertson in Flint, Michigan and an associate at Braun Kendrick Finbeiner in Saginaw, Michigan from 1994 to 1997. Judge Behm received her J.D. from the University of Michigan Law School in 1994 and her B.A., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Albion College in 1991.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President Recep Tayyip Erdogan of&#160;Turkey</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/29/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-recep-tayyip-erdogan-of-turkey-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 18:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Recep Tayyip Erdogan on the margins of the NATO Summit. President Biden welcomed Turkey’s conclusion of a trilateral agreement with Finland and Sweden that paved the way for Allies to invite them to join NATO. The leaders discussed their continued support for Ukraine in its defense against&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Recep Tayyip Erdogan on the margins of the NATO Summit. President Biden welcomed Turkey’s conclusion of a trilateral agreement with Finland and Sweden that paved the way for Allies to invite them to join NATO. The leaders discussed their continued support for Ukraine in its defense against Russian aggression, as well as the importance of removing Russian obstacles to the export of Ukrainian grain. They also talked about the importance of maintaining stability in the Aegean and Syria. President Biden reiterated his desire to maintain constructive bilateral relations, and the leaders agreed on the importance of continued close consultations between our governments.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan of the Republic of Turkey Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/29/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-recep-tayyip-erdogan-of-the-republic-of-turkey-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 17:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Institución Ferial de MadridMadrid, Spain 5:54 P.M. CEST PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Okay.&#160; Mr. President, it’s good to see you again.&#160; And thank you for &#8212; are we ready? AIDE:&#160; Yes, sir. PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Thank you for making the effort to come over.&#160; I want to particularly thank you for what you did putting together the situation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Institución Ferial de Madrid<br>Madrid, Spain</p>



<p>5:54 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Mr. President, it’s good to see you again.&nbsp; And thank you for &#8212; are we ready?</p>



<p>AIDE:&nbsp; Yes, sir.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you for making the effort to come over.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to particularly thank you for what you did putting together the situation with regard to Finland and Sweden, and all the incredible work you’re doing to try to get the grain out of Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; I mean, you’re doing a great job.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just want to thank you, and I’d like to talk to you about those things when we have a chance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the floor is yours.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT ERDOĞAN:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Mr. President, hello.&nbsp; I would like to especially mention that it gives me great &#8212; Mr. President, it gives me great pleasure to be able to get together with you after a long interval.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this NATO Summit that we’re attending, in terms of its agenda, is going to be quite busy and it’s going to be quite important.&nbsp; And tomorrow, the activities will be sustained.&nbsp; And thanks to our efforts, we believe that we will be able to go back to our countries with our hands full and with full satisfaction.</p>



<p>And as the United States, we think your pioneering in this regard is going to be crucial in terms of strengthening NATO for the future, and it’s going to have a very positive contribution to the process between Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Russia and Ukraine conflict and the negative developments with regards to taking out of the grain from the Ukrainian ports, as well as the developments involving oil and natural gas, require all of us to work together in order to settle the disputes once and for all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I hope and pray that we will be able to establish a balance to diplomacy in order to cultivate positive results, especially with regards to the grain.&nbsp; There are countries deprived of the grains, and we will open corridors, and we will allow them to have access to the grains that they so need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; And it’s in large because of your leadership.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>5:57 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden, President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea, and Prime Minister Kishida Fumio of Japan Before Trilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/29/remarks-by-president-biden-president-yoon-suk-yeol-of-the-republic-of-korea-and-prime-minister-kishida-fumio-of-japan-before-trilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 15:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2:38 P.M. CEST PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, it’s great to be here again with President Yoon following our detailed and productive conversations in Seoul last month and also to be joined by Prime Minister Kishida, who I visited in Tokyo last month and spent the last few days in Germany with, at the G7. And this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>2:38 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, it’s great to be here again with President Yoon following our detailed and productive conversations in Seoul last month and also to be joined by Prime Minister Kishida, who I visited in Tokyo last month and spent the last few days in Germany with, at the G7.</p>



<p>And this is an opportunity to further coordinate our trilateral efforts, specifically with regard to the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.</p>



<p>Our trilateral cooperation, in my view, is essential to achieving our shared objective, including a complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and a free and open Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>I look forward to additional dialogues in this format as we continue to strengthen our trilateral &#8212; our trilateral engagement.&nbsp; And we remain deeply concerned at the DPRK’s continued escalatory ballistic missiles and tests and potential for &#8212; to conduct a nuclear test.</p>



<p>I’m particularly pleased that this meeting is taking place on the margins of this historic NATO Summit and that, for the first time, it includes Indo-Pacific partners of Australia and Japan, New Zealand, and the Korean Republic, and &#8212; excuse me, the Republic of Korea.&nbsp; And attendance of all four of these leaders highlights the global resolve to hold Russia accountable for its brutal and unprovoked war in Ukraine and our shared determination to defend the rules-based international order.</p>



<p>And with that, I’d like to turn to President Yoon.&nbsp; And the floor is yours, sir.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; In conjunction with the NATO Summit, I find it deeply meaningful that we &#8212; as leaders of the Republic of Korea, the United States, and Japan &#8212; came together.</p>



<p>I extend my sincere appreciation to President Biden for hosting this summit, and I am delighted to meet Prime Minister Kishida once again.</p>



<p>The DPRK’s nuclear and missile threats continue to evolve, and the global landscape is facing increased uncertainties, thereby rendering our trilateral partnership all the more significant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In almost five years, the ROK-U.S.-Japan Summit is reconvening, indicating the three nations’ commitment to enhancing their cooperation in order to tackle regional and global issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I hope that our meeting today will position ROK-U.S.-Japan partnership as yet another central pillar for global peace and stability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; I am deeply concerned over the possibility of further provocation by North Korea, including nuclear testing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As confirmed on the occasion of President Biden&#8217;s visit to Japan and to the ROK, the deterrence capabilities of the Japan-U.S. and U.S.-ROK alliances need to be upgraded as part of the essential effort to strengthen the trilateral partnership between Japan, the U.S., and ROK.</p>



<p>From such perspective and for other reasons, this trilateral summit is being organized at a timely juncture.&nbsp; Through this meeting, I hope that trilateral cooperation regarding our response to North Korea will be solidified.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I very much welcome the prompt response by the Japan-U.S. and U.S.-ROK alliances against ballistic missiles launched by North Korea, and the agreement reached at the recent trilateral ministerial meeting between defense ministers to conduct trilateral missile warning and ballistic missile search and tracking exercises is welcomed.</p>



<p>In the case a nuclear test is performed, I hope that response can be taken at the trilateral level, including joint exercises.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In order to strengthen the deterrence and response capabilities of our alliance with the U.S., Japan will fundamentally reinforce our defense capabilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, Joe, President Yoon, I am deeply grateful for your support towards the immediate solution of the abduction issue, and I ask you for your continued understanding and cooperation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, gentlemen, thank you very much.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll let the press out, which ought to be interesting watching.</p>



<p>2:42 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Trilateral with President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea and Prime Minister Fumio Kishida of&#160;Japan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/29/readout-of-president-bidens-trilateral-with-president-yoon-suk-yeol-of-the-republic-of-korea-and-prime-minister-fumio-kishida-of-japan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 14:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56468</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met today with President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea and Prime Minister Fumio Kishida of Japan on the sidelines of the NATO Summit. This was a historic trilateral meeting in which the three Leaders discussed enhancing trilateral cooperation throughout the Indo-Pacific, particularly in regard to addressing the evolving threat posed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met today with President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea and Prime Minister Fumio Kishida of Japan on the sidelines of the NATO Summit. This was a historic trilateral meeting in which the three Leaders discussed enhancing trilateral cooperation throughout the Indo-Pacific, particularly in regard to addressing the evolving threat posed by the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea’s unlawful weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs. They also followed up on their detailed and productive conversations in Seoul and Tokyo last month. President Biden underscored the United States’ unshakable commitment to the defense of both Japan and the Republic of Korea.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg &#124; Madrid,&#160;Spain</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/29/remarks-by-president-biden-and-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg-madrid-spain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 14:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Institución Ferial de MadridMadrid, Spain 10:17 A.M. CEST PRESIDENT BIDEN: Well, Jens, thank you very much for having me this morning. And, you know, we &#8212; we got a big agenda. And it’s great to be here with you to kick off the &#8212; I think is a history-making summit. And we talked about this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Institución Ferial de Madrid<br>Madrid, Spain</p>



<p>10:17 A.M. CEST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Well, Jens, thank you very much for having me this morning. And, you know, we &#8212; we got a big agenda. And it’s great to be here with you to kick off the &#8212; I think is a history-making summit. And we talked about this for a year, and now we’re here.</p>



<p>Our meetings today &#8212; we’re going to approve a new NATO Strategic Concept and reaffirm the unity and determination of our Alliance to defend every inch of NATO territory. And Article 5 is sacrosanct, and we mean it when we say, “An attack against one is an attack against all &#8212; every inch.”</p>



<p>And so, at this summit, the full Alliance is going to welcome Finland and Sweden &#8212; their historic application for membership &#8212; and their decision to move away from neutrality and the tradition of neutrality to join NATO Alliance is going to make us stronger and more secure, and NATO stronger.</p>



<p>We’re sending an unmistakable message, in my view &#8212; and I think yours as well &#8212; that NATO is strong, united, and the steps we’re taking during this summit are going to further augment our collective strength.</p>



<p>To that end, today I’m announcing the United States will enhance our force posture in Europe and respond to the changed security environment, as well as strengthening our collective security.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, we surged 20,000 additional U.S. forces to Europe to bolster our Alliance in response to Russia’s aggressive move, bringing our force total in Europe to 100,000.</p>



<p>We’re going to continue to adjust our posture based on the threat, in close consultation with our Allies.</p>



<p>Here in Spain, we’re going to work with our Ally to increase U.S. Navy destroyers stationed in Spain’s Rota Naval Base from three to &#8212; from four to six &#8212; four to six destroyers.</p>



<p>In Poland, we’re going to establish a permanent headquarters for the U.S. Army Fifth Corps and &#8212; strengthening our U.S.-NATO interoperability across the entire eastern flank.</p>



<p>We’re going to maintain additional rotational Brigade &#8212; which is 3,000 fighters and another 2,000 personnel &#8212; Combat Team here in Europe, headquartered in Romania.</p>



<p>And we’re going to enhance our rotational deployments in &#8212; deployments in the Baltic states.</p>



<p>And we’re going to send two additional F-35 squadrons to the UK, and station additional air defense and other capabilities in Germany and in Italy.</p>



<p>And together, our Allies &#8212; we’re going to make sure that NATO is ready to meet threats from all directions, across every domain: land, air, and the sea.</p>



<p>In a moment when Putin has shattered peace in Europe and attacked the very, very tenets of the rules-based order, the United States and our Allies &#8212; we’re going to step up. We’re stepping up.</p>



<p>We’re proving that NATO is more needed now than it ever has been and it’s as important as it has ever been.</p>



<p>So I want to thank you, Jens, for leading the Alliance through this crisis and for your work to strengthen NATO for all the challenges that lie ahead. And I &#8212; I genuinely look forward to our discussion today.</p>



<p>And, again, thank you for your leadership. It’s important.</p>



<p>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG: Thank you so much, President Biden, dear Joe. It&#8217;s really good to see you here in Madrid so soon after we met in the White House in Washington. And thank you for your personal leadership and the U.S. commitment to NATO, to European security demonstrated by the announcement &#8212; the announcements you just made to further increase U.S. presence in Europe.</p>



<p>And this really demonstrates your decisive leadership in strengthening the transatlantic bond, and also see that in the unwavering support from you and from the United States to Ukraine. That will be a main issue at the summit today.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll meet with President Zelenskyy. He will address the summit. And as you said, this will be an historic summit. It will be a transformative summit where we will make decisions that will actually change this Alliance for many years to come.</p>



<p>We will agree a new Strategic Concept, the blueprint for NATO into the future &#8212; a more dangerous world, a more competitive world. We will agree the biggest overhaul of our collective defense deterrence since the end of the Cold War &#8212; and the U.S. is, of course, very much part of that.</p>



<p>And then we will invite Finland and Sweden to join NATO. And that demonstrates that NATO&#8217;s door is open. It demonstrates that President Putin has not succeeded in closing NATO’s door.</p>



<p>He is getting the opposite of what he wants. He wants less NATO; President Putin is getting more NATO by Finland and Sweden joining our Alliance.</p>



<p>We will agree a comprehensive assistance package for Ukraine. And then I also welcome the fact that we are able now to state that actually &#8212; that European Allies and Canada are stepping up with more troops, higher readiness, and also increased defense spending.</p>



<p>New figures shows that they have added 350 billion extra U.S. dollars for defense since we made the pledge back in 2014.</p>



<p>So, all in all, this demonstrates unity and the strength of our Alliance. So, thank you, Joe.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Well, you know, I was asked about this one &#8212; about Finland and &#8212; and Sweden &#8212; when each of their leaders came to the White House. And I said Putin was looking for the “Finlandization” of Europe. He’s going to get the “NATO-ization” of Europe. And that&#8217;s exactly what he didn&#8217;t want, but exactly what needs to be done to guarantee security for Europe.</p>



<p>And I think it&#8217;s &#8212; I think it&#8217;s necessary, and I&#8217;m looking forward to it happening formally.</p>



<p>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG: Thank you so much.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Thank you.</p>



<p>10:23 A.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
