<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:09:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer Pride Month, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/01/a-proclamation-on-lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-and-queer-pride-month-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The uprising at the Stonewall Inn in June, 1969, sparked a liberation movement &#8212; a call to action that continues to inspire us to live up to our Nation&#8217;s promise of equality, liberty, and justice for all.&#160; Pride is a time to recall the trials the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer (LGBTQ+) community has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The uprising at the Stonewall Inn in June, 1969, sparked a liberation movement &#8212; a call to action that continues to inspire us to live up to our Nation&#8217;s promise of equality, liberty, and justice for all.&nbsp; Pride is a time to recall the trials the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer (LGBTQ+) community has endured and to rejoice in the triumphs of trailblazing individuals who have bravely fought &#8212; and continue to fight &#8212; for full equality. &nbsp;Pride is both a jubilant communal celebration of visibility and a personal celebration of self-worth and dignity.&nbsp; This Pride Month, we recognize the valuable contributions of LGBTQ+ individuals across America, and we reaffirm our commitment to standing in solidarity with LGBTQ+ Americans in their ongoing struggle against discrimination and injustice.</p>



<p>The LGBTQ+ community in America has achieved remarkable progress since Stonewall.&nbsp; Historic Supreme Court rulings in recent years have struck down regressive laws, affirmed the right to marriage equality, and secured workplace protections for LGBTQ+ individuals in every State and Territory.&nbsp; The Matthew Shepard and James Byrd, Jr. Hate Crimes Prevention Act broadened the definition of hate crimes to include crimes motivated by sexual orientation or gender identity.&nbsp; Members of the LGBTQ+ community now serve in nearly every level of public office &#8212; in city halls and State capitals, Governors&#8217; mansions and the halls of the Congress, and throughout my Administration. &nbsp;Nearly 14&nbsp;percent of my 1,500 agency appointees identify as LGBTQ+, and I am particularly honored by the service of Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg, the first openly LGBTQ+ person to serve in the Cabinet, and Assistant Health Secretary Dr. Rachel Levine, the first openly transgender person to be confirmed by the Senate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For all of our progress, there are many States in which LGBTQ+ individuals still lack protections for fundamental rights and dignity in hospitals, schools, public accommodations, and other spaces.&nbsp; Our Nation continues to witness a tragic spike in violence against transgender women of color.&nbsp; LGBTQ+ individuals &#8212; especially youth who defy sex or gender norms &#8212; face bullying and harassment in educational settings and are at a disproportionate risk of self-harm and death by suicide.&nbsp; Some States have chosen to actively target transgender youth through discriminatory bills that defy our Nation&#8217;s values of inclusivity and freedom for all.</p>



<p>Our Nation also continues to face tragic levels of violence against transgender people, especially transgender women of color. &nbsp;And we are still haunted by tragedies such as the Pulse Nightclub shooting in Orlando. &nbsp;Ending violence and discrimination against the LGBTQ+ community demands our continued focus and diligence. &nbsp;As President, I am committed to defending the rights of all LGBTQ+ individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My Administration is taking historic actions to finally deliver full equality for LGBTQ+ families. &nbsp;On my first day in office, I signed an Executive Order charging Federal agencies to fully enforce all Federal laws that prohibit discrimination on the basis of gender identity or sexual orientation. &nbsp;As a result, the Federal Government has taken steps to prevent discrimination against LGBTQ+ people in employment, health care, housing, lending, and education.&nbsp; I also signed an Executive Order affirming all qualified Americans will be able to serve in the Armed Forces of the United States &#8212; including patriotic transgender Americans who can once again proudly and openly serve their Nation in uniform &#8212; and a National Security Memorandum that commits to supporting LGBTQ+ Federal employees serving overseas.&nbsp; My Administration is also working to promote and protect LGBTQ+ human rights abroad.&nbsp; LGBTQ+ rights are human rights, which is why my Administration has reaffirmed America&#8217;s commitment to supporting those on the front lines of the equality and democracy movements around the world, often at great risk.&nbsp; We see you, we support you, and we are inspired by your courage to accept nothing less than full equality.</p>



<p>While I am proud of the progress my Administration has made in advancing protections for the LGBTQ+ community, I will not rest until full equality for LGBTQ+ Americans is finally achieved and codified into law.&nbsp; That is why I continue to call on the Congress to pass the Equality Act, which will ensure civil rights protections for LGBTQ+ people and families across our country. &nbsp;And that is why we must recognize emerging challenges, like the fact that many LGBTQ+ seniors, who faced discrimination and oppression throughout their lives, are isolated and need support and elder care.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During LGBTQ+ Pride Month, we recognize the resilience and determination of the many individuals who are fighting to live freely and authentically.&nbsp; In doing so, they are opening hearts and minds, and laying the foundation for a more just and equitable America.&nbsp; This Pride Month, we affirm our obligation to uphold the dignity of all people, and dedicate ourselves to protecting the most vulnerable among us.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2021 as Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer Pride Month.&nbsp; I call upon the people of the United States to recognize the achievements of the LGBTQ+ community, to celebrate the great diversity of the American people, and to wave their flags of pride high.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-Harris Administration Champions LGBTQ+ Equality and Marks Pride Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/01/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-champions-lgbtq-equality-and-marks-pride-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden issued a proclamation affirming June 2021 as Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer (LGBTQ+) Pride Month, marking a time a time of hope, progress, and promise for LGBTQ+ Americans across the country. After four years of relentless attacks on LGBTQ+ rights, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken historic actions to accelerate the march&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden issued a proclamation affirming June 2021 as Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer (LGBTQ+) Pride Month, marking a time a time of hope, progress, and promise for LGBTQ+ Americans across the country. After four years of relentless attacks on LGBTQ+ rights, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken historic actions to accelerate the march toward full LGBTQ+ equality. From protecting the civil rights of every LGBTQ+ American, enabling all qualified Americans – including transgender Americans – to serve their country in uniform, ensuring that LGBTQ+ Americans are leaders at every level of the federal government, to protecting and defending the human rights of LGBTQ+ persons around the world, the Biden-Harris Administration is a consistent and reliable partner in the fight for equality at home and abroad.</p>



<p>Too many LGBTQ+ Americans across our nation continue facing discrimination and hate, especially LGBTQ+ people of color and transgender Americans, and some states are attempting to roll back the clock on equality with discriminatory bills that target LGBTQ+ people and families. The Biden-Harris Administration reaffirms that no one should face discrimination or harassment because of who they are or whom they love. As President Biden said during his first joint address to Congress, the President has the back of LGBTQ+ people across the country and will continue fighting for full equality for every American – including through continuing to urge the U.S. Senate to pass the Equality Act and provide overdue civil rights protections to LGBTQ+ people and families across the country. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This Pride Month, the Biden-Harris Administration celebrates the historic progress made towards LGBTQ+ equality since President Biden took office, including:</p>



<p><strong>Signing One of the Most Comprehensive Executive Orders in History on LGBTQ+ Rights on His First Day in Office.&nbsp;</strong>Within hours of taking the oath of office, President Biden signed an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-preventing-and-combating-discrimination-on-basis-of-gender-identity-or-sexual-orientation/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;Preventing and Combating Discrimination on the Basis of Gender Identity or Sexual Orientation. The Executive Order established that it is the official policy of the Biden-Harris Administration to prevent and combat discrimination against LGBTQ+ individuals, and to fully enforce civil rights laws to prevent discrimination on the basis of gender identity or sexual orientation. The President directed all federal agencies to implement fully all federal laws that prevent discrimination on the basis of sex, to include sexual orientation and gender identity. This Executive Order is one of the most consequential policies for LGBTQ+ Americans ever signed by a U.S. President. As a result of that Order, agencies have already taken key steps to advance LGBTQ+ equality.</p>



<ul><li>The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS)&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/05/10/hhs-announces-prohibition-sex-discrimination-includes-discrimination-basis-sexual-orientation-gender-identity.html">announced</a>&nbsp;it will interpret and enforce Section 1557 of the Affordable Care Act and Title IX to prevent discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>To address the pervasive discrimination LGBTQ+ families continue to face in housing, the Department of Housing and Urban Development&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/hud_no_21_021">announced</a>&nbsp;it will interpret the Fair Housing Act to prevent discrimination in housing and rental assistance against LGBTQ+ people. HUD will require state and local jurisdictions who receive funding through its Fair Housing Assistance Program to apply the same protections.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>In response to the continuing discrimination many LGBTQ+ individuals face in credit and lending services, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau&nbsp;<a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/about-us/newsroom/cfpb-clarifies-discrimination-by-lenders-on-basis-of-sexual-orientation-and-gender-identity-is-illegal/">announced</a>&nbsp;that it will enforce against discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity in credit and lending services.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The Department of Justice&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/crt/page/file/1383026/download">issued new guidance</a>&nbsp;to agencies clarifying that Title IX sex discrimination protection includes protection on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>To ensure that LGBTQ+ Veterans are treated with dignity and respect, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) has undertaken an&nbsp;<a href="https://blogs.va.gov/VAntage/85152/secretary-orders-review-vas-transgender-policies/">agency-wide review</a>&nbsp;of its policies and practices to remove barriers that transgender veterans and their families face.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>To advance protections for incarcerated individuals who are transgender, the Department of Justice filed a statement of interest in litigation clarifying that it is DOJ’s position that transgender prisoners should be assigned to housing that aligns with their gender identity, and that transgender prisoners should receive medically-necessary gender affirming care.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Launching a Whole-Of-Government Initiative to Advance Equity and Justice for Underserved Communities, Including LGBTQ+ Communities.&nbsp;</strong>On his first day in office, President Biden signed a historic&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-advancing-racial-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through-the-federal-government/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;establishing a cross-government initiative to advance equity and justice for communities who have been left behind, underserved, or discriminated against by federal policies, laws, and programs, including LGBTQ+ communities. The President directed all agencies to take steps to advance equity by taking comprehensive action to root out bias from federal programs and policies, engage with underserved communities, and ensure that federal resources equitably reach all Americans, including LGBTQ+ Americans.</p>



<p><strong>Enabling All Qualified Americans to Serve Their Country in Uniform.&nbsp;</strong>In his first week in office, President Biden&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/25/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-enabling-all-qualified-americans-to-serve-their-country-in-uniform/">signed</a>&nbsp;an Executive Order reversing the ban on openly transgender servicemembers serving in the Armed Forces, enabling all qualified Americans to serve their country in uniform. President Biden believes that gender identity should not be a bar to military service, America’s strength is found in its diversity, and an inclusive military strengthens our national security As a result of his Executive Order, the Department of Defense issued new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Releases/Release/Article/2557220/dod-announces-policy-updates-for-transgender-military-service/">policies</a>&nbsp;which prohibit discrimination against transgender servicemembers, provide a path for transgender servicemembers to access gender-affirming medical care, and require that all transgender servicemembers are treated with dignity and respect. Patriotic transgender servicemembers are once again able to openly and proudly serve our Nation in uniform.</p>



<p><strong>Advancing an Equitable Recovery from COVID-19 for LGBTQ+ Americans across the Country.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden knows that LGBTQ+ individuals and families have been disproportionately burdened by the COVID-19 health crisis and economic crisis. Even before COVID-19, LGBTQ+ Americans were more likely to be uninsured and unemployed, and were more likely to experience poverty, have a pre-existing condition, and experience food insecurity. These barriers have posed unique risks to the physical and financial health of LGBTQ+ people during this crisis. The President’s American Rescue Plan makes significant investments in an equitable recovery, and is helping LGBTQ+ families across the country recover from COVID-19 by:</p>



<ul><li>Addressing food insecurity among LGBTQ+ communities by increasing the value of nutrition assistance by 15 percent.</li><li>Advancing health equity for LGBTQ+ Americans, who remain more likely to be uninsured, by improving access to and affordability of health coverage through the Marketplace, and expanding mental health resources.</li><li>Supporting LGBTQ+ Americans, who are more likely to experience unemployment and continue to face discrimination in the job market, by extending unemployment insurance benefits critical to helping many families, including LGBTQ+ families, stay afloat.</li><li>Addressing the disproportionate rates of housing insecurity and homelessness faced by LGBTQ+ Americans, especially transgender youth, by expanding emergency rental assistance programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Signing and Leading Implementation of a Presidential Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex Persons Around the World.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/04/memorandum-advancing-the-human-rights-of-lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-queer-and-intersex-persons-around-the-world/">directed</a>&nbsp;all agencies engaged abroad to ensure that United States diplomacy and foreign assistance promote and protect the human rights of LGBTQ+ persons. His Memorandum establishes that it “shall be the policy of the United States to pursue an end to violence and discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, or sex characteristics, and to lead by the power of our example in the cause of advancing the human rights of LGBTQ+ persons around the world.” As previously&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-is-advancing-lgbtqi-human-rights-at-home-and-across-the-globe/">highlighted</a>&nbsp;by the White House, Departments and Agencies are already making progress in areas towards the goals outlined in the &nbsp;Presidential Memorandum, including: strengthen existing efforts to combat the criminalization by foreign governments of LGBTQ+ people and expand efforts to combat discrimination, homophobia, transphobia, and intolerance on the basis of LGBTQ+ status or conduct; protect vulnerable LGBTQ+ refugees and asylum seekers; help ensure the Federal Government has a swift and meaningful response to serious incidents that threaten the human rights of LGBTQ+ persons abroad; and build coalitions with like-minded nations to counter discrimination against LGBTQ+ people around the world.</p>



<p><strong>Establishing the White House Gender Policy Council to Advance Gender Equity and Equality.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden signed an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/08/executive-order-on-establishment-of-the-white-house-gender-policy-council/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;establishing the White House Gender Policy Council to advance gender equity and equality across the whole of the government, including by addressing barriers faced by LGBTQ+ people, in particular transgender women and girls, across our country. &nbsp;<br><br><strong>Ensuring Educational Environments are Free from Sex Discrimination and Protecting LGBTQ+ Students from Sexual Harassment.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden signed an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/08/executive-order-on-guaranteeing-an-educational-environment-free-from-discrimination-on-the-basis-of-sex-including-sexual-orientation-or-gender-identity/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;recommitting the Federal Government to guarantee educational environments free from sex discrimination, including sexual harassment and including discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity, and directing the Department of Education to review and as necessary consider revising agency actions that are inconsistent with that policy. The Executive Order charged the Department of Education with reviewing the significant rates at which students who identify as LGBTQ+ are subject to sexual harassment, including sexual violence.</p>



<p><strong>Signing a National Security Memorandum Supporting Federal Employees Serving Overseas, including LGBTQ+ Employees.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden signed a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/04/memorandum-revitalizing-americas-foreign-policy-and-national-security-workforce-institutions-and-partnerships/">National Security Memorandum</a>&nbsp;on Revitalizing America’s Foreign Policy and National Security Workforce, Institutions, and Partnerships. The Memorandum directs agencies to take steps to retain, develop, promote, and support LGBTQ+ and other national security employees, and employees with LGBTQ+ family members.<br><br><strong>Ensuring Transgender Americans Can Access Emergency Shelter That Dignifies and Respects Their Identity.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Housing and Urban Development&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/HUD_No_21_069">restored protections</a>&nbsp;for transgender individuals seeking emergency shelter and homeless services. HUD reaffirmed its commitment that no person be denied access to housing or other critical services because of their gender identity.<br><br><strong>Creating a Historically Diverse Cabinet and Administration.&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;The Biden-Harris Administration includes barrier-breaking LGBTQ+ leaders, including Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg, who is the first openly gay Cabinet Secretary confirmed by the U.S. Senate, and Assistant Secretary for Health Dr. Rachel Levine, who is the first openly transgender person ever confirmed by the U.S. Senate. President Biden has assembled the most diverse Administration in our Nation’s history, and is proud to serve alongside the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/29/fact-sheet-100-days-in-biden-harris-administration-makes-history-with-presidential-appointees/">14 percent</a>&nbsp;of all appointees who identify as lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer.</p>



<p><strong>Issuing the First White House Proclamation for Transgender Day of Visibility.&nbsp;</strong>On March 31, 2021 President Biden became the first U.S. President to issue a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/31/a-proclamation-on-transgender-day-of-visibility-2021/">proclamation</a>&nbsp;commemorating Transgender Day of Visibility. The proclamation honored and celebrated the achievements and resiliency of transgender individuals and communities, and recognized the generations of struggle, activism, and courage that have brought our country closer to full equality for transgender and gender non-binary people in the United States and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Ensuring Pride Flags Fly on U.S. Embassies Around the World. </strong>The State Department announced it will allow U.S. diplomatic outposts to fly the Pride flag on the same flagpole as the U.S. flag at their embassy or consulate, demonstrating that the United States will lead on LGBTQI+ human rights around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Announces New Actions to Build Black Wealth and Narrow the Racial Wealth Gap</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/01/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-new-actions-to-build-black-wealth-and-narrow-the-racial-wealth-gap/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One hundred years ago, the thriving Black community of Greenwood in Tulsa, Oklahoma, known as “Black Wall Street,” was ruthlessly attacked by a violent white supremacist mob. An estimated 300 Black Americans were killed and another 10,000 were left destitute and homeless. The destruction wrought on the Greenwood neighborhood and its families was followed by&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One hundred years ago, the thriving Black community of Greenwood in Tulsa, Oklahoma, known as “Black Wall Street,” was ruthlessly attacked by a violent white supremacist mob. An estimated 300 Black Americans were killed and another 10,000 were left destitute and homeless.</p>



<p>The destruction wrought on the Greenwood neighborhood and its families was followed by laws and policies that made recovery nearly impossible. The streets were redlined, locking Black Tulsans out of homeownership and access to credit. Federal highways built through the heart of Greenwood cut off families and businesses from economic opportunity. And chronic disinvestment by the federal government in Black entrepreneurs and small businesses denied Black Wall Street a fair shot at rebuilding. These are the stories of Greenwood, but they have echoes in countless Black communities across the country.<br><br>Because disparities in wealth compound like an interest rate, the disinvestment in Black families in Tulsa and across the country throughout our history is still felt sharply today. The median Black American family has thirteen cents for every one dollar in wealth held by White families.<br><br>Today, on the centennial of the Tulsa Race Massacre, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new steps to help narrow the racial wealth gap and reinvest in communities that have been left behind by failed policies. Specifically, the Administration is expanding access to two key wealth-creators – homeownership and small business ownership – in communities of color and disadvantaged communities.</p>



<p>The Administration will:</p>



<ul><li>Take action to address racial discrimination in the housing market, including by launching a first-of-its-kind interagency effort to address inequity in home appraisals, and conducting rulemaking to aggressively combat housing discrimination.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Use the federal government’s purchasing power to grow federal contracting with small disadvantaged businesses by 50 percent, translating to an additional $100 billion over five years, and helping more Americans realize their entrepreneurial dreams.<br>&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>The Administration is also releasing new information regarding President Biden’s American Jobs Plan proposals to create jobs and build wealth in communities of color:</p>



<ul><li>A new $10 billion Community Revitalization Fund to support community-led civic infrastructure projects that create innovative shared amenities, spark new local economic activity, provide services, build community wealth, and strengthen social cohesion.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>$15 billion for new grants and technical assistance to support the planning, removal, or retrofitting of existing transportation infrastructure that creates a barrier to community connectivity, including barriers to mobility, access, or economic development.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>A new Neighborhood Homes Tax Credit to attract private investment in the development and rehabilitation of affordable homes for low- and moderate-income homebuyers and homeowners.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>$5 billion for the Unlocking Possibilities Program, an innovative new grant program that awards flexible and attractive funding to jurisdictions that take steps to reduce needless barriers to producing affordable housing and expand housing choices for people with low or moderate incomes.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>$31 billion in small business programs that will increase access to capital for small businesses and provide mentoring, networking, and other forms of technical assistance to socially and economically disadvantaged businesses seeking to access federal contracts and participate in federal research and development investments.<br>&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Taking Action to End Racial Discrimination in the Housing Market.&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;The Biden-Harris Administration is announcing additional steps to end discrimination and bias in the housing market. More than 50 years since the Fair Housing Act’s passage, access to wealth through homeownership remains persistently unequal. In his first week in office, President Biden issued a memorandum directing the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to address discrimination in our housing market. Today, the Administration is announcing that it is taking critical steps towards realizing the President’s directive.&nbsp; HUD has now sent both its proposed rule on countering housing practices with discriminatory effects and its proposed interim final rule on the legal duty to Affirmatively Further Fair Housing to HUD’s Congressional authorizing committee in the Senate and the House of Representatives for review and will publish them in the Federal Register next week. These proposed rules will align federal enforcement practice with the congressional promise in the Fair Housing Act to end discrimination in housing and will collectively provide the legal framework for HUD to require private and public entities alike to rethink established practices that contribute to or perpetuate inequities.<br><br>Additionally, the Biden-Harris Administration is taking on discrimination in home appraisals. A&nbsp;<a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/devaluation-of-assets-in-black-neighborhoods/">2018 Brookings study</a>&nbsp;found that homes in majority-Black neighborhoods are often valued at tens of thousands of dollars less than comparable homes in similar—but majority-White—communities. And the crisis is worsening: a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-09-21/race-gap-in-home-appraisals-has-doubled-since-1980?sref=A1Z2GUXp">recent study</a>&nbsp;found that the gap between the appraised value of homes in predominantly White neighborhoods compared to comparable homes in predominantly Black and Latino neighborhoods nearly doubled between 1980 and 2015. The impact of these disparities in home appraisals can be sweeping, limiting homeowners’ ability to properly benefit from refinancing or re-selling their homes at higher valuations and thereby contributing to the already-sprawling racial wealth gap.<br><br>President Biden is charging Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Marcia Fudge with leading a first-of-its-kind interagency initiative to address inequity in home appraisals. The effort will seek to utilize, quickly, the many levers at the federal government’s disposal, including potential enforcement under fair housing laws, regulatory action, and development of standards and guidance in close partnership with industry and state and local governments, to root out discrimination in the appraisal and homebuying process. These are the kinds of policies and practices that keep Black families in Greenwood and across the nation from building generational wealth through homeownership.<br><br><strong>Using the Government’s Purchasing Power to Drive an Additional $100 Billion to Small Disadvantaged Business Owners.&nbsp;</strong>The federal government is the largest consumer of goods in the world, buying everything from software to elevator services to financial and asset management, Federal procurement is one of our most powerful tools to advance equity and build wealth in underserved communities.&nbsp;And yet, just roughly 10 percent of federal agencies’ total eligible contracting dollars typically go to small disadvantaged businesses (SDB), a category under federal law for which Black-owned, Latino-owned, and other minority-owned businesses are presumed to qualify. Increasing federal spending with these businesses will help more Americans realize their entrepreneurial dreams and help narrow racial wealth gaps. In 2019, for instance, the gap in business ownership between Black and Latino households, relative to White households, accounted for 25 percent of the overall racial wealth gap between these groups.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is launching an all-of-government effort to expand contracting opportunities for underserved small businesses across the country. At its center is a new goal: increasing the share of contracts going to small disadvantaged businesses by 50 percent by 2026—translating to an additional $100 billion to SDBs over the 5-year period. To achieve this goal, agencies will assess every available tool to lower barriers to entry and increase opportunities for small businesses and traditionally-underserved entrepreneurs to compete for federal contracts. The impact could be historic: all told, attainment of the new goal will represent the biggest increase in SDB contracting since data was first collected more than 30 years ago.<br><br><strong>Detailing the President’s Proposal for Historic Investments to Build Wealth and Opportunity More Equitably, Including in Communities of Color.&nbsp;</strong>Today the Biden-Harris Administration is also releasing new details of President Biden’s American Jobs Plan, which will make historic investments in building wealth and opportunity in Black and other communities of color. The American Jobs Plan will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Create a Community Revitalization Fund to Support Community-Led Civic Infrastructure.</strong>&nbsp;The American Jobs Plan calls for a new $10 billion Community Revitalization Fund based at the Department of Housing and Urban Development to support community-led civic infrastructure projects in urban, suburban, and rural areas that create innovative shared amenities, spark new local economic activity, provide services, build community wealth, and strengthen social cohesion.&nbsp;The Fund would be targeted to economically underdeveloped and underserved communities, including those, like Greenwood, that suffer from the effects of persistent poverty, historic economic disinvestment, and ongoing displacement of longtime residents.</li></ul>



<p>The Community Revitalization Fund will:</p>



<ul><li><em>Invest directly in community-led projects that benefit residents.</em>&nbsp;The Community Revitalization Fund will provide $500 million in planning grants and $9.5 billion in implementation funds to community-based organizations, non-profits, community development corporations (CDCs), and their partners, centering the community as direct beneficiaries and drivers of project outcomes. These grants will flow to persistent poverty counties, high-poverty census tracts, and areas both at risk of or rapidly gentrifying. Recognizing that a legacy of underinvestment may mean some communities lack capacity to build complex projects or apply for federal grants, the Fund will seek partnerships with philanthropy, community development financial institutions (CDFIs), and local government to provide technical assistance and capacity-building support.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><em>Activate vacant land and buildings to create community amenities.</em>&nbsp;The Community Revitalization Fund will support a wide range of projects, including: upgrading access to natural areas, adaptive reuse of vacant buildings and storefronts to provide low-cost space for services and community entrepreneurs (such as health centers, arts and cultural spaces, job training programs, business incubators, and community marketplaces), and removing toxic waste to create new parks, greenways, urban agriculture, and community gardens. The Fund will promote the best of American equitable and resilient design, advancing the Biden-Harris Administration’s Justice40 climate goals and building a strong link between past and future. This includes in-fill development that reknits areas damaged by urban renewal and the revitalization of commercial corridors with locally-owned businesses and services.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><em>Strengthen social cohesion and build community wealth.</em>&nbsp;The Community Revitalization Fund will prioritize projects that strengthen social cohesion through shared use and civic engagement, and build community wealth and equity for existing residents. The Fund will encourage innovative approaches to achieve those goals, including land acquisition, creation of new businesses and stronger connections to existing employment centers, establishment of community investment trusts and similar wealth-building models, and projects that provide for intercultural and intergenerational mixing.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><em>Spark new local economic activity and unlock private capital.</em>&nbsp;The Community Revitalization Fund will support projects that show potential to spark new local commercial activity and unlock private investment for further equitable development, with a strong vision of continued community benefit. The Fund will encourage collaboration with CDFIs to leverage additional resources, and integration with existing federal economic development resources and tax credits to drive upward community mobility. The Fund will also support pilot projects, tactical urbanism projects, pop-up spaces for local retail, and other smaller-scale interventions that build activity and opportunity for residents.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Retrofit Transportation Infrastructure to Reconnect Neighborhoods.</strong>Too often, past transportation investments meant to provide greater access instead divided low-income communities, displacing and disconnecting people from their homes, work, and families. Recognizing this history and committed to redressing it, President Biden proposes funding specifically for neighborhoods where historic transportation investments cut people off from jobs, schools, and businesses. This proposal will support the planning, removal, or retrofitting of existing transportation infrastructure that creates a barrier to community connectivity, including barriers to mobility, access, or economic development.</li></ul>



<p>Specifically, the Reconnecting Neighborhoods Program will provide $15 billion in new competitive grants for planning, technical assistance (TA) and capital investments:</p>



<ul><li><em>Planning and TA grants</em><em>.</em>&nbsp;These can be used for planning studies and public engagement activities to evaluate the feasibility of infrastructure removal or retrofitting, building organizational or community capacity, transportation planning, and identifying innovative solutions to infrastructure challenges, including reconnecting communities impacted by disruptive infrastructure or those lacking safe, reliable, and affordable transportation choices. It will prioritize grantmaking to historically disadvantaged, underserved and overburdened communities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><em>Capital grants</em><em>.</em>&nbsp;These may be used to support infrastructure construction, demolition, and all necessary feasibility and related planning activities, community partnerships, and anti-displacement and equitable neighborhood revitalization strategies including land banking and equitable transit-oriented development. The minimum grant size will be $5 million and will prioritize communities most impacted by past inequitable infrastructure development.</li></ul>



<p>The program will begin to correct past harms and reduce pollution, create more public and green spaces, support local businesses, increase job opportunities, and lay the groundwork for more equitable transit systems and affordable housing solutions. The “Highway to Boulevards” movement has already seen 18 U.S. cities either replace or commit to replace a freeway with more urban and accessible streets. Cities like Rochester, NY, have chosen to remove dividing highways and replace the highway with infrastructure that has revived and reconciled neighborhoods decades later. President Biden’s proposed investment will fund and accelerate reconnecting neighborhoods across the country.<br><br>In addition, the Department of Transportation will establish a new Thriving Communities program to support communities with eliminating persistent transportation barriers and increasing access to jobs, school, and businesses. This initiative seeks to invest $5 billion in historically marginalized communities and bring everyone to the table to ensure that more communities have clean, robust, and affordable transportation options, including high-quality transit, equitable neighborhood revitalization, and other enhancements to improve neighborhood quality of life and address climate change.</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Enact a New Neighborhood Homes Tax Credit.</u></strong>&nbsp;The American Jobs Plan calls for a new Neighborhood Homes Tax Credit to attract private investment in the development and rehabilitation of affordable homes for low- and moderate-income homebuyers and homeowners. These tax credits will increase homeownership opportunities and asset-building for underserved communities, reduce blight and vacant properties, and create thousands of good-paying jobs. The Neighborhood Homes Tax Credit will:<br>&nbsp;</li><li><em>Encourage investment in homes that cost more to redevelop than they can sell for on the open market.</em>&nbsp;Across the country, millions of homes are in poor condition with property values that are too low to support new construction or substantial renovation. Approximately 40 percent of U.S. housing stock is at least 50 years old and more than 15 million properties are vacant even as families struggle to find affordable housing. In many neighborhoods, these properties make it difficult to attract or retain local homebuyers, reducing property values and community wealth. Modeled after the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit and the New Markets Tax Credit, state housing finance agencies would receive an annual allocation of Neighborhood Homes Tax Credits based on population. Each state’s housing finance agency would then award tax credits to project sponsors—developers, lenders, or local governments—through a competitive application process. Sponsors would use the credits to raise investment capital for their projects, and the investors could claim the credits against their federal income tax when the homes are sold and occupied by eligible homebuyers. These tax credits would cover the difference between total development costs (including acquisition, rehabilitation, demolition, and construction) and the sales price. This would, for example, make it financially viable to spend $120,000 acquiring and rehabilitating a vacant property that would only sell for $100,000 on the open market by offering a $20,000 tax credit to cover the difference.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><em>Bolster homeownership rates for low- and moderate-income homebuyers in underserved communities, while protecting against gentrification.</em>&nbsp;The U.S. is home to stark and persistent disparities in homeownership and wealth. Across the country, just 49 percent of Hispanic Americans and 45 percent of Black Americans own their own homes, compared to 74 percent of White Americans. Hispanic and Black households also have just a fraction of the wealth of their White counterparts. As home prices rise, the Neighborhood Homes Tax Credit will make a generational investment in homeownership affordability. Specifically, only homes that are located in census tracts with poverty rates of at least 130 percent of the area poverty rate, median family income below 80 percent of area median income, and median home values lower than the area median value are eligible for the credit. This covers approximately 1 in 4 census tracts nationwide – the most underserved communities in America. Homes that are redeveloped using the credit may only sell for four times the area median family income, and homebuyers cannot have incomes exceeding 140 percent of the area median family income. This will enable low- and moderate-income buyers – including homebuyers of color – to purchase their own homes and build wealth.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Incentivize Ending Exclusionary Zoning and Expanding Housing Choices.</strong>&nbsp;Exclusionary zoning laws – like minimum lot sizes, mandatory parking requirements, and prohibitions on multifamily housing – inflate housing and construction costs and lock families out of neighborhoods with more opportunities. In the American Jobs Plan, President Biden is calling on Congress to enact the Unlocking Possibilities Program, an innovative, new $5 billion competitive grant program that awards flexible and attractive funding to jurisdictions that take concrete steps to eliminate needless barriers to producing affordable housing and expand housing choices for people with low or moderate incomes.</li></ul>



<p>The fund has several key features to support locally-led efforts to advance zoning reforms:</p>



<ul><li>Grant program for community engagement, technical assistance and analysis that will help communities identify the most powerful levers to produce more affordable housing;</li><li>Investment and incentives to implement land-use and zoning policies that remove needless barriers to needed housing; and</li><li>Extensive evaluation and development agenda to identify the policy changes that most effectively encourage affordable housing production.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Communities that qualify for implementation and investment awards will have access to flexible funding that help support public services in neighborhoods where new affordable housing is being developed and that benefit all community members. The goal of these efforts will be to increase the production of affordable housing, expanding access to good jobs and powering inclusive economic growth.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Invest $31 Billion to Scale Up Efforts to Support Minority-Owned Small Businesses.</strong> Too many small businesses owned by people of color struggle to access loans and federal programs that can help them grow and succeed.  President Biden has proposed a historic effort to tackle these persistent challenges and empower small business creation and expansion in communities of color. Specifically, the President’s American Jobs Plan will invest $30 billion in new Small Business Administration (SBA) initiatives that will reduce barriers to small business ownership and success.  These initiatives will increase access to capital by establishing a new direct loan program for the smallest businesses, developing new loan products to support small manufacturers and businesses that invest in clean energy, and launching a new Small Business Investment Corporation that will make early stage equity investments in small businesses with priority for those owned by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals. The American Jobs Plan will also invest billions of dollars in SBA technical assistance programs that incubate and offer mentoring and technical assistance to 8(a) firms, reinforce the American subcontracting network to create pathways to prime contracting, encourage Fortune 500 firms to diversify their procurements, and bring more socially and economically disadvantaged businesses into federal research and development programs.  These investments will also include an innovative new $1 billion grant program through the Minority Business Development Agency that will help minority-owned manufacturers access private capital.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at the 153rd National Memorial Day Observance</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/05/31/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-153rd-national-memorial-day-observance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 20:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Arlington National CemeteryArlington, Virginia 10:34 A.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Madam Vice President, Secretary Austin, Secretary McDonough, General Milley, Gold Star families, my fellow Americans &#8212; we’re gathered at this sacred place in this solemn hour to engage in the most fundamental of undertakings: the rite of remembrance.&#160;We remember those who gave their all in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Arlington National Cemetery<br>Arlington, Virginia</p>



<p>10:34 A.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Madam Vice President, Secretary Austin, Secretary McDonough, General Milley, Gold Star families, my fellow Americans &#8212; we’re gathered at this sacred place in this solemn hour to engage in the most fundamental of undertakings: the rite of remembrance.<br>&nbsp;<br>We remember those who gave their all in the service of America, in the service of freedom, in the service of justice.&nbsp; We remember their sacrifice, their valor, and their grace.&nbsp; We remember their smiles; their loves; their laughter; their essential, vibrant, and transcendent humanity.<br>&nbsp;<br>For while we stand amid monuments of stone, we must never forget that each of these markers, for those known and unknown, here at Arlington and far beyond represent a precious life: a son, a daughter, a mother, a spouse, a brother, a sister, a friend, a neighbor.<br>&nbsp;<br>To those who mourn a loved one today: Jill and I have some idea how you’re feeling.&nbsp; Our losses are not the same, but that black hole you feel in your chest &#8212; as if it’s going to suck you into it &#8212; we get.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know the incredible pride you felt seeing your loved one wear the uniform of our country, and the pride they felt wearing it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our son Beau’s service in the Delaware Army National Guard unit, the year he spent deployed in Iraq, was one of the things that he was most proud of in life.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Yesterday marked the anniversary of his death.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a hard time &#8212; a hard time of year for me and our family, just like it is for so many of you.&nbsp; It can hurt to remember, but the hurt is how we feel and how we heal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I always feel Beau close to me on Memorial Day.&nbsp; I know exactly where I need to be: right here, honoring our fallen heroes.&nbsp; Because through pain and anguish of his loss, I remember the pride on his face the day I pinned those bars on his shoulders.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>To all of you who are fighting with the fresh pain of loss, as hard as it is to believe, I promise you this: The day will come when the image of your loved one will bring a smile to your lips before it brings a tear to your eyes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Bible teaches, “Blessed are they that mourn, for they shall be comforted.”&nbsp; That comfort, that reassurance can be a long time in coming, but it will come &#8212; I promise you.&nbsp; And my prayer for all of you is that that day will come sooner rather than later.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We all know Memorial Day origins lie in the wake of the Civil War &#8212; a war for the freedom of all.&nbsp; A war for union.&nbsp; A war for liberty and for the preservation of the Constitution.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In calling for such today, General John Logan, commander of the Grand Army of the Republic, issued General Order Number 11.&nbsp; He directed the nation set aside a day to honor, and I quote, “those who died in defense of their country during the late rebellion and whose bodies now lie in almost every city, village, and hamlet churchyard throughout the land.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so we have and so we do again today, in our time, where the children of sacrifice made by a long line of American servicemembers, each a link in that chain of honor.&nbsp; We live by the light of the flame of liberty they kept burning.&nbsp; We’re free because they were brave.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here on these gentle, rolling green hills and across America and around the globe lie buried the heroes of the greatest experiment the world has ever known, ever seen.&nbsp; The experiment bears the noble name: The United States of America.<br>&nbsp;<br>Women and men, all those we honor today, gave their lives for their country, but they live forever in our hearts &#8212; forever proud, forever honorable, forever American.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They are &#8212; they are the sentinels of liberty, defenders of the downtrodden, liberators of nations.&nbsp; And still today, Americans stand watch around the world, often at their great personal peril.<br>&nbsp;<br>War and conflict, death and loss are not relics of our American history; they’re a part of Americans’ story.&nbsp; Here in Arlington lie heroes who gave what President Lincoln called “the last full measure of devotion.”<br>&nbsp;<br>They did not only die at Gettysburg or in Flanders Field or on the beaches of Normandy, but in the mountains of Afghanistan, the deserts of Iraq in the last 20 years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Section 60 &#8212; when I walk through it, it reminds me of the cost of war.&nbsp; Hundreds of graves &#8212; hundreds of graves are here from recent conflicts.&nbsp; Hundreds of patriots gave their all, each &#8212; each of them of the leaving behind a family who live with their pain and their absence every single day.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to assure each of those families: We will never forget what you gave to our country.&nbsp; We will never fail to honor your sacrifice.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Each day &#8212; starting when I was Vice President of the United States &#8212; I carry in my pocket a number of troops killed during the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq.&nbsp; Not an approximation, not rounded-off numbers &#8212; they each leave behind an entire community and family.&nbsp;&nbsp; And today, that number is 7,036 &#8212; 7,036 fallen angels who have lost their lives in these conflicts.<br>&nbsp;<br>And on this Memorial Day, we honor their legacy and their sacrifice.&nbsp; Duty, honor, country &#8212; they lived for it, they died for it.&nbsp; And we, as a nation, are eternally grateful.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, America has been forged in the battle and the fires of war.&nbsp; Our freedom and the freedom of innumerable others has been secured by young men and women who answered the call of history and gave everything in the service of an idea: the idea of America.<br>&nbsp;<br>It’s the greatest idea in the long history of humankind.&nbsp; An idea that we&#8217;re all created equal in the image of Almighty God.&nbsp; That we&#8217;re all entitled to dignity, as my father would say, and respect, decency, and honor.&nbsp; Love of neighbor.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not empty words, but the vital, beating heart of our nation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that democracy must be defended at all costs, for democracy makes all this possible.&nbsp; Democracy &#8212; that&#8217;s the soul of America, and I believe it&#8217;s a soul worth fighting for, and so do you; a soul worth dying for.&nbsp; Heroes who lie in eternal peace in this beautiful place, this sacred place, they believed that too.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The soul of America is animated by the perennial battle between our worst instincts &#8212; which we&#8217;ve seen of late &#8212; and our better angels.&nbsp; Between “Me first” and “We the People.”&nbsp; Between greed and generosity, cruelty and kindness, captivity and freedom.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Americans of Lexington and Concord, of New Orleans, Gettysburg, the Argonne, Iwo Jima and Normandy, Korea and Vietnam, Afghanistan and Iraq, and thousands of places in between &#8212; these Americans weren’t fighting for dictators; they were fighting for democracy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They weren&#8217;t fighting to exclude or to enslave; they were fighting to build and broaden and liberate.&nbsp; They weren&#8217;t fighting for self; they were fighting for the soul of the nation, for liberty and simple fair play &#8212; simple fair play and decency.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, as we remember their sacrifice, we remind ourselves of our duty to their memory, to the future they fought for.&nbsp; We owe the honored dead a debt we can never fully repay.&nbsp; We owe them our whole souls.&nbsp; We owe them our full best efforts to perfect the Union for which they died.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We owe them the work of our hands and our hearts, to make real the promise of a nation founded on the proposition that all of us &#8212; all of us &#8212; all of us are created equal and deserve to be treated that way throughout our lives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Democracy is more than a form of government.&nbsp; It’s a way of being; it’s a way of seeing the world.&nbsp; Democracy means the rule of the people &#8212; the rule of the people.&nbsp; Not the rule of monarchs, not the rule of the moneyed, not the rule of the mighty &#8212; literally, the rule of the people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The lives of billions, from antiquity to our own hour, have been shaped by the battle between aspirations of the many and the greed of the few.&nbsp; Between people’s right to self-determination and the self-seeking of the dictator.&nbsp; Between dreams of democracy and appetites for autocracy, which we&#8217;re seeing around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our troops have fought this battle on fields around the world, but also the battle of our time.&nbsp; And the mission falls to each of us, each and every day.&nbsp; Democracy itself is in peril, here at home and around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we do now &#8212; what we do now, how we honor the memory of the fallen, will determine whether or not democracy will long endure.&nbsp; We all take it for granted.&nbsp; We think we learned in school. &nbsp;You have to &#8212; every generation has to fight for it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, look, it&#8217;s the biggest question: Whether a system that prizes the individual, that bends towards liberty, that gives everybody a chance at prosperity &#8212; whether that system can and will prevail against powerful forces that wish it harm.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>All that we do in our common life as a nation is part of that struggle.&nbsp; The struggle for democracy is taking place around the world &#8212; democracy and autocracy.&nbsp; The struggle for decency and dignity &#8212; just simple decency.&nbsp; The struggle for posterity &#8212; prosperity and progress.&nbsp; And, yes, the struggle for the soul of America itself.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, you all know it: Democracy thrives when the infrastructure of democracy is strong; when people have the right to vote freely and fairly and conveniently; when a free and independent press pursues the truth, founded on facts, not propaganda; when the rule of law applies equally and fairly to every citizen, regardless of where they come from or what they look like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Coughs.)&nbsp; Excuse me.<br>&nbsp;<br>Wherever Americans are, there &#8212; there is democracy: churches and synagogues and mosques, neighborhoods and coffee shops and diners, bleachers at kids’ baseball or soccer games, libraries and parks.&nbsp; Democracy begins and grows in the open heart and the impetus to come together for a common cause.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I might note, parenthetically: Thank you, TAPS.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what you do.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s where it will be preserved.&nbsp; For empathy is the fuel of democracy.&nbsp; Let me say that again: Empathy &#8212; empathy is the fuel of democracy, a willingness to see each other &#8212; not as enemies, neighbors. &nbsp;Even when we disagree, to understand what the other is going through.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>To state the obvious: Our democracy is imperfect.&nbsp; It always has been.&nbsp; But Americans of all backgrounds, races, creeds, gender identities, sexual orientations, have long spilled their blood to defend our democracy.&nbsp; The diversity of our country and our arm- &#8212; and of our armed services is and always has been an incredible strength.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And generation after generation of American heroes have signed up to be part of the fight because they understand the truth that lives in every American heart: that liberation, opportunity, justice are far more likely to come to pass in a democracy than an autocracy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If every person is sacred, then every person&#8217;s rights are sacred.&nbsp; Individual dignity; individual worth; individual sanctity; the right to life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.&nbsp; We say those words so often, but think of it: the right to vote, the right to rise in a world as far as your talent can take you, unlimited by unfair barriers of privilege and power &#8212; such are the principles of democracy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So how would you put these noble principles into practice?&nbsp; How do we do that?&nbsp; How do we make the idea real, or as close to real as we can make it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This nation was built on an idea &#8212; the only nation in the world built on an idea.&nbsp; Every other nation was built on ethnicity, geography, religion, et cetera.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We were built on an idea: the idea of liberty and opportunity for all.&nbsp; We have never fully realized that aspiration of our founding, but every generation has opened the door a little wider, and every generation has opened it wider and wider to be more inclusive, to include those who have been excluded before.&nbsp; It’s a mission handed down generation to generation: the work of perfecting our union.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In 1830, when we were a young nation, dis-unionists put their sectional interests ahead of the common good.&nbsp; A great senator, Daniel Webster, rose in the Capitol to defend the Union.&nbsp; To him, we were not just a collection of competing forces, but a coherent whole.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>His cry, first uttered just across the Potomac in the Capitol, resonates even now.&nbsp; He stood on the floor and he said, “Liberty and Union, now on forever, one and inseparable.”&nbsp; Liberty and Union.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>More than 142 years later, when I first came to the United States Senate &#8212; at a time when our country was so deeply divided over Vietnam, the struggle of civil rights, the fight over women&#8217;s rights &#8212; I had the notion that my first task, as I stood to make my first speech on the floor of the Senate &#8212; it all of a sudden hit me: I&#8217;m standing where Daniel Webster had stood; his desk was next to mine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I was struck by the weight of history, as corny as it sounds, by the legacy of the work we&#8217;re charged to carry forward: liberty and union, now and forever.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now as then, unity is essential to life; liberty and the pursuit of happiness.&nbsp; And so we remember those who gave their all in the cause of unity, in the cause of a nation that endures because of them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We must honor their sacrifice by sustaining the best of America, while honestly confronting all that we must do to make our nation fuller, freer, and more just.&nbsp; We must remember that we may find the light and the wisdom and, yes, the courage to move forward &#8212; in the words of that great hymn, fight as they “nobly fought of old.”<br>&nbsp;<br>For in remembrance lies not just our history, but our hope.&nbsp; Not just our solemn remembrance, but our renewed purpose.&nbsp; Not just our solace, but our strength.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This Memorial Day, remember that not all of us are called to make the ultimate sacrifice.&nbsp; We all are called, by God and by history and by conscience, to make our nation free and fair, just and strong, noble and whole.<br>&nbsp;<br>To this battle, may we now dedicate our souls, that our work may prove worthy of the blood of our fallen.&nbsp; For this work &#8212; the work of democracy &#8212; is the work of our time, and for all time.&nbsp; And if we do our duty, then ages still to come will look back on us and say that we too kept the faith.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s nothing more important, nothing more sacred, nothing more American than keeping the faith.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>May God bless the United States of America.&nbsp; And may the light perpetually shine upon the fallen.&nbsp; May God bring comfort to their families.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops, today and always.&nbsp; God bless you all.<br>&nbsp;<br>10:56 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Day Of Remembrance: 100 Years After The 1921 Tulsa Race Massacre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/31/a-proclamation-on-day-of-remembrance-100-years-after-the-1921-tulsa-race-massacre/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 15:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One hundred years ago, a violent white supremacist mob raided, firebombed, and destroyed approximately 35 square blocks of the thriving Black neighborhood of Greenwood in Tulsa, Oklahoma. Families and children were murdered in cold blood. Homes, businesses, and churches were burned. In all, as many as 300 Black Americans were killed, and nearly 10,000 were&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One hundred years ago, a violent white supremacist mob raided, firebombed, and destroyed approximately 35 square blocks of the thriving Black neighborhood of Greenwood in Tulsa, Oklahoma. Families and children were murdered in cold blood. Homes, businesses, and churches were burned. In all, as many as 300 Black Americans were killed, and nearly 10,000 were left destitute and homeless. Today, on this solemn centennial of the Tulsa Race Massacre, I call on the American people to reflect on the deep roots of racial terror in our Nation and recommit to the work of rooting out systemic racism across our country.</p>



<p>Before the&nbsp;Tulsa Race Massacre, Greenwood was a thriving Black community that had grown into a proud economic and cultural hub. At its center was Greenwood Avenue, commonly known as Black Wall Street. Many of Greenwood&#8217;s 10,000 residents were Black sharecroppers who fled racial violence after the Civil War.</p>



<p>In the decades following the Civil War and Reconstruction, Greenwood became a place where Black Americans were able to make a new start and secure economic progress despite the continued pain of institutional and overt racism. The community was home to a growing number of prominent&nbsp;Black entrepreneurs as well as working-class Black families who shared a commitment to social activism and economic opportunity. As Greenwood grew, Greenwood Avenue teemed with successful Black-owned businesses, including restaurants, grocery stores, hotels, and offices for doctors, lawyers, and dentists. The community also maintained its own school system, post office, a savings and loan institution, hospital, and bus and taxi service.</p>



<p>Despite rising Jim Crow systems and the reemergence of the Ku Klux Klan, Greenwood&#8217;s economic prosperity grew, as did its citizens&#8217; demands for equal rights. This made the community a source of pride for many Black Americans. It also made the neighborhood and its families a target of white supremacists. In 2 days, a violent mob tore down the hard-fought success of Black Wall Street that had taken more than a decade to build.</p>



<p>In the years that followed, the destruction caused by the mob was followed by laws and policies that made recovery nearly impossible. In the aftermath of the attack, local ordinances were passed requiring new construction standards that were prohibitively expensive, meaning many Black families could not rebuild. Later, Greenwood was redlined by mortgage companies and deemed &#8220;hazardous&#8221; by the Federal Government so that Black homeowners could not access home loans or credit on equal terms. And in later decades, Federal investment, including Federal highway construction, tore down and cut off parts of the community. The attack on Black families and Black wealth in Greenwood persisted across generations.</p>



<p>The Federal Government must reckon with and acknowledge the role that it has played in stripping wealth and opportunity from Black communities. The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to acknowledging the role Federal policy played in Greenwood and other Black communities and addressing longstanding racial inequities through historic investments in the economic security of children and families, programs to provide capital for small businesses in economically disadvantaged areas, including minority-owned businesses, and ensuring that infrastructure projects increase opportunity, advance racial equity and environmental justice, and promote affordable access.</p>



<p>A century later, the fear and pain from the devastation of Greenwood is still felt. As Viola Fletcher, a 107-year-old survivor of the Tulsa Race Massacre courageously testified before the Congress recently, &#8220;I will never forget the violence of the white mob when we left our home. I still see Black men being shot, Black bodies lying in the street. I still smell smoke and see fire. I still see Black businesses being burned. I still hear airplanes flying overhead. I hear the screams. I have lived through the massacre every day. Our country may forget this history, but I cannot.&#8221;</p>



<p>With this proclamation, I commit to the survivors of the Tulsa Race Massacre, including Viola Fletcher, Hughes Van Ellis, and Lessie Benningfield Randle, the descendants of victims, and to this Nation that we will never forget. &nbsp;We honor the legacy of the Greenwood community, and of Black Wall Street, by reaffirming our commitment to advance racial justice through the whole of our government, and working to root out systemic racism from our laws, our policies, and our hearts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 31, 2021, a Day of Remembrance: 100 Years After The 1921 Tulsa Race Massacre. I call upon the people of the United&nbsp;States to commemorate the tremendous loss of life and security that occurred over those 2 days in 1921, to celebrate the bravery and resilience of those who survived and sought to rebuild their lives again, and commit together to eradicate systemic racism and help to rebuild communities and lives that have been destroyed by it.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at an Annual Memorial Day Service</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/05/30/remarks-by-president-biden-at-an-annual-memorial-day-service/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Veterans Memorial ParkNew Castle, Delaware 10:53 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; Good morning, everyone.&#160; It&#8217;s good to be here on this solemn occasion with so many friends &#8212; Governor Carney, Senator Carper, Attorney Keneral- [sic] &#8212; General Kathy Jennings.&#160; General Berry, it’s good to see you.&#160; And thank you for everything you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Veterans Memorial Park<br>New Castle, Delaware</p>



<p>10:53 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good to be here on this solemn occasion with so many friends &#8212; Governor Carney, Senator Carper, Attorney Keneral- [sic] &#8212; General Kathy Jennings.&nbsp; General Berry, it’s good to see you.&nbsp; And thank you for everything you do for the Delaware National Guard.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the way, I saw General Vavala this morning.&nbsp; He&#8217;s become not only a general, but a great friend.&nbsp; A great friend.&nbsp; He was at Beau’s memorial mass this morning.&nbsp; Thank you for being there, General.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, by the way, Hunter has had one shot &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; not two, and he&#8217;s just making sure everybody is okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me and my family, we&#8217;ve tried to participate in this event every year because it&#8217;s an important tradition in the Delaware community.&nbsp; Even last year, in those early dark days of the pandemic, Jill and I didn&#8217;t want to let Memorial Day pass like every other day.&nbsp; And there was no event here, but we came to lay a wreath at the plaza.&nbsp; It was the first time we did any sort of event since the lockdown had begun in March because we were determined &#8212; determined &#8212; to honor the fallen, to pay tribute to the women and men who braved every danger, who made the ultimate sacrifice for their country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because as a nation, we must always remember &#8212; always remember.&nbsp; We must remember the price that was paid for our liberties.&nbsp; We must remember the debt we owe those who have paid it, and the families left behind.&nbsp; My heart is torn in half by the grief.&nbsp; The communities were never whole again.</p>



<p>Folks, it&#8217;s also an important tradition in our family.&nbsp; As many of you know, this is a hard day for us.&nbsp; Six years ago today, Hunter lost his dad and I lost my son.&nbsp; It’s &#8212; the first year after his passing back in 2016, General Vavala did a great honor in inviting us to a ceremony renaming the Delaware National Guard headquarters in Beau’s honor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the way, I’d note that when Beau made the grade of major in &#8212; in Iraq, I said &#8212; I had been in and out of Iraq over 25 times.&nbsp; I said, “Beau, you&#8217;re now a field-grade officer.”&nbsp; He said, “Dad, I have no illusion who runs the United States Army.&nbsp;&nbsp;It’s the master sergeants.” (Laughter.)&nbsp; “They run the army.”</p>



<p>Well, I woke up that morning hearing Beau in my ear saying, “Not me, Dad.&nbsp; Today is not about me.&nbsp; It&#8217;s Memorial Day.&nbsp; You should be over at the bridge.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, if he were here, he would be here as well, paying his respects to all those &#8212; all those who gave so much for our country, and particularly honoring the Gold Star families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, a lot of time passes, but you all know better than I do &#8212; or as well as I do &#8212; that the moment that we celebrate it is the toughest day of the year.&nbsp; We&#8217;re honored, but it&#8217;s a tough day.&nbsp; It brings back everything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I can&#8217;t thank you enough for your continued service to the country.&nbsp; And your &#8212; your sons, your daughters, they live on in your hearts and in their children as well.&nbsp; And we have to carry on without them.&nbsp; But I know how hard it is for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beau didn’t die in the line of duty, but he was serving a Delaware National Guard unit in Iraq for a year.&nbsp; That was one of the proudest things he did in his life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you for allowing us to grieve together today.&nbsp; I know how much the loss hurts.&nbsp; I know the black hole that it leaves in the middle of your chest, that feels like you may get sucked into it and not come out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Greetings like this and gatherings help.&nbsp; And while I know nothing I can say to ease the pain, I just know that each year it gets a little bit &#8212; a little bit easier.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I promise you the day will come when the mention of the name of your son or daughter, husband, wife &#8212; they will, in fact, bring not a tear to your eye, but a smile to your lips.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks &#8212; and I hope that day comes sooner than later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, you know, despite all the pain, I know the pride you feel in the loved one and &#8212; that you lost and those who are still serving, the pride and the bravery in the service to our great American experiment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our military community is the solid spine of this country.&nbsp; It’s literally the spine of the nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on my first Memorial Day as Commander-in-Chief, I want to reaffirm my longstanding belief: We may have many obligations as a nation, but we only have one truly sacred obligation, and that&#8217;s to equip those we send into harm&#8217;s way with all they need, and care for them and their families when they re-ho- &#8212; when they return home, and when they don&#8217;t.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all of us who remain have a duty to renew our commitment to the fundamental values to our nation in their honor &#8212; the values that have inspired generation after generation to service and that so many have died to defend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Every day since I was Vice President, I&#8217;ve carried with me a card with the exact number of troops killed in our operations in Afghanistan and Iraq &#8212; not an approximation or a rounded number; an accounting of every life laid down for our country over the 20 years of war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, it&#8217;s 7,036 military members &#8212; fallen angels &#8212; have given the “last full measure of devotion,” as Lincoln termed it, in those modern conflicts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will never forget.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the guardians and we’re the guardians.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the guardians of us, and we&#8217;re the guardians of their legacy, inheritors of their mission, and the living testament to their sacrifice that is not going to be in vain.&nbsp; Because every American democracy endures.&nbsp; We have been tested, and we still will be surely tested further.&nbsp; But I know that we as a people are up to the task.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each generation of Americans receives the precious gift of liberty.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we work to share it with more people; to make our country more open, more free, more fair; to bring us closer &#8212; closer to making our American creed a reality for all Americans: that all women and men are created equal; that all women and men equally deserve to be treated with dignity; that all men and women deserve equal rights, equal protection to build up futures for their families, and hope and opportunity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The American creed is the connective tissue that binds us.&nbsp; It’s a long chain of patriots that come before us and those who will follow us in turn.&nbsp; That creed holds that the ideals that inspire people to service and that us &#8212; fill us with pride when we see our loved ones put on that uniform.&nbsp; And our progress toward that creed together, as one nation united and preserved through their sacrifices, is the best and strongest memorial to their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ladies and gentlemen, America is unique.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an idea.&nbsp; Unlike any other country in the world, it is formed based on an idea.&nbsp; Almost every other country is based on a creed, a religion, a geography, an ethnicity, but not us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re based on an idea: that we hold these truths to be self-evident that all men and women are created equal.&nbsp; We&#8217;re unique in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I had a long conversation &#8212; for two hours &#8212; recently with President Xi, making it clear to him that we could do nothing but speak out for human rights around the world because that&#8217;s who we are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll be meeting with President Putin in a couple of weeks in Geneva, making it clear that we will not &#8212; we will not stand by and let him abuse those rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, we’re unique in all of history.&nbsp; We really are.&nbsp; But those names that&#8217;s on that wall, and every other wall and tombstone in America of veterans, is the reason why we&#8217;re able to stand here.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t kid ourselves about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I hope &#8212; I hope that the nation comes together.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not Democrats or Republicans today.&nbsp; We&#8217;re Americans.&nbsp; We&#8217;re Americans &#8212; (applause) &#8212; who have given their lives.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s time we remind everybody who we are.</p>



<p>Thank you all for being here.&nbsp; May God bless you all, particularly the Gold Star families and survivors.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops, because they&#8217;re still out there.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>11:03 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Texas Senate Bill 7</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/29/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-texas-senate-bill-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 18:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Texas legislators put forth a bill that joins Georgia and Florida in advancing a state law that attacks the sacred right to vote. It’s part of an assault on democracy that we’ve seen far too often this year—and often disproportionately targeting Black and Brown Americans. It’s wrong and un-American. In the 21st&#160;century, we should&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Texas legislators put forth a bill that joins Georgia and Florida in advancing a state law that attacks the sacred right to vote. It’s part of an assault on democracy that we’ve seen far too often this year—and often disproportionately targeting Black and Brown Americans.</p>



<p>It’s wrong and un-American. In the 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century, we should be making it easier,&nbsp;not harder,&nbsp;for every eligible voter to vote.</p>



<p>I call again on Congress to pass&nbsp;the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act. And&nbsp;I&nbsp;continue to call&nbsp;on all Americans, of every party and persuasion, to stand up for&nbsp;our&nbsp;democracy and protect the right to vote and the integrity of our elections.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on the United States Response to Belarus’s Forced Diversion of Ryanair Flight and Continuing Attack on Fundamental Freedoms</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/28/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-united-states-response-to-belaruss-forced-diversion-of-ryanair-flight-and-continuing-attack-on-fundamental-freedoms/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Belarus’s forced diversion of a commercial Ryanair flight under false pretenses, traveling between two member states of the European Union, and the subsequent removal and arrest of Raman Pratasevich, a Belarusian journalist, are a direct affront to international norms.&#160;These events took place amid an escalating wave of repression by the Lukashenka regime against the aspirations&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Belarus’s forced diversion of a commercial Ryanair flight under false pretenses, traveling between two member states of the European Union, and the subsequent removal and arrest of Raman Pratasevich, a Belarusian journalist, are a direct affront to international norms.&nbsp;These events took place amid an escalating wave of repression by the Lukashenka regime against the aspirations of the people of Belarus for democracy and human rights.&nbsp;In response to the events of May 23 and the Lukashenka regime’s continuing attack on fundamental freedoms, the United States is taking the following actions:</p>



<ul><li>The United States has joined the public condemnation of the events of May 23 at the United Nations (UN), the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), the International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO), the Group of Seven (G7), and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO). We will continue to advocate at these bodies for action against the Lukashenka regime for its affront to international norms and undermining of democracy and human rights.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Department of State has issued a Level 4 Do Not Travel warning to U.S. citizens urging them not to travel to Belarus. The Federal Aviation Administration has issued a Notice to Airmen warning U.S. passenger carriers to exercise extreme caution when considering flying in Belarusian airspace.</li></ul>



<ul><li>On June 3, 2021, the United States will re-impose full blocking sanctions against nine Belarusian state-owned enterprises previously granted relief under a series of General Licenses by the Treasury Department. As a result of this measure, U.S. persons will be prohibited from engaging in transactions with these entities, their property, or their interests in property.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The United States, in coordination with the EU and other partners and Allies, is developing a list of targeted sanctions against key members of the Lukashenka regime associated with ongoing abuses of human rights and corruption, the falsification of the 2020 election, and the events of May 23.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Treasury Department will develop for the President’s review a new Executive Order that will provide the United States increased authorities to impose sanctions on elements of the Lukashenka regime, its support network, and those that support corruption, the abuse of human rights, and attacks on democracy.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Department of Justice, including the FBI, is working closely on this matter with our European counterparts.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The United States will suspend its discretionary application of the 2019 U.S-Belarus Air Services Agreement.</li></ul>



<p>We take these measures, together with our partners and Allies, to hold the regime accountable for its actions and to demonstrate our commitment to the aspirations of the people of Belarus. We call on Lukashenka to allow a credible international investigation into the events of May 23, immediately release all political prisoners, and enter into a comprehensive and genuine political dialogue with the leaders of the democratic opposition and civil society groups that leads to the conduct of free and fair Presidential elections under OSCE auspices and monitoring.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Addressing Service Members and their Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/05/28/remarks-by-president-biden-addressing-service-members-and-their-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 22:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19209</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base Langley-EustisHampton, Virginia 2:06 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I&#8217;ll let you guys get comfortable.&#160; (Laughs.) Colonel Ross &#8212; Clint, it&#8217;s wonderful to see you again.&#160; Thank you.&#160; When our path last crossed, as Jill said, you were serving in the White House.&#160; And I never thought we&#8217;d be standing here today doing what we&#8217;re&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Langley-Eustis<br>Hampton, Virginia</p>



<p>2:06 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let you guys get comfortable.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Colonel Ross &#8212; Clint, it&#8217;s wonderful to see you again.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; When our path last crossed, as Jill said, you were serving in the White House.&nbsp; And I never thought we&#8217;d be standing here today doing what we&#8217;re doing today.&nbsp;<br><br>And, Chief Master Sergeant Peterson, thank you, and to all members of your team who helped put this visit together today. It &#8212; it means a lot to Jill and me.&nbsp;<br><br>When I was Vice President and &#8212; as Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee, we tried to visit almost every major military base in the country, and as Vice President, around the world.&nbsp; And you are &#8212; simply stated, you are the backbone of the country.&nbsp; You&#8217;re the backbone of the country.&nbsp;<br><br>And although our son Beau was the Attorney General of the state of Delaware and had spent nine months in Kosovo trying to &#8212; as assistant U.S. attorney &#8212; trying to set up their criminal justice system.&nbsp; And I might say, I&#8217;ve &#8212; I can do this with the military; I&#8217;m going to brag about him a little bit &#8212; he&#8217;s the only foreigner to have a war memorial erected to him in Kosovo, just below <s>Fort</s> [Camp] Bondsteel and a highway &#8212; the first highway they built &#8212; named after him: the Joseph R. &#8220;Beau&#8221; Biden Memorial Highway.&nbsp; And he was a &#8212; he was proud as hell &#8212; as hell of his work.&nbsp;<br><br>But then he decided that &#8212; I kept on &#8212; he had contracted a &#8212; exposure to a virus in &#8212; when he was in Kosovo and in Turkey as a civilian.&nbsp; And he came back with a problem.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But he kept going to Walter Reed.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t understand why he was &#8212; they finally found &#8212; it&#8217;s called ankylosing spondylitis.&nbsp; They finally found a cure.&nbsp; It prevented him from having what they call &#8220;bamboo spine.&#8221;&nbsp; But he kept going back.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t understand why.&nbsp; I thought I knew why, but, Gov, he went back because he was trying to get an exemption to be able to join the United States Army.&nbsp; He was a sitting attorney general, and as all my colleagues &#8212; the Governor and Bobby Scott and Congresswoman &#8212; they all know is that when you do that &#8212; he joined the National Guard.&nbsp; And his unit deployed, and he wanted to deploy to Iraq with them.<br><br>So he literally had to give up his seat.&nbsp; Temporarily, he could not have any business done &#8212; as you National Guard folks know, you can&#8217;t do any business with a state if in fact &#8212; you&#8217;re now federal property.<br><br>And so, he gave up the seat and had the courage to appoint a fellow who had been a Republican attorney general as attorney general while he &#8212; while he went.&nbsp; The proudest thing he ever did &#8212; proudest thing he ever did.&nbsp;<br><br>And he &#8212; he spent a year in Iraq.&nbsp; And it was &#8212; it was one of the great honors of his life to do it.&nbsp; Won the Bronze Star, the Conspicuous Service Medal, and other awards &#8212; like many of you have &#8212; but he never, ever talked about it.<br><br>I remember we had an event at the White House &#8212; I shouldn&#8217;t be talking so much about my son, but I&#8217;m not going to apologize for it.&nbsp;<br><br>We had an event for Iraqi veterans at the White House and the President, without telling me and Jill, invited Beau to be there with another 75 soldiers and sailors and airmen.&nbsp; But he wouldn&#8217;t wear any of his decorations.&nbsp; And General Odierno called him &#8212; he served under him &#8212; and said, &#8220;Put them on now.&#8221;&nbsp; Swear to God.&nbsp; Walking out of the VP Residence, he wouldn&#8217;t put them on until then.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the first time I ever saw the Bronze Star on him.<br><br>But I&#8217;m just telling you that is &#8212; he&#8217;s like a lot of you.&nbsp; You do your duty.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t expect anything for it except be a little &#8212; have &#8212; get a little respect.&nbsp; It deserves so much more.&nbsp; You deserve so much more.<br><br>And, you know, I&#8217;m honored to be joined today by Governor Northam and by two great representatives of the Commonwealth: Congresswoman Luria and Congressman Scott.&nbsp; And I want to thank &#8212; thank you for all that you do to represent these service veterans, because they&#8217;re devoted to you; for the family members, the caregivers, survivors who call Virginia home.<br><br>I&#8217;m especially honored to share the stage with Brittney, and Jerdan, and Nathan, and Margrit Katherine.&nbsp; I love those barrettes in your hair, man.&nbsp; I tell you what &#8212; and look at her; she looks like she&#8217;s 19 years old, sitting there with her &#8212; like a little lady with her legs crossed.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Brittney, you’re doing triple duty: as a veteran, a military spouse, and a teacher.&nbsp; And, kids, thank you for being there for your mom.&nbsp;<br><br>I can remember all those times &#8212; and all of you remember, the spouses &#8212; when your husband or wife are deployed.&nbsp; Every morning, you wake up, you say that little extra prayer while you&#8217;re drinking your coffee.&nbsp; You just spend a little more time wondering.<br><br>And, you know, you only &#8212; you make up 1 percent of the population.&nbsp; You&#8217;re defending 99 percent of the rest of us.&nbsp; And we owe you.&nbsp; But you do your job so gracefully.&nbsp; You hardly ever say anything about what you&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;<br><br>But it matters.&nbsp; It matters to your families &#8212; for that time we&#8217;re sitting across from an empty chair at the kitchen table and the dining room table; for those birthdays or Christmases or holidays when they&#8217;re gone.<br><br>You know, there&#8217;s a famous English poet who said, &#8220;They also serve who only stand and wait.&#8221;&nbsp; &#8220;Also serve who only stand and wait.&#8221;<br><br>I know Major Beene &#8212; having been deployed to Afghanistan during the pandemic has only made everything much harder during the pandemic.&nbsp; I want to thank you so much &#8212; your entire family’s service to our country.&nbsp; You&#8217;re all incredible.&nbsp; You so underestimate how important you are.<br><br>And there&#8217;s nothing that Jill and I enjoy more than spending time with our troops here and abroad &#8212; if you&#8217;re stationed here United States or deployed around the world.<br><br>I&#8217;ve been in and out of Iraq and Afghanistan over 20 &#8212; I think it&#8217;s 25 times.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve seen &#8212; I wish everyone could see what you do when you&#8217;re there.&nbsp; I wish they could see every day how you saddle up, how you jump in that cockpit.&nbsp; Just see &#8212; no, you&#8217;re just &#8212; just doing your job.&nbsp;<br><br>Not to mention all of the troops I&#8217;ve had the chance to visit in the Middle East and Europe and the Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve traveled all over.&nbsp; Jill has traveled all over with me and her own visits to servicemembers in Iraq.&nbsp; I think she&#8217;s the only Second Lady ever to go into the middle of a warzone, because she wanted to be there and see you.<br><br>I always want you to know &#8212; always &#8212; that the issues you and your family are facing, we need to know how we can support you better.&nbsp; I mean it sincerely from the bottom of my heart: support you better.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s reason for that.&nbsp; I said, we Bidens are proud to have family in the military.&nbsp; And our son Beau&#8217;s service was &#8212; was among the achievements, as I said, he was most proud of.<br><br>My heart swelled to see him in uniform.&nbsp;<br><br>When I went into Iraq &#8212; I was there for five times &#8212; when he was in Baghdad.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; And I remember, the first time I saw him, his name was &#8220;Hunter.&#8221;&nbsp; I said, &#8220;What in the hell happened?&#8221;&nbsp; He said, &#8220;Dad, I didn&#8217;t want anybody to do me any special favors because my Vice President is my dad.&#8221;&nbsp; He got permission to put a different nametag on.<br><br>I also remember what it was like to listen to him talk about the needs that people had when he got back home.&nbsp; About all the folks he served with who came back with post-traumatic stress, and he was back being attorney general, having to deal with that.<br><br>But here&#8217;s the point: You do so much and you ask for so little.&nbsp; You know, our experience is a fraction of what so many of you and your families have gone through &#8212; a family like Brittney and her kids.&nbsp; You&#8217;re the absolute best America has to offer: our heart, our honor, your solid steel spine.&nbsp;<br><br>So my message to all of you is quite simply: Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Not &#8220;thank you for your service&#8221; &#8212; just thank you for who you are, because it&#8217;s contagious.&nbsp; Thank you for choosing a selfless service to your country.<br><br>I know we have mostly soldiers and airmen in attendance today, but there can be a lot of friendly rivalries on a base.&nbsp; Each branch has its own proud, cherished traditions and culture.&nbsp; I know how proud Langley is of their premier 5th-generation F-22 Raptor Wing.&nbsp; Oh, God, I&#8217;d love to go up in one of those.&nbsp;<br><br>I asked, &#8220;I&#8217;m your Commander-in-Chief.&nbsp; Why the hell can&#8217;t I command you let me go up in one?&#8221;&nbsp; But, you know, they won&#8217;t let me do that.<br><br>And Fort Eustis hosts one of Army&#8217;s busiest airfields, which is led by the Air Force, primarily used by the Navy.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; It&#8217;s all about as joint as it can possibly get.<br><br>Every day, the more than 20,000 members of the Air Force and Army, along with civilian personnel, come to work with a shared mission.&nbsp; No matter which branch of our armed forces you proudly represent, you&#8217;re part of the greatest fighting force in the history of the world.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; The greatest fighting force in the history of the world.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;re integral to the most powerful nation in the world.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been no Army, Navy, or Air Force ever like you &#8212; or Marines.&nbsp;<br><br>Here at Joint Base Langley-Eustis, you enable the success of our mission around the world.&nbsp; You provide intelligence support and airpower.&nbsp; You ensure our soldiers and airmen are ready, trained to deploy the COCOMs around the world &#8212; including, this year, adhering to COVID-19 safety protocols and quarantines before to ship out in order to minimize the spread of the virus.&nbsp;<br><br>I know that many of you deployed yourselves, probably more than once.&nbsp; Over the past 20 years, our volunteer force and our military families have made incredible sacrifices for this country.&nbsp;<br><br>Early in my term as Vice President, when I traveled overseas, I&#8217;d sometimes meet service men and women who were deployed their fourth, fifth, sixth times.&nbsp; I remember going into Baghdad, just remember &#8212; and those of you who had to fly in, you do those circular deals so we wouldn&#8217;t get shot at, we wouldn&#8217;t get hit.&nbsp;<br><br>I walked up in the cockpit of a silver bullet that they had me in.&nbsp; And I asked &#8212; I said, &#8220;How many…&#8221; &#8212; there were five people in the cockpit at the time &#8212; the loadmaster as well.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;How many is this your first tour?&#8221;&nbsp; Nobody raised their hand.&nbsp; &#8220;How many the second tour?&#8221;&nbsp; Nobody raised their hand.&nbsp; &#8220;Third tour?&#8221;&nbsp; Two raised their hand.&nbsp; &#8220;Fourth tour?&#8221;&nbsp; Two raised their hand.&nbsp; &#8220;Fifth tour?&#8221;&nbsp; One raised their hand.&nbsp; No other war have you gone in, served, and got back up and go back again and again and again.&nbsp; Once.&nbsp; Once.&nbsp;<br><br>Wiping the blood off the seat of an up-armored HMMWV is enough to get you focused.&nbsp; Then to saddle up next time and go back and back again?&nbsp; You&#8217;re incredible.&nbsp; You&#8217;re incredible.&nbsp;<br><br>The country &#8212; they owe you, and they&#8217;re &#8212; this time, they&#8217;re more appreciative.&nbsp; In my generation, you didn&#8217;t come home and get off an airplane in a uniform in an airport coming back from Vietnam.&nbsp; People will treat you with respect, but they have no idea the sacrifices you make in theater.&nbsp;<br><br>As we bring &#8212; as we get close to bringing down the longest war drawdown in American history &#8212; our troop presence in Afghanistan &#8212; I want to recognize the significance to &#8212; of what all of you, the United States Armed Forces, have accomplished in the past 20 years.<br><br>Went to Afghanistan with a clear purpose: to get the people who attacked us on 9/11 and to prevent al Qaeda from using Afghanistan as a base from which to attack America in the future.&nbsp; To achieve that purpose &#8212; you achieved that purpose.&nbsp; Year after year, deployment after deployment, American troops pursued the terrorist threat through some of the most unforgiving terrain on the planet.&nbsp;<br><br>I have now had the pleasure, as they say, of being to every part of Afghanistan, from the FOBs up in the Kunar Valley; down south, looking at all those poppy fields; and all in between.&nbsp; It&#8217;s one godforsaken landscape.&nbsp;<br><br>But you all just showed up and did your job, and it helped make sure there hasn&#8217;t been another attack on the homeland from Afghanistan for the last 20 years.&nbsp; And you never gave up until we delivered justice to Osama bin Laden.<br><br>I got criticized after 9/11 for saying, “We’ll follow the son of a bi- &#8212; gun to the gates of hell until we get him.”&nbsp; It&#8217;s exactly what you did.&nbsp; That’s exactly what you did.&nbsp; And you got him.<br><br>And now, as we draw down, we&#8217;re also going to focus on the urgent work of rebuilding over-the-horizon capabilities that’ll allow us to take out al Qaeda if they return to Afghanistan &#8212; but to focus on the threat that has metastasized.&nbsp;<br><br>The greatest threat and likelihood of attack from al Qaeda or ISIS is not going to be from Afghanistan; it&#8217;s going to be from five other regions of the world that have significantly more presence of both al Qaeda and organizational structures, including ISIS.<br><br>We&#8217;re going to update our security stance and turn our forces to the threats that will dominate our future to ensure the security of the American people for decades to come.&nbsp;<br><br>But we’ll never, ever, ever forget the terrible cost that we paid as a nation.&nbsp; Many of you likely have lost friends and colleagues in Afghanistan and Iraq.&nbsp; I know this is personal to you, especially as you head into Memorial Day weekend.&nbsp; We as a nation will always remember and pay tribute to those we lost.&nbsp;<br><br>After I announced my decision to end the war in Afghanistan, the first thing I did was visit &#8212; visit Section 60 of Arlington National Cemetery &#8212; just walked through those headstones, seeing all those stones.&nbsp;<br><br>Our son did not die in Iraq, but he came back &#8212; went as an incredibly healthy young man and came back with a severe brain tumor because his hooch was just downwind from those burn pits &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s the reason.&nbsp; But he came home &#8212; it was just a matter of how long he lived.&nbsp;<br><br>I still carry with me &#8212; every single solitary day I have my staff, for the last &#8212; since the war began &#8212; I have my schedule.&nbsp; In the back of my schedule, it says, “U.S. daily troop update.&nbsp; U.S. troops died in Iraq and Afghanistan: 6,927” &#8212; not “over 6,000.”&nbsp; Total fallen angels across the board: over 7,000.<br><br>Every one of these lives lost is a tragedy, an empty seat at the dinner table, a missing voice at the holidays.&nbsp; Every one of them left behind a whole community &#8212; not just one, a whole community.&nbsp; We can never repay that debt.&nbsp; But I promise you this &#8212; and to all the Gold Star families across the country: We will never, ever, ever, ever forget.&nbsp;<br><br>Each year, Memorial Day offers us a chance to reflect on the enormity of the sacrifices that generation after generation of Americans has made and the responsibilities that we bear &#8212; the citizens bear in return.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ve said many times &#8212; it used to get me in trouble 25 years ago, 30 years ago in the Senate &#8212; I said, “America has many obligations.&nbsp; We only have one sacred obligation.&nbsp; We have obligations to our children, to the elderly, and so many more things, but only one sacred obligation &#8212; is to prepare you, when we send you into harm&#8217;s way, with everything you need; to care for your families when you&#8217;re gone; when you come home, care for you and your families, and the needs that may be a consequence of the war.&#8221;<br><br>We owe it.&nbsp; We owe it to you. &nbsp;We particularly owe it to their memories to affirm the very best of what America stands for &#8212; to uphold honor and democratic values that are the foundation and the strength of this nation.<br><br>You know, I sometimes get criticized for saying what I deeply believe, having done this for the bulk of my life.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in a &#8212; we&#8217;re in a battle between democracies and autocracies.&nbsp; The more complicated the world becomes, the more difficult it is for democracies to come together and reach consensus.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spent more time with President Xi of China than any world leader has &#8212; for 24 hours of private meetings with him with just an interpreter; 17,000 miles traveling with him in China and here.&nbsp;He firmly believes that China, before the year &#8217;30, &#8217;35,&nbsp; is going to own America because autocracies can make quick decisions.&nbsp;<br><br>But America is unique.&nbsp; From all nations in the world, we&#8217;re the only nation organized based on an idea.&nbsp; Every other nation you can define by their ethnicity, their geography, their religion, except America.&nbsp; America is born out of an idea: &#8220;We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men [and women] are created equal… endowed by their Creator with certain inalienable Rights, [including] Life, Liberty,&#8221; et cetera.&nbsp;<br><br>None of you get your rights from your government; you get your rights merely because you&#8217;re a child of God.&nbsp; The government is there to protect those God-given rights.&nbsp; No other government has been based on that notion.&nbsp; No one can defeat us except us.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s an idea that generations of patriots have fought and died for to defend it.&nbsp; I know that&#8217;s a conviction that each and every day you all share.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why you joined up, why you run around danger when duty calls.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s my greatest honor &#8212; it should not surprise anybody; it should be anybody&#8217;s greatest honor in all of life &#8212; to be able to serve as your Commander-in-Chief.&nbsp; No greater honor.<br><br>So, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for spending this time with me today.&nbsp; And thank you for your commitment to our country, because without you, as I said &#8212; I&#8217;ll be &#8212; end where I began: You are the spine of America &#8212; the spine.&nbsp;<br><br>And I can&#8217;t tell you how much it matters.&nbsp; I think you underestimate just the consequence of who you are and what you do.&nbsp;<br><br>So, thank you.&nbsp; May God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>2:29 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequestration Order for Fiscal Year 2022 Pursuant to Section 251a of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act, as Amended</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/28/sequestration-order-for-fiscal-year-2022-pursuant-to-section-251a-of-the-balanced-budget-and-emergency-deficit-control-act-as-amended/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 20:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the laws of&#160;the United States of America, and in accordance with section&#160;251A of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act (the &#8220;Act&#8221;), as amended, 2 U.S.C. 901a, I hereby order that, on October 1, 2021, direct spending budgetary resources for fiscal year 2022 in each&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the laws of&nbsp;the United States of America, and in accordance with section&nbsp;251A of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act (the &#8220;Act&#8221;), as amended, 2 U.S.C. 901a, I hereby order that, on October 1, 2021, direct spending budgetary resources for fiscal year 2022 in each non-exempt budget account be reduced by the amount calculated by the Office of Management and Budget in its report to the Congress of May 28, 2021.</p>



<p>All sequestrations shall be made in strict accordance with the requirements of section 251A of the Act and the specifications of the Office of Management and Budget&#8217;s report of May 28, 2021, prepared pursuant to section 251A(9) of the Act.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>May 28, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
