<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 10:25:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by President&#160;Biden and President von der Leyen on European Energy&#160;Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/joint-statement-by-president-biden-and-president-von-der-leyen-on-european-energy-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following the further invasion of Ukraine, Russia continues to use natural gas as a political and economic weapon. &#160;Russia’s energy coercion has put pressure on energy markets, raised prices for consumers, and threatened global energy security. This was most recently demonstrated by the politically motivated acute disruptions of gas supplies to several European Union Member&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Following the further invasion of Ukraine, Russia continues to use natural gas as a political and economic weapon. &nbsp;Russia’s energy coercion has put pressure on energy markets, raised prices for consumers, and threatened global energy security. This was most recently demonstrated by the politically motivated acute disruptions of gas supplies to several European Union Member States. These actions only underscore the importance of the work both the United States and the European Commission are doing to end our reliance on Russian energy. We are also working together to find ways to further reduce Russia’s energy-derived revenues in the coming months to further curtail Russia’s ability to fund its unprovoked war in Ukraine. These actions are important, necessary, and immediate steps we can take, but we also recognize the enormity of the challenge is significant. To meet the challenge and support Europe’s efforts, we established on 25 March 2022 the Task Force on European Energy Security. Since then the United States and the European Commission have made important strides towards reducing the European Union’s dependence on Russian fossil fuels by decreasing natural gas demand, cooperating on energy efficiency technologies, and diversifying energy supplies. The United States and the European Commission are also taking decisive action to reduce overall demand for fossil fuels in line with the Paris Agreement and our shared goal of net zero emissions no later than 2050.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Task Force has met regularly to discuss options to reduce Europe’s demand for natural gas and has also met with key stakeholders to promote the deployment of heat pumps, smart thermostats, and energy demand response solutions. &nbsp;We will encourage Member States and European and U.S. companies to reach an initial goal of deploying at least 1.5 million energy saving smart thermostats in European households this year. &nbsp;In the coming days we will reconvene with Member States and stakeholders to discuss actionable policy recommendations to accelerate smart thermostat and heat pump deployment and production in an effort to ensure supply for key energy efficiency solutions are ramping to meet the growing demand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are also partnering to diversify energy supplies to Europe. While Russia has cut supplies of natural gas to several EU Member States, the United States and other producers have stepped up. &nbsp;Since March, global LNG exports to Europe have risen by 75 percent compared to 2021, while U.S. LNG exports to Europe have nearly tripled. &nbsp;To facilitate these efforts, the European Commission and Member States, in line with a mandate given by the European Council in March 2022, established the EU Energy Platform to coordinate measures to secure reliable and diversified energy supplies for the EU, including through the voluntary common purchase of pipeline gas, LNG, and hydrogen. The Commission has also established the first Regional Energy Platform for South East Europe to support gas diversification of the region traditionally dependent on Russian supplies. The United States is a key partner for the sustainable diversification of gas supplies to this region and other acutely impacted EU Member States, including by supporting demand reduction and accelerating clean technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mindful of the environmental impact of LNG production and consumption, the United States and the European Commission will step up their cooperation to reduce methane emissions, to ensure that EU-U.S. LNG trade is aligned with the scope of an internationally accepted measurement, reporting and verification standard for methane emissions while working to reduce venting and flaring in natural gas production, and methane leakage in the transmission and LNG supply chain. We will also continue our cooperation on reduction of methane emissions globally. Most recently, the joint launch with 11 other countries of the Global Methane Pledge Energy Pathway will advance both climate progress and energy security internationally.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Second Day in&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/27/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-president-bidens-second-day-in-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 09:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[8:39 A.M. CEST MODERATOR:&#160; All right.&#160; So, in the interest of time, we’re going to go ahead and get started.&#160; First, you know, I’m sorry that we had to move the time up &#8212; just, you know, shifting schedules that we just couldn’t plan for.&#160; So I’m &#8212; again, I’m sorry, and thank you for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>8:39 A.M. CEST</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; So, in the interest of time, we’re going to go ahead and get started.&nbsp; First, you know, I’m sorry that we had to move the time up &#8212; just, you know, shifting schedules that we just couldn’t plan for.&nbsp; So I’m &#8212; again, I’m sorry, and thank you for joining so early this morning.<br><br>So we’re going to preview some announcements that are going to be coming as part of a coordinated G7 announcement on Tuesday, but we wanted to give you a sense of where things are and also a laydown of some new U.S. actions.<br><br>This call is on background.&nbsp; It is attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And the contents of the call are embargoed until 10:00 a.m., Germany; 4:00 a.m., U.S.<br><br>So, with that &#8212; and, sorry, for your awareness but not for reporting, our speaker is [senior administration official].<br><br>So, [senior administration official], I’ll turn it over to you.&nbsp; And then we’ll try to take as many questions as we can.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, Saloni.&nbsp;<br><br>And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; We had a packed day at the G7 yesterday, and we are now headed into day two.<br><br>President Biden and the whole team here have been working around the clock to leverage the fact that close to 50 percent of the world’s economy is in one place and put forward further efforts to support Ukraine, hold Russia accountable, and manage the impacts of Putin’s war on the global economy.<br><br>I want to take just a few minutes to preview some of the efforts the U.S. will be taking in coordination with the G7.&nbsp; But before I get to that, I want to start with setting some context.<br><br>As you all know, the United States has rallied over 30 allies and partners around the world to impose drastic historic costs on Russia.<br><br>It was reported overnight that Russia defaulted on its sovereign debt for the first time in more than a century.<br><br>So, in the span of a few months, U.S. exports to Russia, including of critical technology inputs that Putin needs to maintain his military, those have decreased 97 percent.&nbsp; Russia’s imports of goods from around the world could fall by as much as 40 percent this year.<br><br>Factories across Russia are struggling to maintain production.&nbsp; Russia’s GDP is likely to fall by double digits this year, and inflation is rising to over 20 percent.<br><br>So, just by way of context, and I think this morning’s news around &#8212; around the finding of Russia’s default for the first time in more than a century situates just how strong the reactions are that the U.S., along with allies and partners, have taken, as well as how dramatic the input &#8212; the impact has been on Russia’s economy, both today and cumulating &#8212; accumulating across time.<br><br>Today, the United States will continue &#8212; pardon me &#8212; the United States will continue to increase pressure on Putin.&nbsp; That’s why today we’re announcing:</p>



<p>First &#8212; and on this first one, you know, we’re still in final discussions with other G7 counterparts, working to finalize this, but we’re very close to a place where G7 leaders will have decided to urgently direct relevant ministers to develop mechanisms to set a global price cap for Russian oil in shipments to countries outside of the U.S., EU, the UK, and the broader G7.<br><br>The goal here is to starve Russia &#8212; starve Putin of his main source of cash and force down the price of Russian oil to help blunt the impact of Putin’s war at the pump.</p>



<p>As I’ve said repeatedly, we have dual objectives here.&nbsp; The dual objectives of G7 leaders have been to take direct aim at Putin’s revenues, particularly through energy, but also to minimize the spillovers and the impact on the G7 economies and the rest of the world.<br><br>And G7 leaders are going to acknowledge those two objectives and also acknowledge that the path forward is to urgently direct ministers to work on achieving a price cap, which can, in our judgement, best achieve both of those objectives simultaneously.<br><br>Secondly, G7 leaders will align and expand targeted sanctions to further restrict Russia’s access to key industrial inputs, to services and technologies produced by our economies, particularly those supporting Russia’s armament industrial base and technology sector.<br><br>On Tuesday, the United States Departments of State and Treasury will aggressively target Russian defense supply chains by imposing blocking sanctions on major state-owned defense enterprises, in addition to defense research organizations, and dozens of other defense-related entities and individuals, and limit Russia’s ability to replace the military equipment it has already lost during its brutal war against Ukraine.</p>



<p>We will align on using tariffs on Russian goods to help Ukraine.&nbsp; Earlier this year, G7 leaders committed to strip Russia of “most favored nation” trading status, which guaranteed low tariff rates for Russian goods sold globally.<br><br>President Biden and other G7 leaders will seek authority to use revenues collected by new &#8212; any new tariffs on Russian goods to help Ukraine and to ensure that Russia pays for the cost of its war.<br><br>President Biden is also announcing that, pursuant to Congress’s revocation of trade &#8212; Russia’s trade status in the U.S., the U.S. will implement a higher tariff rate on more than 570 groups of Russian products worth approximately $2.3 billion.<br><br>These measures will restrict Russia’s ability to benefit economically from sales to the U.S. market and are carefully calibrated to impose costs on Russia, and are not expected to have impacts on U.S. supply chain or raise costs to U.S. consumers.<br><br>G7 Leaders will decide to impose sanctions on those responsible for human rights abuses, including war crimes, exercising illegitimate authority in Ukraine, and involved in Russia’s tactics to steal Ukrainian grain or otherwise profit illegitimately from the war.<br><br>On Tuesday, the U.S. Departments of Treasury and State will implement blocking sanctions on private military companies operating in Ukraine, Russian military units that have been credibly implicated in human rights abuses or violations of international humanitarian law in Ukraine, and Russia-installed senior officials in contested areas, including ministers and mayors of contested cities.<br><br>State will impose visa restrictions on approximately 500 officials for threatening or violating Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, or political independence, or suppressing dissent in Russia.<br><br>And lastly, you will see significant G7 &#8212; significant G7 commitment to help Ukraine cover its short-term budgetary shortfalls, including a $7.5 billion commitment from the United States from the recently passed second supplemental.</p>



<p><br>With that, I will go ahead and stop and take any questions from the group that we have time for.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great, thank you.&nbsp; If you have a question, could you please raise your hand?<br><br>All right, let&#8217;s go to Jim from the Times.&nbsp; Jim, can you ask your question, please?</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], can you tell us more about how the price cap is shaping up?&nbsp; Who all would implement it?&nbsp; How might it work?&nbsp; I know you haven&#8217;t figured out the details yet.&nbsp; But &#8212; and, sort of, what would the &#8212; a potential price cap be that is in the ballpark of what you guys are discussing?</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Jim.&nbsp; So, again, I would take a step back and say: What leaders are likely to articulate here is a set of shared objectives.&nbsp; Those objectives are denying Russia&#8217;s energy revenues, their resources to continue to wage war, and also to minimize the spillovers on the rest of the economy, minimize the disruption in global energy markets, minimize the impact for consumers in the United States and around the world.<br><br>What is been &#8212; what is likely to be further acknowledged here is that while we are &#8212; in the U.S., the EU, Canada, the UK &#8212; implementing our own oil embargos on Russian oil, we collectively have a set of tools that can go to the services that are provided to allow Russian oil to be transported elsewhere in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And by zeroing in on those services and the way in which they&#8217;re provided &#8212; and particularly, potentially, through the mechanism of a price gap &#8212; there&#8217;s an ability to achieve both of those objectives simultaneously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What leaders are likely to do is task the relevant ministers, including finance ministers across the G7, to work intensively with other partners around the world, to work intensively with the private sector in the period of time ahead to urgently take steps to determine how to design and implement such a mechanism and, again, design and implement such a mechanism with those two shared objectives squarely in mind.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great, thank you.&nbsp; Let’s go to Zeke Miller from the AP.&nbsp; What’s your question, please?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], can you just clarify a little bit &#8212; so it sounds like you&#8217;re saying there is an agreement in principle but not an agreement on substance on the price cap and &#8212; including no details on how it would actually work.&nbsp; How long would it take to actually come up with those details to be in a place where this would be able to be implemented?</p>



<p>And then also, what do you predict the impact would be, if any, of this action on the price of U.S. energy and U.S. consumer prices?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so I&#8217;d say a couple of things.&nbsp; You know, one: Yes, what we&#8217;re likely to achieve here is leaders aligning around those shared objectives, leaders acknowledging that a price cap on Russian oil implemented through the services that G7 economies provide collectively to transport Russian oil elsewhere in the world &#8212; that that is a very promising avenue to pursue to achieve our shared objectives &#8212; again, denying Putin revenue, minimizing the disruption in global energy markets, providing greater stability and supply in global energy markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, there are &#8212; this, as you might imagine, requires a great deal of coordination, a great deal of effort across a number of different ministries in the G7.&nbsp; It requires a great deal of coordination with international partners.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the statement recognizes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it tasks ministers to go do urgently.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we would expect, in the coming period of time, that we will have &#8212; that we will get &#8212; that we will take steps towards identifying the precise mechanisms through which this would be achieved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in terms of impact on consumer prices, you know, I don&#8217;t want to make any forecasts.&nbsp; Again, I think what we have been focused on is how do we achieve these dual objectives.&nbsp; And importantly, you know, one of those dual objectives is ensuring stability in global energy markets, ensuring supply on global energy markets.&nbsp; We think this is a tool that is going to do exactly that: provide additional clarity that there will be supply and stability in global energy markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so we are of the belief that this is a tool that is going to &#8212; that is &#8212; while I don&#8217;t want to make any forecasts &#8212; is going to achieve those objectives of providing stability, providing greater certainty, and providing greater comfort around supply in global energy markets in ways that that we think will have the intended effect with respect to energy prices.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; So I think we just have time for one more, and then I know you have to run.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So let&#8217;s do Andrea Shalal from Reuters.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Hey, thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], can you just sort of explain to me how much, you know, further this takes it?&nbsp; There&#8217;s 30 countries already doing sanctions.&nbsp; This set of measures that G7 leaders are expected to agree to, does it take you to, sort of, 90 percent of what&#8217;s possible?&nbsp; You know, can you just sort of characterize what this is &#8212; stepping back, zooming out &#8212; in terms of ratcheting up pressure on Russia?</p>



<p>And then if I could just ask you with regard to the price cap and the transportation of oil and &#8212; I&#8217;m wondering whether your conversations, you know, with other countries that have been the so-called fence sitters on this and have continued to draw oil &#8212; are you making headway?&nbsp; Have any substantial countries &#8212; say, India &#8212; agreed?&nbsp; Have you had conversations with China about how they will deal with this and whether they&#8217;re willing to reduce their purchases or &#8212; you know, how would the price caps affect those purchases?</p>



<p>Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; So, just to take the second question first: I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of news, to get ahead of consultations, but I think what you will see &#8212; what you&#8217;re likely to see reflected in what leaders say is a recognition that the ministers that have been tasked to do this work need to engage intensively with potential partner countries around the world; engage intensively with stakeholders, including those in the private sector.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to be a very intensive set of dialogues, an intensive set of conversations in the days and weeks ahead.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t want to characterize the state of those to date, the state of what those might be going ahead, other than to say we&#8217;re very intensely focused on having that dialogue and having those conversations around potential partners in this effort and ensuring that we work closely with the private sector and other stakeholders to implement this step effectively.</p>



<p>And then, with respect to the broader perspective on the sanctions package, I mean, I think that you&#8217;ve seen through the steps that G7 have taken together an ongoing focus on a few things on ensuring that Russia&#8217;s economy is isolated from the global economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think, with respect to the actions that you saw yesterday on gold, that was taking another step to disconnect Russia&#8217;s financial sector from the global financial system, cutting off yet another route for Russian transactions back into the global financial system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think what you&#8217;re seeing today is also a continuation of a number of themes that we&#8217;ve been articulating for a while: degrading Russia&#8217;s defense industrial base and significant new steps and actions there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think you also see an ongoing effort to focus on individuals who are most egregiously connected to Russia&#8217;s aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what you&#8217;re seeing today with respect to the set of steps that are being articulated on those who are credibly implicated in human rights abuses and war crimes, those who are profiteering from Russia&#8217;s invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, these &#8212; there are an existing set of, I think &#8212; there have been an existing set of lines of effort, of themes that have been getting advanced over the months since Russia&#8217;s invasion.&nbsp; And these are our collective next set of steps to ensure that we&#8217;re continuing to ratchet up the pressure across each of those lines of efforts.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and the contents are going to lift at 10:00 a.m., Germany; 4:00 a.m., D.C.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to send a factsheet shortly.&nbsp; So if you don&#8217;t get it in the next 10 to 15 minutes, just feel free to ping me.&nbsp; And if you have any other questions, let us know.&nbsp; Thanks for your time.</p>



<p> 8:57 A.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The United&#160;States and G7 to Take Further Action to Support Ukraine and Hold the Russian Federation&#160;Accountable</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/fact-sheet-the-united-states-and-g7-to-take-further-action-to-support-ukraine-and-hold-the-russian-federation-accountable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In Germany today, President Biden will meet with G7 leaders and President Zelenskyy to continue delivering on our unwavering, unified commitment to support Ukraine and build on our unprecedented sanctions to hold President Putin accountable. &#160;The G7 will issue a statement of support for Ukraine, which will include significant new sanctions commitments to further intensify&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In Germany today, President Biden will meet with G7 leaders and President Zelenskyy to continue delivering on our unwavering, unified commitment to support Ukraine and build on our unprecedented sanctions to hold President Putin accountable. &nbsp;The G7 will issue a statement of support for Ukraine, which will include significant new sanctions commitments to further intensify our economic measures against Russia.</p>



<p>The United States has rallied over 30 allies and partners around the world to impose drastic costs on Russia and the U.S. led coalition will continue to increase pressure on Putin. In the span of a few months, U.S. exports to Russia, including of critical technology inputs Putin needs to maintain his military, have decreased approximately 97%. Russia’s imports of goods from around the world could fall by 40%. Factories across Russia are struggling to maintain production. Russia’s GDP will likely decline by double digits, inflation is rising to over 20%, Russia’s struggling to make bond payments, and <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-06-26/russia-defaults-on-foreign-debt-for-first-time-since-1918#xj4y7vzkg">Russia’s defaulted on its sovereign debt for the first time in more than a century</a>.  </p>



<p>Our measures will continue to sap Putin’s military-industrial complex of critical components, prevent the central bank’s foreign reserves from propping up an ailing economy and deprive Putin of the resources he needs to wage his war, and hold the kleptocracy to account for its ill-gotten gains. The effectiveness of our measures will only compound over time to further isolate Russia from the world economy.</p>



<p>The United States, in coordination with the G7, will implement significant commitments, including sanctions on hundreds of individuals and entities that adds to the over 1,000 already sanctioned, take action on evasion by targeting companies in several countries that adds to the over 300 Entity Listings already in place; impose tariffs on hundreds of Russian products worth billions of dollars to Russia, among other things:<br><br></p>



<p><strong>Measures targeting the Russian military production and supply chains. </strong>G7 Leaders will align and expand targeted sanctions to further restrict Russia’s access to key industrial inputs, services, and technologies produced by our economies, particularly those supporting Russia’s armament industrial base and technology sector. &nbsp;The United States Departments of State and the Treasury will aggressively target Russian defense supply chains by imposing blocking sanctions on major state-owned defense enterprises, in addition to defense research organizations, and dozens of other defense-related entities and individuals and limit Russia’s ability to replace the military equipment it has already lost during its brutal war against Ukraine.</p>



<p><strong>Using tariffs on Russian goods to help Ukraine.</strong> Earlier this year, G7 leaders committed to strip Russia of “most favored nation” trading status, which guaranteed low tariff rates for Russian goods sold globally. President Biden and other G7 leaders will seek authority to use revenues collected by new tariffs on Russian goods to help Ukraine and to ensure that Russia pays for the costs of its war. President Biden is also announcing that, pursuant to Congress’s revocation of Russia’s trade status in the U.S., the U.S. will implement a higher tariff rate on more than 570 groups of Russian products worth approximately $2.3 billion to Russia. These measures will restrict Russia’s ability to benefit economically from sales to the U.S. market and are carefully calibrated to impose costs on Russia, while minimizing costs to U.S. consumers.</p>



<p><strong>Restrictions on Russia’s participation in the global market and further crack downs on evasion attempts. </strong>G7 Leaders are determined to limit Russia’s revenues, including from gold, Russia’s second largest export after energy. The United States will take several key actions to implement these commitments. The U.S. Department of the Treasury will be issuing a determination to prohibit the import of new gold into the United States, which will prevent Russian participation in the formal gold market<strong>. </strong>G7 Leaders will also commit to continue to target efforts by those engaging in evasion and backfill activities. The U.S. Department of Commerce will take its first action against companies engaging in backfill activities in support of Russia by adding several companies around the world to the Entity List, which will prohibit those companies from purchasing U.S.-made origin goods and technologies, such as semiconductors. State and Treasury will implement blocking sanctions against persons tied to aiding Russia’s evasion efforts. Commerce and Treasury will jointly issue an alert to financial institutions to aid in detecting potential violations of export controls. <strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><strong>Imposition of costs on those responsible for human rights abuses – including war crimes, profiteering, and illegitimate authorities. </strong>G7 Leaders will decide to impose sanctions on those responsible for human rights abuses – including war crimes, exercising illegitimate authority in Ukraine, and&nbsp;involved in Russia’s tactics to steal Ukrainian grain or otherwise profit illegitimately from&nbsp;the&nbsp;war. The U.S. Departments of Treasury and State will implement blocking sanctions on private military companies operating in Ukraine, Russian military units that have been credibly implicated in human rights abuses or violations of international humanitarian law in Ukraine, and Russia-installed senior officials in areas besieged or held by Russia’s forces, including ministers and mayors of contested cities. State will impose visa restrictions on approximately 500 officials for threatening or violating Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, or political independence, or suppressing dissent in Russia.</p>



<p><strong>A significant G7 Commitment for Budgetary Support and other support for Ukraine. </strong>The G7 will commit to help Ukraine cover its short-term budgetary funding shortfalls, including a $7.5 billion commitment from the United States from the recently passed second supplemental. Leaders will also make an unprecedented, long-term security commitment to providing Ukraine with financial, humanitarian, military and diplomatic support as long as it takes. The commitment by the leaders will include maintaining Ukraine’s credible military readiness and defense, including through the timely provision of modern defense equipment and advanced weapons systems.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the Republic of the Philippines to Attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Ferdinand Romualdez Marcos,&#160;Jr.</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/26/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-republic-of-the-philippines-to-attend-the-inauguration-of-his-excellency-ferdinand-romualdez-marcos-jr/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 20:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Ferdinand Romualdez Marcos, Jr. on June 30, 2022, in Manila, Republic of Philippines.&#160; Mr. Douglas Emhoff, Second Gentleman of the United States, will lead the delegation.&#160; Members of the Presidential Delegation: Ms. Heather Variava, Chargé&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Ferdinand Romualdez Marcos, Jr. on June 30, 2022, in Manila, Republic of Philippines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. Douglas Emhoff, Second Gentleman of the United States, will lead the delegation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</p>



<p>Ms. Heather Variava, Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim, U.S. Embassy Manila</p>



<p>The Honorable Bobby Scott, Chairman of the Committee on Education and Labor, United States Representative (D), Virginia</p>



<p>The Honorable Nani A. Coloretti, Deputy Director, Office of Management and Budget</p>



<p>Admiral James “Sandy” A. Winnefeld, Jr. (Ret.), Former Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Honorable Edgard D. Kagan, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for East Asia and Oceania, National Security Council&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Honorable Chantale Y. Wong, U.S. Director of the Asian Development Bank</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Launch of the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and&#160;Investment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/26/remarks-by-president-biden-at-launch-of-the-partnership-for-global-infrastructure-and-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 16:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Schloss ElmauKrün, Germany 5:19 P.M. CEST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; Well, good afternoon, folks.&#160; Our nations and our world stand at a genuine inflection point in history.&#160; Technology has made our world smaller, more immediate, and more connected.&#160; It’s opened up incredible opportunities, but also accelerated challenges that impact on all of us:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Schloss Elmau<br>Krün, Germany</p>



<p>5:19 P.M. CEST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Well, good afternoon, folks.&nbsp;<br><br>Our nations and our world stand at a genuine inflection point in history.&nbsp; Technology has made our world smaller, more immediate, and more connected.&nbsp; It’s opened up incredible opportunities, but also accelerated challenges that impact on all of us: managing global energy needs, taking on the climate crisis, dealing with the spread of diseases.<br><br>And the choices we make now, in my view, are going to set a direction of our world for several generations to come.<br><br>These challenges are hard for all of us, even nations with resources of the G7.&nbsp; But developing countries often lack the essential infrastructure to help navigate global shocks, like a pandemic.&nbsp; So they feel the impacts more acutely, and they have a harder time recovering.<br><br>In our deeply connected world, that’s not just a humanitarian concern, it’s an economic and a security concern for all of us.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why, one year ago, when this group of leaders met in Cornwall, we made a commitment: The democratic nations of the G7 would step up &#8212; step up and provide financing for quality, high-standard, sustainable infrastructure in developing and middle-income countries.<br><br>What we’re doing is fundamentally different because it’s grounded on our shared values of all those representing the countries and organizations behind me.&nbsp; It’s built using the global best practices: transparency, partnership, protections for labor and the environment.<br><br>We’re offering better options for countries and for people around the world to invest in critical infrastructure that improves the lives &#8212; their lives, all of our lives &#8212; and delivers real gains for all of our people, not just the G7 &#8212; all of our people.<br><br>Today, we officially launch the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment.&nbsp; We collectively have dozens of projects already underway around the globe.<br><br>And I’m proud to announce the United States will mobilize $200 billion in public and private capital over the next five years for that Partnership.<br><br>We’re here today because we’re making this commitment together as a G7 in coordination with one another to maximize the impact of our work.<br><br>Collectively, we aim to mobilize nearly $600 billion from the G7 by 2027.&nbsp;<br><br>These strategic investments are areas of &#8212; critical to sustainable development and to our shared global stability: health and health security,&nbsp;digital connectivity, gender equality and equity, climate and energy security.<br><br>Let me give you some examples of the kinds of projects that are underway in each of these areas.<br><br>First, health.&nbsp; Two years ago, COVID-19 &#8212; didn’t need any reminders about how critical investments in healthcare systems were and health sec- &#8212; and health security is, both to fight the pandemic and to prepare for the next one, because it will not be the last pandemic we under- &#8212; we have to deal with.<br><br>That’s why the United States, together with the G7 partners and the World Bank, are investing in a new industrial-scale vaccine manufacturing facility in Senegal.&nbsp; When complete, it will have the potential to produce hundreds of millions of doses of vaccines annually for COVID-19 and other diseases.<br><br>It’s an investment that will enhance global vaccine supplies as well as improve access and equity for developing countries.<br><br>Second, in the digital area.&nbsp; Our economies’ future increasingly depends on people’s ability to connect to secure information and communications technologies.&nbsp; And we need to strengthen the use of trusted technologies so that our online information cannot be used by autocrats to consolidate their power or repress their people.<br><br>That’s why the Digital Invest Program is mobilizing $335 million in private capital to supply secure network equipment in Africa, Asia, and Latin America.<br><br>And the U.S. government also supported the successful bid by an American company, SubCom, for a $600 million contract to build a global subsea telecommunications cable.&nbsp; This cable will stretch from Southeast Asia, through the Middle East and the Horn of Africa, to Europe.<br><br>This will be essential to meeting the growing demand for reliable security, high-tech connectivity in three key regions of the world.<br><br>Third, gender.&nbsp; When women and girls have the ability and the opportunity to parcia- &#8212; to participate more fully in those societies and economies, we see positive impacts not only in their communities but around the board &#8212; across the board.<br><br>We have to increase those opportunities, though, for women and girls to thrive, including practical steps to make childcare more accessible and affordable as we continue the vital work to protect and advance women’s fundamental rights.<br><br>The United States is committing $50 million over five years to the World Bank’s global Childcare Incentive Fund.&nbsp; This public-private partnership supported by several G7 partners will help countries build infrastructure that makes it easier for women to participate equally &#8212; equally &#8212; in the labor force.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Fourth and very important, climate and energy.&nbsp; We’re seeing just how critical this is every day.&nbsp; The entire world is feeling the impact of Russia’s brutal war in Ukraine and on our energy markets.<br><br>We need worldwide effort to invest in transformative clean energy projects to ensure that critical infrastructure is resilient to changing climate.&nbsp;<br><br>Critical materials that are necessary for our clean energy transition, including the production of batteries, need to be developed with high standards for labor and the environment.<br><br>Fast and reliable transportation infrastructure, including railroads and ports, is essential to moving inputs for refining and processing and expanding access to clean energy technologies.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, the U.S. government just facilitated a new partnership between two American firms and the government of Angola to invest $2 billion in building new solar projects in Angola.&nbsp; It’s a partnership that will help Angola meet its climate goals and energy needs while creating new markets for American technologies and good jobs in Angola and, I suspect, throughout Africa.<br><br>And in Romania, the American company, NuScale Power, will build a first-of-its-kind small modular reactor plant.&nbsp; This will help bring online zero-emission nuclear energy to Europe faster, more cheaply, and more efficiently.<br><br>The U.S. government is helping to advance the development of this groundbreaking American technology, which will strengthen Europe’s energy security and create thousands of jobs in Romania and the United States.<br><br>These deals are just some of what’s in store.&nbsp; And we’re ready.&nbsp; We’re ready to get to work, together, all of us.<br><br>To lead efforts &#8212; to lead U.S. efforts, in my case &#8212; appointed &#8212; I appointed Amos Hochstein, my Special Presidential Coordinator, to deal with the rest of our colleagues.&nbsp; <s>I’ll</s> [He’ll] lead the U.S. whole-of-government approach to drive a coalition and a collaboration with the G7 and our partners around the world, including private sector and multilateral development banks.<br><br>I want to be clear: This isn’t aid or charity; it’s an investment that will deliver returns for everyone, including the American people and the people of all our nations.&nbsp; It’ll boost all of our economies, and it’s a chance for us to share our positive vision for the future and let communities around the world see themselves &#8212; and see for themselves the concrete benefits of partnering with democracies.<br><br>Because when democracies demonstrate what we can do, all that we have to offer, I have no doubt that we’ll win the competition every time.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; And now I invite President von der Leyen to the podium.<br><br>5:28 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and&#160;Investment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/26/memorandum-on-the-partnership-for-global-infrastructure-and-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES SUBJECT:    Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment  By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and to establish my Administration&#8217;s policy and approach to executing the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment (PGII), it&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES</p>



<p>SUBJECT:    Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment </p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and to establish my Administration&#8217;s policy and approach to executing the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment (PGII), it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1. &nbsp;Policy. &nbsp;Infrastructure is critical to driving a society&#8217;s productivity and prosperity. &nbsp;When done well, infrastructure connects workers to good jobs; allows businesses to grow and thrive; facilitates the delivery of vital services; creates opportunities for all segments of society, including underserved communities; moves goods to markets; enables rapid information-sharing and communication; protects societies from the effects of climate change and public health crises or other emergencies; and supports global connection among nations. &nbsp;Infrastructure comes in many forms and sizes, from the large-scale energy systems that power inclusive economies, to the local healthcare networks that contribute to global health security, to the range of innovative infrastructure developed through investments from financial institutions and small- and medium-sized enterprises. &nbsp;My Administration is making an urgent, once-in-a-generation investment in domestic infrastructure that will create jobs, help address the climate crisis, and help the Nation recover from the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic –– and the same focus is needed around the globe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Internationally, infrastructure has long been underfunded, with over $40 trillion in estimated need in the developing world –– a need that will only increase with the climate crisis and population growth. &nbsp;Many low- and middle-income countries lack adequate access to high-quality financing that meets their long-term infrastructure investment needs. &nbsp;Too often, financing options lack transparency, fuel corruption and poor governance, and create unsustainable debt burdens, often leading to projects that exploit, rather than empower, workers; exacerbate challenges faced by vulnerable populations, such as forced displacement; degrade natural resources and the environment; threaten economic stability; undermine gender equality and human rights; and put insufficient focus on cybersecurity best practices &#8212; a failure that can contribute to vulnerable information and communications technology networks.</p>



<p>The underinvestment in infrastructure is not just financial, but also technical. &nbsp;Delivering high-quality infrastructure in low- and middle-income countries must include helping to establish and improve the necessary institutional and policy frameworks, regulatory environment, and human capacity to ensure the sustainable delivery of services to communities; defining strong engineering, environmental, social, governance, and labor standards; and structuring projects to attract private investment. &nbsp;Through the PGII, the United States and like-minded partners will emphasize high-standards and quality investments in resilient infrastructure that will drive job creation, safeguard against corruption, guarantee respect for workers&#8217; organizations and collective bargaining as allowed by national law or similar mechanisms, support inclusive economic recovery, address risks of environmental degradation, promote robust cybersecurity, promote skills transfer, and protect American economic prosperity and national security. &nbsp;The PGII will also advance values-driven infrastructure development that is carried out in a transparent and sustainable manner &#8212; financially, environmentally, and socially &#8212; to lead to better outcomes for recipient countries and communities.</p>



<p>There is bipartisan support for international infrastructure development. &nbsp;The Congress passed the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (BUILD Act) (Division F of Public Law 115-254, 132 Stat. 3485) with bipartisan support to mobilize private-sector dollars to support economic development in low- and middle income countries, which can include support for projects to build infrastructure, creating first-time access to electricity, starting businesses, and creating jobs. &nbsp;The BUILD Act institutionalized the United States&#8217; commitment to private sector–funded development by establishing the United States International Development Finance Corporation (DFC), authorized a higher exposure cap for the DFC than the exposure cap for the former Overseas Private Investment Corporation, and provided new tools to engage entrepreneurs and investors to help low- and middle-income countries access private resources to generate economic growth. &nbsp;These investments help ensure that our partners are stronger, create opportunities for people around the world, and reduce the need for future United States foreign aid.</p>



<p>In a similar spirit, in 2018 the Congress passed the AGOA and MCA Modernization Act (Public Law 115-167, 132 Stat. 1276), authorizing the Millennium Challenge Corporation (MCC) to make concurrent regional compacts under specified conditions, which can include investments in regional infrastructure. &nbsp;This new authority builds on the MCC&#8217;s record of delivering complex infrastructure projects that result in the delivery of vital services for communities and sustainable, inclusive economic growth. &nbsp;In addition, recognizing the need for access to high-quality, fair, and transparent financing for United States exporters and foreign buyers, the Congress also reauthorized the Export-Import Bank of the United States (EXIM) for 7 years in 2019. &nbsp;The EXIM&#8217;s reauthorization legislation also took steps to advance American leadership in transformational exports, which can include support for goods and services necessary for open, secure, reliable, and interoperable information and communications technology.</p>



<p>The United States and its partners have a long history of providing high-quality financing and technical support for infrastructure projects throughout the world. &nbsp;However, the lack of a comprehensive approach for coordinating infrastructure investments with like-minded partners often leads to inefficiencies and missed opportunities for coordinated investments to deliver at scale. &nbsp;Greater flexibility, speed, and resources, combined with expanded internal coordination within the United States Government, will provide opportunities for the United States Government and United States companies to better meet the infrastructure needs of low- and middle-income countries around the world. &nbsp;At the same time, greater coordination with G7 and other like-minded partners will increase efficiency and catalyze new financing to advance a shared vision of values driven, high-quality, and sustainable infrastructure around the world.</p>



<p>Four key priorities relating to infrastructure will be especially critical for robust development in the coming decades: &nbsp;climate and energy security, digital connectivity, health and health security, and gender equality and equity. &nbsp;Economic prosperity and competitiveness will largely be driven by how well countries harness their digital and technology sectors and transition to clean energy to provide environmentally sustainable and broadly shared, inclusive growth for their people. &nbsp;Countries not only will need new and retrofitted infrastructure, secure clean energy supply chains, and secure access to critical minerals and metals to facilitate energy access and transitions to clean energy, but also will need significant investments in infrastructure to make communities more resilient to diverse threats, from pandemics to malicious cyber actors, to the increasing effects of climate change. &nbsp;Further, the COVID-19 pandemic has highlighted the unequal infrastructure needs in the developing world and has disproportionately affected low- and middle-income countries and regions, particularly with respect to the health sector. &nbsp;In the developing world, the pandemic has also set back the economic participation of women and members of underserved communities and has reversed decades of progress toward ending poverty, with global extreme poverty rising for the first time in more than 20 years due to COVID 19. &nbsp;The pandemic has highlighted the need for expanded investments in and high-quality financing for strengthened health systems to both fight the current pandemic and prepare for future health crises.</p>



<p>It is therefore the policy of the United States to catalyze international infrastructure financing and development through the PGII, which is designed to offer low- and middle-income countries a comprehensive, transparent, values-driven financing choice for infrastructure development to advance climate and energy security, digital connectivity, health and health security, and gender equality and equity priorities. &nbsp;The PGII will mobilize public and private resources to meet key infrastructure needs, while enhancing American competitiveness in international infrastructure development and creating good jobs at home and abroad. &nbsp;In this effort, the United States is working in close partnership with G7 and other like-minded partners toward infrastructure financing and infrastructure development that are sustainable, clean, resilient, inclusive, and transparent, and that adhere to high standards.</p>



<p>Sec. 2. &nbsp;Approach. &nbsp;In order to meet the enormous infrastructure needs in the developing world, a new approach to international infrastructure development that emphasizes high-standards investment is needed. &nbsp;To meet this challenge and seize this opportunity, the PGII should:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (a) &nbsp;partner with low- and middle-income countries to finance infrastructure across key sectors that advances the four key priorities critical to sustainable, inclusive growth: &nbsp;climate and energy security, digital connectivity, health and health security, and gender equality and equity;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (b) &nbsp;promote the execution of projects in a timely fashion in consultation and partnership with host countries and local stakeholders to meet their priority needs and opportunities, balancing both short- and longer-term priorities;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (c) &nbsp;pursue the dual goals of advancing prosperity and surmounting global challenges, including the climate crisis, through the development of clean, climate-resilient infrastructure that drives job creation, accelerates clean energy innovation, and supports inclusive economic recovery;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (d) &nbsp;support the policy and institutional reforms that are key to creating the conditions and capacity for sound projects and lasting results and to attracting private financing;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (e) &nbsp;boost the competitiveness of the United States by supporting businesses, including small- and medium-sized enterprises in overseas infrastructure and technology development, thereby creating jobs and economic growth here at home;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (f) &nbsp;advance transparency, accountability, and performance metrics to allow assessment of whether investments and projects deliver results and are responsive to country needs, are financially sound, and meet a high standard;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (g) &nbsp;mobilize private capital from both the United States private sector and the private sector in partner countries;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (h) &nbsp;build upon relationships with international financial institutions, including the multilateral development banks (MDBs), to mobilize capital;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (i) &nbsp;focus on projects that can attract complementary private-sector financing and catalyze additional market activity to multiply the positive impact on economies and communities;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (j) &nbsp;coordinate sources of bilateral and multilateral development finance to maximize the ability to meet infrastructure needs and facilitate the implementation of high standards for infrastructure investment;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (k) &nbsp;uphold high standards for infrastructure investments and procurement, which safeguard against bribery and other forms of corruption, better address climate risks and risks of environmental degradation, promote skills transfer, generate good jobs, mitigate risks to vulnerable populations, and promote long-term economic and social benefits for economies and communities; and</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (l) &nbsp;align G7 and other like-minded partners to coordinate our respective approaches, investment criteria, expertise, and resources on infrastructure to advance a common vision and better meet the needs of low- and middle-income countries and regions.</p>



<p>Sec. 3. &nbsp;Execution. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;A whole-of-government approach is necessary to meet the challenge of international infrastructure development, with executive departments and agencies (agencies) working together with like minded partners. &nbsp;The Special Presidential Coordinator for the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment shall be responsible for overseeing the whole-of-government execution of these efforts and serving as the central node for United States coordination among the G7, as well as with other like-minded partners, the private sector, and other external actors. &nbsp;While specific lines of effort and initiatives may each have agency leads, such as on sourcing critical minerals or identifying trusted 5G and 6G vendors, whole-of-government policies should be addressed through the Coordinator.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (b) &nbsp;Agencies shall, consistent with applicable law and available appropriations, prioritize support for the PGII and make strategic investments across the PGII&#8217;s key priorities of climate and energy security, digital connectivity, health and health security, and gender equality and equity.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (c) &nbsp;The PGII shall be executed through the following key implementation efforts:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (i) &nbsp; &nbsp; The Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs (APNSA), through the interagency process identified in National Security Memorandum 2 of February 4, 2021 (Renewing the National Security Council System) (NSM-2), shall submit a report to the President within 180 days of the date of this memorandum. &nbsp;The report shall include recommendations on United States Government actions to boost the competitiveness of the United States in international infrastructure development, and to improve coordination on international infrastructure development across relevant agencies.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (ii) &nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), and the heads of other relevant agencies shall prioritize programming consistent with the policy and approach described in sections 1 and 2 of this memorandum to support timely delivery of international infrastructure development, particularly across the PGII&#8217;s four key priorities, as appropriate and consistent with their respective authorities. &nbsp;The Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of MCC, the CEO of DFC, the President of EXIM, the Director of the Trade and Development Agency (TDA), and the heads of other relevant independent agencies are encouraged to follow this same line of effort, as appropriate and consistent with their respective authorities.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (iii) &nbsp; The Secretary of State shall direct Chiefs of Mission to use all appropriate tools and to develop coordination mechanisms –– including through Embassy Deal Teams –– to address host country strategic infrastructure needs within the PGII&#8217;s four key priority areas.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (iv) &nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of USAID, the CEO of MCC, the CEO of DFC, the President of EXIM, and the Special Presidential Coordinator, shall develop a strategy for using Embassy Deal Teams to identify potential priority infrastructure projects for the PGII and refer promising opportunities to relevant agencies for consideration, based on each agency&#8217;s strengths and authorities.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (v) &nbsp; &nbsp; The Secretary of State, through the Special Presidential Coordinator and in consultation with the heads of other relevant agencies, shall coordinate diplomatic engagements to expand the PGII beyond the G7 to bring greater resources and opportunities for partnership.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (vi) &nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretary of State, through the Special Presidential Coordinator and in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Administrator of USAID, the CEO of MCC, and the CEO of DFC, shall lead interagency efforts regarding international coordination on infrastructure development standards and metrics, including on labor and environment, and certification mechanisms, including through the Blue Dot Network.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (vii) &nbsp; The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the President of EXIM, the Director of TDA, and the Special Presidential Coordinator, shall develop and implement a strategy to boost the competitiveness of the United States and promote the use of United States equipment and services in international infrastructure development.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (viii) &nbsp;The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the CEO of MCC, the CEO of DFC, and the Special Presidential Coordinator, shall develop and implement a strategy to catalyze private-sector investment and support low- and middle income countries across the PGII&#8217;s four key priority areas.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (ix) &nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Administrator of USAID, and the Special Presidential Coordinator shall develop a plan for engaging the MDBs to foster high-quality infrastructure investment and increased private-capital mobilization for low- and middle-income countries, and shall coordinate with like-minded partners in the plan&#8217;s execution. &nbsp;The CEO of DFC, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Administrator of USAID, and the Special Presidential Coordinator, is encouraged to develop a plan to enhance engagement with national and international development finance institutions to increase private-capital mobilization.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (x) &nbsp; &nbsp; The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the heads of other relevant agencies, shall develop and implement a strategy to promote high-quality, sustainable, and resilient transportation infrastructure in low- and middle-income countries, including through the launch of a comprehensive toolkit for national, subnational, and multilateral partners that emphasizes best practices in planning, finance, project delivery, safety, and maintenance.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (xi) &nbsp; &nbsp;The APNSA, through the interagency process identified in NSM-2 and in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall identify potential legislative and administrative actions that could improve the ability of United States economic development and assistance, development finance, and export credit tools to meet international infrastructure development needs.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (xii) &nbsp; The APNSA, through the interagency process identified in NSM-2, shall lead biannual reviews to monitor the progress, metrics, and outcomes of the PGII&#8217;s investments and projects; identify strategic opportunities across the PGII&#8217;s four key priorities; and ensure that the execution of the PGII aligns with, and supports, broader strategic United States national security and economic objectives and values, including by supporting United States companies in international infrastructure development.</p>



<p>Sec. 4. &nbsp;Definition. &nbsp;For purposes of this memorandum, &#8220;agency&#8221; means any authority of the United States that is an &#8220;agency&#8221; under 44 U.S.C. 3502(1), other than one considered to be an independent regulatory agency, as defined in 44 U.S.C. 3502(5). &nbsp;&#8220;Agency&#8221; also means any component of the Executive Office of the President.</p>



<p>Sec. 5. &nbsp;General Provisions. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (i) &nbsp; the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (ii) &nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (b) &nbsp;This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (c) &nbsp;This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (d) &nbsp;The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden and G7 Leaders Formally Launch the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and&#160;Investment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/26/fact-sheet-president-biden-and-g7-leaders-formally-launch-the-partnership-for-global-infrastructure-and-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment will deliver game-changing projects to close the infrastructure gap in developing countries, strengthen the global economy and supply chains, and advance U.S. national security  President Biden will announce new flagship projects and lay out the Administration&#8217;s comprehensive effort to execute the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment. At the 2021 G7&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment</em> <em>will deliver game-changing projects to close the infrastructure gap in developing countries, strengthen the global economy and supply chains, and advance U.S. national security </em><br> <br><em>President Biden will announce new flagship projects and lay out the Administration&#8217;s comprehensive effort to execute the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment.</em></p>



<p>At the 2021 G7 Summit, President Biden and G7 leaders announced their intent to develop a values-driven, high-impact, and transparent infrastructure partnership to meet the enormous infrastructure needs of low- and middle-income countries and support the United States’ and its allies’ economic and national security interests. Over the past year, members of the Administration have traveled to hear directly from countries on how we can meet their infrastructure needs, deepened our coordination across the U.S Government and with the G7, honed our infrastructure investment tools, and closed game-changing deals.<br> <br>At the G7 Leaders’ Summit in Schloss Elmau, Leaders will formally launch the <strong>Partnership for Global Infrastructure (PGII) </strong>to mobilize hundreds of billions of dollars and deliver quality, sustainable infrastructure that makes a difference in people’s lives around the world, strengthens and diversifies our supply chains, creates new opportunities for American workers and businesses, and advances our national security.<br> <br><strong>Today, President Biden will announce that the U.S. aims to mobilize $200 billion for PGII over the next 5 years through grants, Federal financing, and leveraging private sector investments.</strong> Together with G7 partners, we aim to mobilize $600 billion by 2027 in global infrastructure investments. And this will only be the beginning. The United States and its G7 partners will seek to mobilize additional capital from other like-minded partners, multilateral development banks, development finance institutions, sovereign wealth funds, and more.<br> <br><strong>President Biden will release a Presidential Memorandum to execute the PGII across four priority pillars that will define the second half of the 21<sup>st</sup> century.</strong><br><br>This includes:</p>



<ul><li>Tackling the climate crisis and bolstering global energy security through investments in climate resilient infrastructure, transformational energy technologies, and developing clean energy supply chains across the full integrated lifecycle, from the responsible mining of metals and critical minerals; to low-emissions transportation and hard infrastructure; to investing in new global refining, processing, and battery manufacturing sites; to deploying proven, as well as innovative, scalable technologies in places that do not yet have access to clean energy.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Developing, expanding, and deploying secure information and communications technology (ICT) networks and infrastructure to power economic growth and facilitate open digital societies—from working with trusted vendors to provide 5G and 6G digital connectivity, to supporting access to platforms and services that depend upon an open, interoperable, secure, and reliable internet and mobile networks with sound cybersecurity.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Advancing gender equality and equity—from care infrastructure that increases opportunities for economic participation by women, to improved water and sanitation infrastructure that addresses gender gaps in unpaid work and time use – in order to boost the global economic recovery by ensuring that half the population is not forced to sit on the sidelines.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Developing and upgrading the infrastructure of health systems and contributing to global health security through investments in patient-centered health services and the health workforce; vaccine and other essential medical product manufacturing; and disease surveillance and early warning systems, including safe and secure labs. Addressing the current pandemic and preventing and preparing for the next one is crucial to U.S. economic and national security.</li></ul>



<p><strong>President Biden will announce flagship projects of PGII, </strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Other-PGII-projects.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">along with additional projects that have been undertaken over the past year.</a><strong> PGII will demonstrate how millions of dollars can mobilize tens or hundreds of millions in further investments and tens or hundreds of millionscan mobilize billions.</strong></p>



<ul><li>With support from the U.S. Department of Commerce and the Export-Import Bank of the United States (EXIM), U.S. firm AfricaGlobal Schaffer (Washington, DC), in collaboration with U.S. project developer Sun Africa (Miami, FL), signed a contract with the Government of Angola to develop a $2 billion solar project in four southern Angola provinces. The project will include solar mini-grids, solar cabins with telecommunications capabilities, and home power kits. In addition to supporting up to $1.3 million in U.S. exports, the project will help Angola meet their climate commitments, including generating 70% carbon-free power by 2025.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>In collaboration with G7 members as well as the European Union and multilateral organizations, the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC) is disbursing a $3.3 million technical assistance grant to Institut Pasteur de Dakar (IPD) for early-stage project development for an industrial-scale flexible multi-vaccine manufacturing facility in Senegal with potential annual capacity of millions of doses of COVID-19 and other vaccines, potentially using both viral vector and mRNA technologies. DFC’s grant is part of a $14 million grant financing package that also includes $3.3 million from the International Finance Corporation, $2 million from the Agence Française de Développement, and $5.2 million from the European Investment Bank (EIB). DFC, along with other development finance institutions, is currently evaluating a loan to support IPD’s expansion to supplement EIB’s recent announcement of a nearly $80 million sovereign loan financing package.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>U.S. telecommunications company SubCom (Eatontown, NJ), awarded a $600 million contract, to build the Southeast Asia–Middle East–Western Europe 6 submarine telecommunications cable that will connect Singapore to France through Egypt and the Horn of Africa. The submarine cable will stretch over 17,000 km and connect countries across the region with high-speed, reliable connectivity. The U.S. Government, including through the U.S. Department of State, Commerce’s Advocacy Center, EXIM, and the U.S. Trade and Development Agency’s (USTDA) commitment of nearly $4 million in additional capacity building to support five countries using SubCom’s technology, collectively helped secure the award of the construction and deployment of the undersea fiber optic cable for SubCom.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The U.S. Government with U.S. firm NuScale Power LLC (Tigard, OR) will provide $14 million in support for the Front-End Engineering and Design study for Romania’s deployment of a first-of-its-kind small modular reactor (SMR) plant. Building on U.S. Government efforts, including advocacy support from Commerce and technical assistance from State and USTDA, this investment is meant to mobilize a multi-billion-dollar effort and showcase U.S. ingenuity in the advanced nuclear sector, accelerate the clean energy transition, create thousands of jobs, and strengthen European energy security while upholding the highest standards for nuclear safety, security, and nonproliferation.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) will aim to commit up to $50 million over five years to the World Bank’s new global Childcare Incentive Fund – $200 million public-private partnership to address the gap in suitable childcare infrastructure; boost women’s employment opportunities, productivity and income, and broader economic growth; and promote human capital and early learning for children. Other partners include the Governments of Canada and Australia, the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, the Conrad N. Hilton Foundation, Echidna Giving, the Ford Foundation, the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, and the LEGO Foundation.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>DFC will invest up to $25 million in the Uhuru Growth Fund I-A, which will provide needed growth capital to small-and medium-sized enterprises in West Africa – including women-led businesses. Some of the largest economies in Africa, including Nigeria, Ghana, and Cote d’Ivoire, are facing a shortage of growth capital. Uhuru has committed to investing at least 30 percent of capital in eligible portfolio companies that support DFC’s 2X women’s economic empowerment initiative, and over 40 percent of the Uhuru team members are women. In addition to U.S. support, like-minded partners are investing including $35 million from the German Development Finance Institution, $30 million from the European Investment Bank, and $15 million from British International Investment, among others. Through this investment, DFC expects to mobilize $78 million in private capital.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The Digital Invest program will leverage $3.45 million in State and USAID funding to mobilize up to $335 million in investment capital for internet service providers and financial technology companies in Africa, Asia, and Latin America that use secure network equipment and advance competition and choice in emerging markets. This new blended finance program for fund managers and project developers through the Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership will promote the growth of resilient, secure digital ecosystems in developing countries.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>USAID will invest $40 million in the Southeast Asia’s Smart Power Program to decarbonize and strengthen the region&#8217;s power system by increasing regional energy trade, accelerating the deployment of clean energy technologies, and actively engaging private sector leaders and key development partners in shared priorities. The program is expected to mobilize $2 billion in financing as a result of U.S. Government assistance, increase regional energy trade by five percent, and result in 2 gigawatts of advanced energy systems deployed.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>DFC will invest up to $30 million in&nbsp;<a>Omnivore Agritech and Climate Sustainability Fund 3,&nbsp;</a>an impact venture capital fund that invests in entrepreneurs building the future of agriculture, food systems, climate, and the rural economy in India.&nbsp;The Fund seeks to invest in companies that increase food security and promote both climate resilience and climate adaptation in India, as well as improve the profitability and agricultural productivity of smallholder farms.&nbsp;The Fund is targeting a $65 million first close in September 2022 and a final close in 2023 to reach its target capitalization of $130 million.&nbsp;Through this investment, DFC expects to mobilize $30 million in private capital.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>ABD group (Philadelphia, PA), a project development company, was awarded a $320 million healthcare infrastructure project to renovate or construct over 100 hospitals and clinics across Côte d’Ivoire and has already begun work on 10 locations. ABD Group credits the Memorandum of Understanding for commercial cooperation between the U.S. Government and the Government of Côte d’Ivoire with providing the necessary foundation of partnership for this deal to come to fruition. With the support of Commerce, the project has already received $160 million in closed financing with another $160 million nearing completion.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s First Day in&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/26/background-press-call-on-president-bidens-first-day-in-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 8:04 A.M. CEST MODERATOR:&#160; All right, so in the interest of time, we’re going to go ahead and get started.&#160; Thanks for your patience.&#160; Just some logistical things we were dealing with this morning. So we’re &#8212; thanks for coming.&#160; Thanks for joining the background call today.&#160; This call is on background, attributable&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>8:04 A.M. CEST<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, so in the interest of time, we’re going to go ahead and get started.&nbsp; Thanks for your patience.&nbsp; Just some logistical things we were dealing with this morning.</p>



<p>So we’re &#8212; thanks for coming.&nbsp; Thanks for joining the background call today.&nbsp; This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; And it&#8217;s to preview day one in Germany today.</p>



<p>So for your awareness, not for reporting, the speakers on the call are [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].&nbsp; They&#8217;re both going to just give some quick remarks at the top, and then we&#8217;re going to try to take as many questions as we can, given the time limitations that we&#8217;re going through today.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re going to start with [senior administration official], and then we&#8217;ll go to [senior administration official].&nbsp; So, [senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thanks.&nbsp; Good morning, everybody.&nbsp; And welcome to Bavaria.&nbsp; Sorry for running a little bit late this morning; was getting through security on the way up to the Schloss.</p>



<p>The President is looking forward to kicking off his Europe trip with a meeting with the German Chancellor.&nbsp; The administration has been investing very heavily in our bilateral relationship with Germany since he took office, including engagements last summer with former Chancellor Merkel.&nbsp; And the President has developed a very close and effective working relationship with Chancellor Scholz, who took office&nbsp;on December 8th.</p>



<p>The President, just to remind, spoke to him two days after that and then hosted him for an Oval Office meeting in February.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve since had a number of bilateral calls, as well as broader calls with other transatlantic and G7 leaders, particularly around the crisis in Ukraine.&nbsp; So this meeting is going to provide a good opportunity to affirm the deep and enduring ties between our two countries.</p>



<p>In terms of the meeting agenda, expect that Russia and Ukraine are going to be at the top of the list, including our continued close coordination on the political and diplomatic front; ongoing conversation about the security assistance that we, as well as other allies and partners, are providing to Ukraine; financial supports; and as well as continued efforts on sanctions to impose economic costs on Russia.</p>



<p>But it&#8217;s a full agenda, as it is our bilateral relationship.&nbsp; So I would expect there will also be discussion of transatlantic defense issues, especially in anticipation of the NATO Summit, which we’ll be heading to from here.&nbsp; This meeting will be a good opportunity for them to check signals on the G7 under the German presidency, and given the next couple of days of meetings that we have here with the G7, and then also an opportunity to discuss our shared interest in a range of other global challenges, including climate change and energy.</p>



<p>I would expect that the President will be thanking Chancellor Scholz for his leadership of the G7 during what&#8217;s been a truly unprecedented time in Europe over the last number of months.</p>



<p>In addition to coordinating the G7 response on Ukraine, the President will undoubtedly recognize the Chancellor&#8217;s leadership on other shared challenges, including climate change and economic resilience.</p>



<p>Many of the priorities that Germany has chosen for its G7 dovetail very closely with the administration&#8217;s focus, including on issues such as health, climate, economic resilience, and COVID.</p>



<p>So let me leave it there for now on the bilateral side, and then happy to answer any other questions after [senior administration official] is done.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [moderator].&nbsp; So, after his bilateral meeting with Chancellor Scholz, the President will participate in the G7 Summit.&nbsp; The first session will be on the global economy.&nbsp; And I think you can expect that leaders will be focused on discussing some of the core problems that are at the top of mind for all of us across the board, things like energy security challenges, the food security challenge globally, the disruptions generally that are emanating from Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>Even as the leaders, including President Biden, will be focused on the challenges and disruptions of the moment, while &#8212; we should also recognize that the U.S. is positioned to weather those challenges because of the strong economic leadership of President Biden and the policies and investments he is putting in place.</p>



<p>The President obviously passed historic rescue legislation last year, has achieved significant bipartisan infrastructure legislation.&nbsp; These have put the United States in a position both to respond to the crisis that the President inherited economically and put the United States in a strong position, as well as to invest in our resilience and ongoing economic strength looking ahead.</p>



<p>Of course, the President has also taken significant steps to address the energy crisis, including &#8212; including historic releases from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, and rallying the world through intensive diplomacy to make that a coordinated action across a number of different partners globally.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s important to note that it&#8217;s not just the United States that&#8217;s in a strong position to address the challenges and the headwinds that the globe faces, the G7 as a whole is collectively in a strong place.</p>



<p>The unemployment rate, to take one example, is as low across the G7 as a whole as it&#8217;s been at any time in the last 40 years.</p>



<p>So even as the United States, the G7 as a whole faces significant challenges, disruptions, headwinds as a result of Putin&#8217;s war, we should also recognize that the United States and the G7 are collectively in a strong position to address and manage those challenges.</p>



<p>I would expect that after the session on the global economy, you&#8217;ll hear leaders move on to talking about the ways in which we can help, in the G7, to invest in global infrastructure, in particular in the emerging and developing world.</p>



<p>That is going to be the topic of the second session that leaders meet around.&nbsp; Last year, G7 leaders agreed to explore offering positive alternatives to the infrastructure model that sell debt traps to low- and middle-income countries.&nbsp; That positive alternative from the G7 will also advance U.S. economic competitiveness and our national security.</p>



<p>You will hear how the President is moving forward this line of effort, along with announcements on new flagship product &#8212; projects.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have a press call later on today that will offer more details on that effort, and not just the session that leaders will be having, but also the side events between the President and other leaders to announce those steps forward.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, the President and other G7 leaders will continue to work to hold Putin accountable.&nbsp; Today, the U.S. and the UK are announcing that G7 leaders will ban imports of Russian gold.&nbsp; The official announcement will come on Tuesday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. has rallied the world in imposing swift and significant economic costs to deny Putin the revenue he needs to finance his war.&nbsp; In this case, gold, after energy, is the second-largest export for Russia and a source of significant revenue for Putin and Russia.</p>



<p>The United States Treasury will issue a determination to prohibit the import of new gold into the United States on Tuesday, which will further isolate Russia from the global economy by preventing its participation in the gold market.</p>



<p>So, between the session on the global economy, the session on global infrastructure and the side event, as well, of course, as the bilateral meeting that [senior administration official] spoke to, it&#8217;s going to be a very action-packed day here and one that the President is looking forward to.</p>



<p>I’ll go ahead and pause there and hand it back to [moderator] to take questions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know if I said this, but just a reminder: This call is &#8212; the embargo on this call is going to lift after this call ends.</p>



<p>So if you have a question, could you just please raise your hand and I will do my best to get to as many as we can in the limited time that we have.&nbsp; So let&#8217;s go first to Sebastian Smith from AFP, please.</p>



<p>&nbsp;Sebastian, are you there?</p>



<p>&nbsp;[Senior administration official], can you still hear me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, I can hear you, [moderator].</p>



<p>&nbsp;MODERATOR:&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; So maybe Sebastian might be having some trouble, so let&#8217;s go to Tamara Keith from NPR.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tamara, can you unmute yourself, please?<br><br>Hey, Angela, are you making sure that people can unmute themselves?&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure what’s going on here.</p>



<p>Hey, guys, give us just one minute to figure out what’s going on.</p>



<p>&nbsp;Hey, Angela, were you able to fix people&#8217;s un-muting problem?</p>



<p>Guys, sorry.&nbsp; Just give us a couple of minutes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Is that Tamara?</p>



<p>&nbsp;Q &nbsp; &nbsp;This is Tam, yes.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Okay, sorry.&nbsp; Okay, go ahead, Tam.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s a muting miracle.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; I know that you are announcing the gold export limitations.&nbsp; Are you expecting there to be anything on sanctions with regards to further punishing Russia?&nbsp; Or is this gold thing, sort of, the primary pushback on Russia out of the G7?</p>



<p>And just a quick question about the Global Infrastructure Partnership.&nbsp; The event is happening on the margins.&nbsp; Should we read anything into it being on the margins and not part of the main program, or not?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On the first question, Tamara &#8212; this is [senior administration official] &#8212; I think you should expect to see a series of steps that are designed to increase pressure in an ongoing way on Putin and Russia.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We think that the step forward that&#8217;s being taken with gold is a very important illustration of the additional steps that we expect to be taken now and in the weeks ahead.</p>



<p>This is a key export, a key source of revenue, a key alternative for Russia, in terms of their ability to transact in the global financial system.&nbsp; Taking this step cuts off that capacity and, again, is an ongoing illustration of the types of steps the G7 can take collectively to continue to isolate Russia and cut it off from the global economy.</p>



<p>To your second question, I would &#8212; I would say, you know &#8212; and we&#8217;ll have more to say about this later&nbsp;this afternoon&nbsp;in the background call &#8212; you know, what you&#8217;re going to see is leaders speaking together in one of the plenary sessions of the G7 to global infrastructure, to the global infrastructure challenge, to what the G7 can do to provide an alternative, to provide a high-road, transparent alternative for low- and middle-income countries around partnering in their common future and in infrastructure together.</p>



<p>You know, what&#8217;s going to happen after they leave that session where they speak privately about that initiative and that priority is to go join together to talk about formally launching this joint infrastructure partnership.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think far from the margins, this is a moment when leaders are going to speak privately to this core priority.&nbsp; Then they&#8217;re going to join together to speak about the action that they&#8217;ve collectively taken since last year&#8217;s declaration of intent in Carbis Bay, and now what it means to launch this with a year&#8217;s worth of work under their belts and to take the steps forward from here.</p>



<p>So I think, again, far from being on the margins, this is a very, I think, compelling choreography that you&#8217;re going to see with leaders reviewing together privately the steps that have been taken and the steps they intend to take, and then to describe those steps to the world at a joint event.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great, thanks.&nbsp; And also just add on to [senior administration official]’s, it&#8217;s just &#8212; I would not read into it.&nbsp; This is just how G7 and other G20 and other summits work.&nbsp; There&#8217;s, like, the plenary sessions, and then everything else is a side event.&nbsp; So I wouldn&#8217;t read anything into it at all.<br><br>All right, I think &#8212; so the muting problem should be fixed.&nbsp; So, Sebastian Smith from AFP, can you hear us and can you ask your question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me now?</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perfect.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I’m out of the purgatory there.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I wanted to ask about the gold measure.&nbsp; Is there a reason that the other members of the G7 didn&#8217;t sign up to this, if I understand it right &#8212; the European ones.<br><br>And another question related: Given the way the Russians seem to have found a workaround on their oil exports, how confident is the U.S. that gold won&#8217;t find another, you know, an alternative route to going through London, for example?&nbsp; Like, say, could it go via South Africa instead?&nbsp; Is it going to become a smuggler’s delight?<br><br>Just lastly, (inaudible), again related, if you could zoom out, (inaudible) out the summit &#8212; and it’s (inaudible) needed to review their progress on this whole campaign.&nbsp; How do they see it going in terms of pressuring Russia?&nbsp; Because, if I remember, the very first briefing for you guys ever did on &#8212; when you first announced sanctions, the language was things like, you know, “we&#8217;re going to cripple the ruble,” and it was pretty much “bring the Russian economy to its knees.”&nbsp; That, obviously, hasn&#8217;t happened and neither has the war really slacked off.&nbsp; So, is there something more to this that we should be thinking about thinking about?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So perhaps we’ll take the last question first.&nbsp; I think that the collective efforts the G7 has taken with (inaudible) sanctions, export controls, and other measures against Russia is having a dramatic effect on the Russian economy.&nbsp;<br><br>The Russian economy is expected to shrink by double digits this year, and that&#8217;s just looking at headline GDP.&nbsp; If you look at things like imports, those have fallen off a cliff, likely to decline this year by 40 percent or more.&nbsp; Those are very substantial changes in the underlying economic conditions of the Russian economy.&nbsp; And those dramatic changes are attributable to the actions the G7 has taken collectively.<br><br>The other thing I&#8217;d observe is: The sanctions effort is intended to be cumulative, not just in the moment.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re already seeing the extent to which sanctions are degrading the productive capacity of the Russian economy, particularly in sectors like technology, like defense, like other key important industries.<br><br>And those impacts only accumulate over time, such that Russia’s ability to produce, Russia’s ability to wage war are going to decline over time as a result of the collective steps that the G7 has taken.<br><br>With respect to your question on gold, I would say, you know, I think one of the ongoing focuses of the sanctions effort has been to identify places where Russia, where others are seeking to evade the steps that have been taken.&nbsp; This is an ongoing area of focus by the G7 and an ongoing place where the G7, the United States, other partners &#8212; where we take steps forward to block off areas where evasion risk is becoming more prominent.<br><br>And, in fact, I think one way of thinking about the measure on gold is: To the extent that so many other avenues, with respect to Russia&#8217;s ability to interact with the global financial system, have been cut off, taking this step on gold is just yet another way to block off paths between the Russian economy and the broader global financial system.&nbsp;<br><br>So we will continue to identify places where evasion is a risk, continue to take steps to block off those paths.&nbsp; And the measure on gold in some ways is, in fact, another step forward to block off ways that Russia might seek to engage with the financial system by virtue of all the other ways that have now been cut off to them.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; And, sorry, I lost service.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], you answered the question about whether &#8212; if the G7 announcing the gold thing on Tuesday?&nbsp; Right?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, this is &#8212;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; You will &#8212;&nbsp; exactly.&nbsp; So the U.S. and the UK have &#8212; are announcing today, but &#8212; when the G7 takes steps collectively, and you&#8217;ll see that on Tuesday. This will be a &#8212; this will be a G7 principle that is articulated.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; All right, so we only have time for one more, unfortunately.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to go to Francesca Chambers from USA Today.&nbsp; Can you hear us?&nbsp; And can you ask your question, please?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I can.&nbsp; And I had difficulty at the beginning (inaudible) can attribute these before I get into the substance of the question?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yeah, of course.&nbsp; So this is &#8212; this call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.” And the contents of the call embargo will lift after this call is over.&nbsp; Does that help?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; And we appreciate you having this, as always. However, it would facilitate greater public trust in our reporting if this information were attributable to named officials.&nbsp;<br><br>But again, as to the substance of the call, this question is for [senior administration official].&nbsp; The U.S. has unsuccessfully pushed the EU to enact a full embargo on Russian oil and gas.&nbsp; For what new incentive or new information is President Biden prepared to offer his counterparts this week to entice them to support the sanctions?&nbsp;<br><br>And then I have a second question.&nbsp; Are there any additional measures or steps that the U.S. is preparing to take to try to speed up getting grain out of Ukraine faster?&nbsp; Poland says that construction of the silos that President Biden proposed will take three to four months to build.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; On the first, what I would say is: In fact, this is a place where the G7 has taken significant steps forward.&nbsp; At this stage, each of &#8212; the United States, Canada, the United Kingdom, the EU &#8212; has taken steps to ban the importation of Russian oil into their economies.&nbsp; So, far from a measure of &#8212; far from (inaudible), of course, that’s what the G7 has taken together.&nbsp; At this stage, again, you know, the U.S., the EU, Canada, the UK have all taken steps to embargo imports of Russian oil.<br><br>To you second question around food security, around speeding the facilitation of grain exports from Ukraine: Obviously, this is something that G7 leaders are focused on.&nbsp; But the thing I would start by saying is: There is a reason that there is a crisis in global food markets, why there is a crisis of global food security, and that is Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; This is their invasion, their blockade of Ukrainian ports, the inability of Ukrainian grain to reach global markets.&nbsp; This is why, at core, global food markets are under stress.&nbsp;<br><br>And G7 leaders are focused on what can be done to get that grain out of Ukraine, recognizing that that is &#8212; that is, at root, one of the key sources of this broader set of challenges.&nbsp; So, yes, I expect this to be a (inaudible) of discussions on the food security challenge (inaudible).<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, Francesca, for raising your point.&nbsp; You know, we’re endeavoring here to give you guys as many background and on-the-record opportunities as we can.&nbsp; And, of course, we&#8217;ll always try to do our best in that regard.&nbsp;<br><br>So as a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; And the contents of this call &#8212; the embargo will lift after this call is over.<br><br>Thanks for bearing with us with the logistical problems in the beginning.&nbsp; Hopefully it&#8217;ll only (inaudible).<br><br>Thanks, guys.&nbsp; And talk to you later tonight.</p>



<p>8:31 A.M. CEST&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on International Day in Support of Victims of&#160;Torture</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/26/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-international-day-in-support-of-victims-of-torture-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Torture remains a moral stain on the world’s collective conscience. That is why today, 35 years after the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment came into effect, I am proud to re-affirm that the United States stands unequivocally against this barbaric act. As one of the original&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Torture remains a moral stain on the world’s collective conscience. That is why today, 35 years after the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment came into effect, I am proud to re-affirm that the United States stands unequivocally against this barbaric act. As one of the original drafters of the Convention, the United States remains committed to eradicating torture throughout the world.<br> <br>Any instance of torture is one too many, and yet every year countless victims suffer this brutal violation of their human rights and dignity. This year we have been shocked by the horrific acts committed by Russian forces in Ukraine, including multiple, credible reports of torture such as beatings, electric shocks, and mock executions. In Mali and Burkina Faso, terrorist groups have been documented to have massacred and tortured local populations, while in Mali and Central African Republic, Kremlin-aligned Wagner mercenaries have reportedly employed similar cruel and unlawful tactics. In the Americas, transnational crime organizations, including cartels and gangs, have been reported as torturing journalists, activists, and minorities, including LGBTQI+ individuals, as a tactic to sow fear and intimidation. In Burma, reports document security forces torturing and killing those who support democracy, including through electrocution, rape, and other forms of sexual violence. Each of these examples tears at our humanity.<br> <br>Today, I reaffirm the United States’ dedication to eliminating torture and supporting its victims. The United States has legally prohibited torture in all of its forms, without exception. We also remain the top contributor to the United Nations Voluntary Fund for Victims of Torture, which helps nearly 50,000 victims and their families receive medical, psychological, legal, social, and other assistance necessary to rebuild their lives. And this year, I submitted to Congress a budget that requests the largest ever funding amount for the U.S. Survivors of Torture Program in HHS’s Office of Refugee Resettlement.<br> <br>When a government commits torture, it surrenders its moral authority and undermines its own legitimacy. And, critically, when torture is committed in the name of national security, it only emboldens and multiplies enemies, fuels unrest, and leaves governments isolated internationally.<br> <br>Today, and every day, let us stand in solidarity with survivors of torture, while calling on all nations to end this inhuman practice.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/26/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-chancellor-olaf-scholz-of-germany-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 10:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany ahead of the G7 Leaders’ Summit. President Biden expressed appreciation for the Chancellor’s leadership of the G7, and the importance of coordinating responses to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, climate, and economic and democratic resilience. The leaders underlined their commitment to Ukraine’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany ahead of the G7 Leaders’ Summit. President Biden expressed appreciation for the Chancellor’s leadership of the G7, and the importance of coordinating responses to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, climate, and economic and democratic resilience. The leaders underlined their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, as well as their continued provision of military, economic, humanitarian, and diplomatic support to help Ukraine defend its democracy against Russian aggression. The leaders also discussed efforts to alleviate the impacts of Russia’s war in Ukraine on global food and energy security. The President welcomed Germany’s historic commitment to significantly boost defense spending and meet its NATO commitments, which will strengthen the Alliance’s long-term deterrence and defense posture. Finally, the leaders also discussed the challenges posed by China and our shared commitment to provide transparent and high-standard solutions to address global gaps in key infrastructure.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
