<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 03:49:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President Jair Bolsonaro of&#160;Brazil</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-jair-bolsonaro-of-brazil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 02:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and President Jair Messias Bolsonaro met today to reaffirm the strategic importance of the relationship between the United States and Brazil—two of the world&#8217;s largest democracies. At a moment when the globe is facing a cascade of crises, from Russia’s war in Ukraine to global warming and pandemic recovery, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and President Jair Messias Bolsonaro met today to reaffirm the strategic importance of the relationship between the United States and Brazil—two of the world&#8217;s largest democracies. At a moment when the globe is facing a cascade of crises, from Russia’s war in Ukraine to global warming and pandemic recovery, the partnership between the United States and Brazil is vital to international efforts to address the climate crisis, and ensure peace. The Leaders pledged to continue their ongoing collaboration on trade and commercial matters, including through U.S. support for Brazil&#8217;s OECD candidacy. President Biden and President Bolsonaro also discussed how our countries must work together to facilitate sustainable development in the larger Amazon Basin to dramatically reduce deforestation, coordinate closely at the UN Security Council over Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine, and support democratic renewal.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Jair Bolsonaro of Brazil Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-jair-bolsonaro-of-brazil-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles Convention CenterLos Angeles, California 4:00 P.M. PDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Great to see you.&#160; And I want to say that I was fortunate enough to visit your magnificent country &#8211;(knocking at the door) &#8212; somebody is trying to get in &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; your magnificent country on three different occasions, including for the World&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles Convention Center<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>4:00 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Great to see you.&nbsp; And I want to say that I was fortunate enough to visit your magnificent country &#8211;(knocking at the door) &#8212; somebody is trying to get in &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; your magnificent country on three different occasions, including for the World Cup in 2014.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I also walked in the &#8212; in the festival in Rio.&nbsp; And I &#8212; Brazil is a wonderful place, magnificent people, and &#8212; because of the vibrant, inclusive democracy and your strong electoral institutions.</p>



<p>Our nations are linked by deeply rooted shared values that unlocks incredible opportunities for both our nations, in my view, so &#8212; driving an equitable, inclusive global economic recovery, and raising our climate ambitions, and a whole range of things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you have &#8212; you’ve made some real sacrifices as a country in the way you&#8217;ve tried to protect the Amazon, which is a great carbon sink in the world.&nbsp; And I think the rest of the world should be participating in helping you finance being able to preserve as much as you can.&nbsp; It seems like it&#8217;s an international responsibility because we all benefit from it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the principal driver of our relationship is a connection between our people.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m anxious to hear what&#8217;s on your mind and talk about what you &#8212; whatever you want to talk about.&nbsp; I’m &#8212; I&#8217;d like to listen as well as raise a few issues that are of, I think, mutual interest to us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, welcome, Mr. President.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BOLSONARO:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Mr. President &#8211;President Biden, it gives me great pleasure, once again, to visit your country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have a great deal in common, such as, for example, our shared love for freedom, democracy.&nbsp; We also share the same values.&nbsp; And we want, ultimately, the very wellbeing of our peoples and peace worldwide.</p>



<p>Brazil is a gigantic country whose territory is as vast as &#8212; can be one of the largest countries in the world.&nbsp; We also have many riches very much in the heart &#8212; heartland of Brazil.&nbsp; Our Amazon region, which is larger than Western Europe by comparison, endowed with incalculable riches, wealth, and biodiversity, as well as mineral wealth, drinking water resources, and also a source of oxygen.</p>



<p>At times, we feel threatened in our sovereignty in that region of the country, but the fact is that Brazil does very well preserve its territory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as much as two thirds of the Brazilian territory are fully preserved.&nbsp; More than 85 &#8212; that&#8217;s eight-five &#8212; percent of the Brazilian Amazonian region are preserved.&nbsp; Our environmental legislation is very strict, and we do all we possibly can to enforce it and comply with it to ensure the overall wellbeing of our nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Currently, Brazil presents itself to the world as a very concrete reality in the eyes of the world at large.&nbsp; In the near future, we may become the world&#8217;s largest exporter of clean energy by means of green hydrogen exports.</p>



<p>We also have other matters or issues of interest on the agenda &#8212; such as, for example, the fact that Brazil currently feeds more than 1 billion people worldwide with our state-of-the-art agriculture and highly mechanized agricultural practices and using unmatched technology anywhere in the world.</p>



<p>The world today, I dare say, depends &#8212; and largely depends on Brazil for its very survival.</p>



<p>The environmental agenda: Yes, we do recognize our challenges, but we &#8212; yes, we do our utmost.&nbsp; We do all we can to, of course, meet our needs, to foster our interests, and why not also, of course, accommodate the will of the world at large?&nbsp; But as I said before, we stand as an example in the eyes of the world when it comes to the environmental agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition to food security and clean energy and also with regards to the environmental agenda &#8212; in addition to these topics, Brazil remains a huge country &#8212; a giant &#8212; and presents herself to the world as a solution for many of the current problems.</p>



<p>We are tremendously interested in drawing closer and closer ties with the United States.&nbsp; We have experienced almost 200 years of good partnership in our history.&nbsp; A few times, here and there, we may have distanced from each other due to perhaps ideological issues.&nbsp; But I am quite certain that with the advent of my administration, our both administrations have never had such a great opportunity, given the many affinities or shared areas of interest we have.</p>



<p>This year, we will be having elections in Brazil &#8212; in Brazil.&nbsp; And we do wish to have honest, clean, transparent, auditable, reliable elections so that there&#8217;ll be no shadow of a doubt whatsoever following the elections.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m quite certain that the elections will very much be carried out in this democratic spirit.</p>



<p>I came to office through democracy.&nbsp; And I am quite certain that when I leave office, it will also be through democratic means.</p>



<p>Brazil and the United States have all it takes to seal our trade relations, thus materializing a north-south axis of relations.&nbsp; Because other countries can work in a complementary fashion mutually, and we have the wherewithal &#8212; we have all it takes to become increasingly integrated nations and countries and serve as an example for the world.</p>



<p>Furthermore, Brazil, of course, still depends or relies on other countries in certain matters.&nbsp; We have always taken a balanced approach to these matters.&nbsp; We want peace in the world, and we will do everything for peace to be achieved.</p>



<p>We do regret the ongoing conflicts.&nbsp; But then again, I have a country to manage.&nbsp; I have a country to administer before me. And given our reliance on certain foreign players, we have to be cautious &#8212; always cautious, because the consequences following the pandemic and the mistaken policy, in my view, of “stay at home and we’ll take care of the economy later on,” further worsened by a war that currently takes place 10,000 kilometers away from Brazil &#8212; the economic consequences in effect are harmful and felt by all of us &#8212; and, in Brazil, especially harmful towards the more vulnerable segments of the population, who have to face inflation in foodstuffs as well as in energy prices.</p>



<p>So, Mr. President &#8212; President Biden, we remain fully available to cooperate towards building a way out of this episode that we, of course, never wish had happened between Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; We intend and we support and we pray that we will find a way out from the current situation as soon as possible so that not only Brazil, but the world at large can go back to normalcy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s essentially what I had to convey to you by way of introduction, dear colleague and head of this nation, as we bear in mind the wellbeing of our peoples.</p>



<p>Thank you so much for the opportunity, Mr. President, for holding this bilateral session and meeting with you.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>4:09 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the Opening Plenary Session of the Ninth Summit of the&#160;Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-opening-plenary-session-of-the-ninth-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 23:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles Convention CenterLos Angeles, California 2:37 P.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Please &#8212; please, sit down.&#160; Well, welcome again to the ninth Summit of the Americas.&#160; A lot of hard work has gone into this summit, and a lot of strong and constructive diplomacy so far, I believe.&#160; We brought together diverse&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles Convention Center<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>2:37 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Please &#8212; please, sit down.&nbsp; Well, welcome again to the ninth Summit of the Americas.&nbsp; A lot of hard work has gone into this summit, and a lot of strong and constructive diplomacy so far, I believe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We brought together diverse voices and stakeholders and <s>development</s> [developed] an ambition agenda and &#8212; agenda for action to address the issues that matter most to the future of our region.&nbsp; They’re not all the same concerns, in some &#8212; one sense.&nbsp; In another sense, they’re all incredibly intertwined.</p>



<p>I’m incredibly honored to be hosting all of you here in Los Angeles.</p>



<p>My administration and the proposals that we’re eager to discuss with you were &#8212; we wanted to begin to talk about today &#8212; proposals that I think are a far cry from what we saw from our previous American administration.&nbsp; But equally important, we &#8212; the Vice President and I &#8212; we want to listen, hear all of you &#8212; what you think we should we be doing.</p>



<p>The next few days, we have an opportunity to find ways we can do better for all of our people by working together.&nbsp; And I emphasize “together.”&nbsp; Together.&nbsp; That’s what our people expect of us.&nbsp; And it’s our duty to show them the power of democracies to deliver when democracies work together.</p>



<p>The United States stands ready to work in partnership with all of you &#8212; governments, institutions, civil societies, young leaders of tomorrow.&nbsp; And I invite my fellow heads of state and heads of government of the Americas to join me in adopting concrete hemispheric commitments that are going to advance our efforts to build a more sustainable, resilient, and equitable future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With our Action Plan on Health and Resilience, we’re going to help our region recover from COVID-19, while strengthening health systems, improving our ability to respond to future health emergencies by investing in health workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The new Americas Health Corps will train 500,000 public health and medical professionals in the region over the next five years.&nbsp; The United States is going to fund this together with the Pan American Health Organization so when the next pandemic hits, which it will, we’ll be ready and trained healthcare workers to administer the vaccines and the needed care, which we don’t have now.&nbsp; And it won’t cost your countries anything.</p>



<p>Through our efforts to strengthen the clean energy economy in the Americas, we’re committing to just &#8212; not just an energy transition but to make communities that have been historically marginalized are able to share equally in the gains, with equitable access to both good-paying jobs we’ll create and the affordable clean energy that will be made available.</p>



<p>I’m going to continue to work, just as I did when I was Vice President with Barack Obama, to promote trade and investment in clean energy, including using the United States International Development Finance Corporation, to help countries that need assistance to access financing and to help the region reach ambitious renewable energy goals by 2030.</p>



<p>By adopting the Inter-American Action Plan on Democratic Governance, we will &#8212; we’re going to commit our nations to making real the promise of the Inter-American Democratic Charter.&nbsp; And sometimes we forget what it says.&nbsp; It says: inclusive democratic governance, transparency and accountability, protections for human rights of all people, respect for the rule of law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on all these issues and more, the United States is making critical commitments to demonstrate our enduring investment in our shared future &#8212; and to address our shared concerns, because they are shared.</p>



<p>Last night, I announced the Americas Partnership [for] Economic Prosperity plan to drive equitable economic recovery and invest in working families throughout the hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I rolled out a new partnership and collaboration with the Caribbean countries to address climate change.&nbsp; I just spent a little time with the Caribbean leaders.&nbsp; We have to go back and do a lot more and hear directly about their concerns and discuss all the ways we can move together, as they pointed out to me just an hour ago, with a sense of urgency &#8212; not years, not months, but soon.&nbsp; Soon.</p>



<p>We’re making good on our commitment to vaccinate the Americas against COVID-19, building more than &#8212; going to be more than 65 million doses that we’ve already donated to the region.</p>



<p>Over the next few days, we’re also announcing more than $645 million in new lifesaving assistance to address food insecurity in the region and increase the ability to respond to disasters, as well as historic refugee and migration flows.</p>



<p>Each one of our countries has been impacted by unprecedented migration, and I believe it’s our shared responsibility to meet this challenge.&nbsp; And I emphasize “shared.”</p>



<p>Tomorrow, a number us will join &#8212; a number of us will join in announcing the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection.&nbsp; This will bring our nations together around a transformative new approach to invest in the region solutions that enhance stability, to increase opportunities for safe and orderly migration, to crack down on the criminals and human traffickers who prey on desperate people,&nbsp;and coordinate specific, concrete actions to secure our borders and resolve the shared challenges.</p>



<p>And tomorrow, I’ll be speaking more to this and laying out our commitments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The bottom line is this: The Western Hemisphere is home for all of us.&nbsp; Back in 2013, when I was Vice President to Barack Obama, he asked me to lead our engagement with the region.&nbsp; And I said we should be talking about the hemisphere and I made a speech back then, saying the hemisphere &#8212; we should look at it as a “middle-class, secure, democratic” hemisphere &#8212; from Chile &#8212; “from Canada to Chile and everywhere in between.”</p>



<p>Over the past decade, our region has changed.&nbsp; The challenges we faced have changed.&nbsp; And so, our policies and our solutions have to change as well.</p>



<p>But I want to be very clear: My fundamental view and my approach to the hemisphere has not changed.&nbsp; I still believe what I said then, and I hope that you do too.&nbsp; There is no reason why the Western Hemisphere can’t be the most forward-looking, most democratic, most prosperous, most peaceful, secure region in the world.&nbsp; We have unlimited potential.&nbsp; We have enormous resources and a democratic spirit that stands for freedom and opportunity for everybody.</p>



<p>And no matter what else is happening in the world, the Americas will always be a priority for the United States of America.</p>



<p>So, thank you again for being part of this summit.&nbsp; We have a busy few days and incredible opportunities ahead of us.&nbsp; So, let’s get to work.</p>



<p>And I’m now supposed to hush up and sit down, and we’re going to have a conversation.&nbsp; Is that right?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, Mr. President.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>(The plenary session begins.)</p>



<p>(The plenary session concludes.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ll be very brief.&nbsp; I want to thank you again for participating in the summit.</p>



<p>I think we’re off to a strong start.&nbsp; I heard a lot of important ideas raised.&nbsp; And notwithstanding some of the disagreements relating to participation, on the substantive matters what I heard was almost unity &#8212; uniformity: rational migration policy, doing something about the need to provide access to recovery and funding, a situation where we concluded that we must work on the environment and climate change, and so many other things.</p>



<p>And there’s no reason why the Western Hemisphere can’t be the most forward-looking, most democratic, most open and peaceful secure region in the world.</p>



<p>We can lead the world and &#8212; with the potential that exists in our people and our values.&nbsp; And so, the way we achieve that vision, I think, is by working together.&nbsp; And that’s what we’re doing these last couple of days.&nbsp; It’s going to take a challenge that’s &#8212; impacts on all of us &#8212; and to unlock the opportunities and the benefits that are available.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But notwithstanding the disagreements, think back to what we heard today.&nbsp; We heard almost total agreement on the substantive things that we should be doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let’s get down to real specifics in the next couple days as to what those substantive things are, how they’re implemented, who implements them, how we agree on them, what differences we have on them, so we get down to as &#8212; as the expression in English goes, “to brass tacks.”&nbsp; There’s probably a better Spanish or other phrase for it than mine.&nbsp; But get down to really what’s at stake so we can solve some serious problems.</p>



<p>Thank you all, and enjoy the rest of the day.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>3:47 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces Commitments to Advance Food Security in the Western&#160;Hemisphere</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-commitments-to-advance-food-security-in-the-western-hemisphere/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 22:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55223</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A year of rising energy and fuel prices, disruptions from the global pandemic, climate change, and the impact of Putin’s unprovoked war in Ukraine, are challenging food prices across the world and in the Western Hemisphere. Many of our neighbors rely significantly on imports for food and are particularly vulnerable to rising food costs. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>A year of rising energy and fuel prices, disruptions from the global pandemic, climate change, and the impact of Putin’s unprovoked war in Ukraine, are challenging food prices across the world and in the Western Hemisphere. Many of our neighbors rely significantly on imports for food and are particularly vulnerable to rising food costs. The region is experiencing the highest spike in food prices in a generation.<br><br>At the Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, the President is bringing together key partners to address this crisis and announcing $331 million for humanitarian assistance, food security assistance, and disaster risk reduction assistance&#8211; out of the $645 million total, that includes support for refugee and migrant populations.<br><br>The number of people facing severe food insecurity in Latin America and the Caribbean (LAC) doubled from 2014 to 2020 to more than 90 million people. Venezuela’s humanitarian, economic, and political crises have left approximately one-third of Venezuela’s population food-insecure and brought child malnutrition rates to emergency levels, with as many as 50% of children under five showing signs of malnutrition. In Honduras, the World Food Program reported that in late 2021, the number of people facing food insecurity had nearly doubled in just one year, due largely to the COVID-19 pandemic and the impact of Hurricanes Eta and Iota. And, we must address food insecurity in the region in order to advance our cooperative efforts on migration and climate smart economic reform.<br><br>The United States is expanding investments in key social safety nets to help reduce poverty and food shocks in the region and to contributing more funding for humanitarian and food security needs that will improve the quality of life for peoples across the region. The United States is a leader in the global campaign to improve food security, from our work last month as chair of the Global Food Security Call to Action Ministerial meeting, to our pledges at the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-commit-to-end-hunger-and-malnutrition-and-build-sustainable-resilient-food-systems/">UN Food Systems Summit</a> and the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/07/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-plans-for-11-billion-to-end-malnutrition-at-global-nutrition-summit/">2021 Tokyo Nutrition for Growth Summit</a>, and our recent assumption of the co-chairmanship of the Global Agricultural and Food Security Program (GAFSP). We are working closely with the International Financial Institutions to accelerate the response to food insecurity in key areas including: (i) supporting vulnerable people; (ii) promoting open trade; (iii) mitigating fertilizer shortages; (iv) supporting food production now; and (v) investing in climate-resilient agriculture for the future. We also welcome the prompt implementation of commitments outlined in the International Financial Institution (IFI) Action Plan to Address Food Insecurity.  <br><br><strong>Joint Declaration of Agriculture Exporters</strong>: One-third of the world’s food is produced in the Americas, and the current global food crisis is an opportunity and responsibility for the region to step up to supply a greater share of the world’s commodities. The United States will commit during the Summit to work together to increase food production for export, increase fertilizer production and transportation, and to improve agriculture efficiency through technical solutions and information exchanges.<br><br><strong>Food Security and Humanitarian Assistance</strong>: The Administration is announcing approximately $331 million in assistance to support food security needs and to provide humanitarian assistance across the hemisphere.  This contribution will complement the United States’ existing commitment to providing life-saving humanitarian assistance, responding to acute food insecurity, and advancing capacity-building activities that bolster disaster preparedness and response across LAC, including by developing early warning systems and providing technical assistance to first responders and community-based risk management entities. Through USAID partners, the United States continues to prioritize food as well as water and sanitation, shelter, protection services and basic health care for vulnerable populations in Haiti.  In Central America, USAID is delivering emergency food, livelihood, and protection assistance, particularly in El Salvador, Honduras, Guatemala.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris During Meeting with Leaders of Caribbean&#160;Nations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-during-meeting-with-leaders-of-caribbean-nations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55237</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles Convention CenterLos Angeles, California 1:45 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Welcome, Mr. President.&#160; We are in the midst of a discussion &#8212; a family conversation &#8212; with our colleagues, our friends who are members of CARICOM and, of course, the Dominican Republic.&#160; We have been engaged in a very candid conversation about the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles Convention Center<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>1:45 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Welcome, Mr. President.&nbsp; We are in the midst of a discussion &#8212; a family conversation &#8212; with our colleagues, our friends who are members of CARICOM and, of course, the Dominican Republic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have been engaged in a very candid conversation about the challenges that this region &#8212; our neighbors in this region are experiencing &#8212; an urgent need for resources, for collaboration, for cooperation, and for consideration of the challenges they face &#8212; and a way that we will help.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the range of topics has included the imminent, urgent matter of food insecurity.&nbsp; It has been about the development of climate finance and getting rid of some of the obstacles to access to finance for these nations &#8212; obstacles which I believe that some are unnecessary and can be eliminated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and also, we have talked about security issues.&nbsp; And in particular, one of the last points that was made about &#8212; was made about guns &#8212; and something that you are an extraordinary leader on, of course, in our country &#8212; and the need to take that seriously in terms of the trafficking of guns and what that has meant for these countries.</p>



<p>I have underscored in this meeting our commitment as an administration, your commitment as President to putting time and resources into strengthening this relationship, because we are neighbors and these countries are important to us for many reasons that include a shared history and shared values.</p>



<p>I present the President of the United States.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; Anyway, thank you for letting me crash the meeting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, folks, I thought it was important that I come by, because I think when you have everyone from presidents to prime minister to foreign ministers here, this should be principal to principal.&nbsp; The Vice President has been kind enough to take on managing this part of the portfolio for me, just as I did for &#8212; when I was Vice President for my former president.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I &#8212; but it is &#8212; it is something that &#8212; and I&#8217;ve asked her to personally do this, but it is my responsibility.&nbsp; And I want you to know that on a leader-to-leader level, like we did whether it&#8217;s at dealing with climate in Europe or here, it’s &#8212; it should be person to person.&nbsp; And you should have access to me, and I hope I can have access to you as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, there&#8217;s a lot to talk about.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know if what you &#8212; were you talking about it all in front of the press here?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because &#8212;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; we had &#8212; we had a bit of a conversation &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; I love the press &#8212;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; in front of the press, but it’s &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; but I’d like to get into &#8212; if you’re willing, for a few minutes &#8212; how &#8212; let you know my intention is to intensify the relationship with the Caribbean.&nbsp; And I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; You&#8217;re critically important to us in every way, and I hope we&#8217;re important to you.</p>



<p>And I think that there&#8217;s a means by which we can maybe undo some of the damage done the previous four years, when it wasn&#8217;t very much taken seriously &#8212; the relationships.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, you know, I know most of you represent middle- and high-income countries, and it’s put you in a difficult position which cuts you off from any of the international financial tools that are out there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we&#8217;ve got some answers to be able to be significantly helpful in that regard I’d like to talk with you about in a few minutes.&nbsp; And &#8212; and I think that, you know, we can better prepare for natural disasters and rebuild after you get hit, increase resilience for future crises, including dealing with &#8212; there will be other pandemics that are coming down the line.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, there&#8217;s a lot that I think that we can and should do.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m here not to tell you anything, but to hear what&#8217;s on your minds.&nbsp; This is a partnership.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not &#8212; I&#8217;m not &#8212; we&#8217;re not here to dictate.&nbsp; We&#8217;re here to &#8212; I&#8217;m here to learn, as well as to tell you what we&#8217;re prepared to do and what &#8212; you can ask me additional things you think we should or shouldn&#8217;t be doing.</p>



<p>And, for example, you know, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; I think we can work with you to strengthen the region’s ability to adapt to climate change; improve collaboration at the government-to-government level on great &#8212; you know, a lot greater private investment for &#8212; from around the world and from the United States and the hemisphere in &#8212; in the Caribbean; and our new U.S.-Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis (inaudible) going to help enhance your climate resilience and your energy security; and to meet some sustainable development goals.</p>



<p>So, I think there’s an awful lot we can do.&nbsp; And I think as &#8212; as the gentlelady from Barbados will tell you &#8212; we discussed this at the climate conference there &#8212; you know, I think we have to understand that the major countries of the world, not just us, have an obligation to help the rest of the world &#8212; not just the Caribbean, but the African continent and other places &#8212; to deal with the consequences of the damage done by climate by the wealthy countries.&nbsp; Why we&#8217;ve &#8212; because we&#8217;ve developed &#8212; we&#8217;ve cleared our land,&nbsp;we planted, we &#8212; you know, we’ve done all this stuff.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and now to come along &#8212;&nbsp;and the infrastructure you need to deal with your &#8212; the consequences of climate are going to be incredibly expensive.&nbsp; And I think we have an obligation to step up and &#8212; and help meet those obligations, meet those infrastructure changes, and so much more.</p>



<p>So, that&#8217;s what I&#8217;d like to talk with you about, and I&#8217;d like to find out what&#8217;s on your mind.&nbsp; But thank you for being here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think, with your permission, I’d like to listen to what&#8217;s on your minds and &#8212; and maybe follow up on this as we can.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any concerns about the boycott?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>1:52 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-justin-trudeau-of-canada-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles Convention CenterLos Angeles, California 12:08 P.M. PDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Mr. Prime Minister and to your delegation, we start by saying we have no better friend in the whole world than Canada.&#160; And that&#8217;s not hyperbole.&#160; That&#8217;s real.&#160; And you’re a good personal friend as well. Before I begin, one of the things that’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles Convention Center<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>12:08 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Mr. Prime Minister and to your delegation, we start by saying we have no better friend in the whole world than Canada.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; That&#8217;s real.&nbsp; And you’re a good personal friend as well.</p>



<p>Before I begin, one of the things that’s going to occupy my country tonight, I suspect, is the first open hearings on January the 6th.&nbsp; And as I said when it was occurring and subsequent, I think it was a clear, flagrant violation of the Constitution.&nbsp; I think these guys and women broke the law, tried to turn around the result of an election.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a lot of questions &#8212; who&#8217;s responsible, who&#8217;s involved.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to make a judgment on that, but I just want to know that &#8212; want you to know that we&#8217;re going to probably be &#8212; a lot of Americans are going to be seeing for the first time some of the detail that occurred.</p>



<p>But you and I have a lot to talk about.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be hanging out with each other a fair amount at the G7, at the NATO conference in Spain.</p>



<p>But today we&#8217;re engaged in our hemisphere.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; it’s presumptive of me to say, but I think we both share the same sense that the possibilities for the hemisphere are unlimited.</p>



<p>We already have with &#8212; notwithstanding some difficulties in the hemisphere, we already have a circumstance where it&#8217;s the most democratic hemisphere in the world.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no reason why, from Canada and along the Arctic, all the way down to the tip of Chile and Argentina, that we can&#8217;t &#8212; this can&#8217;t become a more &#8212; a democratic, a united, and middle-class, economically prosperous hemisphere.</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s one of my objectives in this Summit of the Americas.&nbsp; There’s a lot we have to work through.&nbsp; But I want to thank you for your partnership.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER TRUDEAU:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; That’s a place I want to start &#8212; just the friendship between Canada and the United States is deep.&nbsp; It was reminded to me as I was visiting NORAD a couple of days ago just how much we do together.&nbsp; We’re the only places &#8212; the only place in world where there is a truly binational command to protect our homelands.&nbsp; It is an example of that.</p>



<p>But as we gather here today, and the reflections that you’re bringing forward on democracy, it reminds us that it is extraordinarily important to be there for each other and to be there for our allies around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the work that we can do on supporting and projecting and sharing our values has a way of actually supporting and impacting citizens around the world to make the case that democracy is not just fairer but it’s also better for citizens, in terms of putting food on the table, putting futures in front of them.&nbsp; Those are the things we need to work on.</p>



<p>We have worked very closely over the past many months on the issue of Ukraine, where Canada is deeply engaged and supportive of everything we’re doing as a West on being there against Russia’s illegal invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; And we will continue to work together on that.</p>



<p>We’re also dealing with real challenges around climate around the world and stepping up on that.&nbsp; And it’s always a pleasure to be doing that.&nbsp; But the center of it has to be, even as we gather with our friends across the Americas, how we create prosperity, how we counter the rising cost of living, how we create good jobs for our citizens not just in our respective countries but in each other’s countries and throughout the hemisphere.</p>



<p>And that’s why I’m so pleased to be here to work with you on.</p>



<p>(Speaks in French.)&nbsp; (No translation provided.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Well, thank you all very much.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>12:12 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in a Meeting With Leaders of Caribbean&#160;Nations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-a-meeting-with-leaders-of-caribbean-nations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 21:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:40 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone.  I &#8212; it is good to see all of you again.  We met virtually just a few weeks ago, and I&#8217;m looking forward to the conversation that we will have &#8212; a continuing conversation about the work we will do together, our partnership, and the commitments that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:40 P.M. PDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone.  I &#8212; it is good to see all of you again.  We met virtually just a few weeks ago, and I&#8217;m looking forward to the conversation that we will have &#8212; a continuing conversation about the work we will do together, our partnership, and the commitments that we are prepared to make with each other around the issues that challenge us, but also the opportunities that are presented.<br> <br>As neighbors in the Western Hemisphere, the United States shares common bonds and interests with Caribbean nations.  As I said when we convened six weeks ago, our partnership is key to our shared prosperity and security.<br> <br>Today, our main focus will be the climate crisis, which, of course, is an existential crisis for our entire planet, and the Caribbean is on the front line of this crisis.<br> <br>In our last meeting, we discussed your priorities as it relates to this issue and many others.  And I indicated that the United States would look into these issues and work with you as we seek to resolve the challenges that each of our nations are presented with.  And I committed that we would develop a plan.<br> <br>Today, I&#8217;m pleased to announce the launch of the United States-Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis, also known as PACC &#8212; P-A-C-C &#8212; 2030.  PACC 2030 is the United States government&#8217;s primary mechanism for addressing energy security and the climate crisis in this region.<br> <br>Through this partnership, we will support energy infrastructure and climate resilience projects at every stage of development, from beginning to end, in four particular ways.<br> <br>First, we will work with you to identify new clean energy projects.<br> <br>Second, we will provide technical assistance to make sure these projects are viable and appealing not only to you, but to investors.  We will bring them &#8212; investors &#8212; to the Caribbean on, essentially, roadshows to showcase the projects.<br> <br>And fourth and finally, we will improve access &#8212; and importantly &#8212; we will improve access to development financing, which will make these projects a reality.  We will engage with the private sector at every stage of this work because, of course, their involvement is essential to making this productive and meaningful.<br> <br>When we accelerate the transition to clean energy, I think we all believe that we unlock great economic opportunities for the entire region.<br> <br>When we work together to address this urgent threat, it benefits the people of the United States and the people of the Caribbean.  And all of us, of course, benefit by reducing emissions.<br> <br>In conclusion, strengthening the U.S.-Caribbean relationship is a priority for me.<br> <br>And regarding the climate crisis, it is one of our highest priorities.  But there are other issues that are also very important that we can and must address together.<br> <br>I want to thank all of the leaders for being here.  Again, welcome to Los Angeles, to California.  And I look forward to a meaningful conversation and a productive conversation &#8212; meaning that out of our conversations thus far, we have actually taken action.  And I look forward to continuing to do just that.<br> <br>And with that, I now invite Dr. Carla Barnett, the Secretary General of the Caribbean Community, also known as CARICOM, to share a few words.<br> <br>END                 12:44 P.M. PDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the Fourth CEO Summit of the&#160;Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-fourth-ceo-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 20:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Intercontinental HotelLos Angeles, California 11:13 A.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Mr. Ambassador.&#160; Thank you all so much.&#160; Please, have a seat.&#160; I’ve only been President about a year and a half, but every time I walk in a room and everybody stands up, I think there may be a fire or something.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Press,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Intercontinental Hotel<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>11:13 A.M. PDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Ambassador.&nbsp; Thank you all so much.&nbsp; Please, have a seat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve only been President about a year and a half, but every time I walk in a room and everybody stands up, I think there may be a fire or something.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Press, that was a joke.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; That was a joke.</p>



<p>Well, it’s wonderful to be with you this morning.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; I want to thank the Chamber of Commerce for bringing together this group of business leaders from all across the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all of us here in Los Angeles for a simple reason: because we believe in the incredible economic potential of the Americas.&nbsp; I know I do.&nbsp; We all do.&nbsp; I mean, it’s &#8212; I &#8212; I just think the potential is unlimited.</p>



<p>The region is filled with dynamic energy: entrepreneurs who are ready to break out, innovators who will change the way we think and the way we do things, young people poised to seize the future.</p>



<p>Everybody &#8212; the press always asks me why am I so optimistic with the way things are.&nbsp; Take a look at all these young folks.&nbsp; They’re the best educated.&nbsp; They’re the most generous.&nbsp; They’re the people who have done the most, they’re ready to volunteer, and they’re the least prejudiced folks in the world.&nbsp; It’s a new generation.&nbsp; And underpinning &#8212; it gives me an enormous sense of &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; an enormous sense of optimism.</p>



<p>We have everything we need right here in the Western Hemisphere not only to point ourselves toward a future that is more prosperous, secure, and democratic, but the ability to achieve it as well.&nbsp; And for &#8212; all of you are essential to making sure we get to this place we have to get to.</p>



<p>You know, the private sector is able to move quickly to mobilize vast amounts of investment capital that’s going to be needed to unlock the enormous potential for growth in this hemisphere, in the region.</p>



<p>And when we combine the ability of government to direct economic activity toward specific challenges, to help mitigate risks, guard against unfair practices, and create a predictable demand with the agility of the private sector, I believe we can deliver real improvements for people’s lives.&nbsp; I really believe it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, just &#8212; well, I &#8212; my wife often reminds me that I had a doctor who &#8212; a long time ago &#8212; who was saying, when I had &#8212; I had an aneurism, he kept saying, “Is it congenital or is it environmental?”&nbsp; And I said, “I don’t care.&nbsp; I just &#8212; just get it done.”&nbsp; He said, “You know what your problem is, Senator?”&nbsp; I said, “No.”&nbsp; He said, “You’re a congenital optimist.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I am.&nbsp; I’m an American, and that’s why I’m a congenital optimist.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So, look &#8212; I really mean it.&nbsp; We can do anything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jobs that pay good wages and respect workers’ rights.</p>



<p>Communities that come to life around investments.&nbsp; Families that can envision a future with an opportunity to just &#8212; as my dad would say, “just give them a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp; A little bit of breathing room.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When that happens, everyone prospers, including all of you.&nbsp; All of you.&nbsp; But to achieve this, we’ve got to update our recipe, in my view, for economic growth.&nbsp; It’s time to put a nail in the coffin, in my view, of trickle-down economics.&nbsp; It doesn’t work.&nbsp; It keeps you in an increasingly smaller and smaller world.&nbsp; It doesn’t work.&nbsp; It keeps yielding the same results: greater inequity, slower growth, less competition, and less innovation.</p>



<p>In the past few years, we exposed the weakness of prioritizing short-term profits and working exclusively to maximize efficiency.</p>



<p>We learned firsthand the pain that happens when just-in-time supply chains break down or hit a bottleneck.&nbsp; It’s a fundamental difference.&nbsp; And to all of &#8212; and you all felt it as well.</p>



<p>The COVID-19 pandemic triggered a global economic crisis that we’re still digging out of.</p>



<p>And now, Putin’s brutal, unprovoked war in Ukraine has created economic disruptions that are affecting the entire globe.&nbsp; And that’s not hyperbole.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And these won’t be the only shocks we’re going to have to navigate.&nbsp; Climate change is increasing the pace and intensity of natural disasters. I leave from here &#8212; on my way back east, I&#8217;m going to be stopping in New Mexico.&nbsp; They’ve had an incredible impact on their &#8212; on their environment of late.</p>



<p>Rising inequity and food insecurity around the world can fuel political instability.&nbsp; You all know that.</p>



<p>And the question is not “if” we face another pandemic; it’s “when” we face it and are we going to be prepared this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the economy of the future will increasingly belong to those who place a premium on resilience and reliability, who invest in innovation over long te- &#8212; over the long term and strengthen systems and supply chains now, and mitigate the impact of future shocks before they hit.</p>



<p>Each of us &#8212; each of us &#8212; the government and the private sector &#8212; have a critical role to play.&nbsp; That’s why I’m focused on driving economic policies that grow our economy from the bottom up and the middle out, because, quite frankly, when that works, everybody does well and the wealthy do very, very well.&nbsp; No one gets hurt.&nbsp; No one gets hurt.</p>



<p>For example, here in the United States, we’re making a generational investment on our infrastructure.&nbsp; It used to &#8212; we used to be number one in the world when I first came to the United States Congress.&nbsp; Now we’re number 13 in the world.&nbsp; Thirteen.</p>



<p>I don’t have to tell business people what that means in term of economic growth.&nbsp; But we’re fixing that.&nbsp; That’s going to be the benefit to the entire region.</p>



<p>We’re investing $1.2 trillion, bipartisanly, to upgrade our infrastructure &#8212; to fix crumbling roads and bridges and ports, airports all across the country.</p>



<p>And that’s going to help you get goods to market faster while creating good-paying union jobs &#8212; and I know a lot of you don’t like my saying “union” &#8212; but unions jobs to support working families, because that’s what&#8217;s happening.</p>



<p>Everyone benefits.&nbsp; Everybody wins when that occurs.</p>



<p>And the return on our investment is going to strengthen U.S. competitiveness throughout the 21st century.</p>



<p>You know, this is the same approach we’re taking across the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity.</p>



<p>Many of the countries in our region qualify as middle-income countries, but that label doesn’t remove the persistent structural challenges that run &#8212; and deep inequity.&nbsp; “Middle-income” means you don’t get the benefit of a lot of opportunities.</p>



<p>So, we can change that and help governments make life better, easier, and fairer for their peoples by using hemispheric multinational financial institutions to modernize and mobilize greater levels of private investment and create good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>I know there are real barriers for you to contend with.&nbsp; That’s why we want to work with you to level the playing field.</p>



<p>As I said last night, the United States is prepared to put new capital in the Inter-American Development Bank’s private-sector lending arm &#8212; the IDB Invest &#8212; to help catalyze the flow of private capital into the region, especially to support startups, digital connec- &#8212; digital connectivity, and renewable energy, and health.</p>



<p>For example, we need to make it easier for countries in Latin America and the Caribbean to develop their 5G infrastructure without having to choose between investing in their digital future or renewable energy structure &#8212; to be able to do both.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We de- &#8212; we need to unlock the financing so that both can be done at the same time.&nbsp; We want to make sure our closest neighbors have a real choice between the debt-trap development that has become more common &#8212; more and more common in the region and the high-quality, transparent approach to infrastructure and investment that delivers lasting gains for workers and their families.</p>



<p>And by working through the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation to lower the risk around these kinds of investments, support policy reforms to improve investment in climate in countries &#8212; excuse me &#8212; the investment in climate &#8212; the climate investment in these countries, and level the playing field, we’re going to open up new areas of private-sector investors that are not only economically viable but are highly desirable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, over the course of this summit, the governments are coming together to make significant, concrete commitments across a range of issues vital to achieving sustainable and equitable growth throughout the region:</p>



<p>On bringing supply chains closer to home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On fostering innovation and developing a shared framework for our digital future.</p>



<p>On kicking our action on climate change into high gear and speeding our clean energy transition.</p>



<p>On bolstering health systems and food security in the Western Hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On managing safe and orderly migration as a shared responsibility through innovative and coordinated action to enforce our borders and stabilize migrant populations, while seizing the shared opportunity for economic growth.</p>



<p>My challenge to all of you is: If you step up and play a bigger role in driving inclusive, sustainable, equitable growth in the 21st century, a lot is going to happen.&nbsp; What more can you do to engage in these issues that shape our future?&nbsp; Not as a favor to me or to any government leader, but because it’s in your own overwhelming economic self-interest.</p>



<p>If you make the investments necessary to build more secure and resilient supply chains, that’s ultimately going to bring down your cost and make you more competitive and boost your bottom line.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’re going to hear from John Kerry about the opportunities for private-sector innovation and new markets that will be critical to reach our climate goals.</p>



<p>Yesterday, Vice President Harris spoke about the $3.2 billion mobili- &#8212; mobilized by our Call to Action efforts in Central America, including &#8212; including from several companies in this room, to bring quality economic opportunity to the region.</p>



<p>We’re expanding the 100,000 Strong in the Americas program to focus on opportunities for young people in climate and STEM fields, especially in the Caribbean and Central America.</p>



<p>And I urge you &#8212; I urge you to join us with matching funds, just as you did when we launched the program 10 years ago.</p>



<p>There are many more examples, but let me close with this:&nbsp; We stand at an inflection point.&nbsp; I know you’re tired of hearing me say when I was running, and I continue to say it every day.&nbsp; We’re at an inflection point.&nbsp; More is going to change in the next 10 years than has changed in the last 30 years in the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Decisions we make today are going to have far-reaching impacts on our future.&nbsp; They’re going to last well into the middle of the century.&nbsp; And, business leaders, as &#8212; you all see where the trend lines are reporting &#8212; are pointing as clearly as I do.</p>



<p>And our challenge is to shape the outcomes so the future reflects the democratic values of our region, an economy that we want to live and work in and that ensures a fair playing field for our workers and our businesses.</p>



<p>As we navigate this inflection point, leaders and business and those who come out ahead are going to be the people who are going to lead this change for the future &#8212; not those stuck looking backwards and sitting on the sidelines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>None of us will be able to fully realize our ambition for the region on our own.</p>



<p>So let’s use this summit to tackle the obstacles to growth, come together around new ideas and new opportunities to take our region’s biggest challenges on and defeat them, and for all of us &#8212; all of us to prosper.</p>



<p>I really believe there is nothing we&#8217;re unable to do.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;re prime &#8212; we’re primed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll close with this that I&#8217;m going to say a little later at the general session: I think &#8212; I find no reason why the Western Hemisphere &#8212; the Western Hemisphere, over the next 10 years, is not developed into the most democratic hemisphere in the world, most democratic region in the entire world.&nbsp; We have everything.&nbsp; We have the people.&nbsp; We have the resources.&nbsp; And we have more democracies in this hemisphere than any other hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there&#8217;s a lot we can do, but a lot of it matters in the private enterprise side of the equation.&nbsp; You all &#8212; you all are on the <s>font</s> [front] of enormous ideas and opportunities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I want to thank you all, and I look forward to working with you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as &#8212; as my &#8212; every time I’d walk out of my Grandpop Finnegan’s house, he’d yell, “Joey, keep the faith.”&nbsp; And my grandmother would yell, “No, Joey, spread it.&nbsp; Spread the faith.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>11:26 A.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Trudeau of&#160;Canada</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-trudeau-of-canada/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 20:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada in Los Angeles on the margins of the Ninth Summit of the Americas to review regional cooperation on economic development, the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, and food insecurity. The President and Prime Minister underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada in Los Angeles on the margins of the Ninth Summit of the Americas to review regional cooperation on economic development, the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, and food insecurity. The President and Prime Minister underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for its brutal actions in Ukraine, and reviewed their ongoing efforts to provide economic, development, and humanitarian aid to the millions of Ukrainians affected by the violence, as well as to provide security assistance to the government of Ukraine.  The President lauded Canada’s close partnership with the United States throughout this crisis and its leadership in enacting comprehensive sanctions and restrictions on Russia. The President also stated he looks forward to seeing the Prime Minister in Madrid for the NATO Summit.<br> <br>The Leaders also discussed the potential of developing critical minerals in both countries and joint efforts to make our supply chains and economies more resilient to external shocks, including through the work of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/CANADA-U.S.-SUPPLY-CHAINS-PROGRESS-REPORT.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the U.S.-Canada Supply Chain Working Group</a>.  As major energy producers, both Canada and the United States play key roles in supporting security and resilience of supply chains, but Leaders also emphasized a shared commitment to achieve net-zero emissions by 2050 to decrease our reliance on fossil fuels. The President thanked the Prime Minister for Canada’s support to bolster democracy in the Americas and throughout in the world, and for Canada’s support of the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity and the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection. Both Leaders reaffirmed the strong bonds between our nations and their commitment to deepening the U.S.-Canada relationship across the breadth of our bilateral agenda.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/09/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-85/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 19:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 11:10 A.M. EDT DR. JHA:&#160; Good morning, everybody.&#160; I’m delighted to be joined by two great colleagues: the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, Dawn O’Connell, and our nation’s Surgeon General, Dr. Vivek Murthy.&#160; Thank you for joining us. Now, today we want to provide an update on a topic that I know&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:10 A.M. EDT<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Good morning, everybody.&nbsp; I’m delighted to be joined by two great colleagues: the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, Dawn O’Connell, and our nation’s Surgeon General, Dr. Vivek Murthy.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us.</p>



<p>Now, today we want to provide an update on a topic that I know many parents and grandparents are focused on: the potential for the first COVID-19 vaccines for kids under five.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have waited a long time for this moment.&nbsp; More than two years into the COVID-19 pandemic and after nearly 18 months since the first set of vaccines became available for adults, we are on the cusp of having safe, highly effective vaccines for kids under five.</p>



<p>Now, we want to lay out today the work we’re doing to make sure parents can easily get access to those vaccines.</p>



<p>Let me start off by making one very important point: We are not here to prejudge the outcome of the independent, science-driven process that is being led both by FDA and the CDC.</p>



<p>The FDA’s advisory committee is going to be meeting next week on Tuesday, June 14th, and Wednesday, June 15th, to review the data that was submitted by Pfizer and Moderna, and they will make their recommendations.&nbsp; We expect the FDA to make a decision shortly after those meetings.</p>



<p>The CDC’s Advisory Committee is then going to meet on Friday, June 17th, and Saturday, June 18th.&nbsp; We expect the CDC Director, Dr. Rochelle Walensky, to then make her recommendation sometime after those meetings.&nbsp; If the FDA authorizes and CDC recommends that kids under five get vaccinated, vaccinations will begin quickly thereafter.</p>



<p>So, what does this mean for you if you’re a parent or a pediatrician?&nbsp; Realistically, it means we could see shots in arms of kids under five as early as the week of June 20th.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, as a reminder, Monday, June 20th, is an important federal holiday in observation of Juneteenth, and so we expect that many pediatricians’ offices may be closed.&nbsp; So we think that vaccinations would really start in earnest on Tuesday, June 21st.</p>



<p>And importantly, vac- &#8212; the vaccination program is going to ramp up in the days and weeks that follow, with more and more doses and more and more appointments becoming available.</p>



<p>Now, let’s actually take a moment to understand what a historic moment this is.&nbsp; If the FDA and CDC recommend these vaccines, this would mark an important moment in the pandemic.&nbsp; It would mean that, for the first time, essentially every American, from our oldest to our youngest, would be eligible for the protection that vaccines provide.</p>



<p>Now, I know many parents have been eagerly awaiting the opportunity to vaccinate their youngest kids.&nbsp; We share in that eagerness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also know that it is important to do this right.</p>



<p>As my HHS colleagues will detail, we have been planning for this moment for months.&nbsp; We have been getting ready to launch a comprehensive effort to help America’s youngest kids get protected.&nbsp; That means working with state and local health departments.&nbsp; It means working with America’s pediatricians and family doctors.&nbsp; It means working with pharmacies and rural health clinics and community health centers and so many more.</p>



<p>Now, I want to close with a word on what we already know about COVID-19 vaccines and kids.&nbsp; While the deliberations and the data review for vaccines for kids under five are ongoing, we know that for kids over five, vaccines have made a tremendous difference.</p>



<p>Kids who are vaccinated are far less likely to get seriously ill from COVID.&nbsp; They’re far less likely to end up in the hospital or in the ICU.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re far less likely to get complications of COVID, like Multisystem Inflammatory Syndrome of Children.</p>



<p>Vaccines are already making an enormous difference in keeping our kids over five protected as the pandemic continues.</p>



<p>Tens of millions of children in the U.S. and around the world have been vaccinated against COVID, and the safety profile of these vaccines is truly extraordinary.</p>



<p>So, the data on kids over five and vaccines is clear: Kids are better protected, they are better off if they’re vaccinated.&nbsp; That’s why I, as a dad, have three children, all of whom have been vaccinated and boosted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is why every physician, including every pediatrician and family physician I know, has vaccinated their own eligible kids and why we are anxiously awaiting the careful review of the FDA and the CDC to determine whether we can extend that protection to kids under five.</p>



<p>You know, when President Biden took office, he made a commitment to ensure that every American benefitted from the miracles that science has delivered us in these pandemics.</p>



<p>If these vaccines are authorized and recommended, we will get one giant step closer to fulfilling that commitment.</p>



<p>So, thank you for joining us this morning.&nbsp; I’d like to turn it over now to my colleague, Dawn O’Connell.</p>



<p>Dawn.</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Jha.&nbsp; I&#8217;m pleased to be here.</p>



<p>Over the past 16 months, together with our partners, we have managed one of the most complex logistical challenges in our nation’s history: delivering more than 700 million doses of COVID-19 vaccine to more than 90,000 locations nationwide.</p>



<p>Today, more than 220 million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; But we know that our work is not done yet.</p>



<p>COVID-19 vaccines for kids under the age of five would be a momentous milestone in our historic vaccination program, helping extend the protection that vaccines offer to our youngest Americans and some additional peace of mind to parents and guardians.</p>



<p>Our objective is clear: to be ready to swiftly and efficiently deliver vaccines for kids under the age of five to communities nationwide as soon as the FDA grants emergency use authorization.</p>



<p>We are ready.</p>



<p>To achieve our objective, we have engaged state, local, Tribal, and territorial health departments; pediatricians and primary care providers; children’s hospitals and health systems; and pharmacies on operational planning.</p>



<p>These are many of the same partners we&#8217;ve been engaged with on other vaccination and COVID-19 response efforts over the past few years.&nbsp; These partners are on the frontlines and critical to success, and we stand ready to help them in any way we can.</p>



<p>Last week, we opened up pre-ordering for states, Tribes, territories, and other partners to order doses.&nbsp; We are making 10 million doses of vaccine available initially, with millions more available in the coming weeks.</p>



<p>This approach allows us to seed communities with enough vaccine so that it is readily accessible and equitably distributed across the country.</p>



<p>We estimate that 85 percent of children under the age of five live within five miles of a potential vaccination site.</p>



<p>We have asked states and other partners to leverage prior pediatric vaccination best practices and tap into existing pediatric vaccination locations as they continue to sign up additional pediatricians and providers.</p>



<p>We have also asked states and other partners to ensure equity, giving priority to sites that will vaccinate children at highest risk for severe COVID-19 disease and considering factors such as hours of operation.</p>



<p>At this point in the Biden administration’s vaccination program, our partners are accustomed to this process, and so are we.&nbsp; Our teams are standing by and will immediately begin shipping vaccines across the country after &#8212; should FDA authorize a vaccine.</p>



<p>It will take some time to position these vaccines across the country, and vaccinations can’t begin until CDC has made its decision.&nbsp; But we also know that many parents have been waiting for a long time, so we will be working 24/7 until every dose is shipped and delivered.</p>



<p>As we have said previously, we are not in the predicting business, we’re in the planning business.&nbsp; Our teams are hard at work planning for the possibility that FDA and CDC will give the green light in the near future.&nbsp; And if and when they do, we will be ready to deliver.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; And I’ll turn to you now, Dr. Murthy.</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Thanks so much, Dawn.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First of all, it’s good to be with everyone again today.</p>



<p>As many of you know, my daughter is four years old, and she&#8217;s not yet eligible to be vaccinated.&nbsp; And my wife Alice and I, like millions of parents across the country, carry with us every day an added layer of worry knowing that our children under five don’t have the same opportunity as older children and adults to get vaccinated and, hence, protected from the worst outcomes of COVID-19.</p>



<p>More than 30,000 children under five in our country have been hospitalized with COVID during this pandemic, and nearly 500 deaths have been reported in this age group.&nbsp; So I know how eager many parents and caregivers are for good news on this front, to know that our youngest children have an added layer of protection.</p>



<p>But I also know that all of us as parents want to ensure that anything we are giving our children has gone through a rigorous scientific assessment and that it is both safe and effective for our kids.</p>



<p>That is why as soon as the FDA authorizes and the CDC recommends a pediatric vaccine for kids under five, we are going to launch a national public education campaign to ensure parents and families have all the information they need to make the best choices for their children.</p>



<p>Now, in addition to having medical and scientific experts from government speaking to communities, we will be working closely with community partners, as we have done in the past, to make sure that community members are hearing from local leaders and organizations that they know and trust.</p>



<p>We’re going to partner with organizations like the American Academy of Pediatrics, the Association of Children’s Museums, the American Library Association, the National PTA, the National Diaper Bank Network, and the National Association of Community Health Centers, as well as a number of Black, Latino, Asian American, Native Hawaiian, Pacific Islander, and Native American community-based organizations, including the W. Montague Cobb Health Institute and LULAC, the League of United Latin American Citizens.</p>



<p>We will support these organizations and local stakeholders as they launch health fairs, pop-up clinics, community forums, doctors’ speaking bureaus, and more.</p>



<p>And we’re going to mobilize the 17,000-plus-member COVID-19 Community Corps, which we launched last spring, to help provide creative, kid-focused English and Spanish language toolkits for trusted local messengers, including, I would add, a superhero-themed toolkit that I can tell you will play well in my house.</p>



<p>In this effort, we’re going to be building on lessons that we have learned and the trusted networks that we’ve built over the last 18 months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our prior COVID-19 vaccination efforts helped us protect millions of Americans from hospitalization and loss of life.&nbsp; As before, we will ensure that equity is at the center of our approach as we work hard to get vaccines to our hardest-hit communities.</p>



<p>I do want to caution parents about one thing, and that is misinformation.&nbsp; Misinformation has been a challenge throughout this pandemic.</p>



<p>And as I have said in the past when I issued a Surgeon General’s Advisory on Health Misinformation, false and misleading information about COVID-19 &#8212; misinformation that is often spread on social media, in fact &#8212; has led to confusion and has prevented people from benefiting from lifesaving treatments and vaccines.</p>



<p>So please make sure the information you are relying on is coming from trusted sources like your doctor, your local children&#8217;s hospital, your department of health, medical associations like the American Academy of Pediatrics, and the FDA and CDC.</p>



<p>Lastly, I want to emphasize this: Real progress in our vaccination effort has happened when people who are trusted in their communities reach out to their friends, families, neighbors, and community members.&nbsp; And that is what we will need to do now as well: build a people-powered campaign to protect our youngest children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to close by saying to those trusted messengers and, in particular, the pediatricians, family physicians, and nurses out there just how much our nation needs your help right now to make this effort a success as we work to keeping our youngest ones safe.</p>



<p>Whether it is in countering misinformation with accurate, science-based information or helping families find places to get vaccinated, your role could not be more vital right now as it has been throughout this pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m incredibly grateful for all you have done to serve and protect your communities over the last two and a half years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, let me turn it back to Dr. Jha.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Murthy.&nbsp; And thank you, Dawn.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s now open it up for questions.&nbsp; And to Kevin, do you want to call on folks to ask their questions?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Yes, thank you.&nbsp; We have time for a few questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Joyce Frieden at MedPage Today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp; Hello?</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Hi, Joyce.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you &#8212; okay.&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; My question is about the money.&nbsp; I&#8217;m interested in how much doing all this is costing.&nbsp; And also, you know, previously, the President had talked about there maybe not being enough money for vaccines later on if, you know, Congress didn&#8217;t act and so forth. &nbsp;So I&#8217;m wondering how that might impact this effort.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to start it and then see if Ms. O’Connell has anything else to add.</p>



<p>Look, the good news is, because of prior funding from Congress, we have secured enough vaccines and we have the resources to get these vaccines out to the American people. We&#8217;ve been very clear that because of those resources, we can get every child who wants to be vaccinated, every parent who wants to vaccinate their kid vaccinated now.&nbsp; We have the resources to do this this summer.</p>



<p>The challenge &#8212; the resource challenge, the money challenge you&#8217;ve been hearing about from me, from others, is really about what&#8217;s going to happen in the fall.&nbsp; We do not have enough resources for the &#8212; to have enough vaccines for every American for the next generation of vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the challenges are coming up in the fall.&nbsp; We need the money now.&nbsp; But the money we&#8217;re using for kids’ vaccines today is money that was appropriated previously by Congress.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, next question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Betsy Klein at CNN.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Betsy?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, can you &#8212;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yes, we can hear you now.&nbsp; Or not.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Betsy, we can &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; Just to follow up on COVID funding, can &#8212; Dr. Jha, if you could give us an update on whether the last month you&#8217;ve had meetings on Capitol Hill, if that&#8217;s borne any fruit, and whether there&#8217;s been any congressional reaction on your end to some of the funding reallocations you announced yesterday.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So let&#8217;s take a step back and talk about the kinds of decisions we are having to make.&nbsp; What you heard yesterday was us making a series of very painful decisions, taking resources away from what we think are vital programs to make sure that we&#8217;re at the table when it comes to purchasing the next generation of vaccines, to make sure that we have enough therapeutics for Americans so &#8212; as we get into the fall and winter.</p>



<p>These are very, very difficult choices.&nbsp; These are not &#8212; this is not where we should be in the pandemic.&nbsp; We have been making &#8212; we&#8217;ve been communicating this very clearly to Congress.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been meeting with members of Congress, both Democrats and Republicans, in the House and Senate.</p>



<p>And I think members of Congress that I&#8217;ve been meeting with and speaking with understand the situation we are in.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve got to keep making this point clear.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me just say one more thing.&nbsp; Because of the delay that Congress has not acted, we are losing our place in line in terms of our ability to get vaccines and therapeutics out to the American people this fall and winter.&nbsp; This is why it&#8217;s urgent that Congress act now and get us the resources we need as an administration so we can continue to get the tools we need to protect the American people.</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; (Inaudible) add something to that as well?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Please.</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Betsy, I&#8217;m really glad you asked this point.&nbsp; And I would just add to what Dr. Jha said.&nbsp; When I go around the country and talk to people across America about our &#8212; where we are in the COVID pandemic, people don&#8217;t understand why it is that after incredible progress that we made developing lifesaving vaccines or treatments, after demonstrating that we&#8217;re actually able to save lives by making these available to people, we are now suddenly halting, when it comes to funding, the ongoing availability of these lifesaving treatments and tests.</p>



<p>It doesn&#8217;t make sense to people, and I think that&#8217;s because it doesn&#8217;t make sense.&nbsp; It&#8217;s because we learned in prior public health emergencies that when we fail to sustain our attention and funding to public health interventions, the cost of that failure can be measured in illness incurred and lives lost.</p>



<p>This is a choice.&nbsp; You know, it is not inevitable that we &#8212; you know, that we don&#8217;t have funding and that we don&#8217;t make these treatments and tests available.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a choice.&nbsp; And my hope is that we can &#8212; and our collective hope is that we can make the choice, work together with Congress to get that funding &#8212; because, again, we are in a much better place in this pandemic than we were, but we are not done with the pandemic.&nbsp; The virus is still here, and we&#8217;re reminded that, you know, each day.&nbsp; You know, and we look at the folks who are getting infected; we&#8217;re still losing several hundred people a day to this virus.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve got to keep going.&nbsp; This is not the time to take our focus off the pandemic.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Thank you, Vivek.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m just going to add one more quick thing to this, which is a point that I think often gets lost and it&#8217;s really the point that Dr. Murthy was making.&nbsp; We are in a better place in this pandemic because we&#8217;re using these tools &#8212; right? &#8212;&nbsp;because we&#8217;re &#8212; we have vaccines, because we&#8217;re using therapeutics.</p>



<p>And so there&#8217;s a sense that some people have that, “Oh, because we&#8217;re in a better place, we don&#8217;t have to fund this anymore.”&nbsp; It&#8217;s actually quite the opposite.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve demonstrated that we can get us &#8212; we can get the country to a better place.&nbsp; It&#8217;s particularly important that we keep and sustain that effort to get us through the rest of this pandemic.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks, both.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Adrianna Rodriguez at USA Today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for holding this briefing and for taking my question.&nbsp; Another question on COVID funding.&nbsp; It seems to be popular this morning.&nbsp; I was wondering if we could talk about maybe the thought process behind some of those difficult decisions that were mentioned, specifically the one to reallocate funding from testing and protective equipment to vaccines.&nbsp; What was, I guess, the thought process behind going there?&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Dawn, do you want to take it?</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to start, absolutely.</p>



<p>So as has been noted already this morning, each of these decisions has been challenging; none of them are ideal.&nbsp; And they all require using funds that we were planning to spend on other critical programs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We looked across all six supplemental bills that we&#8217;ve received funding with and are pulling funds from each of those bills.&nbsp; One of the &#8212; to look at the legally available funding for the purchase of the vaccines that Dr. Jha mentioned &#8212; the Paxlovid and then the monoclonal that we&#8217;re purchasing in these next few weeks.</p>



<p>Not all the funds that are out there are available to be used for those purchases.&nbsp; So we looked at all the legally available funds, and we landed on some very difficult decisions. We&#8217;re going to give up domestic testing capacity, something that you all know we worked so hard to build through Delta and Omicron.&nbsp; We&#8217;re also not going to be able to do out-year support for the PPE warehousing and supplies that we&#8217;ve worked so hard to build.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it is challenging for us to think about taking a step backwards in that way.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve come so far in these two years, thanks to the support of Congress.&nbsp; And now having to make these challenging decisions is going to set us back.&nbsp; We hope to continue to work with our partners in Congress to continue to move forward and to not have to make any more of these difficult decisions.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; And I will add: One of the urgencies of this &#8212; and we&#8217;ve been saying this to Congress for the last couple of months &#8212; is that we are starting to lose our place in line; that other countries are negotiating contracts with these companies to purchase the next generation of vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The idea that America would not have the next generation of vaccines available to any American, we thought, was unacceptable.&nbsp; And so we have pulled enough funds that we can be at the negotiating table and begin to &#8212; begin to negotiate so that we don&#8217;t fall further behind in line.</p>



<p>Let me be very clear: We do not have enough resources to make sure that every American who wants one of the next generation of vaccines will be able to get one.&nbsp; That part is clear to us.&nbsp; But we needed to be at the negotiating table.&nbsp; And waiting longer, waiting for Congress no longer felt like an acceptable option.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we pulled the funds that Ms. O’Connell talked about.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Mike Stobbe at the Associated Press.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; This question came up before, but I don&#8217;t think I understand the answer.</p>



<p>Assuming that both the Pfizer and Moderna shots are authorized and recommended, will parents get to choose which vaccine their child gets?&nbsp; How will they do that?&nbsp; Will there be a federal resource that will tell them where the Moderna shots are and the Pfizer shots are?&nbsp; If you could help parents understand how they could do that.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Dawn, any thoughts on that?</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; So we&#8217;re now not in the position of presupposing what the FDA and CDC are going to authorize and recommend.&nbsp; But in planning for the potential authorization of both, we&#8217;re making both vaccines available in equal numbers during our preordering phase, and we’ll continue to provide equal numbers as states would like them.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Any other thoughts on that, Vivek?</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Well, I would just say, Mike, to your question also &#8212; I mean about how parents are going to make this decision: That will depend in part on the FDA and CDC process that unfolds over the next few days.&nbsp; They will be, you know, looking at the data very closely, and we will also be looking for their recommendations to help parents &#8212; help guide parents in their decisions about which vaccine to choose.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Let’s go Shannon Pettypiece at NBC News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a question on the vaccine for kids.&nbsp; But real quick, just to make sure we&#8217;re clear on the funding: Do you expect there &#8212; is there more money from the previously allocated COVID funds that you could reach into to get more vaccines for the fall?&nbsp; It sounds like you&#8217;re saying that this money you&#8217;ve reallocated so far gets you started, but it&#8217;s not going to be enough for the vaccines to be widely available in the fall.&nbsp; So is there any more money that you think you could reallocate to get additional vaccines for the fall if Congress doesn&#8217;t come through?</p>



<p>And then, yeah, I have a follow-up about the questions &#8212; about the vaccine for kids real quick, too.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Any thoughts on that?</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; So we&#8217;re looking under every couch cushion to see what is available.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;ve made available yesterday with that announcement about the $5 billion is what we&#8217;re able to put towards the vaccine negotiation right now.&nbsp; We certainly hope that we can work with Congress in the coming weeks to, you know, receive additional funds to be able to purchase more doses.&nbsp; But at this point, we&#8217;re not in a position to guarantee that we&#8217;ll be able to do that with remaining funds.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, the only thing I will add is: These were incredibly painful decisions.&nbsp; If you&#8217;ve, you know, certainly tracked the work of this administration, listened to us for last couple of years, we believe deeply in widespread availability of testing.&nbsp; To cut back on funding &#8212; to pull funds from testing availability, to lose funds for domestic testing manufacturing &#8212; these were incredibly difficult decisions.</p>



<p>And so, you know, the bottom line here is: These are not the tradeoffs that we should be having to make at this point in the pandemic.&nbsp; We shouldn&#8217;t have to choose between testing and vaccines.&nbsp; We should be able to do both.&nbsp; We can do both, but we do need Congress to step up and be a partner in this effort.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, you had a question about kids under five, I think, as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Do you guys &#8212; I know you&#8217;re going to do everything you can to get as many kids vaccinated in this age group as possible.&nbsp; Do you expect the adoption rate to be similar to the 5- to 11-year-olds, where I think the numbers are around a third of 5- to 11-year-olds who have gotten their first doses.&nbsp; Do expect it to be higher, lower with this youngest age group?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Well, let me start off with a couple of thoughts on this, and then I&#8217;d love Dr. Murthy to talk about it as well.</p>



<p>Two things.&nbsp; First is: Our job, first and foremost, is to make sure that these vaccines are widely available and highly accessible.&nbsp; That is &#8212; that is number one.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to make sure that happens.</p>



<p>Again, all of this, and everything we&#8217;re talking about today, is with the assumption that FDA and CDC authorize these.&nbsp; So let&#8217;s set that aside.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to be the critical part.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Assuming they do, first and foremost, we&#8217;re going to make sure that in the &#8212; in the days and weeks that follow any CDC recommendation, we make these vaccines widely available, highly accessible so that parents can get their kids vaccinated.</p>



<p>Now, second important point is: If you go back to December of 2020 and look at surveys that were done of adults, about a third of adults said they would go out and get vaccinated right away.&nbsp; What we know now is about 80 percent of adults have gotten at least one shot.</p>



<p>A reminder that these things take time, that vaccine confidence builds over time.&nbsp; It builds with trusted voices, physicians, faith leaders, others helping people get vaccinated.&nbsp; This is not a one-and-done, this is not an automatic.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we have seen for kids 12 and above.&nbsp; We’re continuing to see that with kids 5 to 11.&nbsp; And we expect that to be an ongoing journey for kids under five.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I remain very optimistic that we&#8217;re going to get more and more children vaccinated and protected over time.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t have any internal targets of what that number should look like after a week or after three weeks or after a month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vivek.</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Yeah, no, I certainly agree with Dr. Jha on this.&nbsp; And, you know, if you look at the past, like Dr. Jha was saying, the things that have actually increased people&#8217;s confidence in getting vaccinated is when the FDA and CDC weigh in, look at the data, and make that data publicly available, and then weigh in with a recommendation.&nbsp; When people see their friends and family members getting vaccinated, that also helps. And when people can have conversations with their doctors, with their friends and family, that also helps to increase their comfort with getting vaccinated.</p>



<p>What we are going to do in this vaccination effort is build on all of the lessons that we have learned over the last 18 months to make sure that we are getting parents the information that they need to make a decision for their kids, but also to make sure they have as much access as possible to these vaccines &#8212; that they can get them easily in pharmacies, in children&#8217;s hospitals, in pediatricians’ offices, and in other locations around the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But our lessons from the past have taught us that in addition to us speaking directly to the public, that our partnerships &#8212; partnerships we built over the last 18 months &#8212; are going to be critical here &#8212; partnerships with doctors and nurses, with faith leaders, with educators, and with community organizations across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is why we built the COVID-19 Community Corps to begin with in the spring of 2021.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve continued to engage with that community.&nbsp; And it’s why we&#8217;re calling the broader community to action right now to make sure parents have accurate information, that they don&#8217;t fall prey to misinformation that&#8217;s out there but they have the right information so they can make the best decisions for their kids.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Kevin, back to you.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Just a couple more questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Jeannie Baumann at Bloomberg.&nbsp; Hey, Jeannie, can &#8212; might be on mute.&nbsp; All right, Jeannie, we will come back to you.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s go to Nate Weixel at the Hill.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; A question about supply.&nbsp; You know, it seems like there&#8217;s going to be 10 million doses initially.&nbsp; Is there a plan B if only one gets authorized, in terms of what&#8217;s going to be available to states?&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Dawn, thoughts?</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; Thank &#8212; thank you for that good question.&nbsp; So we do have 10 million available across both vaccines, and we&#8217;re not in a position to pre-judge what the FDA and CDC are going to decide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we&#8217;ll continue to make both vaccines available in our preordering phase accordingly.&nbsp; Should we end up with only one vaccine authorized, which we&#8217;re not anticipating or pre-judging whether that might happen, we will adjust supply accordingly.&nbsp; But at this point, it has been our goal to have both of these vaccines available and preordering.</p>



<p>You know, we&#8217;re really lucky to have two good options being considered by FDA and CDC next week, and we&#8217;ll continue to prepare as if both will be recommended and authorized.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Jeannie, I&#8217;m just checking if you&#8217;re able to speak.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me now?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Hi, Jeannie.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; I was just wondering how this rollout is different from the 5- to 11-year-old vaccine rollout, or if it is, what the distinction is.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll start off, because I was not in this role during the 5 to 11-year-olds.&nbsp; So I &#8212; what I know &#8212; and then, again, my colleagues here were, so I&#8217;d love to hear from them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One thing that I think is going to be different is, you know, while we are going to make this widely available across a variety of different locations and channels, my suspicion is a lot more parents are going to get their kids vaccinated in physician offices and pediatricians’ and offices of family physicians.&nbsp; So, I think that part will be different.</p>



<p>But &#8212; and every time we&#8217;ve done a rollout, we have learned from the lessons of the past.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve looked at what has worked and not and thought about what are the changes that we need to make so that we&#8217;re constantly learning and constantly getting better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I wasn&#8217;t here for the previous rollout, so I&#8217;m going to first turn it to Dawn and then to Vivek to see if you have any more specific reflections.</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just a couple of distinctions that Dr. Jha didn&#8217;t mention.&nbsp; One is we didn&#8217;t have two vaccines that were both being considered at the same time for the five to elevens.&nbsp; And so, the planning we&#8217;ve been talking about, where we&#8217;re making and planning for both to be available, is different.&nbsp; And &#8212; but one of the things that we know is important for us to be able to provide both, should both be authorized and recommended.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then just to underscore what Dr. Jha said about the smaller children likely not going into a major pop-up clinic or site or large vaccination center but likely, you know, seeking this vaccine in a pediatrician’s office, a &#8212; you know, a family care provider, a pharmacy setting.&nbsp; And so, making sure that we adjust the availability of doses to accommodate the needs of this younger age population.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Dr. Murthy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Yeah, and as Dr. Jha said, you know, this &#8212; we&#8217;re really building on lessons we&#8217;ve learned in the past.&nbsp; And one of the key lessons that has come up, especially during our 5 to 11 campaign, is that, you know, parents, understandably, are cautious about the decisions they make when it comes to their children&#8217;s healthcare.&nbsp; Sometimes they want to have not one but two or three conversations with somebody they trust.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, our goal then is to double, triple down on the relationships and partnerships we&#8217;re building with those trusted messengers.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re working even more closely with pediatricians and family medicine doctors.&nbsp; We’re working harder to make sure that parents can get vaccines in sites that they&#8217;re comfortable with, like doctors’ offices and their children&#8217;s hospital.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;ll continue to do in this, knowing that parents of kids, you know, who have &#8212; of under five &#8212; and I say this as a parent myself of a four-year-old &#8212; they want to be absolutely sure that they&#8217;ve got the right information, and sometimes that requires multiple contexts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re going to keep working on this.&nbsp; And again, our goal is to make sure that every parent out there of a child under five has the information they need to get their child vaccinated.&nbsp; And we also want to use this as an opportunity, Nate, to make sure that &#8212; or Jeannie &#8212; to make sure that people who have kids who are over five also take this as an opportunity to remember that getting vaccinated is important as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, if you&#8217;re out there and you&#8217;ve got a child who&#8217;s five years old or above and they haven&#8217;t gotten vaccinated yet, or they&#8217;re eligible to get boosted and they haven&#8217;t gotten boosted yet, please go out there and consider getting your child a shot &#8212; because we know that there is still COVID around.&nbsp; We know that kids who are vaccinated are less likely to be hospitalized or end up with severe complications, like the Multisystem Inflammatory Syndrome.</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s a step we&#8217;re taking.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why I got my five-year-old vaccinated.&nbsp; And it’s why when a vaccine is available for kids under five, I will be in line with my four-year-old to get her vaccinated as well.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Last question, let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett with ABC News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering when you will need funding to be able to reverse the stoppage of the domestic manufacturing on testing and if you&#8217;re still asking for $22.5 billion, even though you&#8217;ve now moved some funds around.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Let me start, and I&#8217;d love to hear Dawn&#8217;s thoughts on this.&nbsp; The domestic manufacturing of testing issues really &#8212; it&#8217;s really very unfortunate because we &#8212; the U.S. government put in a lot of effort and resources into building up that domestic manufacturing.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re seeing is, day by day, week by week, that beginning to go away.</p>



<p>Companies, because the demand has fallen for these tests, are laying off workers.&nbsp; They&#8217;re shutting down production lines. And in some cases, they’re se- &#8212; they’ve &#8212; in the past &#8212; and they&#8217;re going to likely do this again &#8212; selling off their equipment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, if we get more resources down the road, we will be able to reverse some of it.&nbsp; It will be more expensive.&nbsp; It will be difficult.&nbsp; If we do not get these resources now and we find ourselves in a surge without enough tests, we will largely rely on foreign manufacturers, mostly from China, to provide the tests that Americans need.</p>



<p>That is not the situation we need to be in.&nbsp; And it is absolutely essential that we continue to have a domestic manufacturing capacity that can produce tests for the American people, both during times when infection numbers are low but particularly so when infection numbers are high.&nbsp; And I think, personally, that it&#8217;s hugely problematic that we&#8217;re not able to continue doing that because of congressional inaction.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of the resources we need &#8212; $22.5 billion has been our request, because what that will do is allow us to get enough vaccines for every American, to make sure that we have enough therapeutics, to make sure that we actually can continue the domestic manufacturing, but just make sure we have enough testing supply.</p>



<p>So those resources are still what are essential.&nbsp; And, of course, the money we&#8217;ve taken away &#8212; we need to have a PPE national stockpile.&nbsp; It&#8217;s unacceptable that, as a country, we are not stockpiling personal protective equipment to protect doctors and nurses.&nbsp; Those are the kinds of choices we are being forced into.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, yes, the resources that we need are still there to make sure that we are able to continue those efforts.</p>



<p>Dawn?</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; And just to underscore what Dr. Jha said, you know, we would need the money as soon as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the lessons we learned last year and have applied during the Omicron surge is when &#8212; in the spring of last year, when vaccines were being introduced and tests weren&#8217;t as readily available, we didn&#8217;t have the over-the-counter tests, a lot of, you know, the companies saw demand drop off, and they let workers go; sold the equipment, as Dr. Jha mentioned; and really downsized.&nbsp; And then we saw Delta, and then we saw Omicron.</p>



<p>And what we also learned was how long it takes for them to hire the employees they need and to ramp up production.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a weeks-to-months process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also learned in the course of these two years that this virus is anything but predictable.&nbsp; So for us to lose this capacity again and then be forced to ramp up by hook or by crook in the coming months with a potential variant coming, you know, it&#8217;s just not a good place for the country to be.&nbsp; It puts us back to where we were, despite all the effort and all the hard work we&#8217;ve invested in this testing manufacturing capacity.</p>



<p>So we, you know, urge Congress to work with us to restore this funding as quickly as possible so we don&#8217;t find ourselves flat-footed.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; And let me make one last point on this.&nbsp; It is also fiscally the prudent thing to do.&nbsp; It&#8217;s far more expensive to have to rebuild that domestic manufacturing capacity, far more expensive to have to go back and rehire and buy new equipment, and how &#8212; and we end up funding and supporting a lot of that effort.</p>



<p>So, from a just pure fiscal prudence point of view, maintaining this capacity, making sure we can tap into it when there is a surge and we need more testing, is really a smart thing to do.&nbsp; Obviously, from a public health point of view, it&#8217;s a no-brainer, in terms of protecting the health of the American people.&nbsp; But even financially, it&#8217;s much smarter.</p>



<p>So, acting early is clearly the right thing to do.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re hoping that Congress steps up and acts much &#8212; as quickly as possible so we can move in the right direction.</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Kevin, back to you.&nbsp; Are we &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; We&#8217;re done.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody, for joining us today.&nbsp; And a huge thanks to both Dawn O’Connell, our Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, and Dr. Vivek Murthy, our Surgeon General, for joining us.&nbsp; Thank you both.&nbsp; And thank you for all your questions.</p>



<p>And we look forward to staying engaged and involved and sharing with you all the information we have in the days and weeks ahead as we &#8212; as we work to get vaccines out to the last group of Americans who are yet eligible &#8212; who have not yet been eligible, to make sure they get protected as well.</p>



<p>Thank you so much.&nbsp; And have a great day, everybody.</p>



<p>11:49 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
