<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 17:24:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  President&#160;Biden Signs National Security Memorandum to Combat Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and Associated Labor&#160;Abuses</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-national-security-memorandum-to-combat-illegal-unreported-and-unregulated-fishing-and-associated-labor-abuses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden signed a National Security Memorandum (NSM) to address illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing and related harmful fishing practices. &#160; IUU fishing is among the greatest threats to ocean health and is a significant cause of global overfishing, contributing to the collapse or decline of fisheries that are critical to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden signed a National Security Memorandum (NSM) to address illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing and related harmful fishing practices. &nbsp;</p>



<p>IUU fishing is among the greatest threats to ocean health and is a significant cause of global overfishing, contributing to the collapse or decline of fisheries that are critical to the economic growth, food systems, and ecosystems of numerous countries around the world.&nbsp; Distant water fishing vessels, which engage in industrial-scale fishing operations on the high seas and in waters under other states’ jurisdictions, can be significant perpetrators of IUU fishing and related harmful fishing practices.&nbsp; IUU fishing often involves forced labor, human trafficking, and other crimes and human rights abuses.&nbsp; Left unchecked, IUU fishing and associated labor abuses undermine U.S. economic competitiveness, national security, fisheries sustainability, and the livelihoods and human rights of fishers around the world and will exacerbate the environmental and socioeconomic effects of climate change.</p>



<p>The Biden Administration will address IUU fishing by increasing coordination with diverse stakeholders — public and private, foreign and domestic.&nbsp; The United States Government will use the full range of existing conservation, labor, trade, economic, diplomatic, law enforcement, and national security authorities to address these challenges, including:</p>



<ul><li>Promoting labor rights, human rights, and fundamental freedoms through worker-centered trade policies and working to ensure that supply chains are free from forced labor, including by engaging with international institutions and trade partners to address forced labor and other abusive labor practices in IUU fishing;<br></li><li>Collaborating within international organizations, including regional bodies, and partnering with stakeholders from governments, civil society, and the private sector, to increase global attention on the challenges of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and related abusive labor practices, such as the use of forced labor in seafood supply chains; and<br></li><li>Combatting abuses and strengthening incentives for ethical behavior in the global seafood industry, including by limiting the market for products derived from IUU fishing, forced labor, or other abusive labor practices.</li></ul>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is also taking the following actions to combat IUU fishing, which will be announced throughout this week’s U.N. Ocean Conference.</p>



<ul><li>The United States, the UK, and Canada will launch an <strong>IUU Fishing Action Alliance</strong> aimed at increasing ambition and momentum in the fight against IUU fishing, including <strong>a pledge to take urgent action</strong> to improve the monitoring, control, and surveillance of fisheries, increase transparency in fishing fleets and in the seafood market, and build new partnerships that will hold bad actors accountable.<br></li><li>The <strong>U.S. Interagency Working Group on Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing</strong>, comprising 21 Federal agencies, will release its <em>National Five-Year Strategy for Combating Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing (2022-2026)</em> by the end of July.&nbsp; The strategy prioritizes the Working Group’s efforts to combat IUU fishing, curtail the global trade of IUU fish and fish products, and promote global maritime security, while working in partnership with other governments and authorities, the seafood industry, academia, and non-governmental stakeholders.&nbsp; The United States will engage with priority partners, including Ecuador, Panama, Senegal, Taiwan, and Vietnam.&nbsp; Information on the member agencies and activities of the Working Group can be found <a href="https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/national/us-interagency-working-group-iuu-fishing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here.<br></a></li><li>NOAA will also issue a <strong>proposed rule to enhance and strengthen its ability to address IUU fishing activities and combat forced labor in the seafood supply chain</strong>. &nbsp;Specifically, the rule will enhance NOAA’s ability to implement the Agreement on Port State Measures to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing and the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act.&nbsp; The rule proposes to broaden the scope of activities that NOAA can consider when identifying nations that engage in IUU fishing to include fishing in waters under the jurisdiction of a nation, without the permission of that nation, or in violation of its laws and regulations.&nbsp; This will ensure consistency with the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization’s <em>International Plan of Action to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing</em>.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>These new actions build on President Biden’s proclamation declaring June as <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-ocean-month-2022/">National Ocean Month</a> and key <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-celebrates-world-ocean-day-with-actions-to-conserve-americas-deepest-atlantic-canyon-cut-plastic-pollution-and-create-americas-first-ever-o/">announcements</a> the White House made earlier this month to conserve and restore the health and productivity of the ocean for the benefit of all Americans. &nbsp;These announcements included initiating the designation process for a new national marine sanctuary to conserve Hudson Canyon in the Atlantic Ocean, a phase out of the sale of single-use plastics in national parks and public lands, the launch of efforts to create America’s first-ever Ocean Climate Action Plan, and the launch of an initiative to center environmental justice in ocean science and technology activities and investments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The White&#160;House Announces Public Tours Will Resume A Full Operating&#160;Schedule</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/the-white-house-announces-public-tours-will-resume-a-full-operating-schedule/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden-Harris Administration is pleased to announce public tours of the White House will resume a full operating schedule from Tuesdays through Saturdays beginning on Tuesday, July 19, 2022. Public tours will be available from 8:00 AM to 12:30 PM on Tuesdays, Wednesdays, Thursdays, Fridays, and Saturdays, excluding Federal holidays or unless otherwise noted. All&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is pleased to announce public tours of the White House will resume a full operating schedule from Tuesdays through Saturdays beginning on Tuesday, July 19, 2022. Public tours will be available from 8:00 AM to 12:30 PM on Tuesdays, Wednesdays, Thursdays, Fridays, and Saturdays, excluding Federal holidays or unless otherwise noted. All White House tours are free of charge. The White House tour schedule is subject to change based on inclement weather or official use<br><br><strong>Public White House Tour Requests</strong></p>



<p>Public tour requests are scheduled on a first come, first served basis and must be submitted through a Member of Congress and their Congressional Tour Coordinator. Constituents may reach your Member of Congress and Congressional Tour Coordinator through the U.S. House of Representative’s Switchboard at 202-225-3121, the U.S. Senate Switchboard at 202-224-3121, or online at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.congress.gov/members">www.congress.gov/members</a>.</p>



<p>Consistent with prior practices, public White House tour requests must be submitted a minimum of 21 days in advance and no more than 90 days in advance of the requested tour date(s). Reservations cannot be accepted for tour dates outside this 21 – 90-day window.&nbsp;Congressional Tour Coordinators will be able to submit tour requests for the full operating schedule on Monday, June 27, 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The White House will continue to closely monitor the COVID-19 situation with guidance based on recommendations from the CDC, and other public health officials and medical experts, and reserves the right to adjust availability of the public tours as necessary to adhere to the latest health guidance. Within the 10 days prior to the public tour, anyone who has tested positive for COVID-19, has had any COVID-19 symptoms, or been in close contact with someone confirmed or suspected to have COVID-19, should stay home. Face masks will be available when entering the White House complex for those who choose to wear them.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Combating Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and Associated Labor&#160;Abuses</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/27/memorandum-on-combating-illegal-unreported-and-unregulated-fishing-and-associated-labor-abuses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 15:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Memorandum/NSM-11 MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE ATTORNEY GENERAL &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF COMMERCE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF LABOR &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE UNITED STATES TRADE REPRESENTATIVE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE REPRESENTATIVE OF THE UNITED STATES &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Memorandum/NSM-11</p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE ATTORNEY GENERAL</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF COMMERCE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF LABOR</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE UNITED STATES TRADE REPRESENTATIVE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE REPRESENTATIVE OF THE UNITED STATES</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; OF AMERICA TO THE UNITED NATIONS</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE DIRECTOR OF THE OFFICE OF SCIENCE AND</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; TECHNOLOGY POLICY</p>



<p>THE ADMINISTRATOR OF THE UNITED STATES AGENCY</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; FOR INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Combating Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fishing and Associated Labor Abuses</p>



<p>Illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing and related harmful fishing practices are among the greatest threats to ocean health and are significant causes of global overfishing, contributing to the collapse or decline of fisheries that are critical to the economic growth, food systems, and ecosystems of numerous countries around the world.&nbsp; Distant water fishing vessels, which engage in industrial-scale fishing operations on the high seas and in waters under other states&#8217; jurisdictions, can be significant perpetrators of IUU fishing and related harmful fishing practices.&nbsp; IUU fishing often involves forced labor, a form of human trafficking, and other crimes and human rights abuses.&nbsp; Left unchecked, IUU fishing and associated labor abuses undermine U.S.&nbsp;economic competitiveness, national security, fishery sustainability, and the livelihoods and human rights of fishers around the world and will exacerbate the environmental and socioeconomic effects of climate change.</p>



<p>Section 1.&nbsp; Policy.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to address the problem of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and associated labor abuses, including the use of forced labor in the seafood supply chain.&nbsp; I hereby direct executive departments and agencies (agencies) to work toward ending forced labor and other crimes or abuses in IUU fishing; promote sustainable use of the oceans in partnership with other nations and the private sector; and advance foreign and trade policies that benefit U.S. seafood workers.&nbsp; No nation, government entity, or non-governmental organization can address IUU fishing and associated labor abuses single-handedly.&nbsp; I therefore direct agencies to increase coordination among themselves and with diverse stakeholders &#8212; public and private, foreign and domestic &#8212; to address these challenges comprehensively.&nbsp; With this memorandum, I direct agencies to use the full range of existing conservation, labor, trade, economic, diplomatic, law enforcement, and national security authorities to address these challenges.&nbsp; Where applicable, activities will be carried out through or in coordination with the Interagency Working Group on IUU Fishing established pursuant to section 3551 of the Maritime Security and Fisheries Enforcement (SAFE) Act (16 U.S.C. 8031), the Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force established pursuant to section 741 of the United&nbsp;States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act (19 U.S.C. 4681), and as appropriate the President&#8217;s Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons established pursuant to section 105 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (22 U.S.C. 7103).</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; Forced Labor in the Fishing Industry.&nbsp; The United&nbsp;States is committed to promoting labor rights and human rights and fundamental freedoms through worker-centered trade policies, and to working to eliminate abusive labor practices, in particular forced labor, in supply chains.&nbsp; Agencies shall enhance interagency coordination and the use of existing tools and authorities to address the challenge of forced labor in the seafood supply chain.</p>



<p>(a)  The United States Trade Representative (USTR), in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Commerce through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), and other relevant agencies, shall:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; continue to engage in the World Trade Organization negotiations on fisheries subsidies to seek additional disciplines prohibiting fisheries subsidies that contribute to overcapacity and overfishing, and to seek additional transparency with respect to IUU fishing and the use of forced labor on fishing vessels;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;engage, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, with trade partners, including free trade agreement partners and preference program beneficiaries, to address forced labor and other abusive labor practices in fishing; and</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; seek to collaborate with Mexico and Canada under the United&nbsp;States-Mexico-Canada Agreement to prohibit the importation of goods, including seafood, produced in whole or in part by forced labor.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The Secretary of State, the Secretary of Labor, the USTR, and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), in coordination with the Administrator of NOAA and other relevant agencies, shall continue to highlight links between IUU fishing and forced labor and other abusive labor practices, with a focus on distant water fishing and vessels using flags of convenience to continue unsustainable fishing practices.&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall adjust the mix of United States Government messaging and promotion of non-governmental voices to achieve the greatest effect and shall develop themes and narratives that resonate with target audiences including foreign governments, the private sector, and global and U.S. consumers.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Secretary of Homeland Security, through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and in coordination with the Administrator of NOAA, shall:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;investigate fishing vessels and operators suspected to be harvesting seafood with forced labor and issue withhold release orders, as appropriate;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;at the discretion of relevant CBP officials, share evidence with allies and partners to encourage parallel customs enforcement actions, as appropriate;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; investigate prospective civil penalty cases against importers connected to previously issued fishing vessel withhold release orders, as appropriate;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;in coordination with other relevant agencies, use the Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force to monitor United&nbsp;States enforcement of the prohibition under section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (19 U.S.C. 1307) to prevent the importation of seafood harvested with forced labor into the United&nbsp;States; and</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;use Maritime Operational Threat Response processes to facilitate interagency notifications, responses, and legal enforcement actions for IUU fishing offenses, including taking appropriate action when forced labor is identified.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and the Treasury shall, as appropriate, consider whether their respective sanctions and visa restriction authorities may be used to address IUU fishing and associated labor abuses.&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall consider, as appropriate, whether to share evidentiary packages with allies and partners to facilitate parallel sanctions or visa restriction actions.</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; The Secretary of Labor, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID, shall engage financial institutions, business organizations, labor stakeholders, and seafood importers on forced labor in seafood supply chains, including by promoting supply chain transparency and responsible business practices.&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall promote dissemination of information on the harms of IUU fishing and associated labor abuses in order to encourage greater corporate and consumer demand for due diligence, mechanisms to certify that seafood supply chains are free of forced labor, and the halting of financial transactions involving forced labor.&nbsp; These heads of agencies are encouraged to apply lessons learned from United States Government policies addressing the use of forced labor in the cotton sector and in other relevant sectors. &nbsp;The Administrator of USAID shall work to build regional networks between civil society organizations, trade unions, migrant worker networks, and recruitment agencies to address exploitation in the seafood industry. &nbsp;These networks should incorporate worker voices, including survivors of forced labor, to counter labor abuses and provide legal aid to migrant workers in the fishing industry.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>(f)&nbsp; The Secretary of Labor shall use labor and development programs to provide training and technical support to national security-focused agencies, including the Department of Defense and the United States Coast Guard, and foreign partners on combating forced labor and other abusive labor practices on fishing vessels.</p>



<p>(g)&nbsp; The Secretary of Labor shall continue to raise public awareness about labor practices in the seafood industry, including by continuing to maintain its list of goods it has reason to believe are produced by forced labor or child labor in violation of international standards.</p>



<p>Sec. 3.&nbsp; Multilateral and Regional Solutions That Support Sustainable Fishing.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to revitalize U.S. leadership in multilateral institutions, including regional bodies.&nbsp; I therefore direct agencies to collaborate with these organizations to increase global attention to the challenges of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and related abusive labor practices, such as the use of forced labor in seafood supply chains.&nbsp; My Administration will harness our international partners&#8217; energy and innovative capacity to design and implement solutions.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Labor, the USTR, and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall promote decent work, counter forced labor, and take other actions to address IUU fishing and related harmful fishing practices at the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) of the United Nations (UN), the International Labor Organization (ILO), and the International Maritime Organization (IMO).&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall work with the FAO to draft guidelines on social responsibility in fisheries and value chains and shall support ILO research on forced labor in fishing.</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretaries of State and the Treasury shall consider whether to seek funding from the Congress and donors for multi-donor trust funds or regional programs at multilateral development banks to combat IUU fishing.</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretary of State, the Attorney General, and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall, as appropriate, elevate the issue of IUU fishing at the UN Food Systems Summit.</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; The Attorney General and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall support the International Criminal Police Organization to combat conservation crimes, including those related to IUU fishing, and build capacity for fisheries managers and investigators.</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretaries of State and Labor, the USTR, and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall explore concrete efforts to collaborate with G7 members on addressing forced labor in fishing. &nbsp;The Secretary of State, the Administrator of NOAA, and other relevant agencies shall use the G7&#8217;s focus on addressing unsustainable fishing practices as outlined in the 2030 Nature Compact to increase attention to and pursue efforts to counter harmful fishing practices.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Administrator of NOAA, in coordination with the Secretaries of State and Labor, the Secretary of Homeland Security through the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard, and the USTR, shall engage with regional fisheries management organizations to encourage adoption of measures that identify and counter IUU fishing, including high seas boarding inspection schemes. &nbsp;Additionally, these heads of agencies shall collaborate on regional initiatives to address forced labor and other harmful practices in the seafood industry, which will include:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Administrator of NOAA and other relevant agencies shall promote transatlantic cooperation to counter the use of forced labor in seafood supply chains, including through the United States-European Union (EU) High-Level Dialogue on Fisheries.</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Defense shall collaborate with counterparts in the Quad (which is composed of Australia, India, Japan, and the United States) to design and facilitate the implementation of a multilateral initiative, the Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness, to strengthen maritime domain awareness and maritime security in South Asia, Southeast Asia, and the Pacific Islands using advanced commercial satellite data.&nbsp; The Administrators of NOAA and USAID, the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard, and the Intelligence Community shall support this endeavor as appropriate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp;&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Labor and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall collaborate with the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) to encourage the design of technical assistance programming to address forced labor in fishing, linking these efforts to the US-ASEAN Plan of Action.</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretary of State and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall collaborate with Pacific Island nations, including through the Pacific Islands Forum, to counter IUU fishing and related human trafficking, including forced labor.</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretaries of State and Labor and the Administrator of NOAA shall explore opportunities for cooperation in the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) to begin discussions on forced labor and other abusive practices in fishing, linking these efforts to the APEC Roadmap on Combatting IUU Fishing.</p>



<p>(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretary of State, in collaboration with the Administrators of NOAA and USAID, shall elevate the issue of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and related harmful fishing practices, at any future Our Ocean Conferences and in meetings and working groups of the Organization of American States, APEC, the African Union, relevant African sub-regional bodies, and the Pacific Alliance.</p>



<p>(vii) &nbsp;&nbsp;The Administrator of USAID shall work to initiate partnerships with and support multilateral institutions such as the Southeast Asian Fisheries Development Center and the Coral Triangle Initiative to counter IUU fishing.</p>



<p>(viii)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Defense, in collaboration with the Administrator of NOAA, shall explore opportunities for cooperation between Atlantic Basin African maritime forces and the United States Africa Command to improve West African capacity to detect and counter IUU fishing.</p>



<p>(ix)    The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in collaboration with the Secretaries of State and Commerce and the Administrator of NOAA, shall continue to pursue opportunities through the High Level Panel for a Sustainable Ocean Economy (Ocean Panel) to promote international collaboration to counter IUU fishing and integrate best practices into the National Sustainable Ocean Plans of each Ocean Panel country.</p>



<p>Sec. 4.&nbsp; Partner Engagement, Capacity, and Resilience.&nbsp; The United States benefits from an unparalleled ability to shape global discourse and convene stakeholders from government, civil society, and the private sector.&nbsp; The United States&#8217; track record of conserving fisheries and combating forced labor enables it to lead by the power of example.&nbsp; The United States&#8217; robust network of alliances and partnerships and its broad array of conservation, law enforcement, trade, economic, diplomatic, labor, and other authorities and programs can be used to generate innovative, cross-cutting, and powerful solutions.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to harness these advantages to address the challenge of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and related harmful fishing practices, such as forced labor in the seafood supply chain.</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; The United States has a strong track record of making environmental data, such as data produced by the U.S. Global Change Research Program and its participating agencies, freely available to partners and the general public. &nbsp;The Office of Science and Technology Policy shall support the interagency policy committee process in assessing the best-available evidence concerning fisheries-environment interactions. &nbsp;This may include, for example, identifying regions more likely to be at risk of harmful and unsustainable fishing practices due to climate change and its resulting threats to food security.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Defense and the Administrator of USAID shall work with partners to use all available tools to increase maritime domain awareness to combat IUU fishing, including increasing the use of vessel tracking systems, aerial surveillance, and radio frequency data, as well as utilizing emerging technologies such as advances in machine learning paired with synthetic aperture radar, as appropriate. &nbsp;The Administrator of USAID shall also continue to promote the use of communication technology to improve connectivity and safety for commercial fishing vessels and support ethical and sustainable fishing practices.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Administrator of USAID, in coordination with the Secretaries of State, Commerce, and Labor; the USTR; the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard; and the Administrator of NOAA, shall strengthen alliances with non-governmental organizations, think tanks, organized labor, academia, industry associations, and the business community to highlight and address IUU fishing and associated labor abuses, including forced labor, in the seafood sector, and to develop best practices for combating these abuses, promoting sustainable fisheries, rebuilding fish stocks, and empowering fisheries workers.&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall engage with fishers, fish processing workers, port workers, and relevant trade unions to seek input on the real-world impacts of IUU fishing and abusive labor practices.&nbsp; The Administrator of USAID and other relevant agencies shall use development and technical assistance programs, as appropriate, to address corruption in governance systems; support judicial reform and public financial management; and build journalist, trade union, and civil society capacity to raise awareness of IUU fishing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretaries of the Treasury, Defense, and Homeland Security; the USTR; the Administrators of NOAA and USAID; the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard; the United States Mission to the European Union; and other heads of departments and agencies as appropriate, shall cooperate with the EU, Japan, other G7 members, and other partner countries, together or individually, to work to counter harmful fishing practices in West Africa, Latin America and the Caribbean, and the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; These heads of departments and agencies shall:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;identify and, as appropriate, seek resources for technical skills training in littoral Africa, including ship inspections, ship maintenance, and oversight of maritime governance programs;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;develop information-sharing networks and arrangements with partner countries to inform a maritime common operating picture to improve regional maritime domain awareness and combat IUU fishing in the South Atlantic, Oceania, Indo-Pacific, Eastern Pacific, and West Africa;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; leverage opportunities to include IUU fishing provisions within existing and new bilateral maritime law enforcement agreements with partner nations, including in Latin America and the Caribbean and Africa; and</p>



<p>(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;use all available intelligence capabilities to identify and enable, as appropriate, interdiction of vessels conducting or engaged in IUU fishing, particularly those that are operating within the exclusive economic zones of nations with which the United States has bilateral maritime law enforcement agreements.</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; The Administrator of NOAA, in collaboration with the Secretary of State and the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard, shall encourage adoption of the Agreement on Port State Measures to Prevent, Deter, and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and shall provide assistance, as appropriate, for its implementation, including training and capacity building, as directed by the Maritime SAFE Act.&nbsp; The Administrator of USAID shall strategically support interagency partners to strengthen Port State Measures programs in individual states.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (f)&nbsp; The Administrator of NOAA shall seek resources, as appropriate, to deploy fisheries enforcement representatives to posts to support regional efforts to counter IUU fishing and to build capacity for monitoring, control, and surveillance to combat IUU fishing and related harmful fishing practices, such as forced labor. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;The Administrator of NOAA, in collaboration with the Secretary of State and the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard, shall work to improve maritime law enforcement coordination in partner countries to address IUU fishing, related abusive labor practices, and trade of protected marine species.</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; The Secretary of Defense shall use, as appropriate, Maritime Security Initiatives to enhance maritime detection capabilities of eligible countries within their exclusive economic zones, increase maritime domain awareness in the Indo-Pacific and Africa, and develop a common operating picture for regional information sharing.</p>



<p>(g)&nbsp; The Secretary of State and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall endeavor to assist developing countries with the establishment and enforcement of marine protected areas to promote the conservation of fish species and sustainable coastal management.</p>



<p>(h)&nbsp; The Secretary of State, the Administrators of NOAA and USAID, and other relevant agencies shall engage with partners to promote legally caught fish and seafood supply chains that are free of forced labor as the preferred option and to highlight its benefits.<strong></strong></p>



<p>Sec. 5.&nbsp; Import Markets. &nbsp;The United States is the world&#8217;s single largest country market for seafood; more than 85 percent of the seafood Americans consume is imported.&nbsp; The United&nbsp;States has taken steps to limit the market for products derived from IUU fishing and forced labor, but additional action is required.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to combat abuses and to strengthen incentives for ethical behavior in the global seafood industry, including by limiting the market for products derived from IUU fishing, forced labor, or other abusive labor practices.&nbsp; Agencies should seek opportunities to leverage the United States&#8217; large seafood import market to advance these objectives and unify public messaging that condemns IUU fishing.&nbsp; Wherever possible, agencies should seek opportunities to coordinate international messaging that condemns IUU fishing with like-minded partners.&nbsp; The United States, the EU, and Japan together account for approximately 55 percent of the global seafood market, providing an opportunity to work with democratic market economies to develop more powerful signals to the global seafood market.</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; By the end of 2022, the Administrator of NOAA shall initiate a rulemaking to expand the Seafood Import Monitoring Program (SIMP) to include additional species and species groups, as appropriate. &nbsp;NOAA shall continue to seek resources and technological tools to improve the effectiveness of SIMP and other efforts to address IUU fishing. &nbsp;NOAA shall pursue its ongoing efforts to conduct risk-based assessments of SIMP species and species groups and continuously expand coverage of the program, as appropriate, to meet the objectives of combating IUU fishing and seafood fraud most effectively.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Administrator of NOAA, the Commissioner of CBP, and other relevant agencies shall work to leverage existing and emerging technologies to detect IUU fishing and prevent or deter illegal seafood imports from entering U.S. markets.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Labor, the USTR, the Administrator of NOAA, the Commissioner of CBP, and other relevant agencies shall explore opportunities to use existing trade tools and authorities to counter forced labor in the seafood supply chain and IUU fishing generally, such as through the use, as appropriate, of countervailing duties, actions pursuant to section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2411), import declarations, certification under the Pelly Amendment to the Fishermen&#8217;s Protective Act of 1967 (22 U.S.C. 1978), and due diligence requirements.&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall work to develop new tools and authorities to address gaps and shall work with partners to take parallel actions.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Labor and the Administrator of NOAA shall work to build on existing dialogues and cooperation mechanisms with allies, partners, and international organizations to develop joint or complementary approaches to addressing forced labor in the global seafood industry.</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; The Administrator of USAID shall convene leaders from industry, civil society, and government to develop recommendations for improving information flows that create meaningful deterrence, accountability, and remedies for illegality in labor and harvesting practices in wild fisheries.</p>



<p>Sec. 6. &nbsp;General Provisions. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Extending and Expanding Eligibility for Deferred Enforced Departure for&#160;Liberians</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/27/memorandum-on-extending-and-expanding-eligibility-for-deferred-enforced-departure-for-liberians/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 15:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY SUBJECT:&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Extending and Expanding Eligibility for Deferred Enforced Departure for Liberians Since 1991, the United States has provided safe haven for Liberians who were forced to flee their country as a result of armed conflict and widespread civil strife, in part through the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Extending and Expanding Eligibility for Deferred Enforced Departure for Liberians</p>



<p>Since 1991, the United States has provided safe haven for Liberians who were forced to flee their country as a result of armed conflict and widespread civil strife, in part through the grant of Temporary Protected Status (TPS).&nbsp; The armed conflict ended in 2003, and TPS for affected Liberian nationals ended effective October 1, 2007.&nbsp; President Bush then deferred the enforced departure of those Liberians originally granted TPS.&nbsp; President Obama, in successive memoranda, extended that grant of Deferred Enforced Departure (DED) to March 31, 2018.&nbsp; President&nbsp;Trump then determined that conditions in Liberia did not warrant a further extension of DED, but that the foreign policy interests of the United States warranted an orderly transition period for Liberian DED beneficiaries.&nbsp; President&nbsp;Trump later extended that DED transition period through March 30, 2020.</p>



<p>In December 2019, the Congress enacted the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (Public Law 116-92) (NDAA), which included, as section 7611, the Liberian Refugee Immigration Fairness (LRIF) provision.&nbsp; The LRIF provision, with limited exceptions, makes Liberians who have been continuously present in the United States since November 20, 2014, as well as their spouses and children, eligible for adjustment of status to that of lawful permanent resident (LPR).&nbsp; The NDAA gave eligible Liberian nationals until December 20, 2020, to apply for this adjustment of status.&nbsp; After the enactment of the LRIF provision, President Trump further extended the DED transition period through January 10, 2021, to ensure that DED beneficiaries would continue to be eligible for employment authorization during the LRIF application period.</p>



<p><a>The LRIF application process was new and complex, resulting in some procedural and administrative challenges.&nbsp; </a>Recognizing these difficulties, the Congress enacted a 1-year extension to the application period in section 901 of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (Public Law 116-260).&nbsp; That legislation, however, did not provide for continued employment authorization past January 10, 2021.&nbsp; Through my memorandum of January 20, 2021 (Reinstating Deferred Enforced Departure for Liberians), DED was subsequently reinstated through June 30, 2022, in order to permit employment authorization for eligible Liberians while they made their applications for adjustment of status under the LRIF provision.</p>



<p>There are compelling foreign policy reasons to extend DED for an additional period for those Liberians presently residing in the United States who were under a grant of DED until June 30, 2022, as well as to defer enforced departure for Liberians who have been continuously present in the United States since May 20, 2017.&nbsp; In addition to updating the continuous presence requirement, I have also determined that it is appropriate to include qualifying Liberians whose LRIF applications have been denied for reasons other than ineligibility under sections&nbsp;7611(b)(1)(C) and (b)(3) of the NDAA in this DED designation.&nbsp; In particular, this includes providing protection from removal to those who arrived in the United States during a time when conditions prevented them from returning safely, including through May 20, 2017, and have since established family and community ties in the United States. &nbsp;Providing protection from removal and work authorization to these Liberians, for whom we have long authorized TPS or DED in the United States, including while they complete the LRIF status-adjustment process, honors the historic close relationship between the United States and Liberia and is in the foreign policy interests of the United States.</p>



<p>Pursuant to my constitutional authority to conduct the foreign relations of the United States, I have determined that it is in the foreign policy interests of the United States to defer through June 30, 2024, the removal of any Liberian national, or person without nationality who last habitually resided in Liberia, who is present in the United States and who was under a grant of DED as of June 30, 2022, as well as any Liberian national, or person without nationality who last habitually resided in Liberia, who has been continuously physically present in the United States since May 20, 2017.&nbsp; I have also determined that any Liberian national, or person without nationality who last habitually resided in Liberia, who was under a grant of DED as of June 30, 2022, or who has been continuously physically present in the United States since May 20, 2017, should have continued employment authorization through June 30, 2024.</p>



<p>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall promptly direct the appropriate officials to make provision, by means of a notice published in the <em>Federal Register</em>, for immediate allowance of employment authorization for those Liberians who held appropriate DED-related employment authorization documents as of June 30, 2022, or those Liberian nationals who have been continuously present in the United States since May 20, 2017.&nbsp; The Secretary of Homeland Security shall also provide for the prompt issuance of new or replacement employment authorization documents in appropriate cases.</p>



<p>This grant of DED and continued employment authorization shall apply to any Liberian DED beneficiary as of June 30, 2022, or any Liberian national who has been continuously present in the United States since May 20, 2017, but shall not apply to such persons in the following categories:</p>



<p>(1)&nbsp; individuals who would be ineligible for TPS for the reasons provided in section 244(c)(2)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, 8 U.S.C. 1254a(c)(2)(B);</p>



<p>(2)&nbsp; individuals who sought or seek LPR status under the LRIF provision but whose applications have been or are denied by the Secretary of Homeland Security due to ineligibility for the LRIF provision under sections&nbsp;7611(b)(1)(C) and (b)(3) of the NDAA;</p>



<p>(3)&nbsp; individuals whose removal the Secretary of Homeland Security determines is in the interest of the United&nbsp;States, subject to the LRIF provision;</p>



<p>(4)&nbsp; individuals whose presence or activities in the United&nbsp;States the Secretary of State has reasonable grounds to believe would have potentially serious adverse foreign policy consequences for the United States;</p>



<p>(5)&nbsp; individuals who have voluntarily returned to Liberia or their country of last habitual residence outside the United&nbsp;States for an aggregate period of 180 days or more, as specified in subsection (c)(2) of the LRIF provision; or</p>



<p>(6)&nbsp; individuals who are subject to extradition.</p>



<p>Accordingly, I hereby direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to take the necessary steps to implement for eligible Liberians:</p>



<p>(1)&nbsp; a deferral of enforced departure from the United&nbsp;States through June 30, 2024, effective immediately;&nbsp;and</p>



<p>(2)&nbsp; authorization for employment valid through June 30, 2024.</p>



<p>The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Amends New Mexico Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-amends-new-mexico-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 15:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the State of New Mexico by authorizing an increase in the level of Federal funding for debris removal and emergency protective measures undertaken in the State of New Mexico as a result of wildfires and straight-line winds beginning on April 5, 2022, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the State of New Mexico by authorizing an increase in the level of Federal funding for debris removal and emergency protective measures undertaken in the State of New Mexico as a result of wildfires and straight-line winds beginning on April 5, 2022, and continuing.</p>



<p>Under the President&#8217;s order today, the Federal share for debris removal and emergency protective measures, including direct Federal assistance has been increased to 100 percent of the total eligible costs for a 90-day period from the date of declaration.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proclamation on Increasing Duties on Certain Articles from the Russian&#160;Federation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/27/proclamation-on-increasing-duties-on-certain-articles-from-the-russian-federation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 15:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1.&#160; On April 8, 2022, I signed the Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act (19 U.S.C. 2434 note) (Suspending NTR Act).&#160; Section 3(a) of the Suspending NTR Act suspended nondiscriminatory tariff treatment for products of the Russian Federation and of the Republic of Belarus, and imposed the rates of duty set forth&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1.&nbsp; On April 8, 2022, I signed the Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act (19 U.S.C. 2434 note) (Suspending NTR Act).&nbsp; Section 3(a) of the Suspending NTR Act suspended nondiscriminatory tariff treatment for products of the Russian Federation and of the Republic of Belarus, and imposed the rates of duty set forth in column 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTSUS) on all products of the Russian Federation and of the Republic of Belarus, effective as of April 9, 2022. &nbsp;Section 3(b)(1) of the Suspending NTR Act provides that the President may proclaim increases in the column 2 rates of duty applicable to products of the Russian Federation and of the Republic of Belarus.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2.&nbsp; On April 8, 2022, I signed the Ending Importation of Russian Oil Act (22 U.S.C. 8923 note).&nbsp; Section 2 of the Ending Importation of Russian Oil Act prohibits imports of all products of the Russian Federation classified under chapter 27 of the HTSUS, in a manner consistent with any implementation actions issued under Executive Order 14066 of March 8, 2022.</p>



<p>3.&nbsp; In Executive Order 14066 of March 8, 2022, I prohibited, inter alia, importation into the United States of the following products of Russian Federation origin: &nbsp;crude oil; petroleum; petroleum fuels, oils, and products of their distillation; liquefied natural gas; coal; and coal products.</p>



<p>4.&nbsp; In Executive Order 14068 of March 11, 2022, I prohibited, inter alia, the importation into the United States of the following products of Russian Federation origin: &nbsp;fish, seafood, and preparations thereof; alcoholic beverages; and non-industrial diamonds.</p>



<p>5.&nbsp; In accordance with section 3(b)(1) of the Suspending NTR Act, I have determined that increasing the column 2 rates of duty to 35 percent ad valorem on certain other products of the Russian Federation, the importation of which has not already been prohibited, is warranted and consistent with the foreign policy interests of the United States. &nbsp;These products are listed in Annex A to this proclamation.&nbsp; The United States will monitor the implementation of the increased duties, and I may revisit this determination, as appropriate.</p>



<p>6.&nbsp; Section 604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended (19&nbsp;U.S.C. 2483), authorizes the President to embody in the HTSUS the substance of statutes affecting import treatment, and actions thereunder, including the removal, modification, continuance, or imposition of any rate of duty or other import restriction.</p>



<p>Now, Therefore, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United&nbsp;States of America, by the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;3 of the Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act; section 301 of title 3, United&nbsp;States Code; and section&nbsp;604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended, do hereby proclaim as follows:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (1)&nbsp; To increase the column 2 rates of duty on imports of certain articles of the Russian Federation as set forth in paragraph 5 of this proclamation, HTSUS heading 9903.90.08 and new U.S. Note 30 to subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS are provided for in Annex A to this proclamation. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(2)&nbsp; The modifications to the HTSUS made by clause 1 of this proclamation shall be effective with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on the day that is 30 days after the date of this proclamation and shall continue in effect, unless such actions are expressly reduced, modified, or terminated.</p>



<p>(3)&nbsp; General Note 3(b) to the HTSUS is amended to add the Republic of Belarus and the Russian Federation to the list of countries subject to column 2 duties.&nbsp; This amendment is provided in Annex B to this proclamation.</p>



<p>(4)&nbsp; Any provision of previous proclamations and Executive&nbsp;Orders that is inconsistent with the actions taken in&nbsp;this proclamation is superseded to the extent of such inconsistency.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-seventh day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Meeting with Global Reproductive Rights&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-global-reproductive-rights-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 13:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, June 21, officials from the White House Gender Policy Council and National Security Council convened a meeting with leaders and experts on global reproductive rights. Participants discussed how a ruling in Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization might impact access to sexual and reproductive health and rights around the world, and offered recommendations&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, June 21, officials from the White House Gender Policy Council and National Security Council convened a meeting with leaders and experts on global reproductive rights. Participants discussed how a ruling in <em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization</em> might impact access to sexual and reproductive health and rights around the world, and offered recommendations to the Administration to protect and advance women’s health globally.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>White House officials thanked the leaders for their efforts and underscored the Administration’s commitment to support sexual and reproductive health and rights across the globe.</p>



<p>Participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Amnesty International</li><li>Center for Reproductive Rights</li><li>EngenderHealth</li><li>Ibis Reproductive Health</li><li>Ipas</li><li>PAI</li><li>Women Deliver</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On-the-Record Press Gaggle by National Security Advisor Jake&#160;Sullivan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/27/on-the-record-press-gaggle-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56335</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:55 P.M. CEST MR. SULLIVAN:  All right.  Well, first, I want to make maximum use of your time, so the only thing I’d say at the top is the President had a productive set of sessions yesterday at the G7 this morning.        He had opportunity to hear from President Zelenskyy and then to spend two hours&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:55 P.M. CEST<br> <br>MR. SULLIVAN:  All right.  Well, first, I want to make maximum use of your time, so the only thing I’d say at the top is the President had a productive set of sessions yesterday at the G7 this morning.  <br> <br>     He had opportunity to hear from President Zelenskyy and then to spend two hours with his fellow G7 leaders and President Zelenskyy, talking about the way forward in Ukraine.  <br> <br>     It was a good session &#8212; very detailed and substantive across all the major lines of effort, including military, economic, humanitarian assistance, sanctions, and other steps we’re taking to support the Ukrainians and hold Russia accountable.<br> <br>     And I’ll just leave it there at the top and open it up for questions on the session this morning or really on anything else that&#8217;s on your guys&#8217; minds. <br> <br>     Q    Can you talk to the new military assistance that is being confirmed by an administration official?<br>    <br>     MR. SULLIVAN:  So I&#8217;ve seen the reports of specific details around advanced air defense capabilities that the United States is preparing to provide to the Ukrainians.  I can confirm that we are, in fact, in the process of finalizing a package that includes advanced air defense capabilities.  I won&#8217;t get into the details of the system.  I&#8217;ll wait until the contract actually gets done. <br> <br>     But this week, as the President told his fellow G7 leaders &#8212; and as he told President Zelenskyy &#8212; we do intend to finalize a package that includes advanced medium- and long-range air defense capabilities for the Ukrainians, along with some other items that are of urgent need, including ammunition for artillery and counterbattery radar systems.<br> <br>     Q    I was asking more about the conversation with President Zelenskyy this morning with the G7 leaders.  Did President Zelenskyy have any specific requests of them?  Did the President and the other G7 leaders have a particular message for President Zelenskyy?  What was the nature of that conversation?<br> <br>     MR. SULLIVAN:  So, he did have some specific requests.  His first request in the presentation he made was for further air defense systems.  In particular, at the top of his mind was the set of missile strikes that took place in Kyiv and other cities across Ukraine, and his desire to get additional air defense capabilities that could shoot down Russian missiles out in sky. <br> <br>     So, the President was able to be positively responsive to him on that. <br> <br>     He had some other requests relating to economic assistance to ensure that Ukraine&#8217;s economy can remain basically stable and afloat.  And President Biden and other G7 leaders were able to explain to him the assistance that we&#8217;re providing on a monthly basis to the tune of a total of $7.5 billion in economic assistance from the United States. <br> <br>     But the bulk of the conversation was not about asks and gives; it was really about the way forward and how President Zelenskyy sees the course of the war and is trying to assimilate and incorporate all of the assistance he&#8217;s been given to maximize Ukraine&#8217;s capacity both to resist Russian advances and to pursue counterattacks where possible. <br> <br>     A lot of it was detailed and sensitive.  It was a real conversation about strategy.  And so, I&#8217;m not going to go further in terms of public characterizations of it, because this was genuinely an opportunity for the G7 leaders plus Zelenskyy to really talk turkey about how to help Ukraine achieve its objectives and how to help deny Russia its objectives.  And I think a lot came out of it that we can collectively follow up on.  <br>     Q    Do you have a sense of how the security package that you&#8217;re putting together &#8212; like what it would tangibly mean on the ground in Ukraine, like how it would help? <br></p>



<p>   MR. SULLIVAN:  So it&#8217;s a little difficult for me to talk about the specific practical impact of the air defense capability without frontrunning the announcement of that capability.  <br> <br>     So what I will tell you is this: that by the end of this week, we&#8217;ll make sure that you get some expert military briefers who can walk through what it will actually mean tangibly, in terms of the defense of Ukrainian airspace and particularly population centers. <br> <br>     The other pieces of it &#8212; artillery, ammunition &#8212; is self-evident.  This is an artillery battle in the East.  We&#8217;ve provided now well more than 100 howitzers, tubes of M777 artillery.  And that artillery needs a constant supply of ammunition to continue to be effective, and we&#8217;re providing that on an ongoing basis. <br> <br>     And then the counterbattery radars are really about helping give the Ukrainians an advantage in an artillery fight because it helps them have better visibility into what they&#8217;re up against.  <br> <br>     So what we&#8217;re trying to do at this point is tailor our military assistance to the particular immediate needs of the Ukrainians on the battlefield at a given point in time.  Months ago, that was really about anti-tank and anti-air systems like Stingers.  Then it became about artillery.  Now, increasingly, it&#8217;s about some of these sophisticated systems like counterbattery radar and the HIMARS.  And of course, we&#8217;ve announced two tranches of those, along with the very sophisticated munitions that go along with them. <br> <br>     So, we&#8217;ll continue to do that as we go forward.  I have an open channel with my counterpart, and General Milley has an open channel with his.  And oftentimes, the four of us speak, just so that we level-set both around what the strategic picture looks like and then, tactically, what the Ukrainians need.  And we use those conversations as the basis to formulate these packages. <br> <br>     Q    Jake, I was just going to ask: We have quoted some European officials saying that Zelenskyy made clear that he wants the war to end this year, that it would be difficult to go into the winter.  Can you say something about whether the winter poses a particular danger?  And can you characterize, you know, what Zelenskyy told the leaders about the &#8212;<br> <br>     MR. SULLIVAN:  I want to be very careful about characterizing his remarks.  I think he should speak for himself on this.  What I will say is that Zelenskyy was very much focused on trying to ensure that Ukraine is in as advantageous a position on the battlefield as possible in the next months as opposed to the next years because he believes that a grinding conflict is not in the interest of the Ukrainian people, for obvious reasons.  <br> <br>     So he would like to see his military and those in the West who are supporting his military make maximum use of the next few months to put the Ukrainians in as good a position as they can possibly be in with respect to the situation on the ground in both the East and the South.  And that’s consistent with the American approach of trying to flow in the necessary materiel and equipment to put the Ukrainians in an advantageous position on the battlefield.  But that’s really what he was focused on. <br> <br>     I think, from his perspective, pushing the pace of both assistance and operations on the battlefield is an important part of Ukrainian strategy, as opposed to letting things just drag out indefinitely.<br> <br>     Q    On the oil price cap that we know you guys are announcing tomorrow, or on that process of it, can you talk a little bit about why there wasn&#8217;t more success in getting closer to an agreement in principle?  Who are the holdouts?  What&#8217;s the dynamics there? <br> <br>     And given that this is one of the main revenue streams for funding his war &#8212; Putin&#8217;s war &#8212; did this come up in the Zelenskyy conversation?  Is this at all something that he&#8217;s pushing the leaders to, you know, get to an agreement sooner rather than later?<br> <br>     MR. SULLIVAN:  Zelenskyy didn&#8217;t specifically raise the price cap.  What he did raise was denying Putin revenues from oil sales.  And I think the characterization that there are holdouts in this conversation isn&#8217;t quite correct.  If I take a step back, there is absolute consensus across the G7 that the purpose of our energy sanctions on Russia should ultimately be to deny revenue to Russia while at the same time ensuring a stable global energy market. <br> <br>     There is also consensus emerging &#8212; although there continue to be discussions around it, so I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the leaders on this &#8212; that the price cap is a serious method to achieve that outcome.  <br> <br>     So then the question becomes: How do you implement it working with consuming countries and with the private sector?  What are the details?  What are the methods of execution?  That requires technical work that has to be done by ministers &#8212; energy ministers and finance ministers &#8212; in order to develop an actual executable cap that then goes into effect.<br> <br>     So the leaders can&#8217;t design every element of the program here at Elmau.  What they can do is give direction to ministers to design such a program and then come back to leaders to bless it and have it be implemented.</p>



<p>Nothing is finalized yet, but we think that the trend is looking good towards leaders coming together around the idea that this is one of the options available to achieve the goal of driving down Putin’s revenues from oil while maintaining stable oil &#8212; energy markets.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, just on that, can you tell us: Has the President been sort of personally lobbying the other leaders on the idea of the price cap?&nbsp; And what have you all had to convince them of?&nbsp; Are they worried that it won’t work?&nbsp; Are they there might be sort of bad effects to it?&nbsp; Like, what’s been the holdup?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think the single biggest factor here is that this is not something that can be pulled off the shelf as a tried-and-true method that has repeated historical precedent and therefore can simply be taken as a standing option and implemented.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is a new kind of concept to deal with a particularly novel challenge, which is how to effectively deal with a country that’s selling millions of barrels of oil a day and try to deprive it of some of the revenues that they&#8217;re getting from the sale of that oil.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, this has been less about having to break down particular resistance and more about a process of consultation, education, thinking through all of the puts and takes.<br><br>And so I wouldn’t describe what the President has been doing here as lobbying so much as posing the problem, which is: If you merely try to reduce flows and not reduce price, you have certain impacts on the energy market that are averse, whereas if you reduce price &#8212; if you focus on price more than flows, you might be able to actually maximize your overall objectives of both depriving revenues to Putin and keeping energy market stable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in a way, this conversation &#8212; starting at the expert working level, then ministers, now leaders &#8212; has been one of the G7 countries puzzling through a difficult challenge together and arriving at a point, we believe, where there is convergence around really trying to pursue this.&nbsp;<br><br>And the President has been at the center of that over the course of the past 24 hours, talking it through with leaders, both one on one and then in group settings.<br><br>And we&#8217;ll see where things land.&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;m not announcing some deal.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying I think it&#8217;s headed in the right direction because everybody sees the logic and merit of tasking ministers to really try to develop a &#8212; an affirmative proposal on this score.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the realistic timeframe, though, for this given &#8212; you know, you just said, Zelenskyy really wants to move things along, not have this drag out into years.&nbsp; This isn&#8217;t going to happen over this &#8212; you know, at the summit.&nbsp; How long is realistic to see something like this take shape and take effect?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first of all, if we do get an agreement to task ministers, if that actually happens, I think<br>you guys can obviously look at that and say, “Okay, we don&#8217;t have a price cap in effect”&nbsp;on Wednesday of this week.&nbsp; I look at that as a pretty dramatic step forward and one that would be a &#8212; looking back over the course of the last several years, one of the more significant outcomes of a G7 summit.&nbsp;<br><br>Then, in terms of the actual timetables and modalities, it&#8217;s hard for me to say.&nbsp; There is no reason, though, that if leaders come together around this, that there couldn&#8217;t be relatively rapid work done on it, but I&#8217;m not going to put a timetable on it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can&#8217;t say whether that’s &#8212; “rapid” is weeks or months or &#8212;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Just in the interest of not having you guys come back to me and read a particular timetable prediction, I&#8217;ll just say I think it can be done relatively quickly.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to the “months, not years” from President Zelenskyy &#8212; or request from President Zelenskyy for urgent support.&nbsp; Does that stem, in fact &#8212; how does that &#8212; does that stem from sort of the assessment that Russia is having difficulty resupplying its forces, backfilling casualties, and that by flowing in Allied resources now that it can sort of provide Ukraine, there&#8217;s a window of opportunity for Ukraine to launch a counteroffensive in some places before Russia can sort of bolster and rearm and resupply its forces?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is there a window of opportunity here?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; President Zelenskyy wasn&#8217;t explicit on that point.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s fair to say that that battlefield analysis is one consideration.&nbsp; I think another really important consideration is just the sense of suffering of the Ukrainian people with each day and week that this goes on.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, he&#8217;s got an urgency to try to show his people that Ukraine is, first of all, holding fast against the Russian onslaught and, secondly, making some progress in areas where they feel that they can, in fact, push back against the Russians.<br><br>So, I should probably leave it there because I think, in terms of Zelenskyy’s logic for this, I&#8217;d rather have him speak to it himself than me speak for him.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak about the U.S. assessment of Russian &#8212; of the degradation of Russia&#8217;s military capacity now as it sort of seems to be on the cusp of taking Luhansk and maybe can’t go much further beyond that?&nbsp; That &#8212; you know, what &#8212; is Russia running out of resources, running out of people to throw into this fight?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I would put it this way: Russia faces limitations in terms of its ability to resupply and to fill out its battalion tactical groups.&nbsp; Those limitations are real.&nbsp; They have an impact on Russia&#8217;s capacity to achieve its ultimate strategic aims in this conflict, which we do not believe are limited to the Donbas, certainly are not limited to Luhansk.<br><br>But I will leave it to the Pentagon to characterize more specifically the question you&#8217;re posing about &#8212; you know,<br>whether or not they have enough munitions or whether or not they literally have enough people to be able to keep going over the next several months.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would just say that the limitations &#8212; the operational, logistical, manpower, and munition limitations on them are a constraint on their capacity to achieve what they want to achieve.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, as we get to the very end, I want to ask you quickly whether you think that there could be possibility for bilateral discussion for the President with President Erdoğan.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And also, on the Iran missile strike, just if you could say a word or two about the prospects for &#8212; your assessment of that situation with Iran and the missile strike and the possibility of moving forward.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, on the question of meeting with President Erdoğan, nothing is scheduled at the moment, but they may very well have the opportunity to see one another at the NATO Summit.&nbsp; Let’s see how the next 24 hours unfold.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There is a flurry of diplomatic activity occurring.&nbsp; Today, the Swedish Prime Minister will be in Brussels making a statement.&nbsp; Tomorrow, we understand that there will be further engagements among the Turks, Finns, Swedes, and the NATO Secretary General.&nbsp; And so we want to see how that unfolds as we head into Madrid.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President is following this very closely.&nbsp; His team is working it with the Finns, Swedes, and Turks, and I’m on the phone daily with my counterparts from all three countries.&nbsp; So let’s &#8212; let’s see how things go, I guess is the &#8212; the answer to your question.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Iran, the United States’ view is straightforward and has been now for quite some time, which is that we&#8217;re determined to ensure that Iran does not acquire a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; We think a diplomatic agreement is the best way to do that.&nbsp; We think a mutual return to the JCPOA is in the interest of the United States and our partners.&nbsp; And there is a deal available on the table to Iran, and it&#8217;s up to Iran to decide whether or not it wants to take it.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Last question.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On that flurry of activity with the Finns and Swedes and the Turks, are they &#8212; we aren&#8217;t expecting, like, action at this NATO Summit,&nbsp;or are we?&nbsp; Or is it moving in that direction that they could be added to NATO this quickly?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think the goal is to create as much positive momentum as we can behind the candidacies of Finland and Sweden.&nbsp; I am not sitting here today suggesting that all issues will be resolved by Madrid, but we&#8217;re going to try and resolve as many of them as possible so that Madrid gives a boost to their candidacies, even if there remains some concerns on the part of Turkey that need to be worked out.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can I ask one more on China &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sure, one more.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; since we&#8217;re also expecting language on that that you guys tell us is very strong &#8212; stronger than last year&#8217;s.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, we’re expecting a call and potential meeting between the President and the President of China.&nbsp; Is this &#8212; to what extent is this an opportunity to sort of brief the G7 leaders?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, should we expect on, you know, the U.S. policies and, you know, announcements that you have forthcoming?&nbsp; And then should we expect a call with Xi shortly after this meeting, given &#8212; I don&#8217;t know what you need to schedule it; sort of, the dynamics on that one.</p>



<p>      MR. SULLIVAN:  So, first, the President has already had the opportunity to have a discussion with his fellow leaders on China and, in particular, in briefing them on the U.S. approach to China and some of his recent conversations, as well as my own and others’ conversations with Chinese counterparts.</p>



<p>&nbsp;We do expect that the President and President Xi will have the opportunity to engage over the course of the next few weeks.&nbsp;&nbsp;I can&#8217;t put a particular timeframe on it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not going to be immediately after the G7.&nbsp;<br><br>And we do think that there is increasing convergence, both at the G7 and at NATO, around the challenge China poses and around the need &#8212; the urgent need for consultation and especially alignment among the world&#8217;s leading market democracies to deal with some of those challenges &#8212; in particular, China&#8217;s non-market economic practices, its approach to debt, and its approach to human rights.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I think you can expect that the G7 statement will speak to all of those, and then I think you can expect that the NATO Strategic Concept will also speak in ways that are unprecedented about the challenge that China poses.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But in both contexts, it&#8217;s important to underscore something the President says to all of his fellow leaders and which they all agree, and it’s: Competition does not mean confrontation or conflict.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not looking for a Cold War, and we&#8217;re not looking to divide the world into rival blocs and make every country choose.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We want to stand for a set of principles, rules of the road that are fair and understood and agreed by everybody.&nbsp; And we want to ensure that we&#8217;re working with like-minded partners to hold China accountable to adhere to those rules.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the spirit and the message that I think will emerge both from Elmau and from Madrid.</p>



<p>1:18 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by President&#160;Biden and President von der Leyen on European Energy&#160;Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/joint-statement-by-president-biden-and-president-von-der-leyen-on-european-energy-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following the further invasion of Ukraine, Russia continues to use natural gas as a political and economic weapon. &#160;Russia’s energy coercion has put pressure on energy markets, raised prices for consumers, and threatened global energy security. This was most recently demonstrated by the politically motivated acute disruptions of gas supplies to several European Union Member&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Following the further invasion of Ukraine, Russia continues to use natural gas as a political and economic weapon. &nbsp;Russia’s energy coercion has put pressure on energy markets, raised prices for consumers, and threatened global energy security. This was most recently demonstrated by the politically motivated acute disruptions of gas supplies to several European Union Member States. These actions only underscore the importance of the work both the United States and the European Commission are doing to end our reliance on Russian energy. We are also working together to find ways to further reduce Russia’s energy-derived revenues in the coming months to further curtail Russia’s ability to fund its unprovoked war in Ukraine. These actions are important, necessary, and immediate steps we can take, but we also recognize the enormity of the challenge is significant. To meet the challenge and support Europe’s efforts, we established on 25 March 2022 the Task Force on European Energy Security. Since then the United States and the European Commission have made important strides towards reducing the European Union’s dependence on Russian fossil fuels by decreasing natural gas demand, cooperating on energy efficiency technologies, and diversifying energy supplies. The United States and the European Commission are also taking decisive action to reduce overall demand for fossil fuels in line with the Paris Agreement and our shared goal of net zero emissions no later than 2050.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Task Force has met regularly to discuss options to reduce Europe’s demand for natural gas and has also met with key stakeholders to promote the deployment of heat pumps, smart thermostats, and energy demand response solutions. &nbsp;We will encourage Member States and European and U.S. companies to reach an initial goal of deploying at least 1.5 million energy saving smart thermostats in European households this year. &nbsp;In the coming days we will reconvene with Member States and stakeholders to discuss actionable policy recommendations to accelerate smart thermostat and heat pump deployment and production in an effort to ensure supply for key energy efficiency solutions are ramping to meet the growing demand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are also partnering to diversify energy supplies to Europe. While Russia has cut supplies of natural gas to several EU Member States, the United States and other producers have stepped up. &nbsp;Since March, global LNG exports to Europe have risen by 75 percent compared to 2021, while U.S. LNG exports to Europe have nearly tripled. &nbsp;To facilitate these efforts, the European Commission and Member States, in line with a mandate given by the European Council in March 2022, established the EU Energy Platform to coordinate measures to secure reliable and diversified energy supplies for the EU, including through the voluntary common purchase of pipeline gas, LNG, and hydrogen. The Commission has also established the first Regional Energy Platform for South East Europe to support gas diversification of the region traditionally dependent on Russian supplies. The United States is a key partner for the sustainable diversification of gas supplies to this region and other acutely impacted EU Member States, including by supporting demand reduction and accelerating clean technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mindful of the environmental impact of LNG production and consumption, the United States and the European Commission will step up their cooperation to reduce methane emissions, to ensure that EU-U.S. LNG trade is aligned with the scope of an internationally accepted measurement, reporting and verification standard for methane emissions while working to reduce venting and flaring in natural gas production, and methane leakage in the transmission and LNG supply chain. We will also continue our cooperation on reduction of methane emissions globally. Most recently, the joint launch with 11 other countries of the Global Methane Pledge Energy Pathway will advance both climate progress and energy security internationally.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Second Day in&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/27/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-president-bidens-second-day-in-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 09:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[8:39 A.M. CEST MODERATOR:&#160; All right.&#160; So, in the interest of time, we’re going to go ahead and get started.&#160; First, you know, I’m sorry that we had to move the time up &#8212; just, you know, shifting schedules that we just couldn’t plan for.&#160; So I’m &#8212; again, I’m sorry, and thank you for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>8:39 A.M. CEST</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; So, in the interest of time, we’re going to go ahead and get started.&nbsp; First, you know, I’m sorry that we had to move the time up &#8212; just, you know, shifting schedules that we just couldn’t plan for.&nbsp; So I’m &#8212; again, I’m sorry, and thank you for joining so early this morning.<br><br>So we’re going to preview some announcements that are going to be coming as part of a coordinated G7 announcement on Tuesday, but we wanted to give you a sense of where things are and also a laydown of some new U.S. actions.<br><br>This call is on background.&nbsp; It is attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And the contents of the call are embargoed until 10:00 a.m., Germany; 4:00 a.m., U.S.<br><br>So, with that &#8212; and, sorry, for your awareness but not for reporting, our speaker is [senior administration official].<br><br>So, [senior administration official], I’ll turn it over to you.&nbsp; And then we’ll try to take as many questions as we can.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, Saloni.&nbsp;<br><br>And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; We had a packed day at the G7 yesterday, and we are now headed into day two.<br><br>President Biden and the whole team here have been working around the clock to leverage the fact that close to 50 percent of the world’s economy is in one place and put forward further efforts to support Ukraine, hold Russia accountable, and manage the impacts of Putin’s war on the global economy.<br><br>I want to take just a few minutes to preview some of the efforts the U.S. will be taking in coordination with the G7.&nbsp; But before I get to that, I want to start with setting some context.<br><br>As you all know, the United States has rallied over 30 allies and partners around the world to impose drastic historic costs on Russia.<br><br>It was reported overnight that Russia defaulted on its sovereign debt for the first time in more than a century.<br><br>So, in the span of a few months, U.S. exports to Russia, including of critical technology inputs that Putin needs to maintain his military, those have decreased 97 percent.&nbsp; Russia’s imports of goods from around the world could fall by as much as 40 percent this year.<br><br>Factories across Russia are struggling to maintain production.&nbsp; Russia’s GDP is likely to fall by double digits this year, and inflation is rising to over 20 percent.<br><br>So, just by way of context, and I think this morning’s news around &#8212; around the finding of Russia’s default for the first time in more than a century situates just how strong the reactions are that the U.S., along with allies and partners, have taken, as well as how dramatic the input &#8212; the impact has been on Russia’s economy, both today and cumulating &#8212; accumulating across time.<br><br>Today, the United States will continue &#8212; pardon me &#8212; the United States will continue to increase pressure on Putin.&nbsp; That’s why today we’re announcing:</p>



<p>First &#8212; and on this first one, you know, we’re still in final discussions with other G7 counterparts, working to finalize this, but we’re very close to a place where G7 leaders will have decided to urgently direct relevant ministers to develop mechanisms to set a global price cap for Russian oil in shipments to countries outside of the U.S., EU, the UK, and the broader G7.<br><br>The goal here is to starve Russia &#8212; starve Putin of his main source of cash and force down the price of Russian oil to help blunt the impact of Putin’s war at the pump.</p>



<p>As I’ve said repeatedly, we have dual objectives here.&nbsp; The dual objectives of G7 leaders have been to take direct aim at Putin’s revenues, particularly through energy, but also to minimize the spillovers and the impact on the G7 economies and the rest of the world.<br><br>And G7 leaders are going to acknowledge those two objectives and also acknowledge that the path forward is to urgently direct ministers to work on achieving a price cap, which can, in our judgement, best achieve both of those objectives simultaneously.<br><br>Secondly, G7 leaders will align and expand targeted sanctions to further restrict Russia’s access to key industrial inputs, to services and technologies produced by our economies, particularly those supporting Russia’s armament industrial base and technology sector.<br><br>On Tuesday, the United States Departments of State and Treasury will aggressively target Russian defense supply chains by imposing blocking sanctions on major state-owned defense enterprises, in addition to defense research organizations, and dozens of other defense-related entities and individuals, and limit Russia’s ability to replace the military equipment it has already lost during its brutal war against Ukraine.</p>



<p>We will align on using tariffs on Russian goods to help Ukraine.&nbsp; Earlier this year, G7 leaders committed to strip Russia of “most favored nation” trading status, which guaranteed low tariff rates for Russian goods sold globally.<br><br>President Biden and other G7 leaders will seek authority to use revenues collected by new &#8212; any new tariffs on Russian goods to help Ukraine and to ensure that Russia pays for the cost of its war.<br><br>President Biden is also announcing that, pursuant to Congress’s revocation of trade &#8212; Russia’s trade status in the U.S., the U.S. will implement a higher tariff rate on more than 570 groups of Russian products worth approximately $2.3 billion.<br><br>These measures will restrict Russia’s ability to benefit economically from sales to the U.S. market and are carefully calibrated to impose costs on Russia, and are not expected to have impacts on U.S. supply chain or raise costs to U.S. consumers.<br><br>G7 Leaders will decide to impose sanctions on those responsible for human rights abuses, including war crimes, exercising illegitimate authority in Ukraine, and involved in Russia’s tactics to steal Ukrainian grain or otherwise profit illegitimately from the war.<br><br>On Tuesday, the U.S. Departments of Treasury and State will implement blocking sanctions on private military companies operating in Ukraine, Russian military units that have been credibly implicated in human rights abuses or violations of international humanitarian law in Ukraine, and Russia-installed senior officials in contested areas, including ministers and mayors of contested cities.<br><br>State will impose visa restrictions on approximately 500 officials for threatening or violating Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, or political independence, or suppressing dissent in Russia.<br><br>And lastly, you will see significant G7 &#8212; significant G7 commitment to help Ukraine cover its short-term budgetary shortfalls, including a $7.5 billion commitment from the United States from the recently passed second supplemental.</p>



<p><br>With that, I will go ahead and stop and take any questions from the group that we have time for.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great, thank you.&nbsp; If you have a question, could you please raise your hand?<br><br>All right, let&#8217;s go to Jim from the Times.&nbsp; Jim, can you ask your question, please?</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], can you tell us more about how the price cap is shaping up?&nbsp; Who all would implement it?&nbsp; How might it work?&nbsp; I know you haven&#8217;t figured out the details yet.&nbsp; But &#8212; and, sort of, what would the &#8212; a potential price cap be that is in the ballpark of what you guys are discussing?</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Jim.&nbsp; So, again, I would take a step back and say: What leaders are likely to articulate here is a set of shared objectives.&nbsp; Those objectives are denying Russia&#8217;s energy revenues, their resources to continue to wage war, and also to minimize the spillovers on the rest of the economy, minimize the disruption in global energy markets, minimize the impact for consumers in the United States and around the world.<br><br>What is been &#8212; what is likely to be further acknowledged here is that while we are &#8212; in the U.S., the EU, Canada, the UK &#8212; implementing our own oil embargos on Russian oil, we collectively have a set of tools that can go to the services that are provided to allow Russian oil to be transported elsewhere in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And by zeroing in on those services and the way in which they&#8217;re provided &#8212; and particularly, potentially, through the mechanism of a price gap &#8212; there&#8217;s an ability to achieve both of those objectives simultaneously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What leaders are likely to do is task the relevant ministers, including finance ministers across the G7, to work intensively with other partners around the world, to work intensively with the private sector in the period of time ahead to urgently take steps to determine how to design and implement such a mechanism and, again, design and implement such a mechanism with those two shared objectives squarely in mind.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great, thank you.&nbsp; Let’s go to Zeke Miller from the AP.&nbsp; What’s your question, please?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], can you just clarify a little bit &#8212; so it sounds like you&#8217;re saying there is an agreement in principle but not an agreement on substance on the price cap and &#8212; including no details on how it would actually work.&nbsp; How long would it take to actually come up with those details to be in a place where this would be able to be implemented?</p>



<p>And then also, what do you predict the impact would be, if any, of this action on the price of U.S. energy and U.S. consumer prices?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so I&#8217;d say a couple of things.&nbsp; You know, one: Yes, what we&#8217;re likely to achieve here is leaders aligning around those shared objectives, leaders acknowledging that a price cap on Russian oil implemented through the services that G7 economies provide collectively to transport Russian oil elsewhere in the world &#8212; that that is a very promising avenue to pursue to achieve our shared objectives &#8212; again, denying Putin revenue, minimizing the disruption in global energy markets, providing greater stability and supply in global energy markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, there are &#8212; this, as you might imagine, requires a great deal of coordination, a great deal of effort across a number of different ministries in the G7.&nbsp; It requires a great deal of coordination with international partners.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the statement recognizes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it tasks ministers to go do urgently.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we would expect, in the coming period of time, that we will have &#8212; that we will get &#8212; that we will take steps towards identifying the precise mechanisms through which this would be achieved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in terms of impact on consumer prices, you know, I don&#8217;t want to make any forecasts.&nbsp; Again, I think what we have been focused on is how do we achieve these dual objectives.&nbsp; And importantly, you know, one of those dual objectives is ensuring stability in global energy markets, ensuring supply on global energy markets.&nbsp; We think this is a tool that is going to do exactly that: provide additional clarity that there will be supply and stability in global energy markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so we are of the belief that this is a tool that is going to &#8212; that is &#8212; while I don&#8217;t want to make any forecasts &#8212; is going to achieve those objectives of providing stability, providing greater certainty, and providing greater comfort around supply in global energy markets in ways that that we think will have the intended effect with respect to energy prices.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; So I think we just have time for one more, and then I know you have to run.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So let&#8217;s do Andrea Shalal from Reuters.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Hey, thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], can you just sort of explain to me how much, you know, further this takes it?&nbsp; There&#8217;s 30 countries already doing sanctions.&nbsp; This set of measures that G7 leaders are expected to agree to, does it take you to, sort of, 90 percent of what&#8217;s possible?&nbsp; You know, can you just sort of characterize what this is &#8212; stepping back, zooming out &#8212; in terms of ratcheting up pressure on Russia?</p>



<p>And then if I could just ask you with regard to the price cap and the transportation of oil and &#8212; I&#8217;m wondering whether your conversations, you know, with other countries that have been the so-called fence sitters on this and have continued to draw oil &#8212; are you making headway?&nbsp; Have any substantial countries &#8212; say, India &#8212; agreed?&nbsp; Have you had conversations with China about how they will deal with this and whether they&#8217;re willing to reduce their purchases or &#8212; you know, how would the price caps affect those purchases?</p>



<p>Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; So, just to take the second question first: I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of news, to get ahead of consultations, but I think what you will see &#8212; what you&#8217;re likely to see reflected in what leaders say is a recognition that the ministers that have been tasked to do this work need to engage intensively with potential partner countries around the world; engage intensively with stakeholders, including those in the private sector.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to be a very intensive set of dialogues, an intensive set of conversations in the days and weeks ahead.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t want to characterize the state of those to date, the state of what those might be going ahead, other than to say we&#8217;re very intensely focused on having that dialogue and having those conversations around potential partners in this effort and ensuring that we work closely with the private sector and other stakeholders to implement this step effectively.</p>



<p>And then, with respect to the broader perspective on the sanctions package, I mean, I think that you&#8217;ve seen through the steps that G7 have taken together an ongoing focus on a few things on ensuring that Russia&#8217;s economy is isolated from the global economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think, with respect to the actions that you saw yesterday on gold, that was taking another step to disconnect Russia&#8217;s financial sector from the global financial system, cutting off yet another route for Russian transactions back into the global financial system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think what you&#8217;re seeing today is also a continuation of a number of themes that we&#8217;ve been articulating for a while: degrading Russia&#8217;s defense industrial base and significant new steps and actions there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think you also see an ongoing effort to focus on individuals who are most egregiously connected to Russia&#8217;s aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what you&#8217;re seeing today with respect to the set of steps that are being articulated on those who are credibly implicated in human rights abuses and war crimes, those who are profiteering from Russia&#8217;s invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, these &#8212; there are an existing set of, I think &#8212; there have been an existing set of lines of effort, of themes that have been getting advanced over the months since Russia&#8217;s invasion.&nbsp; And these are our collective next set of steps to ensure that we&#8217;re continuing to ratchet up the pressure across each of those lines of efforts.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and the contents are going to lift at 10:00 a.m., Germany; 4:00 a.m., D.C.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to send a factsheet shortly.&nbsp; So if you don&#8217;t get it in the next 10 to 15 minutes, just feel free to ping me.&nbsp; And if you have any other questions, let us know.&nbsp; Thanks for your time.</p>



<p> 8:57 A.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
