<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 03:37:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s call with President Alberto Fernandez of the Argentine&#160;Republic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-alberto-fernandez-of-the-argentine-republic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 03:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Alberto Fernandez of the Argentine Republic in advance of the Summit of the Americas. The President invited President Fernandez to visit Washington in July to build upon active U.S.-Argentina engagement on bilateral, regional, and global issues, specifically human rights, food insecurity, climate change and energy, technological&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Alberto Fernandez of the Argentine Republic in advance of the Summit of the Americas. The President invited President Fernandez to visit Washington in July to build upon active U.S.-Argentina engagement on bilateral, regional, and global issues, specifically human rights, food insecurity, climate change and energy, technological innovation, and critical supply chains. The President also outlined his vision for a region that is secure, middle class, and democratic, which is fundamentally in the national security interest of the United States. The President reiterated that the U.S. relationship with the Americas is based on partnership, mutual respect, and a shared objective of promoting a green and equitable recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden During Virtual Meeting on Accelerating Infant Formula Production Through Operation Fly&#160;Formula</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/01/remarks-by-president-biden-during-virtual-meeting-on-accelerating-infant-formula-production-through-operation-fly-formula/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 23:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54609</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 2:47 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Thank you all for &#8212; for doing this today, including our Secretary, Xavier Becerra, who is here; the Surgeon General, Vivek Murthy; and our Deputy Director of Domestic Policy, Christen Young; the Deputy Director of the National Economic Council, Sameera, who&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>2:47 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you all for &#8212; for doing this today, including our Secretary, Xavier Becerra, who is here; the Surgeon General, Vivek Murthy; and our Deputy Director of Domestic Policy, Christen Young; the Deputy Director of the National Economic Council, Sameera, who is going to sit right behind me and &#8212; and do all the hard work; as well as a group of manufacturers from infant formula joining us virtually.&nbsp; Thank you all again.</p>



<p>Look, as a father and a grandfather &#8212; and I&#8217;m sure we all feel the same way &#8212; I understand how difficult this shortage has been for families all across the country.&nbsp; There is nothing more stressful than the feeling like you can’t get what your child needs &#8212; what he or she needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it’s why I’ve directed my administration to use every tool available to increase the supply [and] get more formula on shelves as quickly as possible, working with manufacturers to re-open factories that have closed and ramp up production quickly so we can increase the availability of infant formula and lower the costs for American families.</p>



<p>We’re &#8212; we’re here today to hear from these manufacturers and to get updates on the progress we’re making together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The shortage of baby formula is due to the closure, back in February, of one of Abbott’s infant formula plants, and we need to take immediate action to stop conta- &#8212; we needed to take immediate &#8212; immediate action to stop contamina- &#8212; contaminated formula from hitting store shelves and putting American children at risk.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last thing we should ever do is allow unsafe formula to be sold to parents.&nbsp; Instead, we should increase the production of safe formula to make every American family &#8212; so they can get what they need for their child.</p>



<p>That’s the approach we’ve taken.&nbsp; The Food and Drug Administration acted quickly to bring Abbott back into compliance with safety standards, but it takes time.&nbsp; Abbott accounts for about 40 percent of the overall infant formula market in the United States.&nbsp; And this factory was one of their leading plants.</p>



<p>So, since February, my administration has been working diligently across to &#8212; every spectrum we could find to address this shortage and to bring more infant formula into the country and onto shelves.</p>



<p>We’ve taken three key actions.&nbsp; First, we invoked what is known as the Defense Production Act, a measure that makes sure that manufacturers are the first in line for the material and ingredients they need to make safe, high-quality infant formula at home.</p>



<p>To date, Secretary Becerra has approved three authori- &#8212; authorizations of the Defense Production Act &#8212; three &#8212; so that companies like Reckitt’s, joining us here today virtually, can now get oils and filters they need to increase production of their &#8212; in their factories in Indiana and in Michigan.</p>



<p>Second, we launched Operation Fly Formula, the major effort to airlift infant formula that meets American’s health standards and safety standards.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I am proud to say that because of these flights, high-quality formula is already on the way to American shelves.&nbsp; We’ve already conducted two flights with 1.5 million 8-ounce bottles of Nestlé and Gerber’s hydro- &#8212; excuse me, hypoallergenic formulas for children with severe allergies.</p>



<p>Without Operation Fly Formula, we wouldn’t have take &#8212; it would’ve take &#8212; we&#8217;ve &#8212; taken three weeks to get this product to the United States.&nbsp; Because of our actions, it took three days.&nbsp; And it’s heeded the request that people had, and it’s headed to American shelves.</p>



<p>And I want to thank the Department of Agriculture for helping fund and support Operation Fly Formula.&nbsp; And today, I’m announcing plans for a third flight with Bubs Australia.&nbsp; And &#8212; and the CEO of Bubs, Kristy Carr, is with us today &#8212; virtually today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This flight would bring 4.6 million bottles of infant formula and pave the way for up to 27.5 million total bottles of Bubs infant formula to be supplied to American families in the weeks ahead.</p>



<p>Third, the Food and Drug Administration is reviewing applications for another new, high-quality imports to increase our supply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition to getting Bubs formula through the process, on Friday, the FDA announced that &#8212; that Kendal Nutricare would be able to import formula from the UK.</p>



<p>Today, we’re announcing that United Airlines has agreed to offer cargo space for Kendal Nutricare for the delivery of 3.7 [million] bottles of the formula here in the states.&nbsp; And I want to thank United Airlines for partnering with us to get this done &#8212; they&#8217;re doing it on their own &#8212; with the first flight next week, continuing over the next two to three weeks.</p>



<p>And Target, the department store, has agreed to partner with Kendal Nutricare to distribute this formula quickly to American families in stores and online.</p>



<p>And still, we have work to do though, but we’re making critical progress.&nbsp; And today, I look forward to hearing from these leading manufacturers to learn more about their actions they’re taking to increase supply to American families and to discuss how my administration can continue to support their efforts &#8212; speeding up manufacturing, helping move goods faster from factory floors to store shelves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition to the companies I mentioned, I also &#8212; we’ll also hear from ByHeart operation, out of Pennsylvania.&nbsp; We need more new entrants into the infant formula market like them &#8212; like ByHeart.</p>



<p>And finally, we’re going to hear from the Surgeon General on what he’s doing to help families get information they can trust as we continue making progress to resolve this shortage.</p>



<p>The work ahead is not going to be easy, but we will continue to work around the clock with manufacturers, states, doctors, and families.&nbsp; And that includes working with states to ensure that, with the help of the Department of Agriculture, we continue to cut red tape for families that participate in the Women and Infants and Children program &#8212; the so-called WIP [sic] &#8212; WIC program.</p>



<p>I recently signed legislation to help make it easier for families to get the formula they need through the WIC program.&nbsp; I called on all 50 states to take action, and all 50 states answered the call &#8212; working with us to make that program more flexible.&nbsp; And we’re going to stay focused on go- &#8212; on doing even more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to make sure that families in every part of the country can get the formula they need.&nbsp; And I look forward to our conversations today.&nbsp; So I want to thank you all.&nbsp; <a></a><a></a></p>



<p>And now you &#8212; I’m going to hand it over to Secretary &#8212; Mr. Secretary, I’m going to have you speak now and &#8212; your remarks, and then we’re going to hand it over to &#8212; to Sameera to my &#8212; behind me here.<br><br>But all yours, Mr. Secretary.<br><br>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; Mr. President, let me start by thanking you for convening today&#8217;s roundtable.&nbsp; At your direction, we are working 24/7 to get infant formula into the hands of parents across the country.<br><br>As my team at HHS recently told Alexa, a mom from Leesburg, Virginia, whose sons &#8212; a one-and-a-half-year-old and a six-month-old &#8212; require specialty infant formula: Getting more formula, particularly specialty formula, on shelves quickly and safely is a priority for us.<br><br>Mr. President, thanks for your leadership.&nbsp; And thanks to that leadership, we have partnered with federal colleagues across the administration to support Operation Fly Formula to bring formula in from other countries and bring it in swiftly and safely.<br><br>In addition, the FDA is working with Abbott to get its facility to reopen safely.&nbsp; And we are working to quickly and safely bolster the supply of products so that the industry can get them to people in urgent need, with a focus on specialty formula.<br><br>Under a consent decree with the FDA, Abbott agreed to take corrective actions following an FDA inspection of its Sturgis, Michigan, facility &#8212; actions that are expected to ultimately result in an increase in the safety of infant formula.<br><br>As I have invoked the Defense Production Act three times already, that was done to accelerate delivery of raw materials needed to manufacture infant formula for Americans &#8212; America&#8217;s families.<br><br>And one more important point: At HHS, we have launched a new online hub &#8212; HHS.gov/formula &#8212; to help parents and caregivers navigate their baby formula options.<br><br>At HHS.gov/formula, parents and caregivers can connect to community resources, such as community centers or an accredited food bank.&nbsp; They can connect to preliminary recommendations from physicians and clinicians, and they can check if the brand of formula they rely on was affected by Abbott&#8217;s recall.&nbsp; We invite feedback from the public and plan to update this page further in the coming days.&nbsp; And all of this information can be found in multiple languages.<br><br>We&#8217;re engaging governors across the country so that they too have the latest information on how to help families in their states navigate their needs.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working closely with the U.S. Department of Agriculture to support the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children &#8212; the WIC program &#8212; to ensure WIC families can access new supplies of baby formula as they become available.<br><br>We will keep working 24/7 to make sure parents have the infant formula they need.&nbsp; But remember: HHS, FDA, USDA &#8212; we&#8217;re not manufacturers.&nbsp; We need infant formula manufacturers and the industry as a whole to keep stepping up and working with us.<br><br>As you&#8217;ve made clear, Mr. President, only together can we solve this challenge and get families the infant formula they need.<br><br>And with that, let me now turn to Deputy Director Sameera Fazili for her comments.</p>



<p>DEPUTY DIRECTOR FAZILI:&nbsp; Thank you, Secretary Becerra.&nbsp; Thank you everyone for joining us today.&nbsp; We &#8212; what we’ll do now is turn to the manufacturers and get some updates.&nbsp; We last spoke to you in mid-May, heard about the work you were doing building upon a lot of the work that the administration had been doing diligently since February.<br><br>But I want to begin with Robert Cleveland.&nbsp; And since we last spoke to you, we&#8217;ve now invoked the Defense Production Act and want to hear how the Defense Production Act is enabling Reckitt to speed up its production of infant formula.</p>



<p>MR. CLEVELAND:&nbsp; Sure, I&#8217;d be happy to address that.&nbsp; And thank you for convening this roundtable.<br><br>So, you know, as the next largest manufacturer of scale after Abbott United States, getting as many feedings to shelf as possible has been an enormous priority for us.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve left no stone unturned in the way we can do that safely and in a high-quality manner.<br><br>And since the &#8212; since the recall event occurred, there are a number of actions we&#8217;ve taken.&nbsp; First and foremost, our plants are running 24/7 with unlimited overtime.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve optimized our portfolio to focus on those products that move through our plants the fastest.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve worked with our retail and our distribution partners to ensure that our trucks are getting to distribution centers and prioritized with our retail partners &#8212; like Walmart and Target, Kroger &#8212; such that our trucks are unloaded first and feedings get to shelf faster.&nbsp; Because it&#8217;s not just about more, it&#8217;s about how much more we can put at shelf.<br><br>And since the recall began, or since the beginning of the year, we have been able to increase the amount we&#8217;ve put to market by over 30 percent and to do it 40 percent faster.<br><br>To (inaudible) that a little bit more: That&#8217;s about 211,000 more infants that we’re feeding after the recall than before the recall.<br><br>But to address your question directly on the impact of the Defense Production Act: When we spoke to the White House middle of last month, there were a number of very rapid actions that the government took, and we&#8217;re very appreciative of them.&nbsp; Part of it is the Defense Production Act.&nbsp; We have been a ben- &#8212; the beneficiary of one implementation of that, that got us some essential oil to our manufacturing process.&nbsp; But there have also been calls from staffers from the NEC and HHS to other manufacturers who supply to us.&nbsp; And those calls alone have been helpful.</p>



<p>And because of those calls, because of all that&#8217;s been done, we now have a production schedule in June where we&#8217;re looking to produce 40 million feedings per week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s because we have a special response for a special and temporary responsibility to produce more than half of the infant formula in the U.S.&nbsp; And our employees are dedicated to meeting that responsibility and, in fact, over Memorial Day weekend, worked to produce another 5 million feedings at our plants in Michigan and Indiana.&nbsp; And they couldn&#8217;t have done that without all the efforts to get us more inputs through the DPA and the efforts of the staffers at HHS and NEC, and we&#8217;re deeply appreciative.</p>



<p>But the other thing I wanted to lead to is that we can do even more.&nbsp; So, we have a unique opportunity with our brand Enfamil, which has fed generations of infants in the U.S. and is the most trusted by pediatricians and mothers.&nbsp; And with that unique position, we&#8217;ve submitted applications to the FDA to bring formula in from our world-class facilities in Singapore and Mexico.&nbsp; And if those applications are approved, we believe we can bring enough formula in to add an additional 250,000 infants to the ones we were already feeding post the recall and come a long way to substantially ending this crisis. &nbsp;And if those approvals happen fast enough, we can make an impact as soon as this month.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re really, really looking forward to working with the HHS and the FDA in processing those applications as quickly as we can.</p>



<p>But, you know, in closing on my opening remarks, I just wanted to recognize the efforts of the USDA and the local governments that implement the program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been working to fill the gap created by the shutdown of the Sturgis facility ever since it happened and the flexibility of the administration of that program has allowed manufacturers like ourselves and our retail partners to be able to put products out the shelves that WIC participants can more easily access.&nbsp; And since they are the most vulnerable in our society, I just want everybody to know those efforts have been fruitful, meaningful, and I know we&#8217;re feeding more WIC participants because of them.</p>



<p>So, thank you for the efforts for the government &#8212; from the government, the USDA to improve flexibility in that regard.</p>



<p>And if there are other questions later, I&#8217;m happy to answer them.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; I’d like to ask question, if I may.&nbsp; What &#8212; tell us about what changes you&#8217;ve made to move the formula faster from your factory to the floor shelves.&nbsp; I mean, what &#8212; you talked about the trucks and other priorities.&nbsp; Are there other things you&#8217;ve done as well?</p>



<p>MR. CLEVELAND:&nbsp; Yes, sir.&nbsp; So, typically, the process would &#8212; the way our process would work is we would make our product, it would go through its normal quality release checks, be released into a system that then eventually becomes visible to retailers to order from.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we&#8217;ve done now is to make sure that every retail partner we have is aware of &#8212; the moment that product is released from quality, their order is waiting for it, the truck is booked to ship it to their facility, and once it gets to their facility, it&#8217;s prioritized among all the other deliveries that they receive to get to shelf as fast as possible.</p>



<p>And again, those changes, in totality, we believe we&#8217;re now delivering product to market 40 percent faster than we were prior to the recall.</p>



<p>And again, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s partnership up and down the line, sir.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; One last question.&nbsp; Did you &#8212; and I&#8217;m going to ask this to your other colleagues &#8212; did you anticipate that the closure of the Abbott facility because it was produced &#8212; not producing the quality that was necessary, that it would have this profound an effect immediately?&nbsp; Or did it &#8212; or did it take a little time to &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. CLEVELAND:&nbsp; I think &#8212; no, sir.&nbsp; We were aware of the general impact that this would have.&nbsp; And so, from the moment that that recall was announced, we reached out immediately to retail partners like Target, Walmart to tell them this is what we think will happen and this is the inventory we have on hand right now.&nbsp; You should order it.&nbsp; And any inventory in your distribution centers should be pushed to shelves as fast as possible.</p>



<p>And they’ve been great partners in taking all of those actions.&nbsp; And then, of course, as the recall has gone on, more specific impacts have been felt and we’ve learned and adjusted to those as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But &#8212; no, we knew from the very beginning this would be a very serious event.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I met early on with those CEOs and they were &#8212; they were trying to figure out how they could move quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you’ve been very helpful, so thank you.</p>



<p>DEPUTY DIRECTOR FAZILI:&nbsp; Thank you, Robert.</p>



<p>MR. CLEVELAND:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>DEPUTY DIRECTOR FAZILI:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for that.&nbsp; Forty percent faster is incredible and just a testament to the work that you and your team have been doing with all of your partners.</p>



<p>Tarun, I’m going to turn to you next.&nbsp; You know, while most of us here in the U.S. know of your company as Gerber, we know that Gerber and Nestlé are essentially the same &#8212; the same brand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I wanted to get an update from you on the work that Gerber has done since Operation Formula helped them bring so much Nestlé specialty formula to the U.S. market.&nbsp; Can you give us an update on your ability to distribute that product to the families that need it?</p>



<p>MR. MALKANI:&nbsp; Thank you, Sameera.&nbsp; Thank you for the opportunity speak with yourself, the President, and members of the administration.</p>



<p>I’m going to first start by saying we take this responsibility very seriously to be part of the solution there.&nbsp; And in fact, without overstating it, at Gerber we feel this is our national duty.&nbsp; And we have crisis teams that are operating today, three and a half months after the recall, with the same level of urgency as we did when I got that first phone call informing me of the crisis situation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is demonstrated by our factories that continue to run 24/7.&nbsp; We have, in fact, from our domestic demand, increased 60 percent additional supply to the marketplace since the recall.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as you mentioned, Sameera alluded to, the broader Nestlé &#8212; we&#8217;re leveraging the full power of entire Nestlé network to be able to come to our aid in &#8212; at this time of crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the things we will not compromise on, obviously, is quality and safety.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a core, core principle at Nestlé.&nbsp; So everything we do, even in these very dynamic and fluid times, we make sure that every product that goes out meets our highest standards.&nbsp; And the President alluded to that as well, when referring to Operation Fly Formula.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That has been a very powerful statement.&nbsp; The same urgency was shared by the administration.&nbsp; And since we received &#8212; to your specific question, Sameera &#8212; since we&#8217;ve received 60 tons of that product on one shipment and another shipment with the with Nestlé Health Science product, we have been rapidly moving those products through our distribution centers into the marketplace.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, the product &#8212; and it was a privilege and a very proud moment for me to be with our First Lady, Dr. Jill Biden, and our Surgeon General, Dr. Murthy, to get that.&nbsp; Since that time, those &#8212; 40 percent of those cans that were received have already been &#8212; made their way to the store shelves, to hospitals, and other high-need areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, from our perspective, Fly Formula has been very helpful for us.&nbsp; Again, the President alluded &#8212; we shaved off weeks from normal transit time.&nbsp; We&#8217;re getting product off the shelf as quickly as we can turn it around.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then finally, if I may add, is the same point that Robert alluded to earlier and the President alluded to as well: Working with the FDA under the enforcement discretion, we have submitted multiple proposals of, again, high-quality formula that has the potential of bringing in nine and a half million individual eight-ounce servings over the course of the next month and a half.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re of course following all process.&nbsp; We have to follow the details here &#8212; make sure the recipes are compatible with our current recipes.&nbsp; We can track the product, as well as make sure that the label is in English for easy translation and obviously easy comprehension and have no translation issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So again, we&#8217;re a small player at Gerber, but we believe now is the time to go above and beyond.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Can I ask a question?&nbsp; How &#8212; how are you supporting families that participate in the &#8212; in the WIC program, the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program &#8212; you know, Women, Infants, and Children?</p>



<p>When I spoke with the &#8212; with the retailers, we talked about making sure that they could be able to purchase &#8212; you can limit what you purchase under WIC and &#8212; based on the size of the container and the like.&nbsp; And we worked out a deal where they could &#8212; whatever container was available would be the ones that we used, and they would not be limited to being able to be stuck with &#8212; if you only had an X ounces or what- &#8212;</p>



<p>What have you been doing to accommodate that or talk about that with your &#8212; with your customers?</p>



<p>MR. MALKANI:&nbsp; Mr. President, that hits to the heart of the matter.&nbsp; In terms of WIC families, Gerber currently has seven contracts.&nbsp; However, working very closely &#8212; and big thanks to the USDA’s flexibility, specifically referring to what you alluded to in terms of substitution opportunities, can size flexibility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We now have, in addition to our seven WIC contracts &#8212; which we must protect to ensure product is available where we have contracts.&nbsp; But today, you will find Gerber product available in all 35 Abbott WIC contract states.</p>



<p>That comes through a lot of work on the ground with &#8212; again, I represent a large number of teams, a number of colleagues across the U.S. and across even Europe and across the world supporting us in this matter, working with the WIC offices on a local level, making sure our products are available for them in their formularies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The WIC parent may shop at a WIC office; they may shop at a retail.&nbsp; They have multiple different distribution options.&nbsp; And we make sure our product is available through all of those means.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve been able &#8212; again, taking advantage in full partnership with the USDA, to get our product available &#8212; both the product that is normal-term usage, but also the specialized products that we have, because there are WIC families that have needs for those products as well.&nbsp; In fact, that is a core, core part of how we want to move forward &#8212; is make sure products available for the WIC families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then if I can build on that a bit, we&#8217;re also making sure our specialized products, which have a unique need in the marketplace, is available through children&#8217;s hospitals and other home healthcare partners where it&#8217;s not the traditional (inaudible).&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it really is a number of different initiatives across multiple touchpoints where the WIC family has to be supported to make sure that they get the product, and we believe we&#8217;re working very closely with the administration and having good success on that, sir.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s really important.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m sorry for interrupting you.</p>



<p>DEPUTY DIRECTOR FAZILI:&nbsp; No, and USDA has done incredible work to approve a lot of those waivers in 24- to 48-hour timelines since February.&nbsp; And as the President laid out, all 50 states finally took action after &#8212; after he called them to task a few weeks ago on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, the 35 Abbott states that you mentioned, some of that was also due to USDA’s effort to work with Abbott to make sure that companies like yours were able to get your product into those store shelves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So thank you, Tarun, for that update.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MALKANI:&nbsp; Thank you, Sameera.</p>



<p>DEPUTY DIRECTOR FAZILI:&nbsp; Murray, I&#8217;m going to turn to you next.&nbsp; A lot of families might not be familiar with the name “Perrigo,” but I know that you provide a lot of the manufacturing for the private-label brands that they may be buying at a Target or a Walmart.&nbsp; So can you speak to us about what you&#8217;ve done to scale up production since February and the result of all that effort that you and your company have taken?</p>



<p><br>MR. KESSLER:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; First off, thank you for the opportunity to be here, Sameera.&nbsp; And thank you, Mr. President, for your leadership in this crisis.&nbsp; We all appreciate it.</p>



<p>We are indeed a private-label manufacturer.&nbsp; And for those who aren&#8217;t familiar with that, we don&#8217;t actually market a national brand ourselves.&nbsp; We enable competition and we pack for 18 national store brands.&nbsp; Those are the retailers’ brands and several national smaller brand and marketers.<br><br>So, in essence, we are creating competition, and those store brands sell for about half the price of the national brand.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re proud that we provide an affordable, accessible, while still maintaining superior quality.&nbsp; Consistent with our vision to make lives better, we play a vital role in providing access to affordable infant formula.&nbsp; And we &#8212; as I said, we also foster competition.<br><br>Now, when I joined the company about three years ago, we saw the need for strengthening the resiliency of our infant formula business.&nbsp; And over the last three years, we&#8217;ve put about $100 million into the facilities so that they would be reliable and they would be resilient.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s benefiting us tremendously right now.<br><br>Like what you heard from everyone else so far, our 500 associates and our manufacturing facilities in Ohio and Vermont are running 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, and have done so all while navigating global supply chain shortages and tight labor market.<br><br>Let me walk you through the specific steps to increase output.&nbsp; The very first thing we did when we heard about the Abbott recall was &#8212; we could foresee that this was going to create a tremendous shortage.&nbsp; We significantly increased all our material orders.&nbsp; We began communication with the FDA immediately.&nbsp; We began collaborating closely with the &#8212; you know, the FDA, our retail customers, and other stakeholders to identify and prioritize what was most critical.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been meeting, by the way, weekly with the FDA ever since.<br><br>The very first thing that we did was take one facility and run a year&#8217;s worth of hypoallergenic formula, because we believed that was most critical.&nbsp; After that, the second thing and what we&#8217;ve done ever since is focused on the highest four formulas &#8212; volume formulas in the category to feed as many babies as possible with a formula that most closely resembled what the babies were already eating.<br><br>Remember, as a private label manufacturer, it&#8217;s our job to &#8212; to &#8212; and we strive to develop products that are designed to be almost exactly the same as the national brands, so it wouldn&#8217;t be a change for infants.&nbsp; And because of that, we felt we had a unique responsibility.&nbsp; And it was in collaboration with our &#8212; our customers and the retailer that we pick the four that we focused on.<br><br>By focusing on four, we were able and still today are running at 115 percent of our maximum capacity.&nbsp; So our theoretical capacity, we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re running millions of pounds more.&nbsp; And in the four months of 2022, our output is up 32 percent.&nbsp; That is, we shipped 32 percent more product than a year ago through the combination of that higher output and the use of the safety stock inventories we had.&nbsp; That&#8217;s gigantic for us.</p>



<p>Mr. President, we appreciate you making your staff, the FDA, and, most recently, HHS representatives available to us right from the beginning &#8212; like I said, it was within a matter of days &#8212; to help get through this crisis.&nbsp; And I can assure you that Perrigo is doing everything that can be done in order to help.<br><br>We are well prepared.&nbsp; We are not having supply problems.&nbsp; We are not having supply issues.&nbsp; We are running full out and will continue to do so for as long as needed.&nbsp; And we are continuing to make investments and will continue to invest going forward to support increased reliability and capacity in the &#8212; the industry.<br><br>Our company is proud to be part of the solution to this shortage, as no family should have to worry about being able to feed their baby.<br><br>So, once again, thank you for your leadership on this crisis.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you for doing such an incredible job moving so quickly.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>DEPUTY DIRECTOR FAZILI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, it was helpful to get an update from the, kind of, leading domestic manufacturers.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re &#8212; we’re going to switch gears a little bit and switch countries and talk about &#8212; one of the new actions that we&#8217;ve taken is that the FDA has put in place new flexibilities to allow imports to bring new entrants into the market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, Kristy, I want to turn to you next to tell us about &#8212; about your company, about Bubs, and the formula you make, and how soon we&#8217;re going to be able to get that formula here in the U.S. now that the FDA has approved you for sale and distribution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although I should probably ask you first: What time is it down there?</p>



<p><br>MS. CARR:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s around four o&#8217;clock in the morning.&nbsp; But now that we run a 24/7 operation, and &#8212; I think most of the Bubs team now feel like they&#8217;re on Washington, D.C., time.&nbsp; So &#8212; so that&#8217;s perfectly okay.<br><br>And, Mr. President, I&#8217;d like to start by saying just what an honor it is to be able to be here and talk to you personally.&nbsp; And thank you for inviting myself, on behalf of Bubs Australia, to participate in this important roundtable conversation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Bubs Australia is Australia’s leading, vertically integrated brand of infant formula.&nbsp; I first founded the business 17 years ago when my first daughter was born.&nbsp; And over those 17 years, we have been nourishing children, both here in Australia and in the 10 markets that we export, over 1 million babies without incident.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are very passionate about feeding the next generation of children with clean, safe, and reliable infant nutrition products.</p>



<p>So, we already sell our Aussie Bubs toddler milk formula products in the United States &#8212; in many retailers across the states.&nbsp; And as we&#8217;ve started to see this infant formula shortage unfold &#8212; and I&#8217;ve visited the States a couple of times already this year &#8212; we knew we wanted to help.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m sitting here in our Bubs Australia facility in Victoria, the dairy capital of Australia.&nbsp; It is a FDA-approved facility.&nbsp; And we had already started the journey for having our three lines of infant formula products approved for export into the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We knew that our products already met the FDA nutritional requirements, so we would make contact with your sales, with the administration, and with the FDA.&nbsp; And I am very &#8212; I&#8217;m very pleased to be able to now be in a position where we can help &#8212; help the situation.&nbsp; And I commend you, Mr. President, on being able to bring government and regulatory &#8212; and industry together to help solve this problem as one collective group.</p>



<p>Obviously, logistics in moving this quantity of infant formula in a short period of time is complex.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d like to take this opportunity to thank you for including Bubs Australia in Operation Fly Formula.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as you mentioned, the White House has announced today that we are now in a position to fly our first two air cargo carriers over to the United States.&nbsp; We will be sending two planes full of our infant formula products next week, with the first plane leaving on June 9 to fly into Pennsylvania and the second plane leaving on June 11 to fly into California.</p>



<p>Across those first two planes is about 380,000 pounds of infant formula &#8212; or the equivalent of 4.6 million standard eight-ounce baby bottles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are now working alongside the HHS to wo- &#8212; to determine when the first possible time is to bring in the next two planes, and we plan to do that in the coming weeks.</p>



<p>So, our pl- &#8212; our strategy around distribution is to be able to initially put our products into the distribution centers on both the West and the East Coast.&nbsp; We will be distributing our products to both the major retailers of infant formula, as well as some of our smaller retail partners, to make sure that we prioritize the states that are most in need and, of course, the vulnerable population areas who need infant formula most.</p>



<p>So, again, I’d just really like to take this opportunity to thank you, Mr. President, and your administration.&nbsp; Both the HHS and the USDA have been working with us around the clock since this new initiative took place.&nbsp; And we are delighted we&#8217;re able to help out in some way and bring Bubs infant formula products to American families.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You&#8217;re helping out a great deal.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. CARR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DEPUTY DIRECTOR FAZILI:&nbsp; And, you know, that partnership is going to continue what &#8212; with these Operation Fly Formula flights.&nbsp; We continue to work to make sure there aren&#8217;t regulatory barriers, border barriers to bringing this stuff in quickly.&nbsp; So, we will continue to be working with you, Kristy, and others.</p>



<p>Well, let me turn it next to &#8212; to Ron, because it&#8217;s not like new entrants are only sitting overseas.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of entrepreneurs and innovators here in the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I want to hear from you about how your company was recently able to receive FDA approval and the steps that you&#8217;re now able to take to ramp up production as one of our, kind of, first new companies in this space in a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although I should also say, like, you might also not know what time it is, I hear, because I hear you may have a new entrant in your family as well.&nbsp; So, thank you for joining us despite being a new father, I think, as of last week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. BELLDEGRUN:&nbsp; Yes, correct.&nbsp; Well, look, first of all, thank you for having me at this important discussion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we launched in an unprecedented time, when parents are more anxious than they&#8217;ve ever been.&nbsp; You know, no parent should have to experience a shortage of sole-source nutrition for their baby.&nbsp; And I say that not just a CEO by heart, but, as you point out, as a parent myself.&nbsp; My wife and I just had our second little one this past weekend.</p>



<p>My co-founder and sister, Mia Funt, and I started ByHeart six years ago to translate major advancements in nutrition science and breast milk research into infant formulas that are the most wholesome and functional alternative to breast milk.&nbsp; You know, all parents deserve to feel proud in how they feed their babies.&nbsp;<br><br>With ByHeart’s launch earlier this year, we became the first new infant formula manufacturer to be registered with FDA in this country in over 15 years.&nbsp; We started this work, you know, well before a shortage, with a motivation really to innovate.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re grateful to the Biden administration and this FDA’s kind of recognition for the need for new manufacturers.<br><br>You know, with our launch, this became the first administration and FDA to register a new infant formula manufacturer in over four administrations.<br><br>Having been immersed in this category 15 years, we knew full well the barriers to entry we were up against.&nbsp; You know, infant formula is appropriately the most highly regulated food in the world, and the consolidated supply chain makes it nearly impossible for new entrants.<br><br>There were just four companies that manufacture infant formulas.&nbsp; Three of those dominate 90 percent of the category.&nbsp; And so every new entrant in decades has taken the same path: to outsource to the one and only contract manufacturer in the country and rely on an expedited generics-like path to market, which only allows for incremental change based on existing recipes.<br><br>Now, had we taken that path, we would have been on the market four years ago, but we didn&#8217;t get into this for incremental change.&nbsp; We knew there was only one way to truly innovate for babies, and that was to build from scratch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we acquired and built manufacturing in Reading, Pennsylvania.&nbsp; We directly sourced all our ingredients to ensure we have complete oversight and highest quality.&nbsp; And we brought together the world&#8217;s experts to completely rewrite the recipe and conduct the largest clinical trial from a new brand in 25 years to clinically prove our benefits.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why it took us five years and not one.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, now, we are just one of five companies in this country that manufacture infant formula, and we take that responsibility very seriously.<br><br>Just two months into our launch, which saw unprecedented demand, pacing at 15 times our most aggressive projections, we are investing heavily into initiatives here at home in the U.S. that can enable an additional over 500,000 new babies to be fed and put us in a position to feed some 15 percent of new births.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re investing heavily into Reading, Pennsylvania, with a new $30 million investment.&nbsp; We&#8217;re hiring relentlessly, adding a whole new shift.&nbsp; We&#8217;re already working 24 hours a day, 5 days a week.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in processed of moving to 24/7.<br><br>Within days of the enforcement discretion policy being announced, we had two submissions into FDA to expand our manufacturing footprint and accelerate fulfillment to get parents formula quicker, all here in the U.S.<br><br>You know, we&#8217;re throwing everything we have at this crisis, but we can&#8217;t do it alone, and we&#8217;re grateful for the support we&#8217;ve received to date from the Commonwealth.<br><br>Mia and I are in this moment ourselves.&nbsp; You know, Mia&#8217;s third baby, Simone, is 10 months and actually drinking ByHeart.&nbsp; And my wife and I just had our second this past weekend.&nbsp; So we know personally and professionally that this country can never be in a situation again where one company has a recall and 40 percent of the country is without infant formula.&nbsp; And the only way we ensure that doesn&#8217;t happen again is to invest in new domestic manufacturing, diversify the supply chain, and create that ecosystem for innovation in infant nutrition here in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>So that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve done.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we plan to continue to do.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good luck with the new babe, ol’ buddy.<br><br>MR. BELLDEGRUN:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>DEPUTY DIRECTOR FAZILI:&nbsp; Thank you for that.&nbsp; I will say, as a &#8212; as a parent myself, hearing the kind of rigorous standards that the FDA has in place to bring new entrants into the market is reassuring and &#8212; and shows how we have this science-based policy here to make sure that the formula that&#8217;s available for families, whether it&#8217;s through new imports or through new domestic entrants, is safe and healthy for families to have.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me &#8212; now that we&#8217;ve had that update from the manufacturers and have a sense of how production is increasing, how new entrants and new supply is now on its way and already making its way to store shelves, I want to turn to have us talk a little bit about parents and what they&#8217;re going through right now.<br><br>Again, as a parent myself, who had a child who was on a specialty formula and pretty recent &#8212; recently weaned, I know that the administration has been taking a lot of steps to work with families to make sure they’re &#8212; they&#8217;re getting the support they need to make their way through this crisis.<br><br>So I&#8217;ll turn it over to Christen.</p>



<p>DEPUTY ASSISTANT LINKE YOUNG:&nbsp; Great, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you so much, Sameera.&nbsp; And thank you to all that &#8212; that you all are doing as manufacturers to bring new supply to market and help us serve Americans parents.<br><br>But as we heard from all of you, this is just an incredibly challenging time for &#8212; for American families.&nbsp; I, too, am a parent, and I&#8217;m expecting my second child at the &#8212; at the end of this month.&nbsp; And we &#8212; we know &#8212; we know how difficult and how scary this time can &#8212; can be for folks.<br><br>Dr. Murthy, you have been talking to parents and doctors across the country about the challenges of this moment.&nbsp; Can you tell us a little bit about what you &#8212; what you think the key messages are that parents need to hear who are worried about finding formula for their families?</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Well, thank you, Christen.&nbsp; And, yes, talking to communities, our public, you know, information efforts have been a key part of this overall effort.&nbsp; I just want to say, also, thank you to everyone who has joined the manufacturers from around the world, really.&nbsp; This has been a team effort.&nbsp; And, you know, President Biden, thank you for making this a priority and for instructing everyone in this administration that no stone should be left unturned in solving this problem.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Our military servicemembers have moved mountains to make sure we can get formula to shelves here, and our departments like HHS, DOD, USDA have also just pulled out the stops to increase production.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of this has made the progress possible that we&#8217;ve seen today, but we&#8217;re not going to stop now.&nbsp; Because a key group that&#8217;s been involved in the &#8212; in these efforts has been community groups, doctors and nurses, medical and nursing organizations, community institutions which have stood up to help reassure patients and get them accurate information.&nbsp; And I want to thank those groups because we are really pulling together in this crisis.</p>



<p>To all the parents out there who might be worried at this point about the food supply for your child, there are a few key messages I&#8217;d like to share with you today.&nbsp; The first is to know that while we are moving fast and pulling out the stops here, safety is still our priority.</p>



<p>We are bringing in formula from abroad but only formula that meets the FDA’s gold standards for safety.&nbsp; The FDA knows how important those standards are.&nbsp; It takes its responsibility to provide safe formula to families very, very seriously.</p>



<p>The second point I want to share is that for safety reasons, we are recommending that there are certain things that you not do, like water down formula or make formula at home, or use toddler formula for infants.&nbsp; I can absolutely understand why people may consider some of these options, but the FDA does not consider those safe at this moment, which is why we&#8217;re not recommending them.</p>



<p>The third point I&#8217;d like to make is that it is okay to use a different brand of formula if the one that you&#8217;re used to isn&#8217;t on the shelf.&nbsp; And look, as a parent whose child is recently on formula, I know how scary it can feel sometimes to switch brands of formula.&nbsp; The key thing to know is that if you find formula on the shelf, it is formula that has met the FDA’s standards for safety.&nbsp; So that is the good news here.</p>



<p>And the last point I want to make is that if you&#8217;re a parent out there who&#8217;s worried about food for your child, I want you to know that we are right here with you.&nbsp; We are standing alongside you, and we are not going to give up until this challenge has been met &#8212; until every parent has the formula that they need for their children.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to pull every lever that we have.</p>



<p>And I want you to know that we approach this not just as public servants, but as parents as well.&nbsp; This is very personal to many of us who are parents or grandparents.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve heard that already from the folks here today.</p>



<p>This is &#8212; a few years ago, my son was on infant formula.&nbsp; And I can just imagine how I would have felt if that formula had not been available to him.</p>



<p>So, I just want people to know that &#8212; while we have made progress in increasing production, while we&#8217;ve made progress in bringing supply in from abroad and taking steps to reopen the plant that was closed in Sturgis that the company is now working to get back into production &#8212; we are not going to stop until every family has a formula that they need for their children.&nbsp; That&#8217;s our commitment to the public not just as public servants, but as parents ourselves.</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;ll turn it back to Sameera.</p>



<p>DEPUTY DIRECTOR FAZILI:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Mr. President, I&#8217;ll turn it back to you.&nbsp; A few weeks ago when we met with you, you told us: Pull every lever, find new levers, do what you can do to solve this challenge.&nbsp; Because it was weighing on families and it was important that we showed people what the government can do when it kind of is put to the test and brings everyone together.</p>



<p>So, since then, HHS, the USDA &#8212; the U.S. Department of Agriculture &#8212; the FDA have continued to pull together.&nbsp; Working closely with manufacturers, as you&#8217;ve heard, we&#8217;ve brought some new ones to the table.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve worked closely with states.&nbsp; We got all 50 to take action.&nbsp; And we continue to work closely with the retailers to kind of answer your charge.</p>



<p>But I would turn it back to you now that we&#8217;ve given you this update on where we&#8217;ve &#8212; where we&#8217;ve gone and where we&#8217;re headed.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll be very brief.&nbsp; Look, I used to have a friend &#8212; and Vivek has heard me say this before &#8212; used to say, “You got to know how to know.”&nbsp; “You got to know how to know,” meaning that we need, what I&#8217;ve found, as parents come up to me in the street and I talked to my family about it &#8212; and I don&#8217;t have any infants in my family; I have a two-year-old grandson, but that&#8217;s &#8212; he&#8217;s beyond that and &#8212; but there&#8217;s a lot of kids in my family.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And people will come up to me at church or wherever, and they want to know whether or not, even though they&#8217;re not on a particular formula, that &#8212; can they switch a formula?&nbsp; And &#8212; and because they hear about all the safety requirements, Doc. And you talked about it a little bit.&nbsp; You le- &#8212; let people know that there are things, there are options within even the limited supplies that occurred, or you may not have the exact brand you used before, but another brand is in fact able to be used.</p>



<p>And so, I think that&#8217;s an important thing to &#8212; because the anxiety that men and women have &#8212; mothers and fathers, grandmothers and grandfathers with infants &#8212; is pretty profound.&nbsp; No one ever wants to make a mistake.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; so I think part of it is just relieving a little bit of the anxiety.</p>



<p>Once we have &#8212; we have significantly more formula available now, and we&#8217;ll have significantly more in the next month or more.&nbsp; And as we get Abbott back online, there&#8217;s going to be a whole lot more.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to solve the problem.</p>



<p>But, you know, ensuring safety of a newborn child is &#8212; is a mother and father&#8217;s top priority.&nbsp; I mean, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s a basic, basic thing.&nbsp; It has been my top priority as a father and grandfather, and it remains at the top of my priorities today as President of the United States.</p>



<p>You know, as we close, I want to thank all of you &#8212; I really mean it &#8212; I want to thank all of you for the updates on the progress you’ve made because, you know, we&#8217;ve had other crises that I&#8217;ve dealt with as President and as Vice President,&nbsp;but I find that this is almost personal to everybody &#8212; to the manufacturers, to the &#8212; just it’s &#8212; it takes on a personal aspect to it.</p>



<p>And, you know, the hard work your employees have made an important difference in restoring the supply for infant formula.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s still a lot more to do.&nbsp; So, I ask you to keep focused, stay focused, stay in high gear.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t let up on the infant &#8212; on the infant formula market back &#8212; until it&#8217;s all the way back to normal.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s going to take a couple more months, but we&#8217;re making significant progress.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and I thank the folks from Down Under as well.&nbsp; Kristy, thank you very much and for all the &#8212; all the way in which that we&#8217;re bringing in formula from around the world.&nbsp; That is, again, letting our constituents know, Doc, that it meets the standard.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not bringing anything in that doesn&#8217;t meet the highest standards.</p>



<p>And so, as my grandfather would say, “With the grace of God and the goodwill of the neighbors, and the crick not rising,” we&#8217;re going to make a lot more progress and ease the anxiety &#8212; a significant amount of anxiety on the part of moms and dads&nbsp;with newborns, so &#8212;</p>



<p>And we particularly want to ease that anxiety on the staff.&nbsp; You know, we’re going to &#8212; that&#8217;s going to be coming pretty soon.</p>



<p>So, thank you all very, very much.&nbsp; I truly appreciate it.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve really answered the call.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, will anyone at the FDA be held accountable for how they handled this?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; The &#8212; the question is whether or not there was a &#8212; this could have been moved quicker.&nbsp; You know, the question you always love to ask me is, on every single thing: Why didn’t you act sooner?</p>



<p>Well, I don’t think anyone anticipated the impact of the shutdown of one facility in &#8212; the Abbott facility.&nbsp; And it was accurately shut down because it was &#8212; the formula was questioned, in terms of its purity.</p>



<p>And so, once we learned of the extent of it and how broad it was, we kicked everything into gear.&nbsp; And I think we’re &#8212; I think we’re on the way to be able to completely solve the problem, but &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But didn’t those &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, sir, the executives said that they knew it immediately.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Excuse me, Mr. President, didn’t those CEOs just tell you that they understood it would have a very big impact?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They did, but I didn’t.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But shouldn’t the FDA have been more aware of that when they took months to conduct the inspection to interview people at this plant after the complaints were made and then only shuttered it in February?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, the real problem occurred when it started &#8212; when it got shuttered.&nbsp; So, you’re saying we &#8212; they should have anticipated it would be shuttered.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They got complaints about &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The answer is &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the facility last fall, Mr. President.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, here’s the deal.&nbsp; I became aware of this problem sometime in &#8212; after April &#8212; in early April, about how intense it was.</p>



<p>And so, we did everything in our power from that point on, and that’s all I can tell you right now.&nbsp; And we’re going to continue to do it until we get the job done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, on another topic: gas prices.&nbsp; When are gas prices going to start coming down?&nbsp; Record high today.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible) record high.&nbsp; It could be higher, but we were able to keep it from going higher.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, look, there’s a lot to do.&nbsp; We’re in a situation where, you know, because of a war in &#8212; in Ukraine, gas prices and food prices are extremely high.&nbsp; For example, we have millions of tons of wheat that is not able to get out and get to market, causing everything from a loaf of bread to cost so much money to food shortages all across the world.</p>



<p>And so, we’re trying to work through, you know, a war.&nbsp; We’re trying to work through how we can get that harbor opened and get &#8212; get the, you know, tens of thousands of tons of grain that are there.</p>



<p>The same with gasoline.&nbsp; You have the &#8212; the issue that is occurring now is you have Europe deciding that they’re going to further curtail the purchase of Russian oil, and there’s a whole lot of consideration going on about what can be done to maybe even purchase the oil but at a limited price so that it has to be sold.&nbsp; There’d be an overwhelming need for the Russians to sell it, and it would be sold at a significantly lower price than the market is generating now.</p>



<p>There’s a lot going on right now, but the idea we’re going to be able to, you know, click a switch, bring down the cost of gasoline, is not likely in the near term, not is it with regard to food.</p>



<p>But here’s one thing we can do.&nbsp; Look, and I’ll talk about this a little bit tomorrow, and I’m going to stop.&nbsp; One of the things &#8212; one of the things that happens, when you talk about gas prices &#8212; the cost of a ga- &#8212; a gallon of gasoline or the price of a loaf of bread, there are things that affect families in their everyday budget.&nbsp; You know, their standard of living are affected by that.&nbsp; They have X amount of dollars they make and &#8212; although, thank God, employment is up and wages are up.&nbsp; Notwithstanding that, inflation is running at a high rate.</p>



<p>And they have all these needs and concerns.&nbsp; There’s more than one way to change &#8212; to maintain the standard of living for people, in the sense that the overall, out-of-pocket money needed to be able to make sure that they’re able to get through all their needs for &#8212; on a monthly basis.</p>



<p>You can compensate &#8212; you can compensate, for example, by having drug prices drop significantly or impact on child care or impact &#8212;</p>



<p>The bottom line is the bottom line: how much it costs you to maintain your household and your standard of living.&nbsp; And there’s not &#8212; we can’t take immediate action, that I’m aware of yet, to figure out how we bring down the price of gasoline back to three dollars a gallon.&nbsp; And we can’t do that immediately with regard to food prices either.</p>



<p>But we can compensate by providing for other necessary costs for families by bringing those down.&nbsp; That reduces the inflation for that family.&nbsp; And we can do that &#8212; we can do that, at the same time, by increasing the tax rate that should go up on some corporations that are paying no taxes at all &#8212; have a mini- &#8212; pay a minimum tax &#8212; and the very wealthy.&nbsp; No one under 400 grand would have to pay another single penny in taxes, but it would not be inflationary.&nbsp; It would help pay for &#8212; it’d reduce the deficit even further, and it would provide relief for families.</p>



<p>But I’m going to talk more about that later.&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you confident Congress will take action on gun legislation, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I served in Confre- &#8212; Congress for 36 years.&nbsp; I’m never confident, totally.&nbsp; It depends.&nbsp; And I don’t know.&nbsp; I’ve not been in &#8212; on the negotiations that are going on right now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to get in on the negotiations?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you plan to get involved?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ve been involved.&nbsp; I’m just not confident.</p>



<p>3:43 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Baltic&#160;Allies</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-baltic-allies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 21:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with counterparts from our Baltic Allies to discuss European security in light of Russia’s war in Ukraine.&#160; Mr. Sullivan underscored the ironclad U.S. commitment to NATO’s Article 5. Participants discussed joint efforts to strengthen our collective defense and security, as well as preparations for the June&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with counterparts from our Baltic Allies to discuss European security in light of Russia’s war in Ukraine.&nbsp; Mr. Sullivan underscored the ironclad U.S. commitment to NATO’s Article 5. Participants discussed joint efforts to strengthen our collective defense and security, as well as preparations for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Participants in today’s call included Kęstutis Budrys, Chief Security Advisor to the Lithuanian President; Asta Skaisgirytė, Chief Foreign Affairs Advisor to the Lithuanian President; Māris Cepurītis, National Security Advisor to the Latvian Prime Minister; Jānis Kažociņš, National Security Advisor to the Latvian President; and Indrek Sirp, Director for National Security and Defense for the Estonian Prime Minister.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Meeting of the U.S.-Israel Strategic Consultative&#160;Group</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/joint-statement-on-the-meeting-of-the-u-s-israel-strategic-consultative-group/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 19:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54594</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On May 31, 2022, U.S. National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and Israeli National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata convened a meeting at the White House of the U.S.-Israel Strategic Consultative Group (SCG). They were joined by senior representatives from their respective foreign policy, defense, and intelligence agencies. The officials committed to coordinate on efforts to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On May 31, 2022, U.S. National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and Israeli National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata convened a meeting at the White House of the U.S.-Israel Strategic Consultative Group (SCG). They were joined by senior representatives from their respective foreign policy, defense, and intelligence agencies. The officials committed to coordinate on efforts to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon and toward deterring Iran’s aggressive regional activities. They also discussed economic and diplomatic steps to achieve these goals and reviewed ongoing cooperation between the U.S. and Israeli militaries. The U.S. and Israeli officials committed that, working toward the same goal, they will remain in close coordination on the full range of issues of mutual interest and to remain united against all threats to their national security.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at U.S. Coast Guard Change of Command&#160;Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/01/remarks-by-president-biden-at-u-s-coast-guard-change-of-command-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 18:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:23 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for giving my speech.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And I’m going to sit down.&#160; (Laughter.) You probably wish I would; it’s kind of getting a little warm in here.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160;&#160; Today we witness a tradition long-standing in the United States Coast Guard: the change of command as a new&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:23 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for giving my speech.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I’m going to sit down.&nbsp; (Laughter.) You probably wish I would; it’s kind of getting a little warm in here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Today we witness a tradition long-standing in the United States Coast Guard: the change of command as a new admiral assumes the leadership of our nation’s “oldest, continuous seagoing service.”&nbsp; And it is both a connection to our earliest days as a nation and a new milestone in our history.&nbsp; We use those phrases lightly, but this is a big deal.<br><br>Admiral Linda Fagan, Coast Guard Academy Class of 1985.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Class of ’85, stand up if you’re out there.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; As they say in Southern Delaware, “You all knew it then, didn’t you?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Well, you’ve crewed the Polar Star, a heavy icebreaker.&nbsp; You’ve captained the Port of New York.&nbsp; You’ve served on all seven continents.&nbsp; And you’ve commanded the Coast Guard operations in the Pacific.&nbsp; You’ve served as Vice Commandant of the Coast Guard.<br><br>Throughout her decades of service, she has demonstrated an exceptional skill, integrity, and commitment to our country.&nbsp; She upholds the highest traditions of the United States Coast Guard.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This moment of acceleration of global challenges and hybrid threats that don’t stop at any border, there’s no one more qualified to lead the proud women and men of the Coast Guard, and she will also be the first woman to serve as Commandant of the Coast Guard &#8212; the first woman to lead any branch of the United States Armed Forces.&nbsp; And it’s about time.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The Secretary of Defense, when he sent me the name, I said, “What in the hell took you so long?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; Really, congratulations.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, with her trailblazing career, Admiral Fagan shows that young people &#8212; young people entering service that we mean it when we say there are no doors &#8212; no doors closed to women.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I might add that includes her daughter, Coast Guard Lieutenant Aileen Fagan.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Now that you’re &#8212; I thoroughly embarrassed you, haven’t I?&nbsp; Because you look like my son used to look when they’d say, “Vice President Biden and his son, Major Biden.”&nbsp; And he’d go, “Oh, Dad.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; It’s not meant to embarrass; it’s meant to compliment.<br><br>Every little kid growing up today who dreams of serving their country will know that this is what an Admiral and a Service Chief of the United States Armed Forces looks like.&nbsp; I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; It matters.<br><br>I concluded, when I ran, by the way, that I’d make sure that my government, my administration, and the service looked like America.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to thank you, Admiral Fagan, for taking the helm during this critical moment and for all that you’ve done throughout your career to open the doors of opportunity just a little bit wider to allowing those following behind you a way through.<br><br>I want to acknowledge your family.&nbsp; They’re here to support you and supported you every day, just as they have throughout your career.<br><br>John &#8212; where &#8212; John, where are you?&nbsp; I’m going to embarrass you.&nbsp; John, stand up, will you?&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; John, we don’t know one another, but we have something in common: We both married way above our station.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And Moira and Aileen, and your parents, Jon and Loann. &nbsp;Where &#8212; where’s Mom and Dad?<br><br>I watched Dad watching that young woman in the Honor Guard coming around with that rifle.&nbsp; You did &#8212; you had to &#8212; you moved quickly, Dad.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; All kidding aside, thank you for the values you instilled.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; It matters a great deal to both &#8212; both of you.&nbsp; And I &#8212; you know, from the time that she was a swab, it &#8212; it just is amazing.&nbsp; I want to thank you for sharing Admiral Fagan with us<br><br>And, Admiral Schultz, thank you for leading our Coast Guard as Commandant over the last four years &#8212; a stellar capstone to your nearly four decades of outstanding service to the nation.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I got the advantage of doing &#8212; for, I think, the third time in my career &#8212; the Academy Commencement.&nbsp; And your la- &#8212; second-to-last one.&nbsp; And he also has a young man &#8212; a good-looking boy, man &#8212; who is a &#8212; who was also commissioned at the time.&nbsp; So, I don’t think we’ve seen the last of this.&nbsp;<br><br>To Dawn and to all the children &#8212; Lindsey, Kelsey, Anna- &#8212; is it Annaliese?&nbsp; I hope I’m pronouncing it correctly &#8212; and is that right? &#8212; and Zach &#8212; Zachary and Ensign Shultz.&nbsp; Where’s Ensign Shultz?&nbsp; Is he here?<br><br>ADMIRAL SHULTZ:&nbsp; He’s underway, sir.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He’s underway.&nbsp; (Laughter.) &nbsp;For those of you &#8212; (applause).&nbsp; For those of you who are not in the military, “underway” doesn’t mean they’re late on the way here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; If you say “underway” in my family, they think, “Where the hell are they?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>But, look, it’s not just those who wear the uniform who serve &#8212; and I’ve said this many times &#8212; it’s the whole family.&nbsp;<br><br>As an English poet said, “They also serve who only stand and wait.”&nbsp; “They also serve who only stand and wait.”<br><br>Many times, your son, your &#8212; was on &#8212; your daughter was on patrol somewhere, and you’re wondering &#8212; your wife or your mom.&nbsp; You stand there and you wait.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Or the year my son was in Iraq.&nbsp; And the year before that, when he was &#8212; eight months, he was &#8212; six months, he was in &#8212; in the Balkans.&nbsp; It’s what my moth- &#8212; my wife would stand there at the coffee &#8212; at the sink, drinking that coffee, just saying a prayer every day.&nbsp; It’s what all of you &#8212; we owe you.&nbsp; We owe you big.<br><br>Thank you for all that you’ve done for the country over the years.&nbsp; We’ve asked a lot of you, and you’ve risen to every challenge.</p>



<p>I also want to thank the women and men of the Coast Guard who are standing the watch today and every day, here at home and around the globe, including my Military Aide who is here today &#8212; Lieutenant Commander Jayna McCarron.&nbsp; Where is she?&nbsp; I’m going to embarrass the devil out of her, but she &#8212; (applause).&nbsp; I asked &#8212; she’s hiding somewhere.&nbsp; I met her at the Academy and asked her to come with us.</p>



<p>Our nation is grateful to all of you for your years of service and your continued service.&nbsp; And as we look to the years and the decades ahead, the Coast Guard is only going to play an increasingly prominent role in our homeland and our national security.</p>



<p>The challenges we face continue to evolve, and the choices we make today are literally going to shape the direction of the world throughout the 21st century.&nbsp; What we do the next 10 years are going to lay it down.&nbsp; We’ll be calling on the Coast Guard more and more frequently, as you know, to underwrite the international maritime security; to keep the sea lanes open and secure; to uphold a rules-based international order; to protect the waters, as was mentioned, through which nearly one quarter of United States’ GDP is transported; to manage the impact of changing climate becoming more extreme &#8212; more extreme weather and growing migration flows.</p>



<p>In addition, you see what’s happening in the Arctic.&nbsp; The Arctic is going to change drastically and become much &#8212; a place that is going to also potentially generate potential conflict, in terms of dominating the Arctic as it melts.</p>



<p>The Coast Guard is central element to the administration’s new Indo-Pacific Strategy, building partnerships with nations throughout the region to take on illegally and unreported and unregulated fishing, reported the &#8212; the shared threats that conduct and coordinate human, environmental missions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I met yesterday with the Prime Minister of New Zealand.&nbsp; Part of what we’re initiating now is there’s another country that is literally eating up all of the fishing grounds, literally overfishing everything.&nbsp; We’ve decided we have to be engaged, and we have to be engaged with our Coast Guard and our military, our Navy.</p>



<p>And with the climate change accelerating, we’re seeing more frequent and more intense storms that carry devastating impacts across our nation and throughout the hemisphere.</p>



<p>Admiral Shultz, you oversaw the Coast Guard’s response to the most active hurricane season on record, in 2020.&nbsp; Thirty named storms, twelve of which impacted the Gulf and Atlantic coasts.&nbsp; And the Coast Guard was there for every single one of them.</p>



<p>And with today marking the official first day of the&nbsp;<s>2020</s>&nbsp;[2022] hurricane season, we’re anticipating the seventh straight year of above-average hurricane activity in the Atlantic.</p>



<p>We turned to the Coast Guard to help facilitate our national response to COVID-19 &#8212; from helping with vaccinations to protecting ports and maritime supply chains.&nbsp; And we rely &#8212; we rely on the Coast Guard to interdict illicit drug shipments at sea before they can enter the United States, and respond to the greatly increased migration flows from the Americas.</p>



<p>Folks and Admiral Fagan, we know &#8212; we know there is more work to be done to ensure the Coast Guard and all the branches of our Armed Forces reflect the full strength and diversity, including at the highest levels of our leadership.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>When Admiral Fagan commissioned in 1985, only five years after the first women graduated from the Academy, she was one of just 16 commissioned female Ensigns &#8212; only 8 percent of her graduating class.&nbsp; She was the only woman aboard Polar Star for the first set of orders.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Currently, the Corps of Cadets at the Academy &#8212; more than 1,000 cadets strong &#8212; 40 percent are women. &nbsp;Forty percent are women.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Admiral Fagan is part of a generation of pioneering women in the force, and this ceremony is historic and f- &#8212; and a historic first in that effort, a promotion earned through a career of outstanding leadership and accomplishment.</p>



<p>Now we need to keep working to make sure Admiral Fagan may be the first but not the only person.&nbsp; We need to see more women at the highest levels of command in the Coast Guard and across every service in the Armed Forces.</p>



<p>We need to ensure women have an opportunity to succeed and thrive throughout their professional careers, and that means providing support and resources so women can compete fairly and fully for promotions and make sure women are not penalized in their career for having children.</p>



<p>It also means creating an environment where every member of the Armed Forces feels safe in the ranks, including from sexual assault and harassment, and where their contributions are respected.</p>



<p>So thank you again, Admiral Shultz, for your dedicated service to our nation and your steady leadership through the years at the Coast Guard.&nbsp; He’s been called to &#8212; into &#8212; into new missions and asked to serve in extremely difficult circumstances.</p>



<p>And thank you, Admiral Fagan, for accepting this next mission and this great responsibility to lead the women and men of the Coast Guard &#8212; the finest Coast Guard in the world.</p>



<p>The Coast Guard is Semper Paratus &#8212; “always ready.”&nbsp; Always ready.&nbsp; I know that you’re ready for all that’s ahead of you, and I look forward to watching you execute your job.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, thank you.&nbsp; May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>11:36 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Delivering on Tulsa Commitments to Build Black&#160;Wealth</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/fact-sheet-delivering-on-tulsa-commitments-to-build-black-wealth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 18:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, commemorating the centennial of the Tulsa Race Massacre, President Biden announced two expanded efforts to help Black families and communities build wealth through homeownership and entrepreneurship. The President: Launched a first-of-its-kind interagency initiative to address inequity in home appraisals, charged with identifying and utilizing the levers at the federal government’s disposal to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, commemorating the centennial of the Tulsa Race Massacre, President Biden announced two expanded efforts to help Black families and communities build wealth through homeownership and entrepreneurship.</p>



<p>The President:</p>



<ul><li>Launched a first-of-its-kind interagency initiative to address inequity in home appraisals, charged with identifying and utilizing the levers at the federal government’s disposal to root out discrimination in the appraisal and homebuying process.<br></li><li>Announced a goal of increasing the share of federal contracts going to small disadvantaged businesses (SDBs), including Black- and brown-owned small businesses, by 50 percent by 2025.</li></ul>



<p>Since then, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken swift action:<br><br><strong><u>Rooting out bias in the home appraisal process</u></strong><br><br>Homeownership is the primary contributor to building wealth for Black and brown households, but bias in home valuations limits the ability of Black and brown families to enjoy the financial returns associated with homeownership, thereby contributing to the already sprawling racial wealth gap.<br><br>In March, the Biden-Harris Administration released the&nbsp;PAVE Action Plan,&nbsp;which, once enacted, will represent the most wide-ranging set of reforms ever put forward to advance equity in the home appraisal process.&nbsp;The Action Plan details a set of more than 20 commitments and actions across all stages of the home appraisal process, including making the appraisal industry more accountable; empowering consumers with critical information and assistance if they receive a valuation that is lower than expected; preventing algorithmic bias in home valuation; cultivating an appraiser profession that is well-trained and looks like the communities it serves; and leveraging federal data and expertise to inform policy, practice, and research on appraisal bias. You can read the PAVE Action Plan <a href="https://pave.hud.gov/">here</a>.<br><br><strong><u>Advancing equity in federal procurement</u></strong><br><br>Increasing federal spending with underserved businesses not only helps more Americans realize their entrepreneurial dreams, but also narrows persistent wealth disparities. According to an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/cea/blog/2021/12/01/the-benefits-of-increased-equity-in-federal-contracting/">analysis</a> from the White House Council of Economic Advisers, differences in business ownership account for 20 percent of the wealth gap between average white and Black households.<br><br>Recognizing this historic opportunity, the Biden-Harris Administration adopted a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/02/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-reforms-to-increase-equity-and-level-the-playing-field-for-underserved-small-business-owners/">bold set of reforms</a> to meet the President’s target of increasing the share of federal contracts to SDBs and increase opportunity for all underserved businesses. These actions include:</p>



<ul><li>For the first time, asking agencies to increase their goals so that governmentwide spending in FY22 results in 11 percent of contracting dollars being awarded to small disadvantaged businesses, up from the current statutory goal of 5 percent<br></li><li>Releasing, for the first time, disaggregated data of federal contracting spend by race/ethnicity of business owner, a powerful transparency and management tool<br></li><li>Implementing major changes to the federal government’s use of “category management” to boost contracting opportunities for underserved small businesses<br></li><li>Increasing the number of new entrants to the federal marketplace and reversing declines in the small business supplier base.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by the Vice President at the Global Water Security White House Action Plan&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/01/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-global-water-security-white-house-action-plan-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 17:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian Treaty RoomEisenhower Executive Office Building 12:03 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you all.&#160; Thank you, Sonia.&#160; And this whole &#8212; what a powerful group of American leaders.&#160; I’m honored to be with all of you this morning and in this fight.&#160; So thank you, each one of you, for the work&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Indian Treaty Room<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></p>



<p>12:03 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; Thank you, Sonia.&nbsp; And this whole &#8212; what a powerful group of American leaders.&nbsp; I’m honored to be with all of you this morning and in this fight.&nbsp; So thank you, each one of you, for the work that you are doing.<br><br>I was remembering and talking with my team about how even when I was in the Senate, you know, we would talk about this issue in some of the committee hearings when we were reviewing nominees, and the connection between this issue and national security.&nbsp; And people laughed it off.&nbsp; “Oh, is that a serious issue?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is there really a connection there?”&nbsp; And it&#8217;s only been a few short years, where people are &#8212; because of the &#8212; the extreme nature of it and the rapidity of the &#8212; of the time that has passed, in terms of the escalation of the issue, that people are finally understanding what you all have been working on for years and years and years.&nbsp; So, thank you for that, and to everyone here.<br><br>So, as many of you know, I am a daughter of California.&nbsp; And as a result, many things have probably flowed from that &#8212; pardon the pun &#8212; but one of them has been: I have been, my entire life, acutely aware of the reality of water scarcity.<br><br>I remember I was, I think, 12 &#8212; in middle school, about that age &#8212; 13 &#8212; when we experienced an extreme drought in California.&nbsp; And I remember watching in the Oakland Hills, northern California, the landscape turning from green to brown.&nbsp; And everyone &#8212; from my mother, our teachers, the radio DJs &#8212; KDIA “Lucky 13” &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; saying how important it was to conserve water.&nbsp;<br><br>And we understood that each of us had a personal responsibility, no matter our age, to take the matter seriously and to understand that with the extreme nature of the harm that results from drought, we each have a personal responsibility that may include and require some sacrifice.&nbsp; And I remember how unsettling it was to imagine how our access to a resource so basic and essential as water, how that could become so uncertain and we could not take it for granted.<br><br>It is a reality that more and more people in our nation are, however, experiencing and understanding this issue every day.<br><br>As our planet warms and weather patterns change, extreme drought is becoming increasingly common.<br><br>At this moment, about 90 million Americans are living under drought conditions.&nbsp; And the start of summer is still weeks away.&nbsp;<br><br>Across the West, we have seen the terrible cost of the climate crisis.&nbsp; And I have visited many of the places where we have seen the wildfires, where families have lost their homes and their loved ones, where entire communities have been wiped out.&nbsp;<br><br>I have met with and talked with the firefighters.&nbsp; My brother-in-law is a firefighter in California.&nbsp; And many of them who work 24-hour shifts in some of the most dangerous conditions that you can imagine to keep us safe.<br><br>Farmers and agricultural workers who lost their livelihoods because the rains just simply did not come.&nbsp; And communities who have felt firsthand how the economic impact of water scarcity ripples out, driving up prices and driving a real sense of urgency about what also results in terms of lack of opportunity.<br><br>And that’s not all.&nbsp; Our nation also faces water insecurity challenges beyond those driven by climate change.&nbsp;<br><br>For decades, of course, our country has chronically underinvested in water infrastructure, depriving many communities of reliable access to safe drinking water.<br><br>Take the issue, which many of us worked on together, of lead pipes.&nbsp; Lead is a poison.&nbsp; For adults, drinking water contaminated with lead &#8212; it can lead to an increase in blood pressure and a decrease in kidney function.&nbsp; For children, it can stunt growth, slow down learning, and cause irreparable damage to the brain.<br><br>And yet, today, as many as 10 million households get their water through lead pipes and service lines in America, as do up to 400,000 schools and childcare facilities.&nbsp; As a result, our country today &#8212; in this country, more than half of children under the age of six are at risk of lead exposure.&nbsp; Obviously, this is unconscionable and utterly unacceptable.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Every person in our nation deserves access to clean water, and every community in our nation deserves water security.<br><br>As a United States senator, I introduced legislation to advance smart water policy, to invest in efficiency and recycling technology, and to take on the problem of lead pipes.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Over the past year, I have met with many world leaders to discuss these issues &#8212; from the King of Jordan to the Prime Minister of Vietnam, to the President of Israel.<br><br>Our administration recognizes the urgency of water security, which is why our President, Joe Biden, invested over $63 billion in our nation&#8217;s water infrastructure through the bipartisan infrastructure law to put us on a path to remove every lead pipe in our country within the next 10 years and to fund water efficiency, water reuse, and groundwater storage projects &#8212; hopefully emphasizing underwater storage projects &#8212; in communities across our nation.&nbsp;<br><br>In addition, our administration has made drought resilience a priority.&nbsp; Today, we are releasing the one-year report of the first ever Drought Resilience Interagency Working Group.&nbsp; It will help chart our nation&#8217;s path forward to a more sustainable future.&nbsp;<br><br>Since we took office, our administration has made important progress in protecting water security here at home.&nbsp; We also recognize how important it is to extend that work beyond our nation&#8217;s borders.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, billions of people around the world do not have access to clean, safe water.&nbsp; And in the coming years, climate change, population growth, urbanization, and environmental degradation will only drive that number higher.<br><br>By 2030, almost half of the world&#8217;s population will struggle to meet their water needs.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; Almost half of the world&#8217;s population will struggle to meet their needs &#8212; to have access to water.&nbsp; And it will, of course, have then a profound impact on America&#8217;s interests around the globe.&nbsp;<br><br>Water insecurity makes our world less stable.&nbsp; When water is scarce, it becomes more difficult for communities to produce food, as these experts have talked about, more difficult to protect public health and to drive economic growth.&nbsp; This, in turn, as has been discussed, can lead to mass migration, which can put significant pressure on neighboring communities.&nbsp;<br><br>Water insecurity also makes our world less safe.&nbsp; Disputes between countries or communities over limited water resources can, predictably and by extension, over time provoke armed conflict.<br><br>So let&#8217;s get in front of this.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s take it seriously.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s understand the various ramifications of this issue.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s also deal with the reality that within the variety of issues that are presented, there is the issue of equity &#8212; because finally we know that water insecurity makes our world less equitable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Think about it this way: In many countries, the responsibility for collecting water disproportionately falls on women and girls.&nbsp; Worldwide, women and girls spend 200 million hours a day &#8212; 200 million hours a day &#8212; gathering water.</p>



<p>That is 200 million hours that could have been spent &#8212; we often, around this place, talk about opportunity costs; let’s have that discussion.</p>



<p>It is 200 million hours a day that could be spent by those women and girls in school, at work, or at home with loved ones.&nbsp; And unless we take action to make water more accessible for communities around the world, that number will only grow in the coming years.&nbsp;<br><br>So it comes down to this: Many of our most fundamental national security interests depend on water security.&nbsp; And that is why, today, we are releasing our Action Plan on Global Water Security.</p>



<p>This Action Plan will cement America’s role of leadership on water security issues.&nbsp; And it will do so first by fully committing our nation to the collective fight to provide access to safe water, hygiene, and sanitation services in every community in every country.</p>



<p>Second, by sharing our world-leading water data, which we are collecting on the ground, literally, and through satellite technology &#8212; collecting that data and sharing it, and technical expertise that comes with that, with the international community to help manage and preserve global water resources.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And third, by using our nation&#8217;s considerable diplomatic resources &#8212; the great leader of USAID; we have so many leaders &#8212; to elevate water security as an international priority.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This action plan will help our country prevent conflict and advance cooperation among nations, increase equity and economic growth, and make our world more inclusive and resilient.&nbsp;<br><br>The past two and a half years during the pandemic have demonstrated that our world is more interconnected and interdependent than ever before.&nbsp; Water scarcity is a global problem, and it must be met with a global solution.<br><br>So, today, we make clear: The United States will be a leader in the solution.<br><br>Thank you all for your partnership in this fight.&nbsp; Together, I know we will create a future in which every person and every community has access to our world’s most precious resource.</p>



<p>Thank you all.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 12:15 P.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Fourth Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/president-biden-announces-fourth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 17:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 4.6 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of  Bubs Australia infant formula. Additional deliveries will follow. Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing two flights, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Bubs Australia infant formulas&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 4.6 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of  Bubs Australia infant formula. Additional deliveries will follow</em>.</p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing two flights, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Bubs Australia infant formulas from Melbourne, Australia to Pennsylvania and California on June 9 and June 11 respectively. This delivery will include 380,000 pounds of Bubs Australia infant formula, approximately 4.6 million 8-ounce bottles. Additional deliveries of Bubs Australia Infant formula will be announced in the coming days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last week, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Bubs Australia can export infant formula. Under this increased flexibility, Bubs Australia plans to export to the United States enough powdered formula to produce 27.5 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of several varieties of its infant formulas,&nbsp;including Bubs Organic Infant Formula S1, Bubs Organic Follow On Formula S2, Bubs Supreme Infant Formula, Supreme Follow On Formula, Bubs Goat Milk Infant Formula S1, and Bubs Goat Milk Follow On Formula S2.<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) are authorized to use Department of Defense (DOD)-contracted commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. Earlier today, the President announced a third Operation Fly Formula mission to air ship approximate 3.7 million 8-ounce equivalents of Kendamil infant formula,<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA to reopen Abbott Nutrition’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="1294" height="626" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?w=640" alt="" class="wp-image-54573" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png 1294w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?resize=615,298 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?resize=768,372 768w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?resize=1270,614 1270w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?resize=1180,571 1180w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?resize=1038,502 1038w" sizes="(max-width: 1294px) 100vw, 1294px" /></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/01/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 17:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961&#160; By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the Secretary of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section&nbsp;506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $700 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Additional Security Assistance to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-additional-security-assistance-to-ukraine-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 16:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The people of Ukraine continue to inspire the world with their courage and resolve as they fight bravely to defend their country and their democracy against Russian aggression. The United States will stand with our Ukrainian partners and continue to provide Ukraine with weapons and equipment to defend itself. &#160; Today, I am announcing a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The people of Ukraine continue to inspire the world with their courage and resolve as they fight bravely to defend their country and their democracy against Russian aggression. The United States will stand with our Ukrainian partners and continue to provide Ukraine with weapons and equipment to defend itself. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I am announcing a significant new security assistance package to provide timely and critical aid to the Ukrainian military. Thanks to the additional funding for Ukraine, passed with overwhelmingly bipartisan support in the U.S. Congress, the United States will be able to keep providing Ukraine with more of the weapons that they are using so effectively to repel Russian attacks. This new package will arm them with new capabilities and advanced weaponry, including HIMARS with battlefield munitions, to defend their territory from Russian advances. We will continue to lead the world in providing historic assistance to support Ukraine’s fight for freedom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
