<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:38:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 15,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/15/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-15-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 4:17 P.M. EST MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, I have two items for all of you at the top.&#160; Today we have some exciting updates on our competition agenda.&#160; First, we have progress on our administration’s effort to lower the price of Internet for millions of Americans.&#160; I bet&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>4:17 P.M. EST<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, I have two items for all of you at the top.&nbsp;<br><br>Today we have some exciting updates on our competition agenda.&nbsp; First, we have progress on our administration’s effort to lower the price of Internet for millions of Americans.&nbsp; I bet you there are people who once lived in apartments or still do in this room who will love this, if you haven&#8217;t already seen it.<br><br>Today, the FCC announced important steps to increase competition in the market for high-speed Internet, which President Biden requested in his executive order on competition.<br><br>As some of you may know, the landlord, if you live in an apartment, sometimes requires you to purchase Internet service from one source.&nbsp; And today, the FCC voted on a bipartisan, unanimous basis to crack down on exclusivity agreements between landlords and Internet providers, known as “sweetheart deals,” which lock tenants in apartments and office buildings into just one option for Internet.<br><br>That might be good for the landlord and for the Internet service provider but bad for tenants, bad for American &#8212; the American people, bad for people living in apartment buildings who may have to pay more and accept lower quality service.<br><br>More than a third of Americans live in apartments and condos, and many businesses operate in multi-tenant buildings, like office buildings or malls, so this is a sweeping problem the FCC is starting to fix today.<br><br>And second, a competition update that is relevant for our national security: Today, the Department of Defense released a new report required by the President’s competition executive order, explaining the new actions to promote competition in defense contracting.&nbsp;<br><br>This report details that since the 1990s, the number of aerospace and defense prime contractors has shrunk from 51 to just 5.&nbsp; That consolidation means taxpayers have to pay more for defense services, and it threatens our national security.&nbsp; Strengthened merger oversight is one of the five actions the Defense Department is taking to address the problem.<br><br>We&#8217;ve already seen concrete progress on that front this week.&nbsp; On Sunday, the FTC successfully blocked Lockheed Martin’s $4 billion attempt to acquire Aerojet &#8212; a proposed megamerger of major defense suppliers.&nbsp;<br><br>The FTC had filed a lawsuit explaining that the merger would jack up the price the U.S. government has to pay, while delivering lower quality and less innovation.&nbsp;<br><br>Also wanted to note &#8212; last item from me at the top &#8212; is we’re thrilled the Senate did its job today and confirmed the renowned clinical trialist Dr. Robert Califf once again to the job of FDA Commissioner and once again on a bipartisan basis.<br><br>He brings to this critical post a lifetime of knowledge and the institutional experience that will ensure he hits the ground running and is guided by the science on critical missions facing the FDA &#8212; from continuing to lead the fight against COVID-19, to combatting the opioid crisis, to ensuring the safety of our nation’s food supply.<br><br>Josh, why don’t you kick us off.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two things on Ukraine.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, markets have obviously already been reacting to that situation.&nbsp; Gasoline prices are up 20 cents a gallon over the last 30 days on average.&nbsp;<br><br>Is the President saying that if people are paying more at the pump, that is essentially a direct result of Vladimir Putin&#8217;s actions and he is to blame for the current burst we&#8217;ve seen in higher prices?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President wasn&#8217;t making a market assessment or how the market moves.&nbsp; What he was conveying very &#8212; very clearly to the American public is that if Russia to &#8212; were to invade and we were to put in place crippling sanctions, that would have consequences or an impact here at home.<br><br>So I know that wasn&#8217;t exactly how you were asking the question, but that was what he was conveying in his answer.&nbsp; In terms of the price of gasoline, what we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; as we know, back in December, it went down by about 10 cents, thanks to tapping the Strategic Petroleum Reserve &#8212; something where there&#8217;s still releases that have been ongoing.&nbsp;<br><br>The President also made clear in his remarks that he is open to &#8212; all options are on the table to help bring down the price of gasoline.&nbsp; But he wasn&#8217;t making a market assessment; he was just making clear to the public that if Russia invades and we put in place crippling sanctions, that would have an impact on the public.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then secondly, on Ukraine, the President talked about diplomatic efforts.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could you go into more detail on what those diplomatic efforts could be?&nbsp; Is this going to be more U.S. interaction?&nbsp; Could there be a face-to-face meeting with Putin?&nbsp;<br><br>And then how would you define success under diplomacy?&nbsp; Is it as simple as no invasion or are there broader goals you&#8217;re looking for, given that everything is now on the table &#8212; or more things are on the table?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, on the first part: You may have seen, or not, that our Secretary of State spoke with Foreign Minister Lavrov earlier today.&nbsp; The President spoke with President Macron earlier today as well.&nbsp; I think the readout just went out to all of you, or it should be in your inboxes as well.&nbsp;<br><br>And what he means by “ongoing diplomacy” is that it will continue at the pace and urgency that you have seen from him over the last several weeks and from his team.&nbsp; And it &#8212; some of it will come from the President.&nbsp; Some will come from high-level members of his national security team.&nbsp; And some of it will come from our European partners or NATO Allies, who we remained in very close contact with.<br><br>In terms of engagement with President Putin, you &#8212; as you know, he spoke with him on Saturday.&nbsp; And he believes in the power of leader-to-leader diplomacy, but I don&#8217;t have a prediction of a next engagement at this point in time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what about &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, sorry.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How do you define success?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wanted &#8212; sorry, I didn’t get to that last part of your question.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, the &#8212; how we define success is, I think, how a lot of our European partners and NATO Allies would define it, which would be a de-escalation &#8212; a proven de-escalation at the border of Ukraine, where the Russians are pulling back their troops, where they are making clear to all of &#8212; to the global community, to the media, to the public that they are not invading Ukraine and backing that up with actions.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Following up on this energy question in terms of the impact on our energy, which the President mentioned &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and then the consequences here at home.&nbsp; What should Americans be prepared for?&nbsp; Worst-case scenario, what should they expect if this happens?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what the President was touching on was the fact that if Russia decides to invade, there could be consequences here at home.&nbsp; And that could have an impact on energy prices, which could have an impact on prices at the gas pump.<br><br>And we&#8217;re taking &#8212; while we are taking active steps to alleviate the pressure on our own energy markets &#8212; and every option is on the table to offset rising prices, as you saw the President act last fall &#8212; a range of options remain on the table &#8212; he also wanted to be very clear and direct with the American people about what the impact could be and the fact that, in his view, defending democracy and liberty is never without cost, but we need to convey to the American people exactly what that could look like.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on Russia.&nbsp; If President Putin decides not to invade, does President Biden consider that a victory?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the world &#8212; the global community would consider that a victory.&nbsp; But again, I think what the President’s view is and what the national security team’s view is, is that this is ultimately up to President Putin.<br><br>And every step we&#8217;ve taken up to date over the last weeks and even months &#8212; to coordinate with our NATO Allies; to stay in lock- &#8212; in close touch with leaders in Congress and members about what our plans are; to put together a crippling sanctions package &#8212; what we are doing is we’re presenting the choice to President Putin.&nbsp; He, ultimately, is going to decide which path he chooses.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, I just wanted to close the loop on a few things.&nbsp; So the &#8212; Ukraine has been experiencing a number of cyberattacks today.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A number of its banks were affected.&nbsp; The Defense Ministry was affected. &nbsp;Has the United States attributed those attacks to Russia?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything on the attribution at this point in time.&nbsp; I know there have been a range of reports.&nbsp; What I can say is that we have been in touch with the Ukrainians, our Allies and partners &#8212; working with them to deter and respond to malicious cyberactivity.&nbsp;<br><br>We have also been warning for weeks and months, both publicly and in our engagements with the Ukrainians as well as our European partners, about the potential for Russia to conduct cyber operations in Ukraine, but I don’t have anything more specific on attribution at this point.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just, you know, kind of moving a little bit into the realm of the hypothetical.&nbsp; There are a lot of steps that &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, boy.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; There are a lot of steps that Russia could take that are short of an invasion but that are still, you know, aggressive &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you know, including cyber, including &#8212; there&#8217;s this step that their congress has taken on recognizing its breakaway regions in Ukraine as being, you know, separatist legitimately &#8212; and the separatist regions.&nbsp; Would the U.S. respond to any &#8212; any things like that with sanctions as you would to, you know, an actual invasion?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have conveyed before and I’ll reiterate now that we would be prepared to respond <s>with</s> [to] a range of malicious activities or actions that the Russians were to take.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then one more thing.&nbsp; I know that you &#8212; there&#8217;s &#8212; you know, you’ve said that there is very little daylight with you and European allies on this issue.&nbsp; The German Chancellor said today that Ukraine joining NATO is simply not on the table; it’s not on &#8212; an agenda item right now.&nbsp; Is that how you would characterize it from the White House?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as you’ve heard the President conveying and you just heard him convey in his remarks, our view from the United States is that nations have the right to sovereignty, to territorial integrity, freedom to set their own course and choose who they associate with.&nbsp;<br><br>So we, the United States &#8212; we&#8217;re never going to pressure or any country to join or not join a global alliance.&nbsp; That is up to them and up to the other members of NATO.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just &#8212; you say all options are on the table.&nbsp; Let’s be more specific: On the possibility of a gas tax, how would they &#8212; would the White House support doing that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have nothing to predict for you at this point, but all options remain on the table.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He said in his speech, “If Russia attacks Americans in Ukraine, we will respond.”&nbsp; Is there specific intelligence suggesting that some kind of targeted attack on Americans in Ukraine is possible?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t think he was suggesting that.&nbsp; I think, as we’ve conveyed, as we&#8217;ve warned and been very clear about the risks that would be posed to anyone who&#8217;s in Ukraine, including American citizens, were Russia to invade &#8212; one of the biggest militaries in the world &#8212; that there would be serious risk to civilians.&nbsp; That&#8217;s, I think, what he was conveying.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with the Ukrainian President slated to be out of his country this weekend to go to the Munich Security Conference, does the U.S. think that&#8217;s a good idea for him to be gone right now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we have an assessment on that from here.&nbsp; Obviously, the Munich Security Conference is an opportunity for any leader to engage with, communicate with other leaders in the world.&nbsp; And, obviously, the Vice President is going, as you know.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He’s got a busy day, obviously, with Ukraine, but has the President talked to any Supreme Court nominee?&nbsp; Have any interviews been scheduled?&nbsp; Will they happen in person or virtually?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m going to disappoint you here, Ed, and just convey that I think we&#8217;re not going to give day-to-day updates from here, moving forward, about whether or not he&#8217;s done interviews.&nbsp;<br><br>What I can confirm for you is we&#8217;re still on track to &#8212; for the President to make a decision and make an announcement before the end of the month, which is in two weeks.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We file that under the &#8220;got to ask.&#8221;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He will do some interviews in the next two weeks.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I can confirm for you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There we go.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jacqui.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been told for a long time that some cyberattacks would likely precede an invasion.&nbsp; So, if it turns out that Russia is behind what happened today &#8212; or is &#8212; I guess, how I should phrase it is: Is there work being done quickly to figure out if Russia is behind what happened today so that sanctions can be imposed before there is bloodshed? &nbsp;Or is the calculus still sort of centering on force on force or some, you know, passing over the border?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, we are constantly doing those assessments.&nbsp; And certainly, as any cyberattack happens, that is certainly a process that happens behind the scenes and that our intelligence community and our national security community undertakes, as it would be in this case as well.<br><br>I would note, though, as it relates to sanctions: One, there&#8217;s a range of means that we could respond, both seen and unseen, to a &#8212; to a cyberattack or any other attack.&nbsp; And the President has the purview to do whatever he chooses in that regard.&nbsp;<br><br>But our view remains that the crippling package of sanctions is an effective deterrent.&nbsp; So if you do that all in advance, what is to stop them from moving forward?<br><br>Now, that may be a different policy issue &#8212; difference of opinion, I should say, on policy issues with some in Congress, and that&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; But that is our view from the administration.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, this may or may not be related at all, but is there any information on what caused the power outage on the North Lawn?&nbsp; Every TV network lost power at the same time<br>during the President’s remarks.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It was a very inconvenient time, I will just note, for all of you &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The timing was suspect, yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; and for us.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any assessment of that, no.&nbsp; Or &#8212; yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, does the White House view Ukraine giving up on NATO aspirations as a possible off ramp?&nbsp; I understand that, you know, the President has said, the administration has said over and over that NATO members would not, you know, encourage &#8212; or would not &#8212; would not give up that ability for someone else to join.&nbsp;<br><br>But, you know, they do have a long way to go, and now that there&#8217;s, you know, all of this concern that if there was a member &#8212; if they did become members, it could potentially trigger Article 5.<br><br>Is there any discussion among NATO Allies about, you know, how significant it would be if Zelenskyy were to make that offer himself?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have not raised that from the United States.&nbsp; And again, I would reiterate what I said a little bit earlier, which is that our position is that we are not going to pressure Ukraine or any country to join or not join an alliance, that it is &#8212; nations have the right to sovereignty and territorial integrity, and that&#8217;s a choice for them to make.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, why is the administration encouraging Americans who are evac- &#8212; or fleeing through Poland to be &#8212; to bring proof of COVID-19 vaccination?&nbsp; As I understand it, Poland does not require that.&nbsp; So is there going to be a shift in messaging for Americans who are trying to get out through Poland?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would check with the State Department on that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to follow up with you &#8212; for you on your behalf as well.<br><br>Go ahead, Kristen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to circle back to the idea of what de-escalation would look like and how the administration would trust that it were actually real.&nbsp; Do you have a sense of how many troops you would need to actually see with your own eyes, through satellite images or otherwise, would need to withdraw in order for this administration to feel as though Putin were, in fact, de-escalating (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, Kristen, that is a decision that we would make in partnership with our NATO Allies &#8212; right? &#8212; and European countries.&nbsp;<br><br>And you look at everything from satellite imagery &#8212; something that many of you have access to &#8212; to validation and verification of what they&#8217;re saying they would do.<br><br>So I can&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to be in a position, nor would I expect the Defense Department would be, to give you a troop number, but I think it would be very clear if that were a step they were taking.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And I think there’s been a lot of mixed messages publicly coming out today.&nbsp; Among them, the NATO Secretary-General that there is cause for “cautious optimism” when it comes to some of these talks that are happening behind the scenes.&nbsp; Does the administration, does the President share that cautious optimism?&nbsp; Because we heard from the President very firm language.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President also conveyed it would be positive if it was verified that they pulled back their troops.<br><br>And certainly, the openness to diplomacy is something that everybody should support and I think our NATO Allies would support as well.<br><br>At the same time, we&#8217;ve seen this playbook before.&nbsp; And especially given the history of President Putin and the Russians, their history of false-flag operations, of misinformation, we need to verify.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So &#8212; and I guess that&#8217;s my question: Does the administration share the NATO Secretary General&#8217;s cautious optimism?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I don&#8217;t think we need to put in more words than what the President just conveyed in a speech to the country.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The GOP senators have unveiled a sanctions bill.&nbsp; Have you assessed whether or not this is something the administration wants to see some movement on, this is something that you would potentially support, given that the bipartisan talks stalled?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not yet, because it just came out.&nbsp; But again, our view remains that a bipartisan effort would be the best effort moving forward.&nbsp; And as I conveyed to Jacqui a few minutes ago, you know, our view continues to be that the crippling sanctions package we&#8217;ve designed is meant to be a deterrent.<br><br>Go ahead, Ken.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the Senate is working on this stopgap funding bill that, you know, the deadline is Friday.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the level of confidence that the President will be able to sign that extension by Friday?<br><br>And, separately, has the administration been talking to the two Republican senators who have raised concerns &#8212; Senator Lee and Blackburn?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are engaged with a range of Democrats and Republicans, and certainly we are hopeful that we will be able to sign this.<br><br>I would note, though, that I believe &#8212; and correct me if I&#8217;m wrong here &#8212; that one of Senator Blackburn&#8217;s primary concerns is about a relation to the &#8212; to the funding of crack pipes.&nbsp; Is this correct?&nbsp; Which is not an issue.<br><br>So, this is a &#8212; this is an issue &#8212; what is happening here is the potential to hold up funding in the government and important programs around an issue that is not an issue, because we&#8217;ve been very clear that we are not providing funding for crack pipes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, the Senate Banking Committee had planned to vote on your Fed nominees today.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There was a holdup there.&nbsp; Republicans have objected to Sarah Bloom Raskin’s nomination.&nbsp; What does the administration think of this delay?&nbsp; And is the administration going to provide any additional details to Senator Toomey &#8212; some of the issues that he’s raised?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say that this is a very extreme step that&#8217;s totally irresponsible, in our view.&nbsp; It&#8217;s never been more important to have confirmed leadership at the Fed to help continue our recovery and fight inflation.&nbsp; And, obviously, they have a unique role to play, an important &#8212; a vital role to play as it relates to inflation.&nbsp; And I think Democrats and Republicans have agreed on that for decades.&nbsp;<br><br>So Republicans are out there saying, “Inflation is a problem.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a huge issue.”&nbsp; We agree.&nbsp; And then they&#8217;re not even bothering to show up to even vote against these nominees to the Federal Reserve.&nbsp; What message is that sending to the American public?<br><br>So we &#8212; and I would note, just on Sarah Bloom Raskin, since you asked me about her as well: You know, she&#8217;s one of the most qualified individuals to ever be nominated to the Federal Reserve.&nbsp; She&#8217;s made the strongest ethics commitments in the history of the Fed, even as she&#8217;s made extensive disclosures to the Banking Committee as a natural part of the process.<br><br>Senator Toomey has continued to promote false allegations that have already been shot down by ethics experts, the Kansas City Fed, the founder of Reserve Trust, and Sarah Bloom Raskin herself.<br><br>So we&#8217;re going to continue to work with Chairman Brown on a path forward and look forward to the Banking Committee eventually holding a vote to commit these &#8212; to confirm these five nominees.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any entertaining of other options if it stalls in committee?&nbsp; You know, there appears to be some question about whether the Senate as a whole can advance these nominations.&nbsp; Is that something you’re exploring?&nbsp; Or is that something that you don’t think you have the power to do?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean in terms of different legislative processes or different &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s some speculation that the full Senate could, sort of, skip the committee vote if it stalls out in bringing them forward.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I don’t &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe the Senate has that power, or does it have to go through a committee?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our focus right now is on working with Chairman Brown on moving these nominees through the committee.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask also on COVID funding?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; HHS briefed Congress this week, requesting what &#8212; $30 billion in funding.&nbsp; Can you just give us a sense of &#8212; A, can you confirm that?&nbsp; B, what, in particular, do you need this funding for?&nbsp; And has the existing funding been allocated?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, HHS&#8217;s briefing today, or this afternoon, was a part of our regular conversations with Congress about various resources it needs, including what is needed for COVID response.&nbsp; This is important because, while we continue to have sufficient funds to respond to the current Omicron surge in the coming weeks, our goal has always been to ensure that we are well prepared to stay ahead of the virus.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve been in these ongoing conversations about what those needs might look like, and this was a part of that effort.<br><br>In terms of funds that have been allocated or spent, more than 90 percent &#8212; so, available Rescue Plan funds, which is where the funding has come from to date, have been obligated or allocated.&nbsp; Ninety percent of that has been for purchases of vaccines and therapeutics, vaccine distribution efforts that have gotten shots in arms, testing, including for schools and at other high-need locations.<br><br>Resources from the Rescue Plan and prior COVID response bills have enabled us to respond forcefully to the Delta and Omicron surges.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re trying to do now is stay ahead and stay in contact with Congress about what those needs might look like.<br><br>Q &nbsp;And Secretary Blinken said yesterday that the U.S. is not on pace right now to meet the President&#8217;s goal &#8212; or the WHO goal of vaccinating 70 percent of the world by later this year. &nbsp;Is any of this funding aimed at jumpstarting global vaccination efforts? &nbsp;And can you talk a little bit about why you&#8217;re not on pace? &nbsp;Is it, for instance, a supply problem? &nbsp;Or is it a problem with what Secretary Blinken called &#8220;last-mile&#8221; type stuff, getting &#8220;shots in arms&#8221; &#8212; to borrow language of the COVID group?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is &#8212; that is an undervalued part of it, I should say.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m &#8212; thank you for raising that part of it.<br><br>So, right now, we&#8217;ve shipped over around 440 million doses and are continuing to aggressively share around 10 million doses a week to the world free of charge.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the first country to buy doses for the sole purpose of sharing them with the world.&nbsp; We also bought, as you know, a billion doses.&nbsp;<br><br>And Secretary Blinken, I think, made those comments in part because he wants to rally the world to do more.&nbsp;<br><br>But a big part of our effort right now and where we have seen challenge is turning vaccines into vaccination, which means working closely with our partners on the ground and dealing with hyperlocal issues countries may be facing to increase vaccination.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is a big part of the focus of Ambassador Power and USAID&#8217;s Global Vaccination initiative, but part of it is that “shots in arms” component.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have countries started deferring their U.S. donations because the capacity is the problem more than the supply?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There have been moments, yes, where countries are not able to receive the doses that we&#8217;re able to provide.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Raise &#8212; creating a gas tax holiday takes legislation.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering, what are other things that the President could do on his own to mitigate a gas price hike because of Ukrainian conflict?&nbsp; What else can he do by himself?&nbsp;<br><br>And in terms of releasing oil from the SPR, have you made a determination of how much cost rise that would offset?&nbsp; In other words, what good does it do?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; And those are assessments that our economic team is constantly, of course, making.&nbsp; We did see even the anticipation of the release, back in December, helped lower the price by about 10 cents.&nbsp; But that &#8212; those assessments are constantly being made.<br><br>In terms of &#8212; without a decision being made, which I know you&#8217;re not asking, but just to be clear: There are steps the President has taken in the past, obviously tapping the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; He has also engaged, we have engaged with oil-producing countries around the world.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something we will continue to do because, clearly, we need to ensure that the supply out in the global market is meeting the demand.&nbsp; And, obviously &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mean, encouraging other countries to produce more?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re saying?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, okay.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been a part of our effort, even as we anticipate what impact there could be from an invasion.&nbsp; So, as you know, there&#8217;s obviously a difference between natural gas shortages and the impact on home heating, which is largely a regional issue, but we have been still &#8212; in Europe &#8212; but we&#8217;ve been still working with partners on that as well, but also on the supply of gas out in the market &#8212; oil, I should say, or gas.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said that &#8220;an invasion remains distinctly possible.&#8221;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some senior administration officials said, a couple days ago, that &#8220;as soon as this week.&#8221;&nbsp; Is that still the timeline, or has anything shifted based on kind of mixed messages of the last couple of days?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a new assessment.&nbsp; As I think you heard the President say, it&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s a distinct possibility, but we don&#8217;t have a new assessment of a decision being made either.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, I know there&#8217;d been internal discussions about giving a speech like the one the President gave &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; today for some time.&nbsp; Why today?&nbsp; And then, the intent behind it: Obviously, it seemed to be looking to hit on multiple audiences to deliver specific messages to them.&nbsp; So why &#8212; why today?&nbsp; And why that range of messages?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, Phil &#8212; Phil, I mean, you all have been covering this very closely &#8212; the potential of an invasion, our diplomatic engagements &#8212; and there&#8217;s no question the American people have been consuming what you have been reporting.&nbsp;<br><br>But I think we felt and the President felt it was important to be very clear and direct with the American people about what the impact could be on them, what the consequences would be, what our values are, and why it is important to stand by not just the territorial integrity and sovereignty of a country, but also stand among our Allies and partners around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>So, it was very important to him to lay out very clearly what &#8212; the steps we&#8217;ve taken, the actions we’re prepared to take, what&#8217;s at stake for the United States and the world, and how this will impact us here at home.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of why today: It wasn&#8217;t based on &#8212; obviously, as you saw &#8212; a desire to put out a new policy or based on something new internally.&nbsp; It was just our &#8212; the President&#8217;s interest and feeling it was time to speak directly to the American people about all of those issues.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just last one.&nbsp; On the first point that you made there: Is there concern, either by the President or inside the White House, that perhaps the understanding or support for, kind of, traditional Western alliances that have been a pillar over the last 80 years is waning or doesn&#8217;t exist to the degree that it used to?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, I think, Phil &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Inside the country, I mean.&nbsp; Inside the country.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, no, it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any data assessment of that.&nbsp; But we also are fully aware of the fact that, right now, the American people are still grappling with a pandemic.&nbsp; They&#8217;re grappling with rising costs.&nbsp; Some &#8212; two iss- &#8212; two big issues the President speaks to quite frequently.&nbsp;<br><br>And it was important to him to be able to lay out clearly for them what this, you know, potential conflict, potential invasion &#8212; in a place that may feel far away &#8212; and how it could impact them &#8212; how that could impact them, and his engagement.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you, Jen.&nbsp; President Biden today said there&#8217;s 150,000 Russian troops encircling Ukraine.&nbsp; That appeared to be a higher number than previously reported.&nbsp; I think 130,000 is how, most recently, we&#8217;ve seen it characterized.&nbsp; So was the President confirming an actual escalation of Russian troops?&nbsp; Or why did he present a new number there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think over the last dozen days or so we&#8217;ve seen a dramatic acceleration and buildup of troops.&nbsp; And so, the President said in his remarks very carefully, it’s encircling Ukraine on the border and also in Belarus.&nbsp; And so, I think he felt it was important to give an assessment of where things stand.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, secondly, regarding a gas tax holiday, you said, quote, &#8220;All options remain on the table.&#8221;&nbsp; There is right now a bill from Senate Democrats that would institute a suspension of the gas tax for the rest of the year.&nbsp; Does the White House support that specific bill?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t made any decision about additional steps at this point in time.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; As you mentioned earlier, Vice President Harris is headed to the Munich Security Conference this week.&nbsp; Does the President plan to also send Secretary Blinken?&nbsp; And if so, would a last-minute addition suggest a different or perhaps reduced or more limited role for Vice President Harris at that conference?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s any plans to limit or reduce the Vice President&#8217;s role at the Munich Security Conference or at the global stage &#8212; on a global stage.&nbsp; She&#8217;s going to give a speech while she&#8217;s there.&nbsp; And she is a vital and important representative for the United States and our values and our intentions at this point in the world.&nbsp;<br><br>But in terms of plans for Secretary Blinken to attend or not, I can check with the State Department and see.&nbsp; There are plenty of leaders to meet with, so more bandwidth.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on &#8212; on a different note: The President continues to talk about his Build Back Better plan.&nbsp; He did so today; did a couple of events last week.&nbsp; What is the White House expectation at this point about the future of that plan?&nbsp; Is there any evidence of any sort of forward movement, forward progress, even on a pared-back version of that?&nbsp; There doesn&#8217;t seem to be a lot of optimism or action right now on Capitol Hill.&nbsp; But can you talk about what the White House expectation is for that and why the President continues to bring this up?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President continues to bring it up because, as we talk about the impact of inflation &#8212; which most people experience in their daily lives as rising costs &#8212; one of the ways that we can address that is by passing legislation that will help lower costs for Americans, whether it&#8217;s childcare or healthcare or the cost of prescription drugs.&nbsp; And we can do that and fully pay for it by making the tax system more fair.&nbsp;<br><br>So, what is encouraging to the President is that there is broad support for lowering costs for the American people in all of those categories and for making the tax system more fair. &nbsp;And we are continuing to work in lockstep and in partnership with a range of senators. &nbsp;And they’re having their own discussions about moving these efforts forward.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much, Jen.&nbsp; One question on Asian Americans, and one question on Ukraine.&nbsp; On Asian Americans: Actually, the Team USA Gold Medal winner, Chloe Kim, revealed, as an Asian American, according to AP, quote, “…she was tormented online daily.&nbsp; She says she was consumed by the fear that her parents could be killed whenever she heard the news about another brutal assault on an Asian person.”&nbsp; Unquote.<br><br>Actually, under President Biden&#8217;s watch, in 2021, the anti-Asian hate crimes increased by 339 percent.&nbsp; It seems we don&#8217;t see much action taken by the White House.&nbsp; And even in a press briefing, the very last time you mentioned about Asian Americans was last May.&nbsp; So, will the President take some action or even just record a video, like what he did last year to raise the awareness?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me say first that Chloe Kim &#8212; I&#8217;m obsessed with the Olympics, so I&#8217;m just going to give you a little biography here, but she&#8217;s 21 years old, and she made those comments, which is incredibly courageous and brave that she spoke out about the fear she had &#8212; the fear she has for her family members.&nbsp; And she&#8217;s not the only Asian American to do that, but she is somebody who is now a double Gold medalist.&nbsp; Amazing.&nbsp; And so I just want to take a moment to applaud her for her courage in doing that.<br><br>I will say that the President has put in place a task force.&nbsp; He has hired a senior-level staffer to be a representative and be someone who can speak to these threats and these concerns and these fears felt by the Asian American community, because there&#8217;s a number of steps we need to take and continue to take to address.<br><br>And we&#8217;ve seen this rise, unfortunately, because of hate-filled rhetoric and language around the origins of the pandemic.&nbsp; And that is something that Asian Americans across the country have been feeling.&nbsp;<br><br>So I can just reiterate for you that the President is absolutely committed to continuing to speak out, to crack down, to take steps, and again, would thank Chloe Kim for her courage.<br><br>Go ahead, Amna.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me &#8212; I just have to keep going because we got a &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a couple quick on Ukraine, Jen.&nbsp; President Biden said that we should give diplomacy every chance to succeed.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken, after his call with Foreign Minister Lavrov, said that a window remains open to resolve this peacefully.&nbsp; I just &#8212; on the timeline, how long does the President think that window should stay open if there&#8217;s no invasion but also no pullback of Russian troops?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what&#8217;s the alternative if we don&#8217;t leave the open &#8212; the window to diplomacy open, right?&nbsp; I mean, you know, our objective, obviously, is that you heard the President say today there is no threat the United States is posing to Russia, to the Russian people.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no threat that Ukraine is posing to Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>What we&#8217;re working to do here is leave a forum for de-escalation for &#8212; and prevent a war.&nbsp; And so, for &#8212; to us, the door to diplomacy should always be open, and we should always look for opportunities to de-escalate.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any concern this turns into, like, a frozen conflict basically, where troops just stay on the border and there’s no invasion but also no pullback?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, there&#8217;s going to have to be a continued dialogue and discussion.&nbsp; But Russia not invading Ukraine and not risking and impacting the lives of many, many people in that country, including potentially American citizens, would certainly be a step we would welcome.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on what Americans should prepare for: You mentioned the threat of cyberattacks.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President mentioned that as well.&nbsp; And we know Homeland Security has previously mentioned they&#8217;ve seen an uptick in scanning on U.S. critical infrastructure and so on.&nbsp; Should Americans be prepared for a potential Russian cyberattack on critical U.S. infrastructure or other networks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say: Even before we&#8217;ve been discussing the buildup of troops at the border, and even before we&#8217;ve been discussing the bellicose rhetoric, we have seen an uptick in cyber activity by malicious actors around the world, either those living in countries or the countries themselves.&nbsp;<br><br>And so that is something &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any new threat or new warning to post today, but that is something we have certainly been amping and increasing our focus on, as an &#8212; as a threat that&#8217;s emerging but has been the case for the last several years.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you take a question on Africa?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; One second.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;ll go to you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, just this hour, lawmakers put out a bipartisan statement warning President Putin.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve said from the podium that the White House doesn&#8217;t need Congress to pass the sanctions package to implement your own sanctions package, but wouldn&#8217;t it have sent a stronger message if there had been an agreement reached?&nbsp; What message do you think it sends to Putin that all we got out of Congress was a statement?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think President Putin knows very clearly, because he&#8217;s heard it directly from President Biden&#8217;s mouth, that if he invades &#8212; if he invades Ukraine, that there will be crippling sanctions, and we don&#8217;t need Congress to act in order to do that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when will the President make a decision on any new energy policies to impact prices at the pump?&nbsp; Because even without an invasion, prices have risen beyond where they were before the emergency reserve release back in November.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You&#8217;re right.&nbsp; And the President is very focused on making sure we&#8217;re doing everything we can to lower the cost for Americans in any way it hits them, whether it&#8217;s prices at the pump, or when you go buy a pound of meat, or wherever it may be.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re continuing to assess.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s continuing to look at options.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a prediction of &#8212; of any decision though.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On Africa &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go to you after, Simon.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Switching topics entirely.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President is headed later this week to Ohio.&nbsp; He said that he&#8217;d like to be out in communities with people &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; frequently.&nbsp; How often would he like to be out there per week?&nbsp; What are you guys (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Every day?&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; well, but when he says that &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what is your anticipation?&nbsp; Is he looking to travel two, three days a week?&nbsp; And when would you expect that to ramp up?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, I think you can expect that to increase around the State of the Union and after.&nbsp; And I think we are constrained by a couple of things, including the CR funding but also the fact that there is a whole lot going on in the world.&nbsp; Even though he can be President anywhere, he also has a responsibility to sometimes be in the White House &#8212; or oftentimes be in the White House.&nbsp; So &#8212; but he&#8217;s looking forward to getting out there more in the coming weeks.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he have anywhere specific that he hasn’t been yet, or places that he hasn’t been, that he feels &#8212; frequently enough &#8212; that he&#8217;d really like to get back to?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Good question.&nbsp; I would venture to guess that he has probably been nearly everywhere, given he ran for President a couple times and Vice President.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I meant since he’s been &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As President, I don’t have any prediction of states or a readout of states that he is looking forward to going to, but I’m sure he &#8212; he is looking forward to traveling around the country &#8212; blue states, red states &#8212; across the gamut. &nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On Africa, you said &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay, Simon.&nbsp; I’ll go to you.&nbsp; Go ahead, Simon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; It’s been three months.&nbsp; So, if you can allow me to ask two questions.&nbsp; The President spoke with Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed of Ethiopia on January 10.&nbsp; It’s been almost a month now &#8212; more than a month since that call took place.&nbsp; And the WHO yesterday released a statement saying that they still don’t have access to the Tigray region for humanitarian access because the government is not allowing them to have fuel.<br><br>So, is the President still interested in anything else apart from Ukraine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Of course, he is.&nbsp; The President has to be the &#8212; a global leader in the world.&nbsp; And he is responsible for not just what&#8217;s happening around the world but also what&#8217;s happening domestically.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me give you an update or a comment from here:<br><br>We are hopeful that recent steps taken by the government of Ethiopia and other actors might open a path to resolving the conflict.&nbsp; Over the last month, the Prime Minister has taken steps to promote dialogue, release political prisoners, and enable expanded delivery of medical supplies in the Tigray region.&nbsp; We continue to have serious concerns about the humanitarian situation in Ethiopia, and we are focused on working with our parties &#8212; with all parties to end the source of the suffering, the military conflict.<br><br>Go ahead, Karen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; President Zelenskyy tomorrow is calling for a day of unity &#8212; a national holiday tomorrow in Ukraine.&nbsp; His message for the last couple of days, if not longer, has been “don’t panic” to Ukrainians.<br><br>Does the administration have concerns that Zelenskyy and Ukrainian leaders have not adequately prepared the Ukrainian people for a Russian invasion?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to speak to that.&nbsp; What I can speak to is what we feel our role and responsibility is, which is to provide a range of information about what we see at the border, what we see Russia preparing, and our assessment of what impact that could be.&nbsp; Every leader makes their own decisions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you have an update on the humanitarian assistance that the U.S. is talking with European allies should that happen and the Ukrainian people need that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I know we &#8212; Secretary Blinken made an announcement &#8212; I believe it was yesterday &#8212; about additional assistance.&nbsp; Let me just see if I have any more details on it in here, and if not, I will get that to you shortly after the briefing, Karen.&nbsp; Let me just see.<br><br>Let&#8217;s see here.&nbsp; Let me get you &#8212; I can get you &#8212; let&#8217;s see.&nbsp;<br><br>Last &#8212; so, we did offer &#8212; we just announced &#8212; sorry &#8212; a&nbsp; sovereign loan guarantee to Ukraine of up to $1 billion to bolster Ukraine&#8217;s economy amidst pressure resulting from Russia&#8217;s military buildup.&nbsp; This builds on the $3 billion in sovereign loan guarantees we issued to Ukraine between 2014 and 2016.<br><br>We&#8217;ve also committed more security assistance to Ukraine in the last year than at any point in history &#8212; $650 million.&nbsp;<br><br>And we also announced we&#8217;re launching a new Partnership Fund for a Resilient Ukraine with our European &#8212; with our Allies and partners to include &#8212; to continue to expand on that.<br><br>The last thing is we &#8212; the Export-Import Bank has made available $3 billion in support for projects in Ukraine, and&nbsp;the Development Finance Corporation has a current investment portfolio in Ukraine of approximately $800 million across more than a dozen projects.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve obviously provided a range of assistance, which we will continue to build on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, will Vice President Harris be meeting with President Zelenskyy when she&#8217;s in Munich?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything on her planned meetings at this point in time.&nbsp; I expect we&#8217;ll have more as we get a little bit closer, and I expect they&#8217;ll do a preview call from her team as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then an Olympics question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Does the administration have any reaction to the IOC’s decision to allow Russian figure skater &#8212; I’m going to butcher her name &#8212; Kamila Valieva to continue competing in the Olympics after her doping scandal?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, I would point you to the statement made by the U.S. Olympic and Paralympic Committee, who oppose the decision made in Beijing, saying it, quote, “appears to be another chapter in the systemic and pervasive disregard for clean sport by Russia.”&nbsp;<br><br>But these were independent decisions made by the <s>U.S. Anti-Doping</s> [International Testing] Agency and Court of Arbitration for Sport.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any additional comment from here.&nbsp; I would point you, again, to the U.S. Olympic Committee.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the U.S. Energy Information Administration shows data that Russian oil being imported in the U.S. has been increasing over the past year.&nbsp; In May of 2021, it was the most on record.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the President said he wants to use all tools to keep gas prices down.&nbsp; Is he looking at temporary things to keep gas prices down should there be a Russian invasion?&nbsp; Or is there any consideration in reversing some of the policies and going back to increasing U.S. energy independence?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to detail for you, inclu- &#8212; in terms of what he is considering.&nbsp; But our overarching objective is to decrease the impact on American consumers and increase the impact on Russian leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you talked about the boycott on the Republicans of the Fed nominees.&nbsp; Does the White House support allowing four of the five nominees to go through and then dealing with Sarah Bloom Raskin later?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, we are working with Chairman Brown to move all five nominees forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Right there.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Do you have any update on maybe steps the White House is taking in the event that the trucker protesting in Canada heads to the U.S. and, also, especially to D.C. around the time of the State of the Union?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; our Department of Homeland Security team has been assessing and I gave an update last week that they also increased support &#8212; federal support around the Super Bowl when there were those reports.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note the Super Bowl did move forward and there was no halting of that, so that is a positive development as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we are constantly assessing any impacts or any security impacts.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to ask &#8212; back to the Supreme Court.&nbsp; The President received a report with recommendations on how to reform the Supreme Court late last year.&nbsp; Has he at all reviewed the report yet and taken a position on it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t a &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t &#8212; I would just remind everyone: It wasn&#8217;t recommendations; it was a broad assessment from across the gamut of scholars from all ends of the political spectrum who were looking at a range of historic issues as it relates to the Court.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has been reviewing that, but I don&#8217;t have anything to read out for you on that front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The other thing I wanted to ask you was about voting rights.&nbsp; The President signed this expansive executive order a year ago on voting.&nbsp; I believe Susan Rice put out &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; an update on it in September or October.&nbsp; Could you provide an update on what agencies are doing?&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to start beginning seeing elections as soon as next month.&nbsp; I believe that&#8217;s in Texas, but other states are going to start to have them.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, I do have a lot on this, not in front of me.&nbsp; So, in terms of what agencies are working on or what they&#8217;ve been working on and what they&#8217;ve basically been doing &#8212;&nbsp; so you&#8217;re &#8212; have more detail on this than maybe others do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But all of the agencies were tasked with putting together their own plans to expand voting access, and they&#8217;ve been working on those plans.&nbsp; They&#8217;re all at different points in the review process and how it will be implemented.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if you look at past examples, where &#8212; I think it was back in the ‘90s &#8212; where if you went to the DMV to renew your driver&#8217;s license, they would offer you the opportunity to register to vote &#8212; you know, stuff like that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me see if we can get you something &#8212; and anyone else who&#8217;s interested &#8212; after the briefing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, we&#8217;ll do one more.&nbsp; And then we&#8217;ll wrap it up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; One on China, one on Afghanistan.&nbsp; First of all, China&#8217;s foreign ministry has been really critical of U.S. rhetoric on the Russia-Ukraine crisis, calling it “hyping up the possibility of warfare,” saying the U.S. is “clamoring for bloc confrontation.”&nbsp; What does the White House make of this rhetoric?&nbsp; Are you going to take any action against it, either through talk or other means?&nbsp; And what do you make this closeness between Moscow and Beijing?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the &#8212; first, the meeting that they had a couple of weeks ago reflects an approach both countries have already taken for some time, which is to move closer together.&nbsp; We know, and we&#8217;ve said before, but China is not in a position to compensate Russia for their economic losses.&nbsp; And we have tools to deploy if we see foreign companies, including those in China, trying to backfill sanctions.<br><br>You know, I would say our overarching view, though, is that if Russia chooses to move forward, it will cost China and how it&#8217;s viewed in the eyes of Europe and the world.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something for them to assess.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are trying to prevent a war here.&nbsp; That is why we are putting information out and why we are engaging with the global community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then how do you respond to Afghans who are critical of the executive order that proposes to split the frozen Afghan money?&nbsp; They say that, you know, they weren&#8217;t involved in the 9/11 attacks, so why are they getting less of these funds that they&#8217;re entitled to?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that, first &#8212; let me start with the fact that this is one step in the process.&nbsp; No funds can be transferred until the courts make a ruling.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What the President was trying to do was enable certain U.S.-based assets belonging to Afghanistan’s central bank to be used to benefit the Afghan people, otherwise it would have been held &#8212; right? &#8212; and that money wouldn&#8217;t have been going.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, that&#8217;s why we saw &#8212; and he took a proactive step to facilitate access to $3.5 billion of those assets for the benefit of the Afghan people and Afghanistan&#8217;s future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>More than &#8212; as you know, many U.S. victims of terrorism, including the relatives of victims who died in the September 11&nbsp; terrorist attacks have brought claims against the Taliban and are pursuing these assets in federal court.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, more than $3.5 billion in assets are going to remain in the United States and are subject to the ongoing litigation.&nbsp; But what I think it&#8217;s important for people to know and understand is he took this proactive step to sign the executive order in an effort to try to provide some of this funding to the Afghan people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When will that happen?&nbsp; When will &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the courts have to rule in order for it to happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the other half &#8212; the $3.5 billion?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; The court &#8212; that has &#8212; it has to &#8212; the courts have to rule in order for any of the funding to move forward, I believe, is my understanding.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But why &#8212; how is that proactive then?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He’s making clear that he believes that half of the funding should go to the Afghan people to &#8212; for humanitarian purposes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will President Biden meet in person with the Russian president?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I answered that question a little bit earlier.<br><br>5:04 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Head of Cabinet of the President of the European Council Frédéric&#160;Bernard</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/15/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-president-of-european-council-frederic-bernard/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke with Frédéric Bernard, Head of Cabinet of the President of the European Council, on February 14. They discussed their shared concerns about Russia’s continued build-up of military forces around Ukraine. They reviewed recent diplomatic engagements to address the crisis, ongoing preparations by the U.S. and EU to impose severe&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke with Frédéric Bernard, Head of Cabinet of the President of the European Council, on February 14. They discussed their shared concerns about Russia’s continued build-up of military forces around Ukraine. They reviewed recent diplomatic engagements to address the crisis, ongoing preparations by the U.S. and EU to impose severe economic consequences if Russia chooses further military escalation, and efforts to provide continued support to Ukraine, including through economic assistance.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Polish Head of the International Policy Bureau Jakub&#160;Kumoch</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/15/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-polish-head-of-the-international-policy-bureau-jakub-kumoch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Dr. Jakub Kumoch, Head of the International Policy Bureau at Poland’s Presidential Chancellery.&#160; They discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts related to Russia’s destabilizing military buildup along Ukraine’s border, including Poland’s leadership in the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe. They also discussed transatlantic coordination on deterrence and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Dr. Jakub Kumoch, Head of the International Policy Bureau at Poland’s Presidential Chancellery.&nbsp; They discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts related to Russia’s destabilizing military buildup along Ukraine’s border, including Poland’s leadership in the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe. They also discussed transatlantic coordination on deterrence and defense efforts, with Mr. Sullivan expressing appreciation for Poland’s hosting of additional U.S. forces to reinforce NATO’s eastern flank.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden on Sandy Hook&#160;Settlement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/15/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-sandy-hook-settlement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 23:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the families of nine victims of the Sandy Hook Elementary School Shooting have secured a historic settlement with the gun manufacturer Remington. While this settlement does not erase the pain of that tragic day, it does begin the necessary work of holding gun manufacturers accountable for manufacturing weapons of war and irresponsibly marketing these&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the families of nine victims of the Sandy Hook Elementary School Shooting have secured a historic settlement with the gun manufacturer Remington. While this settlement does not erase the pain of that tragic day, it does begin the necessary work of holding gun manufacturers accountable for manufacturing weapons of war and irresponsibly marketing these firearms.<br> <br>This progress is the result of the perseverance of nine families who turned tragedy into purpose. They have demonstrated that state and city consumer protection laws – like Connecticut’s Unfair Trade Practices Act – provide an opportunity to hold gun manufacturers and dealers accountable for wrongdoing despite the persistence of the federal immunity shield for these companies. <br> <br>As I have repeatedly called for, Congress must repeal the Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act so we can fully hold gun manufacturers and dealers accountable. But, in the meantime, I will continue to urge state and local lawmakers, lawyers, and survivors of gun violence to pursue efforts to replicate the success of the Sandy Hook families. Together, we can deliver a clear message to gun manufacturers and dealers: they must either change their business models to be part of the solution for the gun violence epidemic, or they will bear the financial cost of their complicity.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Providing an Update on Russia and&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/15/remarks-by-president-biden-providing-an-update-on-russia-and-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 23:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 3:29 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Today, I’d like to provide an update on the crisis involving Russia and Ukraine. From the beginning of this crisis, I have been absolutely clear and consistent: The United States is prepared no matter what happens.  We are ready with diplomacy &#8212; to be engaged in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>East Room</em></p>



<p>3:29 P.M. EST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Today, I’d like to provide an update on the crisis involving Russia and Ukraine.<br><br>From the beginning of this crisis, I have been absolutely clear and consistent: The United States is prepared no matter what happens. <br><br>We are ready with diplomacy &#8212; to be engaged in diplomacy with Russia and our Allies and partners to improve stability and security in Europe as a whole. <br><br>And we are ready to respond decisively to a Russian attack on Ukraine, which is still very much a possibility.<br><br>Through all of the events of the last few weeks and months, this has been our approach.  And it remains our approach now.<br><br>So, today I want to speak to the American people about the situation on the ground, the steps we’ve taken, the actions we’re prepared to take, and what’s at stake for us and the world, and how this may impact on us here at home.<br><br>For weeks now, together with our Allies and partners, my administration has engaged in non-stop diplomacy.<br><br>This weekend I spoke again with President Putin to make clear that we are ready to keep pursuing high-level diplomacy to reach written understandings among Russia, the United States, and the nations of Europe to address legitimate security concerns if that’s what &#8212; his wish.  Their security concerns and ours.<br><br>President Putin and I agreed that our teams should continue to engage toward this end along with our European Allies and partners.<br><br>Yesterday, the Russian government publicly proposed to continue the diplomacy.  I agree.  We should give the diplomacy every chance to succeed.  I believe there are real ways to address our respective security concerns.<br><br>The United States has put on the table concrete ideas to establish a security environment in Europe.<br><br>We’re proposing new arms control measures, new transparency measures, new strategic stability measures.  These measures would apply to all parties &#8212; NATO and Russia alike.<br><br>And we’re willing to make practical, results-oriented steps that can advance our common security.  We will not sacrifice basic principles, though.<br><br>Nations have a right to sovereignty and territorial integrity.  They have the freedom to set their own course and choose with whom they will associate.<br><br>But that still leaves plenty of room for diplomacy and for de-escalation.  That’s the best way forward for all parties, in our view.  And we’ll continue our diplomatic efforts in close consultation with our Allies and our partners.<br><br>As long as there is hope of a diplomatic resolution that prevents the use of force and avoids the incredible human suffering that would follow, we will pursue it.<br><br>The Russian Defense Ministry reported today that some military units are leaving their positions near Ukraine.<br><br>That would be good, but we have not yet verified that.  We have not yet verified that Russian military units are returning to their home bases.  Indeed, our analysts indicate that they remain very much in a threatening position.  And the fact remains: Right now, Russia has more than 150,000 troops encircling Ukraine in Belarus and along Ukraine’s border.<br><br>An invasion remains distinctly possible.  That’s why I&#8217;ve asked several times that all Americans in Ukraine leave now before it’s too late to leave safely.  It is why we have temporarily relocated our embassy from Kyiv to Lviv in western Ukraine, approaching the Polish border. <br><br>And we&#8217;ve been transparent with the American people and with the world about Russia’s plans and the seriousness of the situation so that everyone can see for themselves what is happening.  We have shared what we know and what we are doing about it.<br><br>Let me be equally clear about what we are not doing:<br><br>The United States and NATO are not a threat to Russia.  Ukraine is not threatening Russia. <br><br>Neither the U.S. nor NATO have missiles in Ukraine.  We do not &#8212; do not have plans to put them there as well.<br><br>We’re not targeting the people of Russia.  We do not seek to destabilize Russia.<br><br>To the citizens of Russia: You are not our enemy.  And I do not believe you want a bloody, destructive war against Ukraine &#8212; a country and a people with whom you share such deep ties of family, history, and culture.<br><br>Seventy-seven years ago, our people fought and sacrificed side by side to end the worst war in history.<br><br>World War Two was a war of necessity.  But if Russia attacks Ukraine, it would be a war of choice, or a war without cause or reason.<br><br>I say these things not to provoke but to speak the truth &#8212; because the truth matters; accountability matters.<br><br>If Russia does invade in the days or weeks ahead, the human cost for Ukraine will be immense, and the strategic cost for Russia will also be immense.<br><br>If Russia attacks Ukraine, it’ll be met with overwhelming international condemnation.  The world will not forget that Russia chose needless death and destruction.<br><br>Invading Ukraine will prove to be a self-inflicted wound.<br><br>The United States and our Allies and partners will respond decisively.  The West is united and galvanized.<br><br>Today, our NATO Allies and the Alliance is as unified and determined as it has ever been.   And the source of our unbreakable strength continues to be the power, resilience, and universal appeal of our shared democratic values.<br><br>Because this is about more than just Russia and Ukraine.  It&#8217;s about standing for what we believe in, for the future we want for our world, for liberty &#8212; for liberty, the right of countless countries to choose their own destiny, and the right of people to determine their own futures, for the principle that a country can’t change its neighbor’s borders by force.  That&#8217;s our vision.  And toward that end, I’m confident that vision, that freedom will prevail.<br><br>If Russia proceeds, we will rally the world to oppose its aggression.<br><br>The United States and our Allies and partners around the world are ready to impose powerful sanctions on [and] export controls, including actions that did not &#8212; we did not pursue when Russia invaded Crimea and eastern Ukraine in 2014.  We will put intense pressure on their largest and most significant financial institutions and key industries.<br><br>These measures are ready to go as soon and if Russia moves.  We&#8217;ll impose long-term consequences that will undermine Russia’s ability to compete economically and strategically.<br><br>And when it comes to Nord Stream 2, the pipeline that would bring natural gas from Russia to Germany, if Russia further invades Ukraine, it will not happen.<br><br>While I will not send American servicemen to fight Russia in Ukraine, we have supplied the Ukrainian military with equipment to help them defend themselves.  We have provided training and advice and intelligence for the same purpose. <br><br>And make no mistake: The United States will defend every inch of NATO territory with the full force of American power.  An attack against one NATO country is an attack against all of us.  And the United States commitment to Article 5 is sacrosanct. <br><br>Already, in response to Russia’s build-up of troops, I have sent additional U.S. forces to bolster NATO’s eastern flank.<br><br>Several of our Allies have also announced they&#8217;ll add forces and capabilities to ensure deterrence and defense along NATO’s eastern flank.<br><br>We will also continue to conduct military exercises with our Allies and partners to enhance defensive readiness. <br><br>And if Russia invades, we will take further steps to reinforce our presence in NATO, reassure for our Allies, and deter further aggression.<br><br>This is a cause that unites Republicans and Democrats.  And I want to thank the leaders and members of Congress of both parties who have forcefully spoken out in defense of our most basic, most bipartisan, most American principles.<br><br>I will not pretend this will be painless.  There could be impact on our energy prices, so we are taking active steps to alleviate the pressure on our own energy markets and offset rising prices.<br><br>We’re coordinating with major enersy [sic] &#8212; energy consumers and producers.  We’re prepared to deploy all the tools and authority at our disposal to provide relief at the gas pump. <br><br>And I will work with Congress on additional measures to help protect consumers and address the impact of prices at the pump.<br><br>We are not seeking direct confrontation with Russia, though I have been clear that if Russia targets Americans in Ukraine, we will respond forcefully.<br><br>And if Russia attacks the United States or our Allies through asymmetric means, like disruptive cyberattacks against our companies or critical infrastructure, we are prepared to respond. <br><br>We’re moving in lockstep with our NATO Allies and partners to deepen our collective defense against threats in cyberspace.<br><br>Two paths are still open.  For the sake of the historic responsibility Russia and the United States share for global stability, for the sake of our common future &#8212; to choose diplomacy.<br><br>But let there be no doubt: If Russia commits this breach by invading Ukraine, responsible nations around the world will not hesitate to respond. <br><br>If we do not stand for freedom where it is at risk today, we’ll surely pay a steeper price tomorrow. <br><br>Thank you.  I’ll keep you informed.<br><br>END                3:50 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Hawaii Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/15/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-hawaii-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 21:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47338</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Hawaii and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, flooding, and landslides during the period of December 5 to December 10, 2021. Federal funding is available to state and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Hawaii and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, flooding, and landslides during the period of December 5 to December 10, 2021.<br><br>Federal funding is available to state and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storms, flooding, and landslides in the City and County of Honolulu and Maui County.<br><br>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.<br><br>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Benigno Bern Ruiz as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp;<br><br>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.<br><br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Emmanuel Macron of&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/15/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-emmanuel-macron-of-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 21:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France.  They reviewed their recent conversations with their Russian and Ukrainian counterparts, and affirmed their continued support for a diplomatic path forward. They discussed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts undertaken in close coordination with Allies and partners in response to Russia’s military buildup&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France.  They reviewed their recent conversations with their Russian and Ukrainian counterparts, and affirmed their continued support for a diplomatic path forward. They discussed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts undertaken in close coordination with Allies and partners in response to Russia’s military buildup along Ukraine’s borders, including their readiness to impose severe consequences and to reinforce the defensive posture on NATO’s eastern flank.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the National Association of Counties 2022 Legislative&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/15/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-national-association-of-counties-2022-legislative-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Washington HiltonWashington, D.C. 1:20 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you. Folks, my name is Joe Biden.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And I used to be a county councilman.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; And I ran for the Senate because it was too damn hard being in the council.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; It’s great to be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Washington Hilton<br>Washington, D.C.</em></p>



<p>1:20 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Folks, my name is Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I used to be a county councilman.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And I ran for the Senate because it was too damn hard being in the council.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>It’s great to be back with you all.&nbsp; Commissioner Larry Johnson of DeKalb County, Georgia, thank you for your leadership.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also want to thank all the folks working so hard here in the Washington Hilton to make this conference possible.&nbsp; Thank you all very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if you want to know how seriously I take the role you play on the frontlines in this country, just look at who I asked to come with you.&nbsp; You said you wanted to know what was going on.&nbsp; I sent you the whole damn administration.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Yeah, Secretaries &#8212; three Secretaries, an Administrator &#8212; Regan of the EPA; Gene Sperling leading the Rescue Plan implementation; Mitch Landrieu, who’s leading the implementation of the Infrastructure Law; and you all know Julie Rodriguez, my Director of Intergovernmental Affairs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And along with a number of other key deputies and &#8212; leading my economic strategy.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, I want to recognize my home county executive, Matt Meyer, so I can go back home.&nbsp; Matt, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Matt is doing one heck of a job, and I’m sure he’s told you the story, I heard, of the &#8212; my time in the county council.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I used to &#8212; I don&#8217;t know about you all, but commissioner, councilman &#8212; whichever your title is &#8212; you knock on the door and say, “My name is Joe Biden, and I’m a candidate for the county council.”&nbsp; And they look at you like, “Okay?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And you’re wondering &#8212; you’re wondering what the county council does, aren’t you?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Well, it affects their lives more than anybody else’s.&nbsp; No, it really does.&nbsp; You’re involved in everything.&nbsp;<br><br>When a constituent called, she said &#8212; I represented a &#8212; we had &#8212; we have one county that has 60 percent of the state’s population.&nbsp; And we had six councilmen.&nbsp; So a councilman’s district was seven times bigger than a house member and &#8212; in the state house &#8212; and three time bigger than the state senator.<br><br>And I represented a middle-class district to a working-class district, but there was one very wealthy neighborhood.&nbsp; And I got a call one night; the woman said to me &#8212; obviously not of the same persuasion as I was, politically &#8212; called me and said, “There’s a dead dog on my lawn.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I said, “Yes, ma’am.”&nbsp; I said, “Have you called county?”&nbsp; She said, “Yes, they’re not here.”&nbsp; And I said, “Well, I’ll get them in the morning.”&nbsp; She said, “I want it removed now.&nbsp; I pay your salary.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, I went over.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; I picked it up.&nbsp; She said, “I want it out of my front yard.”&nbsp; I put it on her doorstep.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>But I’ve gotten much better since then.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I know from personal experience how hard the job you have is.&nbsp; People &#8212; people having to phone or &#8212; you know, or not afraid to use that phone.&nbsp; I used to give out my phone number; can’t do that anymore.&nbsp; They don’t even allow me to have a phone anymore.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But I &#8212; I also know you work often on the basis of what other people &#8212; whether they’ve lost faith, they have faith, they lose faith in government &#8212; you’re there.&nbsp; You represent the frontlines of public service.&nbsp; It’s not hyperbole.<br><br>That’s why I was elected &#8212; one of the first calls I made was to your board of directors.&nbsp;&nbsp;And I reminded Judge Gary Moore, your past president, that this administration includes a President and Vice President who are both former county officials.&nbsp;&nbsp;And I promised I’ll always have you as a partner with us.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The partnership was critical when we passed American Rescue Plan &#8212; the most significant investment in the country’s local governments in American history.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I also inherited a tough situation in 2020.&nbsp; But after an incredibly difficult year, local and state governments have added 448,000 new jobs in 2021 &#8212; the strongest growth in 20 years.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, you know, it’s &#8212; it’s amazing what you all do.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; I’m not being solicitous.&nbsp; After a year of disruption for our kids, we were able to add education jobs in 2021, more than &#8212; more than any other year on record.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You got county law enforcement officers and first responders back on the job so ambulances could arrive on time and communities could be kept safe.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the big reason why America’s recovery has led the world is because of all of you and why, in my first year in office, more jobs were created than ever any time in America history &#8212; 6.6 million jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, folks, look, we had the strongest economic growth in nearly 40 years &#8212; 5.7 percent increase in the GDP.&nbsp; The unemployment rate dropped more than any time &#8212; any year in American history.&nbsp; Child poverty dropped by 40 percent, more than any year in American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And, folks, new business applications grew at a faster rate than any year on record.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Rescue Plan also was the first major relief bill to get directly to counties, because here is what I learned when I was a county councilman: If you get money for &#8212; for the state, what happens is it goes through the state legislature.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;And guess what?&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughs.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, I wanted to make sure the money goes directly to the counties.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Directly to the counties &#8212; no, really.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;We allocated $350 billion to state and local budgets.&nbsp;&nbsp;We made sure that $1 billion [$100 billion] of that went straight to the counties and cities.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;And look, I know how much it matters.&nbsp;&nbsp;It really matters giving you &#8212; giving you the ability, the flexibility, the control to meet both the short-term and long-term challenges you face.&nbsp; Which, by the way, even &#8212; and I &#8212; I&#8217;m not being critical of the state legislatures or to &#8212; or others, but people don’t know the full responsibility and &#8212; that you all have, even other elected officials.&nbsp; They &#8212; I mean, I&#8217;m not being solicitous.&nbsp; It’s just true.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, by the way, that Rescue Plan is still delivering.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I urge all of you to use the flexibility we built into the law and spend those funds wisely, to build a future around working people who make up the communities you run.&nbsp; Put these funds to work to keep people on the job, connect people with better jobs &#8212; providing retention bonuses for teachers and bus drivers, like Howard County, Maryland, did; adding healthcare centers and training new childcare workers, like &#8212; I hope I pronounce it &#8212; Deschutes County, Oregon.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; where are you, Deschutes County?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, what you did matters.&nbsp;<br><br>Helping unemployed parents get back to work by covering childcare costs, like Oakland County, Michigan, did.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Reducing gun crime by retaining police officers, like DeKalb County did in Georgia.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Expanding community violence intervention programs, like King County did in Washington.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ensuring people get the full benefit of one of the most consequential tax cuts for working families in our history.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We expanded the Childcare Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit included in the Rescue Plan.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the past, if you paid taxes and you had a good income, you could deduct $2,000 per child.&nbsp; So if you&#8217;re making 200 grand a year and you have three kids, you got to deduct 6,000 bucks off your &#8212; off the taxes you owed.&nbsp; Well, that’s fair.<br><br>But guess what?&nbsp; If you were making minimum wage and you had four kids, you didn’t get anything.&nbsp; It wasn’t refundable.&nbsp; You didn’t pay $8,000 in taxes.&nbsp; There wasn’t what &#8212; you couldn’t re- &#8212; you couldn’t reduce your taxes.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So we made sure it was refundable.&nbsp; Because guess what?&nbsp; It’s just as hard for a firefighter or a teacher or a cop who has the benefit of that tax break to raise his kids as for a wealthy person to raise their kid.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>No, and &#8212; and by the way, it’s not a criticism of the wealthy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just to think about it.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; It was well intended originally when &#8212; when the Childcare Tax Credit &#8212; when the Child Tax Credit existed early on.&nbsp; Because you said, “Well, we got to give a break for raising kids.”<br><br>But I remember it used to drive my dad nuts, because we had four kids.&nbsp; It was a lot less.&nbsp; It was less than a thou- &#8212; it was 1,000 bucks then.&nbsp; But, you know, if you&#8217;re making what was 12,000 bucks a year &#8212; that was like making 40 now or 50 &#8212; if you&#8217;re making that kind of money, you didn&#8217;t have any taxes you could deduct it from, so there wasn&#8217;t any benefit for your kids.<br><br>Look, that&#8217;s why the American Rescue Plan &#8212; we didn&#8217;t expand the amount &#8212; well, we expanded the amount, but I &#8212; even if we don&#8217;t expand the amount &#8212; middle-class tax cut &#8212; we made it refundable.&nbsp; So you get paid back what you would’ve had to pay, which you got to deduct if you made more money.&nbsp; So the money you &#8212; go directly into your pocket, helping with your kids.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why I’m so thankful for counties like Salt Lake County and Miami-Dade County &#8212; created programs to help lower-income folks who typically don’t even file taxes because they&#8217;re below minimum wage or don’t have any income to get the assistance they need but they have to file in order to get the assistance.<br><br>You all reached out and said, “Look, you have a benefit coming, but you got to file taxes.”&nbsp; And you helped them do it.&nbsp; You &#8212; and I used to have a friend who was a great basketball player back in the days when Providence had great teams &#8212; Providence College.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>No, I mean, they had &#8212; they had some superstars at the time.&nbsp;&nbsp;His name was Pete McLaughlin, and he wasn’t the &#8212; he passed away.&nbsp;&nbsp;But he wasn&#8217;t the &#8212; he used to say &#8212; he wasn’t the sharpest academic candle on the table, but he knew what was going on.&nbsp;&nbsp;And he knew how to &#8212; he said, you know &#8212; he had an expression: “You got to know how to know.”&nbsp;&nbsp;I can take you into the greatest library in the world, the Library of Congress; if you don&#8217;t know how to read the card catalog, it’s useless to you.&nbsp;&nbsp;You got to know how to know.<br><br>So, you’re helping people know how to know how to get inter- &#8212; what they need.&nbsp;&nbsp;And it&#8217;s all about making sure people [who] have more economic difficulty raising their families can finally get a benefit that wealthier people get in the tax burdens and the Child Tax Credit.<br><br>But, look, another thing that funding can support, thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill, is jobs.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to create millions &#8212; several million jobs.&nbsp; Folks, look, it took a long time and a lot of administration, but we finally passed a Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill.&nbsp; Everybody.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we finally ended “Infrastructure Week.”&nbsp; We got something done.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Everybody knew America was falling behind in infrastructure.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; After years of dead ends and broken promises, we came together &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; and we did something about it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not only has Infrastructure Week finally arrived, we can look forward to an infrastructure decade; that’s what this is for 10 years.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Just 92 &#8212; just 92 days after I signed the law, it’s already making a tangible difference.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We announced billions of funding allocations to put people to work in good-paying jobs cleaning up rivers in Ohio, chemical plants in Florida, and dozens of other sites; bolstering the energy grid with a stronger transmission lines and towers; modernizing bridges like the one I visited in Grafton County up in New Hampshire, where the weight restrictions could force school buses and firetrucks to go 10 miles out of their way to get on the other side of the river; and capping and plugging tens of thousands of orphaned oil wells and gas wells that continue to spew methane, which is a &#8212; deadly for the environment.&nbsp; Creating jobs as good as the folks who dug those wells in the first place with the same salaries.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This is only the beginning.&nbsp; Hundreds of billions in new investments are on the way.&nbsp; Now it’s time for the counties to get ready.&nbsp; You don’t have to wait until the projects start.&nbsp; You can use the resources from the American Rescue Plan now.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re going to need welders, pipefitters, advanced manufacturers ready to take on those jobs.&nbsp; And it takes training to do those jobs well, and that’s why union workers are the best in the world, because they actually get the job done cheaper because they don’t waste any time.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>But you can start &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I know you all know, but you can start those Rescue Plan funds now by building pathways to better jobs through union-based apprentice programs and on-the-job training.&nbsp; Like, you know, Maricopa County in Arizona, where they’re using American Rescue Plan funds to help young workers develop in-demand technical skills so you know what the country is going to need.&nbsp; Community colleges are doing it as well.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Boone County, Campbell County, Kenton County, Kentucky, where you’re expanding high-speed Internet to nearly 100,000 homes and businesses.<br><br>You know, how many times did you ride by a McDonald&#8217;s parking lot in the middle of the pandemic and see people out there sitting &#8212; a mom and dad &#8212; tying into the network so their kids could do their homework remotely?&nbsp; This is the United States of America, for God&#8217;s sake.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Cook County, Illinois, where you’re using Rescue Plan funds to work with the Southland Metals Hub, helping workers prepare to take on manufacturing and infrastructure jobs and strengthening the supply chains in the Heartland.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Rescue Plan funds we delivered to your count- &#8212; to your counties, they can help each of you build a strong, diverse workforce you’ll need to take up and take on these infrastructure jobs so that we’re &#8212; there are &#8212; more families can deal themselves into this booming economy.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The truth is, we have an incredible opportunity ahead of us.&nbsp; And that’s not hyperbole; we really do.&nbsp; We still have a lot of work to do to put together we’ve &#8212; we’ve proven that we can get big things done in this country bipartisanly.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we all know the challenges still remain.&nbsp; We’re still fighting a deadly virus.&nbsp; We still need more people to get vaccinated and boosted.&nbsp;<br><br>But thanks to our &#8212; your partnership, we’ve gone from 2 million people vaccinated, when I got elected, to 215 million people vaccinated.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;And &#8212; and, again, I’m not being solicitous.&nbsp;&nbsp;You’ve been critical partners since day one on masking, texing [sic] &#8212; testing, and vas- &#8212; vaccinations, standing strong against misinformation, and sometimes even withstanding shameful personal attacks.&nbsp;&nbsp;Through it all, you’ve led with patriotism and resolve.&nbsp;&nbsp;And you’ve saved lives.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Another challenge we face is eading- [sic] the &#8212; easing the burden on working families.&nbsp; This &#8212; there’s real inflation.&nbsp; And if you’re in a working-class family, it hurts.&nbsp; That’s why my Build Back Better plan &#8212; what it’s all about.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, families are getting clobbered by the cost of everyday things.&nbsp; You know, I know that gas and food prices are up; we’re working to bring them down.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I grew up in a family where the price at the pump was felt in the kitchen.&nbsp; Everybody knew.&nbsp; Everybody felt it.&nbsp; I understand.&nbsp; These are necessities, but they’re not the totality of what a family needs.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, while we work on supply chains and we work on bringing down the costs of the things that we’re talking about have gone up so high, we still have other ways we can reduce the burden on working-class families.&nbsp;<br><br>They still have to pay for childcare.&nbsp; Families can spend as much as $14,000 a year in some parts of the country for childcare.&nbsp; My plan: The cost of childcare for working families will cost 7 percent of your income.&nbsp; No more.&nbsp; And that helps millions of parents, especially women, get back to work.&nbsp; Twenty million of them are not working now.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, by the way, it ends up paying for itself when they’re back to work paying taxes.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, we still pay for &#8212; we still have to pay for prescription drugs.&nbsp; You want to benefit a family? &nbsp;Reduce the cost of the prescription drugs they have to pay.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>In America &#8212; in America, we pay the highest price for prescription drugs in the world &#8212; of any developed nation in the world.&nbsp; About two to three times what other countries pay.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me give you a &#8212; I can give you hundreds of examples; I’m giving you one.&nbsp; One anti-cancer drug to treat leukemia and lymphoma that costs $14,000 a month in the United States &#8212; that same exact drug, by the same drug company &#8212; the same company &#8212; that drug sold in France costs $6,000.&nbsp; Six thousand dollars.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Those of you who live on the Canadian border &#8212; you know, when you cross the border, you can buy the same drug for a hell of a lot less than you can buy in the United States.&nbsp; Same manufacturer.<br><br>Or take insulin: The costs of drug companies to provide insulin &#8212; a vial of insulin &#8212; costs less than $10 to make.&nbsp; But there are many families, like families I met last week in Culpeper, Virginia, paying $300 per vial for medicine they need every single day for Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; If they have good healthcare coverage &#8212; this family does &#8212; but they still have to pay $5,600 for prescriptions before their insurance kicks in.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Think about that: 200,000 American children with Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; Think about being one of those parents.&nbsp; “We don’t have insurance.”&nbsp; But you know your child, to live, needs that insulin.&nbsp; How do you look that child in the eye when you don’t have the income&nbsp;or you don’t have &#8212; you don’t have the insurance?&nbsp; What do you do?<br><br>Not only do you worry if your child may die, but you’re stripped of your dignity.&nbsp; You’re stripped of your sense of who you are, not being able to afford that child’s needs.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, we can cap the cost of insulin to $35 a month.&nbsp; Drug companies will still make money.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Now, let me digress just for a moment.&nbsp; I started the Cancer Moonshot, which I worked very hard on in the administration &#8212; the administration I served in last.&nbsp; And I held conferences all over the country with literally thousands of people and, at the same time, doing it virtually.&nbsp; And after one of them, I got the 12 largest drug companies in one room.&nbsp;&nbsp;And I said, “If you found a cure for a particular cancer” &#8212; and I named a cancer &#8212; I said, “What amount of money do you think you should be able to charge for that drug?”&nbsp;&nbsp;They said, “Whatever the market will bear.”&nbsp;<br><br>And I said, “Well, you know, many places, like Germany, you can get and make sure you make a profit that’s 20 to 30 percent &#8212; even 40 percent &#8212; more than your total investment.&nbsp;&nbsp; But once they set the price, that’s the only price you can pay to sell that drug.&nbsp; You still make 30, 40 percent profit after all your expenses you demonstrate.&nbsp; And the other provision is you can’t increase the price for that drug beyond the cost of inflation unless you’ve done additional work on the drug to improve it.”</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Think about where we’re going.&nbsp; We’re on the &#8212; we’re on the verge &#8212; thank God &#8212; of some significant breakthroughs in healthcare.&nbsp; But should it be based upon what you can afford to pay?&nbsp; If Congress acts, we could take care of things with the stroke of a pen tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have a generation of so-called “sandwich generation” &#8212; many of you are part of it &#8212; trying to take care of your children while taking care of your aging mom or dad.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We can help make it work &#8212; care for our elderly parents and have someone install a handrail in the shower, make sure they have steps that they can get up and down, someone can pick up their prescriptions while you’re working, and allow them to continue to live in the dignity of their home.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; That saves a hell of a lot of money, because the cost of that &#8212; and by the way, that’s available under Medicare now, except 880,000 people don’t &#8212; can’t get into the program yet.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s a lot cheaper to have mom and dad live at home with minimal expense than have the public pick up the cost of healthcare &#8212; of housing for the elderly.&nbsp; We can do all that and still save money so when they put their head on the pillow at night, they can have peace of mind.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m going to work like the devil to bring gas prices down.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we’re going to keep working to strengthen supply chains to bring the cost of every good down, particularly food and automobiles.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you know the best news of all of this?&nbsp; Nobody earning less than $400,000 a year will pay an additional penny in taxes for any of these services.&nbsp; We can do it without increasing the deficit.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As a matter of fact, last year, we reduced the deficit by $300 billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But by passing the elements of the Build Back Better plan, which reduced the burden on families, I got a letter from 17 Nobel laureates &#8212; came to me to say this plan, my plan, will ease long-term inflationary pressures.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, we can tackle these challenges, but only if we keep coming together.&nbsp; The fact is: We can’t do it without you.&nbsp; You understand what families are up against.&nbsp; You understand the cost if we fail to act.&nbsp; We need your voices, of the county officials, helping us &#8212; folks understand what our communities need.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If we can get this done, there’s no limit to what America can achieve.&nbsp; So let’s g- &#8212; let’s give working people a better chance than they’ve had, a quality they deserve, by investing in the future of every county.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let’s face these challenges head on, but let’s keep building back better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re the only country in the world where whatever crisis we’ve gone through, we’ve ended up on the other side better off than we were before we got into the crisis.&nbsp; We’re the only one.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And folks, let me say one other thing: I had a group of eight major utilities come to see me to tell me they wanted to see the Build Back Better plan put in place, even though they knew they were going to pay higher taxes; corporate taxes could go up to 24 percent.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, there are &#8212; of the major Fortune 500 companies, there are 52 that made over $40 billion, didn’t pay a single penny in tax.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; I know &#8212; I think you should be able to go out and make a million or a billion dollars if you have the capability, but just pay a little bit.&nbsp; Pay your fair share.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I’m serious.&nbsp; I’m serious.&nbsp; And that’s why we’re getting so much support for the things we’re doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why, for example &#8212; and it’s major corporations coming to us.&nbsp; For example, you ride through some fields in Iowa &#8212; I mean, excuse me, Ohio, and it looks like there’s nothing there except beautiful land stretched out.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; An outfit called Intel came to me and said, “We want to invest $20 billion in those fields, creating 7,600 jobs to build a facility and 3,500 jobs permanent; average salary of those permanent jobs, $135,000 a year.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know what they’re doing?&nbsp; They’re going to make computer chips, because there are no &#8212; you know, one third of inflation is a consequence of the cost of automobiles going up.&nbsp; Why are they going up?&nbsp; We invented the computer chip, but we don&#8217;t make it.&nbsp; We have to get it from &#8212; everyone from Taiwan to China to other places.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, we can do this.&nbsp; We can do this by reasserting who, in God&#8217;s name, we are: the United States of America.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing &#8212; I mean this from the bottom of my heart &#8212; there&#8217;s nothing beyond our capacity.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing we cannot do if we do it together.&nbsp; That&#8217;s always been who we are.&nbsp;<br><br>This is the United States of America.&nbsp; You can make a million bucks and still pay your fair share.&nbsp; And everybody &#8212; when have you ever seen &#8212; I was talking to somebody.&nbsp; I said, “You know, you go through…&#8221;&nbsp; Neighboring state of New Jersey, from Delaware &#8212; my area is down by the shore.&nbsp; You ride through an intersection where there&#8217;s a big circle and there are four or five roads coming off of it.&nbsp; And usually in the middle of that circle, there&#8217;s plant &#8212; you can &#8212; you know, you can plant trees and flowers and the like.&nbsp;<br><br>I can tell you the communities &#8212; and I said this to somebody and then they showed me a study that it was true.&nbsp; I can tell you whether the community has renters or owners.&nbsp; When they&#8217;re owners, that middle circle is beautiful; it&#8217;s planted.&nbsp; When they&#8217;re renters, they&#8217;re not.&nbsp; Doesn’t mean there’s anything wrong with renting, but it means engaging in the community.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, folks, when middle-class folks do well, there&#8217;s never been a time the wealthy don&#8217;t do very, very well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; So, folks, let’s stick to the people we need.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you for listening to me.&nbsp; May God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>1:48 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Department of Defense Releases New Report on Safeguarding our National Security by Promoting Competition in the Defense Industrial&#160;Base</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/15/fact-sheet-department-of-defense-releases-new-report-on-safeguarding-our-national-security-by-promoting-competition-in-the-defense-industrial-base/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of President Biden’s whole-of-government approach to promoting competition, the Department of Defense (DoD) released a new report today on the state of competition in the defense industrial base. The report surveys the state of competition across key defense sectors and finds that extreme consolidation poses risks to our nation’s national and economic security.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As part of President Biden’s whole-of-government approach to promoting competition, the Department of Defense (DoD) released a new report today on the state of competition in the defense industrial base. The report surveys the state of competition across key defense sectors and finds that extreme consolidation poses risks to our nation’s national and economic security. The report emphasizes that promoting competition is a top priority for DoD and outlines a series of actions that DoD will pursue to rebuild its competitive bench, lower costs for taxpayers, and safeguard our national security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The term “defense industrial base” (DIB) describes the vast network of companies that provide goods and services to DoD. These companies make up a significant part of our economy, ranging from small businesses and startups to some of the biggest corporations in the world. They provide products ranging from intercontinental ballistic missiles and highly specialized military satellites to everyday commercial products like batteries and laptops.</p>



<p>The report observes that extreme consolidation in the defense sector has reduced competition and heightened national security risks. Since the 1990s, the number of aerospace and defense prime contractors has shrunk from 51 to just 5. The same pattern has played out across categories of major weapons systems: for example, today, 90% of missiles come from 3 sources. Such consolidation leaves DoD increasingly reliant on a handful of companies for critical defense capabilities. It also hurts taxpayers, as companies no longer feel the competitive pressure to innovate or perform at the highest level to win contracts.</p>



<p>The report also emphasizes the need to rebuild DoD’s competitive bench by lowering barriers for small businesses and bringing in new entrants. Small businesses spur innovation, producing 16.5 times more patents than large firms, and form the next generation of suppliers to support the DoD mission. However, the number of small businesses in the DIB shrunk by over 40% over the past decade. Without action, DoD could lose an additional 15,000 suppliers over the next decade—a national security and economic risk that threatens key domestic capabilities. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The report outlines five lines of effort to achieve the goals of President Biden’s Executive Order on Promoting Competition in the American Economy, confront the challenges posed by industry consolidation, and ensure sufficient domestic capacity and capability in the defense industrial base:</p>



<ul><li><em>Strengthening Merger Oversight.</em> DoD faces a historically consolidated DIB, making careful attention by DoD in the review of any further mergers necessary. When a merger threatens DoD interests, DoD will support the Federal Trade Commission and Department of Justice in antitrust investigations and recommendations involving the DIB.<br></li><li><em>Addressing Intellectual Property Limitations</em>. Certain practices surrounding intellectual property (IP) and data rights have been used to limit competition in DoD purchasing. In its ongoing modernization of its approach to IP rights, DoD should remain conscious of potential unnecessary anticompetitive consequences of any new IP-related procedures do what it can to create IP-related procedures that do not result in unnecessary anticompetitive consequences.<br></li><li><em>Increasing New Entrants</em>. To counteract the trend of overall shrinking of the DIB, DoD should endeavor to attract new entrants to the defense marketplace by reducing barriers to entry. That includes through small business outreach, support, and use of acquisition authorities that provide DoD the flexibility to reduce barriers and attract new vendors.<br></li><li><em>Increasing Opportunities for Small Businesses</em>. DoD should increase small business participation in defense procurement, including with small disadvantaged businesses, women-owned small businesses, service disabled veteran owned small businesses, and HUBZone businesses, with an emphasis on increasing competition in priority industrial base sectors.<br></li><li><em>Implementing Sector-specific Supply Chain Resilience Plans</em>: DoD should take steps to ensure resilience in the supply chain for five priority sectors: casting and forgings, missiles and munitions, energy storage and batteries, strategic and critical materials, and microelectronics.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Advances Cleaner Industrial Sector to Reduce Emissions and Reinvigorate American&#160;Manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-advances-cleaner-industrial-sector-to-reduce-emissions-and-reinvigorate-american-manufacturing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Pro-Climate, Pro-Worker Actions Create Jobs and Harness the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, Federal Purchasing Power, and Trade Policy Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new actions across agencies to support American leadership on clean manufacturing—including low-carbon production of the steel and aluminum we need for electric vehicles, wind turbines, and solar panels, and the clean&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>New Pro-Climate, Pro-Worker Actions Create Jobs and Harness the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, Federal Purchasing Power, and Trade Policy</em></p>



<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new actions across agencies to support American leadership on clean manufacturing—including low-carbon production of the steel and aluminum we need for electric vehicles, wind turbines, and solar panels, and the clean concrete we need to upgrade our transportation infrastructure. These actions will create more good-paying jobs and follow on a historic comeback for American factories, with <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/MANEMP">367,000</a> manufacturing jobs added during President Biden’s first year in office, the most in nearly 30 years. Further strengthening our industrial base will revitalize local economies, lower prices for consumers, provide more pathways to the middle class through union jobs, and boost American competitiveness in global markets.&nbsp;<br><br>The industrial sector is also central to tackling the climate crisis, as it is currently responsible for nearly a third of domestic greenhouse gas emissions. By helping manufacturers use clean energy, efficiency upgrades, and other innovative technologies to reduce emissions, the Administration is supporting cleaner industry that can produce the next generation of products and materials for a net-zero economy. These same manufacturing improvements will also protect public health, by reducing releases of air and water pollutants and toxic materials that disproportionately harm low-income households and communities of color.<br><br>Today’s announcements will clean up industrial processes that have long been challenging sources of pollution; create good-paying, union jobs across American manufacturing; and use domestic procurement and global trade policy to reward clean, American-made materials:</p>



<ul><li>The Department of Energy is launching<strong> major clean hydrogen initiatives of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</strong>: $8 billion for Regional Clean Hydrogen Hubs that will create jobs to expand use of clean hydrogen in the industrial sector and beyond; $1 billion for a Clean Hydrogen Electrolysis Program to reduce costs of hydrogen produced from clean electricity; and $500 million for Clean Hydrogen Manufacturing and Recycling Initiatives to support equipment manufacturing and strong domestic supply chains.<br></li><li>The Council on Environmental Quality and White House Office of Domestic Climate Policy are establishing the <strong>first-ever Buy Clean Task Force</strong>, which will harness the federal government’s massive purchasing power to support low-carbon materials made in American factories. The General Services Administration and the Department of Transportation are also announcing new efforts to promote use of l<strong>ow-carbon materials in construction projects funded by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</strong>, and the State Department and U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate are securing corporate purchasing commitments for low-carbon materials and technologies through the <strong>First Movers Coalition</strong>.<br></li><li>The Administration is advancing<strong> carbon-based trade policies to reward American manufacturers of clean steel and aluminum</strong>. Working with the European Union, the Administration is taking steps to align global trade with climate goals, which will keep out dirty products and result in more jobs and lower prices for Americans.<br></li><li>The Council on Environmental Quality is issuing new <strong>guidance on responsible deployment of Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Sequestration (CCUS)</strong> technologies that can reduce emissions from heavy industry and help us achieve a net-zero economy. This guidance will support CCUS projects that create union jobs and protect communities from cumulative pollution impacts. Actions by agencies will incorporate environmental justice considerations across CCUS activities.&nbsp;<br></li><li>To equitably advance innovation across the entire sector, the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy is launching a new <strong>Initiative for Interdisciplinary Industrial Decarbonization Research</strong> with a focus on benefitting American workers and communities. The Department of Energy is working to establish the <strong>Industrial Technology Innovation Advisory Committee (ITIAC)</strong> to bring together a diverse group of stakeholders charged with creating a comprehensive strategy to lower the carbon footprint of America’s industrial base.</li></ul>



<p>These actions and continued implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will reduce climate pollution from industrial facilities, while growing the economy and creating jobs in producing clean materials—which customers around the world are increasingly demanding.<br><br>With a strong foundation in place from today’s announcements, the President’s Build Back Better agenda will further boost clean manufacturing and American competitiveness for decades to come, by supporting low-carbon processes across our industrial base; driving long-term investment in our clean steel, cement, and aluminum industries; and increasing domestic production of electric vehicles, wind turbines, solar panels, and more. Earlier this month, the House passed the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/04/statement-from-president-biden-on-house-passage-of-the-america-competes-act/">America COMPETES Act</a>, which would strengthen supply chains, lower prices, and create more manufacturing jobs, while decarbonizing the industrial sector—including through a $250 million Regional Clean Energy Innovation Program and new programs to decarbonize American steel.</p>



<p>Specifically, today the Administration is announcing new efforts on:<br><br><strong>Accelerating Clean Hydrogen</strong><br><br>Clean hydrogen can reduce emissions in many sectors of the economy, and is especially important for hard-to-decarbonize sectors and industrial processes, such as steel manufacturing. But clean hydrogen is not yet in widespread use. Targeted investments can help reduce costs, make new breakthroughs, and create jobs for American engineers, factory workers, construction workers, and others.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>To seize those opportunities, today the Department of Energy (DOE) is launching three major new initiatives of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law by issuing Requests for Information:</p>



<ul><li><strong>$8 billion for </strong><a href="https://eere-exchange.energy.gov/Default.aspx#FoaId5d96172f-e9b6-48ff-94ac-5579c3531526"><strong>Regional Clean Hydrogen Hubs</strong></a><strong>:</strong> DOE will support development of networks of clean hydrogen producers, potential consumers, and connective infrastructure. These regional hubs will advance the production, processing, delivery, storage, and end-use of clean hydrogen, including innovative uses in the industrial sector. DOE will prioritize hubs that can provide significant training and long-term job opportunities for residents of the region.<br></li><li><strong>$1 billion for a </strong><a href="https://eere-exchange.energy.gov/Default.aspx#FoaIda1255029-22c4-4c18-9e90-356e92cbb795"><strong>Clean Hydrogen Electrolysis Program</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Electrolysis (using electricity to split water into hydrogen and oxygen) allows for clean hydrogen production from carbon pollution-free power sources like wind, solar, and nuclear. This program will improve the efficiency and cost-effectiveness of these technologies, by supporting the entire innovation chain—from research, development, and demonstration to commercialization, and deployment.<br></li><li><strong>$500 million for </strong><a href="https://eere-exchange.energy.gov/Default.aspx#FoaIda1255029-22c4-4c18-9e90-356e92cbb795"><strong>Clean Hydrogen Manufacturing and Recycling RD&amp;D Activities</strong></a><strong>:</strong> DOE will also support American manufacturing of clean hydrogen equipment, including projects that improve efficiency and cost-effectiveness and support domestic supply chains for key components, through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s Clean Hydrogen Manufacturing Initiative. DOE is also launching Clean Hydrogen Technology Recycling Research, Development, and Demonstration activities, to fund innovative approaches to increase the reuse and recycling of clean hydrogen technologies.</li></ul>



<p>These Requests for Information will gather feedback from stakeholders and communities on future implementation and priorities for DOE to consider as it moves forward with maximizing the benefits of the historic clean hydrogen programs in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br><br>To further support DOE’s Hydrogen Shot to reduce the cost of clean hydrogen by 80% to $1 for one kilogram in one decade, last week DOE <a href="https://www.energy.gov/fecm/articles/us-department-energy-announces-28-million-develop-clean-hydrogen">announced</a> $28 million for R&amp;D and front-end engineering design projects to advance clean hydrogen in industrial uses, as well as the transportation and electricity sectors. DOE’s new <a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/fuelcells/h2-matchmaker"><strong>H2 Matchmaker</strong></a> resource is helping clean hydrogen producers, end-users, and others find opportunities to develop networks of production, storage, and transportation infrastructure. H2 Matchmaker displays a map using information received through an online form, which stakeholders can use to connect with others nearby.<br><br>The Administration’s <strong>Interagency Working Group on Coal and Power Plant Communities and Economic Revitalization</strong> is bringing together stakeholders from across the private sector, philanthropy, labor, and community-based organizations to catalyze new job opportunities for energy communities, including in clean hydrogen. For example, a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/15/readout-of-investment-roundtable-hosted-by-the-interagency-working-group-on-coal-and-power-plant-communities-and-economic-revitalization/">December roundtable</a> included discussion of efforts to reduce emissions and create jobs in the South Louisiana industrial corridor. The region is a finalist in the Economic Development Administration’s Build Back Better Regional Challenge. An initial grant will help them continue to plan their clean hydrogen cluster, and they are eligible to apply for a Phase 2 implementation grant.<br><br><strong>Launching “Buy Clean” Procurement</strong></p>



<p>The federal government is the largest purchaser in the world, with annual purchasing power of over $650 billion. To harness that power to support low-carbon, made in America materials, the Council on Environmental Quality and White House Office of Domestic Climate Policy are establishing the first-ever Buy Clean Task Force. As directed by the President’s December 2021 <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-catalyzing-americas-clean-energy-economy-through-federal-sustainability/">executive order</a> on federal sustainability, the Task Force will promote use of construction materials with lower embodied emissions and pollutants across their lifecycle—including each stage of the manufacturing process.</p>



<p>Other members include the Departments of Defense, Energy, and Transportation; the Environmental Protection Agency; the General Services Administration; and the White House Office of Management and Budget. The Task Force, which will continue to expand, is convening to develop recommendations on:</p>



<ul><li>Identifying materials, such as steel and concrete, as well as pollutants to prioritize for consideration in Federal procurement and federally funded projects</li><li>Increasing the transparency of embodied emissions through supplier reporting, including incentives and technical assistance to help domestic manufacturers better report and reduce embodied emissions</li><li>Launching pilot programs to boost federal procurement of clean construction materials&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>With the Buy Clean Task Force now established, the federal government is at the leading edge of using public procurement to increase demand for cleanly manufactured materials, along with states including California, Colorado, Minnesota, New York, and Washington.</p>



<p>Buy Clean efforts are already well underway at the General Services Administration (GSA), which manages a nationwide federal real estate portfolio and oversees approximately $75 billion in annual contracts. Over the past year, GSA has actively engaged stakeholders to learn and adopt best practices for reducing embodied emissions of buildings and materials. Today, GSA <a href="https://www.gsa.gov/about-us/newsroom/news-releases/gsa-announces-actions-to-reduce-emissions-from-building-materials-02152022">is issuing Requests for Information</a> (RFIs) focused on concrete and asphalt. In the coming weeks, GSA will use the RFI responses to shape the launch of <strong>national low-carbon concrete and sustainable asphalt standards for Land Port of Entry projects funded by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. </strong>This groundbreaking effort may include requiring Environmental Product Declarations (disclosing lifecycle impacts) and the use of concrete with at least 20% lower global warming potential, whenever available.</p>



<p>The Department of Transportation (DOT) is announcing new efforts to support <strong>use of low-carbon materials in federal transportation projects</strong>. A new pilot program will target key products and services to increase use of Environmental Product Declarations and incentivize acquisition of low-carbon materials. Additionally, DOT is standing up a Department-wide Embodied Carbon Working Group to assess and implement actions to reduce lifecycle emissions of construction materials used in transportation infrastructure.</p>



<p>The Administration is also bringing together large corporate purchasers to Buy Clean. At COP26, President Biden launched the <strong>First Movers Coalition</strong>, with 34 companies valued at $6 trillion—the biggest demand signal in history for innovation across hard-to-abate sectors, including heavy industry. Led by the State Department through the U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate and the World Economic Forum, and supported by the Departments of Commerce and Energy, the First Movers Coalition is making clean purchasing commitments, beginning with steel, shipping, trucking, and aviation. Today, the Administration is announcing plans to <strong>expand the First Movers Coalition to cover four additional sectors in 2022: aluminum, cement, chemicals, and carbon removal.</strong><br><br>The Administration is also <strong>mobilizing investment in the production of clean technologies</strong> by the Department of Energy, including the Loan Programs Office, the Department of Commerce, and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, as well as through a partnership between the First Movers Coalition and the Breakthrough Energy Catalyst. The First Movers Coalition will recruit additional companies and launch challenge competitions for suppliers to provide the breakthrough technologies that members have committed to purchase.<br><br><strong>Using Trade Policy to Reward Clean Manufacturing<br></strong><br>In October, the United States and the European Union <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/10/31/fact-sheet-the-united-states-and-european-union-to-negotiate-worlds-first-carbon-based-sectoral-arrangement-on-steel-and-aluminum-trade/">announced</a> their commitment to negotiate the <strong>world’s first emissions-based sectoral arrangement on steel and aluminum trade</strong> by 2024. Following on that announcement, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai, and senior White House officials are continuing to work with European Union counterparts on this unprecedented effort—never before have two global partners aligned their trade policies to confront the threats of climate change and global market distortions, ensuring that trade works to solve the challenges of the 21st century.<br><br>Together, the United States and European Union are working to restrict access to their markets for dirty steel and limit access to countries that dump steel in both markets, contributing to worldwide over-supply. The arrangement will be open to any interested country that wishes to join and meets criteria for restoring market orientation and reducing trade in high-emissions steel and aluminum products. It will thus drive investment in green steel and aluminum production in the United States, Europe, and around the world, ensuring a competitive U.S. steel and aluminum industry for decades to come.<br><br><strong>Responsibly Advancing CCUS Technologies</strong></p>



<p>Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Sequestration (CCUS) refers to technologies that remove carbon pollution from point sources like smokestacks, or from the ambient air, and permanently store the carbon. In factories, CCUS can reduce emissions from chemical reactions and high-temperature processes that are difficult and expensive to electrify. The best scientific analyses also find that to achieve a net-zero economy, we will need to remove carbon pollution that has already been released in the atmosphere. While CCUS can be an important tool in tackling the climate crisis, the benefits and impacts of potential projects vary significantly—requiring careful planning and oversight to ensure deployment is safe, equitable, and environmentally sound.<br><br>To help federal agencies advance CCUS responsibly, today <strong>the Council on Environmental Quality is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2022/02/15/ceq-issues-new-guidance-to-responsibly-develop-carbon-capture-utilization-and-sequestration/">issuing CCUS guidance</a>.</strong> This guidance, called for in the bipartisan USE IT Act, builds on CEQ’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2021/06/30/council-on-environmental-quality-delivers-report-to-congress-on-steps-to-advance-responsible-orderly-and-efficient-development-of-carbon-capture-utilization-and-sequestration/">June 2021 CCUS report</a> and addresses issues including:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Sound and transparent environmental reviews for CCUS projects</li><li>Incorporation of environmental justice and equity considerations to protect overburdened communities from any direct, indirect, and cumulative impacts</li><li>Meaningful public engagement and Tribal consultations from early in the process</li><li>Opportunities to create good-paying, union jobs and training programs</li><li>Life cycle analyses of carbon capture and utilization (CCU) and carbon dioxide removal (CDR) projects</li></ul>



<p>As agencies prepare to implement more than $12 billion in CCUS investments provided by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, this guidance will promote projects informed by community perspectives and aligned with climate, public health, and economic goals.<br><br>To further support responsible deployment:</p>



<ul><li>The Environmental Protection Agency is developing proposed rule revisions to <strong>strengthen the Greenhouse Gas Reporting Program to improve transparency on CCUS activities.</strong> This Program collects and publishes annual greenhouse gas data from large industrial sources, and the proposed updates would add reporting requirements for direct air capture and carbon storage.</li><li>To <strong>train a racially diverse, highly skilled generation of engineers and scientists for carbon management roles</strong>, DOE is announcing $5 million for university training and research projects, including $2 million for Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) and other Minority Serving Institutions (MSIs).</li><li>The Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council and its member agencies are working together to facilitate <strong>collaborative CCUS project reviews</strong>.</li><li>The Department of the Interior is working to <strong>establish safeguards for geologic sequestration</strong> on federally managed lands and is developing new regulations for geologic sequestration in the outer continental shelf as required under the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting Equitable Innovation Across the Industrial Sector</strong><br><br>Supporting the industrial sector to achieve net-zero emissions will provide benefits to communities across the country. To ensure that innovations in this sector meet the needs of diverse stakeholders, the Administration is launching a <strong>new Initiative for Interdisciplinary Industrial Decarbonization Research</strong>. Led by the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), this Initiative will bring together social scientists, engineering and physical scientists, community groups, industry, government, and other stakeholders. As a first step, OSTP is convening a workshop to get advice from social science thought leaders about the research agenda needed to support rapid, widespread industrial decarbonization. This research will help build the consensus necessary to ensure a just transition to clean industry, with new, good-paying jobs for American workers and health and economic benefits for communities.<br><br>To identify and catalyze the next generation of breakthroughs, DOE’s Advanced Manufacturing Office is working to establish the <strong>Industrial Technology Innovation Advisory Committee (ITIAC)</strong>. This federal advisory committee will bring together a diverse cross-section of the industrial sector to find viable decarbonization pathways that will equitably benefit the industrial workforce and surrounding communities. DOE has also issued a <a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/amo/articles/department-energy-seeks-input-technology-pathways-decarbonize-americas-industrial"><strong>Request for Information on Industrial Decarbonization</strong></a>. This RFI will provide insights on emerging technologies for industry to demonstrate or adopt, including for clean production of iron and steel, cement, chemicals, and food and beverages. The Advanced Manufacturing Office will use this information to shape priorities for reducing industrial emissions and increasing competitiveness.<br><br>Additionally, DOE is helping manufacturers optimize use of energy and materials while training the workforce of the future through its Industrial Assessment Centers—which provide no-cost energy assessments conducted by university-based teams of engineering students and faculty. <strong>Through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, DOE will expand the Industrial Assessment Centers program</strong> by offering specialized training to staff and students and increasing access to innovation and workforce development opportunities, particularly in disadvantaged communities. These actions build on a year of progress—in 2021, DOE’s Advanced Manufacturing Office <a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/amo/articles/amo-year-review-clean-energy-future-made-america">invested</a> more than $332 million in industrial technical assistance, education and workforce development, and R&amp;D at every stage of the supply chain.<br><br>The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is also partnering with manufacturers through the ENERGY STAR program, which challenges and supports industrial plants in improving energy efficiency and reducing greenhouse gas emissions. EPA is now <strong>expanding ENERGY STAR by incorporating carbon intensity metrics </strong>for certain industries. Going forward, EPA will continue to increase ENERGY STAR’s focus on ambitious emissions reductions that support net-zero goals across the industrial sector.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
