<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 10:20:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Releases Report on Native American Voting&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-report-on-native-american-voting-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris Announces Additional Steps in Response to the to the President’s Executive Order to Promote Access to Voting&#160; Since their first days in office, President Biden and Vice President Harris have prioritized strengthening our democracy and taken steps to protect voters from the current efforts to suppress the vote and subvert our electoral&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Harris Announces Additional Steps in Response to the to the President’s Executive Order to Promote Access to Voting&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Since their first days in office, President Biden and Vice President Harris have prioritized strengthening our democracy and taken steps to protect voters from the current efforts to suppress the vote and subvert our electoral process.&nbsp;&nbsp;The unprecedented nature and scale of the present attacks on voting rights must be met with federal legislation, which is why the President and Vice President have repeatedly called for the Senate to pass the Freedom to Vote Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act. The President and Vice President have also forcefully called for changing Senate rules to prevent a minority of Senators from blocking action on this fundamental right from which all other rights flow.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congress still has the responsibility to act, but the President is committed to using every tool at his disposal to protect the sacred right to vote.&nbsp;&nbsp;On March 7, 2021, the 56th anniversary of Bloody Sunday, he signed an Executive Order on Promoting Access to Voting, directing an all-of-government effort to promote information about the voting process and to further the ability of all eligible Americans to participate in our democracy.&nbsp;&nbsp;That work is ongoing, and agencies will continue to develop ways to deliver non-partisan election information and enable eligible Americans to register and to vote.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>A key provision of the Executive Order on Promoting Access to Voting highlighted the unique trust responsibility that the Federal government has for Tribal Nations and Native communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;In light of this responsibility, President Biden directed the creation of an Interagency Steering Group on Native American Voting Rights, whose mission is to study the barriers Native voters face in casting their ballot and having those votes counted, and to recommend steps to mitigate or eliminate these barriers.&nbsp;&nbsp;For far too long, members of Tribal Nations and Native communities have faced unnecessary burdens when they attempt to exercise their sacred right to vote.&nbsp;&nbsp;Native voters often have to overcome language barriers, a lack of accessibility for voters with disabilities, cultural disrespect and outright hostility, geographically remote residences, and persistent poverty — conditions that have only been exacerbated by the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;&nbsp;State laws and local practices also present too many Native voters with undue impediments to full and fair exercise of the franchise, including barriers in receiving information about the voting process, discriminatory redistricting, and burdens in voter registration, voter identification, voting in person, and voting by mail.</p>



<p>The Steering Group held consultations with Tribal leaders and Native Americans across the country, and engaged in listening sessions with Native Hawaiians, organizations advocating for improved Tribal voting rights, and state and local election officials in jurisdictions with sizable Native populations.  These sessions revealed recurring, unnecessary, and unacceptable impediments to the franchise. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Tribal-Voting-Report-FINAL.pdf">The report released today </a>chronicles the barriers Native voters face and recommends actions for policymakers at every level to help break these barriers down.  To live up to the recommendations of the report, the Department of the Interior is taking the unique step of translating it into six Native languages that reflect the regional consultation structure: Navajo, Yup&#8217;ik, Ojibwe, Cherokee, Lakota, and Native Hawaiian.  The translations will be available in writing and by audio.  </p>



<p>A few key recommendations from the report include:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Congress should pass the Freedom to Vote Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act, which includes the Native American Voting Rights Act.&nbsp;&nbsp;States do not need to wait for Congress to take this action— they can and should pass legislation incorporating and building upon the protections in the Native American Voting Rights Act, as several states since 2017 have already done.</li><li>Federal, state, and local policymakers should institutionalize engagement of Tribal leaders and Native communities, including in ensuring that county and municipal election officials locate offices and polling places serving Native communities for convenience to Native voters, and staff those sites with well-trained, bilingual members of those communities.</li><li>The U.S. Postal Service should evaluate whether it can add routes, offices, and staff hours or personnel in areas serving Native communities, and should prioritize assigning postal addresses to homes on Tribal lands.</li><li>Government offices with significant presence serving Native communities should expeditiously offer their programs for state designation under the National Voter Registration Act, and state officials should accept those requests for designation.</li><li>Jurisdictions serving Native voters should ensure that they offer effective language assistance through adequate translation of materials in appropriate media, even when no statutory mandate compels them to do so.</li></ul>



<p>This important report is the product of an extensive effort across the Administration — and it is also just a beginning.&nbsp;&nbsp;There will be more to come in the weeks and months ahead, as agencies work with partners and allies to implement the report’s recommendations.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Agencies have also been working to implement other provisions of the President’s Executive Order on Promoting Access to Voting, offering nonpartisan information and opportunities to help eligible Americans participate.&nbsp;&nbsp;Those efforts will continue across the whole of government, with new actions rolling out as they are ready for release.&nbsp;&nbsp;A selection of recent developments from individual agencies follows:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The <strong>U.S.</strong> <strong>Small Business Administration</strong> formally requested designation by Michigan as a voter registration agency under the National Voter Registration Act, becoming the first federal agency to request designation in any state.  Designation would ensure that Americans seeking service from a designated District Office are offered convenient one-stop opportunities to register to vote at the same time.</li><li>The <strong>Department of Veterans Affairs </strong>launched a survey to over 12 million Veterans in a first-of-its-kind effort to better understand Veterans’ experience with the voter registration process, and to better assist Veterans in addressing and overcoming any challenges.  The Department also developed a website for Veterans with nonpartisan information about voter registration and elections at va.gov/vote: <a href="https://www.va.gov/initiatives/vote/?msclkid=4ee33ffaa97111ecaf6453e6663908f9">How Veterans Can Register To Vote | Veterans Affairs (va.gov)</a>.  And the Department announced that, by summer, it would launch a pilot program for VA Medical Centers and other offices in six states, with an eye to the geographic and demographic diversity of the Veteran population, seeking designation as a voter registration agency under the National Voter Registration Act.</li><li>The <strong>Department of the Interior</strong> announced that it is working with states to formally designate the Department-operated post-secondary Tribal institutions — Haskell Indian Nations University in Kansas and the Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute (SIPI) in New Mexico — as voter registration agencies under the National Voter Registration Act, facilitating voter registration opportunities for enrolled students and members of the community.  </li><li>With <strong>Treasury Department</strong> and IRS support, Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) sites throughout the country are assisting taxpayers with access to voting opportunities.  The VITA centers provide assistance to low-income taxpayers with their returns.  This year, over 450 VITA centers in 40 states have reported that they will provide information about voting opportunities.  The IRS has also placed voter registration information referring taxpayers to vote.gov in the Form 1040 Instructions both online and in print.</li><li>The <strong>National Institute of Standards and Technology</strong> at the Department of Commerce released a <a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.1273.pdf">report</a>examining barriers across the voting process for people with disabilities.  The report offers recommendations for state and local election officials, the federal government, and other non-governmental organizations to eliminate or mitigate those barriers.</li><li>The <strong>Office of Personnel Management</strong> issued <a href="https://chcoc.gov/content/executive-order-promoting-access-voting">guidance</a> to agencies to offer paid time off that will ensure that the thousands of federal employees in every state have time to vote and to serve in nonpartisan election-related capacities, including as volunteer poll workers.  The guidance amounts to a significant step in fulfilling the directive in the President’s Executive Order that the federal government should serve as a model employer in facilitating employees’ civic participation.</li><li>The <strong>Department of Justice</strong> is offering information and resources to individuals in federal custody to promote access to voting for those who remain eligible to vote while incarcerated or who will regain eligibility to vote upon their release. The Department also created an online resource for the public that connects them with state-specific information about registering and voting, details the Department’s enforcement of federal voting rights laws, and explains how to report potential violations.</li><li>The <strong>Department of Health and Human Services </strong>Health Resources and Services Administration issued <a href="https://bphc.hrsa.gov/programrequirements/scope/voter-requirements">guidance</a>for nearly 1,400 federally funded community health centers, with more than 14,000 service delivery sites providing primary care to nearly 29 million patients in underserved areas in every state across the country, clarifying the ways in which those health centers may support voter registration efforts.</li><li>At the <strong>Department of Housing and Urban Development</strong>, the Office of Public and Indian Housing <a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/PIH/documents/PIH_announcement020922.pdf">wrote</a> to more than 3,000 public housing authorities managing approximately 1.2 million public housing units, explaining the ways in which grantees may support voter registration and information about the electoral process. The Office of Multifamily Housing <a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/PIH/documents/AllVotingCommunications.pdf">reminded</a> multifamily owners and agents of HUD-assisted properties about residents’ voting rights and opportunities to support their exercise of the franchise. And the Office of Field Policy and Management connected with local election officers and placed voter registration materials in all 10 HUD Regional Offices across the country. </li><li>The <strong>U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness</strong> released best practices election checklists—in five different languages—to be distributed to <a href="https://www.usich.gov/tools-for-action/step-by-step-voting-guide-for-people-experiencing-homelessness"><a href="https://www.usich.gov/tools-for-action/step-by-step-voting-guide-for-people-experiencing-homelessness">voters experiencing homelessness</a> and to <a href="https://www.usich.gov/tools-for-action/step-by-step-guide-for-homeless-service-providers-to-help-people-vote">service providers</a> who can help them register and vote. </a></li></ul>



<ul><li>The&nbsp;<strong>Department of Labor</strong>&nbsp;is providing guidance to state and local workforce officials on how they can work with state elections officials to designate American Job Centers, which provide employment, training, and career services to workers in every state, as voter registration agencies under the National Voter Registration Act. The Department’s guidance also clarifies which programs receiving federal workforce development funds could support nonpartisan voter registration efforts.</li><li>The&nbsp;<strong>Department of Agriculture</strong>&nbsp;Food and Nutrition Service issued letters to state agencies administering nutrition assistance programs to encourage the promotion of voter registration and non-partisan voting information.&nbsp;&nbsp;For state SNAP and WIC agencies, the letters remind states of their responsibilities under the National Voter Registration Act.</li><li>The&nbsp;<strong>Department of Education</strong>&nbsp;will send a letter next week to institutions of higher education highlighting their responsibilities under the Higher Education Act to make a good faith effort to distribute voter registration forms to the more than 19 million students enrolled in these institutions.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Department last reminded institutions of this requirement in 2013.&nbsp;&nbsp;The letter will also explain the conditions under which work-study funds may be used to support nonpartisan community service activity related to the electoral process.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea’s Ballistic Missile&#160;Launch</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-koreas-ballistic-missile-launch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States strongly condemns the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea (DPRK) &#160;for its test of a long-range ballistic missile. On March 10th, the United States Government publicly released information that the DPRK’s tests on February 26 and March 4, 2022 EST involved an Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) system. We noted that there would likely&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States strongly condemns the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea (DPRK) &nbsp;for its test of a long-range ballistic missile. On March 10<sup>th</sup>, the United States Government publicly released information that the DPRK’s tests on February 26 and March 4, 2022 EST involved an Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) system. We noted that there would likely be further tests in the future. The President and his national security team are assessing the situation in close coordination with our allies and partners.&nbsp; This launch is a brazen violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions and needlessly raises tensions and risks destabilizing the security situation in the region. This action demonstrates that the DPRK continues to prioritize its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs over the well-being of its people.&nbsp; We urge all countries to hold the DPRK accountable for such violations and call on the DPRK to come to the table for serious negotiations.&nbsp; The door has not closed on diplomacy, but Pyongyang must immediately cease its destabilizing actions.&nbsp;The United States will take all necessary measures to ensure the security of the American homeland and Republic of Korea and Japanese allies.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Deputy National Security Advisor for International Economics Daleep Singh on Russia’s Plans to Partially Re-Open Stock&#160;Market</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/statement-by-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-international-economics-daleep-singh-on-russias-plans-to-partially-re-open-stock-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What we’re seeing is a charade: a Potemkin market opening. After keeping its markets closed for nearly a month, Russia announced it will only allow 15% of listed shares to trade, foreigners are prohibited from selling their shares, and short selling in general has been banned. Meanwhile, Russia has made clear they are going to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>What we’re seeing is a charade: a Potemkin market opening. After keeping its markets closed for nearly a month, Russia announced it will only allow 15% of listed shares to trade, foreigners are prohibited from selling their shares, and short selling in general has been banned. Meanwhile, Russia has made clear they are going to pour government resources into artificially propping up the shares of companies that are trading. This is not a real market and not a sustainable model—which only underscores Russia’s isolation from the global financial system. The United States and our allies and partners will continue taking action to further isolate Russia from the international economic order as long it continues its brutal war against Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Brussels,&#160;Belgium</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/23/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-brussels-belgium/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 22:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1:43 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hi, everybody.&#160; Okay.&#160; We have National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan here.&#160; And he’s going to say a few words, take a couple of questions, and then I’ll take over after that and take any other questions you might have.&#160;&#160;Go ahead, Jake.&#160;MR. SULLIVAN:&#160; Hey, guys.&#160; So, we’re heading into a full day&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1:43 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We have National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan here.&nbsp; And he’s going to say a few words, take a couple of questions, and then I’ll take over after that and take any other questions you might have.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Jake.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; So, we’re heading into a full day tomorrow in Brussels.&nbsp; The President will start by meeting with the Secretary General to check signals, you know, get on the same page in terms of the agenda for the NATO Summit.&nbsp; And then he’ll be at the NATO Summit for three hours with his 29 fellow Allied leaders.&nbsp; So, it’ll be NATO with 30.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>NATO itself has not, as institution, been involved in the coordination or facilitation of security assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; It’s been individual members, individual Allies who have done that.&nbsp; The United States, obviously, providing a really significant amount of military equipment and weapons to Ukraine and also coordinating the supplies of Allies as well to facilitate their delivery.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it will be a subject of discussion at the summit &#8212; even though, institutionally, NATO is not engaged in it, how we make sure that we’re continuing to support Ukraine in its effort to defend itself, you know, will be a topic of conversation among the leaders while the President is in Brussels.<br>&nbsp;<br>They will also discuss the question of NATO’s force posture on the eastern flank.&nbsp; The leaders will ratify some of the decisions taken by defense ministers last week.&nbsp; We’ll have more to say on that tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But they’ll also task the military and political instruments of NATO to set out a longer-term game plan for what forces and capabilities are going to be required in those eastern flank countries &#8212; to be, ultimately, agreed at the Madrid Summit this summer &#8212; so that we’ve got a long-term footprint that is matched to the new security reality that’s been created both by Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine and by what’s happening in Belarus, including the fact that we’re seeing Russian forces and projecting Russian forces ending up in a posture where there is more of them more frequently on the territory of Belarus, and perhaps other capabilities as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that’ll be the NATO Summit piece of it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President will then have opportunity to meet with the G7 leaders, and they’ll issue a statement.&nbsp; And it will cover a range of issues.&nbsp; The G7 has been a central locus for sanctions coordination.&nbsp; It’s where many of the key elements of the sanctions architecture were agreed and have been &#8212; have been &#8212; the details have been worked through.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the G7 leaders tomorrow will agree on an initiative to coordinate on sanctions enforcement so that Russian efforts to evade the sanctions or other countries’ effort to help Russia evade the sanctions can be dealt with effectively and in a coordinated fashion.&nbsp; And there’ll be, you know, a specific example of what that means discussed at the meeting and rolled out tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, we, the United States, will announce a package of sanctions designations tomorrow that relate both to political figures, oligarchs &#8212; so, individual designations as well as entities &#8212; and that’ll be released tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>The G7 will also cover a number of other critical issues, including the global energy picture and the global food security picture, and some of the other knock-on and spillover effects of the conflict in Ukraine on the global economy and on the livelihoods of the citizens of our countries and people all around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then the President will have the opportunity to have a signals check with President Michel, the President of the European Council, before he goes into a European Council meeting where he will have the opportunity to discuss the refugee and humanitarian situation that has been fast evolving over the course of the past month since Russia&#8217;s latest military action got underway.<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;ll have the chance to talk about next steps on sanctions with the European Union.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll have the chance to talk about democratic resilience and supporting civil society and journalists and other instruments of strong democracies in many of the partner countries of the European Union in the east.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there will be a few other elements to the discussion that he will have with European leaders, including China and how we get coordinated on our approach vis-à-vis China, especially as it relates to China&#8217;s involvement in the crisis in Ukraine &#8212; because the EU has a summit with China coming up on April 1st, so just a few days after the President will be engaging them in in Brussels.<br>&nbsp;<br>The last thing is, throughout the day, the President will obviously consult on potential contingencies: the possibility of cyberattacks by Russia against the United States or other Allied and partner countries, the possibility of the use of chemical or biological weapons in Ukraine, the possibility of escalation in the conflict in other ways.&nbsp; And as I discussed yesterday at the podium, how to deal with the rhetoric and the commentary coming out of Russia on this whole question of the potential use of nuclear weapons.<br>&nbsp;<br>I said yesterday that we haven&#8217;t seen anything that&#8217;s made us adjust our posture &#8212; our nuclear posture, but it&#8217;s, of course, something that we will have to continue to stay in close consultation with Allies and partners on, as well as communicate directly to the Russians on.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, let me stop there in terms of what tomorrow looks like, and I&#8217;m happy to take your questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;Can I ask, on energy sanctions or energy actions, what &#8212; you mentioned this yesterday &#8212; what is on the table in terms of some sort of deal or anything between the U.S. and the EU to try to reduce reliance on Russian energy?<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, European partners have been more hesitant to enact the same measures that the UK, the U.S., Canada, and others have because they rely more heavily on it, in particular on natural gas.&nbsp; Is there anything you&#8217;re going to discuss or announce on that?&nbsp; Is there deal in place?&nbsp; What can you tell us?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, this is a substantial topic of conversation.&nbsp; A major priority for both the President and his European allies is to reduce the dependence of Europe on Russian gas.&nbsp; Full stop.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the practical roadmap for how to do that &#8212; what steps have to be taken, what the United States can contribute, what Europe has to do itself &#8212; this has been the subject of intense back-and-forth over the course of the past few days and weeks.&nbsp; And we will have more to say on this subject specifically on Friday, particularly with the European Commission and the European Commission President, von der Leyen.&nbsp; So he&#8217;ll discuss it tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But in terms of further things to say publicly on the subject, I&#8217;m not going to preview it today.&nbsp; But you can zero in on Friday morning for more news on that, so stay tuned.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say what the U.S. will tell its European partners what it wants to see from China or what it hopes Europe will seek from China?&nbsp; In other words, what is the latest in terms of what you&#8217;re &#8212; what you perceive to be China&#8217;s involvement or lack of involvement in Russia&#8217;s war and the trajectory, I guess?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, as I said yesterday, we have not actually seen or do not have evidence of the actual provision of military equipment for use in Ukraine from China to Russia.&nbsp; But we are monitoring that closely and, of course, our European allies are as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve sent a clear message to China about the implications and consequences of any such provision of military equipment.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re on the same page with our European allies on that, and we expect that they will convey similar messages in their dealings at the highest levels with the Chinese government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The same thing goes for systematic efforts to undermine, weaken, or circumvent the sanctions regime that we have put in place.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve communicated on that as well to China, and we expect similar communication by the European Union and individual European countries.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also on the same page in that regard.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the G7 sanctions enforcement initiative ensuring that there isn&#8217;t systematic sanctions busting, that&#8217;s not specifically about China, but it will apply to every significant economy and the decisions that any of those economies take to try in an intentional and active way to undermine or weaken the sanctions that we put in place.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just follow up on the energy issue?&nbsp; The idea of reducing energy dependence sounds like a medium- to long-term question.&nbsp; Is the United States &#8212; is the President going to be pressing the &#8212; his European allies to do more in the immediate term &#8212; a ban on oil, a ban on gas?&nbsp; A ban on coal has been raised.&nbsp; I mean, is &#8212; and understanding that their reluctance is because of their greater dependence, is the message from the United States going to be, “You guys need to act now”?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, I think it&#8217;s important to note that the United States itself is acting now to help Europe on the issue of Russ- &#8212; dependence on Russian gas, diverting cargoes to help increase the supply of gas &#8212; U.S. LNG &#8212; to Europe in the immediate term.&nbsp; And I think you can expect that the U.S. will look for ways to increase LNG supplies, surge LNG supplies to Europe not just over the course of years, but over the course of months as well.&nbsp; Of course, that amount will grow over time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our focus now is not on &#8212; over the course of the next couple of days &#8212; is not on a particular sanctions move we&#8217;re asking Europe to make on this.&nbsp; It is, rather: How do we put in place a strategy that is not just a long-term strategy but is a short-term strategy to help reduce dependence and to create more freedom and flexibility then for different policy choices by the Europeans?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I put a finer point on the China question?&nbsp; You &#8212; they have a preexisting economic relationship &#8212; China and Russia.&nbsp; Are your concerns about an incremental growth in that relationship as a financial relationship?&nbsp; Is status quo okay? Could you maybe elaborate a little bit more about those concerns?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; What do you mean?&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I&#8217;m not sure I fully &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; China and Russia have a preexisting financial relationship: trade.&nbsp; Is it okay if that trade continues as is? Or are you concerned about incremental change in that &#8212; or growth in that kind of trade to avoid sanctions?&nbsp; Can you put a little finer point on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I mean, just three sort of examples that I think will give a little bit more flavor to the kinds of things we&#8217;re looking out for.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One is attempting to backfill in response to the export controls that we have imposed &#8212; Chinese companies or companies from other countries choose to backfill.&nbsp; We obviously have tools available to us to ensure that backfilling can&#8217;t happen.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second is, from the point of view of payment settlements and financial sanctions, systematic efforts, industrial-scale efforts to try to reorient the settlement of financial payments and so forth.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that, in coordination with our G7 allies, we will look at and respond to.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then third, of course, is the kinds of non-steady state, new efforts to try to seize opportunities that have been created by the reduction in commerce between Europe, Japan, and other countries because of the sanctions not just with China but across the board.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that we will look at as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, I&#8217;ve been clear that we&#8217;re not going to lay out in specifics the particular countermeasures we would take, the particular steps we’d impose.&nbsp; We&#8217;re communicating that privately to countries.&nbsp; You know, I don&#8217;t want to use the microphone to threaten; I just want to say this is something we&#8217;re vigilant about and that we have tools at our disposal to deal with in coordination with the G7 and with other countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question on chemical and biological.&nbsp; Has the U.S. seen evidence that Russia has moved or deployed any of these weapons in a way to threaten Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any intelligence to share with you today on this subject.&nbsp; The main thing that we&#8217;re looking at right now is the deliberate drumbeat of misinformation, propaganda, and lies on this subject that has all the markers of a precursor to them actually using these weapons.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is the U.S. assessment based entirely on that drumbeat of propaganda, or is it also based on movements of weapons?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a very fair question.&nbsp; All I can tell you right now is I can&#8217;t comment further on the intelligence picture on this today.&nbsp; To the extent that I&#8217;m in a position to share further information related to our intelligence, I&#8217;ll be sure to do so.&nbsp; But right now, I don&#8217;t have anything else to share.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, was there anything in your conversations with Chinese officials last week or President &#8212; or the President&#8217;s conversations with President Xi that left you at all reassured that the Chinese would not provide weapons or other assistance to the Russians?&nbsp; Or do you &#8212; are you more concerned after those conversations?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I will beg your forgiveness in advance by being sort of intentionally vague in my answer to your question. &nbsp;And the reason is because this is not the kind of circumstance where you just kind of feel reassurance.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to require constant vigilance, constant monitoring.&nbsp; We will have to see what happens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, all I can really say to you is that coming out of that conversation, we have not seen the Chinese government move forward on the supply of weapons, but it&#8217;s something we&#8217;re watching every day.&nbsp; And I really can&#8217;t characterize my level of comfort with that out one way or the other; it&#8217;s something we just have to maintain vigilance about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a question on the EU.&nbsp; Do you want to see the European Union &#8212; does the administration want to see the European Union spend more on defense &#8212; such as what President Macron has suggested, that they should become &#8212; you know, borrowing more money, spending more, bolstering its defense spending to this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; When President Biden and President Macron met in Rome in October, they put out a joint statement.&nbsp; And one of the points in that statement was support across the board for increased European capability and investment in the strength of their defense tools and the modernization of their defense establishments with one very important principle underlying that, and that is complementarity with NATO.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, all of this work that&#8217;s being done by individual European countries, by the European Union, this is something that contributes overall to the health and strength of the transatlantic Alliance so long it is &#8212; it is done in complementarity with NATO.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should Russia still be part of the G20?&nbsp; Any concern, any talk about that?&nbsp; There are some countries that have voiced some &#8212; some opinions on that.&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s a financial leadership meeting in Washington of the G20 come maybe April.&nbsp; Should Russia be a &#8212; should Russia representatives attend that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So what I said yesterday, which I&#8217;ll repeat today, is that we don&#8217;t believe it can be business as usual with Russian international institutions.&nbsp; But in terms of specific answers to that kind of question for the G20 or other international organizations, we want to have the opportunity to consult with our Allies and partners around the world, including our G20 partners before I opine on that question publicly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple.&nbsp; On &#8212; if you&#8217;re looking at the sanctions and the upcoming planned sanctions that you plan to announce, on &#8212; say, on like a scale of 1 to 10, or do it on however measure you would like to &#8212; like, what do you have left?&nbsp; Like, where would you be at if 10 were ratcheted up to the highest degree?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what else could you do?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, how much room to grow do you have?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So I &#8212; I would ask you guys, I guess, two &#8212; two questions &#8212; two things.&nbsp; The first is: In terms of an analysis of the macroeconomic impact of what we have done and then, you know, what additional tools are in the toolkit, Daleep &#8212; who is on the trip, and we&#8217;ll get you with him in a backgrounder so you have the opportunity to speak with him directly on this &#8212; is the expert and then to speak also with the Treasury Department.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s one thing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Because I think this is one where really getting down granularly into what hit has the Russian economy taken, in what way, and then, you know, what are other things that we could do over time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the second thing I would ask you is to consider this not just like we&#8217;re firing bullets out of the chamber of a gun and we fired X number and there&#8217;s Y number left.&nbsp; I think it’s the wrong way to think about it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we&#8217;ve done on the financial sanctions and the export controls is create a vise that is squeezing harder and harder with each passing day and week.&nbsp; And then, as we see the impact and we see efforts to evade, we think about adjustments we need to make to ensure that vise continues to tighten.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So our theory on this was never: Every three days we fire another bullet.&nbsp; It was: Put the major pieces in place, look for ways to continue to tighten the screws, and then consider other means as we go forward.&nbsp; And, of course, we will do that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I can&#8217;t characterize this question of what we&#8217;ve done and what we have left precisely, in part because we don&#8217;t think of it quite in the terms that your question posed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; But on &#8212; on the kind of macro picture, which is a kind of &#8212; the way to back into an answer to your question, I&#8217;d ask you to speak with Daleep.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about Friday?&nbsp; There&#8217;s obviously a big gaping hole in the President&#8217;s schedule.&nbsp; Is he going to go close to the border?&nbsp; Is he going to meet with &#8212; is he going to tour refugees &#8212; with refugees?&nbsp; What &#8212; what else can you tell us about Friday?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let Karine talk to you about Friday when &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When do you think we may see &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; when the time is right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; JCPOA updated?&nbsp; And to what extent that will be discussed on this trip during this week?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So he&#8217;ll have the chance to talk to our E3 European partners &#8212; UK, France, Germany; four members of the P5+1; as well as the European Union, which plays this important coordinating role in the P5+1.<br>&nbsp;<br>Where things stand now is we’ve made progress over the course of the past several weeks.&nbsp; There are still some issues left.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working on those issues.&nbsp; It&#8217;s unclear whether this will come to closure or not.&nbsp; But, you know, we&#8217;re diligently trying to drive the diplomacy to a place where we have put Iran&#8217;s nuclear program back in a box.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you sure that a deal could put more money or more freedom to use money in the hands of Iran, and that, in turn, could be a lifeline to Russia&#8217;s economy?&nbsp; Can you talk about the sort of triangulation of that here?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; First, Russia posed both publicly and privately this proposition that Iran should somehow be entirely carved out of the sanctions regime, which was not accepted by any of the parties.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So the only question of sanctions as it relates to Russia in the context of the JCPOA is about sanctions on Iran being able to, for example, cooperate with the Russian Atomic Energy authorities to ship out their enriched uranium.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we feel confident that if we were to get back into the JCPOA on a compliance-for-compliance basis.&nbsp; It would not create a significant economic opportunity for Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we would take whatever necessary enforcement steps to ensure that that was the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, how much visibility do you have into the status of Russian-Ukrainian negotiations right now?&nbsp; And how much faith do you have in the Russians being a trustworthy negotiation partner in the first place?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I will point out that Russia has not been trustworthy in its public statements about its intentions with respect to Ukraine for months.&nbsp; So, we take everything that they say at the negotiating table or from their podiums with a very large grain of salt.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are in very consistent communication with our Ukrainian friends.&nbsp; And President Biden speaks to President Zelenskyy on this issue. &nbsp;President Biden also speaks with the Presidents of France and Germany, the Prime Minister of Israel, the President of Turkey, others who have been actively engaged in discussions with President Putin and President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re actively engaged in monitoring the ongoing diplomacy, though the United States is not directly at the table or directly playing any kind of mediating or brokering role.&nbsp; And we will see how things unfold.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our basic principle is: This is about Ukraine&#8217;s future, Ukraine&#8217;s destiny, and therefore it is up to Ukraine and the Ukrainian leadership, the Ukrainian people to make their own judgments about any agreement that they would reach with the Russians.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you comment on the transfer of air defense systems to Ukraine.&nbsp; Is that moving forward?&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve talked about the S-300 system &#8212; things like that.&nbsp; There’s a large shuffle going on.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the latest on that?&nbsp; When could Ukraine expect to see those systems in their country?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We feel good about the progress that we are making with respect to air defense systems.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to get into further details on that because I don&#8217;t want to compromise the ongoing effort to ensure that Ukraine gets the tools it needs to protect itself from the sky.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you confirm that NATO &#8212; NATO Allied countries want to extend the contract of the Secretary General, Stoltenberg, and what the President&#8217;s view &#8212; possibly through September of 2023 &#8212; and what the President&#8217;s view on that might be?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President thinks very highly of Secretary General Stoltenberg.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve developed a relationship of trust.&nbsp; And Pres- &#8212; Secretary General Stoltenberg has played an instrumental role in helping secure the powerful unity you&#8217;ve seen at NATO through this crisis.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have anything for you on the question of his tenure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say whether he wants to see continuity there and not sort of breaking this up in the middle of this conflict?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, all I will say is: We think that Jens Stoltenberg has been doing a fantastic job and, day in and day out, has played a critical leadership role for NATO.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you&#8217;ll forgive me if for today, on this plane flight, I will add nothing to that other than our unreserved view that that Stoltenberg is a real asset to the Alliance.&nbsp; And then, you know, the leaders will have the chance to talk tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President plan to send additional U.S. troops to Eastern Europe?&nbsp; And if so, how many?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, we don&#8217;t have any plans for announcements of specific additional units to move to Eastern Europe at this time.&nbsp; But the President is constantly reviewing plans for near-term adjustments to our force posture in all the eastern flank countries, depending on how things develop.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s not a today thing or a tomorrow thing, but it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s a matter of consistent reassessment.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know if any additional troop deployments will be announced on this trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that’s &#8212; but what about the broader &#8212; the long-term of NATO force deployment along the eastern &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, we have &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that &#8212; that could involve U.S. troops to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Two aspects of this will be discussed tomorrow.&nbsp; One is the immediate need to shore up on a rotational basis those Allies on the southern end of the eastern flank, and that will be discussed tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then the second is, across the entire eastern flank, as we head to the Madrid Summit, what decisions does NATO have to take for longer-term force posture adjustments?&nbsp; And of course, some of those will involve U.S. forces.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this trip, what are you looking to hear from other EU and the UK leaders?&nbsp; You’ve talked about trying to reduce Europe&#8217;s energy &#8212; energy dependence on Russian oil and gas.&nbsp; What else would you like to hear from the leaders that the President will be meeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think what we would like to hear is that the resolve and unity that we&#8217;ve seen for the past month will endure for as long as it takes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s at a topline.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Then how that translates specifically: that countries follow through on the commitments they&#8217;ve made with respect to the supply of military equipment and add to those commitments as Ukraine&#8217;s needs evolve over time; that countries remain fully committed to enforcing the sanctions on the books and, to the extent we find additional targets that can help impose pressure on Putin, we do &#8212; we move in a joint way on that; that we all work together to do our part on the humanitarian element of this crisis, both the suffering inside Ukraine and the refugee crisis outside Ukraine &#8212; here, Europe has really stepped up in a huge way, and it&#8217;s the United States that will be coming with additional commitments on both humanitarian assistance and refugees tomorrow; and that NATO, as an Alliance, puts its money where its mouth is when it comes to actually defending every inch of NATO territory, and that means following through on the necessary capabilities and contributions to defend the eastern flank and to defend the whole Alliance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s what tomorrow is all about across an integrated set of three meetings.&nbsp; And we think that we will have a substantial set of outcomes that will emerge by the end of the day when, after many hours, the President will emerge to address all of you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does President Biden plan to have a short bilat with Turkish President Erdoğan on the sidelines of NATO?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a bilat scheduled with President Erdoğan.&nbsp; But you know how these things go.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll be hanging out at NATO Headquarters, and I expect he&#8217;ll have the chance to have brief conversations with a number of leaders.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the U.S. position on giving planes to Ukraine &#8212; remains the same?&nbsp; Or are you looking to discuss that if the Polish, for instance, bring it up?&nbsp; Is it still your belief that it should not be NATO giving planes to Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; There’s been no change in our position on the MiG-29s.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And have you guys formally shot down the idea of a peacekeeping force that the Poles have raised?&nbsp; Or is that something that is still at least open for discussion from the U.S. perspective?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; President Biden&#8217;s been very clear that we&#8217;re not sending U.S. soldiers to fight Russian soldiers in Ukraine.&nbsp; I have not, myself, had the opportunity, nor has President Biden had the opportunity to consult with his Polish counterpart, or I with mine, on exactly what they have in mind.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ll &#8212; we&#8217;ll have that conversation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But our position, with respect to deployment of U.S. forces in Ukraine, has been clear from the start, and it remains unchanged.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s a difference between saying U.S. forces shouldn&#8217;t be deployed and NATO forces should not be deployed into Ukraine.&nbsp; Do you have the same red line about forces under a NATO banner from other NATO countries going into Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think before I opine on what is a hypothetical or theoretical question like that, I think it&#8217;s important for us to get the opportunity to hear more about something we&#8217;ve just seen in the press, and then we can speak to it.<br>&nbsp;<br>All right.&nbsp; Thank you, guys.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jake.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now you get to tell us all about the refugees in the Friday schedule.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Is that what you want me to talk about?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; No, Jake did a great job laying out tomorrow &#8212; NATO, EU, G7 meetings that the President will be &#8212; will be part of.<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, look, what I &#8212; what I can do is &#8212; you guys already have all of this &#8212; is say what happens when he leaves Brussels &#8212; right? &#8212; in a more broad stroke &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right, just because &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; and say what happens after Brussels in a more broad &#8212; broad stroke.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as you guys already know, he&#8217;s going to meet with President Duda once he leaves Brussels and goes to Poland to thank him for everything the people of Poland are doing and to discuss our coordinated humanitarian response to support the many Ukrainians who have been impacted by Putin&#8217;s war.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think Jake also talked about the President &#8212; where he will engage with U.S. troops who are now &#8212; who are now helping to defend NATO territory yesterday.&nbsp; He talked about that.&nbsp; And he will meet with experts involved in a humanitarian response.<br>&nbsp;<br>We talked about the speech that the President will be giving, but I won&#8217;t give any more further &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; His speech?&nbsp; I’m sorry, which?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We talked about that.&nbsp; The President is going to be giving a speech in Poland.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In Poland?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, we announced that probably a day or two ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so those are kind of &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; Michael, you got to keep up.&nbsp; You got to keep up.&nbsp; So, we talked &#8212; I’m just going to, like I said, talk about the broader strokes of things that he’s going to do tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Clearly, we’ll give more guidance on what Friday will look like.&nbsp; But for security purposes, we just want to keep it more broad and not go into details.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us an update on whether the President tested before this trip since Monday and what his most recent COVID test result was?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just any general update of other people who tested positive in the White House.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the President ha- &#8212; was tested yesterday, as Josh just mentioned, and as part of his regular testing cadence.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no change to the President&#8217;s testing cadence during his travel because he was not a close contact.<br>&nbsp;<br>He will be tested throughout the trip in alignment with the various entry and departure requirements for the countries he will be visiting.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, for context here, there&#8217;ll be no testing entry requirement for Brussel &#8212; testing requirement.&nbsp; There&#8217;ll be testing requirement for a Warsaw exit requirement for return to the U.S.<br>&nbsp;<br>As far as your question, so, since &#8212; when we&#8217;re talking about staff and all of those things that you just asked &#8212; so, since July, because of our commitment to transparency, we provide updates when any White House official tests positive for COVID-19 and with White House Medical Unit deems them as having had close contact with the President, Vice President, First Lady, and &#8212; or Second Gentleman.&nbsp; That will be up to the White House Medical Unit based on the criteria of the CDC.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, Jen, for example, shared her positive case yesterday, as she did in October, out of an abundance of transparency.<br>&nbsp;<br>If an individual does not meet this criteria that I just laid out, meaning they are not a close contact of our four principals, it would be up to the individual.&nbsp; This has been our policy since July.&nbsp; It hasn&#8217;t changed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us an update on whether you&#8217;re still considering any further releases of the SPR to deal with the current gas price?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new to share on that, on any new actions.&nbsp; But as the President has said previously, we&#8217;re going to continue to assess, and our government will take action as needed as evidenced &#8212; as evidenced by recent Strategic Petroleum Reserve releases that we announced not too long ago, and the &#8212; and announced International Energy Agency agreement &#8212; those two things that we announced probably, I don’t know, about a month ago &#8212; a couple weeks ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And acknowledging that there are other things on the go, has he made any decisions on when you will name a new Fed nominee?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you on the new Fed nominee.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Forgive me for having to ask.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; No, it’s a fair &#8212; it’s a &#8212; not a surprising ask.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President have any further reaction to yesterday here on the Sup- &#8212; on Ketanji Brown Jackson?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, as we noted, the President did watch some of &#8212; some of the &#8212; did watch some of the portions of yesterday&#8217;s hearing with Judge Jackson.<br>&nbsp;<br>And again, he couldn&#8217;t be more proud of her intellect, her grace, character, and the value of her experience.&nbsp; The country is seeing just how qualified Judge Jackson is and how she determines cases fairly based solely on the facts and the law, which is what the American people expect in a Supreme Court justice.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why she is endorsed by conservative judges, the Fraternal Order of Police, the International Association of Chiefs of Police, dozens of police chiefs, sheriffs, and 83 bipartisan former State Attorney Generals.&nbsp; Just today, 43 former federal prosecutors in Florida endorsed Judge Jackson.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, like we said yesterday, the President was also impressed with how she dismantled bad-faith conspiracy theories and that have &#8212; that have been fact checked by major media outlets and experts, like some of you all here, and moderates in both parties are now dismissing them for the fringe smears that they are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>She thoughtfully and thoroughly answered questions from senators for nearly 12 hours, as you all know, demonstrating the temperament required for a Supreme Court justice and showing the strength of her intellect and character.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess &#8212; I just wanted to follow up really quickly. Does he have any reaction to the kind of questioning that Senator Cruz, Senator Hawley, Senator Cotton &#8212; I mean, you know, a range of them &#8212; did?&nbsp; What did he think of their questions?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to piggyback on that &#8212; just the critical race theory as well &#8212; you know, theory and all of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let me talk more broadly about your point, Michael, about the overall attacks.&nbsp; Look &#8212; so, you know, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re focused on the full Senate.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; She&#8217;s been working hard to earn support since day one.&nbsp; She has &#8212; since the day she was &#8212; the President named her, she&#8217;s met with 45 senators, and she&#8217;s going to meet with more after.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you&#8217;ve heard Republicans react well to her qualifications and her neutral methodology based in the facts of law &#8212; law and facts &#8212; based in the law and facts.&nbsp; And so, I want to be really clear: Our strategy doesn&#8217;t depend on Josh Hawley or any of the other senators who attacked her.<br>&nbsp;<br>On the critical race theory, you know, she actually spoke to this yesterday as well &#8212; Judge Jackson.&nbsp; And to quote her, she said, when it comes to critical race theory, “never been something I&#8217;ve studied or relied on.”&nbsp; She applies the facts and the law when making decisions on the bench, not academic theory.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I also saw PolitiFact already found an attack about base &#8212; about &#8212; based on this “false” after a senator claims she considered it when judging cases.&nbsp; In comments to students about academic subjects that may &#8212; that they may find interesting, she mentioned critical race theory in a list of other academic topics such as administrative law, constitutional law, negotiations, and contracts.<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, I would refer you back to what she said herself about that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I guess the questions is: Did he think the questions from the senators that we mentioned about critical race theory and the other issues &#8212; the, you know, pornography, and whatever &#8212; did he think those questions were inappropriate, racist, whatever &#8212; however you want to say?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, it’s basically what I said, Michael.&nbsp; He&#8217;s very proud &#8212; he&#8217;s very proud of how she handled herself yesterday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That doesn’t answer &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I think &#8212; I think it does.&nbsp; We &#8212; I just told you he watched &#8212; he watched yesterday, and I just told you his reaction.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to go &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to break it down &#8212; break it down specific to details.&nbsp; I just laid out how he felt and why she was chosen and her bipartisan support that she&#8217;s getting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us more of a preview of the humanitarian assistance that we might expect to see?&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to go to Poland.&nbsp; Polish leaders have been pretty clear about their breaking point.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to presumably see some evidence of that.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;re not going to get ahead of the President, but can you give us some &#8212; should Americans expect a more open-door policy to get these &#8212; some of these folks into the U.S.?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look &#8212; you know, again, he&#8217;s going to announce further American contributions to respond to the growing flow of refugees and to the coordinated humanitarian response to ease the suffering of civilians inside Ukraine, but I don&#8217;t have anything further to preview.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, we are surging humanitarian assistance to countries neighboring Ukraine who are providing them with support.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve kind of laid out what we&#8217;ve done in the past &#8212; these past couple weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with Poland, to help them &#8212; some kind of relief package for Poland to help them deal with &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not &#8212; I mean, you even said it in your question.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President, but this is something that&#8217;s coming forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just &#8212; last time on this one, to follow up on Michael&#8217;s point.&nbsp; You know, he&#8217;s served on this panel for many years, like many of these confirmation fights.&nbsp; Like just generally &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t want to respond to any specific senator &#8212; how does he think that these Republican senators have comported themselves?&nbsp; Not her reaction to that, but the senators themselves.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics on that at all.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to lay out what I said already and how he saw her performance, which is what is the most important thing is &#8212; how Judge Jackson performed yesterday.&nbsp; He&#8217;s very proud of her.&nbsp; We feel very confident in her being the next justice on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything further to read out to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any lists of bilats or anything you can share on what meetings he might have during this trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that last part.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you &#8212; can you share anything about what bilateral meetings he might have on this trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; Jake just talked about that.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; at least when he was asked about Turkey &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything else to preview on a bilat meeting.&nbsp; And just to reiterate what Jake said &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; which is, you know, at these type of events &#8212; the NATO in particular and the EU and G7 &#8212; you never know what might happen.&nbsp; But we &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything else to preview on a bilat.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp; Appreciate you all.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>2:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/23/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-84/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 21:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 3:03 P.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; And thanks for joining us.&#160; Today, Dr. Walensky will share the latest on the state of the pandemic and the BA.2 variant, Dr. Fauci will then discuss NIH’s critical role in the research development of COVID therapeutics, and Secretary Becerra and I will discuss the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>3:03 P.M. EDT<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; And thanks for joining us.&nbsp; Today, Dr. Walensky will share the latest on the state of the pandemic and the BA.2 variant, Dr. Fauci will then discuss NIH’s critical role in the research development of COVID therapeutics, and Secretary Becerra and I will discuss the clear consequences if Congress fails to provide more funds for the COVID response.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me start by emphasizing a consistent message you’ll hear from each of us: We urgently need additional funding from Congress to continue our fight against COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’ll start with Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; And good afternoon everyone.&nbsp; I’m delighted to be back with you this week.&nbsp; Let’s start by walking you through the latest data.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have seen cases decrease dramatically over the past few weeks.&nbsp; And our national numbers remain close to historic lows, which is really encouraging.&nbsp; In some areas, we are now recording small increases even as cases continue to fall in other areas.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We continue to closely monitor data from all of our incoming sources, including waste water surveillance, cases, and hospitalizations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nationally, the current seven-day daily average of cases is about 28,600 cases per day, a decrease of about 9 percent over the previous week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 1,900 per day, a decrease of about 23 percent over the previous week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the seven-day average daily deaths are about 900 per day, which is a decrease of about 26 percent over the previous week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>CDC has been closely tracking the BA.2 sublineage of the Omicron variant carefully.&nbsp; The variant has been in the United States for about the past two months, and it has been slowly increasing in proportion compared to BA.1.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This week, we estimate that BA.2 represents about 35 percent of circulating variants nationally.&nbsp; As we&#8217;re learning from our colleagues in Europe, Asia, and South Africa, where BA.2 has resulted in varied peaks of cases, there&#8217;s no evidence that BA.2 variant results in more severe disease, nor does it appear to be more likely to evade our immune protection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, it does have increased transmission in comparison to the related BA.1 Omicron variant that circulated in the U.S. this past winter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the past week, we have seen a small increase in reported COVID-19 cases in New York state and New York City, and some increases in people in the hospital with COVID-19 in New England, specifically where the BA.2 variant has been reaching levels above 50 percent.&nbsp; This small increase in cases in the Northeast is something that we are closely watching as we look for any indication of an increase in severe disease from COVID-19 and track whether it represents any strain on our hospitals.&nbsp; We have not yet seen this so far.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nationwide, cases have been steadily decreasing since the Omicron BA.1 surge.&nbsp; While this is good news, we do expect that cases may continue to fluctuate, including increases in individual communities, which is exactly why the COVID-19 Community Level metrics are in place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One way that CDC and our public health partners collaborate is by monitoring potential increases in cases and transmission is through the COVID-19 wastewater surveillance system.&nbsp; Currently, we&#8217;re seeing a modest uptick of sites reporting an increase of virus levels in wastewater in some communities.&nbsp; In fact, over the past two weeks, we&#8217;ve seen increasing wastewater signals in New York City and parts of New England, where we are now seeing increases in cases and some increased hospitalizations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I want to emphasize that these upticks reflected minor increases from very low levels to still very low levels, but sustained trends over time can give us an early indication of COVID-19 infections in communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So these are the areas that we are watching carefully, and an example of the interplay of our data systems that we use to inform our public health decisions.&nbsp; If cases do go up, we have the framework to implement additional layers of prevention strategies at the local level to swiftly protect individuals and communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>CDC will continue to use all of the tools in our toolbox to closely keep an eye on any increase in COVID-19 in communities, including early indicators like wastewater surveillance, any uptick in cases and hospitalizations, and any changes in our genomic surveillance that monitors for circling variants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d like to emphasize that if cases rise from the Omicron variant or any other variant, we have the tools, vaccines, boosters, tests, and therapeutics to be prepared.&nbsp; But continued investment in these tools so that they are readily available when we need them remains critical.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know Jeff and the Secretary will talk more about the consequences of funding, but from a public health standpoint, it is critical that we continue to provide people with the tools to keep them, their families, and their communities safe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll now turn it over to Dr. Fauci.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; What I&#8217;d like to do in the next couple of minutes is to bring you an update on COVID-19 treatments.</p>



<p>If I have the next slide.</p>



<p>The medical management of individuals with SARS-CoV-2 are essentially threefold.&nbsp; One is to control symptoms, which is usually done as an outpatient for many &#8212; in fact, the vast majority &#8212; of people who are infected with SARS-CoV-2.&nbsp; With serious disease, there&#8217;s end-organ support that we&#8217;ve described in the past.&nbsp; But what I wanted to emphasize over the next couple of minutes is the issue of antivirals and immunomodulators, particularly the newest antivirals, with the purpose of keeping people out of the hospital.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you can see from this schematic, we now have a number of antivirals in our toolkit for non-hospitalized patients with ca- &#8212; with COVID-19 during the Omicron era.&nbsp; And I want to emphasize “during the Omicron era” because several of the others &#8212; for example, some of the monoclonal antibodies &#8212; were negated by the evolution of the Omicron era.&nbsp; What you see on this slide are those interventions which clearly work well to keep people out of the hospital.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to emphasize for a moment, the one you see on the far right, bebtelovimab.&nbsp; I want to talk a little bit about that.</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The FDA authorized this new monoclonal antibody for the treatment of COVID-19 that retains activity in the Omicron era, and it’s for individuals that are described on this slide with positive results of direct viral testing, at a high risk for the progression to severe disease, and for whom we do not have any other alternative therapies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is very important because &#8212; as shown on the next slide &#8212; as we get more variants, we have to make sure &#8212; and we have been fortunate for drugs like Paxlovid and others that they’ve maintained their efficacy against the variants as they’ve arrer- &#8212; as they’ve arisen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you can see on this slide, there have been a number of evolution of variants.&nbsp; But note that the babted- &#8212; the bebtelovimab actually has no change in its ability to neutralize.</p>



<p>A word about this particular monoclonal antibody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It was developed from antibodies from a recovered COVID-19 patient, which is generally the source of all of the monoclonal antibodies.&nbsp; It was developed in a collaborative operation with AbCellera and the NIAID Vaccine Research Center and ultimately developed by Eli Lilly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reason I bring this to your attention is this is the kind of interaction and work that have been done in collaboration between the NIH and our industrial partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Getting back to what was said and what you will hear more of: It&#8217;s important to keep up these interactions, which is the importance for continued funding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in this regard, Secretary Becerra, who you’ll hear from shortly, announced the purchase of 600,000 of these treatment courses of this new monoclonal antibody.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve subcontracted for an additional 500,000.&nbsp; But, again, unless we get the funding requested of the Congress, we will not be able to continue to make these purchases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.</p>



<p>I want to close by just mentioning something that will certainly come up with discussions.&nbsp; We continually get asked, “Will we all need a fourth COVID shot?”&nbsp; Now this is something that is obviously being pursued and examined from the standpoint of the data.&nbsp; Right now, a fourth shot is recommended for people with severe immunocompromised.&nbsp; Other nations, such as the UK, have recommended it for individuals who are elderly and also for those with immune compromise.</p>



<p>Here in this country, we&#8217;re looking at it and letting the data drive us.&nbsp; As you know, on April 6th, the FDA will call their VRBPAC to take a look at the long range of where we might go with new variants and where a fourth shot fits in with that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also the immediate situation of looking at what we might do over the next few weeks to a month.&nbsp; And in that regard, two companies &#8212; Moderna and Pfizer &#8212; have submitted to the FDA for an EUA for the use of a fourth shot.&nbsp; What we can say today is that those data have been submitted, some are continuing to be accumulated, and will be appropriately evaluated, as we usually do, with the FDA and ultimately with the CDC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on the final slide &#8212; just another reminder, if you want to get information about the treatment guidelines, you can go to that website.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a long website.&nbsp; But if you don&#8217;t remember it, just put NIH.gov and it would lead you to that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll stop there.&nbsp; And now back to you, Jeff.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Doctors.&nbsp; Over the past 14 months, we&#8217;ve made tremendous progress in our fight against COVID.&nbsp; Nearly 220 million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; Two in three eligible adults, including over 80 percent of eligible seniors, have now received a booster shot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Dr. Fauci just said, we have highly effective treatments, free and convenient tests, and high-quality masks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bipartisan support from Congress has been key to making this progress.&nbsp; But the President and the doctors have made it abundantly clear that we still have more work to do.</p>



<p>As Dr. Walensky just explained, we&#8217;re seeing BA.2 rise in Europe and in other parts of the world.&nbsp; And we know cases will fluctuate here at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If we maintain our preparedness, an increase in cases does not need to be a cause for alarm like it once was.&nbsp; We know what tools we need to fight the virus.&nbsp; Unfortunately, because of congressional action, we&#8217;re at risk of not having these tools readily available.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This should be unacceptable to every American.&nbsp; For months, we&#8217;ve made clear to Congress, on a bipartisan basis, that funding for core COVID medical supplies &#8212; including vaccines, treatments, and tests &#8212; was running out.&nbsp; Congress has failed to act.&nbsp; They failed to provide the necessary funding, and we&#8217;re already seeing the consequences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me turn to Secretary Becerra to describe what&#8217;s happening as a result of Congress&#8217;s failure to provide the necessary funding.</p>



<p>Secretary?</p>



<p>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; As Jeff has said, we&#8217;re in a new moment in our fight against COVID.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve reached this point because so many Americans have stepped up and done their part and because we&#8217;ve had the resources we need to protect our families and to save lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On numerous occasions, at least six distinct times, Congress has been there to drive resources where they&#8217;ve been needed.&nbsp; The latest critical investment came with last year&#8217;s American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; I want to thank my former colleagues in Congress for the funding that has allowed us to execute on the President&#8217;s pandemic response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Execution means administering more than 550 million shots in arms here at home, distributing more than 7 million treatments to patients across the country, making hundreds of millions of N95 masks and at-home tests available to the American people for free, and leaving no community behind, including by funding more than 1,400 community health centers so they can get vaccines, treatments, tests, and masks to patients without charge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s COVID-19 Preparedness Plan builds on these efforts to help America move forward safely, but continued execution requires continued support from Congress.&nbsp; And at this stage, our resources are depleted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fund Congress established to reimburse doctors and other medical providers for COVID care for Americans &#8212; in particular, the uninsured &#8212; is no longer accepting new claims from providers for testing or for treatment services, as of yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fund will also have to stop accepting new claims for vaccination services on or about April 5th.&nbsp; This means doctors, nurses, pharmacists, labs, and other healthcare providers will no longer get payments through the fund for providing these pandemic services to Americans.</p>



<p>On monoclonal antibody treatments, we have had to cancel a purchase for additional supplies of these treatments which had been planned for this week.&nbsp; Our current supply of these therapeutics is projected to start to run out by late May.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the consequences of diminishing supply or the resources to plan ahead and invest in future needs is that, on Monday, we had to cut the supply of monoclonal antibody treatments that we had distributed in the past to every state.&nbsp; That distribution to each state was reduced by 35 percent.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re also having to scale back our plans to purchase more doses of AstraZeneca’s preventive therapies for Americans who are immunocompromised.&nbsp; This increases the risk of having an insufficient supply of this treatment by the fall of this year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President’s COVID team at the White House and HHS has briefed Congress on a number of occasions in great detail on our pandemic preparation, response, and the status of resources.&nbsp; We’ve provided information orally and in writing to members as requested.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our success in fighting COVID depends on our continued vigilance, our unwavering support for our scientists, our healthcare heroes, our essential workers, and our families navigating this COVID world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re prepared to execute the President&#8217;s plan.&nbsp; We look forward to working with Congress, our state and local partners, and every responsible American to come out of this pandemic in a better place.</p>



<p>Back to you, Jeff.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thanks, Secretary.&nbsp; I want to outline additional impacts that will occur over the coming weeks and months if Congress does not provide the appropriate level of funding for the continued fight against COVID.</p>



<p>Let me start with vaccinations.&nbsp; We have enough supply for the immunocompromised to get a fourth dose and, if authorized in the coming weeks, enough supply for fourth doses for our most vulnerable, including seniors.&nbsp; So we have enough inventory of vaccines to support possible fourth doses this spring.&nbsp; However, if the science shows that fourth doses are needed for the general population later this year, we will not have the supply necessary to ensure shots are available, free, and easy to access for all Americans.</p>



<p>Without more funding, we can&#8217;t procure the necessary vaccine supply to support fourth shots for all Americans.&nbsp; Furthermore, if things change and there&#8217;s a need for a new vaccine, a new formulation &#8212; for example, a variant-specific vaccine &#8212; we won&#8217;t be able to secure doses for the American people and we won&#8217;t be able to ensure America is first in line for them.</p>



<p>Not having enough vaccines is completely unacceptable, as vaccines have proven to be our single most important tool in protecting Americans.&nbsp; We should be securing additional supply right now.</p>



<p>Many other countries are already doing so.&nbsp; In fact, Japan, Vietnam, the Philippines, and Hong Kong have already secured future booster doses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beyond vaccines, without additional funding, we can&#8217;t sustain the domestic testing manufacturing capacity we&#8217;ve built over the past year.&nbsp; And because it takes months to ramp back up to rebuild capacity, failure to invest now will leave us with insufficient testing capacity and supply if we see another surge in cases and demand for testing increases once again.&nbsp; That should not be allowed to happen.</p>



<p>To summarize the consequences of congressional inaction are severe and they are immediate: the uninsured fund is winding down, fewer lifesaving monoclonal treatments are being sent to states, fewer treatments available for the immunocompromised, and we risk not having sufficient vaccine supply or testing capacity.&nbsp; These consequences will only get more significant over time, with less treatments, vaccines, and tests for the American people.</p>



<p>Congressional inaction also hampers our global response.&nbsp; We all know this virus knows no borders, and leaving large unvaccinated populations worldwide will increase the risk of new deadly variants emerging that could put Americans at risk.</p>



<p>Under President Biden&#8217;s leadership, we&#8217;ve donated 1.2 billion vaccine doses to the world with more than 500 million doses already delivered to 113 countries.&nbsp; The challenge now is turning these vaccines into vaccinations &#8212; though without more funding, we can’t extend the support to under-vaccinated countries that they need this year to get shots in arms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The bottom line is we&#8217;ve made tremendous progress across the last 14 months in the fight against COVID.&nbsp; And the President has a plan to sustain and build on this progress and ensure we remain prepared in the face of this very unpredictable virus.&nbsp; But we need Congress to act and provide $22.5 billion in immediate emergency funding so we can execute on the plan, so we can be prepared for whatever comes next.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Importantly, those who have been on the frontlines, Republican and Democratic governors, hospitals across the country, teachers, and 200 leading public health experts have all called for additional funding for the COVID response.</p>



<p>Further congressional inaction will set us back, leave us less prepared, and cost more lives.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no time to waste; Congress needs to act.</p>



<p>With that, let&#8217;s open it up for questions.&nbsp; Over to you, Kevin.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; We have time for a few questions today.&nbsp; So, everybody, please keep their questions brief.</p>



<p>First, let&#8217;s go to Sabrina Siddiqui at the Wall Street Journal.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you as always for doing the briefing.&nbsp; I just wanted to circle back to the BA.2 variant.&nbsp; Is it your expectation that that will become the dominant strain here in the U.S.?&nbsp; And while cases overall, as you said, are in decline nationally, do you expect that we may still see an Omicron-type surge as we did in &#8212; over the winter?</p>



<p>And how are you defining, you know, the trans- &#8212; community transmission levels in terms of restrictions like masks?&nbsp; You know, to move from low to medium to high, is it &#8212; is it focused just on hospital admissions or is it &#8212; or is there a certain threshold or benchmark of cases that would necessitate, for example, bringing back masks?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you, Sabrina.&nbsp; So, we do anticipate and we have seen over the last eight weeks as we&#8217;ve been following BA.2 here that it is representing an increasing proportion of the cases that we have.&nbsp; Now, of course, that is a smaller number of cases, but we do anticipate over the weeks that we may see it become the predominant variant here as it has already in in the Northeast.</p>



<p>In terms of how we&#8217;re defining our &#8212; and what I will say, though, is &#8212; back to what Jeff and I just spoke about &#8212; should we see more BA.2, we actually have the tools &#8212; while it is slightly more transmissible than the original Omicron, our vaccines work, our boosters work, and it does not indicate more severe disease than the original Omicron.&nbsp; So those tools are going to be key in protecting ourselves and our communities against BA.2.</p>



<p>In terms of our COVID-19 community metrics, we look at hospitalizations for COVID-19.&nbsp; We look at hospital capacity.&nbsp; And importantly, we also look at cases.&nbsp; So all of those go into the formulation as we use those metrics for future guidance.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Betsy Klein at CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; Given Dr. Fauci’s remarks on the consideration of a second booster for adults, potentially within the next few weeks, and then your comments, Jeff, that there won’t be supply for Americans who aren’t seniors or immunocompromised without congressional action, should those Americans expect to pay out of pocket for an extra booster?&nbsp; And will there be vaccine supply for Americans who haven’t necessarily had a first, second, or third shot yet and chose to do so in the coming weeks?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Yeah, so let me make it clear that we do have sufficient current inventory of vaccines, both at states and pharmacies, in other access points around the country, and in our central inventory for fourth doses if they&#8217;re called for this spring for our most vulnerable, including seniors.</p>



<p>Where we do not have sufficient doses is later in the year if there&#8217;s a &#8212; the science dictates that all Americans should get a booster or if there&#8217;s a need for a new formulation of the vaccine &#8212; a variant-specific vaccine, for example &#8212; then we will not have sufficient supply.</p>



<p>In terms of people getting their primary series &#8212; their first or second dose, or their first booster &#8212; we continue to have sufficient supply in the near term.</p>



<p>Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Peter Sullivan at The Hill.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; I wanted to ask, on the funding issue, Senator Romney said today that he&#8217;s expecting a new proposal from Democratic leadership.&nbsp; It sounds like with some new offsets in it.&nbsp; Is the White House involved in that new proposal?&nbsp; And, you know, do you feel like you need to engage on the offset question a little more, given that Republican senators still seem to be saying it needs to be offset?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, let me just sort of step back and start with our Hill engagement and how long we&#8217;ve been at this.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been extensively engaged with Congress for months now.&nbsp; And, you know, going back to just after the New Year, mid-January, we&#8217;ve been working with members of Congress, Democrats and Republicans, on the funding needs for the COVID response.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve hosted dozens of briefings, we&#8217;ve held more than three dozen conference calls, and we&#8217;ve shared more than a dozen funding tables.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve given Congress a full accounting of our &#8212; of every dollar that&#8217;s been spent on the COVID medical response and a full accounting of the entire American Rescue Plan, which, as you all know, goes well beyond the direct medical needs.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also provided all the specifics of the planned additional funding &#8212; how it will be deployed against additional purchase of monoclonals and pills and vaccines, as we were just talking about.</p>



<p>In total &#8212; I brought it with us &#8212; we&#8217;ve sent 385 pages of documents and tables to Congress.&nbsp; So let me be very clear: Congress has all the information it needs, and we&#8217;ve been responding to questions for months now.&nbsp; Congress has had plenty of time to act.&nbsp; And time is of the essence, as we heard across the briefing today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With every day that passes, we risk not having the tools we need to fight COVID.&nbsp; And the bottom line is just, you know, crystal clear here: The virus is not waiting for Congress to act.&nbsp; With every minute this funding request is stalled, we&#8217;re losing our ability to protect people and be prepared.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, in terms of offsets, this is emergency &#8212; this is an emergency funding request, and there has not been a need for offsets for an emergency funding request.&nbsp; So, we fully believe that Congress should act, they should fund the $22.5 billion, and there should be no need for offsets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Meg Tirrell at CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, thanks.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if Dr. Fauci or Dr. Walensky could give us some reflections on the news from Moderna today of results they put out in a press release for kids under six for the vaccine.&nbsp; And then also for Jeff, for the Secretary: How does the funding situation impact the potential vaccine rollout for kids under six?&nbsp; Is there sufficient supply for them?&nbsp; And, you know, if there&#8217;s not vaccine being paid for in the same way by the government, could that affect kids being able to access vaccines too?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay, Dr. Fauci, on the Moderna news.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you for that question, Meg. So the data and the announcement made by Moderna reflects a study done in collaboration with the National Institutes of Health in which they looked at the effect of a 25 microgram dose of the Moderna product in children within the age group of six months up to six years &#8212; less than six, but from six months up.</p>



<p>The primary endpoint of the data was not an efficacy endpoint; it was immunogenicity to see if that dose in that particular cohort induced a response comparable to the higher dose that you see in the adults.&nbsp; And it met that primary endpoint.</p>



<p>Also, the safety profile was quite good &#8212; nothing more or less than you would naturally see with so many other vaccinations.&nbsp; However, there was enough events with regard to infection and enough people in the study that they were able to get an efficacy signal.&nbsp; But the efficacy signal was for infection and there was not enough or any severity of disease, either in the placebo or in the vaccine group, to make any determination of the efficacy against severe disease.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The efficacy against infection was 44 percent.&nbsp; Now, that may seem like a low number, but in the era of Omicron, this is actually quite comparable to the efficacy against infection in what we&#8217;re seeing now with other vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the data looked pretty good.&nbsp; Right now, they&#8217;re going to make those data available to the FDA.&nbsp; They will be submitting within a reasonable period of time for an EUA for that particular group for that particular purpose.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; In terms of the supply, we do have that supply secured for kids under the age of six, so that is good news.&nbsp; And we will be ready operationally if the vaccine &#8212; and when the vaccine is authorized and recommended.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have those vaccinations available at tens of thousands of locations across the country that parents know and trust.&nbsp; So, we are &#8212; we do have the supply secured, and we will be ready operationally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Jeff Mason at Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; One follow-up on the issue of an additional booster.&nbsp; Isn&#8217;t it &#8212; if I understood this correctly, isn&#8217;t it possible, Dr. Fauci and Jeff, that there could be approval for everyone in the country to get a fourth booster coming up?&nbsp; And if that is the case, do we have &#8212; does the United States have enough vaccine for that?&nbsp; Not &#8212; and I don&#8217;t mean later in the fall, Jeff, but I mean like right now if that comes through.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then one other question for Dr. <s>Lawensky</s> [Walensky].&nbsp; Could you let us know if the CDC is planning to lift the Title 42 order for all other migrants at the border?&nbsp; And if so &#8212; or if not, why or why not?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; So, Jeff, when we were talking about the possibility in my brief introduction about the possibility of a fourth dose, there&#8217;s the immediate issue and question, and then there&#8217;s the long-range question.</p>



<p>The long-range question, I think is what you&#8217;re referring to, is the advisability or not of a fourth dose of vaccine for the general population.&nbsp; As I mentioned, the FDA will have a VRBPAC meeting on the 6th of April to look at what would be needed with regard to the kind of boost that would be needed, whether it would be variant specific or ancestral-strain specific, and for what population might it be needed in the long range.&nbsp; And in the long range, we&#8217;re talking, for example, towards the beginning of the fall, the end of the summer.</p>



<p>The situation right now of the data that they are looking at with regard to fourth doses from both companies &#8212; from both the companies of the mRNA &#8212; the two companies for mRNA, Moderna and Pfizer &#8212; they&#8217;re going to be looking at data that have been submitted by those companies to the FDA to make a determination if there will be a subset &#8212; perhaps the elderly or others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I mentioned, we already know it&#8217;s already recommended for those with severe immune compromise.&nbsp; So, people need to understand the difference between what&#8217;s being looked at in the next few weeks for the immediate versus the long range, which would involve the question you also asked of Jeff: If a determination is made that we need to do boosters for everyone, will there be available supply?&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, Jeff, back to you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; I think you captured it well.&nbsp; I think that we do have a sufficient supply for what we anticipate could be authorized or rec- &#8212; and recommended in the coming weeks, months.&nbsp; However, when you get later in the year, if there is a vaccine &#8212; fourth dose recommended for all Americans, we need the funding to secure enough supply to ensure that we have sufficient doses for all Americans.</p>



<p>Over to you, Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; So we last reassessed Title 42 at the end of January.&nbsp; As you recall, that was just around or right after the peak of our Omicron surge, and we had hospital capacity challenges really across the country.&nbsp; That reassessment is due next week again, and we are currently reviewing the data and evaluating it right now.&nbsp; So, more soon to come.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; A couple of more questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Victoria Knight at Kaiser Health News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks so much for taking my question.&nbsp; As you guys outlined today, funds are running out to reimburse providers for COVID-related treatment of the uninsured.&nbsp; So what if Congress doesn&#8217;t act soon?&nbsp; What is the administration&#8217;s plan for this?&nbsp; And does this mean uninsured people will be left with big bills for COVID care?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Secretary Becerra.</p>



<p>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; So we&#8217;re planning to continue to provide the different services that we have put in place over the last year.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to divert whatever resources we can to make sure we address the COVID needs of the American public.&nbsp; We’ll continue to provide assistance in regions of the country where COVID is still hitting hard and providing medical support where we can.</p>



<p>So we’ll continue to do everything we can.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll exhaust every dollar that we have.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll use every dollar that we can &#8212; that is flexibly available to continue to provide for the need.&nbsp; And we’ll also begin, if Congress continues to delay any additional funding &#8212; begin a process of outlining what it would take to continue to offer to the American people those vaccines, those treatments, those therapies that they are coming to rely upon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, whether it is moving towards allowing Americans to purchase these through other means or secure them through other means, or whether it means getting the support from Congress that allows us to continue to offer those for free, we&#8217;re going to continue to do what we can to make them available so that every American can remain safe and healthy.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question, let&#8217;s go to Gustau Alegret at NTN24.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for this opportunity and for doing this.&nbsp; I have a couple of questions.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, you mentioned the fourth vaccine shot.&nbsp; However, there&#8217;s still many Americans who resist being vaccinated &#8212; among them, millions in the Latino community.&nbsp; Why you think there is still this resistance among Latinos?&nbsp; And if I may, Secretary Becerra, could you send a clear message in Spanish, if possible, to those in this community to highlight the importance of being vaccinated.&nbsp; Gracias.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, for the first part of your question, it is interesting and noteworthy that we have tried to get the equity of the availability and implementation of vaccines in minority communities &#8212; African Americans, Hispanics.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve done actually quite well in the comparable percentage of non-minorities and minorities who get vaccinated to begin with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the things that has not been as successful &#8212; and we&#8217;re trying our very best to counter that &#8212; is that boosters are not as much being implemented among minorities, including Hispanics compared to whites.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;ve done very, very well with the equity of the original regimen.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to do better when it comes to boosters.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re trying everything we can to get the message out of why it is so important.&nbsp; Because when you look at the data of what boosters do, particularly in the era of Omicron, boosters are extremely important.&nbsp; So that is a deficit that we are trying to correct.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Secretary Becerra.</p>



<p>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; (Speaks Spanish.)</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thank you, everybody, for the questions and for joining today&#8217;s briefing.</p>



<p> 3:41 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/COVID-Press-Briefing_3.23.22.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/COVID-Press-Briefing_3.23.22.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on the Death of Madeleine Korbel&#160;Albright</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/23/a-proclamation-on-the-death-of-madeleine-korbel-albright/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 21:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49587</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Madeleine Albright was a force.&#160; She defied convention and&#160;broke barriers again and again.&#160; She was an immigrant fleeing persecution. &#160;A refugee in need of safe haven. &#160;And like so many&#160;before her &#8212; and after &#8212; she was proudly American. As the devoted mother of three beloved daughters, she worked tirelessly raising them while earning her&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Madeleine Albright was a force.&nbsp; She defied convention and&nbsp;broke barriers again and again.&nbsp; She was an immigrant fleeing persecution. &nbsp;A refugee in need of safe haven. &nbsp;And like so many&nbsp;before her &#8212; and after &#8212; she was proudly American.</p>



<p>As the devoted mother of three beloved daughters, she worked tirelessly raising them while earning her doctorate degree and starting her career in American diplomacy.&nbsp; She took her talents first to the Senate as a staffer for Senator Edmund Muskie followed by the National Security Council under President Carter. &nbsp;And then to the United Nations where she served as United States Ambassador, and ultimately, made history as our first woman Secretary of State, appointed by President Clinton.&nbsp; A scholar, teacher, bestselling author, and later accomplished business woman, she always believed America was the indispensable Nation, and inspired the next generation of public servants to follow her lead, including countless women leaders around the world.&nbsp; Madeleine was always a force for goodness, grace, and decency &#8212; and for freedom.</p>



<p>As a mark of respect for former Secretary of State Madeleine Korbel Albright and her life&nbsp;of service to our Nation, I hereby order, by the authority vested in me as President of&nbsp;the United States by the Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States of America, that the flag of&nbsp;the United&nbsp;States shall be flown at half-staff at the White&nbsp;House and upon all public buildings and grounds, at all military posts and naval stations, and on all naval vessels of&nbsp;the Federal Government in the District of Columbia and throughout the United&nbsp;States and its Territories and possessions until sunset on March 27, 2022.&nbsp; I also direct that the flag shall be flown at&nbsp;half-staff for the same length of time at all United States embassies, legations, consular offices, and other facilities abroad, including all military facilities and naval vessels and&nbsp;stations.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-third day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden On the Passing of Former Secretary of State Madeleine&#160;Albright</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/23/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-former-secretary-of-state-madeleine-albright/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 21:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Madeleine Albright was a force. Hers were the hands that turned the tide of history. As a young girl, she found a home in the United States—after her family fled their home country of Czechoslovakia during World War II, and the Iron Curtain came down across Central and Eastern Europe. Her father, a diplomat, was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Madeleine Albright was a force.<br><br>Hers were the hands that turned the tide of history.<br><br>As a young girl, she found a home in the United States—after her family fled their home country of Czechoslovakia during World War II, and the Iron Curtain came down across Central and Eastern Europe. Her father, a diplomat, was marked for death by the Soviet regime. She spent the rest of her days defending freedom around the world and lifting up those who suffered under repression.<br><br>She was an immigrant fleeing persecution. A refugee in need of safe haven. And like so many before her—and after—she was proudly American.<br><br>To make this country that she loved even better—she defied convention and broke barriers again and again.&nbsp; As the devoted mother of three beloved daughters, she worked tirelessly raising them while earned her doctorate degree and started her career.&nbsp; She took her talents first to the Senate as a staffer for Senator Edmund Muskie, followed by the National Security Council under President Carter. And then to the United Nations where she served as U.S. Ambassador, and ultimately, made history as our first woman Secretary of State, appointed by President Clinton.<br><br>A scholar, teacher, bestselling author, and later accomplished businesswoman, Secretary Albright continued to advise presidents and members of Congress with matchless skill and diplomatic acumen.&nbsp; In every role, she used her fierce intellect and sharp wit—and often her unmatched collection of pins—to advance America’s national security and promote peace around the world. America had no more committed champion of democracy and human rights than Secretary Albright, who knew personally and wrote powerfully of the perils of autocracy.<br><br>Working with Secretary Albright during the 1990s was among the highlights of my career in the United States Senate during my tenure on the Foreign Relations Committee. As the world redefined itself in the wake of the Cold War, we were partners and friends working to welcome newly liberated democracies into NATO and confront the horrors of genocide in the Balkans.<br><br>When I think of Madeleine, I will always remember her fervent faith that “America is the indispensable nation.”<br><br>In the years after she left government, Secretary Albright never stepped away from that belief. &nbsp;As the Chairman of the National Democratic Institute for over two decades, and through other organizations she advised, she continued to champion democratic principles as vitally important to America’s interests in freedom, prosperity and security.<br><br>She continued to mentor and nurture new generations of foreign policy experts at Georgetown University, the Korbel Center for International Studies at the University of Denver, named after her father, and beyond.&nbsp; As always, she shared her insight and wisdom widely, but she was especially dedicated to supporting the next generation of women leaders, including through the establishment of the Albright Institute for Global Affairs at Wellesley College.<br><br>Madeleine was always a force for goodness, grace, and decency—and for freedom.<br><br>Jill and I will miss her dearly and send our love and prayers to her daughters, Alice, Anne and Katie, her sister Kathy, her brother John, her six grandchildren, and her nephews and grandniece.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Idaho Law Restricting Women’s Access to Health&#160;Care</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/23/statement-from-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-idaho-law-restricting-womens-access-to-health-care/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We knew that when Texas passed SB8, its extreme law that blatantly violates the constitutional right reaffirmed by Roe v. Wade, it would invite other states to follow.  Today, Idaho became the first state to adopt a similar law – a six-week restriction relying on private citizens to enforce the law.  This development is devastating for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We knew that when Texas passed SB8, its extreme law that blatantly violates the constitutional right reaffirmed by <em>Roe v. Wade</em>, it would invite other states to follow.  Today, Idaho became the first state to adopt a similar law – a six-week restriction relying on private citizens to enforce the law.  This development is devastating for women in Idaho, as it will further impede women’s access to health care, especially those on low incomes and living in rural communities. <br><br>Over the last six months, Texas’s SB8 has had profoundly negative effects–with women forced to travel hundreds of miles to access care, and clinics in neighboring states seeing a significant increase in demand since the law went into effect.  This is unacceptable, which is why President Biden directed a whole of government response to protect women’s rights that are currently under attack.<br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration will continue to stand with women and support their right to make their own health care decisions, a constitutional right that <em>Roe v. Wade</em> reaffirmed nearly five decades ago. And the President again calls on Congress to act and send a bill to his desk to shut down these radical steps.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Appointments to Federal Salary&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/23/president-biden-announces-appointments-to-federal-salary-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles: Stephen Emerson Condrey, Member and Chair, Federal Salary Council Jared James Llorens, Member, Federal Salary Council Janice Rachel Lachance, Member, Federal Salary Council The Federal Salary Council is an advisory body of the executive branch that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Stephen Emerson Condrey, Member and Chair, Federal Salary Council</li><li>Jared James Llorens, Member, Federal Salary Council</li><li>Janice Rachel Lachance, Member, Federal Salary Council</li></ul>



<p>The Federal Salary Council is an advisory body of the executive branch that provides recommendations on pay differentials for federal employees.&nbsp;The Council submits recommendations to the Secretary of Labor, Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</p>



<p><strong><u>Stephen Emerson Condrey, Member and Chair</u></strong><strong><br></strong>Stephen Emerson Condrey is President of Condrey and Associates, Inc., a human resources consulting firm specializing in compensation systems for state and local governments. In his forty years of experience, Condrey has consulted with over 800 organizations nationally and internationally and served as President Obama’s Federal Salary Council Chair from 2010 to 2017. He has authored or co-authored numerous scholarly articles and is the editor of the Handbook of Human Resource Management in Government (3<sup>rd</sup> edition) as well as the co-editor of Public Administration in Post-Communist Countries. He has degrees from the University of Montevallo (BS), the University of Tennessee (MPA), and the University of Georgia (PhD).&nbsp; After losing his sight in 2015, he received Assistive Technology training from the Birmingham Regional Center of the Alabama Institute for the Deaf and Blind. Condrey served as President of the American Society for Public Administration (2013-2014) and is a Fellow of the National Academy of Public Administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Jared James Llorens, Member</u></strong><strong><br></strong>Jared J. Llorens is Dean of Louisiana State University’s E. J. Ourso College of Business. An expert in the areas of public sector compensation and recruitment, Llorens launched his academic career in 2007 as an Assistant Professor of Public Administration at the University of Kansas. He accepted a faculty position with Louisiana State University’s Department of Public Administration in 2009 and was named chair of the Department in 2015. Llorens began his service as the college’s ninth Dean on November 1, 2020.</p>



<p>In 2020, Llorens was named a Fellow of the National Academy of Public Administration. He is the former editor-in-chief of Public Personnel Management and his research has been widely published in various academic outlets. He is also a co-author of the widely adopted textbook Public Personnel Management: Context and Strategies 6th &amp; 7th editions. Before beginning his academic career, Llorens served as a human resources analyst with the U.S. Office of Personnel Management and the U.S. Department of Labor in Dallas and Washington, D.C. A Baton Rouge native, Llorens received his BA in English from Loyola University of New Orleans, his MPAff from the LBJ School of Public Affairs at The University of Texas at Austin, and his PhD in Public Administration from the University of Georgia’s School of Public and International Affairs.</p>



<p><strong><u>Janice Rachel Lachance, Member</u></strong><strong><br></strong>Janice Lachance is the Executive Vice President for Strategic Leadership and Global Outreach at the American Geophysical Union (AGU), a scientific society supporting more than 130,000 Earth and space scientists in 140 countries. Her work at AGU includes the renovation of the organization’s headquarters into a net-zero energy consumption building – the first renovation of its kind in Washington, D.C. Beyond this innovative project, Janice’s duties include: leadership of AGU’s global partnerships and initiatives; positioning and message development across the range of climate, environmental, and science policy issues, discoveries, and solutions; and global government relations and public policy, membership and career services, and association governance.</p>



<p>Prior to her work in the nonprofit sector, Lachance was nominated by President Clinton and unanimously confirmed by the U.S. Senate to serve as the Director of the U.S. Office of Personnel Management (OPM), where she was responsible for policy and programmatic leadership of the nation’s 2.1-million-member civil service. Leading up to this role, she served as OPM’s Director of Communications, Chief of Staff, and Deputy Director. Janice received the American Society for Public Administration (ASPA) 2020 Elmer B. Staats Lifetime Achievement Award. She is a member of ASPA’s Endowment Board and was its president in 2017-2018. She also has been named a Fellow of the National Academy of Public Administration and the American Society of Association Executives. Born and raised in Biddeford, Maine, and the first in her extended family to attend college, Lachance graduated from Manhattanville College and earned her law degree from Tulane University.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Appointments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/23/president-biden-announces-key-appointments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles on the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &#38; Nutrition, the Commission of Fine Arts, and the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science: José Andrés, Co-Chair, the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &#38; Nutrition Elena Delle&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles on the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &amp; Nutrition, the Commission of Fine Arts, and the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science:</p>



<ul><li>José Andrés, Co-Chair, the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &amp; Nutrition</li><li>Elena Delle Donne, Co-Chair, the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &amp; Nutrition</li><li>Lisa E. Delplace, Member, the Commission of Fine Arts</li><li>May Berenbaum, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Rafael Bras, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Joan Ferrini-Mundy, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Erika Gonzalez, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Juan Maldacena, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Cora Bagley Marrett, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Valerie Montgomery Rice, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Craig Partridge, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Padma Raghavan, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Pedro A. Sanchez, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Robert Sellers, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li><li>Cherese Winstead, Member, the President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>The President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, &amp; Nutrition</u></strong></p>



<p>The President’s Council on Sports, Fitness &amp; Nutrition (PCSFN) is a federal advisory committee that aims to promote healthy, accessible eating and physical activity for all Americans, regardless of background or ability. President Biden issues Executive Order 14048, renewing the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness &amp; Nutrition. This Executive Order allows for continued promotion of the National Youth Sports Strategy, and provides for the work of the Council to include a focus on expanding national awareness of the importance of mental health as it pertains to physical fitness and nutrition.</p>



<p><strong>José Andrés as Co-Chair</strong></p>



<p>José Andrés is an internationally recognized culinary innovator, New York Times bestselling author, educator, and humanitarian. He was named one of Time Magazine’s “100 Most Influential People” in both 2012 and 2018, and awarded the 2015 National Humanities Medal from President Barack Obama. As the chef/owner of the award-winning ThinkFoodGroup restaurant collective, Andrés has been a pioneer of Spanish tapas in the United States and is also known for his groundbreaking avant-garde cuisine. In 2010, Andrés formed World Central Kitchen, a non-profit which uses the power of food to nourish communities and strengthen economies in times of crisis. His team served over 3.6 million meals to the people of Puerto Rico following Hurricane María. Since then, WCK has activated on six continents, serving tens of millions of fresh meals in the aftermath of both natural and manmade disasters. In response to the COVID-19 pandemic, the organization partnered with thousands of restaurants, farmers, and community leaders around the country to combat food and nutrition insecurity, laying the groundwork for smarter national food policy—one which builds longer tables in the US and around the world.&nbsp; Currently, Andrés and World Central Kitchen are working in Ukraine and four neighboring countries, feeding refugees who have fled their homes. Andrés currently serves as co-Chair of the Bipartisan Policy Center’s Food and Nutrition Security Task Force, was named Washington Business Journal’s CEO of the Year in 2020 for his leadership and impact on the global business community during the COVID-19 pandemic, and was awarded the Princesa de Asturias Foundation’s 2021 Concordia Prize for World Central Kitchen’s humanitarian work. As a naturalized citizen originally from Spain, Andrés has also been a tireless advocate for immigration reform.</p>



<p><strong>Elena Delle Donne as Co-Chair</strong></p>



<p>Elena Delle Donne is one of the most dominant players in the WNBA. The Washington Mystics star is a Top 25 WNBA player of all time, two-time WNBA MVP (2015, 2019), WNBA Champion (2019), six-time WNBA All-Star honor, and four-time All-WNBA First Team selection. Delle Donne is also the first WNBA player to join the 50-40-90 club, a group of elite sharp shooters comprised of only eight other NBA players. A member of Team USA, Delle Donne took home a gold medal during the 2016 Olympics and was the WNBA scoring champion in 2015. The 2013 WNBA Rookie of the Year, the Delaware native was drafted second overall in the WNBA draft. Prior to her WNBA career, Delle Donne attended the University of Delaware to remain close to her tight-knit family. While at Delaware, Delle Donne led her team to its first ever NCAA Sweet Sixteen her senior year, was a consensus first team All-American, and finished as CAA Conference Player of the Year three times. Off the court, Delle Donne is the author of a middle-grade series, Hoops, and released her memoir <em>My Shot: Balancing it All and Standing Tall</em>. Additionally, Delle Donne and her wife, Amanda, turned their passion for woodworking and design into their own business, Deldon, creating custom pieces like cutting boards, wall art and basketball hoops. In 2017, she founded the Elena Delle Donne Foundation to raise funds and awareness of Lyme disease research, special needs programs and animal welfare work.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>The Commission of Fine Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>The Commission of Fine Arts is an independent federal agency charged with giving expert advice to the President, the Congress and the federal and District of Columbia governments on matters of design and aesthetics, as they affect the federal interest and preserve the dignity of the nation’s capital. The Commission is composed of seven presidentially appointed experts in relevant disciplines including art, architecture, landscape architecture, and urban design.</p>



<p><strong>Lisa E. Delplace as Member</strong></p>



<p>Lisa E. Delplace, FASLA, is a landscape architect and Chief Executive Officer Emeritus of Washington, DC-based OEHME, VAN SWEDEN | OvS. In a career that spans four decades, Lisa has demonstrated comprehensive knowledge of ecological processes and a commitment to their artistic execution. Her diverse body of work ranges from bucolic sculpture parks to urban redevelopments and reflects a compelling sculptural relationship between architecture and landscape. Lisa holds a Master of Landscape Architecture from the University of Michigan and is a member of the American Society of Landscape Architects’ Council of Fellows. She serves as a visiting critic and lecturer for universities and professional organizations and has international experience in Europe, the Middle East, and service as a U.S. Peace Corps Volunteer in Kenya, East Africa.</p>



<p><strong><u>The President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science</u></strong></p>



<p>The President’s Committee on the National Medal of Science evaluates nominees for the National Medal of Science, a Presidential Award to recognize individuals for their outstanding contributions to knowledge in the physical, biological, mathematical, engineering, social, and behavioral sciences. Since its establishment, the National Medal of Science has been awarded to 506 distinguished scientists and engineers whose careers spanned decades of research and development.</p>



<p><strong>May Berenbaum as Member</strong></p>



<p>May Berenbaum has been on the faculty of the Department of Entomology at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign for more than 40 years, serving as head since 1992 and as Swanlund Chair of Entomology since 1996. A member of the National Academy of Sciences, she has chaired two National Research Council study committees, including Status of Pollinators in North America, testifying before Congress on the study&#8217;s findings. Since January 2019, she has served as Editor-in-Chief of the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. She is a Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, the Ecological Society of America, and the Entomological Society of America. In 2011, she was awarded the Tyler Prize for Environmental Achievement, and, in 2014, she received the National Medal of Science from President Obama.</p>



<p><strong>Rafael Bras as Member</strong></p>



<p>A native of Puerto Rico, Rafael L. Bras is a professor in the School of Earth and Atmospheric Sciences and the School of Civil and Environmental Engineering at the Georgia Institute of Technology. He holds the K. Harrison Brown Family Chair. Dr. Bras works in the field of hydrology with particular interest on land-atmosphere-biosphere interactions. He was Provost and Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs at the Georgia Institute of Technology. He was also Distinguished Professor and Dean of the Henry Samueli School of Engineering of the University of California, Irvine and spent 32 years as a professor in the departments of Civil and Environmental Engineering and of Earth, Atmospheric, and Planetary Sciences at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Dr. Bras is an elected member of the U.S. National Academy of Engineering and the Academy of Arts and Sciences of Puerto Rico.</p>



<p><strong>Joan Ferrini-Mundy as Member</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Joan Ferrini-Mundy was appointed the 21<sup>st</sup> president of the University of Maine and its regional campus in Machias in 2018. She was also named Vice Chancellor for Research and Innovation for the University of Maine System and is a professor in the Department of Mathematics and Statistics. Ferrini-Mundy came to Maine following her service as the chief operating officer of the National Science Foundation. Prior to that role, she headed the National Science Foundation’s Directorate for Education and Human Resources for six years. She also has been a faculty member and administrator at her alma mater, the University of New Hampshire, and at Michigan State University. President Ferrini-Mundy’s awards and recognitions include the U.S. Senior Executive Service Presidential Rank Award of Distinguished Executive, Michigan State University Distinguished Professorship, election as a fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science and of the American Mathematical Society, and the 2020 Seaman A. Knapp Award for leadership and contributions to food and agricultural sciences.</p>



<p><strong>Erika Gonzalez as Member</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Erika Gonzalez is the CEO &amp; President of both South Texas Allergy &amp; Asthma Medical Professionals (STAAMP) and STAAMP Clinical Research. She previously served as the Chief of the Allergy, Immunology &amp; Rheumatology division at the Children’s Hospital of San Antonio and was an Associate Professor of Clinical Pediatrics at Baylor College of Medicine. She serves on the Board of Directors for Central Catholic High School, Girls Inc. San Antonio, and the San Antonio Economic Development Foundation. She is an Advisor to the Dean of Science Engineering &amp; Technology at St. Mary’s University, on the Stock Epinephrine Committee with the Texas Department of State Health Services, and Co-Chair for the Small Business for America’s Future. Dr. Gonzalez recently founded the nonprofit Con Corazon SA to address health inequities and emergency preparedness. She is a native of San Antonio and served 10 years of Active Duty Service as a Medical Officer in the U. S. Air Force. She was selected as a 2019 Presidential Leadership Scholar.</p>



<p><strong>Juan Maldacena as Member</strong></p>



<p>Juan Maldacena was born in 1968 in Argentina, where he obtained his college degree. He moved to the U.S. for his physics Ph.D., completed in 1996 at Princeton University. He has been a professor at the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton since 2001 and currently holds the Carl P. Feinberg chair. His research interests include quantum field theory, quantum gravity, string theory, and cosmology. He is a member of the National Academy of Sciences and the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. His awards include the Dannie Heineman Prize, the Einstein Medal, the Mac Arthur Fellowship, and the Breakthrough Prize in Physics.</p>



<p><strong>Cora Bagley Marrett as Member</strong></p>



<p>Cora Bagley Marrett is Professor Emerita of Sociology at the University of Wisconsin-Madison. She has held posts at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill; Western Michigan University; the University of Wisconsin System; and the University of Massachusetts-Amherst. At the University of Massachusetts-Amherst, she was Provost and Vice Chancellor for Academic Affairs. For eleven years, she served as an administrator at the National Science Foundation and was appointed Deputy Director of the National Science Foundation by President Obama. Throughout her career, she has served on governing or advisory boards with the Social Science Research Council, the Russell Sage Foundation, the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering and Medicine, and the Office of Naval Research. President Carter appointed her to the Commission on the Accident at Three Mile Island, which examined the nuclear power incident in Pennsylvania. She holds honorary degrees from Virginia Union University, the University of Wisconsin-Madison, and Wake Forest University.</p>



<p><strong>Valerie Montgomery Rice as Member</strong></p>



<p>Valerie Montgomery Rice, MD, FACOG, is the sixth President and CEO of Morehouse School of Medicine and the first woman to lead the free-standing medical institution. Prior to joining Morehouse School of Medicine, Montgomery Rice was the founding director of the Center for Women’s Health Research at Meharry Medical College, one of the nation’s first research centers devoted to studying diseases that disproportionately impact women of color. She currently serves on the Georgia Commission on Women, chairs the Georgia Department of Public Health’s Covid-19 Health Equity Council, and is a member of the National Academy of Medicine. A Georgia native, Montgomery Rice holds a bachelor’s degree in chemistry from the Georgia Institute of Technology, a medical degree from Harvard Medical School, an honorary degree from the University of Massachusetts Medical School, and a Doctor of Humane Letters honorary degree from Rush University.</p>



<p><strong>Craig Partridge as Member</strong></p>



<p>Professor Craig Partridge is the chair of the department of Computer Science at Colorado State University. Previously, he was Chief Scientist at Raytheon BBN Technologies. Partridge is a member of the Internet Hall of Fame and a Fellow of the Association for Computing Machinery and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers. Partridge is a member of the Computer Science and Telecommunications Board of the National Academies. He is a former chair of ACM&#8217;s Special Interest Group on Data Communication and a former member of the National Science Foundation&#8217;s Computer and Information Science and Engineering Advisory Committee. Partridge received his A.B., M.Sc., and Ph.D. degrees from Harvard University.</p>



<p><strong>Padma Raghavan</strong><strong> as Member</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Padma Raghavan is the inaugural Vice Provost for Research and Professor of Computer Science at Vanderbilt University. Prior to joining Vanderbilt in 2016, Raghavan served as the Associate Vice President for Research and Strategic Initiatives, the founding Director of the Institute for Computational and Data Sciences, and Distinguished Professor of Computer Science and Engineering at the Pennsylvania State University. Raghavan was named a fellow of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers in 2013 in recognition of her contributions to the development of energy-efficient supercomputing. She also serves on editorial boards of the Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics and the Advisory Boards of the Computing and Information Science and Engineering Directorate and the Office of Advanced Cyberinfrastructure of the National Science Foundation. Raghavan also serves on multiple committees of the National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine, including Technical Advisory Boards for the Army Research Laboratory on Computational Science and Information Sciences.</p>



<p><strong>Pedro A. Sanchez</strong><strong> as Member</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Pedro Sanchez was born and raised in Cuba, where he worked on his family’s farm. He has spent 50 years alternating between American universities and CGIAR&#8217;s international research centers. He has been faculty at North Carolina State University, the University of California Berkeley, Colombia University, and the University of Florida, where he is currently a research professor of tropical soils and core faculty member of the Food Systems Institute. Cambridge University Press published Sanchez’s book “Properties and Management of Soils in the Tropics” in 2019 and its translation into Spanish in 2021. Sanchez has received honorary Doctor of Science degrees from the Catholic University of Leuven, Guelph University in Canada, the Ohio State University, and North Carolina State University. He won the World Food Prize in 2002, became a MacArthur Foundation Fellow in 2004, and was elected to the U.S. National Academy of Sciences in 2012. In 2016, President Obama appointed him to the President´s Committee on the National Medal of Science.</p>



<p><strong>Robert Sellers as Member</strong></p>



<p>Robert M. Sellers is the Vice Provost for Equity and Inclusion, Chief Diversity Officer, and the Charles D. Moody Collegiate Professor of Psychology and Education at the University of Michigan. Prior to joining the Provost’s Office, Dr. Sellers was chair of the University of Michigan Department of Psychology. His research interests include ethnicity, racial and ethnic identity, personality and health, athletic participation, and personality. He has received the Theodore Millon Mid-Career Award in Personality Psychology from the American Psychological Foundation, the American Psychological Association Minority Fellowship Program Research Achievement Award, and the APAGS Kenneth &amp; Mamie Clark Award for Outstanding Contribution to the Professional Development of Ethnic Minority Graduate Students. Sellers received his B.S. in Psychology from Howard University and his doctorate in personality psychology from the University of Michigan.</p>



<p><strong>Cherese Winstead as Member</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Cherese Winstead is ranked as Full Professor in the Department of Chemistry at Delaware State University and currently serves as Dean of the College of Agriculture, Science &amp; Technology. She previously served as the Department Chair of Chemistry at Delaware State University for over eight years. She is a member of Delaware NASA Space Grant, Delaware Comprehensive Sickle Cell Research Center, Materials Research Society, American Chemical Society, and the Delaware Science Coalition. Dr. Winstead is Founder and President of the Young Chemists Society, a non-profit organization dedicated to the early education of underrepresented students in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. Dr. Winstead obtained her Ph.D. from The Virginia Polytechnic Institute &amp; State University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
