<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:28:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Names Twenty-Third Round of Judicial&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/president-biden-names-twenty-third-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing the nominations of four new federal judicial nominees, his intent to nominate a fifth federal judicial nominee, and three nominees for local courts in the District of Columbia—all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to fulfill the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing the nominations of four new federal judicial nominees, his intent to nominate a fifth federal judicial nominee, and three nominees for local courts in the District of Columbia—all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>For example, if confirmed, this slate would include:</p>



<ul><li>The first Black woman to serve on the U.S. District Court for the District of Oregon</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s twenty-third round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his tenth slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 123.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies. And he has won confirmation of the most lower court judges for the first year of a presidency since the Kennedy Administration.</p>



<p><strong><u>District Court – Press Bios</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Matthew L. Garcia: Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of New Mexico</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Matthew L. Garcia has served in the Office of New Mexico Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham as Chief of Staff from 2020 to 2022 and General Counsel from 2019 to 2020. From 2012 to 2018, he was a partner at Garcia Ives Nowara in Albuquerque, New Mexico, and from 2009 to 2012, he was a partner at Bach &amp; Garcia in Albuquerque, New Mexico. Mr. Garcia had his own solo practice from 2008 to 2009. From 2006-2008 Mr. Garcia was an associate at Freedman Boyd Daniels Hollander Goldberg &amp; Ives in Albuquerque, New Mexico. Mr. Garcia received his J.D. from the University of New Mexico School of Law in 2005, an M.P.P. from Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Government in 2003, and a B.A., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from the University of New Mexico in 1999.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>Lindsay C. Jenkins: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois—<em>Intent to Nominate</em></u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Lindsay C. Jenkins is a partner at Cooley LLP in Chicago, Illinois, where she has worked since 2021. She previously served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Northern District of Illinois from 2006 to 2021. Ms. Jenkins was previously an associate at Jones Day from 2004 to 2006. She served as a law clerk for Judge Solomon Oliver, Jr. on the United States District Court for the Northern District of Ohio from 2002 to 2004. Ms. Jenkins received her J.D., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Cleveland-Marshall College of Law at Cleveland State University, in 2002 and her B.A. from Miami University of Ohio in 1998.</p>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong><u>Justice Adrienne C. Nelson: Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of Oregon</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Justice Adrienne C. Nelson has served as an Associate Justice on the Oregon Supreme Court since 2018. From 2006 to 2018, Justice Nelson served as a trial judge on the Multnomah County Circuit Court. Justice Nelson worked as a senior attorney for Portland State University from 2004 to 2006, and she was in private practice at Bennett, Hartman, Morris &amp; Kaplan from 2004 to 2006. From 1996 to 1999, Justice Nelson was a public defender with Multnomah Defenders, Inc. Justice Nelson received her J.D. from the University of Texas School of Law at Austin in 1993 and her B.A., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from the University of Arkansas at Fayetteville in 1989.</p>



<ol type="1" start="4"><li><strong><u>Judge Andrew G. Schopler: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Southern District of California</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Andrew G. Schopler has served as a United States Magistrate Judge for the Southern District of California since 2016.&nbsp;From 2004 to 2016, Judge Schopler was an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of California. He worked at Rudolf and Maher in Chapel Hill, North Carolina from 1998 to 2004 He was a solo practitioner from 1997 to 1998.&nbsp;Judge Schopler received his J.D. from Harvard Law School in 1997 and his B.A., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Dartmouth College in 1994. He has served in the United States Army Reserve and California Army National Guard since 2014.</p>



<ol type="1" start="5"><li><strong><u>Judge James Edward Simmons Jr: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Southern District of California</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge James Edward Simmons Jr. has been a judge on the California Superior Court since 2017. He is currently the Supervising Judge of the North County Branch of the San Diego Superior Court. From 2006 to 2017, he was a Deputy District Attorney in the San Diego District Attorney’s Office. In 2005, Judge Simmons was a Deputy City Attorney in the San Diego City Attorney’s Office. Judge Simmons received his J.D from Golden Gate University School of Law in 2004 and B.A. from the University of California, Berkeley in 2001.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>D.C. Court of Appeals</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Vijay Shanker: Candidate for D.C Court of Appeals</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Vijay Shanker is the Deputy Chief of the Appellate Section in the Criminal Division of the United States Department of Justice, where he has worked since 2005. He was previously Counselor and Acting Deputy Chief of Staff to the Assistant Attorney General for the Criminal Division and Senior Litigation Counsel in the Criminal Division’s Fraud Section at the Department of Justice. Mr. Shanker was an associate at Mayer Brown from 2004 to 2005 and at Covington &amp; Burling from 1999 to 2000 and 2001 to 2004. He served as a law clerk for Judge Chester J. Straub on the United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit from 2000 to 2001. Mr. Shanker received his J.D., Order of the Coif, from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1999 and his B.A., <em>cum laude</em>, from Duke University in 1994.</p>



<p><strong><u>D.C. Superior Court</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Laura Crane: Candidate for D.C. Superior Court</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Laura Cranehas served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia since 2014. Before joining the United States Attorney’s Office, Ms. Crane was a senior associate at WilmerHale in Washington, D.C. from 2013 to 2014 and a litigation associate at Cravath, Swaine, and Moore in New York City from 2010 to 2012. She served as a law clerk for the Judge James E. Boasberg on the United States District Court for the District of Columbia from 2012 to 2013. Ms. Crane received her J.D., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from the Washington University School of Law om 2009 and her B.A., <em>magna cum laude,</em> from Duke University in 2003.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>Veronica Sanchez: Candidate for the D.C. Superior Court</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Veronica Sanchez is an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia, a role she has held since 2009. Ms. Sanchez was a trial attorney in the Antitrust Division of the United States Department of Justice from 2002 to 2009. She served as a law clerk for Judge Melvin Brunetti on the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit from 2001 to 2002 and for Judge Edward C. Reed on the United States District Court for the District of Nevada from 1999 to 2001. Ms. Sanchez received her J.D. from the UCLA School of Law in 1999 and her B.A. from Duke University in 1996</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement From Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on Texas Attorney General’s Lawsuit in the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of&#160;Texas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-texas-attorney-general-ken-paxtons-u-s-district-court-for-the-northern-district-of-texas-lawsuit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 19:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is yet another example of an extreme and radical Republican elected official. It is unthinkable that this public official would sue to block women from receiving life-saving care in emergency rooms, a right protected under U.S. law. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This is yet another example of an extreme and radical Republican elected official. It is unthinkable that this public official would sue to block women from receiving life-saving care in emergency rooms, a right protected under U.S. law.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Council of Governors&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/readout-of-council-of-governors-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 18:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Wednesday, July 13, senior officials from the White House, Department of Defense, and Department of Homeland Security participated in the 25th plenary meeting of the Council of Governors and the second plenary meeting under the Biden-Harris Administration to discuss homeland defense and security priorities. Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro N. Mayorkas, Deputy Secretary of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Wednesday, July 13, senior officials from the White House, Department of Defense, and Department of Homeland Security participated in the 25<sup>th</sup> plenary meeting of the Council of Governors and the second plenary meeting under the Biden-Harris Administration to discuss homeland defense and security priorities. Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro N. Mayorkas, Deputy Secretary of Defense Dr. Kath Hicks, Assistant to the President Julie Chavez Rodriguez, and Special Assistant to the President Caitlin Durkovich provided opening remarks along with the Co-Chairs of the Council of Governors, Ohio Governor Mike DeWine and Minnesota Governor Tim Walz. The Council of Governors members received updates on cybersecurity, disaster preparedness, workforce development, and support for military families.  The Council also received an overview of the National Defense Strategy from Assistant Secretary Melissa Dalton, an update on preparedness for the 2022 disaster season from FEMA Administrator Criswell, and information on the strategic guidelines for the Department of Defense Fiscal year 2024 program from Under Secretary of Defense McCord.  Finally, Director Aylward provided an overview of the progress made on the 50<sup>th</sup> Anniversary Vietnam War commemoration efforts. </p>



<p><br>Participants from the Council of Governors included:</p>



<ul><li>Governor Tim Walz (MN), Co-Chair of the Council of Governors</li><li>Governor Mike DeWine (OH), Co-Chair of the Council of Governors</li><li>Governor John Carney (DE)</li><li>Governor John Bel Edwards (LA)</li><li>Governor Gretchen Whitmer (MI)</li><li>Governor Kate Brown (OR)</li><li>Governor Spencer Cox (UT)</li><li>Governor Phil Scott (VT)</li><li>Governor Mark Gordon (WY)</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Israeli Presidential Medal of Honor&#160;Reception</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/14/remarks-by-president-biden-at-israeli-presidential-medal-of-honor-reception/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 17:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President&#8217;s Residence GardenJerusalem, Israel 6:08 P.M. IDT&#160; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; President Herzog, it&#8217;s wonderful to be with you again and an honor to be with so many familiar faces out in this garden. You know, if anyone should understand my inclination to enthusiasm, you should be.  With a &#8212; with a grandfather who thought Sinn Féin&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">President&#8217;s Residence Garden<br>Jerusalem, Israel</p>



<p>6:08 P.M. IDT&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; President Herzog, it&#8217;s wonderful to be with you again and an honor to be with so many familiar faces out in this garden.</p>



<p>You know, if anyone should understand my inclination to enthusiasm, you should be.  With a &#8212; with a grandfather who thought Sinn Féin was the future of Ireland, you should understand that.  (Laughter.)</p>



<p>You all think I&#8217;m kidding; I&#8217;m not.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT HERZOG:&nbsp; A great day for the Irish.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve known many of you for a long time.&nbsp; And all of you, you know that my love for Israel is deep rooted.&nbsp; I was raised, as we say and you say, by a righteous Christian &#8212; my dad.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’ve had the honor &#8212; it&#8217;s hard to say these words &#8212; for over 50 years &#8212; it can&#8217;t be that long &#8212; but for over 50 years in the federal government to helping build the relationship.&nbsp; Fifty years ago, we never had this audience before.&nbsp; We would not have this audience out here.&nbsp; We have so many people represented, representing so many different nations and faiths as well.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s important.</p>



<p>But, you know, seeing Israel thrive, seeing the wildest dreams of Israel&#8217;s founding fathers and mothers grow into a reality that Israel children enjoy today, to me is close to miraculous.&nbsp; You&#8217;re always &#8212; there&#8217;s a &#8212; we use, in the Catholic Church, a hymn that&#8217;s based on one of the Psalms.&nbsp; And it says, &#8220;May He raise you up on eagle&#8217;s wings and bear you on the breath of dawn.&nbsp; Until we meet again, may God hold you in the palm of his hand.&#8221;</p>



<p>Well, every time I&#8217;ve come over these years, thank God, God seems to be holding us in the palm of his hand, because we get stronger, not weaker.&nbsp; And to me, it&#8217;s pretty miraculous.</p>



<p>The Torah tells a story of the prophet who described the ancient Israeli &#8212; Israe- &#8212; Israelis as the people that &#8220;dwell alone&#8221; &#8212; in the Torah portion that will be read in services across the United States this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I know, President Herzog, that your uncle also wrote a book with that title.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT HERZOG:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; But as I look out on these proud, strong Israelis in the audience, at the nation that made the desert bloom and built the Iron Dome, I see people who are growing more secure, more integrated, more confident, and more &#8212; have greater relations with their neighbors; a nation that has forged peace before and can do it again; and a nation that will never dwell alone.&nbsp; Because as long as we’re the United States, you will never, ever be alone.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as you know, there&#8217;s still so much more work to be done.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why America&#8217;s commitment to Israel’s security remains ironclad.&nbsp; Today and in the future, that commitment is not about me or any other American president.&nbsp; It springs from the deep affinity and enduring connection between our peoples.&nbsp; And it is our responsibility as leaders to nurture that bond, to ensure that it grows stronger, deeper, and broader as we navigate the challenges ahead &#8212; and they will continue to be profound and they will change.</p>



<p>And as a leader, I can say without hesitation that being known as a friend of Israel and receiving this award today is among the greatest honors of my career.&nbsp; And I mean that from the bottom of my heart. (Applause.)&nbsp; In fact &#8212;<br><br>And thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Since I know that you and I share a connection, as I said, to Ireland, I hope you forgive me for ending by quoting an Irish poet, Seamus Heaney.&nbsp; And he wrote &#8212; in “The Cure at Troy,” he said: “History says, Don’t hope on this side of the grave.&nbsp; But then, once in a lifetime, that longed-for tidal wave of justice rises up, and hope and history rhyme.”<br><br>I truly believe that we&#8217;re at one of those moments, if we get lucky and work hard, where we can make hope and history rhyme.<br><br>Israel and the United States are both places built on hope, grit, and determination.&nbsp; And I believe, together, we will stay always true to our founding values and that we can help make hope and history rhyme once more.&nbsp; But this time &#8212; this time, in one of the most dysfunctional, in the past, regions of the world where you, again, will be fully integrated and be one of the leaders.<br><br>So, Mr. President, it&#8217;s an incredible honor.&nbsp; And, as some of you heard me say, if my mother were here, she’d say, “Joey, hush up and let the man get on with his job.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>So, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>PRESIDENT HERZOG:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; So, Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (Speaks Hebrew.)<br><br>President of the State of Israel, Isaac Herzog, will bestow the Presidential Medal of Honor upon the President of the United States of America, Joe Biden.<br><br>PRESIDENT HERZOG:&nbsp; So, the Honorable President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., in recognition of the strong support for Israel you have consistently demonstrated, and the depth of the friendship our nations share, I wish to present you with the highest honor bestowed by an Israeli President, the Presidential Medal of Honor.&nbsp; This tradition was instituted by the late president and your good friend, Shimon Peres.<br><br>The accompanying certificate reads, and I begin with quoting the Bible:&nbsp; (Speaks Hebrew.)&nbsp; “With Him are wisdom and strength.&nbsp; He has counsel and understanding.”</p>



<p>The Presidential Medal of Honor is hereby awarded to the Honorable President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States of America for his true friendship with the State of Israel, the people of Israel, and the Jewish people; his uncompromising, decades-long commitment to Israel&#8217;s security; his contributions to deepening, strengthening, and enhancing the strong and unwavering alliance between Israel and the United States of America; and his struggle against anti-Israeli and antisemitic hatred around the world.”<br><br>(The Medal of Honor is presented.)&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; What a great honor.&nbsp; Thank you very, very much.<br><br>PRESIDENT HERZOG:&nbsp; A pleasure.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p> 6:14 P.M. IDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Yair Lapid of the State of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-yair-lapid-of-the-state-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 17:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57467</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waldorf AstoriaJerusalem, Israel 2:34 P.M. IDT  PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&#160; Mr. President, in March, 1965, on Dr. Martin Luther King&#8217;s famous march from Selma to Montgomery, walking beside him in the front row was a Jewish rabbi &#8212; Rabbi Abraham Joshua Heschel.&#160; When he returned home this &#8212; that day, Rabbi Heschel wrote in his diary,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Waldorf Astoria<br>Jerusalem, Israel</p>



<p>2:34 P.M. IDT </p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; Mr. President, in March, 1965, on Dr. Martin Luther King&#8217;s famous march from Selma to Montgomery, walking beside him in the front row was a Jewish rabbi &#8212; Rabbi Abraham Joshua Heschel.&nbsp; When he returned home this &#8212; that day, Rabbi Heschel wrote in his diary, “Today, I felt my legs were praying.”<br><br>In the State of Israel, Mr. President, our legs pray every single day.&nbsp; Nothing is &#8212; in our lives is taken for granted.&nbsp; My father was a Jewish child in the Budapest ghetto, hiding from those who tried to kill him.<br><br>The fact that I am standing here today did not happen by itself.&nbsp; We learned the lesson, Mr. President: At all times, Israel must be strong, free, and safe, with a powerful army that can defend our citizens.<br><br>Be it Joshua crossing the Jordan River or Dr. King crossing the Alabama River, the principle is the same: If you want your independence, your hands must defend you and your legs must pray for you.&nbsp; You must march fearlessly towards the river.&nbsp;<br><br>This past year, with Russia&#8217;s unjustified invasion of Ukraine, with the Iranian nuclear threat becoming more dangerous, and with the threats of terrorism worldwide, we were all reminded of something: In order to protect freedom, sometimes force must be used.&nbsp; Nobody wants that, but neither can we shy away from it, on the side of terrorists and people who will not hesitate to exploit any weakness, people who do not &#8212; who do not play by the rules.<br><br>Those of us who were fortunate enough to be born free people sometimes do not understand the intensity of the hatred behind the attack on democracy.<br><br>What we &#8212; did we do to them?&nbsp; What makes them crash planes into skyscrapers in New York and fire rockets at kindergartens in the city of Sderot?&nbsp; The answer is fear.<br><br>What scares them the most is that their citizens, their people can see us, can see our quality of life &#8212; the dynamism and creativity of our economy, the rights of women and the LGBTQ community, freedom of religion, freedom of speech.&nbsp;<br><br>Our way of life is what threatens them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s what makes the Iranian regime develop is &#8212; its nuclear program, Hezbollah aim its missiles at us, and terrorist organizations worldwide send suicide bombers.&nbsp; They want to destroy the only Jewish state in the world.&nbsp; That &#8212; we will never let that happen.&nbsp;<br><br>Words will not stop them, Mr. President.&nbsp; Diplomacy will not stop them.&nbsp; The only thing that will stop Iran is knowing that the &#8212; if they continue to develop their nuclear program, the free world will use force.&nbsp; The only way to stop them is to put a credible military threat on the table.<br><br>You have said many times, Mr. President, that big countries do not bluff.&nbsp; I completely agree.&nbsp; It should not be a bluff but the real thing.&nbsp; The Iranian regime must know that if they continue to deceive the world, they will pay a heavy price.&nbsp;<br><br>Here in the Middle East, we have an alternative now.&nbsp; It is growing and gaining power.&nbsp; We are creating an alliance of moderate countries that believe in peace, that believe that our children deserve the opportunity to live a better life.<br><br>From here, from Jerusalem &#8212; the eternal capital of the State of Israel &#8212; you will travel to Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; Your visit to Saudi Arabia is important for Israel and for the entire region, for our security and for the future and prosp- &#8212; prosperity of the Middle East.</p>



<p>We send with you, to all the nations of the region &#8212; including, of course, the Palestinians &#8212; a message of peace.&nbsp;<br><br>Israel wants peace and believes in peace.&nbsp; We will never yield an inch of our security.&nbsp; We are obligated to be cautious at every step.&nbsp; But to any country, any nation that wants peace and normalization with us, we say, “<em>Ahlan wa sahlan</em>. <em>Shalom</em>.&nbsp; Welcome.”<br><br>Mr. President, you will meet with the leaders of Saudi Arabia, Qatar, Kuwait, Oman, and Iraq.&nbsp; I would like you to pass them all a message from us:<br><br>Our hand is outstretched for peace.&nbsp; We are ready to share our technology and experience, ready for our people to meet and learn about one another, ready for our scientists to collaborate and our businesses to cooperate.<br><br>The Book of Psalms says all of this in one verse.&nbsp; Chapter 29 reads, “(Speaks Hebrew.)&nbsp; The Lord will give strength to His people.&nbsp; The Lord will bless His people with peace.”<br><br>If we are strong, if we are determined, if the world understands that we will not hesitate to defend ourselves and our values, peace can come.<br><br>Mr. President, our relationship runs deep.&nbsp; It crosses party lines.&nbsp; It connects not only our governments but also our peoples.<br><br>This friendship is one of the cornerstones of Israel&#8217;s national security.&nbsp; It is moving, and it is certainly not taken for granted.<br><br>Throughout all your years in public service, you were one of the chief architects of this relationship.&nbsp; For that, you have the everlasting gratitude of the people of Zion.<br><br>Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Prime Minister.&nbsp; An eloquent statement.<br><br>I&#8217;m honored to be back here in the capital of Israel.</p>



<p>As I said yesterday, I’ve met every Prime Minister</p>



<p>since Golda Meir, and it was a pleasure to be able to spend some time with you today and to get to know you better.</p>



<p>Mr. Prime Minister, a deep love and respect for Israel has only taken a deeper hold of my heart and my gut since I first visited here back in 1973 as a young senator.<br><br></p>



<p>I’m returning for my 10th visit as Pres- &#8212; this time, as President of the United States.&nbsp; But I’ve never forgotten</p>



<p>what Prime Minister Meir told me when I was a brand new junior senator from the state of Delaware.&nbsp; It was just weeks before the Yom Kippur War, and she could see on my face that I was worried.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we stood before the press taking questions and pictures, she looked at me, and without press hearing, she said, “Don’t look so worried, Senator.&nbsp; Israel has a secret weapon.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I looked at her as I turned my head, and she was tell- &#8212; I just looked at her and she said, &#8220;We have nowhere else to go.”&nbsp; I&#8217;ll never forget what she told me.&nbsp; That was nearly 50 years ago.&nbsp; Fifty years ago, the threats then were real.&nbsp; And the threats to Israel remain real today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The scourge of antisemitism still marches around the world, and we must never forget the horrors which an unchecked hatred can lead.</p>



<p>And that’s why I immediately &#8212; when I returned, I wanted to visit Yad Vashem &#8212; when I landed yesterday &#8212; to bear witness, to remember, to renew our vow of: never &#8212; never again.</p>



<p>At the same time, the Israeli &#8212; the Israel of today is not the Israel of 50 years ago.</p>



<p>You’ve cultivated new resources, capabilities, new relationships, including a growing integration with neighbors in the region.</p>



<p>You have new tools that keep Israel strong and secure.&nbsp; You have an ironclad commitment from the United States of America to Israel’s security.&nbsp; An ironclad commitment.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll make sure that Israel can defend itself by itself.</p>



<p>When I was Vice President under President Obama, we passed a record-setting agreement for Israel’s security &#8212; $38 billion over a 10-year period.</p>



<p>And I was proud that, last year, we also provided an additional $1 billion to replenish Israel’s Iron Dome supplies, making 2022 the largest single year of military assistance that Israel has ever received.</p>



<p>Yesterday, I viewed some of Israel’s Iron Dome technology, as well as the very promising new Iron Beam technology &#8212; a laser-enabled missile defense system.&nbsp; These technologies and advancements are critical.&nbsp; They&#8217;re critical because every rocket that is intercepted is a potential life &#8212; perhaps more &#8212; that has been saved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as we move forward together, partners in both security and in innovation, the United States and Israel defense sectors will cooperate in new high-energy laser weapons systems that can defend Israel &#8212; Israeli lives, as well as the lives of American service members.</p>



<p>Israel and the United States also stand together to defend the fundamental values and underwrite global security, prosperity, and freedom, not just for us but for many around the world.</p>



<p>And Putin’s assault on Ukraine is a challenge to the peace and stability everywhere in the world.&nbsp; Putin’s war must be a strategic failure, and the free world must sustain our resolve to help Ukraine defend its democracy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States will continue to support Ukraine and the Ukrainian people who have been devastated and displaced by the Russian violence.</p>



<p>Today, you and I also discussed America’s commitment to ensuring Iran never obtains a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a vital security interest to both Israel and the United States and, I would add, for the rest of the world as well.</p>



<p>I continue to believe that diplomacy is the best way to achieve this outcome.</p>



<p>And we’ll continue to work with Israel to counter other threats from Iran throughout the region, including its support for terrorism and the ballistic missile program that continues, and the proliferation of weapons to terrorists and proxies like Hezbollah.</p>



<p>We’ll also continue building on the Abraham Accords, which I strongly support, because they deepen &#8212; they deepen Israel’s integration into the broader region and establish lasting ties for business, cooperation, and tourism.</p>



<p>We’ve just completed the first leaders’ summit among Israel, India, the United States, and the United Arab Emirates</p>



<p>to deepen the economic ties between the Middle East and the Indo-Pacific, to create new partnerships to tackle global challenges, like food insecurity and clean energy technology.</p>



<p>Regional integration is also the goal of the historic Negev Forum, which took place here in Israel this past March.</p>



<p>Israel’s integration in the region, Israel’s peace with its neighbors &#8212; these are essential goals.</p>



<p>Tomorrow I’ll be the first American President to fly from Israel directly to Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; That represents important progress.</p>



<p>And when I see the Saudi leadership tomorrow, I’ll be carrying a direct message &#8212; a message of peace and extraordinary opportunities that a more stable and integrated region could bring to the region and, quite frankly, the whole world.</p>



<p>As we work together toward greater integration &#8212; greater integration, we’ll also continue to work for &#8212; toward a lasting negotiated peace between the State of Israel and the Palestinian people.</p>



<p>Israel must remain an independent, democratic, Jewish state &#8212; the ultimate guarantee and guarantor of security of the Jewish people not only in Israel but the entire world.&nbsp; I believe that to my core.</p>



<p>And the best way to achieve that remains a two-state solution for two people, both of whom have deep and ancient roots in this land, living side-by-side in peace and security.&nbsp; Both states fully respecting the equal rights of their citizens;&nbsp;both people enjoying equal measures of freedom.</p>



<p>And any more that takes us further from that outcome &#8212; I believe &#8212; anything is detrimental to the long-term security of Israel.</p>



<p>Prime Minister Lapid, Israel and the United States are natural partners because we share the same values.&nbsp; Our people share the same innovative spirit, the same determination to preserve and persevere through every single challenge.</p>



<p>That’s why we’re launching a new High-Level Strategic Dialogue on Technology that’s going to help Israel and the United States harness critical and emerging technologies and apply them to issues that matter most to our mutual futures.</p>



<p>So thank you, Mr. <s>President</s> [Prime Minister], for welcoming me back, for fostering the enduring bonds, and continuing them, that link the people of Israel and the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s what this visit is about: affirming those ties that stretch back to just 11 minutes &#8212; 11 minutes after Israel declared statehood, when the United States became the first country in the world to recognize Israel.&nbsp; And I assure you, it will be the last country in the world ever to walk away from Israel.<br><br>Ties that have grown deeper and broader with each passing year and now encompass a 21st-century partnership, one grounded on ageless values and looking squarely at the future.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re here to stay, Mr. President &#8212; Mr. Prime Minister.&nbsp; Like it or not, we’re with you.&nbsp; There’s no way out.<br><br>I want to thank you very, very much for your hospitality.&nbsp; And I mean it from the bottom of my heart that your security, the security &#8212; the &#8212; is going to determine the security of Jewish people around the world for the rest of the world.&nbsp; It’s critical.&nbsp; And we’re in it with you.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Mr. President.&nbsp; And before we move on to the &#8212; a question, there was a technical change on the stage.</p>



<p>(An adjustment is made to the onstage technical equipment.)</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; These guys work awful hard.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; Yes, we&#8217;re just standing here.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; We will now be taking questions from the press.&nbsp; The first one to ask a question to Ms. Gili Cohen from Channel 11, Israeli television.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; I want to ask: Will you set a deadline for the nuclear talks or define a certain stage when you will say there is no more opportunity to revive the nuclear deal?&nbsp; And what will happen afterwards?<br><br>And another question, sir.&nbsp; You’ll visit, tomorrow, East Jerusalem, and you won&#8217;t be accompanied by an Israeli official.&nbsp; Does this represent a change in your administration&#8217;s view regarding the recognition of Jerusalem as the capital of Israel and if East Jerusalem is part of it?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; The answer to your last question is no.<br><br>With regard to your first question, we&#8217;ve laid out for the people &#8212; for the leadership of Iran what we&#8217;re willing to accept in order to get back in the JCPOA.&nbsp; We&#8217;re waiting for their response.&nbsp; When that recur- &#8212; when that will come, I&#8217;m not certain.&nbsp; But we are not going to wait forever.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Mr. President, do you want to &#8212;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; The question was for the President.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Mr. President, do you want to call on the next question?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I was given a list here.&nbsp; Steve Holland of Reuters.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; There is some opposition back home to your meeting with Saudi leaders this week.&nbsp; What will you say to Saudi leaders, specifically to Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, about the Khashoggi murder and other human rights practices?<br><br>And if I may, Prime Minister Lapid, how close are you to an agreement with Saudi Arabia to gain overflight rights?&nbsp; And should we expect that soon?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; With regard to the question you asked me, my views on Khashoggi have &#8212; they’ve been absolutely, positively clear.&nbsp; And I have never been quiet about talking about human rights.<br><br>The question that I&#8217;m &#8212; the reason I&#8217;m going to Saudi Arabia, though, is much broader.&nbsp; It’s to promote U.S. interests &#8212; promote U.S. interests in a way that I think we have an opportunity to reassert what I think we made a mistake of walking away from: our influence in the Middle East.<br><br>I&#8217;m going to be meeting with nine other heads of state.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just &#8212; it happens to be in Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; And so, there are so many issues at stake that I want to make clear that we can continue to lead in the region and not create a vacuum, a vacuum that is filled by China and/or Russia, against the interests of both Israel and the United States and many other countries.<br><br>And so the purpose of the visit is to &#8212; is to coordinate with nine heads of state what are in U.S. interests and I believe in Israel&#8217;s interests as well.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you don&#8217;t expect to bring up human rights?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Well, let&#8217;s let the Prime Minister &#8212;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I will bring up &#8212; I always bring up human rights.&nbsp; I always bring up human rights.&nbsp; But my position on Khashoggi has been so clear.&nbsp; If anyone doesn&#8217;t understand it in Saudi Arabia and everywhere else, then they haven&#8217;t been around for a while.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; About the overflights of Saudi Arabia, of course, as I was saying in my speech, we are all for promoting normalizations with every country in the region that it is possible.&nbsp; But since the President is going to Saudi Arabia, and he &#8212; there will be a finalization of the issues over there, I will let the President finalize this when he&#8217;s in Jeddah.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, Prime Minister.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m optimistic.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br><br></p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; And the next question will come from Ms. Tal&nbsp; Schneider from Times of Israel.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, hello.&nbsp; Thank you for being in Jerusalem.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good to see you.<br><br>Israelis have been waiting to hear developments on the Visa Waiver Program.&nbsp; We know that there are hurdles but &#8212; to get there.&nbsp; But can you set a deadline after which Israelis will be granted with a waiver to enter the U.S.?&nbsp; Will you bring this issue with the opposition leader, Netanyahu, when you meet him today?<br><br>And another question for our prime minister: There is a discussion about regional defense cooperation that includes Israel and the Saudis, but we hear that there are technical difficulties as well as other reservations from the Saudis with respect to defense system, which means it&#8217;s mostly about Israel sharing its intelligence, its intel.&nbsp; How do you see the cooperation moving along with those problems?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; With regard to your question to me, we are working very, very, very hard to eliminate the lack of precision in the applications, many times, for the visa program.&nbsp; It is my hope and expectation that in the next several months, we&#8217;ll have it worked out.</p>



<p><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; And jumping on the subject, and we urge the Israeli opposition to become &#8212; to be more responsible and help with the legislation needed to finalize this.<br><br>As for your question, it is no secret that we&#8217;re doing our best, with our American friends, to work on a regional security architecture.&nbsp; So this was no secret.&nbsp; The details of this apparently are, so I&#8217;m not going to go into details on this.&nbsp;<br><br>But we are working with everybody we can in order to promote regional security, especially facing Iran&#8217;s regime and the terror policy they bring to the table.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; The next person to ask a question, I guess &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; is Nadia.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Nadia Bilbassy of Al Arabiya Television.&nbsp; Allow me to press you a little bit on Iran, if I may.</p>



<p><br>You visited the &#8212;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; No, I’m not going to allow that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; We got to &#8212; we got to walk off.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; You are &#8212; you are visiting the Middle East here in Israel and then you go into Saudi Arabia where you meeting with King Salman and other GCC leaders.<br><br>You know in advance, before you come here, their position, their concern, their fear about Iran nuclear program and Iran&#8217;s support for proxies in the region.<br><br>Tangibly, what are you offering them to assuage their fear and concern, practically?&nbsp; Is this anything that you&#8217;re offering them to make them feel comfortable that the United States are on the same page with them?<br><br>And if I may, Mr. Prime Minister, what are the differences and the similarities between you and President Biden regarding Iran?&nbsp; Do you see eye to eye on all the issues?&nbsp; You alluded to some differences just now.<br><br>And, if I may, I wanted you to confirm to us today your position in supporting the two-state solution as a caretaker Prime Minister and if should you be elected as the next prime minister of Israel.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; With regard to Iran and convincing the Saudis and others that we’re &#8212; mean what we say is we mean what we say.&nbsp; They have an opportunity to accept this agreement that’s been laid down.&nbsp; If they don&#8217;t, we made it absolutely clear: We will not &#8212; let me say it again &#8212; we will not allow Iran to acquire a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; Well, with regards to the question about Iran, we have an open discussion about what is the best way to deal with it.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a light between us in terms of &#8212; these are all means to an end.<br><br>We cannot allow Iran to become nuclear.&nbsp; Israel asserts the right to act freely on the subject.&nbsp; But we are, of course, discussing everything with our greatest ally, which is the United States.<br><br>About the two-state solution, I haven&#8217;t changed my position.&nbsp; A two-state solution is a guarantee for a strong democratic state of Israel with a Jewish majority.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; This concludes the signing ceremony and the press conference.&nbsp; Please remain seated until the leaders have left the room.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you all so much.<br><br>2:59 P.M. IDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President Herzog of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-herzog-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met with President Isaac Herzog of Israel today ahead of the Israeli Medal of Honor ceremony this evening. The leaders discussed several issues including the United States’ ironclad support for Israel’s security, their commitment to working together to counter Iran’s destabilizing activities, and efforts to promote regional integration to widen the circle of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met with President Isaac Herzog of Israel today ahead of the Israeli Medal of Honor ceremony this evening. The leaders discussed several issues including the United States’ ironclad support for Israel’s security, their commitment to working together to counter Iran’s destabilizing activities, and efforts to promote regional integration to widen the circle of peace. President Biden and President Herzog reaffirmed the deep bonds and enduring friendship between our two nations and our people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves North Dakota Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/14/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-north-dakota-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of North Dakota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and flooding during the period of April 22 to May 25, 2022. Federal funding is available&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of North Dakota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and flooding during the period of April 22 to May 25, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to State, tribal, eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe winter storm and flooding in the counties of Adams, Barnes, Billings, Bottineau,&nbsp; Burke, Cavalier, Dickey, Divide, Dunn, Foster, Golden Valley, Grand Forks, Grant, Griggs, Hettinger, Kidder, LaMoure, Logan, McHenry, McIntosh, McKenzie, McLean, Mountrail, Nelson, Oliver, Pembina, Ramsey, Ransom, Renville, Richland, Rolette, Sargent, Steele, Stutsman, Towner, Traill, Walsh, Ward, Wells, and Williams.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Alana B. Kuhn as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the State and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Minnesota Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/14/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-minnesota-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Minnesota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, straight-line winds, and flooding during the period of April 22 to June 15, 2022. Federal funding is available to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Minnesota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, straight-line winds, and flooding during the period of April 22 to June 15, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storms, straight-line winds, and flooding in the counties of Beltrami, Clearwater, Cook, Kittson, Koochiching, Lake, Lake of the Woods, Mahnomen, Marshall, Norman, Pennington, Polk, Red Lake, Roseau, and St. Louis and the Bois Forte Band of Chippewa, Leech Lake Band of Ojibwe, Red Lake Nation, and the White Earth Nation.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures in all areas within the state.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Brian F. Schiller as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp;FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Lapid of the State of Israel After Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/14/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-lapid-of-the-state-of-israel-after-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 15:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waldorf Astoria JerusalemJerusalem, Israel 11:56 A.M. IDT  PRIME MINISTER LAPID:  I don’t think we&#8217;re going to tell them what we talked about. PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; We talked American baseball. PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&#160; That is correct.&#160; We had a very long conversation about baseball, which I know nothing about.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And we didn’t mention Iran or Saudi&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Waldorf Astoria Jerusalem<br>Jerusalem, Israel</p>



<p>11:56 A.M. IDT </p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:  I don’t think we&#8217;re going to tell them what we talked about.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We talked American baseball.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; That is correct.&nbsp; We had a very long conversation about baseball, which I know nothing about.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And we didn’t mention Iran or Saudi Arabia or all those issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Folks, I want to thank &#8212; I want to thank the Prime Minister.&nbsp; We had a good and beginning of what&#8217;s going to be a long &#8212; God willing &#8212; relationship, a candid conversation about both the problems and the opportunities both our countries face, particularly in the Middle East.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we talked about how important it was &#8212; I talked about how important it was, from my perspective, for Israel to be totally integrated into the region and completely integrated into the region.</p>



<p>And we &#8212; we are &#8212; I guarantee you our administration &#8211;and I think the vast majority of the American public, not just my administration &#8212; is completely devoted to Israel&#8217;s security without any ifs, ands, or buts &#8212; without any doubts about it.</p>



<p>And we also talked about the fact that we have a full day ahead of us, including a virtual summit with the &#8212; with India and the UAE.&nbsp; The four of us are going to have a discussion after this meeting is over.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and that’s &#8212; we talked about a lot of things but mainly related to developing a personal friendship and the long-lasting commitment to both our countries, to one another.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; It is great, Mr. President.&nbsp; Of course, we’ve discussed your &#8212; we also talked shop about Saudi Arabia and your trip there, which is extremely important to Israel, trying to build an even more moderate coalition here in the Middle East &#8212; long needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we discussed the Iranian threat and what we think is the right thing to do in order to make sure, which is something we share, there will be no nuclear Iran.&nbsp; This is not only a threat on Israel but to the world, to the globe.</p>



<p>And we discussed some other issues we&#8217;re going to keep to ourselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDEN BIDEN:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>12:00 P.M. IDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden, Prime Minister Lapid, President bin Zayed Al Nahyan, and Prime Minister Modi at I2U2 Virtual&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/14/remarks-by-president-biden-prime-minister-lapid-president-bin-zayed-al-nahyan-and-prime-minister-modi-at-i2u2-virtual-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 13:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waldorf Astoria JerusalemJerusalem, Israel 1:35 P.M. IDT&#160; MODERATOR:&#160; (In progress) &#8212; welcome the President of the United States of America, the Honorable Joseph R. Biden, Jr, and joining us virtually: the Honorable President of the United Arab Emirates, His Royal Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan; the Prime Minister of the Republic of India,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Waldorf Astoria Jerusalem<br>Jerusalem, Israel</p>



<p>1:35 P.M. IDT&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (In progress) &#8212; welcome the President of the United States of America, the Honorable Joseph R. Biden, Jr, and joining us virtually: the Honorable President of the United Arab Emirates, His Royal Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan; the Prime Minister of the Republic of India, His Excellency Narendra Modi.</p>



<p>We will begin today&#8217;s ITU2 Summit with opening statements from each of the distinguished leaders followed by closed dialogue.</p>



<p>It is my honor to invite the Honorable President of the United Arab Emirates, His Royal Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan to deliver his opening statement.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; We can’t hear him.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; We seem to be having a technical difficulty.&nbsp; Please bear with us.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIN ZAYED AL NAHYAN:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Your Excellency, Prime Minister of the State of Israel; (inaudible) the United States of America; Your Excellency, Prime Minister of the Republic of India: Greetings to you all.<br><br>Let me begin by thanking the State of Israel for hosting this first I2U2 Leaders’ Summit.<br><br>I also thank the leadership of the United States and India for their participation in the summit and their continued support for the success of the group’s work (inaudible).<br><br>This summit is a clear evidence of the great opportunity for cooperation between countries and economies with shared value and goals centered around peace, tolerance, and prosperity.<br><br>Our countries do not share geographical border, yet they converge (inaudible) for peace, and their joint action to achieve wellbeing and prosperity.<br><br>We, in the UAE, believe that equality offer the best way to achieve peace, security, and progress, especially when governments and people have the will and courage to build partnership and face challenges.<br><br>We also believe that only partnership can overcome today&#8217;s conflicts and overlapping challenges, the most important of which are food and energy security, climate change, and healthcare.<br><br>This is important in the first project of our (inaudible) team, which have focused on food, climate-smart agriculture, solar and wind energy, and energy storage.<br><br>As I extend my appreciation to the leaders of the group and the (inaudible) team of the four countries for what has been achieved, I would like to emphasize the importance of giving priority during the coming period to research and development, healthcare and space.<br><br>I also call for building on the strength that each of our countries (inaudible) and lead (inaudible).<br><br>Dear leader, I look forward today to a fruitful summit and, subsequently, to work with you within the I2U2 group at the bilateral level and within other international platform, the most important of which are the G20 Summit and the Conference of the Party that the UAE will host at its 28th session next year.<br><br>I also hope that our whole team will be a model for those who desire peace and prosperity, and will provide evidence for the great opportunity (inaudible) and squandered by blind extremism at the expense of people eager to live a good life.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, President.&nbsp; It is my honor to invite the Prime Minister of the State of Israel, His Excellency Yair Lapid, to deliver his opening statement.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; Thank you, the Honorable President of the United States, Joe Biden; the Honorable President of the United Arab Emirates, His Royal Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan; the Honorable Prime Minister of India, Narendra Modi.<br><br>Friends, this group was born several months ago during a dinner at the home of the UAE ambassador in Washington, D.C.&nbsp; We sat around the table and spoke about how, after we get control over the pandemic, anyone trying to go back to how things used to be would fail.&nbsp; Anyone who understands that we live in a new world with new challenges would succeed and flourish.<br><br>That dinner was on a Wednesday evening.&nbsp; A few days later, in what might be a world record in the field of international relations, my friend, Dr. Jaishankar, the Minister of External Affairs of India, was already in my office in Jerusalem; Tony Blinken and Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed were on Zoom.&nbsp; And we held the first summit of this quad &#8212; the I2U2 forum.<br><br>Our starting point was that, in the new world we live in, we need to improve our ability to cooperate quickly to make the most of our comparative advantages to put the right advanced tech together with the right resources.<br><br>We need to think in new terms when it comes to energy, food security and water, tech, defense, and trade.&nbsp; Each one of our countries brings very different challenges and very different qualities to the table.&nbsp; But that is what makes our potential even greater.</p>



<p>In the 21st century, challenges are local but solutions are global.</p>



<p>Let me give you two quick examples.&nbsp; The entire world is dealing with issues relating to food security.&nbsp; The combination of the climate crisis, the war in Europe, and the COVID-19 pandemic has created global food insecurity.&nbsp; Food security is going to be the main issue in Africa, in Latin America, in East Asia, and, of course, in the Middle East.</p>



<p>An initiative like the food corridor between India and the UAE, which was put together by this group, is a clear example of a creative solution to a problem we&#8217;re all &#8212; we are all facing.&nbsp; The fast transportation of food and preservation technologies, the ability to connect relative advantages together &#8212; this is the solution to the problem.</p>



<p>Another example is the solar and wind energy storage project.&nbsp; In this case, as well, the idea is to make the most of technological capabilities, some of which are still being developed, in order to deal with an energy market that is facing a serious crisis.</p>



<p>Since the war in Ukraine broke out, each one of us has had to deal with the crisis on the local level.&nbsp; Its effects on cost of living has been immediate and dramatic.&nbsp; And, of course, this has political implications.</p>



<p>Real solutions will only come through cooperation between countries that know how to put together brainpower, knowledge, and resources on the same table.</p>



<p>I would like to emphasize: This is not a philanthropic group.&nbsp; We want to change the world for the better, but we are also creating relative advantages for our countries, for our businesses, for our science sector.&nbsp; In both projects that I mentioned, lists of local companies, relevant technologies have been already &#8212; have already been shared.&nbsp; Our goal is for the private market to be a full partner in this initiative.</p>



<p>This group is interesting because we are four very different countries, but when we started talking, it became clear we all want the same things: for our children to be warm in the winter, for them to have food on the table and clean water from the tap, for them to enjoy a quality education and advanced healthcare and transportation infrastructure.&nbsp; We also want to reduce the damage our generation inflicted on climate and the environment.</p>



<p>These are big challenges. &nbsp;No single country, no matter how big or how rich, can deal with them alone.&nbsp; On the other hand, I also believe &#8212; and this is part of the idea behind this meeting &#8212; that groups that are too big may end up being ineffective.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This quad is, in my view, the correct model.&nbsp; Our advantages are clear to one another, and so are all our needs.&nbsp; We can create enough flexibility and a mechanism that can make fast and smart decisions.&nbsp; At the same time, we can always find ways to create ad hoc connections with countries that want to advance projects with us.</p>



<p>The projects I mentioned are just be- &#8212; are just the beginning; the list is ongoing.&nbsp; Our role as leaders is to push our teams as hard as possible, to research the fields in which real change can be made, to examine new projects, to bring them to the table, to connect them with the scientific and business communities.</p>



<p>The world is watching this meeting.&nbsp; This shows that something special is happening here &#8212; a new kind of economic and regional cooperation &#8212; cooperation that is more flexible and better adapted to the problems we face.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The diplomatic and economic results that we all emerge from &#8212; that will emerge from this meeting will highlight our commitment to a new kind of cooperation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this partnership, each country and each partner brings their own strength so that the whole is greater than the sum of its parts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is just the beginning.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, Prime Minister.&nbsp; It is my honor to invite the President of the United States of America, the Honorable Joseph R. Biden, Jr., to deliver his opening statement.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Prime Minister Lapid, for convening this group for the first time at a leaders level.</p>



<p>Prime Minister Modi, President bin Zayed, thank you for the work you&#8217;re doing deepening the linkage and the muscle cooperation between critical partners in the Middle East and Indo-Pacific to deliver important &#8212; very important projects for all our peoples.</p>



<p>The simple truth is this: The challenge we face in the world, in our world, in the 21st century demand that we find new ways of working together, whether it&#8217;s accelerating climate crisis &#8212; dealing with the accelerating climate crisis, which is being felt here in the Middle East every single day; or growing food insecurity and volatile energy markets made worse by Russia&#8217;s brutal and unprovoked attack against its neighbor, Ukraine; or, as we&#8217;ve all experienced firsthand over the past two years, tackling the health security needs and economic fallout from a global pandemic.</p>



<p>All these issues &#8212; all these issues require cooperation and coordination.&nbsp; And none of us &#8212; none of us can mount a comprehensive response on our own.&nbsp; The more we work together, the more we&#8217;ll see the benefits multiply and grow to advance our shared commitment to peace, stability, and growing prosperity.&nbsp; They all go together.</p>



<p>When our foreign ministers first got together in this format last October, I think we all immediately understood the potential to advance a common agenda.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about demonstrating the importance of practical impacts of building Israel&#8217;s normalization and economic integration using these trusted partnerships to crack down on common challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our nations represent some of the most innovative, technologically capable, and entrepreneurial people on the planet.&nbsp; At every step &#8212; at every step, we should be asking, “What can we achieve together?”</p>



<p>The first two projects that we&#8217;re tackling together on food security and clean energy are designed to take on two of the most urgent crises affecting people around the globe: food insecurity.&nbsp; The UAE’s investment to develop integrated agricultural parks across India with the support of the American and Israeli private sector experts has the potential to sustainably increase India&#8217;s food yields in the region threefold in just five years.</p>



<p>India is a major, major food producer in the world.&nbsp; Think of the beneficial impacts this will have on India&#8217;s farmers and the people suffering from hunger and malnutrition in the region.</p>



<p>Similarly, the United States has already funded a feasible &#8212; a feasibility study for a hybrid renewable energy project in India to develop 300 megawatts of wind and solar capacity as well as battery storage.</p>



<p>With our four nations, our four nations working together to unite our expertise and drive private sector investment, this is going to help India reach its climate and energy goal of 500 <s>megawatts</s> [gigawatts] of non-fossil fuel capacity by 2030.</p>



<p>Our challenge &#8212; our challenge together is to deliver real results that people can feel in their everyday lives.</p>



<p>Another ker- &#8212; key area where we can make big differences is infrastructure.&nbsp; There’s an enormous need around the world</p>



<p>for infrastructure &#8212; infrastructure done the right way: transparently, in partnership with the communities that are being served.&nbsp; Right now, there’s a vacuum.</p>



<p>So over the next few years, this group is going to work to identify new infrastructure projects that we can invest in and develop together.&nbsp; Together.</p>



<p>This meeting is just a first step, a chance to demonstrate the value of this new format for cooperation between our four nations.&nbsp; And I’m looking forward to staying closely connected and engaged at the leaders’ level as we build out the scope of the I2U2 and work together for everyone.&nbsp; We can do a great deal if we stick together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I want to thank you all for having this &#8212; agreeing to proceed this way.&nbsp; I think we can do some great things.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; It is my honor to invite the Prime Minister of the Republic of India, His Excellency Narendra Modi, to deliver his opening statement.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER MODI:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Your Excellency Prime Minister Lapid, your Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Your Excellency President Biden:</p>



<p>First of all, my warmest congratulations and best wishes to Prime Minister Lapid on assuming the office of Prime Minister.&nbsp; My heartfelt thanks to him as well for hosting today&#8217;s summit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This truly is a meeting of strategic partners.&nbsp; We are all good friends as well, and there are a lot of similarities in our approach and in our interests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Excellencies, Your Highness: The I2U2 has established a positive agenda from its very first summit today.  We have identified joint projects in several areas and have also made a roadmap to take them forward.  In the I2U2 framework, we have agreed to increase joint investment in six important areas: water, energy, transport, space, health, and food security.  It is clear that both the vision and agenda of I2U2 are progressive and practical.</p>



<p>We can give an impetus to our agenda by mobilizing the mutual strengths of our countries that is capital expertise and markets, and we can make an important contribution in this way to the global economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the midst of increasing global uncertainties, our cooperative framework is also a good model for practical cooperation.&nbsp; I am sure that with the I2U2, we will make an important contribution at a global level in the areas of energy security, food security, and economic growth.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you to the distinguished leaders.&nbsp; We will now continue to the closed dialogue between the leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The live broadcast will end here.&nbsp; Thank you to the press.&nbsp; Please kindly make your way out.</p>



<p>1:55 P.M. IDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
