<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 15:16:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Biden-⁠Harris Administration Celebrates the Contributions of Dreamers on Ten-Year Anniversary of&#160;DACA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/15/the-biden-harris-administration-celebrates-the-contributions-of-dreamers-on-ten-year-anniversary-of-daca/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 15:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By Betsy Lawrence On June 15, 2012, the Department of Homeland Security announced the&#160;Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) policy, which has allowed hundreds of thousands of noncitizens who were brought to the United States as children to live, study, and work in our communities—contributing to our economy and the future of our country—without fear&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><strong>By Betsy Lawrence</strong></p>



<p>On June 15, 2012, the Department of Homeland Security announced the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dhs.gov/xlibrary/assets/s1-exercising-prosecutorial-discretion-individuals-who-came-to-us-as-children.pdf">Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) policy</a>, which has allowed hundreds of thousands of noncitizens who were brought to the United States as children to live, study, and work in our communities—contributing to our economy and the future of our country—without fear of removal.&nbsp;&nbsp;Today, on the 10<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;Anniversary of DACA, the Biden-Harris Administration celebrates the remarkable contributions of Dreamers and DACA recipients, reaffirms its commitment to preserving this landmark policy, and calls on Congress to pass legislation to provide lasting protections to Dreamers.</p>



<p><strong>Economic Contributions and Educational Achievements of DACA Recipients</strong></p>



<p>DACA has profoundly improved the lives and economic circumstances of individual recipients and their families—and by extension, the communities in which they live, and our country as a whole.&nbsp;&nbsp;Since 2012, approximately 825,000 individuals have been granted DACA.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>DACA recipients have increased earning potential</em>.&nbsp;&nbsp;According to a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.utsa.edu/today/2021/10/story/study-daca-protection.html">2021 study by the University of Texas at San Antonio</a>, DACA beneficiaries experienced increases in college enrollment and degree completions, as well as more professional job opportunities, as compared to their non-DACA-eligible counterparts.&nbsp;&nbsp;During the period of 2012 to 2016—</p>



<ul><li>the number of DACA recipients with a Bachelor’s degree tripled;</li></ul>



<ul><li>professional job attainment for DACA recipients grew by 34%; and</li><li>the incomes of DACA recipients more than doubled.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>The benefits of this increase in prosperity extend well beyond DACA recipients and their families.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/article/the-demographic-and-economic-impacts-of-daca-recipients-fall-2021-edition/#:~:text=DACA%20has%20enabled%20recipients%20to,in%20their%20communities%20and%20nationwide.">DACA households have significant spending power</a>—they own more than 68,000 homes across the country, contribute $760 million in mortgage payments and $2.5 billion in rental payments annually, and pay $6.2 billion in federal taxes and $3.3 billion in state and local taxes each year.</p>



<p><em>DACA recipients enrich our lives and make us safer</em>.&nbsp;&nbsp;Approximately 343,000 DACA recipients are&nbsp;<a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/article/the-demographic-and-economic-impacts-of-daca-recipients-fall-2021-edition/">employed in industries deemed essential</a>&nbsp;by the&nbsp;Department of Homeland Security. This includes an estimated 20,000 educators in our nation’s schools and classrooms, 34,000 healthcare workers, and 100,000 food supply chain workers who have worked tirelessly to support and sustain us during the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>DACA strengthens American families</em>. With the peace of mind that comes with protection from removal, DACA keeps families together.&nbsp;&nbsp;An estimated 300,000 U.S. citizen children have at least one parent with DACA, and&nbsp;<a href="https://americanprogress.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/DACA-Survey-20201.pdf?_ga=2.16623926.1462940483.1654022316-1443532221.1653581699">roughly three-fourths of DACA recipients have a U.S. citizen child, sibling, spouse, or parent</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Economic Benefits of Permanent Protections for Dreamers</strong></p>



<p>Of the 825,000 noncitizens who have been granted DACA since 2012,&nbsp;<a href="https://sgp.fas.org/crs/homesec/R46764.pdf">76,000 have since become lawful permanent residents (green card holders)</a>&nbsp;and approximately&nbsp;<a href="https://sgp.fas.org/crs/homesec/R46764.pdf">4,000 have gone on to become naturalized U.S. citizens</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;While strengthening and fortifying DACA is essential, providing permanent protections to Dreamers and others will generate even more economic value for the country.</p>



<p>At a time when American employers are struggling to find workers in critical industries, providing an opportunity for DACA recipients and Dreamers to obtain lawful status will increase the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/cea/written-materials/2021/09/17/the-economic-benefits-of-extending-permanent-legal-status-to-unauthorized-immigrants/">effective labor supply and boost economic growth</a>. Permanent protections would allow this population to contribute indefinitely to the economy in sectors that are heavily reliant on immigrant workers, such as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/cea/written-materials/2021/09/17/the-economic-benefits-of-extending-permanent-legal-status-to-unauthorized-immigrants/">agriculture, construction, and leisure and hospitality</a>, while also providing increased job mobility and better employment options with long term trajectories for growth.&nbsp;&nbsp;Studies show that new permanent residents have greater productivity than their undocumented counterparts and generate increased&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/cea/written-materials/2021/09/17/the-economic-benefits-of-extending-permanent-legal-status-to-unauthorized-immigrants/">tax revenues</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>



<p>DACA recipients enrich our nation with their deep community ties, exceptional talents, and work ethic.&nbsp;&nbsp;On&nbsp;Day Oneof this&nbsp;Administration, President Biden directed the Department&nbsp;of&nbsp;Homeland Security&nbsp;and&nbsp;the Department of Justice to take&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/preserving-and-fortifying-deferred-action-for-childhood-arrivals-daca/">all appropriate actions to “preserve and fortify” DACA</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Biden Administration has worked vigorously to defend DACA in court and is working expeditiously on a rule to codify and preserve the policy.&nbsp;&nbsp;Ultimately, however, only Congress can&nbsp;provide&nbsp;the permanent relief that&nbsp;Dreamers&nbsp;need and that our country deserves.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unfortunately, for more than two decades, efforts to pass legislation providing a durable solution for Dreamers have failed.&nbsp;&nbsp;It was 2001 when Senators Durbin and Hatch introduced the first bipartisan Dream Act, offering conditional residency and a path to permanent residence to undocumented immigrants who entered the United States as children. In March 2021, the House of Representatives passed H.R. 6, the American Dream and Promise Act, introduced by Rep. Lucille Roybal-Allard, with bipartisan support.&nbsp;&nbsp;On the ten-year anniversary of DACA, the Biden-Harris Administration celebrates DACA recipients and again calls on Congress to pass legislation to protect and&nbsp;honor Dreamers who make our country stronger.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: H.R. 3579 and ​H.R.&#160;4168</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/15/bills-signed-h-r-3579-and-h-r-4168/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 15:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Wednesday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law:&#160;H.R. 3579, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 200 East Main Street in Maroa, Illinois, as the Jeremy L. Ridlen Post Office&#160;Thank you to Representatives Rodney Davis, Cheri Bustos, and many others for their leadership.&#160;H.R. 4168, which designates the facility&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Wednesday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law:<br>&nbsp;<br>H.R. 3579, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 200 East Main Street in Maroa, Illinois, as the Jeremy L. Ridlen Post Office<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you to Representatives Rodney Davis, Cheri Bustos, and many others for their leadership.<br>&nbsp;<br>H.R. 4168, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 6223 Maple Street, in Omaha, Nebraska, as the Petty Officer 1st Class Charles Jackson French Post Office.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you to Representatives Don Bacon and Adrian Smith for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Names Nineteenth Round of Judicial Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/15/president-biden-names-nineteenth-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 14:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55536</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing seven new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country —&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing seven new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>For example, if confirmed, this slate would include the first Latino to serve on the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, the first woman of color to serve on the United States Court of Appeals for the Fifth Circuit, the first South Asian person to serve on the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, and the first openly LGBT federal district court judge in Puerto Rico.<br><br>This is President Biden’s nineteenth round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his sixth slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 105.<br><br>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies.&nbsp;And he has won confirmation of the most lower court judges for the first year of a presidency since the Kennedy Administration.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Circuit Court Press Bios</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Roopali H. Desai: Candidate for the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Roopali H. Desai is a partner at Coppersmith Brockelman where she has practiced since 2007.&nbsp; From 2006 to 2007, Ms. Desai was an associate at Lewis &amp; Roca.&nbsp;She served as a law clerk for Chief Judge Mary Schroeder on the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit from 2005 to 2006. Ms. Desai received her J.D. in 2005, her M.P.H in 2001, and her B.A. in 2000, all from the University of Arizona.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>Judge Dana M. Douglas: Candidate for the United States Court of Appeals for the Fifth Circuit</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Dana M. Douglas has been a United States Magistrate Judge on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana since 2019.&nbsp;Prior to joining the bench, Judge Douglas was a partner at Liskow &amp; Lewis, where she worked from 2001 to 2018. Judge Douglas served on the New Orleans Civil Service Commission from 2003 to 2013.&nbsp;She served as a law clerk for Judge Ivan L. R. Lemelle on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana from 2000 to 2001. Judge Douglas received her J.D. from Loyola University New Orleans School of Law in 2000 and her B.A. from Miami University of Ohio in 1997.</p>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong><u>Bradley N. Garcia: Candidate for the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Bradley N. Garcia is a Deputy Assistant Attorney General in the Department of Justice’s Office of Legal Counsel, a role he has held since 2022. Prior to joining the Department of Justice, Mr. Garcia was a partner in the Supreme Court and Appellate Practice Group&nbsp;at O’Melveny and Myers LLP, where he worked from 2013 to 2022. As an appellate litigator, Mr. Garcia represented clients in over 50 cases before federal and state appellate courts. He has argued 13 cases before federal and state appellate courts, including the U.S. Supreme Court and the U.S. Courts of Appeals for the First, Third, Fourth, Ninth, Eleventh and Federal Circuits.&nbsp; He served as a law clerk for Justice Elena Kagan on the United States Supreme Court from 2012 to 2013 and for Judge Thomas Griffith on the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit from 2011 to 2012. Mr. Garcia received his J.D., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from Harvard Law School in 2011 and his B.A. from Johns Hopkins University in 2008.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>District Court Press Bios</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>María del R. Antongiorgi-Jordán: Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of Puerto Rico</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>María del R. Antongiorgi-Jordán has served as the Clerk of Court for the United States District Court for the District of Puerto Rico since 2019. From 2018 to 2019, she was the Chief Deputy Clerk for the United States District Court for the District of Puerto Rico. Ms. Antongiorgi-Jordán was a partner at McConnell Valdés in San Juan, Puerto Rico, where she worked from 1995 to 2018. Ms. Antongiorgi-Jordán received her LL.M from Georgetown University Law Center in 1994, her J.D. from the Interamerican University of Puerto Rico in 1992, and her B.A. from Seton Hill University in 1989.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>Jerry W. Blackwell: Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of Minnesota</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Jerry W. Blackwell is a founding partner of Blackwell Burke, where he has worked since 2006. From 2000 to 2006, Mr. Blackwell was a partner at Blackwell Igbanugo in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Previously, Mr. Blackwell was a partner at Nilan Johnson Lewis from 1996 to 2000 and a partner at Robins Kaplan from 1987 to 1996. Mr. Blackwell received his J.D. in 1987 and his B.S. in 1984, both from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.</p>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong><u>Judge Gina R. Méndez-Miró Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of Puerto Rico</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Gina R. Méndez-Miró has served as a judge on the Puerto Rico Court of Appeals since 2016. From 2013 to 2016, Judge Méndez-Miró served as the Chief of Staff for the President of the Senate of Puerto Rico. She previously served in the Puerto Rico Office of Court Administration as the General Counsel and Director of the Legal Affairs Office from 2010 to 2012 and as the Director of Judicial Programs from 2008 to 2010. From 2006 to 2008, Judge Méndez-Miró served as the Assistant Attorney General for Human Resources for the Puerto Rico Department of Justice. Judge Méndez-Miró was an associate at O’Neill &amp; Borges in San Juan, Puerto Rico from 2001 to 2006. Judge Méndez-Miró received her J.D. from the University of Puerto Rico School of Law in 2001, her M.A. from Princeton University in 2000, and her B.A., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from the University of Puerto Rico in 1996.</p>



<ol type="1" start="4"><li><strong><u>Judge Camille L. Vélez-Rivé Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of Puerto Rico</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Camille L. Vélez-Rivé has served as a United States Magistrate Judge for the District of Puerto Rico since 2004. Previously, she served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Puerto Rico from 1998 to 2004. From 1994 to 1997, Judge Vélez-Rivé was an associate at Pietrantoni Méndez &amp; Alvarez in San Juan, Puerto Rico. She served as a law clerk for Justice Francisco Rebollo-López on the Supreme Court for the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico from 1993 to 1994. Judge Vélez-Rivé received her J.D., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from the University of Puerto Rico Law School in 1993 and her B.A. from Washington University in St. Louis in 1989.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-⁠Harris Administration Combatting PFAS Pollution to Safeguard Clean Drinking Water for All&#160;Americans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-combatting-pfas-pollution-to-safeguard-clean-drinking-water-for-all-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[$1 Billion from Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Made Available to Communities, First Tranche of $5 Billion to Help Communities Tackle Water Contaminants President Biden and Vice President Harris believe that every American deserves to drink clean water. But for too many communities across this country, children and families are drinking water that is contaminated with lead&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>$1 Billion from Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Made Available to Communities, First Tranche of $5 Billion to Help Communities Tackle Water Contaminants</em></p>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris believe that every American deserves to drink clean water. But for too many communities across this country, children and families are drinking water that is contaminated with lead and dangerous chemicals. That is why the President and Vice President unveiled a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/10/18/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-plan-to-combat-pfas-pollution/">plan to combat water pollution</a>&nbsp;and, six months ago, launched the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/16/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-lead-pipe-and-paint-action-plan/">Biden-Harris Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan</a>&nbsp;outlining how the Administration is leveraging $55 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to replace all of America’s lead pipes. Together, these plans represent how the President and Vice President have activated an unprecedented effort to deliver clean water across America and mobilized federal, state, and local investments to confront contamination, protect public health, and advance environmental justice.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new findings and actions that will help to protect Americans’ drinking water from contamination, including from “forever chemicals” like per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS). PFAS are&nbsp;a set of human-made chemicals that&nbsp;can cause cancer and other severe health problems, pose a serious threat across rural, suburban, and urban areas, and that disproportionately affect disadvantaged communities. PFAS are considered “forever chemicals” because they are environmentally persistent, bioaccumulative, and remain in human bodies for a long time.<br><br><strong>NEW PUBLIC HEALTH INFORMATION<br></strong><br>First,&nbsp;EPA is publishing four new drinking water lifetime health advisories for certain PFAS&nbsp;as part of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/10/18/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-plan-to-combat-pfas-pollution/#:~:text=Consistent%20with%20President%20Biden's%20commitment,from%20discharging%20PFAS%20into%20America's">President’s plan to combat PFAS pollution</a>&nbsp;and the Environmental Protection Agency’s (EPA)&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/pfas/pfas-strategic-roadmap-epas-commitments-action-2021-2024">PFAS Roadmap</a>.&nbsp;These health advisories reflect the&nbsp;Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to follow the science and up-to-date public health information.&nbsp;Specifically:</p>



<ul><li>EPA is releasing&nbsp;<em><u>interim</u></em>&nbsp;updated drinking water lifetime health advisories for perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) and perfluorooctane sulfonic acid (PFOS) that replace those issued by EPA in 2016. The updated advisory levels are based on new science that indicates that some negative health effects may occur with concentrations of PFOA or PFOS in water that are near zero&nbsp;<br></li><li>EPA is also releasing&nbsp;<em><u>final</u></em>&nbsp;health advisories for perfluorobutane sulfonic acid and its potassium salt (PFBS), and hexafluoropropylene oxide (HFPO) dimer acid and its ammonium salt (“GenX” chemicals). In chemical and product manufacturing, GenX chemicals are considered a replacement for PFOA, and PFBS is considered a replacement for PFOS.<br></li></ul>



<p><strong>INFRASTRUCTURE GRANTS TO ADDRESS WATER POLLUTION</strong><br><br>Second, EPA is making available $1 billion in grant funding through President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to help communities that are on the frontlines of PFAS contamination, the first of $5 billion through the Law that can be used to reduce PFAS in drinking water in communities facing disproportionate impacts. These funds can be used in small or disadvantaged communities to address emerging contaminants like PFAS in drinking water through actions such as technical assistance, water quality testing, contractor training, and installation of centralized treatment technologies and systems.<br><br>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides a historic $5 billion in a new Emerging Contaminants in Small or Disadvantaged Communities Grant Program for states to reduce PFAS and other contaminants in drinking water in underserved communities. In total, the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides $10 billion in funding to specifically address PFAS and other emerging contaminants in water.<br><br>EPA will be reaching out to states and territories with information on how to submit their letter of intent to participate in this new grant program. EPA will also consult with Tribes and Alaskan Native Villages regarding the Tribal set-aside for this grant program. This funding complements $3.4 billion in funding that is going through the Drinking Water State Revolving Funds (SRFs) and $3.2 billion through the Clean Water SRFs that can also be used to address PFAS in water this year.<br><br><strong><br>TOOLS FOR STATE AND LOCAL GOVERMMENTS</strong><br><br>Third, in addition to these resources outlined above, the Administration is outlining additional tools state and local governments can use to address PFAS pollution and protect drinking water:</p>



<ul><li>Implementing a recently-launched new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-announces-nationwide-monitoring-effort-better-understand-extent-pfas-drinking">nationwide monitoring program</a>&nbsp;for PFAS in water systems to detect more types of PFAS, at lower levels, in more drinking water systems;</li><li>Proactively using the EPA’s Clean Water Act federal permitting authorities to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/system/files/documents/2022-04/npdes_pfas-memo.pdf">restrict&nbsp;discharges of PFAS</a>&nbsp;at the source and to obtain more comprehensive monitoring information on potential sources of PFAS;&nbsp;</li><li>Developing a national drinking water standard for certain PFAS that will be proposed this fall; and</li><li>Publishing the results of water quality tests in non-DOD drinking water systems that are located near and downstream of military installations.</li></ul>



<p><strong>ADDITIONAL COORDINATED STEPS TO TACKLE PFAS</strong><br><br>The White House is coordinating a government-wide approach to emerging science and policy in real-time. The Council on Environmental Quality leads the Interagency Policy Committee on PFAS and the Office of Science and Technology Policy continues to coordinate accelerated PFAS research within the National Science and Technology Council’s Joint Subcommittee on Environment, Innovation, and Public Health. Both groups continue to assess the need for new policies and scientific research that result from emerging information about PFAS. There will also be enhanced coordination by senior leadership and staff from the Environmental Protection Agency, Department of Defense, and Council on Environmental Quality under the Interagency Policy Committee on PFAS concerning issues around military installations and their communities to accelerate solutions and increase transparency.<br><br>Additionally, the Biden-Harris Administration will continue to work with Congress to secure the President’s Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Request, which includes $126 million for EPA to assess the impacts of PFAS on human health and advance technologies needed to detect PFAS in water. The Administration is also prioritizing prevention of contaminated water supplies as part of the re-ignited Cancer Moonshot to end cancer as we know it which is a pillar of the President’s Unity Agenda for the country. <br><br>Outlined below is how the Biden-Harris Administration is leveraging tools from across the government to <strong>restrict</strong>PFAS from entering the nation’s water, air, land, and food; <strong>clean up</strong> PFAS pollution and holding polluters accountable; and accelerate<strong> research and development </strong>on PFAS science and solutions. <br><br><strong><em>Restricting PFAS from entering Americans’ water, air, land, and food:</em></strong><br></p>



<ul><li><strong>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA)</strong>&nbsp;<strong>is continuing to expand its testing of the food supply,</strong>including expanding its PFAS analysis method development and announcing additional testing results from the general food supply and targeted testing of seafood as those results become available.<br></li><li><strong>The U.S. Department of Agriculture’s (USDA) Farm Service Agency (FSA) has amended the&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fsa.usda.gov%2Fnews-room%2Fnews-releases%2F2021%2Fusda-opens-2022-signup-for-dairy-margin-coverage-expands-program-for-supplemental-production&amp;data=04%7C01%7C%7C3f988a7f1f5a407fccf508d9fd5dd53e%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637819401718059648%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000&amp;sdata=%2BDVK%2BWMv8Mp5%2Fu2WMOQE7YubxyG2%2BGS7bSKM68w52RM%3D&amp;reserved=0"><strong>Dairy Indemnity Payment Program</strong></a><strong>&nbsp;regulations to compensate dairy farmers&nbsp;</strong>whose&nbsp;cows cannot be put on the market due to PFAS contamination.<br></li><li><strong>The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) is leading a set of initiatives to investigate and remediate PFAS and protect emergency responders, including the first-ever inventory of PFAS use and prior releases from its facilities, like fire-fighting foam and possible water source contamination.<br></strong></li><li><strong>The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) has implemented a policy to eliminate the discharge of firefighting foam containing PFAS for testing purposes,</strong>&nbsp;and has also provided funding for airports to use systems that do not require the discharge of foam.&nbsp;FAA is partnering with DOD on research on PFAS-free firefighting foam.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Cleaning up PFAS pollution and to hold polluters accountable:</em></strong><br></p>



<ul><li><strong>In the coming weeks, EPA will issue a proposed rule to designate PFOA and PFOS as hazardous substances&nbsp;</strong>under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (CERCLA), which will enable EPA to leverage the full range of Superfund authorities, including requiring reporting of PFOA and PFOS releases and to hold polluters accountable by recovering cleanup costs.</li><li><strong>EPA has developed a&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.epa.gov/assessing-and-managing-chemicals-under-tsca/national-pfas-testing-strategy"><strong>National PFAS Testing Strategy</strong></a>&nbsp;and has issued the first in a&nbsp;series of Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA) test orders to require companies to conduct and submit testing PFAS.</li><li><a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-adds-five-pfas-chemicals-list-regional-screening-and-removal-management-levels"><strong>EPA recently added</strong></a><strong>&nbsp;five PFAS to the list of Regional Screening Levels (RSLs) and Regional Removal Management Levels (RMLs),</strong>&nbsp;which help EPA determine if further investigation or actions are needed to protect public health in locations where PFAS is detected.</li><li><strong>DOD will issue guidance in early summer to implement EPA’s recently updated Regional Screening Levels (RSLs) for PFAS across DOD’s PFAS sites nationwide.&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>These lower values will incorporate the latest peer-reviewed science and will result in more sites moving forward in the cleanup process.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li><strong>DOD continues to address its PFAS releases and has completed initial assessments at over 300 of 700 installations and started 168 remedial investigations</strong>, the next step in the cleanup process. DOD is also continuing research and demonstration on over 100 projects related to PFAS treatment technologies, sampling, analysis, and monitoring.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) and the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry (ATSDR)&nbsp;have, since October of 2021,&nbsp;released&nbsp;six&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/pfas/activities/assessments.html"><strong>PFAS exposure assessment</strong></a><strong>reports&nbsp;</strong>for communities located in&nbsp;Westfield, Hampden County, Massachusetts;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/pfas/activities/assessments/sites/berkeley-county-wv.html">Berkeley County, West Virginia</a>;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/pfas/activities/assessments/sites/new-castle-county-de.html">New Castle County, Delaware</a>;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/pfas/activities/assessments/sites/spokane-county-wa.html">Spokane County, Washington</a>;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/pfas/activities/assessments/sites/lubbock-county-tx.html">Lubbock County, Texas</a>; and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/pfas/activities/assessments/sites/fairbanks-north-star-borough-ak.html">Moose Creek, Fairbanks North Star Borough, Alaska</a>.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Accelerating the research and development of PFAS science and solutions include:</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>ATSDR is partnering with EPA to expand on the environmental measurements gathered as part of ongoing PFAS exposure assessments.</strong>&nbsp;The investigation will collect environmental samples to evaluate levels of PFAS in the indoor and outdoor environment that may contribute to elevated levels of PFAS in blood in study participants.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>The National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine (NASEM)&nbsp;</strong>has been funded by CDC/ATSDR and the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences (NIEHS)<strong>&nbsp;to review the current evidence regarding human health effects of PFAS</strong>&nbsp;that will help inform clinician guidance regarding PFAS exposure.<br></li><li><strong>The National Institute of Standards and Technology is developing a new reference material, expected to be available by the end of the year, for PFAS in aqueous firefighting foams, a fire suppressant used in firefighting.</strong>&nbsp;NIST is working with organizations including the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) and the US Fire Administration on research to understand how much PFAS from the foams gets on fire-fighting gear and how PFAS is released, including exposure from use of Personal Protective Equipment, to help reduce a firefighter’s risk of being exposed to PFAS.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout from Vice President Harris’s Meeting with Constitutional Law, Privacy, and Technology Experts on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/readout-from-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-constitutional-law-privacy-and-technology-experts-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 03:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris held a roundtable with constitutional law, privacy, and technology experts to discuss what is at stake if Roe v. Wade is overruled. The roundtable followed recent meetings about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with faith leaders, and with health care providers, and is part of the Administration’s work&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris held a roundtable with constitutional law, privacy, and technology experts to discuss what is at stake if <em>Roe v. Wade</em> is overruled. The roundtable followed recent meetings about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with faith leaders, and with health care providers, and is part of the Administration’s work to build coalitions and preparedness in response to the attack on reproductive rights.<br>&nbsp;<br>During the meeting, the Vice President said that the principles of liberty and self-determination are at stake in the Supreme Court’s leaked opinion in <em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization. </em>The conversation highlighted the real-world limitations to liberty that the American people will experience if <em>Roe v. Wade </em>is overruled. The participants discussed constitutional law and the history and meaning of the right to privacy. The participants expressed concerns that if <em>Roe v. Wade</em> is overturned, states with abortion bans could potentially restrict in vitro fertilization if their definition of life begins at the point of fertilization.&nbsp;They raised the impact that overturning<em> Roe</em> could have on access to contraception and same-sex marriage. They also discussed implications on data privacy – including concerns that states that make abortion illegal may subpoena women’s personal data.<br>&nbsp;<br>The participants also discussed the maternal health care crisis, which disproportionately impacts Black women, rural women, and Native women – and they described the detrimental impact that overturning <em>Roe v. Wade</em> will have on women’s health.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Vice President raised the connection between restrictions on reproductive rights and limitations on other rights, noting that many of the states that have trigger ban laws where abortion will be banned if the Supreme Court overrules <em>Roe v. Wade</em> are also the states that are passing laws to restrict voting rights and LGBTQ+ rights.<br>&nbsp;<br>Vice President Harris called on the legal experts to use their voices to inform the American people about the potential consequences of the Court’s decision. The Vice President affirmed that the Administration will continue to fight for the health, safety, and wellbeing of women.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Participants:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Professor Peggy Cooper Davis of NYU School of Law &nbsp;</li><li>Professor Melissa Murray of NYU School of Law</li><li>Professor Glenn Cohen of Harvard Law School</li><li>Professor Michele Bratcher Goodwin of UC Irvine School of Law</li><li>Jennifer Weiss-Wolf of Brennan Center for Justice and Ms. Magazine</li><li>Professor Leah Litman of University of Michigan Law School</li><li>Domestic Policy Advisor to the Vice President Rohini Kosoglu</li><li>White House Counsel Dana Remus</li><li>Executive Director and Co-Chair of the Gender Policy Council Jennifer Klein</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-asian-american-native-hawaiian-and-pacific-islander-leaders-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 02:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, Erika Moritsugu, Deputy Assistant to the President and Senior Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AA and NHPI) Liaison, the White House Office of Public Engagement, the White House Gender Policy Council, and the Office of the Vice President convened a meeting with AA and NHPI leaders on reproductive health and rights. Participants&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, Erika Moritsugu, Deputy Assistant to the President and Senior Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AA and NHPI) Liaison, the White House Office of Public Engagement, the White House Gender Policy Council, and the Office of the Vice President convened a meeting with AA and NHPI leaders on reproductive health and rights. Participants discussed the devastating consequences that overturning&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade</em>&nbsp;would have on AA and NHPI communities, who overwhelmingly support reproductive rights, which have been guaranteed under&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade</em>&nbsp;for nearly 50 years and are integral to equality, opportunity, and self-determination.<br><br>Advocates highlighted the importance of using an intersectional approach&nbsp;anchored on ensuring accessibility, language access, and cultural competency; all crucial in reproductive freedom. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Senior Administration officials highlighted the President and Vice President’s commitment to supporting reproductive health and rights and the Administration’s commitment to including the diverse AA and NHPI communities in conversations on this critical issue and other key priorities.<br><br>Participants included representatives from:<br><br>National Asian Pacific American Women’s Forum (NAPAWF)&nbsp;<br>Asian Americans Advancing Justice – AAJC&nbsp;<br>Empowering Pacific Islander Communities (EPIC)<br>RISE<br>Asian Pacific Institute for Gender Based Violence (API-GBV)<br>Asian &amp; Pacific Islander American Health Forum (APIAHF)<br>National Association of Asian Pacific Community Health Organizations (AAPCHO)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the 29th AFL-CIO Quadrennial Constitutional&#160;Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-29th-afl-cio-quadrennial-constitutional-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 21:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Philadelphia Convention CenterPhiladelphia, Pennsylvania 11:03 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, AFL-CIO!  (Applause.)  You ain’t labor, you’re union.  It makes a difference!  (Laughs.)  It’s good to be home.  (Applause.)  As they say in Claymont, you all brung me to the dance.  Thank you. Please.  Please, have a seat if there is one.  (Laughs.)  You’re a gigantic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Philadelphia Convention Center<br>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>11:03 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, AFL-CIO!  (Applause.)  You ain’t labor, you’re union.  It makes a difference!  (Laughs.)  It’s good to be home.  (Applause.)  As they say in Claymont, you all brung me to the dance.  Thank you.<br><br>Please.  Please, have a seat if there is one.  (Laughs.) <br><br>You’re a gigantic reason why I’m standing here &#8212; standing here today as your President.  I really mean it.  I owe you.  From the very beginning of my running for office, back when I was a kid, it was labor, the unions.  Made a difference.  At the time, we were a right-to-work state, and we changed that too.<br><br>You’ve &#8212; I’ve never forgotten not only what you’ve done for me but how importantly it meant to me and &#8212; and to the country, to our country &#8212; what you’ve done for our country.</p>



<p>And I want to thank Liz for being such a good friend for so long, the first woman to lead the AFL-CIO.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Born into a union household.&nbsp; Started out as an organizer, and she never stopped.&nbsp; Congratulations, Liz.&nbsp; Congratulations.</p>



<p>And congratulations to Fred Redmond, your Secretary-Treasurer as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I hope your daughter-in-law knows she’s marrying into a union family.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Anyway, look, I know this is bittersweet for all of us.&nbsp; This is the first convention without Rich Trumka.&nbsp; Rich was not only a legendary labor leader, he literally was a close friend to me and to so many of you.&nbsp; A true friend, particularly there when things weren’t going well.&nbsp; He was always there.</p>



<p>Above all, he was an American worker.&nbsp; No matter how high he rose through the ranks, he never forgot where he came from.&nbsp; We use that phrase all the time &#8212; “never forget where you came from.”&nbsp; He never forgot where he came from or what this work is all about.</p>



<p>You know, before Rich passed, he gave me &#8212; (applause) &#8212; he gave me the highest compliment that I’ve ever gotten in my life, and I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; He called me &#8212; which your president just did &#8212; the “most pro-union President in history.”&nbsp; I promised you I would be, and I commit to you: As long I have this job, I will remain that.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.<br><br>I’ve got to tell you, nothing made me prouder than that.&nbsp; That’s why I made sure we put a former union president in as Secretary of Labor.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; <em>Marty Walsh.&nbsp; Marty.</em>&nbsp; (Pronounced in Boston accent.)&nbsp; He’s going to learn how to speak English, but he’s real.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I kid him all the time.&nbsp; I’m joking.&nbsp; He <em>parks his car in a car barn</em> &#8212; (pronounced in Boston accent) &#8212; but he knows what he’s doing.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Marty was here yesterday, and he’s doing a hell of a job, but he fights like hell for us all.</p>



<p>And just yesterday &#8212; (applause) &#8212; just yesterday, I had a conversation &#8212; a Zoom conversation &#8212; with our next senator from this state, John Fetterman.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You know, if you’re in a foxhole, you want John with you, man.<br><br>I know he can’t wait to get back on the trail.&nbsp; He’s looking good.&nbsp; And there’s no bigger, stronger voice for working people in this state than John &#8212; certainly no bigger one, for that matter.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p><a>Look, we’re also joined here today by three great members of Congress who flew up with me on Air Force One: Brendan Boyle, who is labor, labor, labor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Donald Norcross, who is labor, labor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And Mary <s>Kay</s> [Gay] Scanlon as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; All &#8212; by the way, they’ve all be there when the tough &#8212; when the votes were tough.&nbsp; When the votes were tough to stay with you, they were there.&nbsp; And they’re great champions of unions.<br><br></a>And Stacey Abrams is here as well.&nbsp; By the way, I’m going to ask you all a favor.&nbsp; Help her in Georgia.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Help Stacey Abrams in Georgia.</p>



<p>There’s three things I learned about her early on.&nbsp; One, she’s loyal.&nbsp; Two, she’s capable.&nbsp; And three, she’s smarter than you &#8212; me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; She knows what she’s doing.&nbsp; So, folks, please, help her out.<br><br>And, folks, thanks to all of you, we’re coming along and &#8212; we’ve come a long way in a short time.</p>



<p>Do you remember when our economy was like &#8212; what it looked like before we took office?&nbsp; Three thousand Americans were dying every day from COVID.&nbsp; Twenty million Americans had lost their jobs under the last guy.</p>



<p>In fact, so many Americans lost their jobs that my predecessor became just the second President in history to leave office with fewer jobs in America than when he took office.&nbsp; But you stepped up.&nbsp; The other one, by the way, was Herbert Hoover.</p>



<p>And just remember &#8212; remember those long lines of cars stretching miles back, waiting for just a box of food to be put back in their trunk?&nbsp; It wasn’t just poor folk, it was working-class folk, it was middle-class folks.&nbsp; A lot of pretty nice cars in those lines.<br><br>And while it was going on, America created more than &#8212; more billionaires during that crisis in 2020 than any year in history.&nbsp; Talk about a contrast.<br><br>Ordinary people getting &#8212; waiting in line for an hour for a box of food.&nbsp; And the policies in the past created more billionaires than ever in American history.<br><br>Folks, it’s hard to believe, but it’s true.&nbsp; That’s what we inherited.</p>



<p>And then, with your help, we went to work with an economic vision that looks out from Scranton, Pennsylvania &#8212; hardworking towns like it all across America &#8212; not down from Wall Street.</p>



<p>Wall Street didn’t build this country, the middle class built this country.&nbsp; And unions built the middle class.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I’m not joking.&nbsp; Without unions, there would be no middle class.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That’s a fact.</p>



<p>And, by the way, there’s a reason.&nbsp; You’re the best-trained workers in the world, not a &#8212; that’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; When you do well, everybody does well.</p>



<p>You know, if investment bankers in America &#8212; they’re not all bad guys. &nbsp;They’re not bad.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; If they went on strike, not a whole hell of a lot would happen.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; I tell this to my buddy &#8212; if the IB- &#8212; IBEW went on strike, everything shuts down.&nbsp; (Applause.) All of you.&nbsp; Go down the row.<br><br>No, I’m serio- &#8212; no, you guys don’t understand; you don’t ta- &#8212; you don’t &#8212; I don’t think you appreciate how critically important you are.&nbsp; I’m not trying to be nice to you; it’s just a fact.<br><br>Folks, we need an economy built from the middle out and the bottom up, not the top down.&nbsp; Because I know when the middle class does well, everybody does.&nbsp; The wealthy do very well.&nbsp; They’re never hurt.</p>



<p>But I also know too often we’ve had an economy where the wealthy do better and better while the middle class gets left behind.</p>



<p>So we went to work to change that.&nbsp; It started with the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; The law helped 41 mi- &#8212; people &#8212; 41 million people put food on their table.&nbsp; Remember, they were having trouble putting food on their table.&nbsp; It put money in the pockets of hardworking Americans who were in trouble, being thrown out on the street because they couldn’t pay their rent through no fault of their own.&nbsp; It gave them what my dad used to call “just a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The next step was the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; And now not only is it Infrastructure Week, we&#8217;ve arrived at Infrastructure Decade!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And people are going to see a lot of it.&nbsp; We got to remind them where it&#8217;s coming from.&nbsp; We announced nearly $3 billion this year to improve more than 3,000 airports across 50 states this year &#8212; this year.&nbsp; We announced $5 billion so union workers could get to work building a national network of electric vehicle charging stations.&nbsp; We announced the largest investment of public transit in American history &#8212; more than the entire Amtrak system when it started: $20.5 billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And the people we come from &#8212; like when the President &#8212; President Obama used to always give me the good assignments.&nbsp; Well, I remember one day, I walked in &#8212; not a joke &#8212; he said, “Joe, fix Detroit.”&nbsp; I said, “Okay, no problem.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, you think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.</p>



<p>What I didn&#8217;t realize is I already knew a lot about the cities.&nbsp; When I was in Detroit, the vast majority of the people living in these cities, their jobs are out of town because they&#8217;re not doing manufacturing in towns anymore.&nbsp; Out of town.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we got a rail system for them.&nbsp; We got a freight sys- &#8212; we got a bus system.&nbsp; It changed it.&nbsp; It’s growing.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to create more good jobs using products that are made in America.&nbsp; And, folks, it&#8217;s also going to reduce pollution while it&#8217;s making it safer and safer for folks to go to work and get to work every day.</p>



<p>What all this means for all of you is a simple proposition.&nbsp; And I remember us having this discussion, old buddy.&nbsp; When I think global warming, I think jobs.&nbsp; Jobs, jobs, jobs.&nbsp; Good-paying union jobs.&nbsp; Jobs you can raise a family on.&nbsp; Jobs you can’t out- &#8212; be outsourced.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, the infrastructure law is about more than rebuilding our infrastructure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about rebuilding the middle class.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we made sure that the infrastructure law included significant labor protections.&nbsp; For example, I insisted that the overwhelming majority of the funds included in the law are subject to Davis-Bacon requirements.&nbsp; Union has to do it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And it’s not just because they want to help unions.&nbsp; It’s simple: You’re the best in the world.&nbsp; If we’re going to build infrastructure, we should have &#8212; you know, what I always find we don&#8217;t talk enough about, and I&#8217;m not going to take the time today &#8212; but you know what?&nbsp; You don&#8217;t just decide you want to be a pipe fitter or an electrician or whatever else you want to pick.&nbsp; It takes you four or five years’ hard work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s like going to college.&nbsp; Fortunately, you get these union paid &#8212; you get paid to do some of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my point is: People don&#8217;t realize &#8212; and I see every place I go &#8212; and you&#8217;ve heard me do it at Chambers of Commerce &#8212; the best-trained workers in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, folks rebuilding our country will earn a prevailing wage.&nbsp; They should.</p>



<p>Another thing the law does: It’s helped expand registered apprenticeships.&nbsp; Remember when the la- &#8212; when the business was saying, “We’ll take care of the apprenticeships?”&nbsp; Bless me Father, for I have sinned.&nbsp; Come on, man!&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; Come on.</p>



<p>Union partnerships that allow workers to earn while they learn.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; Because laying a strong foundation for the future of this country is about more than having strong roads and bridges.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about making sure that, here in America, folks who work hard can live their lives with dignity and respect.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why I continue to call on Congress to finally pass the PRO Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; which will make it easier for workers to organize.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, when Franklin Roosevelt passed the NLRB, it didn&#8217;t say you can&#8217;t have unions.&nbsp; It said we should encourage unions.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the NLRB says.&nbsp; It’s a big difference.</p>



<p>And, look, I&#8217;m not just saying that to be pro-union.&nbsp; I&#8217;m saying it because I&#8217;m pro-American.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, that&#8217;s the approach I&#8217;ve taken to build this economy.&nbsp; And what has to be done?&nbsp; Well, we brought down COVID deaths by 90 percent.&nbsp; We opened schools and businesses that were shuttered.&nbsp; All &#8212; it all created the greatest job recovery in American history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>People don&#8217;t want to talk about it these days, but it&#8217;s true: Since I&#8217;ve become President, we&#8217;ve created 8.7 million new jobs in 16 months.&nbsp; An all-time record.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And even last month, 390,000 jobs and 600,000 new manufacturing jobs.&nbsp; And they said manufacturing is dead in America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, folks, our unemployment rate is near historic lows &#8212; and 3.7 percent.&nbsp; And millions of Americans are leaving &#8212; I love these guys talking about why these &#8212; “This guy left my employment and went to another job.”&nbsp; Because he got paid more.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; Isn&#8217;t that awful?&nbsp; Isn&#8217;t that a shame that they got to compete for labor?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Better-paying jobs, for better jobs for them and their families.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a long time since that&#8217;s happened in this country, but it&#8217;s happening now.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s working.</p>



<p>Since I took office, with your help, families are carrying less debt nationwide.&nbsp; They have more savings nationwide.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; More Americans applied for new small businesses last year than ever before in American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; 5.4 million new small-business applications.&nbsp; Jobs and companies are coming home again.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re making “Buy American” a reality, not just a slogan.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I award no contracts from the federal government unless they can prove they bought it in America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, Republicans like to portray me as some kind of big spender.&nbsp; We have spent a lot of money, but let&#8217;s compare the facts.&nbsp; Under my predecessor, the deficit exploded, raising &#8212; rising every single year.&nbsp; And all of the benefit going to the top 1 percent, basically.</p>



<p>Under my plan, last year we cut the deficit by $350 billion, doing all this.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>You know, they talk about, “Biden wants to spend more on schools and all this.&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; He’s going to create a deficit.”</p>



<p>Ladies and gentlemen, this year, by the end of the fiscal year, we will have cut the federal deficit by another $1.6 trillion &#8212; in one year.&nbsp; One year.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So, when they come to you and talk about big spenders, let them know.&nbsp; Almost $2 trillion in deficit reduction.</p>



<p>I don’t want to hear any more of these lies about reckless spending.&nbsp; We’re changing people’s lives.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And because of the fact, this year, we’re delivering the biggest drop in the deficit in the history of the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, the point is this: Under my plan for the economy, we’ve made extraordinary progress.&nbsp; And we put America in a position to tackle the wor- &#8212; worldwide problem that’s worse everywhere but here: inflation.&nbsp; It’s sapping the strength of a lot of families.</p>



<p>I grew up in household not far from here, in Claymont and Wilmington, where if the price of a gallon of gasoline went up, it was a conversation at the dinner table.&nbsp; It mattered.&nbsp; It mattered in my working family.&nbsp; It mattered if the price of food went up.</p>



<p>The problem is Republicans in Congress are doing everything they can to stop my plans to bring down costs on ordinary families.</p>



<p>That’s why my plan is not finished and why the results aren’t finished either.&nbsp; Jobs are back, but prices are still too high.&nbsp; COVID is down, but gas prices are up.&nbsp; Our work isn’t done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here’s the deal.&nbsp; America still has a choice to make: a choice between a government by the few, for the few, or a government for all of us, democracy for all of us, an economy where all of us have a fair shot and a chance to earn our place in the economy.</p>



<p>My plan is simple.</p>



<p>First, I’m doing everything in my power to blunt Putin’s gas price hike.&nbsp; Just since he invaded Ukraine, it’s gone up $1.74 a gallon &#8212; because of nothing else but that.</p>



<p>So I have a plan to bring down the cost of gas and food.&nbsp; It’s going to take time, but let the world coordinate the largest release of what I have been able to do &#8212; the largest release of oil in &#8212; from the global fund in history.&nbsp; A million barrels a day.&nbsp; And 240 million barrels to boost global supply while I convinced other nations to join us to keep prices from ri- &#8212; keep prices from rising even more.</p>



<p>And I’m working closely with our European partners to get 20 million tons of grains locked in Ukraine out onto the market to help bring down food prices.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Folks, look, what Putin’s war has done is not only tried to wipe out the culture of the Ukrainians, decimate people, and commit innumerable war crimes, but is also &#8212; he’s also prevented the grain &#8212; thousands of tons of grain that are locked up in those silos, ready to be exported, but they can’t get out through the Black Sea because they’ll get blown out of the water.&nbsp; So we’re working on a plan to get it out through other countries by rail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But guess what?&nbsp; Ukraine has a system like Russia has &#8212; a rail gauge that is different than the gauge of the rest of the tracks in Europe.&nbsp; So we’re going to build silos &#8212; temporary silos &#8212; in the borders of Ukraine, including in Poland, so we can transfer it from those cars into those silos, into cars in Europe, and get it out to the ocean, and get it across the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But it’s taking time.</p>



<p>Second, we’re going to work to bring down gas and food prices.&nbsp; We can save families money and other items.&nbsp; We can change the dynamic of the middle-class families.&nbsp; Look, give them a little breathing room, as my dad said.&nbsp; You heard me say that before.</p>



<p>But imagine you’re &#8212; what most middle-class and working-class families do is they look at that monthly bill they have on everything.&nbsp; Maybe the rent or the mortgage.&nbsp; The cost of maintaining the car.&nbsp; The food.&nbsp; The &#8212; everything.</p>



<p>So if portions of that go up, one of the ways to deal with inflation for families is to bring the other costs down.</p>



<p>For example, 200,000 people with Type 1 diabetes are paying up to $1,000 a month for insulin.&nbsp; We can make sure they pay no more than $35 a month.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>By that, I &#8212; and, by the way, drug companies will still do very well.&nbsp; It’ll cost them 10 bucks to develop that insulin.&nbsp; So they’re making three and half times their cost.</p>



<p>My plan gives Medicare the power to negotiate pharmaceu- &#8212; with the pharmaceutical companies, just like the Veterans Administration does.&nbsp; To bring down the average cost of prescription drugs is a gigantic way &#8212; (applause) &#8212; it really does &#8212; it affects the total amount of money you got to write out of that checkbook.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, gas is up and food is up, which we’re going to get down come hell or high water.&nbsp; But there’s other things we can do beyond getting the price of insulin down to $35 a month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Imagine the difference it could make.&nbsp; Imagine the difference it could make if, in fact, you had other things that I&#8217;ve been proposing.&nbsp; Imagine.&nbsp; Just imagine if you&#8217;re in a situation where you&#8217;re going to &#8212; able to be in a position where you pay for preschool for kids that are three and four years old, increasing exponentially their possibility of going, no matter what kind of family they come from, in terms of educational standing &#8212; to raise the standard for people.</p>



<p><a>Imagine what we could do if we &#8212; for childcare in a city like Philadelphia and New York &#8212; the big cities &#8212; Chicago.&nbsp; It costs you twelve to fourteen thousand dollars a <s>month</s> [year] for childcare.&nbsp; Well, they shouldn&#8217;t have to pay more than 7 percent of your income for that.&nbsp; We could easily afford to do it.</a></p>



<p>Look, we could do the same thing &#8212; (applause) &#8212; but I &#8212; but I really mean it.&nbsp; Think how that would change the families that you represent.&nbsp; Think how it would fam- &#8212; change the circumstances for working-class people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, it could do the same thing with utility bills.&nbsp; Congress could ease the cost of families today by passing the clean energy investments I proposed &#8212; things like a tax credit for business to produce cleaner energy, tax cuts for families that make their homes more energy efficient, which is the way &#8212; it would mean a lot more jobs, by the way, for some folks in this room.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I met with nearly a dozen large CEO &#8212; CEOs of the largest 12 utility companies in America.&nbsp; They said, “If you pass that tax cut &#8212; that tax credit for modernizing the homes, winterizing, et cetera, we will guarantee we’ll immediately lower the average cost of &#8212; energy cost $500 a year for the average family.”&nbsp; That’d help a lot.&nbsp; And in the long run, it would help finally make America truly energy independent.</p>



<p>So, in the future, American families no longer are subject to the whims of di- &#8212; whims of dictators halfway around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve laid out concrete plans for families to save money &#8212; (applause) &#8212; not only prescription drugs and utility bills, but on rent and mortgage costs, high-speed Internet.&nbsp; You guys out there are going to be putting in high speed, and we&#8217;ve already got the money for it &#8212; billions of dollars.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; When you get it done, it&#8217;s going to lower the cost of high-speed Internet for every family in America by 30 bucks a month.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a lot of money.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a lot of jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, we can do all this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m asking &#8212; all I&#8217;m asking is for the largest corporations and the wealthiest Americans to begin to pay their fair share in taxes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m deadly earnest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anybody out there think the tax system is fair?&nbsp; Raise your hand.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, under my plan &#8212; I made this commitment in the beginning, and nothing has changed &#8212; no one making less than $400,000 a year will pay a single, solitary penny more in federal taxes.&nbsp; Nobody.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we’ll no longer have the situation where 55 of the largest Fortune 500 companies made $40 billion the last &#8212; each year of the last two years, and paid zero &#8212; zero &#8212; zero in federal income tax on that profit.&nbsp; $40 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, that&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp; I know it sounds like I’m making &#8212; I give you my word it&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact is we&#8217;ve got about roughly 790 or so billionaires in America.&nbsp; You know what their average tax rate is for a billionaire?&nbsp; I&#8217;m serious now.&nbsp; This is dead earnest.&nbsp; You can check it out.&nbsp; Eight percent.&nbsp; The tax rate for all of you is significantly higher &#8212; two to three to four times higher.&nbsp; Tax rate.&nbsp; I say it again: 8 percent in federal taxes.&nbsp; Anybody in this room who thinks that &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s fair, but we got to do something about it.</p>



<p>And, by the way, it&#8217;s not just labor &#8212; organized labor, unions, and Democrats who think that.&nbsp; The average Republican knows it&#8217;s not fair.&nbsp; That suburbanite mom and dad out there, they look around and know it’s not fair.</p>



<p>I happen to believe that no billionaires should be paying a lower tax rate than a teacher, a firefighter, an electrician, or a cop.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Republicans have it all backwards.&nbsp; Their plan literally calls for increasing taxes on middle-class and working people and cutting taxes on corporations and wealthy Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m not talking about punishing anyone; just pay your fair share.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a matter of decency.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a matter of dignity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a matter of fiscal responsibility.</p>



<p>Look, I believe in bipartisanship, but I have no illusions about this Republican Party &#8212; the MAGA party.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been able to bring some Republicans along on parts of my plan.&nbsp; But the fact is Republicans in Congress are still in the grip of the ultra-MAGA agenda.&nbsp; They still refuse to consider changing any part of the Trump tax cuts, which delivered massive windfalls to billionaires and others, and they weren’t paid for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They still refuse to consider a minimum corporate tax of 15 per- &#8212; 15 percent minimum tax.&nbsp; They seem to think that the problem in America today is that working families aren’t paying enough.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congressional Republican Senator Rick Scott of Florida &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; as my mother would say, “God love him” &#8212; he laid out a plan.&nbsp; I think you have it on your desks.&nbsp; I just took one page of that plan.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; This is published.<br><br>It says, “All…” &#8212; this is one &#8212; just one of their ideas.&nbsp; “All federal legislation sunsets in five years.&nbsp; If the law is worth keeping, Congress <s>could</s> [can] pass it again.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, guess what that is?&nbsp; Social Security.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Social Security.&nbsp; Medicare.&nbsp; Medicaid.&nbsp; Every &#8212; that’s not a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Every five years, it would be put on the chopping block.&nbsp; Every five years.&nbsp; And if it’s not reinstated by a vote in the Senate of 60 or more, guess what?&nbsp; It automatically goes out of existence.&nbsp; That’s what they’re proposing.&nbsp; Unless a common &#8212; the Congress affirmatively votes back that &#8212; bring them back into existence.<br><br>Think about that.&nbsp; Social Security you paid for your whole life.&nbsp; Medicare.&nbsp; Medicaid.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Really, ask yourself: How well are you going to sleep at night knowing that every five years Ted Cruz and the other ultra-MAGA Republicans are going to vote on whether you’ll have Social Security, Medicare, or Medicaid?<br><br>It’s unlikely they’ll be able to wipe it out, but any one of you doubt for a second they’ll find ways to cut benefits and programs in order to keep anything going?<br><br>That’s what this is about.&nbsp; They’ve always wanted to cut Social Security.&nbsp; They’ve always wanted to cut Medicare.&nbsp; They’ve always wanted to cut Medicaid.&nbsp; But if you have to start from scratch?</p>



<p>The gentleman from Wisconsin, Senator Ron Johnson, is back at it again, trying to dismantle the Affordable Care Act, including its protections for pre-existing conditions.&nbsp;&nbsp; Hundred million people have pre-existing conditions.&nbsp; The only reason the insurance company has to cover it is because of that law &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and they’re never going to stop going after it.&nbsp;<br><br>So, now, with the plan of Senator Scott trying to walk back.&nbsp; But it’s clear: The last thing they want to see is workers with power in this country.<br><br>The bottom line is this: I truly believe we’ve made extraordinary progress by laying a new foundation for our economy, which becomes clear once global inflation beco- &#8212; begins to recede.</p>



<p>There’s so much at stake today.&nbsp; But the truth is: I’ve never been more optimistic about America than I am today.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I travel the world trying to put things back together.&nbsp; You know, Trump did not leave a very good situation.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You think I’m kidding.<br><br>No matter where I go in the world, whether it was the inter-American conference we just had for the &#8212; this si- &#8212; this hemisphere; or NATO; or dealing with the ASEAN countries; or the Far East, guess what?&nbsp; They look at me and I say &#8212; I say, “America is back.”&nbsp; And they look and me and they say, “For how long?”<br><br>This is America.&nbsp; We can do any damn thing we put our minds to.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; We’re not going back to the false promises of the trickle-down economics.&nbsp; We’re going forward.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’re going forward.<br><br>I really mean this. &nbsp;I know I’m called a cockeyed optimist, but this is based on history.&nbsp; We’re the most unique country in the world.&nbsp; We’re organized on one notion.&nbsp; Every other country is organized based on ethnicity, religion, geography.&nbsp; But the United States is based on an idea.&nbsp; The only country in the world based on an idea.&nbsp; Think about it.<br><br>Look to your right.&nbsp; Look at your left.&nbsp; See if you’re &#8212; everybody all shares the same &#8212; the same backgrounds.&nbsp; We’re so diverse.<br><br>Why are we doing it?&nbsp; Because we said, “We hold these truths to be self-evident that all men and women are created equal” &#8212; (applause) &#8212; “endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights…life, liberty.”<br><br>We’ve never met the goal, but we’ve never &#8212; other than the Trump administration &#8212; tried to walk away from that goal.&nbsp; And it gets better every time we push.<br><br>And unions &#8212; unions are going to play a critical role in that future.&nbsp; America has always counted on union workers.&nbsp; Given just half a chance, you have never, ever, ever, ever let the country down.&nbsp; We’re counting on you again to build this country for all of us &#8212; (applause) &#8212; help build an economy that works for working people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I promise you, I’m going to keep fighting for you!&nbsp; Are you prepared to fight with me?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Well, let’s build it together!&nbsp; Let’s continue to give working families a fighting chance, face our challenges head on, and let’s keep building a better America.&nbsp; Because we can do it!&nbsp;</p>



<p>God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We can do anything!&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>11:37 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with State Legislative Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-state-legislative-leaders-on-reproductive-rights-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55506</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, convened a meeting with state legislative leaders from Colorado, New Mexico, and Nevada on reproductive rights. Colorado, New Mexico, and Nevada have taken and will continue to take critical steps to improve reproductive health care and protect&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, convened a meeting with state legislative leaders from Colorado, New Mexico, and Nevada on reproductive rights.</p>



<p>Colorado, New Mexico, and Nevada have taken and will continue to take critical steps to improve reproductive health care and protect access to abortion. In the 2022 legislative session, Colorado passed the Reproductive Health Equity Act, which codifies the right to make reproductive health decisions free from government interference. In 2021, New Mexico repealed an abortion ban that had been in place since 1969, before the Supreme Court’s ruling in <em>Roe v Wade</em>.</p>



<p>This fall, Nevadans will also vote on an Equal Rights Amendment to the state constitution, which would prohibit the denial or abridgement of rights on account of an individual’s race, color, creed, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, age, disability, ancestry or national origin.</p>



<p>Legislators from all three states discussed specific policy measures that would advance women’s reproductive health, including expanding coverage of abortion care and protecting the safety and security of doctors and clinics. They also discussed the need to prepare for an anticipated surge in out-of-state patients seeking abortion care; after Texas’s six-week abortion ban went into effect last September, some clinics in the region experienced a <a href="https://www.krqe.com/health/new-mexico-abortion-clinics-seeing-increase-in-texas-patients/">500% increase</a> in patients.</p>



<p>Senior Administration officials thanked the state legislative leaders for their efforts to protect reproductive rights and expand access to reproductive health care, and committed to working together in the months ahead.</p>



<p>State legislative leaders from today’s meeting included:</p>



<ul><li>Nevada Senate Majority Leader Nicole Cannizzaro</li><li>Colorado House Majority Caucus Co-Chair Meg Froelich</li><li>Colorado State Senator Julie Gonzales</li><li>New Mexico House Majority Floor Leader Javier Martinez</li><li>New Mexico State Senator Shannon Pinto</li><li>New Mexico State Representative Micaela Cadena</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before Roundtable to Discuss Roe V.&#160;Wade</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-roundtable-to-discuss-roe-v-wade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 19:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President&#8217;s Ceremonial OfficeEisenhower Executive Office Building 2:32 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you for being here to be a part of this conversation.  And I look forward to &#8212; to consulting with you about the implications of what we believe might be the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision on Roe and what&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President&#8217;s Ceremonial Office<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></p>



<p>2:32 P.M. EDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you for being here to be a part of this conversation.  And I look forward to &#8212; to consulting with you about the implications of what we believe might be the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision on Roe and what the implications of that will be for the people of our country.<br> <br>I think we all believe and know that our nation was founded on certain principles that we hold dear: principles of freedom, liberty, and self-determination.  And I do believe that all of those principles are at stake when we look at the leaked draft opinion about what this decision may end up being.<br> <br>From these principles, most notably, come the constitutional right to privacy &#8212; the right of an individual to make decisions about their life, about their family, about their body without government interference.  And so, there&#8217;s a lot at stake in the outcome of this decision. <br> <br>And for that reason, I&#8217;ve asked these &#8212; these experts to be here to talk with me about how we might best prepare the American people for the consequences of what this decision will be &#8212; in terms of their life and the choices that they are able to make and have a right to make &#8212; so that, at the very least, folks can be prepared.<br> <br>But I do believe that we should prepare for the right to privacy to be attacked and under attack with this decision, and that will have a number of implications.  If Roe is overturned, I believe that states will then have the power to interfere in personal decisions.  I do believe that there are three specific areas that we should be prepared to address. <br> <br>One is the issue of data privacy and the potential that if Roe is overturned, that states that have criminalized abortion could subpoena a woman&#8217;s personal data.  And so, I’m &#8212; I want to talk to these experts about their concern and the level of their concern about that very issue, including, for example, the vulnerability of women who are using menstrual tracking apps; those who use a search engine to find certain locations or certain help, in terms of their reproductive health, and how vulnerable those searches will be to bad actors attempting to track their history, much less any government forces that may be interested in investigating that for whatever purpose.<br> <br>The issue of IVF &#8212; in vitro fertilization.  I have a concern that if Roe is overturned, states with abortion bans could potentially restrict IVF if their definition of life begins at the point of fertilization.  So I&#8217;d like to talk with these experts about their thoughts about that and whether the law is established or not &#8212; well established or not, in terms of the protection that individuals have if they are in the process of IVF.<br> <br> And then on the issue of contraception, if Roe is overturned, we believe that states with abortion bans from the moment of fertilization could potentially restrict specific types of contraception &#8212; in particular, IUDs and the so-called morning-after pill.  And so, I&#8217;d like to talk with these experts about their thoughts, in terms of the legal theories that would be at play if that were to take place.<br> <br>I do believe that overturning Roe could clear the way for challenges to other fundamental rights, including the right to use contraception and &#8212; and same-sex marriage.  And so, I&#8217;m going to talk with these folks about that.<br> <br>And I think it&#8217;s a very important point to make that many of the states that have passed trigger ban laws are also the states that are passing laws to restrict trans rights, gay rights, and the freedom to vote.<br> <br>And when you look at a diagram of the &#8212; just a Venn diagram, in that regard, it tells a real tale of the ideo- &#8212; ideological perspective that some of these state legislatures have, in terms of this various &#8212; these various rights that &#8212; that folks have been given as part of what we believe are inherent rights under the principles and the ideals and the values that we hold dear.<br> <br>So I look forward to this conversation.  In particular, again, it is focused on the right to privacy to which all Americans should be entitled and what we must do to be aware of what the Court might be doing to attack those rights to privacy and &#8212; and what we can do to educate and inform the American people of what is at stake with this decision coming down, probably sometime this month.<br> <br>So, with that, let&#8217;s get started with our conversation.  And I thank the press for being part of this part of it.<br> <br>Thank you.  See you later.<br> <br>END                 2:38 P.M. EDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on World Elder Abuse Awareness Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/a-proclamation-on-world-elder-abuse-awareness-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 16:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55490</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA A PROCLAMATION It is more vital than ever that we ensure our older adults can age with the dignity, security, and appreciation that every person deserves.  Honoring and respecting older Americans is a matter of basic human dignity and justice &#8212; it is part of the character&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">A PROCLAMATION</p>



<p>It is more vital than ever that we ensure our older adults can age with the dignity, security, and appreciation that every person deserves.  Honoring and respecting older Americans is a matter of basic human dignity and justice &#8212; it is part of the character of our Nation.  Yet every year, many Americans aged 60 and older experience abuse and neglect.  On World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, we join the international community to raise awareness and help end elder abuse here at home and across the world. </p>



<p>Elder abuse takes many forms, such as&nbsp;financial, emotional, physical, and sexual harm, including intimate partner violence in later life.&nbsp;&nbsp;It often comes in the form of neglect, abandonment, or exploitation.&nbsp;&nbsp;It is estimated that approximately 1 in 10 elderly Americans are abused annually.&nbsp;&nbsp;However, many of those who are abused suffer in silence, and many cases&nbsp;are never reported or brought to light.&nbsp;&nbsp;In the past few years, while the pandemic isolated all of us to different extents, it especially exacerbated the isolation felt by too many older adults.&nbsp;&nbsp;All of us have a role to play in preventing elder abuse and ensuring that our Nation&#8217;s seniors are able to age with dignity.&nbsp;&nbsp;With a majority of elder abuse victims being women, my Administration is focused particularly on improving our support for all women and preventing and addressing gender-based violence that impacts older adults both domestically and abroad.</p>



<p>We must remain steadfast in our commitment to preventing elder abuse.&nbsp;&nbsp;My Administration allotted $178 million through the American Rescue Plan and the COVID-19 recovery bill to improve and strengthen the work of Adult Protective Services (APS).&nbsp;&nbsp;Additionally, my budget proposal for 2023 would provide ongoing support for APS and State Long-Term Care Ombudsman programs.&nbsp;&nbsp;Our comprehensive, collaborative efforts to respond to elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation include initiatives to reform guardianship, support adult decision-making, crack down on scammers and fraudsters, and empower victims of exploitation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Our commitment to supporting survivors of all ages is reflected in the reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act, which includes dedicated Federal funds to support survivor service providers, law enforcement, and prosecutors working to respond to domestic and sexual violence experienced by older adults.</p>



<p>As we continue to build a better America, we must ensure that we bring everyone along.&nbsp;&nbsp;That is why my Administration is&nbsp;committed to safeguarding the rights of those who live in retirement and shared residential settings.&nbsp;&nbsp;I have called on the Congress to deliver significant reforms to improve the safety and quality of care in our Nation&#8217;s nursing homes.&nbsp;&nbsp;Recognizing the critical work of caregivers,&nbsp;I have also proposed measures to create a strong and well-compensated caregiving workforce to advance the well-being of our Nation&#8217;s older adults.&nbsp;&nbsp;By ensuring a high quality of life and care for older Americans, we can support every community and honor the dignity of every person.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On this World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, let us recommit to delivering all older Americans the promise of a comfortable and peaceful life with dignity.&nbsp;&nbsp;Let us reaffirm our commitment to a&nbsp;world free from the scourge of abuse and neglect.&nbsp;&nbsp;Let us join the world in celebrating the essential role older adults play in our lives.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 15, 2022, as World Elder Abuse Awareness Day.&nbsp;&nbsp;I encourage all Americans to be diligent, work&nbsp;togetherto&nbsp;strengthen existing partnerships, and develop new opportunities to improve our Nation&#8217;s prevention and response to&nbsp;elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this&nbsp;fourteenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
