<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 02:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President Biden on Pandemic Preparedness, Prevention and Response Fund at the World&#160;Bank</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/statement-by-president-biden-on-pandemic-preparedness-prevention-and-response-fund-at-the-world-bank/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 02:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the World Bank Board voted to approve the establishment of a new Financial Intermediary Fund that will make the world safer and more secure from pandemics.&#160; Since Day One of my Administration, I have called for a mechanism to catalyze global progress to prevent, detect, and respond to infectious disease threats.&#160; The United States&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the World Bank Board voted to approve the establishment of a new Financial Intermediary Fund that will make the world safer and more secure from pandemics.&nbsp; Since Day One of my Administration, I have called for a mechanism to catalyze global progress to prevent, detect, and respond to infectious disease threats.&nbsp; The United States is doing its part to collectively and collaboratively build global consensus towards establishing this new fund through calls to action and partnership from leaders across our government.&nbsp; Strong and relentless leadership from our allies and partners, including through the Indonesia G20 Presidency in 2022 and the Italy G20 Presidency in 2021, has brought us to this significant milestone.</p>



<p>Infectious diseases that cross borders, cause death, and disrupt societies and economies are a threat to national and global security. Over one million Americans and millions more around the world have died from COVID-19. Economies and societies have been devastated in its wake, and studies suggest the risk of another pandemic is significant. When it comes to preparing for the next pandemic, the cost of inaction is greater than the cost of action.&nbsp; Investing in preparedness now is the right thing and the smart thing to do.</p>



<p>The generosity of the American people and Congress enabled my initial U.S. pledge of $450 million to support the fund from the outset, and it has galvanized other partners to step up immediately: commitments totaling nearly $1.1 billion have been made by the United States, the European Commission, Germany, Indonesia, the United Kingdom, Singapore, and a philanthropic foundation; we are optimistic others will soon join us.</p>



<p>To protect lives at home and all over the world, we must increase investments in pandemic preparedness. This requires sustained investment that goes beyond traditional global health and development programming, to ensure we address health security risks in addition to, and not in place of, existing global health challenges. Experts estimate that more than $10 billion annually is needed to fill international financing gaps for health security and pandemic preparedness. To begin filling those gaps, this new fund will complement existing global health programs – it is an investment in our global and national security that will yield significant economic and health dividends for years to come. As requested in my Fiscal Year 2023 Budget, I call on Congress to provide an additional $4.75 billion in mandatory and discretionary funds, which will greatly enhance the fund’s effectiveness and catalyze commitments from others. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me be clear: protecting the United States from infectious disease threats cannot be accomplished with incremental increases in annual global health spending alone.&nbsp; Additional financing is needed to make new progress against infectious diseases we will face, on top of continued demands for the ongoing global COVID-19 pandemic, and sustained support for longstanding global health investments and health systems, including the Seventh Replenishment of the Global Fund, which I look forward to hosting this September.<br><br></p>



<p>Today’s World Bank Board vote is a significant milestone, and the United States looks forward to doing its part to strengthen the global health security architecture.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from White&#160;House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on Sen. McConnell Holding American Jobs and Competitiveness Versus China Hostage to Protect Big&#160;Pharma</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/statement-from-white-house-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-sen-mcconnell-holding-american-jobs-and-competitiveness-versus-china-hostage-to-protect-big-pharma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 21:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Republican Senate leader is holding hostage a bipartisan package to strengthen American competitiveness versus China, that would yield hundreds of thousands of manufacturing jobs in places like Southern Ohio, Idaho, and other states around the country.  It would lower the cost of countless products, and end our reliance on imports.  Why? To protect the ability of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Republican Senate leader is holding hostage a bipartisan package to strengthen American competitiveness versus China, that would yield hundreds of thousands of manufacturing jobs in places like Southern Ohio, Idaho, and other states around the country.  It would lower the cost of countless products, and end our reliance on imports.  Why? To protect the ability of big pharmaceutical companies to price gouge. Senate Republicans are literally choosing to help China out compete the U.S. in order to protect big drug companies. This takes loyalty to special interests over working Americans to a new and shocking height.  We are not going to back down in the face of this outrageous threat.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Swearing in of Supreme Court Justice Ketanji Brown&#160;Jackson</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-swearing-in-of-supreme-court-justice-ketanji-brown-jackson/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 21:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am honored that the very first judicial nominee I selected as President – the brilliant lawyer who became “Judge Jackson” – has now become “Justice Jackson.”&#160; Her historic swearing in today represents a profound step forward for our nation, for all the young, Black girls who now see themselves reflected on our highest court,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I am honored that the very first judicial nominee I selected as President – the brilliant lawyer who became “Judge Jackson” – has now become “Justice Jackson.”&nbsp;<br><br>Her historic swearing in today represents a profound step forward for our nation, for all the young, Black girls who now see themselves reflected on our highest court, and for all of us as Americans.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Supreme Court just gained a colleague with a world-class intellect, the dignified temperament the American people expect of a justice, and the strongest credentials imaginable. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Justice Jackson is a former public defender who served for almost a decade as a district and circuit judge. &nbsp;Her nomination was endorsed by top legal experts across the political spectrum, as well as our country’s leading law enforcement organizations.&nbsp; In her career, she has been confirmed four times by the U.S. Senate with bipartisan support.<br>&nbsp;<br>She is the daughter of educators and the niece of a police chief—and she too has devoted her life to public service.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>She is also the embodiment of hard work, grace, and perseverance.<br>&nbsp;<br>Justice Jackson’s wisdom and experience, will make all of us proud for so many years to come.<br>&nbsp;<br>Like I said after her confirmation, Justice Jackson’s ascension to the highest court in the land makes the sun shine on so many of us in a new way.<br>&nbsp;<br>Justice Jackson succeeds another extraordinarily brilliant jurist who has also devoted their life to their country, including in the U.S. Army as a teenager and on the Watergate Committee &nbsp;&#8211; Justice Steven Breyer. Justice Breyer’s integrity and his commitment to ensuring our nation’s laws worked for the people have made him beloved by his colleagues and deeply respected across our country. I thank him again for his many years of exemplary service. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Eleventh Operation Fly Formula Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/president-biden-announces-eleventh-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 20:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 849,000 8-ounce bottle equivalents of&#160;Nestlé® NAN® EXPERTpro SensiPro infant formula this weekend Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Nestlé infant formula from Australia to Fort Worth,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 849,000 8-ounce bottle equivalents of&nbsp;Nestl</em>é® <em>NAN® </em>EXPERTpro<em> SensiPro infant formula this weekend</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Nestlé infant formula from Australia to Fort Worth, Texas on July 4. This delivery will include over 56,000 pounds of <a>Nestlé </a>NAN SensiPro formula, the equivalent of approximately 849,000 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available through Gerber.com.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Nestlé can export additional infant formula into the U.S.&nbsp;Nestlé will import both standard and specialty infant formulas including&nbsp;<a>Nestlé&nbsp;NAN</a> SupremePro 1, Nestlé NAN SupremePro 2, Nestlé&nbsp;NAN EXPERTpro SensiPro Premium Instant Starter Formula, Nestlé Health Science Alfamino/Alfamino, Jr., Gerber® Good Start® Gentle and Gerber® Good Start® Extensive HA®. Over time Nestlé plans to bring approximately 42 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. <em>By July 3, Operation Fly Formula will have transported more than 37.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents to the U.S.</em></p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Twelfth Operation Fly Formula Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/president-biden-announces-twelfth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 20:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Danone’s Nutricia specialized medical infant formula on July 8 Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing flights, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport&#160;Danone’s Nutricia specialized medical formulas&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Danone’s Nutricia specialized medical infant formula on July 8</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing flights, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport&nbsp;Danone’s Nutricia specialized medical formulas from Europe to New York, New York and Chicago, Illinois on July 8 These two deliveries will include a total of approximately 190,000 pounds of Neocate Junior and Neocate Infant DHA/ARA, the equivalent of approximately 2 million 8-ounce bottles and are for babies with severe cow’s milk or multiple food protein allergies. The specialty formula will be mainly available through medical distributors.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Danone can export additional infant formula, including&nbsp;Neocate Infant DHA/ARA and Aptamil First Infant Milk Stage 1. Danone plans to export approximately 38 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market, which also includes their Aptamil baby formula from Ireland and New Zealand.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores and medical distributors as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to families who need it faster. <em>By July 3, Operation Fly Formula will have transported more than 37.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents to the U.S.</em></p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<p>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on Hong Kong 25 Years After&#160;Handover</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/statement-from-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-hong-kong-25-years-after-handover/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 18:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[July 1st marks the 25th anniversary of the of the handover of Hong Kong to the People’s Republic of China (PRC). This date was originally envisioned as the halfway point of 50 years of promised autonomy under the Sino-British Joint Declaration. Instead of looking forward to another 25 years of autonomy for Hong Kong, we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>July 1<sup>st</sup> marks the 25<sup>th</sup> anniversary of the of the handover of Hong Kong to the People’s Republic of China (PRC). This date was originally envisioned as the halfway point of 50 years of promised autonomy under the Sino-British Joint Declaration. Instead of looking forward to another 25 years of autonomy for Hong Kong, we have witnessed the dismantling of Hong Kong’s democratic institutions and the unprecedented pressures on the judiciary, the stifling of academic, cultural, and press freedoms, and the coerced disbandment of dozens of civil society groups and news outlets. These actions undermine fundamental freedoms and the rules-based order which serves to preserve global stability.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today is the second anniversary of National Security Law, the aggressive implementation of which has eliminated any meaningful political opposition in Hong Kong and stifled dissent. As a result, today almost all of Hong Kong&#8217;s pro-democracy politicians are either in prison pending trial or in exile overseas. NGOs, trade unions and human rights organizations opposing the Government&#8217;s agenda have been forced to disband or leave, for fear of government reprisals. The PRC’s policies toward Hong Kong also have shaken the institutions, rules, and systems that had been the basis of international confidence in Hong Kong – which was the bedrock of its role as an economic hub.</p>



<p>We call on the PRC to act in accordance with the international obligations it willingly undertook. Ahead of the Chief Executive&#8217;s inauguration, we reiterate the importance that Hong Kong&#8217;s leadership respects the protected rights and freedoms of people in Hong Kong, as provided for in the Basic Law. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Supreme Court Ruling on West Virginia v.&#160;EPA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-supreme-court-ruling-on-west-virginia-v-epa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 17:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Supreme Court’s ruling in West Virginia vs. EPA is another devastating decision that aims to take our country backwards. While this decision risks damaging our nation’s ability to keep our air clean and combat climate change, I will not relent in using my lawful authorities to protect public health and tackle the climate crisis.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Supreme Court’s ruling in <em>West Virginia vs. EPA </em>is another devastating decision that aims to take our country backwards. While this decision risks damaging our nation’s ability to keep our air clean and combat climate change, I will not relent in using my lawful authorities to protect public health and tackle the climate crisis.</p>



<p>I have directed my legal team to work with the Department of Justice and affected agencies to review this decision carefully and find ways that we can, under federal law, continue protecting Americans from harmful pollution, including pollution that causes climate change.</p>



<p>Since the Clean Air Act was passed by a bipartisan majority in Congress in 1970, the landmark law has enabled both Democratic and Republican administrations to protect and improve the air we breathe, cutting air pollution by 78 percent even as our economy quadrupled in size. Yet today’s decision sides with special interests that have waged a long-term campaign to strip away our right to breathe clean air.</p>



<p>We cannot and will not ignore the danger to public health and existential threat the climate crisis poses. The science confirms what we all see with our own eyes – the wildfires, droughts, extreme heat, and intense storms are endangering our lives and livelihoods.</p>



<p>I will take action. My Administration will continue using lawful executive authority, including the EPA’s legally-upheld authorities, to keep our air clean, protect public health, and tackle the climate crisis. We will work with states and cities to pass and uphold laws that protect their citizens. And we will keep pushing for additional Congressional action, so that Americans can fully seize the economic opportunities, cost-saving benefits, and security of a clean energy future. Together, we will tackle environmental injustice, create good-paying jobs, and lower costs for families building the clean energy economy.</p>



<p>Our fight against climate change must carry forward, and it will. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Oklahoma Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/30/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-oklahoma-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 16:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Oklahoma and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, tornadoes, and flooding from May 2 to May 8, 2022. The President’s action makes Federal funding available to affected&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Oklahoma and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, tornadoes, and flooding from May 2 to May 8, 2022.</p>



<p>The President’s action makes Federal funding available to affected individuals in the counties of Adair, Cherokee, Muskogee, Okmulgee, Pottawatomie, Seminole, and Tulsa.</p>



<p>Assistance can include grants for temporary housing and home repairs, low-cost loans to cover uninsured property losses, and other programs to help individuals and business owners recover from the effects of the disaster.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Roland W. Jackson as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>Residents and business owners who sustained losses in the designated counties can begin applying for assistance by registering online at <a href="http://www.DisasterAssistance.gov">http://www.DisasterAssistance.gov</a> or by calling 1-800-621-FEMA(3362) or 1-800-462-7585 (TTY) for the hearing and speech impaired.&nbsp; The toll-free telephone numbers will operate from 7:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m. (local time) seven days a week until further notice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in Press Conference &#124; Madrid,&#160;Spain</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/30/remarks-by-president-biden-in-press-conference-madrid-spain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 16:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Institución Ferial de MadridMadrid, Spain 2:56 P.M. CEST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Thank you.&#160; If you have a seat, please sit down.&#160; You’d think someone else walked in the room.&#160; Thank you very much for taking the time to be here. I think we can all agree that this has been a historic NATO&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Institución Ferial de Madrid<br>Madrid, Spain</p>



<p>2:56 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; If you have a seat, please sit down.&nbsp; You’d think someone else walked in the room.&nbsp; Thank you very much for taking the time to be here.</p>



<p>I think we can all agree that this has been a historic NATO Summit.&nbsp; Some of the folks have been covering me for a while.&nbsp; About a year and a half ago, when the first G7 meeting took place in England, I talked about the need for us to reconsider the makeup of NATO, how it functioned, and come up with a different strategy for the &#8212; for NATO and how we work together.&nbsp; And &#8212; and in addition to that, we also talked about the G7 taking on additional responsibilities.</p>



<p>And before the war started, I told Putin that if he invaded Ukraine, NATO would not only get stronger but would get more united.&nbsp; And we would see democracies in the world stand up and oppose his aggression and defend the rules-based order.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re seeing today.</p>



<p>This summit was about strengthening our Alliance, meeting the challenges of our world as it is today and the threats we&#8217;re going to face in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last time NATO drafted a new mission statement was 12 years ago.&nbsp; At that time, it characterized Russia as a partner, and it didn&#8217;t even mention China.&nbsp; The world has changed, changed a great deal since then.&nbsp; And NATO is changing as well.</p>



<p>At this summit, we rallied our Alliances to meet both the direct threats that Russia poses to Europe and the systemic challenges that China poses to a rules-based world order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve invited two new members to join NATO.&nbsp; It was a historic act.&nbsp; Finland and Sweden, two countries with a long tradition of neutrality and choosing to join NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some of the American press will remember when I got a phone call from the leader of Finland saying could he come and see me.&nbsp; And he came the next day and said, “Will you support my joining &#8212; my country joining NATO?”</p>



<p>We got on the telephone, and he suggested we call the leader of Switzerland &#8212; “Switzerland,” my good &#8212; my goodness.&nbsp; I’m getting really anxious here about expanding NATO.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Of Sweden.&nbsp; And what happened was we got on the phone, and she asked if she could come the next day to want to talk about joining NATO.</p>



<p>Allies across the board are stepping up, increasing defense spending.&nbsp; A majority of them are on track for the first time to exceed our 2 percent of GDP commitment that they made.&nbsp; They agreed to spend 2 percent of the GDP on defense.</p>



<p>Look, for example, Germany: Germany has committed to spending 2 percent going forward, and announced a special fund for its military of more than $100 billion.&nbsp; Slovakia, the Czech Republic, and the Netherlands have announced they will also meet their 2 percent commitments.&nbsp; Poland, Romania, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania are doing more than 2.5 percent, some as high as 3 percent.</p>



<p>Together, we’re deploying more assets and capabilities to bolster our Alliances across all domains &#8212; land, air, sea, cyber, and space.</p>



<p>We &#8212; we’ve reaffirmed that our Article 5 commitment is sacred.&nbsp; And an attack on one is an attack on all, and we will defend every inch of NATO territory.&nbsp; Every inch of NATO territory.</p>



<p>For our part, the United States is doing exactly what I said we would do if Putin invaded: enhance our force posture in Europe.&nbsp; We’ll station more ships in here, in Spain.&nbsp; We’re stationing more air defense in Italy and Germany; more F-35s in the United Kingdom; and, to strengthen our eastern flank, new permanent headquarters for the Army Fifth Corps in Poland.&nbsp; In addition, an additional brigade combat team positioned in Romania, and additional rotational deployments in the Baltic countries.</p>



<p>Things are changing to adapt to the world as we have it today.&nbsp; And all this is against the backdrop of our response to NATO&#8217;s &#8212; to Russia&#8217;s aggression and to help Ukraine defend itself.</p>



<p>The United States is rallying the world to stand with Ukraine.&nbsp; Allies and partners around the globe are making significant contributions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secretary Austin just brought together more than 50 countries &#8212; more than 50 countries &#8212; pledging new commitments, and this is a global effort to support Ukraine: nearly 140,000 anti-tank systems, more than 600 tanks, nearly 500 artillery systems, more than 600,000 rounds of artillery ammunition, as well as advanced multiple launch rocket systems, anti-ship systems, and air defense systems.</p>



<p>And again, the United States is leading the way.&nbsp; We provided Ukraine with nearly $7 billion in security assistance since I took office.&nbsp; In the next few days, we intend to announce more than $800 million more, including a new advanced Western air defense system for Ukraine, more artillery and ammunition, counter-battery radars, additional ammunition for the HIMARS multiple launch rocket system we&#8217;ve already given Ukraine and more HIMARS coming from other countries as well.</p>



<p>We also welcomed, for the first time, our partners in the Indo-Pacific to participate in the NATO Summit.&nbsp; As I indicated to Putin, this would be &#8212; his action would cause worldwide response, bringing together democratic allies and partners from the Atlantic and the Pacific to focus on the challenges that matter to our future and to defend the rules-based order against the challenges, including from China.</p>



<p><a>In the G7 in Germany, we also launched what started off to be the Build Back Better notion, but it&#8217;s morphed into the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment, to offer developing and middle-income countries better options to meet their urgent infrastructure needs.&nbsp; Because when the United States and G7 countries put skin in the game, it helped bring &#8212; it helps bring millions of dollars up to &#8212; before it’s all over &#8212; up to possibly a trillion dollars of private sector money off the sidelines &#8212; $600 billion in just the next few years.</a></p>



<p>Unlike China, these projects will be done transparently and with very high standards.&nbsp; For example, the U.S. government just facilitated a new partnership between two American firms and the government of Angola to invest $2 billion building a significant solar project in Angola.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a partnership to help Angola meet its climate goals and energy needs while creating new markets for American technologies and good jobs in Angola.&nbsp; As you heard me say before: When I think “climate,” I think “jobs.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the G7 also said we&#8217;d work together to take on China&#8217;s abusive and coercive trade practices and rid our supply chains of products made with forced labor.</p>



<p>We tasked our teams to work on the details of the price cap on Russian oil to drive down Putin&#8217;s revenues without hurting Americans and others at the gas pump.</p>



<p>We’ll seek to use the funds from the tariffs on Russian goods to help Ukraine rebuild.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re committed &#8212; we&#8217;ve committed more than $4.5 billion &#8212; more than half of that from the United States &#8212; to address food insecurity and the immediate crisis caused by the Russian war.</p>



<p>At every step of this trip, we set down a marker of unity, determination, and deep capabilities of the democratic nations of the world to do what need be done.&nbsp; Putin thought he could break the transatlantic Alliance.&nbsp; He tried to weaken us.&nbsp; He expected our resolve to fracture.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s getting exactly what he did not want.</p>



<p><a>He wanted the <s>Findalization</s> [Finlandization] of NATO.&nbsp; He got the NATOization of Finland.</a></p>



<p>Just think about this: That&#8217;s what he thought.&nbsp; Now <s>NATO</s> [Finland] and Sweden are closer than ever to joining.&nbsp; And this will occur.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re more united than ever.&nbsp; And with the addition of Finland and Sweden, we’ll be stronger than ever.&nbsp; They have serious militaries, both of them.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to increase the NATO border by 800 miles along the Finnish-Russian border.&nbsp; Sweden is all in.</p>



<p>The point is: We&#8217;re meeting the goals I set out when we first &#8212; the first G7 meeting.&nbsp; We&#8217;re moving to a place that reflects the realities of the 20- &#8212; the second quarter of the 21st century.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re on the verge of making significant progress.</p>



<p>Now, I&#8217;d be happy to take your questions.&nbsp; And the first question, I&#8217;m told, is Darlene Superville from the Associated Press.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Two questions, please.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Of course.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; “America is Back” was your motto at the first NATO Summit last year.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve come to this summit here and the one in Germany after the U.S. Supreme Court overturned constitutional protections for abortion, after the shootings in Buffalo and Texas, at a time of record inflation, and as new polling this week shows that 85 percent of the U.S. public thinks the country is going in the wrong direction.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How do you explain this to those people who feel the country is going in the wrong direction, including some of the leaders you&#8217;ve been meeting with this week, who think that when you put all of this together, it amounts to an America that is going backward?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They do not think that.&nbsp; You haven&#8217;t found one person &#8212; one world leader to say America is going backwards.&nbsp; America is better positioned to lead the world than we ever have been.&nbsp; We have the strongest economy in the world.&nbsp; Our inflation rates are lower than other nations in the world.&nbsp; The one thing that has been destabilizing is the outrageous behavior of the Supreme Court of the United States on overruling not only Roe v. Wade, but essentially challenging the right to privacy.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been a leader in the world in terms of personal rights and privacy rights, and it is a mistake, in my view, for the Supreme Court to do what it did.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I have not seen anyone come up to me and do anything other than &#8212; nor have you heard them say anything other than, “Thank you for America&#8217;s leadership.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve changed the dynamic of NATO and the G7.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I &#8212; I can understand why the American people are frustrated because of what the Supreme Court did.&nbsp; I can understand why the American people are frustrated because of inflation.&nbsp; But inflation is higher in almost every other country.&nbsp; Prices at the pump are higher in almost every other country.&nbsp; We&#8217;re better positioned to deal with this than anyone, but we have a way to go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the Supreme Court &#8212; we have to change that decision by codifying Roe v. Wade.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There were some comments by some of your counterparts after the U.S. Supreme Court ruling.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my second question is: G7 leaders this week pledged to support Ukraine, quote, “for as long as it takes.”&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if you would explain what that means to the American people &#8212; “for as long as it takes.”&nbsp; Does it mean indefinite support from the United States for Ukraine?&nbsp; Or will there come a time when you have to say to President Zelenskyy that the United States cannot support his country any longer?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We are going to support Ukraine as long as it takes.</p>



<p>Look at the impact that the war on Ukraine has had on Russia.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve had to renege on their national debt for the first time since the beginning &#8212; almost well over 100 years.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve lost 15 years of the gains they made in terms of their economy.&nbsp; They&#8217;re in a situation where they&#8217;re having trouble because of my imposition of &#8212; of &#8212; dealing with what can be exported to Russia, in terms of technology.&nbsp; They can&#8217;t even &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re having &#8212; they&#8217;re going to have trouble maintaining oil production because they don&#8217;t have the technology to do it.&nbsp; They need American technology.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re also in a simi- &#8212; similar situation in terms of their weapons systems and some of their military systems.&nbsp; So they&#8217;re paying a very, very heavy price for this.</p>



<p>And just today, Snake Island is now taken over by the &#8212; by the Ukrainians.&nbsp; So we are going to stick with Ukraine and all of the Alliance is going to stick with Ukraine as long as it takes to, in fact, make sure that they are not defeated by &#8212; by Ukraine &#8212; I mean, excuse me, in Ukraine by &#8212; by Russia.</p>



<p>And, by the way, think of this: Ukraine has already dealt a severe blow to Russia.&nbsp; Russia, in fact, has already lost its international standing.&nbsp; Russia is in a position where the whole world is looking and saying, “Wait a minute, all this effort &#8212; you tried to take the whole country.&nbsp; You tried to take Kyiv.&nbsp; You lost.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve tried to take the Donbas and all of it.&nbsp; You haven&#8217;t done that yet.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The generic point is that we&#8217;re supplying them with the capacity &#8212; and the overwhelming courage they&#8217;ve demonstrated &#8212; that, in fact, they can continue to resist the Russian aggression.&nbsp; And so, I don&#8217;t know what &#8212; how it&#8217;s going to end, but it will not end with a Russian defeat of Ukraine in Ukraine.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m supposed to go down the list here.&nbsp; Jim, the New York &#8212; Jim Tankersley, the New York Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you.&nbsp; This week, you and the G7 allies introduced a plan for an oil price cap for Russian exports &#8212; which is not yet filled out &#8212; and, obviously, is a response to the high price of gasoline in the United States and around the world.&nbsp; Are you confident that that cap would bring down prices for American drivers?&nbsp; And how long is it expect &#8212; fair to expect American drivers to continue to pay a premium because of this war?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me hear the &#8212; the second part of the question was, “Would it bring down the price?”</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will it bring down prices.&nbsp; And the war has pushed prices up.&nbsp; They could go as high as $200 a barrel, some analysts think.&nbsp; How long is it fair to expect American drivers and drivers around the world to pay that premium for this war?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; As long as it takes so Russia cannot, in fact, defeat Ukraine and move beyond Ukraine.&nbsp; This is a critical, critical position for the world.&nbsp; Here we are.&nbsp; Why do we have NATO?</p>



<p>I told Putin that, in fact, if he were to move, we would move to strengthen NATO.&nbsp; We would move to strengthen us &#8212; strengthen NATO across the board.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, let me explain the price &#8212; I suggested a while ago that what we should consider doing is putting a cap on the amount of money that we would pay for &#8212; the world would pay for Russian oil, and that we would not &#8212; there would &#8212; we would not provide &#8212; the West &#8212; provides insurance &#8212; would not insure Russian ships carrying oil.&nbsp; We would not provide insurance for them, so they would have great difficulty getting customers.</p>



<p>The point is that we&#8217;ve said to them, “Here&#8217;s the deal: We&#8217;re going to allow you to have a profit on what you make but not the exorbitant prices that you&#8217;re charging for the oil now.”&nbsp; We&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve delegated a commission &#8212; a group of our &#8212; (inaudible) sherpa &#8212; our national security people to sit down and work out that mechanism.&nbsp; We think it can be done.&nbsp; We think it can be done, and it would drive down the price of oil, and it would drive down the price of gasoline as well.</p>



<p>In addition &#8212; in addition, at home, I have also called for changes.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve &#8212; I&#8217;ve released a million barrels of oil per day from our oil reserve, and in addition to getting other nations to move forward a total of 240 million barrels of oil to release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; Number one.</p>



<p>Number two, I&#8217;ve asked Congress would they, in fact, go and end the &#8212; temporarily end the tax on gasoline at the pump.</p>



<p>And thirdly, to ask the states to do the same thing.</p>



<p>If we do these things, it&#8217;s estimated we could bring down, tomorrow, if they &#8212; if Congress agreed and the states agreed, we could bring down the price of oil about a dollar a gallon at the pump, in that range.&nbsp; And so, we could have immediate relief in terms of the reduction of the &#8212; of the elimination of &#8212; temporary elimination of the gas tax.</p>



<p>And so I think there&#8217;s a lot of things we can do and we will do.&nbsp; But the bottom line is: Ultimately, the reason why gas prices are up is because of Russia.&nbsp; Russia, Russia, Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reason why the food crisis exist is because of Russia &#8212; Russia not allowing grain to get out of Ukraine.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s the way in which I think we should move, and I think it would have a positive impact on the price at the pump as well.</p>



<p>Jordan Fabian, Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; I also have two questions for you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Of course.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; The first one is on Turkey.&nbsp; What assurances, if any, did you make to President Erdoğan about his request for new F-16 jets for his military?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What I said was &#8212; I said back in December, as you&#8217;ll recall, we should sell them the F-16 jets and modernize those jets as well.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not in our interest not to do that.&nbsp; And I indicated to them that I&#8217;ve not changed my position at all since December.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there was no quid pro quo with that; it was just that we should sell.&nbsp; But I need congressional approval to be able to do that, and I think we can get that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my second question is on your trip to Saudi Arabia, which is coming up next month.&nbsp; As we just discussed, Americans are paying almost $5.00 a gallon nationally, on average, for gas.&nbsp; So, do you expect to ask the Crown Prince or the King to increase oil production?&nbsp; And if so, how will you balance that with your desire to hold them accountable for their human rights abuses?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, first of all, that&#8217;s not the purpose of the trip.&nbsp; The purpose of the trip &#8212; my &#8212; first of all, I&#8217;m starting off on that trip in Israel.&nbsp; And the Israelis are &#8212; believe it&#8217;s really important that I make the trip.&nbsp; And in addition to that, what we&#8217;re trying to do is that the G- &#8212; it’s the Gulf States plus three.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;m sure &#8212; it’s in Saudi Arabia, but it&#8217;s not about Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; It&#8217;s in Saudi Arabia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so there&#8217;s no commitment that is being made or &#8212; I&#8217;m not even sure; I guess I will see the King and the Crown Prince, but that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s not the meeting I&#8217;m going to.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll be part of a much larger meeting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we&#8217;re talking about in dealing with that trip is that, before I go, I&#8217;m, as I said, going to Israel to meet with Israeli leaders to affirm the unbreakable bond Israel and the United States have.&nbsp; And part of the purpose is &#8212; the trip to the Middle East &#8212; is to deepen Israel&#8217;s integration in the region, which I think we&#8217;re going to be able to do and which is good &#8212; good for peace and good for Israeli security.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why Israel leaders have come out so strongly for my going to Saudi.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the overall piece here is we&#8217;re also going to try to reduce the deaths and &#8212; in the war that&#8217;s occurring in Yemen.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a whole range of things that go well beyond anything having to do with Saudi in particular.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if you were to see the Crown Prince or the King, would you ask them to increase oil production?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m not going to ask them.&nbsp; I’m going to ask &#8212; there&#8217;s &#8212; all the Gulf States are meeting.&nbsp; I’ve indicated to them that I thought they should be increasing oil production, generically &#8212; not to the Saudis particularly.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;re going to &#8212; I hope we see them, in their own interest, concluding that makes sense to do.</p>



<p>And, you know, they have real concerns about &#8212; about what&#8217;s going on in Iran and other places in terms of their security as well &#8212; all of them.</p>



<p><a><s>Tarina</s></a> [Tarini], the Wall Street Journal.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to keep the trend and also ask two questions, if that&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; One on the summit and one domestic question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the summit, you just said that there would be another round of security assistance for Ukraine.&nbsp; After hearing President Zelenskyy’s assessment that the war needs to end before the winter, are you changing your calculation in terms of the pace of the assistance and what kind of assistance you&#8217;re sending to Ukraine?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I &#8212; the war could end tomorrow, by the way, if Russia stops its irrational behavior.&nbsp; So, you know, when the war will end, I hope it ends sooner than later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But for it to end, they have to be in a position where the Is- &#8212; the Ukrainians have all that they can reasonably expect, we can reasonably expect to get to them, in order to perva- &#8212; provide for their physical security and their defenses.</p>



<p>And so, one does not relate to the other.&nbsp; They need &#8212; we&#8217;re going to be providing another &#8212; well, I guess I&#8217;ll announce it shortly, but another $800 billion &#8212; $800 million in aid for additional weaponry, including &#8212; you know, weapons, including air defense system, as well as offensive weapons.&nbsp; I have a whole list I&#8217;d be happy to give to you.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s the next tranche that’s going to occur.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the domestic question, sir: What further specific executive actions are you considering in response to the Roe ruling?&nbsp; And would you declare a public health emergency as several Democrats are calling on you to do?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll be happy to go in detail with you on that, on the &#8212; I&#8217;m having a meeting with a group of governors when I get home on Friday.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll have announcements to make then.</p>



<p>But the first and foremost thing we should do is make it clear how outrageous this decision was and how much it impacts not just on a woman’s right to choose &#8212; which is a critical, critical piece &#8212; and on privacy generally.&nbsp; On privacy generally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I&#8217;m going to be talking to &#8212; to the governors as to what actions they think I should be taking as well.&nbsp; And &#8212; but the bi- &#8212; most important thing to be clear about is we have to change &#8212; I believe we have to codify Roe v. Wade into law.&nbsp; And the way to do that is to make sure that Congress votes to do that.&nbsp; And if the filibuster gets in the way &#8212; it&#8217;s like voting rights &#8212; it should be we provide an exception for this &#8212; the exce- &#8212; the &#8212; require an exception to the filibuster for this action to deal with the Supreme Court decision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hang on.&nbsp; I got one more here.&nbsp; Kelly O&#8217;Donnell, NBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Well, you just made some news saying you would support changing the filibuster rules to codify abortion rights broadly across the country.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Right to privacy, not just abortion rights.&nbsp; But, yes, abortion rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you describe for us, sir &#8212; many Americans are grappling with this.&nbsp; What is your sense today about the integrity and the impartiality of the Supreme Court?&nbsp; Should Americans have confidence in the Court as an institution?</p>



<p>And your views on abortion have evolved in your public life.&nbsp; Are you the best messenger to carry this forward when Democrats &#8212; many of them, many progressives &#8212; want you to do more?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Yeah, I am.&nbsp; I&#8217;m the President of the United States of America.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; That makes me the best messenger.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I really think that it&#8217;s a serious, serious problem that the Court has thrust upon the United States not just in terms of the right to choose, but in terms of the right to who you can marry, the right &#8212; a whole range of issues relating to &#8212; to privacy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I have written, way back, a number of law review articles about the Ninth Amendment and the &#8212; and the Fourteenth Amendment and why that privacy is considered as part of a constitutional guarantee.&nbsp; And the &#8212; they&#8217;ve just wiped it all out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I&#8217;m the only President they got, and I feel extremely strongly that I&#8217;m going to do everything in my power which I legally can do in terms of executive orders, as well as push the Congress and the public.</p>



<p>The bottom line here is: If you care &#8212; if the polling data is correct, and you think this decision by the Court was an outrage or a significant mistake, vote.&nbsp; Show up and vote.&nbsp; Vote in the off-year and vote, vote, vote.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we&#8217;ll change it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, guys, I &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, just a quick one.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, there&#8217;s no such thing as a quick one.&nbsp; I&#8217;m out of here.&nbsp; Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>3:23 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Health Sector Leaders Join Biden Administration’s Pledge to Reduce Greenhouse Gas Emissions 50% by&#160;2030</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/fact-sheet-health-sector-leaders-join-biden-administrations-pledge-to-reduce-greenhouse-gas-emissions-50-by-2030/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56550</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Health Sector Steps Up to Protect Public Health and Lower CostsToday, the Biden-Harris Administration announced that 61 of the largest U.S. hospital and health sector companies responded to the Administration’s Health Sector Climate Pledge, committing to reduce greenhouse gas emissions 50% by 2030. The new commitments represent over 650 hospitals and thousands of other providers&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Health Sector Steps Up to Protect Public Health and Lower Costs<br></em><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration announced that 61 of the largest U.S. hospital and health sector companies responded to the Administration’s <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/04/22/hhs-launches-pledge-initiative-mobilize-health-care-sector-reduce-emissions.html">Health Sector Climate Pledge</a>, committing to reduce greenhouse gas emissions 50% by 2030. The new commitments represent over 650 hospitals and thousands of other providers across the country, and include plans to strengthen resilience to climate change, protect public health, and lower costs. The health care sector accounts for 8.5% of U.S. emissions, so these bold commitments advance President Biden’s goal to reduce nationwide greenhouse gas emissions 50-52% in 2030 and reach net-zero emissions in 2050.<br>Today, historic commitments are being made across the health care industry, including:</p>



<ul><li>Two of the five largest US private hospital and health systems (Ascension and CommonSpirit Health) and the largest US public health system have pledged to halve their carbon emissions by 2030.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Leading health sector suppliers like Pfizer and AstraZeneca have stepped up to achieve net-zero emissions ahead of the 2050 pledge timeline.</li><li>Major medical associations, including America’s Essential Hospitals, the American Association of Medical Colleges, and the National Academy of Medicine, have committed to taking climate action.</li></ul>



<p>The full list of the 61 organizations is outlined below.</p>



<p>President Biden sees action on climate change as a public health priority. Studies show that the increasingly dangerous consequences of climate change are affecting public health, through more frequent and intense severe weather, extreme heat, and threats to food and water security. The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to using every available tool to protect public health, while moving full-speed ahead with our mission to tackle the climate crisis, to create jobs, grow the clean energy economy, and lower costs for families.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration launched the <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/04/22/hhs-launches-pledge-initiative-mobilize-health-care-sector-reduce-emissions.html">Health Sector Climate Pledge</a> on Earth Day 2022 through the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). Since then, over 650 private and public hospitals and health centers, along with pharmaceutical companies, medical device-makers, suppliers, and group purchasing organizations have signed the pledge, joining more than 200 federal hospitals and health facilities from HHS, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and the Military Health System. These organizations are also developing climate resilience plans for facilities and communities, including plans to support individuals and communities most vulnerable to the impacts of climate change. Today, the White House and HHS are re-opening the Health Care Sector Pledge until October 28<sup>th</sup>, 2022 to build on these historic commitments ahead of the United Nations Climate Conference in November.</p>



<p><em>Private Sector Pledge Signers</em></p>



<p>61 organizations have signed the pledge, representing a large share of the US health sector, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Health Systems, Hospitals and Other Providers</strong><br><ul><li>Providence Health, HealthPartners, Kedren Health, CommonSpirit Health, University Medical Center of El Paso, NYC Health + Hospitals, Boston Medical Center, Baystate Health, Stanford Children’s Health, Stanford Health Care, Atrium Health, Cherokee Health Systems, University of California Health, Northwell Health, Rush University System for Health, Northern Arizona Healthcare, Hackensack Meridian Health, UW Medicine, RWJBarnabas Health, Sun River Health, NYU Langone Health, Ascension, Henry Ford Health, Mass General Brigham, Boston Children’s Hospital, Tufts Medicine, Southcoast Health, Children’s National Hospital, Mount Sinai Health System, Kaiser Permanente, Keck Medicine of USC, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Montefiore, Seattle Children’s, Valley Children’s Healthcare, University of Nebraska Medical Center and Nebraska Medicine, Advocate Aurora Health, Gillette Children’s, University of Utah Health, Steward Health Care System, DaVita<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Other Industry Organizations</strong><br><ul><li>Philips, AstraZeneca, Owens &amp; Minor, NewGen Surgical, Chiesi Group, Pfizer, AmerisourceBergen, Excellus Health, Blue Shield of California, Vizient, Aspirus, Anthem, WCM Waste and Compliance Management<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Associations, Nonprofits and Technical Assistance Organizations</strong><ul><li>National Academy of Medicine, Association of American Medical Colleges, the Joint Commission, Health Care Without Harm, American College of Physicians (NJ), Kimball Sustainable Healthcare, Mazzetti</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><em>Leading by Example to Advance Health &amp; Climate Goals</em></p>



<p>Last year, the Administration established the <a href="https://www.bing.com/search?q=ocche+at+hhs&amp;cvid=a82857c4043e4517b778c450e385f0e4&amp;aqs=edge..69i57j0j69i60l3.2674j0j1&amp;pglt=43&amp;FORM=ANNTA1&amp;PC=U531">Office of Climate Change and Health Equity</a> at HHS to identify and address health disparities exacerbated by climate impacts. Since then, the Administration has invested over <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/fact-sheet-white-house-announces-additional-385-million-to-lower-home-energy-bills-for-american-families/">$8 billion in the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP)</a> to help low-income Americans manage energy costs in the face of extreme weather.</p>



<p>The VA has made substantial progress implementing its 2021 Climate Action Plan, including incorporating climate resilience requirements into construction standards, assessing the adequacy of critical supply stockpiles to align with projected climate change impacts, and developing agency wide strategies to address mission risk amplified by climate change. Within its medical centers, VA has also successfully initiated efforts to transition to zero-emission vehicles, is accelerating efforts to increase energy and water efficiency, and is expanding upon existing and new sources of carbon-pollution free electricity.</p>



<p>Today, the Administration is announcing a series of new resources to support the health sector in transitioning to clean energy, reducing emissions, and building climate resilience:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Federal Health Sector Emissions Reduction Resources.</strong> HHS, with contributions from the Department of Energy (DOE), the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and the Department of Agriculture (USDA), is launching the “Accelerating Healthcare Sector Action on Climate Change and Health Equity” webinar series to provide education and training on sustainable infrastructure financing, climate emergency preparedness, and emissions tracking from the health sector supply chain.<br></li><li><strong>Federal Health Network on Decarbonization Best Practices.</strong> The VA, Military Health System, and Indian Health Service are launching a coalition to exchange best practices on emissions reduction and climate resilience with a plan to share their learning with private-sector organizations.<br></li><li><strong>National Research Forum on Climate Impacts and Heart Health.</strong> HHS is launching <em>The Million Hearts Climate Change &amp; Cardiovascular Disease Collaborative (CCC)</em>, a national forum for health care organizations to learn about climate change and the effects of air pollution on cardiovascular health, and to review evidence-based interventions to address those threats.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Health Sector Emissions Assessment Toolkit.</strong> HHS’s Agency for Health Care Research Quality (AHRQ) will release a suite of resources to facilitate consistent measurement and reporting of health facility emissions data and to provide guidance on transitioning to greener models of care delivery.<br></li><li><strong>Federal Funding for Climate Smart Health Facilities.</strong> The Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) launched the Green Mortgage Insurance Premium which will provide incentives for ongoing care facilities to implement energy and water efficiency upgrades. This program will lower costs for renovation and rehabilitation of facilities and increasing the safety of the populations they serve.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><em>Private Health Care Systems Leading the Way</em></p>



<p>Private health care systems are taking up the mantle on climate action – going beyond the HHS Health Care Sector Climate Pledge to achieve even greater progress on climate resilience:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Tackling Super-Polluting Medical Gases:</strong> Providence Health, Advocate Aurora Health, and Children’s National Hospital have committed to reduce emissions from medical anesthetic gases used in surgical procedures by over 75% &#8212; keeping these dangerous greenhouse gasses from being vented into the environment. AstraZeneca and Chiesi Group are tackling emissions from fluorinated gases used in common devices like inhalers, with the goal of reducing their carbon footprint by at least 90%.<br></li><li><strong>Investing in Clean Energy:</strong> Blue Shield of California, NYC Health + Hospitals, AmerisourceBergen, Kaiser Permanente, Children’s National Hospital and others have constructed on-site solar arrays and other clean energy generation sources to reduce emissions and provide direct benefits for surrounding communities. Kaiser Permanente has added over 44 MW of on-site solar generation – enough to power 9,600 homes, while the energy from Children’s National Hospital will benefit communities through a solar program that will lower utility costs for 325 families by up to $500 a year.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Achieving Carbon Neutrality:</strong> Seattle Children’s Hospital, Philips, Kaiser Permanente, and Blue Shield California have all surpassed their pledge commitment and already achieved carbon neutrality.<br></li><li><strong>Building Climate Resilience in Vulnerable Communities:</strong> Valley Children’s Healthcare, University of Utah, and CommonSpirit Health have developed and implemented detailed climate resilience plans that put the focus on communities most vulnerable to the impacts of climate change, because the cascading impacts on health such as poor air quality from wildfires, extreme heat, and increased instances of vector-borne diseases are hitting those communities first.<br></li><li><strong>Increasing Transparency on Climate Costs-Impacts: </strong>Vizient, AstraZeneca, and DaVita are leading the charge to ensure that company costs and accounting include risks to organizations from climate impacts through the Task Force of Climate Related Financial Disclosure. These actions will ensure that companies make climate-smart investments with information about how climate can disrupt health care supply chains, damage facilities or impact energy supply.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
