<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 15:45:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Fight Against Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/03/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-fight-against-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 8:47 A.M. EDT&#160;MODERATOR: Good morning, everyone, from the National Security Council at the White House. I would like to welcome our participants to an on-background conference call to discuss a forthcoming announcement by the White House related to the fight against corruption.&#160;Today we are joined by [senior administration official], as well as [senior&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>8:47 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR: Good morning, everyone, from the National Security Council at the White House. I would like to welcome our participants to an on-background conference call to discuss a forthcoming announcement by the White House related to the fight against corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today we are joined by [senior administration official], as well as [senior administration official]. We will begin with remarks from [senior administration official], and then we&#8217;ll open it up for a question-and-answer session.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a reminder, today&#8217;s briefing is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.” And the call content and the factsheet that we have not circulated yet but we will circulate at the conclusion of the call will be embargoed until they&#8217;re released by the White House later today.<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I will turn it over to our senior administration official for introductory remarks.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Great. Thanks. Hi, everybody. Good morning and thanks for joining the call today. I am really excited to be speaking to all of you about the President&#8217;s anti-corruption agenda in advance of our rollout later this morning of a national security study memorandum &#8212; that&#8217;s NSSM &#8212; on the fight against corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s worth noting that this is the first national security study memorandum of the administration, so it&#8217;ll come out as “NSM-1.” I don&#8217;t want to get hung up on the bureaucratic language of all of that, but the point is the memorandum is important because it&#8217;ll serve as formal and public direction from President Biden that he expects all relevant federal departments and agencies to up their anti-corruption game in very specific ways. And when you see the NSSM yourselves, you&#8217;ll see the specificity in the document itself.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, with the memorandum, President Biden is formally establishing the fight against corruption as a core national security interest of the United States. That was a commitment that he made during the campaign. And his pledge was that he would prioritize anti-corruption efforts and bring additional transparency to the U.S. and international financial systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that&#8217;s what we are embarked on, and the memorandum also speaks to our focus on delivering a foreign policy that benefits the American people, and particularly the middle class.<br>&nbsp;<br>So what the NSSM does is it directs the U.S. government to review and send to President Biden a report and recommendations in 200 days on how the government and its partners can modernize, coordinate, and further resource efforts to better fight corruption, tackle illicit finance, hold corrupt actors accountable, and build international partnerships. So it&#8217;s really the broadest span of what each of our federal departments and agencies does on anti-corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re really confident that implementation of this directive is going to lead to new and bold and decisive actions to combat corruption around the world. It, of course, builds upon much that we&#8217;re already doing &#8212; and I&#8217;m happy to speak to some of that agenda right now &#8212; but this is very much going to accelerate and prioritize that agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, with that, why don&#8217;t I leave it there and we&#8217;ll take a few questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Hi, guys. Thank you for doing this. I just &#8212; my first question is simply, you know, can you talk a little bit about some of the existing efforts under the Biden administration at the various agencies to make corruption a priority? Because I know this has sort of been in the works for a while, so it&#8217;s not like they&#8217;re starting from scratch.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah, thanks for that. So, that’s exactly right. We are very much hitting the ground running on this agenda, so let me just kind of give a few wave tops in terms what different departments and agencies are already doing that we expect to elevate with the NSSM today.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, some on the line may be familiar with the Corporate Transparency Act &#8212; that’s the law that Congress passed in last year’s National Defense Authorization Act that directs the Treasury Department to establish what’s called a “beneficial ownership registry” that effectively bars illicit assets from hiding the proceedings of corruption behind anonymous shell companies. So, Treasury is moving out on making that registry a reality. It&#8217;s a massive undertaking.<br>&nbsp;<br>And among other things, in his budget request, the President asked Congress to increase funding for this work by roughly 50 percent &#8212; 60-odd million dollars above what was enacted last year. So that really gave an early preview of how we&#8217;re looking to transform what Treasury does in terms of making sure that law enforcement is able to view the proceeds of corruption such that illicit actors can&#8217;t hide behind anonymity.<br>&nbsp;<br>Likewise, Treasury is building off of what&#8217;s already been done to limit the ability of illicit actors to hide behind anonymity. In terms of residential real estate, we have seen several instances over past years in which the proceeds of corruption have been funneled through shell companies and wound up in major metropolitan areas in the United States to offshore those ill-gotten gains, and so we&#8217;re going to be taking additional steps to make sure that that doesn&#8217;t happen in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>And across the board, we&#8217;re looking at analyzing the need for additional reforms to close loopholes in the entire regulatory regime that deals with corruption and illicit finance.<br>&nbsp;<br>On the Department of Justice side, some may be familiar with their Kleptocracy Asset Recovery Initiative. This initiative has really helped to make the United States a global leader in terms of recovery and return of stolen assets. In the &#8212; in the past two years, since 2019 alone, these asset recovery efforts have led to the transfer of more than $1.5 billion to countries that have been harmed by corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, on the State and USAID side, I think you&#8217;ve already seen significant statements by Secretary Blinken and Administrator Power on increasing their anti-corruption work. Stay tuned. I think there are going to be more announcements out of USAID soon, but we&#8217;re looking across the board to elevate our anti-corruption work in all of our bilateral context, as well as in multilateral fora, such as the G7 and United Nations.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that’s a little taste of, across departments, what we expect to be working on or accelerating ongoing work in the months to come.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you for taking the time. You know, the previous administration took something of a hands-off approach with corruption or with &#8212; would have them &#8212; you know, a transactional relationship, where they would essentially say, “We won’t worry about what&#8217;s going on in your country if you will work with us on these things that we need to work on.” And I&#8217;m wondering if, in any sense, this is meant to send a signal to the world that the U.S. does care about corruption again. Is there any, sort of, like, response to the past in this?<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, ahead of Vice President Harris&#8217;s trip to Latin America, are there any corruption measures associated with that, or any, sort of, additional push related to that?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: I&#8217;m not going to characterize the views of the prior administration, but I would say, to your point: The essence of the memorandum we&#8217;re going to release today is that the U.S. government is placing the anti-corruption plight at the center of its foreign policy, so we very much want to prioritize this work across the board.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the Vice President&#8217;s trip, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any announcements that are going to be made on the trip, but I can say that anti-corruption in the region is a major focus for the administration and will be a focus of all of her conversations while she&#8217;s traveling.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for doing this. As you know, anti-corruption activists periodically urge the U.S. government to use its various assets and capabilities, including the intelligence community, to expose specific cases of corruption overseas, to name and shame corrupt officials &#8212; and the arguments they make are familiar &#8212; but also include not only, you know, a deterrent to corruption, but also a possible contribution to the promotion of democracy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Does the does the memorandum &#8212; does the program include any component that connects with that?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;What I can say on that front is that the memorandum includes components of the intelligence community. So, the work on that front, in part, remains to be seen, but they are included &#8212; the Director of National Intelligence and Central Intelligence Agency.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so we&#8217;re just going to be looking at all of the tools in our disposal to make sure that we identify corruption where it&#8217;s happening and take appropriate policy responses.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;ll take the opportunity to mention that we&#8217;re also going to be using this effort to think about what more we can do to bolster other actors that are out in the world exposing corruption and bringing it to light.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, of course, the U.S. government has its own internal methods, but, largely, the way that corruption is exposed is through the work of investigative journalists and investigative NGOs.<br>&nbsp;<br>The U.S. government &#8212; to my point earlier, in terms of the support we&#8217;re already providing &#8212; in some instances provides support to these actors. And we&#8217;ll be looking at what more we can do on that front as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does the word “support” mean in that context?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Well, sometimes it boils down to foreign assistance. There are lines of assistance that have jumpstarted investigatory journalism organizations. What comes to my mind most immediately is OCCRP, as well as foreign assistance that goes to NGOs, ultimately, that do investigative work on anti-corruption, as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, good morning. Thank you for doing this. My question is to ask you: How are you going to engage with international allies to combat the impact of corruption coming from Latin American countries into the United States? For example, Venezuela or the Northern Triangle, as my colleague mentioned before. Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;So, as I mentioned earlier, the anti-corruption agenda will be front and center in the Vice President&#8217;s upcoming trip. And, across the board, we are engaging through every relevant multilateral body on this agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>And much of that &#8212; again, we&#8217;re not we&#8217;re not necessarily creating any of that work from scratch, but we are hoping to accelerate and elevate it, and that includes in the Western Hemisphere. But maybe [senior administration official] wants to jump in and say a little bit more on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thanks. You know, I think the general &#8212; underscoring what [senior administration official] just said &#8212; you know, working closely with our allies and partners includes engaging with civil society and investigative journalists, but also through our multinational and multilateral partnerships in the G7 and G20.<br>&nbsp;<br>This has been a big focus as well for the UK during their G7 presidency, to focus on working together on combating corruption. And so we have started those processes already, and I think you will see a lot more, particularly in our own backyard in the Western Hemisphere.<br>&nbsp;<br>A big indication is the Vice President&#8217;s trip &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s her first international trip. She&#8217;ll be going out there and discussing these issues. And as [senior administration official] mentioned earlier, anticorruption will be a key part of her trip there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi. So, [senior administration official], in your intro and in a couple of answers, you’ve referred to “illicit finance” and the danger of people profiting from corruption and being able to hide those profits through anonymity. Are you talking here about cryptocurrency? And if so, is this part of a larger discussion?<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, we&#8217;ve seen the use of cryptocurrency, the risk of cryptocurrency for illicit purposes in the ransomware attacks, for example. And there are certainly growing calls now for the administration to crack down on cryptocurrency and its use in illegal means. Is that what you meant to refer to, and is that where this is going?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah, thanks. We&#8217;ll certainly be looking at the impact of cryptocurrency as a means of illicit finance, but by no means was &#8212; were my remarks limited to crypto. We&#8217;ve seen, over many years, how corruption oversea- &#8212; the proceeds of corruption overseas make their way into the U.S. and international financial systems through anonymity.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this isn&#8217;t in any way limited to new technologies like crypto, but certainly as we think about the regulatory regime &#8212; the Bank Secrecy Act that governs much of this agenda, in terms of illicit finance &#8212; we will be asking for ideas around how we might want to modernize that regime to deal with issues like crypto, certainly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good morning and thanks for doing this. I want –- I think, as you mentioned, this is the first memorandum that we saw before sanctions against corruption yesterday. And there were sanctions against Bulgarian individuals. But also, we know that bad actors were able to survive despite sanctions everywhere, whether they are U.S. sanctions or, let’s say, international sanctions. Now, what tools are you planning to use? And let’s say you are using sanctions again &#8212; how you would use the sanctions as a tool without affecting an entire (inaudible) population? Let&#8217;s say, I give you an example here: Lebanon, let’s say.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Sure, thanks for that. So, this effort is really going to be across the board. And so, thinking about how we can better use sanctions to address corruption is definitely going to be part of the toolkit that we seek to emphasize. But sanctions are not the only tool in our toolkit.<br>&nbsp;<br>As I&#8217;ve been speaking to, we&#8217;re looking to make significant systemic changes to the regulatory structure that governs illicit finance. We&#8217;re looking to increase the use of law enforcement tools to go after corrupt actors. We&#8217;re looking to improve upon U.S. foreign assistance as a tool and increase the role that anticorruption plays in our day-to-day diplomatic work in bilateral engagements, in multilateral fora.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thinking about how sanctions are going to impact our anti-corruption agenda will be part of this conversation, but in no way will it be limited to sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>9:07 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Global Vaccine Distribution</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-global-vaccine-distribution/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 15:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the United States continues our efforts to get every eligible American vaccinated and fight COVID-19 here at home, we also recognize that ending this pandemic means ending it everywhere. As long as this pandemic is raging anywhere in the world, the American people will still be vulnerable. And the United States is committed to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As the United States continues our efforts to get every eligible American vaccinated and fight COVID-19 here at home, we also recognize that ending this pandemic means ending it everywhere. As long as this pandemic is raging anywhere in the world, the American people will still be vulnerable. And the United States is committed to bringing the same urgency to international vaccination efforts that we have demonstrated at home.<br><br>Already the United States has committed $4 billion to support COVAX, and we have launched partnerships to boost global capacity to manufacture more vaccines. My administration supports efforts to temporarily waive intellectual property rights for COVID-19 vaccines because, over time, we need more companies producing life-saving doses of proven vaccines that are shared equitably. We have already shared more than 4 million doses of vaccine with Canada and Mexico, and last month, I announced that, by the end of June, the United States will share 80 million doses of our vaccine supply with the world.<br><br>Today, we’re providing more detail on how we will allocate the first 25 million of those vaccines to lay the ground for increased global coverage and to address real and potential surges, high burdens of disease, and the needs of the most vulnerable countries. At least 75 percent of these doses—nearly 19 million—will be shared through COVAX, including approximately 6 million doses for Latin America and the Caribbean, approximately 7 million for South and Southeast Asia, and approximately 5 million for Africa, working in coordination with the African Union and the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention. The remaining doses, just over 6 million, will be shared directly with countries experiencing surges, those in crisis, and other partners and neighbors, including Canada, Mexico, India, and the Republic of Korea.<br><br>We are sharing these doses not to secure favors or extract concessions. We are sharing these vaccines to save lives and to lead the world in bringing an end to the pandemic, with the power of our example and with our values. And we will continue to follow the science and to work in close cooperation with our democratic partners to coordinate a multilateral effort, including through the G7.&nbsp;<br><br>Strong American leadership is essential to ending this pandemic now, and to strengthening global health security for tomorrow—to better prevent, detect, and respond to the next threat. The United States will be the world’s arsenal of vaccines in our shared fight against this virus. In the days to come, as we draw on the experience of distributing the vaccine doses announced today, we will have more details to provide about how future doses will be shared. And we will continue to do all we can to build a world that is safer and more secure against the threat of infectious disease.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Unveils Strategy for Global Vaccine Sharing, Announcing Allocation Plan for the First 25 Million Doses to be Shared Globally</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-unveils-strategy-for-global-vaccine-sharing-announcing-allocation-plan-for-the-first-25-million-doses-to-be-shared-globally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 15:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we continue to fight the COVID-19 pandemic at home and work to end the pandemic worldwide, President Biden has promised that the United States will be an arsenal of vaccines for the world. To do that, the Administration will pursue several additional measures beyond our robust funding for COVAX: Donating from the U.S. vaccine&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As we continue to fight the COVID-19 pandemic at home and work to end the pandemic worldwide, President Biden has promised that the United States will be an arsenal of vaccines for the world. To do that, the Administration will pursue several additional measures beyond our robust funding for COVAX: Donating from the U.S. vaccine supply to the world and encouraging other nations to do the same, working with U.S. manufacturers to increase vaccine production for the rest of the world, and helping more countries expand their own capacity to produce vaccines including through support for global supply chains. This vaccine strategy is a vital component of our overall global strategy to lead the world in the fight to defeat COVID-19, including emergency public health assistance and aid to stop the spread and building global public health capacity and readiness to beat not just this pandemic, but the next one.<br><br>Today, the Administration announced its framework for sharing at least 80 million U.S. vaccine doses globally by the end of June and the plan for the first 25 million doses.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Specifically, the Administration announced that: &nbsp;<br><br><strong><u>The United States will share vaccines in service of ending the pandemic globally</u></strong>. Today, the Administration announced its framework for sharing these 80 million U.S. vaccine doses worldwide. Specifically, the United States will:<br><br><strong><em>Share 75% of these vaccines through COVAX</em></strong>. The United States will share at least three-quarters of its donated doses through COVAX, supplying U.S. doses to countries in need. This will maximize the number of vaccines available equitably for the greatest number of countries and for those most at-risk within countries. &nbsp;For doses shared through COVAX, the United States will prioritize Latin America and the Caribbean, South and Southeast Asia, and Africa, in coordination with the African Union.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><strong><em>Share 25% for immediate needs and to help with surges around the world.</em></strong> The United States has received requests for vaccines from countries all over the world.&nbsp; The U.S. will share up to one-quarter of its donated doses directly with countries in need, those experiencing surges, immediate neighbors, and other countries that have requested immediate U.S. assistance. Specifically, we will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Set the stage for increased global coverage.</strong>&nbsp; The allocation of this first tranche of donated doses reflects the desire of the United States to respond to all regions and lay the ground for increased supply and access throughout the world.<br></li><li><strong>Prepare for surges and prioritize healthcare workers and other vulnerable populations </strong>based on public health data and acknowledged best practice. We will share with countries in urgent need, with a priority on vaccinating frontline workers. The United States will not use its vaccines to secure favors from other countries.&nbsp; The U.S. will work with partners who are both ready and in need.&nbsp; And, our donations will prioritize countries with vaccine readiness plans that prioritize individuals at highest risk of severe disease and those working to help care for them, like health care workers.<br></li><li><strong>Help countries in need and our neighbors.</strong> The United States will share vaccines in our region and across our borders. We first made doses available to our closest neighbors – Canada and Mexico.&nbsp; Our dose sharing approach prioritizes Latin American and the Caribbean on a <em>per capita </em>basis.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>The U.S. announced the proposed allocation plan for the first 25 Million doses.</u></strong> Based on the framework above and pending legal and regulatory approvals, the United States plans to send our first tranche of 25 million doses:</p>



<ul><li>Nearly 19 million will be shared through COVAX, with the following allocations:<ul><li>Approximately 6 million for South and Central America to the following countries: Brazil, Argentina, Colombia, Costa Rica, Peru, Ecuador, Paraguay, Bolivia, Guatemala, El Salvador, Honduras, Panama, Haiti, and other Caribbean Community (CARICOM) countries, as well as the Dominican Republic.</li><li>Approximately 7 million for Asia to the following countries and entities:  India, Nepal, Bangladesh, Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Afghanistan, Maldives, Malaysia, Philippines, Vietnam, Indonesia, Thailand, Laos, Papua New Guinea, Taiwan, and the Pacific Islands. </li><li>Approximately 5 million for Africa to be shared with countries that will be selected in coordination with the African Union. <br></li></ul></li><li>Approximately 6 million will be targeted toward regional priorities and partner recipients, including Mexico, Canada, and the Republic of Korea, West Bank and Gaza, Ukraine, Kosovo, Haiti, Georgia, Egypt, Jordan, Iraq, and Yemen, as well as for United Nations frontline workers.  </li></ul>



<p>The sharing of millions of U.S. vaccines with other countries signals a major commitment by the U.S. government.&nbsp; Just like in the United States, we will move as expeditiously as possible, while abiding by U.S. and host country regulatory and legal requirements, to facilitate the safe and secure transport of vaccines across international borders.&nbsp; This will take time, but the President has directed the Administration to use all the levers of the U.S. government to protect individuals from this virus as quickly as possible.&nbsp; The specific vaccines and amounts will be determined and shared as the Administration works through the logistical, regulatory and other parameters particular to each region and country.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Establishing the Fight Against Corruption as a Core U.S. National Security Interest</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/fact-sheet-establishing-the-fight-against-corruption-as-a-core-u-s-national-security-interest/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to tackling corruption as an economic and national security priority, and has pledged to lead international efforts to bring transparency to the global financial system and close loopholes that undermine democracy.  As the Interim National Security Strategic Guidance states:  “We will take special aim at confronting corruption, which rots democracy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to tackling corruption as an economic and national security priority, and has pledged to lead international efforts to bring transparency to the global financial system and close loopholes that undermine democracy.  As the Interim National Security Strategic Guidance states:</p>



<p><br> “We will take special aim at confronting corruption, which rots democracy from the inside and is increasingly weaponized by authoritarian states to undermine democratic institutions…We will crack down on tax havens and illicit financing that contribute to income inequality, fund terrorism, and generate pernicious foreign influence.” </p>



<p><br>Today, in line with this commitment, President Biden is releasing a National Security Study Memorandum (NSSM) that establishes the fight against corruption as a core national security interest of the United States. The NSSM directs a 200-day interagency review that will culminate in a report and recommendations on how the U.S. government and its partners can:<br><br><strong>Modernize, Coordinate, and Resource Efforts to Better Fight Corruption. </strong>Corruption threatens U.S. national security by eroding citizens’ faith in government, distorting economies, and enabling authoritarians to weaken democratic institutions. The NSSM therefore directs departments and agencies to identify and where appropriate establish new structures and staffing, improve intelligence collection and analysis, and increase resources aimed at confronting corruption at home and abroad.<br><br><strong>Curb Illicit Finance. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration has pledged to lead efforts internationally to bring transparency to the U.S. and international financial systems, including by reducing offshore financial secrecy, seizing stolen assets, and making it more difficult for those who steal to hide behind anonymity. The NSSM therefore directs departments and agencies to combat all forms of illicit finance, including through accelerating ongoing efforts to establish a “beneficial ownership” registry, so that illicit actors can’t hide the proceeds of corruption behind anonymous shell companies; limiting the ability of illicit actors to hide behind anonymity to buy residential real estate; and closing loopholes in existing regulatory regimes.   <br><br><strong>Hold Corrupt Actors Accountable. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to taking new steps to hold accountable corrupt individuals, transnational criminal organizations, and other actors engaged in illicit activity. This includes strengthening and building upon targeted anticorruption sanctions under the Global Magnitsky Act and similar authorities; and bolstering criminal or civil enforcement actions, such as under the Department of Justice’s Kleptocracy Asset Recovery Initiative. It also means increasing support to grow the capacity of civil society, the media, state and local bodies, international partners, and other oversight and accountability actors.<br><br><strong>Build International Partnerships. </strong>As part of its commitment to strengthening America’s alliances and partnerships, the NSSM directs departments and agencies to work with like-minded international partners through the UN, G7, Financial Action Task Force (FATF), and similar bodies to counteract strategic corruption emanating from autocratic and kleptocratic governments, foreign state-owned or affiliated enterprises, and transnational criminal organizations. This work will include closing loopholes exploited by those actors in order to mask the proceeds of corruption or interfere in democratic processes. <br><br><strong>Improve Foreign Assistance. </strong>The United States partners with foreign governments and civil society to enhance the capacity of their domestic institutions to implement transparency, oversight, and accountability measures. The NSSM therefore directs departments and agencies to focus on anticorruption best practices and improve enforcement measures in the implementation of foreign assistance programs and security cooperation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on the National Security Study Memorandum on the Fight Against Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-the-national-security-study-memorandum-on-the-fight-against-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Strengthening the resilience of rights-respecting democracies is one of the defining challenges of our era.  Corruption eats away at the foundations of democratic societies. It makes government less effective, wastes public resources, and exacerbates inequalities in access to services, making it harder for families to provide for their loved ones.  Corruption attacks the foundations of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Strengthening the resilience of rights-respecting democracies is one of the defining challenges of our era.  Corruption eats away at the foundations of democratic societies. It makes government less effective, wastes public resources, and exacerbates inequalities in access to services, making it harder for families to provide for their loved ones.  Corruption attacks the foundations of democratic institutions, drives and intensifies extremism, and makes it easier for authoritarian regimes to corrode democratic governance.<br><br>Corruption is a risk to our national security, and we must recognize it as such.  <br><br>Today, I am issuing a National Security Study Memorandum on the Fight Against Corruption to establish combatting corruption as a core U.S. national security interest. With this Memorandum, I am directing departments and agencies to make recommendations that will significantly bolster the ability of the U.S. government to combat corruption.<br><br>The United States will lead by example and in partnership with allies, civil society, and the private sector to fight the scourge of corruption. But this is a mission for the entire the world. And, we must all stand in support of courageous citizens around the globe who are demanding honest, transparent governance.<br><br>Fighting corruption is not just good governance.  It is self-defense.  It is patriotism, and it’s essential to the preservation of our democracy and our future.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on Updates to the President’s Travel to the United Kingdom, Belgium, and Switzerland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-updates-to-the-presidents-travel-to-the-united-kingdom-belgium-and-switzerland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to the United Kingdom, Belgium, and Switzerland in June 2021. This will be the first overseas travel by President Biden, who will be joined by First Lady Jill Biden for the stops in the United Kingdom as previously announced. This trip will highlight America’s commitment to restoring our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to the United Kingdom, Belgium, and Switzerland in June 2021. This will be the first overseas travel by President Biden, who will be joined by First Lady Jill Biden for the stops in the United Kingdom as previously announced. This trip will highlight America’s commitment to restoring our alliances, revitalizing the Transatlantic relationship, and working in close cooperation with our allies and multilateral partners to address global challenges and better secure America’s interests.<br><br>President Biden will meet British Prime Minister Boris Johnson on June 10 to affirm the enduring strength of the special relationship between the United States and the United Kingdom. President Biden will attend the G7 Summit in Cornwall, U.K., which is happening from June 11-13, where he will reinforce our commitment to multilateralism, work to advance key U.S. policy priorities on public health, economic recovery, and climate change, and demonstrate solidarity and shared values among major democracies.  He will also hold bilateral meetings with fellow G7 leaders.<br> <br>On June 13, the President and Dr. Biden will meet Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth at Windsor Castle. Dr. Biden will return to the United States following this meeting.<br><br>From the United Kingdom, President Biden will travel to Brussels, Belgium, where he will participate in the NATO Summit on June 14. President Biden will affirm the United States’ commitment to NATO, Transatlantic security, and collective defense. NATO leaders will discuss how to orient the Alliance to future threats and ensure effective burden sharing. The President will also meet with Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan to discuss the full range of bilateral and regional issues.<br><br>While in Brussels President Biden will participate in the U.S.–EU Summit on June 15, which will underscore our commitment to a strong Transatlantic partnership based on shared interests and values. The leaders will discuss a common agenda to ensure global health security, stimulate global economic recovery, tackle climate change, enhance digital and trade cooperation, strengthen democracy, and address mutual foreign policy concerns. President Biden will also meet with His Majesty King Philippe of Belgium and Belgian Prime Minister Alexander De Croo.<br> <br>As previously announced, President Biden will then travel to Geneva, Switzerland where he will hold a bilateral summit with Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin on June 16. While in Geneva President Biden will also meet with Swiss President Guy Parmelin and Foreign Minister Ignazio Cassis.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Establishing the Fight Against Corruption as a Core United States National Security Interest</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/03/memorandum-on-establishing-the-fight-against-corruption-as-a-core-united-states-national-security-interest/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Section 1.  Policy.  Corruption corrodes public trust; hobbles effective governance; distorts markets and equitable access to services; undercuts development efforts; contributes to national fragility, extremism, and migration; and provides authoritarian leaders a means to undermine democracies worldwide.  When leaders steal from their nations&#8217; citizens or oligarchs flout the rule of law, economic growth slows, inequality widens, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section 1.  Policy. </span> Corruption corrodes public trust; hobbles effective governance; distorts markets and equitable access to services; undercuts development efforts; contributes to national fragility, extremism, and migration; and provides authoritarian leaders a means to undermine democracies worldwide.  When leaders steal from their nations&#8217; citizens or oligarchs flout the rule of law, economic growth slows, inequality widens, and trust in government plummets.<br><br>In financial terms alone, the costs of corruption are staggering.  It has been estimated that acts of corruption sap between 2 and 5 percent from global gross domestic product.  While such costs are not evenly shared worldwide, the abuse of power for private gain, the misappropriation of public assets, bribery, and other forms of corruption impact every country and community.  The proceeds of these acts cross national borders and can impact economies and political systems far from their origin.  Anonymous shell companies, opaque financial systems, and professional service providers enable the movement and laundering of illicit wealth, including in the United States and other rule-of-law-based democracies.<br><br>Corruption threatens United States national security, economic equity, global anti-poverty and development efforts, and democracy itself.  But by effectively preventing and countering corruption and demonstrating the advantages of transparent and accountable governance, we can secure a critical advantage for the United States and other democracies.<br><br>In issuing this National Security Study Memorandum, I establish countering corruption as a core United States national security interest.  My Administration will lead efforts to promote good governance; bring transparency to the United States and global financial systems; prevent and combat corruption at home and abroad; and make it increasingly difficult for corrupt actors to shield their activities.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 2.  Strategy.</span>  Accordingly, I hereby direct the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor, in coordination with the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy and the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy, to conduct an interagency review process under National Security Memorandum/NSM-2 (Renewing the National Security Council System) and develop a Presidential strategy that will, when implemented, significantly bolster the ability of the United States Government to: <br>     (a)  Modernize, increase, coordinate, resource, and otherwise improve the ability of key executive departments and agencies (agencies), including those represented in the review and listed below, to promote good governance and prevent and combat corruption, including, as needed, by proposing relevant legislation to the Congress;<br>     (b)  Combat all forms of illicit finance in the United States and international financial systems, including by robustly implementing Federal law requiring United States companies to report their beneficial owner or owners to the Department of the Treasury; reducing offshore financial secrecy; improving information sharing; and, as necessary, identifying the need for new reforms;<br>     (c)  Hold accountable corrupt individuals, transnational criminal organizations, and their facilitators, including by, and where appropriate, identifying, freezing, and recovering stolen assets through increased information sharing and intelligence collection and analysis, criminal or civil enforcement actions, advisories, and sanctions or other authorities, and, where possible and appropriate, returning recovered assets for the benefit of the citizens harmed by corruption;<br>     (d)  Bolster the capacity of domestic and international institutions and multilateral bodies focused on establishing global anti-corruption norms, asset recovery, promoting financial transparency, encouraging open government, strengthening financial institutions&#8217; frameworks to prevent corruption in development finance projects, and combating money laundering, illicit finance, and bribery, including, where possible, addressing the demand side of bribery;<br>     (e)  Support and strengthen the capacity of civil society, media, and other oversight and accountability actors to conduct research and analysis on corruption trends, advocate for preventative measures, investigate and uncover corruption, hold leaders accountable, and inform and support government accountability and reform efforts, and work to provide these actors a safe and open operating environment domestically and internationally;<br>     (f)  Work with international partners to counteract strategic corruption by foreign leaders, foreign state-owned or affiliated enterprises, transnational criminal organizations, and other foreign actors and their domestic collaborators, including, by closing loopholes exploited by these actors to interfere in democratic processes in the United States and abroad;<br>     (g)  Enhance efforts to quickly and flexibly increase United States and partner resources of investigative, financial, technical, political, and other assistance to foreign countries that exhibit the desire to reduce corruption;<br>     (h)  Assist and strengthen the capacity of domestic (including State and local) authorities and institutions, as well as partner and other foreign governments at all levels, to implement transparency, oversight, and accountability measures, which will counter corruption and provide their citizens with accessible and usable information regarding government programs, policies, and spending;<br>     (i)  Promote partnerships with the private sector and civil society to advocate for anti-corruption measures and take action to prevent corruption; and<br>     (j)  Establish best practices and enforcement mechanisms such that foreign assistance and security cooperation activities have built-in corruption prevention measures.  </p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 3.  Interagency Review.</span>  In accordance with this memorandum, the interagency review shall consider the recommendations of expert studies and shall include representatives from the following agencies and offices:<br>     (a)  the Office of the Vice President;<br>     (b)  the Department of State;<br>     (c)  the Department of the Treasury;<br>     (d)  the Department of Defense;<br>     (e)  the Department of Justice;<br>     (f)  the Department of Commerce;<br>     (g)  the Department of Energy;<br>     (h)  the Department of Homeland Security;<br>     (i)  the Office of Management and Budget;<br>     (j)  the United States Mission to the United Nations;<br>     (k)  the Office of the Director of National Intelligence;<br>     (l)  the Central Intelligence Agency;<br>     (m)  the Office of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff;<br>     (n)  the United States Agency for International Development; and<br>     (o)  the National Security Agency.<br><br>Executive departments and agencies shall be responsive to all requests from the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor for information, analysis, and assistance related to the interagency review.  The interagency review shall be completed within 200 days of the date of this memorandum, and the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor shall submit a report and recommendations to the President for further direction and action.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"><br> JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on the Election of Isaac Herzog as the 11th President of the State of Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/02/statement-from-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-the-election-of-isaac-herzog-as-the-11th-president-of-the-state-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On behalf of the people of the United States, I extend my warm congratulations to Isaac Herzog on his election to serve as the 11th President of the State of Israel.&#160; Throughout his career, President-elect Herzog has demonstrated his unwavering commitment to strengthening Israel’s security, advancing dialogue, and building bridges across the global Jewish community.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On behalf of the people of the United States, I extend my warm congratulations to Isaac Herzog on his election to serve as the 11th President of the State of Israel.&nbsp; Throughout his career, President-elect Herzog has demonstrated his unwavering commitment to strengthening Israel’s security, advancing dialogue, and building bridges across the global Jewish community.&nbsp; I am confident that under his presidency, the partnership between Israel and the United States will continue to grow and deepen.</p>



<p>I also want to thank President Reuven Rivlin for his many years of service to the people of Israel.  I look forward to welcoming President Rivlin to Washington in the weeks ahead to honor his dedication to the enduring partnership and the close friendship between our two nations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s and Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh’s Meetings with German Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/02/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-and-deputy-national-security-advisor-daleep-singhs-meetings-with-german-counterparts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Dr. Jan Hecker, Foreign and Security Advisor to the German Chancellor, to discuss our close cooperation on a range of regional and global issues. They talked about the upcoming G7 leaders meeting and NATO summit, the importance of securing Europe’s energy future, collective efforts to share COVID-19&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Dr. Jan Hecker, Foreign and Security Advisor to the German Chancellor, to discuss our close cooperation on a range of regional and global issues. They talked about the upcoming G7 leaders meeting and NATO summit, the importance of securing Europe’s energy future, collective efforts to share COVID-19 vaccines, coordination on cybersecurity and response to ransomware attacks, and foreign policy priorities including Russia, Ukraine, Iran, the Sahel, and the Western Balkans. Experts from both governments discussed the Nord Stream 2 pipeline, including U.S. concerns about the risks it poses to Ukraine and European energy security.</p>



<p>Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh also met today with Professor Lars-Hendrik Röller, German Chancellery Chief of Division for Economic, Financial, and Labor Policy, to discuss a range of economic issues, including objectives for the upcoming G7 Leaders meetings, vaccine dose sharing, forced labor, post-COVID economic recovery, and 5G security.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the COVID-19 Response and Vaccination Program</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/02/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-covid-19-response-and-vaccination-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium 1:41 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT: Good afternoon. Today, the Vice President and I would like to lay out our plan for June, to counter &#8212; continue, I should say, our successful fight against the pandemic as we approach the July 4th date. In just four months, thanks to the American people, we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium</p>



<p>1:41 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: Good afternoon. Today, the Vice President and I would like to lay out our plan for June, to counter &#8212; continue, I should say, our successful fight against the pandemic as we approach the July 4th date.<br><br>In just four months, thanks to the American people, we have made incredible progress getting people vaccinated quickly, efficiently, and equitably. Nearly 170 million Americans of every party, every background, every walk of life have stepped up, rolled up their sleeves, and gotten the shot.<br><br>Fifty-two percent of adults are now fully vaccinated, including seventy-five percent of all seniors. Twenty-eight states and the District of Columbia have achieved 50 percent of adults being fully vaccinated in their jurisdictions.<br><br>And it’s clearer than ever: The more people we get vaccinated, the more success we’re going to have in our fight against this virus.<br><br>Since January 20 &#8212; and we’re talking, now, about <s>15</s> [5] months &#8212; the average daily cases are down from 184,000 to 19,000, below 20,000 for the first time since March of 2020. Average hospitalizations are down from 117,000 to 21,000. Death rates are down over 85 percent.<br><br>And this didn’t just happen by chance. We got to this moment because we took aggressive action from day one with a whole-of-government response. We used every lever at our disposal to get this done.<br><br>We experienced the production and expanded it in a significant way: in lifesaving vaccines available for every single American. They’re available, and we knew that was the case months ago.<br><br>We worked with cities and states to create over 80,000 vaccination sites. We deployed over 9,000 federal staff, including 5,100 active-duty troops to help get shots in arms. Now, as a result, we have built a world-class vaccination program.<br><br>I promised you we’d marshal a wartime effort to defeat this virus, and that’s just what we’ve been doing.<br><br>And now, tens of millions of Americans have been vaccinated. They’re able to return to closer to a &#8212; closer-to-normal life.<br><br>Fully vaccinated people are safely <s>shredding</s> [shedding] their masks and greeting one another with a smile. Grandparents are hugging their grandkids again. Small-business owners are reopening storefronts and restaurants.<br><br>Because of the vaccination strategy, our economic strategy, we’re &#8212; experienced the strongest economic recovery this country has seen in decades.<br><br>There is a group called the Organization of Economic Co-operation and Development &#8212; OECD &#8212; which includes most of the world’s largest economies in its membership. They’ve been one of those leading bodies analyzing economic growth across &#8212; around the world for 60 years.<br><br>Just this week, they increased their projection for the U.S. economic growth this year to 6.9 percent &#8212; 6.9 percent. That’s the fastest pace in nearly four decades. And that’s because of our vaccination program and our economic response, which, alone, are adding 3 to 4 percentage points to our growth; driving stronger growth not just there &#8212; not just this year, but in years to come.<br><br>In fact, America is the only major country where global forecasters have actually increased their five-year forecasts for economic growth since January of 2020.<br><br>And because of that, America is headed into the summer dramatically different from last year’s summer: a summer of freedom, a summer of joy, a summer of get-togethers and celebrations. An all-American summer that this country deserves after a long, long, dark winter that we’ve all endured.<br><br>But what happens after the summer? The data could not be clearer: For all the progress we’re making as a country, if you are unvaccinated, you are still at risk of getting seriously ill or dying, or spreading disease to others, especially when Americans spend more time indoors again, closely gathered in the fall, as &#8212; and as we face the potential threat of a new, more dangerous variants.&nbsp;<br><br>Even now, if you look at the areas of the country where vaccination rates are the highest, the death &#8212; the death rates are dramatically falling. They &#8212; the vaccines are effective; they’re effective against the variants currently circulating in the United States. On the other hand, COVID deaths are unchanged in many parts of our country that are lagging behind in vaccinations.<br><br>And for young people who may think this doesn’t affect you, listen up, please: This virus, even a mild case, can be with you for months. It will impact on your social life. It could have long-term implications for your health that we don’t even know about yet or fully understand yet.<br><br>It’s true that young people are much less likely to die from COVID. But if you do not get vaccinated, you could get COVID sooner or later. But you could get COVID still.<br><br>A substantial percentage of people with COVID, even young people, will suffer illnesses, and some will have long-term health impacts as a consequence.<br><br>If you’re thinking that the side effects from the shot are worse than the COVID, or that you can’t just take a chance, you are just dead wrong.<br><br>Do it for yourself. Do it to protect those more vulnerable than you: your friends, you family, your community.<br><br>You know, some people have questions about how quickly the vaccines were developed. They say they’ve been developed so quickly, they can’t be that good. Well, here’s what you need to know: Vaccines were developed over a decade of research in similar viruses, and they’ve gone through strict FDA clinical trials.<br><br>The bottom line is this &#8212; I promise you: They are safe. They are safe. And even more importantly, they’re extremely effective.<br><br>And if you’re vaccinated, you are protected. If you are not vaccinated, you are not protected.<br><br>Places with high vaccination rates will also see fewer cases of COVID moving forward. Places with lower vaccination rates are going to see more.<br><br>You know, we were elected to be President and Vice President for all Americans. And I don’t want to see the country that is already too divided become divided in a new way &#8212; between places where people live free from fear of COVID and places where, when the fall arrives, death and severe illnesses return.<br><br>The vaccine is free, it’s safe, and it’s effective. Getting the vaccine is not a partisan act. The science was done under Democratic and Republican administrations. Matter of fact, the first vaccines were authorized under a Republican President and widely developed by a Democratic President &#8212; deployed by a Democratic President.<br><br>All over the world, people are desperate to get a shot that every American can get at their neighborhood drug store at no cost, with no wait.<br><br>Every American over 12 years of age &#8212; no matter where you live, what you believe, who you voted for &#8212; has the right to get vaccinated. It’s your choice.<br><br>So, please, exercise your freedom, live without fear. We need to be one America, united &#8212; free from fear this fall.<br><br>Now, how will we keep beating this virus as we enter &#8212; as we enter the fall after summer? On May 4, I asked Americans to come together to get 70 percent of adults with one shot by July 4th &#8212; 70 percent at least with one shot. To date, 12 states have already reached this important milestone. We expect &#8212; we expect more to make this milestone this week.<br><br>Nationally, we are at 63 percent of adults with one shot. And we are getting closer, but we still have work to do. With 73 percent of Americans over the age of 40 with one shot, and as &#8212; we especially need people under 40 to step up. Over 40 is doing much better.<br><br>That’s why, today, we’re announcing a month-long effort to pull all the stops &#8212; all the stops to free ourselves from this virus and get to 70 percent of adult Americans vaccinated.<br><br>Now, I’m going to take everyone &#8212; you know, it’s going to take everyone &#8212; everyone &#8212; the federal government; the state governments; local, Tribal, and territorial governments; the private sector; and, most importantly, the American people &#8212; to get to the 70 percent mark so we can declare our independence from COVID-19 and free ourselves from the grip it has held over us &#8212; our lives for the better part of a year.<br><br>Each of you has the power to help us gain this freedom as a nation. If you get a shot this week, you can be fully vaccinated by July 4th &#8212; by the week of July the 4th. And you can celebrate Independence Day free from fear or worry.<br><br>This effort has five key parts. First, we’re making it easier than ever to get vaccinated. Ninety percent of you live within five miles of a vaccination site. The vaccinations are free, and most places allow walk-up vaccinations. No appointment needed.<br><br>You can go to Vaccines.gov or text your ZIP Code to 438829 to get a text back with the places you can get a shot that are close by.<br><br>And now, we’re going to make it even easier. In response to our call to action, businesses and organizations across the country have stepped up to help everyone get vaccinated.<br><br>Starting next week, many vaccination sites will be offering extended hours during the month of June, including pharmacies that will be open 24 hours every Friday night &#8212; for 24 hours they’ll be open &#8212; this month.<br><br>And if you’re too busy at work or school, you can get vaccinated around the clock on any Friday. Any Friday.<br><br>For parents who haven’t been able to get the shot because they didn’t have the childcare: Starting today, KinderCare, Learning Care Group, the Bright Horizons, alongside with hundreds of YMC- loc- &#8212; YMCA locations, are going to offer free drop-in childcare while the parents are getting vaccinated.<br><br>In addition, Uber and Lyft are both offering free rides to and from vaccination sites &#8212; vaccination centers. It&#8217;s easier than ever to get vaccinated.<br><br>So, again, text 438829 to vi- &#8212; to find out what the nearest places you can get vaccinated are from where you &#8212; from where your ZIP Code. And visit pharmacies with an extended-hour and walk-up shots that are available. Free childcare, free rides, free shots.<br><br>Second, we&#8217;re going to <s>reduce</s> [redouble] our outreach and public education efforts. We&#8217;re going to relaunch them, in effect. We&#8217;re going to launch a national vaccination tour to encourage people to take the shot. The Vice President is going to lead that tour across the South and the Midwest, where we still had millions of people to vaccinate.<br><br>She&#8217;s going to be joined by Jill &#8212; by the First Lady and the Second Gentleman and Cabinet Secretaries along the way.<br><br>In the spirit of meeting people where they are, we&#8217;ll also be working with the Black Coalition Against COVID and other organizations to launch a new initiative called &#8220;Shots at the Shop.&#8221; Barbershops, beauty shops are hubs of activity and information in Black and brown communities in particular, but in many communities across the nation. Local barbers, stylists, they become key advocates for vaccinations in their communities, offering information to customers, booking appointments for them, even using their own businesses as vaccination sites. We&#8217;re going to work with shops across the country to make an even bigger impact over the next month.<br><br>We&#8217;ll also kick things off this weekend with a National Canvassing Weekend, where thousands of volunteers will be out knocking on doors and encourage their communities to get vaccinated.<br><br>And mayors &#8212; mayors will be stepping up even more over the next month and partnering with us on the City Vaccination Challenge to see which city can grow its vaccination rate the fastest &#8212; the most &#8212; by July 4th.<br><br>We need you to join these efforts. This is the kind of on-the-ground work that’s going to get the job done.<br><br>Third, we&#8217;ll be increasing our work with employers &#8212; employers. A lot of working people are holding back because they&#8217;re concerned about losing pay if they take time off to get a shot, or if they don&#8217;t feel well the next day. I&#8217;ve said before: For small- and medium-sized employers, if you give people paid time off to get a shot, you&#8217;ll get a tax credit to cover that cost.<br><br>Already, millions of workers across the country are eligible for paid time off and incentives from their employers. I&#8217;m asking all employers: Do the right thing.<br><br>And we&#8217;re making it easy for employers to set up on-the-job vaccination clinics to make it even more convenient for their employees to get a shot.<br><br>Fourth, we&#8217;re going to continue encouraging people to get vaccinated with incentives and fun rewards. The state of Ohio had a heck of a fun reward &#8212; a new millionaire last week &#8212; thanks to the creative idea of the governor for holding a vaccination &#8212; a vaccine lottery.<br><br>The grocery store, Kroger, announced that they&#8217;re going to give away $1 million each week to someone who gets vaccinated at one of their pharmacies.<br><br>The NBA, the NHL, NASCAR &#8212; NASCAR tracks &#8212; they&#8217;re offering vaccine- &#8212; vaccines outside playoff games and at races. Major League Baseball will be offering free tickets to people who get vaccinated at the ballpark.<br><br>And to top it off, Anheuser-Busch announced that beer is on them on July the 4th. That&#8217;s right, get a shot and have a beer. Free beer for everyone 21 years or over to celebrate the independence from the virus.<br><br>Fifth, and finally, we&#8217;re asking the American people to help. We need you. We need you to get your friends, family, neighbors, and coworkers vaccinated. Help them find an appointment. Drive them to the site. Talk to them about why you made the choice for yourself. So many Americans have already stepped up to help get their communities vaccinated.<br><br>And over the next month, we&#8217;re going to need you more than ever. We need every American to commit to the five actions I&#8217;ve mentioned this month.<br><br>Go to WeCanDoThis.HHS.gov &#8212; WeCanDoThis.HHS.gov &#8212; to sign up to volunteer and learn more about how you can help.<br><br>Take at least five actions to help in June. And you might even be invited to visit us at the White House in July to celebrate independence together.<br><br>I&#8217;ll close with this: We need everyone across the country to pull together to get us over the finish line. I promise you we can do this. Just look at what we&#8217;ve already done &#8212; we&#8217;ve already accomplished together in only four months.<br><br>We know it for a fact: Americans could do anything when we do it together. So, please, do your part. Give it your all through July the 4th. Let&#8217;s reach our 70 percent goal. Let&#8217;s go into the summer freer and safer. Let&#8217;s celebrate a truly historic Independence Day.<br><br>Thank you for listening. Please get engaged. May God bless you all, and may God protect our troops. Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Mr. President, will you retaliate against Russia for this latest ransomware attack?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT: We&#8217;re looking closely at that issue.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Do you think Putin is testing you?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT: No.<br><br>1:58 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
