<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 02:08:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on 900,000 American Deaths from&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/04/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-900000-american-deaths-from-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 02:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, our nation marks another tragic milestone — 900,000 American lives have been lost to COVID-19. They were beloved mothers and fathers, grandparents, children, brothers and sisters, neighbors, and friends. Each soul is irreplaceable. We pray for the loved ones they have left behind, and together we keep every family enduring this pain in our hearts. After nearly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, our nation marks another tragic milestone — 900,000 American lives have been lost to COVID-19. They were beloved mothers and fathers, grandparents, children, brothers and sisters, neighbors, and friends. Each soul is irreplaceable. We pray for the loved ones they have left behind, and together we keep every family enduring this pain in our hearts.<br> <br>After nearly two years, I know that the emotional, physical, and psychological weight of this pandemic has been incredibly difficult to bear. I know what it’s like to stare at an empty chair around the kitchen table. But I also know that we carry an incredible capacity within ourselves — not only to come through our grief stronger, but to come together to protect one another.<br> <br>We now have more tools than ever before to save lives and fight this virus — with vaccines remaining our most important tool. Vaccines and boosters have proven incredibly effective, and offer the highest level of protection. Two hundred and fifty million Americans have stepped up to protect themselves, their families, and their communities by getting at least one shot — and we have saved more than one million American lives as a result.<br> <br>We can save even more lives — and spare countless families from the deepest pain imaginable — if everybody does their part. I urge all Americans: get vaccinated, get your kids vaccinated, and get your booster shot if you are eligible. It’s free, easy, and effective — and it can save your life, and the lives of those you love.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Signing of an Executive Order on Project Labor&#160;Agreements</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/04/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-an-executive-order-on-project-labor-agreements/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Upper Marlboro, MD 2:16 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT: &#160;That&#8217;s progress. &#160;(Applause.) &#160;You know &#8212; folks, thank you. &#160;(Applause.) &#160;(Laughs.) Thank you. Before I begin my somewhat formal remarks, walking in here today and seeing you guys sitting on that beam &#8212; the first &#8220;Local&#8221; ever to endorse me was a guy named Tommy Schrank (ph)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Upper Marlboro, MD</p>



<p>2:16 P.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;That&#8217;s progress. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;You know &#8212; folks, thank you. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;(Laughs.) Thank you.<br><br>Before I begin my somewhat formal remarks, walking in here today and seeing you guys sitting on that beam &#8212; the first &#8220;Local&#8221; ever to endorse me was a guy named Tommy Schrank (ph) in Elsmere, Delaware, Local Ironworkers.&nbsp; And he asked me to come out to a site.&nbsp; They took me up on an elevator outside.&nbsp; There was four of them &#8212; crazy sons of guns like you all, sitting and having their lunch on a beam, I guess about 12 stories above the ground.&nbsp; You&#8217;re nuts.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And thank God you are.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I tell you what: You got to not only have some brains, but you got to be coordinated to be an ironworker, man.<br><br>And I was told that &#8212; they said, you know, they&#8217;ve done a cutout of number 46, the vice pres- &#8212; the presidency.&nbsp; I&#8217;m the 46th President.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m thinking, &#8220;Well, maybe I can take it home.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; That&#8217;s solid steel, man.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And you guys did that on your time.&nbsp; Well, thank you very much.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to try and take it home.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But, look, folks, it really is &#8212; it&#8217;s an honor to be here, for real.&nbsp; And I want to thank your soon-to-be new, full-blown, full-bore ironworker.&nbsp; Marty is already trying to get her to Boston, but that&#8217;s another thing I got to warn you about.&nbsp;<br><br>But, folks, look, it&#8217;s an honor to be here with Vice President Harris and with the Labor Secretary, Marty Walsh –- a proud member and former president of the Laborers Local Union 222 &#8212; 223 up in Boston.&nbsp;<br><br>And our Secretary of Energy, Jennifer Granholm, has got a few things we&#8217;re going to build.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; and I want to thank the Maryland delegation: Ben Cardin, who&#8217;s been a friend for a long time; and Chris Van Hollen, who&#8217;s a really close friend and an outstanding congressman; Anthony Brown and other elected officials that are here.&nbsp; Look, all of whom fight for the working people, in Maryland and in every &#8212; and every other state.&nbsp; Because if it happens here, it happens around the world &#8212; happens around the country.<br><br>It&#8217;s been an honor to be with the ironworkers of Local 5.&nbsp; And we talk about &#8212; we talk about building a future that’s &#8220;made in America.&#8221;&nbsp; We’re talking about you.&nbsp; And this time we&#8217;re going to get it really correct.<br><br>You know, one of the press persons said to me &#8212; and I can&#8217;t remember who &#8212; about three months ago, that &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s factual or not, but he said, &#8220;You&#8217;ve used the word &#8216;union&#8217; as President more than any other President in American history.&#8221;&nbsp; So, let me tell you &#8212; (applause) &#8212; let me tell you: I’m not sure that it&#8217;s true.<br><br>PARTICPIANT:&nbsp; It&#8217;s true!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; But I tell you what: I promised you you would have a union President.&nbsp; And I am, because you&#8217;re the best.<br><br>You know, we talk about whether, you know, Wall Street built America.&nbsp; There are good folks on Wall Street; they&#8217;re not bad folks.&nbsp; There are good people all over the country.<br><br>I tell you who built America: the middle class.&nbsp; And the people who built the middle class are organized labor &#8212; unions, union.&nbsp; Unions did it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a straight fact.<br><br>And the executive order I’m going to sign today is going to help ensure that we build a better America, we build it right, and we build it on time, and we build it cheaper than it would have been otherwise.<br><br>You know, the executive order is making sure that federal construction projects get completed on time and under budget, saving taxpayers money, clearing construction zones quickly, and ensuring that everything the federal government signs to contract to build is built to last.<br><br>You guys really, genuinely, are the best in the world.&nbsp; Not &#8212; that&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a fact.<br><br>To do &#8212; to do that, we’re using a tool that ironworkers here know very well, called &#8220;project labor agreements.&#8221;&nbsp; I know you all know it, but folks who may be watching this may not fully understand it.<br><br>Simply put, these are agreements that contractors, sub-contractors, and unions put in place before a construction site gets underway &#8212; before the construction begins.<br><br>They ensure that major projects are handled by well-trained, well-prepared, highly-skilled workers, and they ward off problems.&nbsp; They resolve disputes ahead of time, ensuring safer work sites, avoiding disruptions and work stoppages that can cause expensive delays down the line.</p>



<p>And that makes a big difference for the American taxpayer.&nbsp; Because when big construction projects are completed efficiently and with the highest degree of professionalism, it’s good for the American taxpayer.&nbsp; That’s not hyperbole; that’s a fact.&nbsp; We don’t talk about it though.&nbsp; We don’t talk about how you all save the American taxpayers money.<br><br>It’s good for families who live in those communities.&nbsp; All across the country, the federal construction projects are being built as I speak.&nbsp; And it means that modernization of your local waterways will get done sooner, won’t cost twice as much as expected.&nbsp; And when the next storm comes, the power will more likely stay on and homes and businesses will be better protected from flooding.<br><br>It means new air traffic control towers at the local airport will be up and running more quickly, so flights are safer at the airports and more efficient.<br><br>It means new housing will be &#8212; built on our military bases will be of the highest quality, which these service members deserve. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp; It will hold up better and make life easier for our military families.<br><br>The executive order I’m going to sign will help defuse problems before they arise.&nbsp; They’re going to improve coordination between contractors, sub-contractors, and workers on the job site.&nbsp; It’s going to help guarantee a consistent supply of high-quality, highly trained workers.</p>



<p>You know, what people don’t understand if they’re not &#8212; don’t know the industry is, you know, it’s like you going to college, kid.&nbsp; Four years.&nbsp; Four years of busting your neck, learning a trade.&nbsp; This isn’t something you walk up and show up in a day and raise your hand, “I need a job.”&nbsp; You work like the devil for it.&nbsp; Fortunately, you get paid while you’re doing it and you’re able to do it, but it is an education &#8212; full-blown education you’re getting in your trade.</p>



<p>You’ll have a voice on the work site, full commitment to getting the job done.<br><br>And it’s going to raise the bar on quality for some of the most vital projects we’re going to be building.<br><br>And we’re going to make sure that federal construction projects are staffed with good-paying union jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of you actually came up to me today and said, “Joe, you said you’re going to do that, and you’re doing it.”&nbsp; Well, when President Obama asked me to run the Recovery Act, I made sure every single job I could get was a union job, prevailing wage.&nbsp; Because I’ve noticed when folks are getting paid a decent wage, everybody in the community does better, everything looks better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re jobs you can raise a family on.&nbsp; Or as my dad would say, “They’re jobs you can put your head on the pillow at night and just have a little breathing room&#8221; &#8212; a little security, a little breathing room.&nbsp; Jobs that can’t be outsourced.<br><br>That’s good for nearly 200,000 workers on federal &#8212; on federal construction contracts right now.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s good for everybody.<br><br>I don’t want to get going because I’ll keep you here too long, because you know all of what I’m about to &#8212; what I’ve said, and you know what I’ve done, and you know what we’re doing, and you know what &#8212; I know what you’re doing.</p>



<p>But let me close with this: A week ago, I went to Pittsburgh to tour a former steel mill that’s now a cutting-edge manufacturing research and development hub.<br><br>Right before I left on that trip, I got word that a bridge collapsed.&nbsp; You saw it on television.&nbsp; It looked as bad in person as it did at the time.&nbsp; The bridge had been rated in poor condition, like, I might add, over 3,000 bridges in Pennsylvania, 45,000 across the nation.&nbsp; It had been rated that way for the last 10 years.<br><br>When I got there, folks told me something close to a miracle had occurred.&nbsp; Because of a snowstorm that morning, school openings were late and commutes were delayed.<br><br>So, when that bridge collapsed &#8212; and it was well over 100 feet off the &#8212; two &#8212; almost two &#8212; I don’t &#8212; I didn’t &#8212; I don’t know the exact, but probably from down to the creek that it went over and the ravine, probably a couple hundred feet.</p>



<p>When it collapsed, instead of a bus with a couple people on it &#8212; being packed with school buses full of children, the people on their way to work on the bridge that is one of the busiest bridges &#8212; you know, there are more bridges in Pittsburgh than any other city in the world; the three rivers &#8212;&nbsp; the bridge was empty &#8212; relatively empty.</p>



<p>Fortunately, no one was killed but for a snowstorm.<br><br>Just imalg- &#8212; imagine the challenges we face and the opportunities to build a better America, and extend it far beyond roads and bridges now that we can &#8212; know what we have to do.&nbsp; We passed that infrastructure bill.&nbsp; But it’s not just that.<br><br>Across the country right now, there are countless buildings, ports, airports, power stations, and other federal construction projects that need to be modernized and built for the future.<br><br>We can’t count on miracles, like happened in &#8212; out in Pittsburgh, to prevent tragedies that are waiting in plain sight.&nbsp;<br><br>But what we can count on, what America has always counted on: the American worker &#8212; the hardest-working, best-trained workers in the world; American workers who, given just half a chance, have never, ever, ever, ever, ever let their country down, and gotten the job done.&nbsp;<br><br>And that’s what this day is all about, in my view: getting the job done for the American taxpayers, getting the job done right the first time.<br><br>You know, folks, there&#8217;s a law that&#8217;s existed for a long time that has too many exceptions like this one had, and that is that &#8212; Buy American.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>As President of the United States, I award contracts.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m now making it the case &#8212; and it’s working; it’s one of the reasons those jobs were up &#8212; is unless the product that I&#8217;m purchasing for the American people was made in America and all of its component parts are made in America, we ain&#8217;t buying it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just simply not buying it.<br><br>And what&#8217;s going to happen here &#8212; not a joke; it’s a fact.&nbsp; It’s not a violation of any international laws either.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re talking about here, with three exceptions I won&#8217;t bore you with &#8212; and they&#8217;re highly unusual &#8212; but three exceptions: Every single project that we&#8217;re talking about that’s paid for with federal dollars and is a federal project, it’s going to be union jobs &#8212; (applause) &#8212; every single one of them.<br><br>The last time we tried it, there were so many exceptions, I think only 19, 20 jobs (inaudible).&nbsp; There are going to be thousands &#8212; thousands of people put to work.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; I mean, this is serious.&nbsp;<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; The American public is going to be safer, and it&#8217;s going to be cheaper &#8212; cheaper paying the right wage and the right trained people to begin with and get the job done right and on time.<br><br>So, I&#8217;m about to walk over and sign an executive order that&#8217;s going to make that happen.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to start once that order is signed.<br><br>Just remember: It ain&#8217;t labor; it’s unions.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Now, usually you have a pen to give out to everybody around you, but we didn&#8217;t have enough pens to bring with us.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m going to sign this order, but you&#8217;re all going to get one of the signing pens, starting with the Maryland delegation.&nbsp;<br><br>(The executive order is signed.)<br><br>There you go.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>2:30 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>October 2021 Visitor Log Records&#160;Posted</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/disclosures/2022/02/04/october-2021-visitor-log-records-posted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Disclosures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the White House released visitor log records generated in October 2021. This set includes 2858 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 21324. These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the White House released visitor log records generated in October 2021. This set includes 2858 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 21324.</p>



<p>These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first administration to post visitor log records from its first full year in office.</p>



<p>To learn more about the policy, read our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/voluntary-disclosure/">voluntary disclosure policy</a>. To view visitor log records, view our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/disclosures/visitor-logs/">disclosure page</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/04/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 20:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:20 P.M. EST&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; I know also there&#8217;s a time limitation today, so we will make sure everybody is where they need to be when they need to be there.&#160;&#160;Good morning.&#160; I just wanted to note at the top: I&#8217;m wearing red today in honor of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:20 P.M. EST<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I know also there&#8217;s a time limitation today, so we will make sure everybody is where they need to be when they need to be there.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Good morning.&nbsp; I just wanted to note at the top: I&#8217;m wearing red today in honor of National Wear Red Day and American Heart Month.<br>&nbsp;<br>Heart disease is the leading cause of death in the United States, claiming the lives of 650,000 people every year, with a disproportionate burden on communities of color.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is committed to supporting Americans in their efforts to achieve better heart health and closing the racial gaps in cardiovascular disease.&nbsp; That’s why we’re taking a whole-of-government approach to reduce diet-related chronic diseases and encourage every American to live a healthy lifestyle.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President has also called on Congress to launch his ARPA-H initiative, which would invest billions of dollars in preventing, detecting, and treating cancer, cardiovascular conditions, and other deadly diseases.<br>&nbsp;<br>And there are a number of other red-wearers today in here, too.&nbsp; I don’t want to &#8212; I don’t want to speak to what you picked out of your closet, but maybe you&#8217;re recognizing the same thing.&nbsp;<br> <br>Also wanted to note that a new competition and supply chain announcement that came out today &#8212; yesterday, I should say &#8212; sorry &#8212; from the Justice Department and the U.S. Department of Agriculture.&nbsp; They launched FarmerFairness.gov &#8212; a new online tool that gives farmers and ranchers a one-stop shop for reporting potentially illegal practices in agricultural markets.<br>&nbsp;<br>As the President noted when he met with farmers and ranchers last month, the meat-processing industry is highly consolidated.&nbsp; Just four companies control most of the markets for beef, poultry, and pork.&nbsp; That gives meat processors enormous power over farmers and ranchers.&nbsp; And too often, they use that power to exploit and underpay them.<br>&nbsp;<br>The launch of this new tool is a critical part of the Biden-Harris administration’s Action Plan for a Fairer, More Competitive, and More Resilient Meat and Poultry Supply Chain.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is a one-stop shop to report potential violations, and it will allow the Justice Department and the USDA to better address anticompetitive actions and create meat and poultry markets that are fairer to American farmers and ranchers.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, wanted to note this &#8212; shortly, the President will sign an executive order to improve timeliness, lower costs, and increase quality in federal construction projects.&nbsp; The order presumptive &#8212; requires the use of project labor agreements on federal construction projects, which will help the management and coordination challenges that can stymie progress on major construction projects.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Federal construction projects span the country, as we all know, from the maintenance of nuclear sites, to the upkeep at our military bases, to waterways and flood projects.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Based on the FY2021 figures, the order could affect $262 billion in federal government construction contracting and improve job quality for near &#8212; for the nearly 200,000 workers on federal construction contracts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Additionally, as directly in the previous executive order, starting January 30th, federal contractors will be paid a $15 minimum wage.<br>&nbsp;<br>And briefly, the week ahead &#8212; last thing: On Monday, as you all know, the President Biden will welcome the Chancellor of Germany to the White House, Chancellor Scholz.&nbsp; They will affirm the deep and enduring ties with &#8212; between the United States and Germany, and discuss their shared commitment to ongoing diplomacy and joint efforts to deter further Russian aggression against Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>They will also discuss our close cooperation on everything from COVID-19 &#8212; the COVID-19 pandemic to addressing the threat of climate change and promoting international security based on our shared democratic values.<br>&nbsp;<br>They will then participate in a joint press availability following the bilateral meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>On Tuesday and Wednesday, the President will participate in events at the White House, providing updates on his economic plan to lower costs for the American people and create more good-paying jobs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And on Thursday, he will travel to continue promoting his agenda.&nbsp; I expect we&#8217;ll have more details on that in the coming days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So yesterday, you and State Department Spokesman Ned Price both took issue with reporters asking for evidence of your statements with respect to the Syria strike and the Russian false-flag operation.&nbsp; Do you really believe that journalists are repeating Russian and Islamic State propaganda in pursuing those questions, first of all?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And second of all, will you be offering evidence of your claims with respect to what happened in Syria when they become available?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And I will &#8212; let me just start by saying that we welcome tough questions and good-faith scrutiny, otherwise I wouldn&#8217;t come out here &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t have come out here almost 180 times and engaged with all of you and your tough questions and good-faith scrutiny.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I noted in the response to a question from your colleague yesterday, which wasn&#8217;t in all of the context of what was put out there, we are less than 48 hours from the end of the mission, so the Department of Defense is still conducting after-action assessments.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a natural part of the process that occurs.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also conveyed in my answer to the question: The President directed his Department of Defense to take every precaution to minimize civilian casualties and that we would release all of the information we could.&nbsp; And we absolutely remain committed to that, to answer the other part of your question.<br>&nbsp;<br>While I did not go into this level of detail during the plane gaggle, we also did a number of briefings a number of you participated in yesterday to brief out a number of the specific details, including the fact that we sent out special operators, at significant risk to themselves, to minimize the risk of civilian casualties.<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, that&#8217;s different than doing a strike, which would not be as much risk to individuals involved.&nbsp; But obviously, these individuals were on the ground for a couple of hours, as we briefed out.&nbsp; It would have been easier to do an airstrike.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But as a result, we have firsthand reports from our elite service members who are on the ground and risked their lives to kill a terrorist responsible to &#8212; for the slaughter and enslavement of the Yazidi religious minority in the north &#8212; in Northwestern Iraq in 2014, who bears responsibility for a recent set of attacks against the Iraqi Security Forces &#8212; and who took a terrorist off the battlefield who seeks to harm Americans.<br>&nbsp;<br>But of course, we respect and value the role of the press &#8212; otherwise, again, I wouldn&#8217;t be out here with all of you every day &#8212; and welcome the scrutiny, welcome to tough questioning.&nbsp; And as I said yesterday, of course we will do everything we can to provide as many details as possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think it&#8217;s important, as people are trying to understand this, to note it is different having operators on the ground than an airstrike where it&#8217;s a different assessment after action.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the jobs report, both administration officials and outside experts expected a worse jobs report than we saw.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any sense of why those expectations were off and what exactly that means for your future, sort of, policy with respect to the recovery and the economy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what is also true: As much as we had a very encouraging jobs report today and as we look back to the revisions made as a part of the report this morning, the largest year of economic &#8212; of job creation ever in American history.<br>&nbsp;<br>Those are certainly things we are proud of, the President is proud of, and we attribute that in part to the actions he took to implement a number of important policies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is also true &#8212; and this is one of the step &#8212; one of the facts that we have been pointing out over the course of last couple of days &#8212; that Omicron forced around 8 million people to take time off of work.&nbsp; And that was during a period of time where it was measured.&nbsp; So, that is also true.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, some of these people who were sick were not &#8212; would not have been counted in these job numbers.&nbsp; And that was a fact we just wanted people to understand as we were leading up to the jobs report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is also clear that it’s very challenging to collect, analyze, adjust the data during this time of the pandemic.&nbsp; We are very grateful to the BLS team that does that.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just incredibly challenging during an ongoing pandemic.&nbsp; But we think they&#8217;ve continued to deliver timely information.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve obviously continued to provide updates on a monthly basis when the &#8212; when their assessments change.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Xi and Putin met on &#8212; today, I guess &#8212; and released a pretty lengthy statement after that meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just moving a little bit further back from the meeting itself, how does the President view the relationship between China, Russia &#8212; Xi and Putin &#8212; through the lens of his broader foreign policy goals, agenda items, relationships?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; the President views it &#8212; views it as we have our own relationship with China.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken spoke to China&#8217;s Foreign Minister Wang and underscored &#8212; just recently, last week &#8212; and underscored the global security and economic risks posed by further Russian aggression against Ukraine, and conveyed that de-escalation and diplomacy are the responsible way forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also conveyed that destable- &#8212; a destabilizing conflict in Europe would impact China&#8217;s interests all over the world.&nbsp; And certainly, China should know that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, certainly, we have our own relationship where we engage directly at a very high level, as you all know, but our focus right now is continuing to unite with Allies and partners to respond decisively if Russia further invades Ukraine.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there any concerns about that relationship &#8212; if it gets closer, if it becomes more intertwined &#8212; in terms of U.S. posture and role in geopolitical spheres?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, what we have control over is our own relationships and the projection of our own values, and also looking for ways to work with countries, even where we disagree, and that is part of diplomacy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would note that &#8212; because some of the reporting has accurately assessed or, you know, raised the question of what took place in these conversations &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything to update on that, I don&#8217;t think you would expect.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the size and the scope of economic measures on the table that we&#8217;re talking about, as it relates to Russian aggression or the potential of invasion, are unprecedented; would pose massive consequences for the Kremlin; and the inputs to &#8212; and I think it&#8217;s important for people to understand that the inputs to the major foundational technologies of the world still come from the West.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s an enormous amount of power we have as we work to continue to strengthen our diplomatic efforts with our partners around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more quick one.&nbsp; And obviously, I&#8217;m not going to try and repeat what Matt did yesterday with Ned, because I know you’ve experienced it times in a past life.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But when it comes to &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I do.&nbsp; I do.&nbsp; I had many engagements with Matt Lee in my time.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The idea though &#8212; and you&#8217;ve done this a couple times of times &#8212; and the British have, to some degree, as well &#8212; of getting out in front.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think almost giving insight into intelligence that perhaps past administrations, including past Democratic administrations, would not have done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you explain, kind of, the thinking in that, strategically, and why you guys have decided to get out front on these types of things in this moment in time?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure. &nbsp;So, over the past several months, we &#8212; but also a number of our Allies &#8212; have developed a significant amount of credible intelligence about Russian efforts to use a false pretext to justify an invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; And this evidence mirrors both public reporting and Russian accounts in past conflicts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I would note: A number of your outlets, obviously, have reporters on the ground &#8212; right? &#8212; who are seeing for themselves what is happening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is also true that &#8212; is that we&#8217;ve seen Russians&#8217; acti- &#8212; the Russians&#8217; actions &#8212; Russians&#8217; actions &#8212; over the past few years.&nbsp; You know, if you look just back at past precedent, it doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s guaranteed to repeat, but it is &#8212; it is important for people to understand contextually what they&#8217;re capable of and what tactics they&#8217;ve used in the past.&nbsp; And sometimes you see &#8212; you do see repetition of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, a few years ago, for example, Russia&#8217;s Defense Ministry falsely claim- &#8212; accused the United States of running a clandestine biological weapons lab in the country of Georgia, enabling Russia&#8217;s efforts to destabilize the Georgian government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Russia also used to fabricate stories in Syria about how attacks on international aid convoys were undertaken by rebels or terrorist, instead of the Assad regime, to enable Russia&#8217;s continued support for the Assad government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you look back at 2016, the Russian media manufactured a false claim of sexual assault against a Russian émigré named Lisa by German refugees in order to stoke hysteria against Syrian immigrants throughout Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there&#8217;s more.&nbsp; Russian state television aired a false report that claimed the Ukrainian army had crucified a three-year-old Ukrainian Boy.&nbsp; That is even more recently.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, our objective is to deny Russia the opportunity to use these lies to justify an invasion of Ukraine and to convey clearly these are actions we&#8217;re seeing that are straight out of their playbook.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen them run false-flag operations in the past and use confusion to launch military action many times in history.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Of course, we would prefer to make as much underlying information available as we can.&nbsp; And in fact, the &#8212; what we conveyed yesterday and was conveyed by my colleagues at the Defense Department and State Department was a result of declassifying information.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We can&#8217;t do &#8212; there are limitations because of compromising intelligence sources and methods.&nbsp; But what we&#8217;re trying to do is take steps to deny Russia the opportunity to use lies, to use past tactics to justify an invasion of Ukraine, essentially, to avoid war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; If Putin decides to make a move into Ukraine, how long does the U.S. believe that the Ukrainians could hold off a full Russian takeover?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Jacqui, it&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I would really point you to the Department of Defense to make any assessment, if they can.&nbsp; And obviously, some assessments they might not be in a position to make publicly.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That they would not want to share publicly or that they don&#8217;t know?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m just conveying that there are some assessments and, obviously, you &#8212; the Department of Defense does a range of contingency planning.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let them speak for themselves on what they could &#8212; what they could lay out publicly for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, we&#8217;ve known about the reality of this threat since October.&nbsp; Putin began amassing troops on the border in April.&nbsp; So, why have we waited so long to send the kind of aid that we&#8217;re seeing now?&nbsp; Why haven&#8217;t we sent, for instance, anti-aircraft weaponry?&nbsp; Because if Russia does an airstrike, wouldn&#8217;t they be able to obliterate what we&#8217;ve sent to them so far?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, remember, the President met with President Zelenskyy back in &#8212; I think it was September, but you can correct me if that&#8217;s wrong; it was sometime early in the fall &#8212; and committed to a large aid package.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That is something that we&#8217;ve been implementing and delivering since that point in time.&nbsp; So, actually, it&#8217;s been continuous security assistance that we&#8217;ve been providing to the Ukrainians &#8212; an enormous package that we&#8217;ve been providing over the course of the last year.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of weapon systems, I’d again point you to the Department of Defense.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the feeling within the administration is that we have responded in a timely manner to Ukraine&#8217;s concerns?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think what&#8217;s important for people to understand is that this has been continuous.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t that we had never provided aid, whether it&#8217;s humanitarian or security assistance, and all of a sudden we did recently.&nbsp; We &#8212; that has been a continuous process.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve provided hundreds of billions of dollars in aid, security assistance over the course of not just the last year, but long before that, and including a commitment the President made and was announced around President Zelenskyy’s visit.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, moving on to energy: I mean, gas prices are at a seven-year high here in the U.S. right after OPEC, again, snubbed requests to increase production.&nbsp; And then there&#8217;s this energy crisis in Western Europe brewing.&nbsp; Is there any point where the President would consider opening up domestic production in order to mitigate some of this?&nbsp; The inflation and, you know, assist our allies in Western Europe?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s a couple of important questions you raised there.&nbsp; Let me start by saying that, as it relates to Europe and the shortage &#8212; or potential, I should say &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t exist currently.&nbsp; Everybody is experiencing high gas prices, but I think you&#8217;re asking as it relates to a potential invasion.&nbsp; That is something we&#8217;ve been very mindful of and in touch with our European partners and also suppliers about what can be done and how we can ensure or take steps to increase capacity out there to meet those needs, should they raise; some of them is natural gas, some of them is gas, as you know.&nbsp; So, that is something we&#8217;ve been quite mindful of.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that the President has been &#8212; has taken a number of steps in recent months to address the gas prices, including tapping the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, of course conveying clearly to OPEC member countries and suppliers that it&#8217;s important to meet the demand on the market.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to &#8212; to look at options that can be done to lower gas prices for the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of whether or not there could be more oil drilling, you know, I&#8217;d point you to the oil companies on what available places they have and if they&#8217;re maximizing that.&nbsp; My understanding is they’re not.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any consideration for increasing, for instance, LNG export licenses?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of additional steps.&nbsp; I can &#8212; can just reiterate to you that the President raises and talks about the importance of taking every step we can to lower gas prices for the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then real quick on the Johns Hopkins study on the lockdowns.&nbsp; It was this meta-analysis that came out of several studies.&nbsp; Lockdowns during the first wave of COVID in the spring of 2020 found that it only reduced COVID mortality by 0.2 percent in the U.S. and Europe, and suggested that they have little to no public health benefit but severe consequences for the economy.&nbsp; And it suggests that lockdowns shouldn&#8217;t be a part of a future pandemic response.&nbsp; Is that the shared view of the administration looking in the rearview mirror?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say &#8212; I would, sort of, first, of course, point to our health and medical experts for specifics on this specific &#8212; scientific study.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that the President has been clear we&#8217;re not pushing lockdowns; we&#8217;ve not been pro-lockdown.&nbsp; That has not been his agenda.&nbsp; Most of the lockdowns actually happened under the previous president.<br>&nbsp;<br>What our objective has been is to &#8212; conveying that we have the tools we need to keep our country open, thanks to the President&#8217;s leadership, and focus on fighting the virus.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s reflected in the fact that 98 percent of schools are open, over 210 million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; We have the tools to avoid lockdowns, and we&#8217;re not moving back.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s our intention at this point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you guys do believe then that the lockdowns were more harmful than helpful?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I would point you to our scientific experts on the specifics of a study.&nbsp; But the President&#8217;s agenda, the President&#8217;s approach has not been lockdowns.&nbsp; It has been using the tools we have to prevent that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Supreme Court nomination, Senator Ben Ray Luján’s office is saying, today, he&#8217;s going to be out for four to six weeks.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve obviously wished him well.&nbsp; Hopefully it’s shorter than that.&nbsp; But, you know, sometimes these recoveries don’t always go as planned.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, is the White House thinking at all about timing, given the senator’s potential absence?&nbsp; Is that affecting at all how the President is now thinking about this nomination versus how he would have been thinking about it a week ago?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, so everything is still on track for a pick by the end of February?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know you&#8217;ve been asked before whether the President is considering Republican votes and whether he can get any Republicans on board.&nbsp; Is the response still: “The President is looking for the best candidate and not thinking about which votes that candidate can get”?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, but I would say it’s important to note that the President’s commitment, above all else, is to nominate a qualified woman &#8212; a Black woman &#8212; to serve on the Supreme Court with impeccable credentials.&nbsp; And he thinks anyone he chooses should have the kind of credentials and be as &#8212; and be so qualified that they should be considered by Democrats and Republicans.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just a couple things on COVID: We&#8217;ve hit the 900,000 death mark, or we&#8217;re quickly going to approach it depending on your tally, but is the President going to do anything to mark this &#8212; for the grim milestone of 900,000 deaths?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will have more on this soon, but I don&#8217;t have anything to preview today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Do you have any updates on the testing efforts &#8212; the shipping out of the free COVID tests?&nbsp; How many have there been shipped out now?&nbsp; Do you have an update on that?&nbsp; Are they still being shipped out every 7 to 12 days from the order?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have an update on numbers.&nbsp; It&#8217;s changing constantly.&nbsp; I know we confirmed &#8212; I think it was last Friday, so I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s changed since then &#8212; that we had about 60 million orders.&nbsp; And we had sent out tens of millions of tests.&nbsp; And you’ve certainly seen on social media people receiving their tests, which is always good news.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I don’t have an update on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this program, of course, is just beginning to ramp up.&nbsp; We&#8217;d said at the beginning we wouldn&#8217;t start sending tests until the end of January.&nbsp; We obviously did it ahead of time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what we&#8217;re really relying on right now is as soon as testing manufacturers deliver tests to the U.S. government, we will get them out to the American people.&nbsp; And the Postal Service is doing their job packing and shipping efficiently.&nbsp; And I expect we&#8217;ll have more updates in due time &#8212; a short time, I hope.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a real quick one on Russia.&nbsp; The Senate has left town without passing a sanctions bill.&nbsp; How important does the White House think it is to get the Senate to pass a Russian sanctions bill?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re in close touch with them.&nbsp; But I &#8212; it&#8217;s not essential for us to implement sanctions.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; It&#8217;s not required.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, we have had &#8212; we have prepared a devastating package of sanctions &#8212; economic sanctions that would have an enormous impact on the Russian economy.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t require congressional action, but we are, of course, working closely with them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, we need to gather.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; Sorry for it to be so short today.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll be around for a little bit.&nbsp; If people have questions, come on by.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you say anything about the Russian oil deal with China?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think I have any additional comments about their meeting.&nbsp; I will see if there&#8217;s more we can offer.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to do that for you, Andrea.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would that undermine any potential U.S. sanctions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m happy to get back to you if there’s more we can offer, Andrea.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>12:41 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Use of Project Labor Agreements For Federal Construction&#160;Projects</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/04/executive-order-on-use-of-project-labor-agreements-for-federal-construction-projects/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 20:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46671</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act, 40 U.S.C. 101 et seq., and in order to promote economy and efficiency in the administration and completion of Federal construction projects, it is hereby ordered that:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act, 40 U.S.C. 101 <em>et seq.</em>, and in order to promote economy and efficiency in the administration and completion of Federal construction projects, it is hereby ordered that:</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section 1. &nbsp;Policy.</span> &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Large-scale construction projects pose special challenges to efficient and timely procurement by the Federal Government.&nbsp; Construction employers typically do not have a permanent workforce, which makes it difficult to predict labor costs when bidding on contracts and to ensure a steady supply of labor on contracts being performed.&nbsp; Challenges also arise because construction projects typically involve multiple employers at a single location, and a labor dispute involving one employer can delay the entire project.&nbsp; A lack of coordination among various employers, or uncertainty about the terms and conditions of employment of various groups of workers, can create friction and disputes in the absence of an agreed-upon resolution mechanism. &nbsp;These problems threaten the efficient and timely completion of construction projects undertaken by Federal contractors. &nbsp;On large-scale projects, which are generally more complex and of longer duration, these problems tend to be more pronounced.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Project labor agreements are often effective in preventing these problems from developing because they provide structure and stability to large-scale construction projects.&nbsp; Such agreements avoid labor-related disruptions on projects by using dispute-resolution processes to resolve worksite disputes and by prohibiting work stoppages, including strikes and lockouts.&nbsp; They secure the commitment of all stakeholders on a construction site that the project will proceed efficiently without unnecessary interruptions. &nbsp;They also advance the interests of project owners, contractors, and subcontractors, including small businesses.&nbsp; For these reasons, owners and contractors in both the public and private sector routinely use project labor agreements, thereby reducing uncertainties in large-scale construction projects.&nbsp; The use of project labor agreements is fully consistent with the promotion of small business interests.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;Accordingly, it is the policy of the Federal Government for agencies to use project labor agreements in connection with large-scale construction projects to promote economy and efficiency in Federal procurement.&nbsp;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 2. &nbsp;Definitions.</span> &nbsp;For purposes of this order:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;&#8220;Labor organization&#8221; means a labor organization as defined in 29 U.S.C. 152(5) of which building and construction employees are members, as described in 29 U.S.C. 158(f).<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;&#8220;Construction&#8221; means construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, modernization, alteration, conversion, extension, repair, or improvement of buildings, structures, highways, or other real property.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;&#8220;Large-scale construction project&#8221; means a Federal construction project within the United States for which the total estimated cost of the construction contract to the Federal Government is $35 million or more.&nbsp; The Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council (FAR Council), in consultation with the Council of Economic Advisers, may adjust this threshold based on inflation using the process at 41 U.S.C. 1908.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;&#8220;Agency&#8221; means an executive department or agency, including an independent establishment subject to the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act, 40 U.S.C. 102(4)(A).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;&#8220;Project labor agreement&#8221; means a pre-hire collective bargaining agreement with one or more labor organizations that establishes the terms and conditions of employment for a specific construction project and is an agreement described in 29 U.S.C. 158(f).&nbsp;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 3.&nbsp; Project Labor Agreement Presumption.</span> Subject to sections 5 and 6 of this order,&nbsp;in awarding any contract in connection with a large-scale construction project, or obligating funds pursuant to such a contract, agencies shall require every contractor or subcontractor engaged in construction on the project to agree, for that project, to negotiate or become a party to a project labor agreement with one or more appropriate labor organizations.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 4.&nbsp; Requirements of Project Labor Agreements.</span> Any project labor agreement reached pursuant to this order shall:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;bind all contractors and subcontractors on the construction project through the inclusion of appropriate specifications in all relevant solicitation provisions and contract documents;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;allow all contractors and subcontractors on the construction project to compete for contracts and subcontracts without regard to whether they are otherwise parties to collective bargaining agreements;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;contain guarantees against strikes, lockouts, and similar job disruptions;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;set forth effective, prompt, and mutually binding procedures for resolving labor disputes arising during the term of the project labor agreement;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;provide other mechanisms for labor-management cooperation on matters of mutual interest and concern, including productivity, quality of work, safety, and health; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(f) &nbsp;fully conform to all statutes, regulations, Executive Orders, and Presidential Memoranda.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 5.&nbsp; Exceptions Authorized by Agencies.</span> A senior official within an agency may grant an exception from the requirements of section 3 of this order for a particular contract by, no later than the solicitation date, providing a specific written explanation of why at least one of the following circumstances exists with respect to that contract:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Requiring a project labor agreement on the project would not advance the Federal Government&#8217;s interests in achieving economy and efficiency in Federal procurement.&nbsp;Such a finding shall be based on the following factors:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;The project is of short duration and lacks operational complexity;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;The project will involve only one craft or trade;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) The project will involve specialized construction work that is available from only a limited number of contractors or subcontractors;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;The agency&#8217;s need for the project is of such an unusual and compelling urgency that a project labor agreement would be impracticable; or<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The project implicates other similar factors deemed appropriate in regulations or guidance issued pursuant to section 8 of this order.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Based on an inclusive market analysis, requiring a project labor agreement on the project would substantially reduce the number of potential bidders so as to frustrate full and open competition.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;Requiring a project labor agreement on the project would otherwise be inconsistent with statutes, regulations, Executive Orders, or Presidential Memoranda.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 6.  Reporting.</span> (a)  To the extent permitted by law and consistent with national security and executive branch confidentiality interests, agencies shall publish, on a centralized public website, data showing the use of project labor agreements on large-scale construction projects, as well as descriptions of the exceptions granted under section 5 of this order.<br>     (b)  On a quarterly basis, agencies shall report to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) on their use of project labor agreements on large-scale construction projects and on the exceptions granted under section 5 of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 7.</span> Nothing in this order precludes an agency from requiring the use of a project labor agreement in circumstances not covered by this order, including projects where the total cost to the Federal Government is less than that for a large-scale construction project, or projects receiving any form of Federal financial assistance (including loans, loan guarantees, revolving funds, tax credits, tax credit bonds, and cooperative agreements).  This order also does not require contractors or subcontractors to enter into a project labor agreement with any particular labor organization.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 8.  Regulations and Implementation.</span> (a)  Within 120 days of the date of this order, the FAR Council, to the extent permitted by law, shall propose regulations implementing the provisions of this order.  The FAR Council shall consider and evaluate public comments on the proposed regulations and shall promptly issue a final rule, to the extent permitted by law.<br>     (b)  The Director of OMB shall, to the extent permitted by law, issue guidance to implement the requirements of sections 5 and 6 of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 9.  Contracting Officer Training.</span> Within 90 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Labor, and the Director of OMB shall coordinate in designing a training strategy for agency contracting officers to enable those officers to effectively implement this order. Within 180 days of the date of the publication of proposed regulations, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Labor, and the Director of OMB shall provide a report to the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy and Director of the National Economic Council on the contents of the training strategy.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 10. Revocation of Prior Orders, Rules, and Regulations<em>.</em></span>  Executive Order 13502 of February 6, 2009 (Use of Project Labor Agreements for Federal Construction Projects), is revoked as of the effective date of the final regulations issued by the FAR Council under section 8(a) of this order. Upon Executive Order 13502&#8217;s revocation, the heads of agencies shall consider, to the extent permitted by law, revoking any orders, rules, or regulations implementing Executive Order 13502.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 11.  Severability.</span>  If any provision of this order, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this order and its application to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 12. Effective Date<em>.</em></span><em> </em> This order shall be effective immediately and shall apply to all solicitations for contracts issued on or after the effective date of the final regulations issued by the FAR Council under section 8(a) of this order.  For solicitations issued between the date of this order and the effective date of the final regulations issued by the FAR Council under section 8(a) of this order, or solicitations that have already been issued and are outstanding as of the date of this order, agencies are strongly encouraged, to the extent permitted by law, to comply with this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 13. General Provisions<em>.</em></span>  (a)  Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>          (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>          (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>     (b)  This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>     (c)  This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. &nbsp;<br><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">&nbsp;The White House,</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; February 4, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces 3 Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/04/president-biden-announces-3-key-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46665</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration: Reuben Brigety, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of South Africa MaryKay Carlson, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of the Philippines Elizabeth Shortino, Nominee for United&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Reuben Brigety, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of South Africa</li><li>MaryKay Carlson, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of the Philippines</li><li>Elizabeth Shortino, Nominee for United States Executive Director of the International Monetary Fund</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Reuben Brigety, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of South Africa</u></strong></p>



<p>Reuben Brigety currently serves as an Adjunct Senior Fellow for African Peace and Security at the Council on Foreign Relations, and as a Member of the Board of Counselors of McLarty Associates in Washington, D.C. Brigety previously served as the Vice-Chancellor and President of the University of the South and the Mayor of Sewanee, Tennessee. During the Obama-Biden Administration, Brigety held several roles in the State Department, including Deputy Assistant Secretary for Population, Refugees and Migration, Deputy Assistant Secretary for African Affairs, U.S. Ambassador to the African Union and U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations Economic Commission for Africa. Earlier in his career, Brigety was the Special Assistant to the Assistant Administrator for Democracy, Conflict and Humanitarian Assistance at the U.S. Agency for International Development, and the Dean of the Elliott School of International Affairs at The George Washington University, the largest school of international affairs in the United States. He is a member of the American Academy of Diplomacy.</p>



<p>Brigety earned a B.S. from the U. S. Naval Academy, and an M.Phil in International Affairs, and a Ph.D. in International Affairs from the University of Cambridge in England. He is the author of numerous publications and speaks Spanish, French, and Amharic.</p>



<p><strong><u>MaryKay Carlson, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of the Philippines</u></strong></p>



<p>MaryKay Loss Carlson, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Buenos Aires, Argentina. Previously, she worked as Deputy Chief of Mission in New Delhi, India for three years, including a ten-month stint as Chargé d’Affaires a.i. Prior to that, she held the position of Principal Deputy Executive Secretary on the staff of the Secretary of State in Washington, D.C. A Foreign Service officer since 1985, she has also served at U.S. diplomatic missions in China (twice), Ukraine, Hong Kong, Mozambique, Kenya, and the Dominican Republic. Her domestic assignments include Director of the Secretary’s Executive Secretariat Staff and Deputy Director of Korean Affairs. Carlson has received numerous performance awards, including six Superior Honor Awards.</p>



<p>A native of Little Rock, Arkansas, Carlson has a Bachelor’s Degree from Rhodes College in Memphis, Tennessee, and holds Master’s Degrees from Georgetown University and the National War College. She speaks Spanish and Chinese.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Elizabeth Shortino, Nominee for United States Executive Director of the International Monetary Fund</u></strong></p>



<p>Elizabeth Shortino has more than 17 years of experience in public service, and has held positions at the Office of Management and Budget, the Department of Treasury, and the Office of the U.S. Executive Director at the International Monetary Fund. While at Treasury, Shortino served as Director of the Middle East North Africa Office and Director of the Office of International Monetary Policy. Since February 2021, Shortino has served as the Acting U.S. Executive Director at the International Monetary Fund.</p>



<p>Shortino holds a Bachelor of Arts in Political Science with a minor in Business Administration from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. She also holds a Masters in International Relations from Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies with a specialization in Quantitative Methods and Economic Theory. Prior to joining government, Shortino worked as a management consultant for Cap Gemini Ernst &amp; Young, LLC. Shortino lives in Arlington, Virginia with her husband and three children.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the January Jobs&#160;Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/04/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-january-jobs-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 19:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46675</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 11:50 A.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, folks.  Good morning.  It’s still morning by about 10 minutes.  (Laughter.)  I want to speak to you this morning about the extraordinary resilience and grit of the American people and American capitalism. Our country is taking everything that COVID has to throw at us, and we’ve&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>11:50 A.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, folks.  Good morning.  It’s still morning by about 10 minutes.  (Laughter.)  I want to speak to you this morning about the extraordinary resilience and grit of the American people and American capitalism.</p>



<p>Our country is taking everything that COVID has to throw at us, and we’ve come back stronger.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m pleased to report this morning what many of you already know: that America’s job machine is going stronger than ever, fueling a strong recovery and opportunity for hardworking women and men all across this great country.</p>



<p>America is back to work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today we learned that in January, our economy created 467,000 jobs.&nbsp;&nbsp; But that’s not all.&nbsp; We learned that job growth in November and December over last year was revised up by more than 700,000 jobs.&nbsp; On top of that, 400,000 jobs are previously &#8212; on top of the 400,000 that were previously reported.</p>



<p>This morning’s report caps off my first year as President.&nbsp; And over that period, our economy created 6.6 million jobs &#8212; 6.6 million jobs.</p>



<p>If you can’t remember another year when so many people went to work in this country, there’s a reason: It never happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Take a look at the chart.&nbsp; You can look at the last &#8212; all the way back to President Reagan.&nbsp; Look how many jobs we&#8217;ve created in &#8212; on average per month.&nbsp; This is &#8212; it’s never happened before.&nbsp; And, look, history has been made here.</p>



<p>But it comes alongside the largest drop in unemployment rate in a single year on record, the largest reduction in childhood poverty ever recorded in a single year, and the strongest economic growth this country has seen in nearly 40 years.&nbsp; Historic economic progress.</p>



<p>And I’m proud of the role the administration played in this economic plan and has played in the recovery: you know, the Rescue Plan that Democrats passed to get the economy going again; the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that’s starting to get underway, rebuilding bridges, roads, highways, ports, airports, Internet, and so much more that we’re doing as well; and my decision at the outset of our administration to buy American.&nbsp; It’s always been the law; it was very seldom ever followed.&nbsp; Now it’s a reality, not an empty promise.</p>



<p>I made clear that when the federal government spends taxpayer dollars, we buy American products &#8212; American products made in America, including all the component parts of that product, with very few exceptions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With the support of the American private sector, our business leaders and entrepreneurs, our workers, our union leaders &#8212; they’ve all come together like never before in my days in Washington.</p>



<p>I know it hasn’t been easy.&nbsp; I know that January was a very hard month for many Americans.&nbsp; I know that after almost two years, the physical and emotional weight of the pandemic has been incredibly difficult to bear for so many people.</p>



<p>But here’s the good news: We have the tools to save lives and to keep businesses open and keep schools open, keep workers on the job, and sustain this historic economic comeback.&nbsp; Vaccination and boosters have proven incredibly effective.</p>



<p>This past month, we started mailing out tens of millions of at-home tests to deliver to your home for free so you can determine whether or not you have COVID.&nbsp; And that’s in addition to the 20,000 sites across America where you can get a test in person, for free, to determine whether or not you have COVID.</p>



<p>And we have more treatments today to keep people out of the hospital, including lifesaving antiviral pills, which we purchased millions of.</p>



<p>And now we’re seeing the difference our efforts have made.</p>



<p>Look at what’s happened: Just in the past three weeks, today’s extraordinary job report data was collected; the COVID crisis has been cut in half &#8212; down in half in just three weeks.&nbsp; Still too many cases, still we have to be on the &#8212; on the alert.&nbsp; But to be clear: This is a dramatic decline.</p>



<p>Now, I want to be clear: Even with the extraordinary news, even with historic economic progress we’ve made across the past year, we still have a lot of work to do.&nbsp; Making sure every American has a job is a great start, but it’s not the finish.</p>



<p>For many Americans, wages are up this year.&nbsp; In January, wage increases were strong across the board, and that’s good.&nbsp; We have to continue to keep wages growing.&nbsp; And we need even more high-paying jobs &#8212; jobs you can raise a family on and have some breathing room.</p>



<p>Two weeks ago, the CEO of Intel, Pat Gelsinger, came to the White House to announce a brand new $20 billion semiconductor factory &#8212; they call it a “campus” &#8212; outside of Columbus, Ohio.&nbsp; It’s going to create 7,000 jobs just constructing the facility and 3,000 permanent jobs running the facility, with an average salary of $135,000.</p>



<p>These semiconductors or microchips power virtually everything in our everyday lives, from our cellphones to automobiles to refrigerators, the Internet, the electric grid.&nbsp; Without semiconductors, these things do not function in a modern economy.</p>



<p>So, the spin-off of this is going to create thousands of additional jobs as well, helping us build more American products in manufacturing automobiles, appliances, and so much more.&nbsp; It’s going to create jobs, and it’s going to help ease inflation.</p>



<p>One of the reasons why automobiles cost so much money these days and they’re responsible for one third of all the inflation that’s calculated in a market is because they lack the semiconductors to build the vehicles.</p>



<p>Intel’s announcement helps us fix that problem.</p>



<p>Last week, I called a meeting of CEOs from General Motors, Ford, Microsoft, and other major corporations in America.</p>



<p>Mary Barra of General Motors, the chairman of the board &#8212; the CEO, I should say &#8212; announced a $7 billion investment in a Michigan manufacturing plant to manufacture electric vehicles.&nbsp; It’s going to create 4,000 new, quality jobs at prevailing wage.</p>



<p>That’s on top of the announcement last year made by Ford’s CEO, Jim Farley, who was with us, to invest $11 billion to make electric vehicles, creating 11,000 new good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>Look, last Friday I went to Pittsburgh, where the Pacific &#8212; the Union Pacific Railroad announced the largest purchase of American battery-electric locomotives in history, built in Erie, Pennsylvania &#8212; built by American manufacturing workers in Western Pennsylvania, creating even more good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>And again, the spin-off from that: These locomotives aren’t just going to be purchased in America.  Countries around the world &#8212; because they’re going to be the best product &#8212; are going to purchase them &#8212; American-made electric vehicles made in Erie, Pennsylvania.  Good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>Look, we all know we’re in competition with the world.&nbsp; These announcements are the drumbeat a job &#8212; of a job resurgence unlike anything we’ve seen in our history.</p>



<p>And it didn’t happen by chance.&nbsp; It’s a result of the economic plan I put into action on day one when I said it’s going be “buy America.”&nbsp; I’m delighted to keep it going and expand what we’ve done, because we have a great opportunity ahead of us to further progress &#8212; make progress where &#8212; beyond what we’ve already made.</p>



<p>Look, the House of Representatives just passed, a few minutes ago &#8212; just before I walked over here &#8212; to provide $90 billion &#8212; over $90 billion &#8212; for research and development, manufacturing, and all those elements of the supply chain needed to produce end products right here in America, so we can keep delivering more announcements like the one we’ve had in these past few weeks.</p>



<p>Another way we’re boosting our economy is by promoting competition.</p>



<p>Look, a hamburger is, you know, up four times &#8212; four-fold almost in many places.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; Meat processing, meat processors are &#8212; shipping, railroads, and other industries &#8212; are dominated by a few giant companies that control the market they operate in.</p>



<p>And over the years, this domination in the market by a smaller number of companies &#8212; smaller and smaller &#8212; it&#8217;s about four in the meatpacking area &#8212; has reduced competition; squeezed out small businesses and farmers; and, in many cases, increased prices &#8212; at almost all of them &#8212; increased prices for consumers.</p>



<p>Look, I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; But capitalism without competition is not capitalism; it’s exploitation.&nbsp; So, I’m going to continue to do everything in my power to work with the Congress to make our capitalist system work better, to provide more competition, and lower prices for American consumers.</p>



<p>And they’re still going to do well.&nbsp; But that isn’t going to be enough.&nbsp; We still need to ease the burden on working families by making everyday things more affordable and accessible.</p>



<p>Look, average people are getting clobbered by the cost of everything today.&nbsp; Gas prices at the pump are up.&nbsp; We’re working to bring them down, but they’re up.</p>



<p>Food prices are up.&nbsp; We’re working to bring them down as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I grew up in a family where if the price for a gallon of gas at the pump went up significantly, it was felt by the family.&nbsp; I get it.&nbsp; I understand.&nbsp; But these things are necessities, but that’s not the totality of what the family needs.&nbsp; They still have to pay for childcare.&nbsp; They still have to pay for prescription drugs.&nbsp; They still have to pay for healthcare.</p>



<p>There’s more than one way to help a family when it comes to their standard of living.&nbsp; We’re going to work to bring down the prices that are way up, but guess what?&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; We’re going to keep strengthening the supply chains to bring down the costs of every &#8212; all of these goods.</p>



<p>But in the meantime, there is a lot we can do to give families a little extra breathing room.</p>



<p>For example, childcare.&nbsp; Families can spend $14,000 a year per child, in some cases in this country &#8212; in some cases less than $14,000 a year &#8212; for childcare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our plan cuts in half most &#8212; what most families are paying, helping their budgets; helping &#8212; keeping millions of parents, and especially women, allowed to go back to work because they can get childcare.</p>



<p>Or the cost of prescription drugs, like insulin.&nbsp; Insulin costs about $10 to make.&nbsp; But for families who need the insulin, they’re paying up to $650 a month on average in some places and as high as $1,000 a month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Think about all of those Americans out there with Type 1 diabetes who need this insulin to stay alive and stay healthy, or the 200,000 American children with Type 1 diabetes.</p>



<p>Think about being one of the parents without the insurance or the money to pay for that insulin.&nbsp; How do you look your child in the eye who needs that insulin?&nbsp; They have no idea how they’re going to figure out how to pay for it.</p>



<p>Think about what it does to them &#8212; to their self-esteem, their dignity, their ability to look their child in the eye.</p>



<p>We cap the cost of insulin at $35 on our plan &#8212; $35 a month.&nbsp; The companies are still going to make a healthy profit.&nbsp; We could do that tomorrow with the stroke of a pen.</p>



<p>But we have a generation of &#8212; so-called, for example, “sandwich generation.”&nbsp; That is you have a young child and an elderly parent who need &#8212; both need help.&nbsp; And look, we can help them take care of mom and dad and make it work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There’s a program that allows us to &#8212; on Medicare &#8212; that someone can come and install a handrail in the shower so mom doesn’t fall; to make sure they have what they need to live with safety and dignity in their home, pick up the prescriptions, make an occasional meal.&nbsp; We can do all that.</p>



<p>So when a mom and dad puts their head on the pillow at night, they can have peace of mind that their elderly parents are doing well and their children are okay.</p>



<p>We’re still going to work on gas prices.&nbsp; We’re still going to work on the food prices.&nbsp; But in the meantime, we can deliver that peace of &#8212; we can deliver that peace of mind to the American people and give them a little breathing room.</p>



<p>And, by the way, the proposals that I have out there &#8212; nobody earning less than $400,000 a year would pay a single additional penny in taxes.&nbsp; Not a single penny.&nbsp; And a lot of companies that I’ve spoken to are willing to pay a little more in their corporate taxes and their personal taxes to see that happen.</p>



<p>You’ve heard me say it a hundred times: You got 55 companies of the Fortune 500 companies that paid zero tax in the last couple years, and they made over $400 billion.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, we can do this without increasing the deficit.&nbsp; Actually, we’ve reduced the deficit over $300 billion.</p>



<p>And 17 Nobel laureates in economics came to me several months ago to say that this plan would not only not raise inflation, it would ease long-term inflationary pressures.</p>



<p>Look, the bottom line is this: The United States is once again in a position to not only compete with the rest of the world but outcompete the rest of the world once again.</p>



<p>If we can keep coming together and invest in the backbone of America &#8212; working class and the middle-class folks &#8212; there’s no limit to what we can achieve.</p>



<p>So let’s keep the rais- &#8212; the wages rising, and let’s start lowering costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our businesses are the best in the world.&nbsp; Our workers are the best in the world.&nbsp; Give them half a chance and they’ll outcompete anyone, anywhere in the world.</p>



<p>We can have a quality of life for working people that they deserve at the same time.</p>



<p>And, by the way, the middle class, when it does well; when the working class does well &#8212; everybody does well.&nbsp; Everything is better for the wealthy, the super-wealthy, and the slightly wealthy.&nbsp; Nobody gets hurt.</p>



<p>So let’s face these challenges head on.&nbsp; Let’s keep building a better America.</p>



<p>I want to thank you.&nbsp; And God bless you, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>12:05 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on House Passage of the America COMPETES&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/04/statement-from-president-biden-on-house-passage-of-the-america-competes-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 18:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The House took a critical vote today for stronger supply chains and lower prices, for more manufacturing – and good manufacturing jobs – right here in America, and for outcompeting China and the rest of the world in the 21st century. I applaud Speaker Pelosi, Majority Leader Hoyer, Whip Clyburn, and Chairwoman Eddie Bernice Johnson&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The House took a critical vote today for stronger supply chains and lower prices, for more manufacturing – and good manufacturing jobs – right here in America, and for outcompeting China and the rest of the world in the 21st century. I applaud Speaker Pelosi, Majority Leader Hoyer, Whip Clyburn, and Chairwoman Eddie Bernice Johnson for their leadership in getting this done.</p>



<p>Business and labor alike have praised this legislation as vital for continuing the economic momentum we’ve seen over the last year, and national security leaders from both parties have said that the investments in this bill are needed if we want to maintain our competitive edge globally. This bill was built on numerous bipartisan elements and on shared bipartisan agreement on the need to act. If House Republicans are serious about lowering prices, making our economy stronger, and competing with China from a position of strength, then they should come to the table and support this legislation, which does just that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I look forward to the House and Senate quickly coming together to find a path forward and putting a bill on my desk as soon as possible for my signature. America can’t afford to wait.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation to Continue Facilitating Positive Adjustment to Competition From Imports of Certain Crystalline Silicon Photovoltaic Cells (Whether or Not Partially or Fully Assembled Into Other&#160;Products)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/04/a-proclamation-to-continue-facilitating-positive-adjustment-to-competition-from-imports-of-certain-crystalline-silicon-photovoltaic-cells-whether-or-not-partially-or-fully-assembled-into-other-produc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; 1.&#160; On January 23, 2018, pursuant to section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended (the &#8220;Trade Act&#8221;) (19 U.S.C. 2253), the President issued Proclamation 9693, imposing a safeguard measure for a period of 4 years that included both a tariff-rate quota (TRQ) on imports of certain crystalline silicon photovoltaic (CSPV) cells,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 1.&nbsp; On January 23, 2018, pursuant to section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended (the &#8220;Trade Act&#8221;) (19 U.S.C. 2253), the President issued Proclamation 9693, imposing a safeguard measure for a period of 4 years that included both a tariff-rate quota (TRQ) on imports of certain crystalline silicon photovoltaic (CSPV) cells, not partially or fully assembled into other products, provided for in subheading 8541.40.6025 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTS), and an increase in duties (safeguard tariff) on imports of CSPV cells exceeding the TRQ and all imports of other CSPV products, including modules provided for in subheading 8541.40.6015 of the HTS.&nbsp; Proclamation 9693 exempted imports from certain designated beneficiary countries under the Generalized System of Preferences from the application of the safeguard measure.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2.&nbsp; Clause (4) and Annex I of Proclamation 9693 directed the United States Trade Representative (USTR) to establish procedures for interested persons to request the exclusion of particular products from the safeguard measure.&nbsp; These provisions also authorized the USTR, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy, to determine whether a particular product should be excluded, and, upon publication of a determination in the <em>Federal Register</em>, to modify the HTS to implement such determination.&nbsp; Furthermore, they authorized the USTR to modify or to terminate such determinations.&nbsp; Effective June 13, 2019, the USTR excluded bifacial solar panels that absorb light and generate electricity on each side of the panel and that consist of only bifacial solar cells that absorb light and generate electricity on both sides of the cells (bifacial modules).&nbsp; Exclusion of Particular Products From the Solar Products Safeguard Measure, 84 FR 27684 (June 13, 2019).<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3.&nbsp; On February 7, 2020, the United States International Trade Commission (USITC) issued its report, pursuant to section&nbsp;204(a)(2) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(a)(2)), on the results of its monitoring of developments with respect to the domestic solar industry (USITC, Crystalline Silicon Photovoltaic Cells, Whether or Not Partially or Fully Assembled Into Other Products: &nbsp;Monitoring Developments in the Domestic Industry, No.&nbsp;TA-201-075 (Monitoring)).&nbsp; In its report, the USITC found that, following imposition of the safeguard measure, prices for CSPV&nbsp;cells and modules declined in a manner consistent with historical trends, but that prices were higher than they would have been without the safeguard measure.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 4.&nbsp; On March 6, 2020, the USITC issued an additional report&nbsp;pursuant to a request from the USTR under section&nbsp;204(a)(4) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(a)(4)), regarding the probable economic effect on the domestic CSPV cell and module manufacturing industry of modifying the safeguard measure to increase the level of the TRQ on CSPV cells from the current 2.5 gigawatts (GW) to 4.0, 5.0, or 6.0 GW (USITC, Crystalline Silicon Photovoltaic Cells, Whether or Not Partially or Fully Assembled Into Other Products: &nbsp;Advice on the Probable Economic Effect of Certain Modifications to the Safeguard Measure, No.&nbsp;TA-201-075 (Modification)). &nbsp;In its report, the USITC advised that increasing the TRQ would help to continue growth in solar module production, but that expanded access to imported cells not subject to safeguard duties would put downward pressure on prices for cells made in the United States.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 5.&nbsp; After taking into account the information provided in&nbsp;the USITC&#8217;s reports, and after receiving a petition from a&nbsp;majority of the representatives of the domestic industry with&nbsp;respect to each of the following modifications, and under section 204(b)(1)(B) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(b)(1)(B)), the President issued Proclamation 10101 on October 10, 2020, in which he determined that the domestic industry has begun to make a positive adjustment to import competition, as shown by the increases in domestic module production capacity, production, and market share.&nbsp; Proclamation 10101 also:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; revoked the exclusion of bifacial modules from application of the safeguard measure on the basis that it had impaired and was likely&nbsp;to continue to impair the effectiveness of the safeguard action; and<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b)&nbsp; adjusted the safeguard tariff for the fourth year of the safeguard measure from 15 percent to 18 percent on the basis that the exclusion of bifacial modules from application of the safeguard tariffs had impaired the remedial effectiveness of the 4-year action proclaimed in Proclamation 9693, and to&nbsp;achieve the full remedial effect envisaged in that action.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 6.&nbsp; On November 16, 2021, the United States Court of International Trade held in Solar Energy Industries Association et al. v. United States (SEIA) that the President acted outside of his statutory authority in issuing Proclamation 10101, and enjoined the Government from enforcing that proclamation.&nbsp; This injunction had the effect of reinstating the exclusion of bifacial modules from the safeguard tariffs and lowering the fourth year safeguard tariff to 15 percent.&nbsp; On January 14, 2022, the Government filed a notice of appeal of SEIA to the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7.&nbsp; On December 8, 2021, in response to petitions by representatives of the domestic industry, the USITC issued its determination and report pursuant to section 204(c) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(c)), finding that safeguard action continues to be necessary to prevent or remedy the serious injury to the domestic industry, and that there is evidence that the domestic industry is making a positive adjustment to import competition (USITC, Crystalline Silicon Photovoltaic Cells, Whether or Not Partially or Fully Assembled Into Other Products, Investigation No. TA-201-75 (Extension)).<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 8.&nbsp; Section 203(e)(1)(B) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2253(e)(1)(B)) authorizes the President, after receiving an affirmative determination from the USITC pursuant to section&nbsp;204(c) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(c)), to extend the effective period of any action taken under section 203 of the Trade Act if the President determines that the action continues to be necessary to prevent or remedy the serious injury, and there is evidence that the domestic industry is making a positive adjustment to import competition.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 9.&nbsp; After taking into account the information provided in&nbsp;the USITC&#8217;s report and the information received from the public through the process published in the <em>Federal Register&nbsp;</em>on&nbsp;September 30, 2021 (86 FR 54279), pursuant to section 203(e)(1)(B) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2253(e)(1)(B)), I have determined that the safeguard action on imports of CSPV cells, whether or not partially or fully assembled into other products, continues to be necessary to prevent or remedy the serious injury to the domestic industry, and that there is evidence that the domestic industry is making a positive adjustment to import competition.&nbsp; I have further determined to extend the safeguard measure proclaimed in Proclamation 9693, as modified by Proclamation 10101 (to the extent permitted by law), as follows:<br>(a)&nbsp; continuation of the TRQ on imports of solar cells not partially or fully assembled into other products described in paragraph 1 of this proclamation for an additional period of 4&nbsp;years, with unchanging within-quota quantities of 5.0 GW for each year and annual reductions in the rates of duty applicable to goods entered in excess of those quantities of cells in the fifth, sixth, seventh, and eighth years, as described in Annex I to this proclamation;<br>(b)&nbsp; continuation of the increase in duties on imports of modules described in paragraph 1 of this proclamation for an additional period of 4 years, with annual reductions in the fifth, sixth, seventh, and eighth years, as described in Annex I to this proclamation; and<br>(c)&nbsp; exclusion of bifacial panels from the extension of duties proclaimed in this paragraph.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 10.&nbsp; I have determined that an extension of this safeguard measure will provide greater economic and social benefits than costs.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 11.&nbsp; As provided in Proclamation 9693, this safeguard measure shall continue to apply to imports from all countries, except as provided in clause (4) of this proclamation and paragraph 10 of Proclamation 9693.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 12.&nbsp; Section 204(a)(2) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(a)(2)) requires the USITC to issue a report on its monitoring of developments with respect to the domestic industry, including the progress and specific efforts made by workers and firms in the domestic industry to make a positive adjustment to import competition, no later than the midpoint of the period of the extension.&nbsp; After I receive that report, I will evaluate whether to reduce, modify, or terminate the safeguard measure pursuant to section 204(b)(1) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(b)(1)).<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 13.&nbsp; As proclaimed in Proclamation 9693, the in-quota quantity in each year of the TRQ described in paragraph 9 of this proclamation shall be allocated among all countries except those countries the products of which are excluded from such TRQ pursuant to clause (4) of this proclamation or paragraph 10 of Proclamation 9693.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 14.&nbsp; In order to address certain technical errors in the HTS, the HTS is modified as set forth in Annex II to this proclamation.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 15.&nbsp; Section 604 of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2483) authorizes the President to embody in the HTS the substance of the relevant provisions of that Act, and of other acts affecting import treatment, and actions thereunder, including the removal, modification, continuance, or imposition of any rate of duty or other import restriction.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including sections 203, 204, and 604 of the&nbsp;Trade Act, do proclaim that:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (1)&nbsp; In order to extend the measure applicable to imports of CSPV cells, not partially or fully assembled into other products, described in paragraph 1 of this proclamation, subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTS is modified as set forth in Annex I to this proclamation, subject to clauses (3) and (4) below.&nbsp; Any merchandise subject to the safeguard measure that is admitted into United States foreign trade zones on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern standard time on February 7, 2022, must be admitted as &#8220;privileged foreign status&#8221; as defined in 19 CFR 146.41, and will be subject upon entry for consumption to any tariffs or quantitative restrictions related to the classification under the applicable HTS subheading.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (2)&nbsp; Except as provided in clause (3) below, imports of CSPV products of World Trade Organization Member countries, as listed in subdivision (b) of Note 18 to subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTS (Note 18), shall continue to be excluded from the safeguard measure extended by this proclamation, and such imports shall not be counted toward the TRQ limits that trigger the over-quota rates of duties.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (3)&nbsp; If, after the extension proclaimed herein is in effect, the USTR determines that:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; the share of total imports of a country listed in subdivision (b) of Note 18 exceeds 3 percent;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b)&nbsp; imports of the product from all listed countries with less than 3 percent import share collectively account for more than 9 percent of total imports of the product; or<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (c)&nbsp; a country listed in subdivision (b) of Note 18 is no longer a developing country for purposes of this proclamation;<br>the USTR is authorized, upon publication of a notice in the <em>Federal Register</em>, to revise subdivision (b) of Note 18 to remove the relevant country from the list or suspend operation of that subdivision, as appropriate.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (4)&nbsp; I instruct the USTR to enter into negotiations pursuant to section 203(f) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2253(f)) with Canada and Mexico.&nbsp; In the event that the USTR concludes an agreement that the USTR, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy, determines will ensure that imports of Canada or Mexico do not undermine the effectiveness of the action extended through clause (1) of this proclamation, the USTR is authorized, upon publication of a notice in the <em>Federal Register</em>, to revise Note 18 to suspend application of that subdivision, in whole or in part, as appropriate, with respect to imports of Canada or Mexico.&nbsp; If the USTR subsequently determines, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy, that such an agreement is not effective, the USTR is authorized, pursuant to section 203(f) of the Trade Act, by publication of a notice in the <em>Federal Register</em>, to revise Note 18 to terminate any previous suspension of the action with respect to imports of Canada or Mexico.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (5)&nbsp; One year after the termination of the safeguard measure established in this proclamation, the U.S. note and tariff provisions established in Annex I to this proclamation shall be deleted from the HTS.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (6)&nbsp; Any provision of previous proclamations and Executive Orders that is inconsistent with the actions taken in this proclamation is superseded to the extent of such inconsistency.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this<br>fourth day of February, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Signs Executive Order to Boost Quality of Federal Construction&#160;Projects</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/03/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-to-boost-quality-of-federal-construction-projects/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration will make federal procurement more economical and efficient by improving coordination and minimizing disruptions on large federal construction projects Tomorrow, the President will sign an Executive Order to improve timeliness, lower costs and increase quality in federal construction projects. Federal construction projects span the country – from the maintenance of nuclear sites to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration will make federal procurement more economical and efficient by improving coordination and minimizing disruptions on large federal construction projects</em></p>



<p>Tomorrow, the President will sign an Executive Order to improve timeliness, lower costs and increase quality in federal construction projects. Federal construction projects span the country – from the maintenance of nuclear sites to base construction to waterways and flood projects. By requiring the use of project labor agreements (PLAs) on federal construction projects above $35 million, the Order will help alleviate the management and coordination challenges that can stymie progress on major construction projects. This helps projects get completed on time and helps the government get the best value for taxpayers’ dollars.</p>



<p>Based on FY2021 figures, this Order could affect $262 billion in federal government construction contracting and improve job quality for the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-24/pdf/2021-25317.pdf">nearly 200,000 workers</a> on federal construction contracts. Additionally, the President’s Executive Order directs the departments of Defense and Labor, along with the Office of Management Budget, to lead a training strategy for the nearly 40,000-person strong contracting workforce on the implementation of this Order’s policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This Executive Order is just one of many steps the Biden-Harris Administration is taking that will improve the efficiency of federal procurement. Since taking office, the President fulfilled his commitments to strengthen Buy American rules, and secured a reliable supply of experienced, quality workers for federal service contracts. As of January 30<sup>th</sup>, federal contractors in new or extended contracts must pay a $15/hour minimum wage, as the President directed in Executive Order 14026.</p>



<p>This new Executive Order, while only applicable to federal procurement, advances the Administration’s commitment to rebuild the nation’s infrastructure, on-time and at reasonable cost. The Order will only apply to provisions in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that are direct federal procurement, which excludes construction projects financed through grant dollars to non-federal entities. The Executive Order will benefit taxpayers, contractors, and workers by:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Alleviating the coordination challenges on large, complex projects. </strong>Multi-million-dollar projects can present real management challenges to the primary contractor on the project, which has to work with multiple businesses and multiple types of skilled labor to complete a project. PLAs can help coordinate diverse contractors and sub-contractors and their employees working on a project and prevent disputes between subcontractors. Additionally, workers will have more confidence in the management of the project and a greater commitment to completing the project if they have a voice at the table. This helps projects get completed on time by minimizing work disruptions. On-time projects save the government, and taxpayers, money.<br></li><li><strong>Raising quality standards for contractors bidding on federal projects. </strong>PLAs help raise the standards of all bidders on federal contracts. Contractors who offer lower wages or do not train their workers will need to raise their standards to compete with other high-wage, high-quality companies. Businesses with well-trained workers will be more likely to bid for and win federal contracts. Well-trained, high quality workers are more productive, completing projects well and on time.<br></li><li><strong>Reducing uncertainty in the contracting process. </strong>PLAs standardize the work rules, compensation costs, and dispute settlement processes on construction projects. This standardization helps create more certainty for the government and, therefore, taxpayers, about the costs and completion rate for projects.<br></li><li><strong>Increasing training for the federal contracting workforce. </strong>The Executive Order directs the Departments of Defense and Labor, along with the Office of Management and Budget, to lead a training strategy for the contracting workforce on Project Labor Agreements and the implementation of this Order. This training will create a more uniform and accessible experience for contractors interacting with departments and agencies across the federal government.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
