<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 22:29:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House and President of the Senate providing notice of the President’s intent to rescind the designation of Afghanistan as a Major Non-NATO&#160;Ally</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-and-president-of-the-senate-providing-notice-of-the-presidents-intent-to-rescind-the-designation-of-afghanistan-as-a-major-non-nato-ally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 22:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) In accordance with section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k), I am providing notice of my intent to rescind the designation of Afghanistan as a Major Non‑NATO Ally. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Sincerely, &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>In accordance with section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k), I am providing notice of my intent to rescind the designation of Afghanistan as a Major Non‑NATO Ally.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Fifteenth Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/president-biden-announces-fifteenth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 21:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56895</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 3.1 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula on July 17 and 22 Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Kendamil baby formula from England to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 3.1 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula on July 17 and 22</em></p>



<p><br>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Kendamil baby formula from England to New York, NY via flights on July 17 and 22 respectively. These two deliveries will include in total approximately 200,000 pounds of Kendamil EU Classic First Infant Milk Stage 1 and Kendamil EU Organic First Infant Milk Stage 1, the equivalent of approximately 3.1 million 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available at Target stores. Parents and Pediatricians can learn more about Kendamil infant formula at <a href="https://us.kendamil.com">https://us.kendamil.com</a>  and compare its nutritional content per 100kcal with other leading formula brands at <a href="https://us.kendamil.com/pages/compare-kendamil">https://us.kendamil.com/pages/compare-kendamil</a>.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Kendamil can export additional infant formula into the U.S., including&nbsp;Kendamil EU Classic First Infant Milk Stage 1 and Kendamil EU Organic First Infant Milk Stage 1. Kendamil plans to export approximately 58 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market over the next 6 months.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. By July 10, Operation Fly Formula will have transported more than 43 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents to the U.S.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img width="483" height="483" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-56896" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg 483w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=600,600 600w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=1200,1200 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 483px) 100vw, 483px" /></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kate Bedingfield to Depart the White&#160;House after Over 3 Years Leading the President’s Communications&#160;Operation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/kate-bedingfield-to-depart-the-white-house-after-over-3-years-leading-the-presidents-communications-operation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 20:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56889</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kate Bedingfield, a longtime trusted aide to President Biden and a senior strategist both in the administration and on his winning campaign, will leave the White House in late July to spend more time with her husband and young children after more than 3 straight years of leading his communications team. She first worked for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Kate Bedingfield, a longtime trusted aide to President Biden and a senior strategist both in the administration and on his winning campaign, will leave the White House in late July to spend more time with her husband and young children after more than 3 straight years of leading his communications team. She first worked for the President as his communications director during his time as Vice President.<br><br>Bedingfield previously served as the Deputy Campaign Manager and Communications Director on the President’s 2020 presidential campaign, playing a leading role advising him on messaging, building his communications and press operations, preparing him for debates and interviews, and devising and executing on strategy as he secured the Democratic nomination faster than any candidate since 2004 and became the first nominee to defeat an incumbent president in almost 30 years. She also represented the campaign on television at key moments, including before and after debates.<br><br>In the White House, Bedingfield continued as the President’s top communications aide and was similarly integral to every major public relations effort while leading the White House Communications Department, ensuring that each part of the team was working to deliver the President’s message and advocate for his agenda.<br><br>“Without Kate Bedingfield’s talent and tenacity, Donald Trump might still be in the White House, the Rescue Plan and the Infrastructure Law might still be unrealized goals, and Ketanji Brown Jackson might not be sitting on the Supreme Court,” <strong>said White House Chief of Staff Ron Klain.</strong> “She has played a huge role in everything the President has achieved – from his second term as Vice President, through the campaign, and since coming to the White House.  Her strategic acumen, intense devotion to the President’s agenda, and fierce work on his behalf are unmatched.  She will continue to remain a critical player in moving the Biden agenda forward from the outside.”<br><br>“From long before we launched the campaign, Kate Bedingfield was a fierce defender of the President and ensured that our message in 2020 and in the White House was consistent with his voice and principles,” <strong>said White House Senior Adviser Anita Dunn.</strong> “Her leadership helped us tell the story about the fight Joe Biden is making for the working families of America.  She’ll always be a core member of this family, even as she takes a little time to put her own family first.  We will miss her intelligence, her talent, her sense of humor, and her commitment to the values President Biden fought for as a candidate and fights for every day as president.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Fourteenth Operation Fly Formula Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/president-biden-announces-fourteenth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 20:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 4.7 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Bubs Australia infant formula on July 10 and 21 Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Bubs Australia infant formula from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 4.7 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Bubs Australia infant formula on July 10 and 21</em><br><br>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport <em>Bubs</em> Australia infant formula from Australia to Ontario, California and Columbus, Ohio via flights on July 10 and 21 respectively. These two deliveries will include in total approximately 318,000 pounds of Bubs Organic Infant Formula S1, Bubs Organic Follow On Formula S2, Bubs Supreme Infant Formula Supreme Follow On Formula, Bubs Goat Milk Infant Formula S1, Bubs Goat Milk Follow On Formula S2, the equivalent of approximately 4.7 million 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available through national and regional retailers.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Bubs Australia can export additional infant formula into the U.S.&nbsp;Bubs Australia will import both standard and specialty infant formulas to the U.S. including&nbsp;Bubs Organic Grass Fed, Bubs Supreme A2 Beta-Casein Protein and Bubs Easy-digest Goat Milk. Bubs plans to export over 27.5 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. <em>By July 10, Operation Fly Formula will have transported more than 43 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents to the U.S.</em></p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre En Route Cleveland,&#160;OH</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/06/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-en-route-cleveland-oh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 20:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Cleveland, Ohio 1:23 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  Hey, everybody.  Okay, so today, the President is traveling to Max South [S.] Hayes High School in Cleveland, Ohio, to announce new protections for millions of workers in multiemployer pension plans thanks to the American Rescue Plan. Up to 3 million&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Cleveland, Ohio</p>



<p>1:23 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  Hey, everybody.  Okay, so today, the President is traveling to Max <s>South</s> [S.] Hayes High School in Cleveland, Ohio, to announce new protections for millions of workers in multiemployer pension plans thanks to the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>Up to 3 million Americans face significant cuts to their retirement benefits because their investments struggled during economic crisis just during the pandemic or more.  But tha- &#8212; but thanks to the ARP, over 200 multiemployer pension plans will receive special financial assistance and remain solvent through at least 2051 or longer.</p>



<p>The President is strengthening families’ retirement savings while Republican members of Congress, led by Senator Rick Scott, want to threaten it by putting Social Security on the chopping blocks every five years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the President will be joined today by Secretary of Labor Marty Walsh, Senator Sherrod Brown, ARP Coordinator Gene Sperling, and Cleveland Mayor Justin Bibb, as well as Representative Shontel Brown and Representative Marcy Kaptur.</p>



<p><a>And worth noting, as we are in route to <s>Chicago </s>[Cleveland], there is currently a bipartisan bill in Congress that would supercharge private sector investment in semiconductor manufacturing here at home.&nbsp; </a>The Bipartisan Innovation Act is good for workers, good for business, and good for communities.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s supported by mayors, governors, CEOs, manufacturers, and unions across the country, including the Republican Governor of Ohio, Mike DeWine.</p>



<p>Intel announced that it will invest $20 billion to open semiconductor factories in Ohio, and that could expand to as much as $100 billion if the Bipartisan Innovation Act is passed.</p>



<p>Senator Cornyn is joining Minority Leader McConnell in holding a bipartisan bill hostage that would make more in America in order to protect pharmaceutical companies’ profits.</p>



<p>But we believe we need to do both: increase American manufacturing and strengthen competitive edge against China and lower prescription drug costs.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we need Congress to pass BIA this summer.</p>



<p>And with that, Aamer.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; Has the President had a chance to reach out to the family of the Al Jazeera journalist since the State Department report?&nbsp; Or does he have plans to?</p>



<p>And just secondly, how big of an issue is he going to press this with the Israelis next week on holding someone accountable?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of a trip or ahead of conversations for a trip that hasn’t yet happened.&nbsp; So I won’t get ahead of that.&nbsp; But we have made very clear that we will continue to work both with Israel and Palestinian Authority to encourage them to bridge this investigation, because we do not want to &#8212; we want to see accountability, which is incredibly important for &#8212; not just for having accountability broadly, but also for the family as well.</p>



<p>So, to your first question, Aamer, I can say that senior American officials at the State Department have been in close touch with Abu Akleh’s fami- &#8212; her family and continue to be.</p>



<p>We again express our deepest condolences to the Abu Akleh family and remain engaged with Israel and, again, the Palestinian Authority on next steps.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one quick other one.&nbsp; Both Governor Pritzker, on guns in the aftermath of the July 4th shooting, and Gavin Newsom, since Dobbs decision, have become arguably more &#8212; the most outspoken voices of the Democratic Party on both of these very fragile issues in the country.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sort of wondering: Is there any concern that the President&#8217;s leadership is being overshadowed at this moment when the &#8212; a big part of the American public, including Democrats, that voted for him?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What was the first part of the question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, that both Pritzker and Newsom have sort of emerged on guns and on Dobbs, with &#8212; in Newsom’s case &#8212; as the loudest and, you know, most potent voices of the Democratic Party at this point.&nbsp; Where&#8217;s the President?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The President has been also very loud and also very focused on those two issues.&nbsp; When it comes to gun reform, the President led on that.&nbsp; One of the reasons that he was able to sign a bipartisan gun reform bill right before he left for G7 and NATO was because of his leadership, was because of him being very committed and being very consistent for more than a year, at least as President, talking about what we needed to do in light of this gun violence epidemic that we are currently in.</p>



<p>And let&#8217;s not forget this President has had the most executive actions on gun reform than any other President at this time.&nbsp; And he not only has led as President this past a year and a half, but also as Vice President and as senator &#8212; the very, very first, I would say &#8212; argue &#8212; the gun reform that we saw, or the last gun reform that we saw was 30 years ago, which this President led, which was on banning assault weapons.&nbsp; And so, you know, 30 years later, he was able to sign a gun reform &#8212; a bipartisan gun reform legislation that is now law.</p>



<p>Now, with all of that said, the President believes there is more work to be done.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to call on more to be done on dealing with this gun violence epidemic.&nbsp; And that does not stop here.&nbsp; And he welcomes &#8212; he welcomes other voices in the Democratic Party, and he welcomes other voices in the Republican Party as well to join him in really dealing with an issue that&#8217;s tearing up communities and families.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, is the White House tracking the drama in Boris Johnson&#8217;s government right now?&nbsp; And are you concerned at all about instability in the British government at a time when you&#8217;re working together on Ukraine and other international issues?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said this before when I&#8217;ve been asked questions about other governments’ elections &#8212; we&#8217;re just not going to comment on another government &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This isn&#8217;t an election though.&nbsp; I’m not talking about an election.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well &#8212; nope, you&#8217;re right, this is not an election.&nbsp; But to be clear, we&#8217;re just not going to comment on another government’s democratic process.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re just not going to comment.</p>



<p>Look, our alliance, our partnership with the United Kingdom continues to be strong.&nbsp; And so &#8212; but we&#8217;re not going to comment on their &#8212; kind of their political process</p>



<p>in their own country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow up on guns, does the President or the White House see this latest shooting in Highland Park as another perhaps opportunity to come out and try again to stop or to ban assault weapons?&nbsp; We haven’t heard the President talk about that since this latest shooting.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I mean, the President first wanted to make sure that the first responders had the space to do what they needed to do, which they have.&nbsp; And he has spoken to that.&nbsp; He wanted to also make sure that &#8212; you know, families and friends are mourning right now, which is incredibly important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We saw the Vice President in Chicago yesterday.&nbsp; She went to speak at NEA, and she stopped &#8212; she did a &#8212; she did a stop-by to thank the police officers, the first responders, and the work that they have done.&nbsp; So she did that representing, clearly, the administration and the President, which is incredibly important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, the President is going to continue to speak about this.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to speak about what we &#8212; what else we can do to really deal with gun reform in a real way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He is &#8212; indeed, you know, welcomes and thankful for this bipartisan bill that is now law that he signed right before &#8212; like I said, right before he left for Europe.&nbsp; But the work doesn&#8217;t stop there, and he&#8217;ll continue to speak to that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, on Ohio: You know, Tim Ryan, the Senate candidate, is not joining the President today and neither is the Democratic gubernatorial nominee, Nan Whaley.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know you listed some people who are, but those are the main statewide candidates.&nbsp; And what does that say about the President&#8217;s clout in Ohio that they&#8217;re &#8212; they&#8217;re not joining him today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I’ll say this: We&#8217;re in close contact with Congressman Tim Ryan in particular and work with him, and also &#8212; also Nan Whaley.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve worked &#8212; we&#8217;ve worked closely with him on &#8212; just as it relates to Tim Ryan &#8212; on ver- &#8212; on a variety of issues.&nbsp; And he released a statement in strong support of the actions we&#8217;re taking through the American Rescue Plan to protect American retirees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And though he can&#8217;t be there with us today, one of the things that the President looks forward to is to talk about building an economy around the power and possibilities of working families and providing financial relief to millions of workers in Ohio and the rest of the country.</p>



<p>I just listed out a long list of other elected officials who will be with him on this trip.&nbsp; And so, I think that counts for something as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, again, Tim Ryan put out &#8212; put out a statement supporting &#8212; supporting his trip, and we&#8217;re in constant communication with (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; His (inaudible) rating in Ohio is &#8212; it&#8217;s pretty low.&nbsp; The state has been moving to the right in recent elections.&nbsp; There are other states that he won that he&#8217;s, I think, spent less time in.&nbsp; This is his sixth visit to Ohio.&nbsp; Why has he been spending so much time in Ohio?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, the President has said this himself many times.&nbsp; He’s the President for, you know, red states, blue states &#8212; for all Americans.&nbsp; And if there is something that he can speak to that’s going to help Americans and American families wherever he goes, he&#8217;s going to do that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, this pension announcement that we&#8217;re making via the American Rescue Plan is going to help &#8212; help families tremendously.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll hear directly from him, and he&#8217;ll &#8212; from the President in &#8212; you know, in a short few hours.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll lay out exactly what this &#8212; what this pension component of the American Rescue Plan is going to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, he will go &#8212; he will go wherever he needs to go to talk directly to the American people.&nbsp; And you guys have seen him.&nbsp; You guys have seen him deal with, you know, everyday Americans whenever he travels, and he connects, and &#8212; and I think it makes a difference for them to hear from &#8212; from their President directly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned the semiconductor legislation.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you can give us an update on the White House&#8217;s efforts to get that passed, given McConnell&#8217;s threat to pull Republican support for it last week.&nbsp; And are you prepared to roll that into a reconciliation package if he does follow through with that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on the &#8212; on USICA &#8212; this has many names &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; the COMPETES bill, CHIPS.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the &#8212; but the Bipartisan Innovative Act, one thing that we do know is that it would lower the costs of countless products, including cars, and end our reliance on imports, which is really important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the question is &#8212; and as you&#8217;ve heard me &#8212; and you heard me say earlier &#8212; is: Does Senator Mitch McConnell really want to hold hostage a bipartisan package that would strengthen the American competitiveness versus China and yield hundreds of thousands of manufacturing jobs, in particular in Ohio, as we&#8217;re headed there today, and Indiana, Idaho, and other states around the country?</p>



<p>So, we know that this is going to make a difference for the American public.&nbsp; And so, this is something that&#8217;s important.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to work with Congress on this.</p>



<p>To your question about reconciliation: I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here.&nbsp; That is another piece of legislation that we&#8217;ve been working very hard on that we know will also bring down inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So two pieces of legislation that we&#8217;re just going to continue to work hard on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you preview a little bit of what&#8217;s in the President&#8217;s letter to Brittney Griner?&nbsp; And does the public support coming out right now help or hurt the ability of the U.S. government to get her out of Russia?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let me just start with the first &#8212; the first part of your question, which is &#8212; and lay this down a little bit about what happened today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So President Biden spoke with Brittney &#8212; Brittney’s wife, Cherelle, today to make sure she knows we are doing everything we can to get Brittney home as quickly as possible.&nbsp; President Biden shared the letter with her &#8212; with her that he is sending back to Brittney after receiving her deeply personal letter on July 4th, which all of you read.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has been clear about the need to see every American who is wrongfully detained or held hostage abroad released, including Brittney Griner.&nbsp; Months ago, he directed his national security team to pursue every avenue to bring her home safely to her family, friends, and loved ones.&nbsp; This has been top of mind for the President.&nbsp; He receives daily updates about the status of her &#8212; of her negotiations to secure Brittney&#8217;s release, and the U.S. government continues to work aggressively using every available means to bring her home, along with other wrongfully detained Americans like Paul Whelan.</p>



<p>And so, this is, again, a top priority for this President. And like I &#8212; like I just read, he gets daily updates on what is happening, how we&#8217;re going to secure her ho- &#8212; her efforts to come home and also Paul Whelan.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there&#8217;s been some reports in Russian media about a trade maybe for Viktor Bout and Gri- &#8212; Brittney Griner.&nbsp; Is that something the U.S. government would consider?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m not going to negotiate in public on this.&nbsp; This is something, clearly, that the State Department, with the Special Envoy, they are focused on getting home &#8212; not just Brittney Griner and Paul Whelan, but all U.S. nationals who are wrongfully detained abroad or held hostage abroad home.</p>



<p>This is a priority for this President.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to negotiate in public on this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The &#8212; how does the White House justify &#8212; you&#8217;ve talked about abortion quite a bit.&nbsp; How does the White House justify the anti-abortion judge in Kentucky &#8212; nominating &#8212; attempting to nominate him even after the leaked document &#8212; leaked ruling on the &#8212; from the Supreme Court?&nbsp; You guys had that May 4th.&nbsp; We reported on that.&nbsp; And then weeks later, you still were thinking about putting an anti-abortion judge to a lifetime appointment.&nbsp; How do you &#8212; how does the White House justify that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, again &#8212; and I &#8212; I know I was asked this question yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Air Force One experiences turbulence.)&nbsp; Hold on, everybody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just not &#8212; we just don’t comment on &#8212; on vacancies, whether executive branch or judicial, in situations where we have not made a nomination.&nbsp; We just have not made a nomination on this yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do want to add and reiterate that the President is proud that we&#8217;ve confirmed more federal judges than tha- &#8212; during &#8212; than during any of the pa- &#8212; the last three presidents &#8212; presidencies at the equivalent time in their administrations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That includes so many history-making firsts to help our judiciary &#8212; judiciary represent the diversity of America, including groundbreaking new Supreme Court justice.&nbsp; And that is something that we&#8217;re going to continue to do, and we won&#8217;t stop there.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Ukraine, Russia just captured its first full Ukrainian territory since Crimea in 2014.&nbsp; Is the United States and its allies going to push an enhanced response to the capture of Luhansk?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; An “enhanced response,” meaning &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Whatever you guys &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; whatever you guys be &#8212; would be willing to do in seeing Russia take over this &#8212; the largest territory since Crimea.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so, you know, I was asked this question yesterday.&nbsp; And basically, you know, we have said for months that the fighting in the Donbas could be prolonged or protracted with gains and losses on both sides &#8212; you know, especially what we&#8217;re seeing today, as you just laid out, Eugene.</p>



<p>But that &#8212; that doesn&#8217;t mean that the Russians have been able to achieve their objectives here.&nbsp; And so &#8212; and the Ukrainians haven&#8217;t given up, right?&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to continue to fight for their democracy.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to continue to fight for their freedom.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to support them as we have been these past several months.&nbsp; We have given them the most amount of security assistance than any other country.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to make sure that they&#8217;re able to &#8212; you know, to fight for that democracy and their &#8212; and their sovereignty.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last question: You mentioned the support that the United States has given Ukraine and continues to give to Ukraine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Ukrainian government says it&#8217;s going to cost upwards of $700 billion to kind of rebuild.&nbsp; Is the United States pledging to help lead that effort and give those &#8212; you know, a portion of that money, a lot of that &#8212; those billions of dollars to the government of Ukraine to help rebuild?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say this: As the President said last week when he was in Europe, we will support Ukraine as it defends itself from Russia&#8217;s unprovoked attack for as long as it takes.&nbsp; The United States has been the world&#8217;s largest donor, as I just mentioned, of security, economic, and humanitarian assistance for Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will continue to coordinate with international partners on our support for Ukraine as they begin planning for how they will recover and rebuild after the war. &nbsp;And so, we&#8217;re going to just continue our support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  We&#8217;ll see you on the ground. </p>



<p>1:41 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56874</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&#160; Phillip (Phil) A. Washington, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration Henry V. Jardine, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mauritius and the Republic of Seychelles Diane Kaplan,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Phillip (Phil) A. Washington, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration</li><li>Henry V. Jardine, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mauritius and the Republic of Seychelles</li><li>Diane Kaplan, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors for the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</li><li>Jeffrey R. Gural, Nominee for Chair of the Public Buildings Reform Board</li></ul>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Phillip (Phil) A. Washington, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration</span></strong><br><br>Phillip A. Washington was nominated by Denver Mayor Michael B. Hancock and unanimously confirmed by the Denver City Council as Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of Denver International Airport. Prior to this, Washington was the CEO of the Los Angeles County Metropolitan Transportation Authority (Metro). At Metro, Washington managed a budget of more than $8 billion and oversaw 11,000 employees that transported 1.2 million boarding passengers daily on a fleet of 2,200 clean-air buses and six rail lines. Washington also previously served as the CEO of Denver Regional Transportation District (RTD) and worked as the Assistant General Manager of RTD for nearly 10 years before being named CEO.<br><br>Originally from the South Side of Chicago, Washington is a 24-year veteran of the U.S. Army, where he held the rank of Command Sergeant Major. He retired from active duty, is a disabled veteran and was awarded the prestigious Defense Superior Service Medal for exceptional service to his country. He holds a B.A. in Business from Columbia College, and an M.A. in Management from Webster University.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Henry V. Jardine, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mauritius and the Republic of Seychelles</span></strong><br><br>Henry V. Jardine is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor. He currently serves as the Director of the State Department’s Office for Career Development and Assignments in Washington, D.C. Previously, Jardine was the Principal Deputy Director of the Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations for the State Department and, prior to that, the Executive Director of the Bureau for Western Hemisphere Affairs. He also held leadership positions overseas as Management Counselor of the U.S. Embassy in Bangkok, Thailand, as Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Tirana, Albania, and as Consul General of the U.S. Consulate General in Kolkata, India. Jardine also served at the U.S. Consulate General in Chiang Mai, Thailand, the U.S. Embassy in Bridgetown, Barbados and the U.S. Embassy, in Dhaka, Bangladesh. Prior to joining the State Department, Jardine served in the U.S. Army from 1989 – 1993. Jardine earned a B.S. Degree from the Georgetown University School of Foreign Service and an M.S. Degree from the National Defense University. His foreign languages include Bengali, Thai, Spanish, German, and Albanian.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Diane Kaplan, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors for the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</span></strong><br><br>Diane Kaplan is President and Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of the Rasmuson Foundation, based in Anchorage, Alaska. As President and CEO, Kaplan’s approach to philanthropy raised the bar for funder partnership with business, government, and other nonprofits. Before joining the Foundation, Kaplan provided consulting services for philanthropic organizations, Native corporations and tribes, and nonprofit organizations. Prior to that, she served as Chief Executive Officer of Alaska’s 28-station public radio network. She serves on the board of United States Artists, and is a member of the Anchorage Homelessness Leadership Council, Anchorage Rotary Club, the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco community advisory council, and Recover Alaska’s governance council. In 2019, Kaplan received the Anchorage ATHENA Society’s Leadership Award, the group’s highest honor. Kaplan earned a degree in Communications and Women’s Studies from the University of Pennsylvania, graduating summa cum laude.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Jeffrey R. Gural, Nominee for Chair of the Public Buildings Reform Board</span></strong><br><br>Jeffrey Gural is currently Chairman of GFP Real Estate LLC. Prior to his current role, Gural served in numerous roles at Newmark Knight Frank including as Chairman until 2017, after which he became Chairman Emeritus. Prior to that, he was a member of the staff of Diesel Construction Co., where he was responsible for the supervision and construction of more than one million square feet of new office space. Gural is a member of the Executive Committee of The Real Estate Board of New York, former Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Times Square Alliance, and member of the Board of Trustees of The New School. Gural was also Vice President of The Broadway Association, member of the Board of Directors of the Statue of Liberty Foundation, and President of The Realty Foundation of New York. Gural is a graduate of Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute with a degree in Civil Engineering. He is married, has three grown children, five grandchildren and resides in Manhattan.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Cherelle&#160;Griner</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-cherelle-griner/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 16:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56872</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden, joined by Vice President Harris, spoke today with Cherelle Griner, the wife of Brittney Griner who is wrongfully detained in Russia under intolerable circumstances. The President called Cherelle to reassure her that he is working to secure Brittney’s release as soon as possible, as well as the release of Paul Whelan and other&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden, joined by Vice President Harris, spoke today with Cherelle Griner, the wife of Brittney Griner who is wrongfully detained in Russia under intolerable circumstances. The President called Cherelle to reassure her that he is working to secure Brittney’s release as soon as possible, as well as the release of Paul Whelan and other U.S. nationals who are wrongfully detained or held hostage in Russia and around the world. He also read her a draft of the letter the President is sending to Brittney today.<br><br>The President offered his support to Cherelle and Brittney’s family, and he committed to ensuring they are provided with all possible assistance while his administration pursues every avenue to bring Brittney home. Today’s call follows calls that National Security Advisor Sullivan and Secretary of State Blinken have had with Cherelle in recent weeks and this past weekend. The President directed his national security team to remain in regular contact with Cherelle and Brittney’s family, and with other families of Americans held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad, to keep them updated on efforts to secure the release of their loved ones as quickly as possible.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris After Meeting with&#160;Firefighters</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/06/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-meeting-with-firefighters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 04:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Santa Monica Fire Station 2Santa Monica, California THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So the President and I have been in close coordination, and we are being briefed on what&#8217;s happening right now in terms of the active shooter situation.  We are sending federal resources to local law enforcement and the folks on the ground to make sure&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Santa Monica Fire Station 2<br><em>Santa Monica, California</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So the President and I have been in close coordination, and we are being briefed on what&#8217;s happening right now in terms of the active shooter situation.  We are sending federal resources to local law enforcement and the folks on the ground to make sure that we can help them in terms of the capture of the shooter and any investigation that will follow.<br> <br>But right now, we do have an active shooter situation.  And so we are putting all of the resources possible into monitoring that in a way that we can bring this to a close in terms of also capture of the individual.<br> <br>I am going to travel to Chicago tomorrow morning to address the National Association of Educators, NEA.  And I was just sharing with some of our heroes, our local firefighters, a part of what I&#8217;m preparing &#8212; sadly, I was preparing it before, but it is resonant every day &#8212; is a whole section on what our teachers go through.  They go to school to learn how to teach our children, to inspire their ambition, to create the future generations of leaders.  And our teachers are also in training to deal with an active shooter.  Our teachers are having to learn how to put a tourniquet on a kid if they have been shot.<br> <br>And so, when we look at the issue of gun violence and when we look at the dangers that it presents to communities, it ranges and it is something that we should take very seriously.<br> <br>The President recently signed bipartisan legislation to address the issue of gun violence, but we clearly have much more to do.<br> <br>So, thank you all. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Highland Park&#160;Shooting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/05/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-highland-park-shooting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 03:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Highland Park, Illinois 7:18 P.M. CDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, to the community of Highland Park: I bring you condolences from President Joe Biden and from our country.  I&#8217;m so sorry for what you all have experienced and the pain, the suffering.  This should never have happened.  We talk about it being senseless; it is senseless. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Highland Park, Illinois</em></p>



<p>7:18 P.M. CDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, to the community of Highland Park: I bring you condolences from President Joe Biden and from our country.  I&#8217;m so sorry for what you all have experienced and the pain, the suffering.  This should never have happened.  We talk about it being senseless; it is senseless.  It is absolutely senseless. <br> <br>I want for you that you hold each other tight as a community, that you know that you have a whole nation who cares deeply about you and stands with you.  This is a &#8212; an incredibly tight community.  I know that.  And this person will be brought to justice, but it&#8217;s not going to undo what happened.<br> <br>And we &#8212; we’re here for you, and we stand with you.  And of course, as we always say &#8212; because it is true &#8212; our prayers are with you. <br> <br>The President and I and our administration have put all of the resources and will continue to put all of the resources that the Mayor and the Chief and others need in terms of the federal assistance.  So the FBI and the ATF are here.<br> <br>There&#8217;s a lot of healing that&#8217;s going to have to happen that is both physical and emotional.  There is no question that this experience is something that is going to linger in terms of the trauma.  And so, I&#8217;d like to urge all the families and all the individuals to do seek the support that you so rightly deserve. <br> <br>And &#8212; and we&#8217;ll deal with what we need to deal with in terms of also, as we move forward, all agreeing that we&#8217;ve got to be smarter as a country in terms of who has access to what and, in particular, assault weapons.  And we got to take this stuff seriously, as seriously as you are &#8212; because you have been forced to have to take it seriously. <br> <br>The whole nation should understand and have a level of empathy to understand that this can happen anywhere, in any peace-loving community.  And we should stand together and speak out about why it&#8217;s got to stop.<br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>                         END  7:21 P.M. CDT<br> <br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the National Education Association 2022 Annual Meeting and Representative&#160;Assembly</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/05/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-national-education-association-2022-annual-meeting-and-representative-assembly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 23:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[McCormick Place Convention CenterChicago, Illinois 5:12 P.M. CDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, NEA!  Good afternoon!  (Applause.)  Oh, what a sight my eyes behold.  I am so happy to be with you all this afternoon.  I am so happy to be with you.  And thank you for everything you do and everything you are.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  And,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>McCormick Place Convention Center<br><em>Chicago, Illinois</em></em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">5:12 P.M. CDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, NEA!  Good afternoon!  (Applause.) <br> <br>Oh, what a sight my eyes behold.  I am so happy to be with you all this afternoon.  I am so happy to be with you.  And thank you for everything you do and everything you are.  Thank you.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And, Becky, thank you for being such an extraordinary leader in extraordinary times. (Applause.)  Truly.  I’ve run into her in different places around the country, and she is always speaking about you and the importance of this organization and the importance of this organization to the future of our country.  Thank you, Becky, for that introduction.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, before I start with my address to you, I want to just briefly but importantly address the tragedy just miles away in Highland Park.<br> <br>As we all know, yesterday should have been a day to come together with family and friends to celebrate our nation’s independence.  And instead, that community suffered a violent tragedy.  Children, parents, grandparents &#8212; victims to a senseless act of gun violence. <br> <br>And Doug, who is here with me, he and I &#8212; of course, we mourn, as you do, for those who were killed.  And we pray for those who were injured.  And we all grieve, I know, for the lives that are forever changed in that community, including, of course, the students and the teachers of that community who have suffered great loss. <br> <br>And I don’t need to tell NEA: We need to end this horror.  We need to stop this violence.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And we must protect our communities from the terror of gun violence.  You know, I’ve said it before: Enough is enough.  (Applause.) <br> <br>I mean, here we are, and our nation is still mourning the loss of those 19 babies and their two teachers in Uvalde.  This massacre was the most recent reminder &#8212; in Uvalde &#8212; of the risks that our children and our educators face every day.<br> <br>Teachers should not have to practice barricading a classroom.  (Applause.)  Teachers should not have to know how to treat a gunshot wound.  (Applause.)  And teachers should not be told that “Lives would have been saved if only you had a gun.”  (Applause.) <br> <br>Now, we have made some progress.  For the first time in 30 years, our President, Joe Biden, signed a federal gun safety bill.  (Applause.)  And it strengthens background checks, and it closes what we call the “boyfriend loophole,” and it includes funding for mental health services and school security. <br> <br>But we have more to do.  We have more to do.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And Congress needs to have the courage to act and renew the assault weapons ban.  (Applause.) <br> <br>You know, I’ll talk in a minute about how you as educators teach the children so much.  And you teach the children, among many things, reason.<br> <br>So, let’s talk about what an assault weapon is designed to do.  An assault weapon is designed to kill a lot of human beings quickly.  There is no reason that we have weapons of war on the streets of America.  We need reasonable gun safety laws!  (Applause.) <br> <br>And we need to have Congress stop protecting those gun manufacturers with the liability shield.  Repeal it!  Repeal it! (Applause.) <br> <br>So we cannot be deterred.  We know we have challenges.  We cannot be deterred.<br> <br>And, NEA, we will not give up this fight.  We will not tire because I know who you are; that is just not in our nature.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And that, NEA, is why I am so honored to be here with you &#8212; because I do know this room.  This is a room of fighters.  And I know &#8212; (applause) &#8212; how deeply personal this work is to each one of you. <br> <br>As an educator, your work doesn’t stop at the end of the day when you walk out of your school.  Your work is full-time.  (Applause.)  I know that. <br> <br>Students come to your classroom before the day starts &#8212; for help with homework; sometimes with an empty stomach that you feed &#8212; (applause); or just to have someone they trust to talk with.  (Applause.)  Your students look to you to tell them everything is going to be okay, even sometimes when you may not be sure. <br> <br>But you continue to show up.  And that is why the President and I are honored to partner with the NEA to build our nation’s leaders.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And as a personal point of pride for all of us to have an educator and one of your active members in the White House as First Lady &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Dr. Jill Biden.  Yes.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And I can tell you &#8212; so I sometimes see her in a different situation than you might, and let me just tell you something.  I have watched her go from the classroom directly to events at the White House or across the country and around the world, grading papers in between.  (Applause.)  So, like you, she is a remarkable educator who inspires us all.<br> <br>NEA, who you are and what you do is also personal to me.  I’ve shared with some of you: My first-grade teacher, Mrs. Frances Wilson &#8212; God rest her soul &#8212; attended my law school graduation.  (Applause.)  And there are many people who have contributed to me to be able to serve as the first woman Vice President of the United States &#8212; (applause) &#8212; but I&#8217;m going to tell you, Mrs. Wilson was one of the earliest.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, you all, you not only shape lives, but you also shape policies. <br> <br>And we heard you when we took office when you told us about the issues that matter most to you and your students. <br> <br>We heard you when you told us about the fear and the uncertainty that you faced during the pandemic and about the extra help children needed once they returned to the classroom. So, with your help, we directed over $120 billion to our nation&#8217;s schools through the American Rescue Plan &#8212; with your help.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And this funding also led to a new initiative, launched just today, to help students who fell behind during the pandemic, which means 250,000 tutors and mentors across the country will be in schools to give students the support they need and to support your work every day.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We also heard you when you said your buildings are falling apart &#8212; that the school buildings are falling apart.  (Applause.)  We heard you that air conditioners were broken in the summer heat.  We heard you when you said too many of our children drink water poisoned with lead and breathe dangerous fumes from their bus ride to school.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We heard you when you said your students cannot do their homework because they cannot afford nor do they have access to be able to get online.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So we passed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and it will repair aging school infrastructure to save schools money.  It will replace lead pipes in 400,000 schools and childcare facilities across the country &#8212; (applause) &#8212; so that our children can drink clean water.  It will electrify our nation&#8217;s school buses so children can have clean air to breathe.  (Applause.)  It will make high-speed Internet accessible and affordable to every American household. <br> <br>And this will happen because of your support and your leadership.  Thank you, NEA.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And we still have more to do, and we have so much to do together.<br> <br>NEA, you are extraordinarily effective as a group advocate for change, which is why we know that you have been able to see the success you have achieved.  And it is no surprise why, because we know unions know how to organize.  (Applause.)<br> <br>I say all over the country: You may not be a member of a union, but you better thank the union for the five-day work week and weekends, paid leave.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And I often meet &#8212; and it&#8217;s &#8212; I know you do, and many are here &#8212; I often meet with young organizers from around the country.  And what&#8217;s exciting is that we are seeing in a new, younger generation that they want the benefits and the protections that come from joining a union.  (Applause.)  They want it.  They want it.  Because they know what we all know: Unions give workers a voice.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And so, this is an historic moment, I think, for the labor movement.  Today, unions have their highest approval rating since 1965.  (Applause.)  About half of all non-union workers say they would join a union if given the chance.  That is almost 60 million people.  (Applause.)  Think about that.<br> <br>But we also know there are obstacles for them to meet that desire.  And we know what it is.  One is that many people still don&#8217;t know how to join a union, and so that&#8217;s part of the work we have ahead is to continue to remind them about how.  But even if they do know how, we also know, across our country, folks face barriers that have been built up over the years by corporate interests and anti-union politicians and regressive court cases.  (Applause.)<br> <br>I’ve fought many of those cases when I was Attorney General of California, so we know the obstacles are there.  (Applause.)<br> <br>California is in the house.  (Laughs.)  (Applause.)<br> <br>And so, our administration, together with you, we are all doing a lot to tear down those barriers. <br> <br>And I&#8217;ll tell you, I&#8217;m very proud to lead the White House Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment, along with my good friend &#8212; our good friend &#8212; Secretary Marty Walsh.  And &#8212; (applause) &#8212; from Massachusetts. <br> <br>And our President, Joe Biden, accepted all of our 70 proposals to make it easier for workers to organize.  And here&#8217;s the significance of that: It relates to federal workers, but the federal workforce is actually &#8212; the federal government is largest employer in the country.  And so, when you think about it, as we adopt the recommendations to make it easier for federal workers to organize, you will point to all of that to say, “If it can happen there, it can happen here.”  (Applause.)<br> <br>And there is more to do.<br> <br>So, we are looking at the fact that the President and I are determined to lead not only the most pro-union administration in American history but to move our country forward. <br> <br>We are determined to fight for a future where a teacher&#8217;s wage can provide for a family.  (Applause.)  Because I know it is still the case that some of you are working two jobs.  (Applause.)  Some maybe even three.  I know that. <br> <br>We are determined to fight for a future where you never again have to spend your own money on school supplies to meet your students’ needs.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We will fight for a future where teachers can educate our children with the resources, with the safety, and the respect that you deserve.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Because we are clear: When we do that, we can be sure that every child can reach their God-given potential.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, these are the values that our administration stands for.  And I think, when it comes down to it, it&#8217;s basically this: When you know what you stand for, you know what to fight for.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And so much of what we just got through talking about is what extremist so-called “leaders” stand against. <br> <br>Since our administration has started, not one Republican leader in Washington voted to rescue our nation in the middle of a pandemic, including when we proposed resources for our children and our educators. <br> <br>Not one Republican leader in Washington, D.C., voted to extend the Child Tax Credit, which helps the poorest students and their families.<br> <br>Instead, these extremist so-called “leaders” fought against raising your pay. <br> <br>Instead, these extremist so-called “leaders” refuse to keep assault weapons off our streets and out of our classrooms and tried to silence your voice through your union.<br> <br>And instead, these so-called “leaders” have tried to make you pawns of their political agenda. <br> <br>Because while you work hard to inspire the dreams and ambitions of our next generation, they dare question your dedication, your motivation, and your value. <br> <br>While you work hard &#8212; (applause) &#8212; while you work hard to teach the principles of liberty and freedom in your classroom, these so-called “leaders” are taking freedoms away &#8212; (applause): freedom away from women and the freedom to make decisions over their own bodies &#8212; (applause); freedom away from a kindergarten-to-third-grade teacher in Florida to love openly and with pride &#8212; (applause); and away from every American as they intentionally try to make it more difficult for folks to vote.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We are 126 days away from an election, and we all know what we need to do.  (Applause.)  And, you know, I also think &#8212; I&#8217;m speaking to a group of educators &#8212; I also think that these extremist so-called “leaders” need to attend a civics lesson.  (Laughs.)  (Applause.) <br> <br>I think &#8212; I actually think it would benefit us all if they sat in your classroom for a few days to remember how a democracy works &#8212; (applause); to remember what freedoms stands for; and to remember what jobs they were elected to do.  (Applause.)<br> <br>All that to say that, as educators, you know, we all know that history has never been an unbroken line toward progress; that even when we have advances, there will be setbacks.  In certain times, those setbacks being more drastic than in others. This is one of those moments, but we will not be deterred. <br> <br>The President and I are counting on you to help us move forward as a nation, just as NEA has done throughout its history.  Because I remember that this organization fought to lower the voting age to 18.  (Applause.)  I remember that this organization fought to protect Black teachers from school districts that defied desegregation orders.  (Applause.)  I remember that this was the organization that stood with others to fight to pass DACA and ensure undocumented people can learn in our communities.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Again and again, you have been champions of social justice.  And it is clear: Educators are a central part, then, of moving our nation forward.  You are not only essential to our children&#8217;s future.  I&#8217;m here to share with you: You, I believe, are essential to the future of our democracy.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, we will do this work together because, NEA, when we look at where we are, we know that NEA has always been a powerful force &#8212; a powerful force whose members understand the power of unity. <br> <br>So, these may be difficult times.  And I know that at the end of this convening, you will each go back to your home district; you will go back and you will spend long evenings and nights preparing for the next day; you will go back and often be in a situation where it feels kind of like you might be the only one who sees what you&#8217;re seeing and understands what&#8217;s at stake.  (Applause.)<br> <br>But let&#8217;s remember moments like this.  And let us remember that the fight toward progress by its very nature is not linear. We&#8217;re going to have our ups; we&#8217;re going to have our downs.<br> <br>Let&#8217;s remember &#8212; I like to paraphrase all the time what Coretta Scott King said.  She said: The fight for justice, the fight for civil rights, the fight for freedom, the fight for equality must be fought and won with each generation.  And I think when she said that, she had two points in mind.  One is that it is the very nature of what we stand for and, therefore, fight for that whatever gains we make will not be permanent.<br> <br>There&#8217;s so much strength in what we achieve, but there is also fragility.  So, we must be vigilant.  And the second point then being: If we understand that&#8217;s the nature of it &#8212; it&#8217;s not going to be permanent; it is fragile, unless we are vigilant &#8212; it&#8217;s the nature of it, so do not despair.  Do not be overwhelmed.  Do not throw up our hands when it is a time to roll up our sleeves.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Thank you, NEA.  God bless you.  God bless our education.  And God bless the United States of America.  Thank you all.  (Applause.)<br>         <br>                         END                 5:38 P.M. CDT<br><br><br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
