<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 20:43:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework Creates Economic Opportunities for Rural America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/08/fact-sheet-bipartisan-infrastructure-framework-creates-economic-opportunities-for-rural-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 20:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, despite the fact that rural and Tribal communities across the country are asset-rich, they make up a disproportionate number of persistent poverty communities. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests in rural and Tribal communities, creating jobs in rural America and wealth that stays in rural America. The Framework delivers 100% broadband coverage, rebuilds crumbling infrastructure&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, despite the fact that rural and Tribal communities across the country are asset-rich, they make up a disproportionate number of persistent poverty communities. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests in rural and Tribal communities, creating jobs in rural America and wealth that stays in rural America. The Framework delivers 100% broadband coverage, rebuilds crumbling infrastructure like roads and bridges, eliminates lead pipes and service lines, builds resilience to climate change and extreme weather events, and puts Americans to work cleaning up pollution that has impacted fossil fuel communities in rural America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition to being the largest-long term investment in our infrastructure in nearly a century – four times the infrastructure investment in the 2009 Recovery Act – the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework is a generational investment in rural America.</p>



<p>Investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework to strengthen and create jobs in rural communities include:</p>



<p><strong>Provide high speed internet to every home. </strong>More than 35 percent of rural Americans and Tribal communities lack wired access to broadband at acceptable speeds. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Frameworkinvests $65 billion, including through USDA rural broadband programs, to make high-speed internet available to all Americans, bring down high-speed internet prices across the board, and provide technical assistance to communities seeking to expand broadband. With the 1936 Rural Electrification Act, the Federal government made a historic investment in bringing electricity to nearly every home and farm in America, and millions of families and our economy reaped the benefits. Broadband internet is the new electricity. It is necessary for Americans to do their jobs, to accelerate precision agriculture, to participate equally in school learning and health care, and to stay connected.<br><br><strong>Ensure clean drinking water in every home. </strong>Across the country, including in rural and Tribal communities, pipes and treatment plants are aging and polluted drinking water endanger public health. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests $55 billion in clean drinking water. It will replace 100 percent of the nation’s lead pipes and service lines, benefiting up to 10 million American households and 400,000 schools and child care centers. The Framework invests in water infrastructure across America, including in Tribal Nations and disadvantaged communities that need it most.</p>



<p><strong>Fix Rural Roads and Bridges. </strong>As part of a $110 billion investment to repair America’s crumbling infrastructure, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests in fixing 10,000 off-system bridges, many in rural areas, that provide critical linkages for communities to economic opportunity.</p>



<p><strong>Build Drought, Fire and Flood Resilience. </strong>Last year, the United States faced 22 extreme weather and climate-related disaster events with losses over $1 billion – a cumulative price tag of nearly $100 billion. These included damaging floods, fires, and wind storms across rural America. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests $52 billion to help communities build resilience to wildfires and floods through investments in forest management and upgrades to critical infrastructure &#8212; such as elevating buildings, roads, and bridges, hardening physical infrastructure, and winterizing the power grid. And, it will fund state and local infrastructure improvements and emergency response strategies, such as planning grants to support the development of evacuation routes or upgrades community shelters.</p>



<p>The Framework also helps Western farmers, ranchers, Tribes, families, and communities better prepare for future droughts. It invests in ecosystem restoration, such as the restoration of wetlands that can reduce flood risk for communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Plug Orphan Wells, Clean Up Abandoned Mines, and Remediate Idle Rural Property. </strong>In rural and Tribal communities around the country, former industrial and energy sites are now idle and sources of blight and pollution. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework provides the full American Jobs Plan funding level &#8212; $21 billion – to create good-paying union jobs plugging orphan oil and gas wells, cleaning up abandoned mines, and remediating Brownfield and Superfund sites in rural areas and on Tribal lands. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework will create jobs and build wealth in communities across the country that powered our economic growth for decades and have been affected most by the impacts of climate change and pollution, including rural communities and communities of color.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Connect Rural Communities Through Rail. </strong>U.S. passenger rail lags behind the rest of the world in reliability, speed, and coverage. China already has 22,000 miles of high-speed rail, and is planning to double that by 2035. The lack of rail options affects rural communities in particular. This the largest investment in passenger rail since the creation of Amtrak 50 years ago. The Framework invests $66 billion in passenger and freight rail, including to bring world-class rail service to areas outside the northeast and mid-Atlantic.</p>



<p><strong>Build and Upgrade Airports, Ports, and Waterways in Rural America. </strong>While the United States pioneered the modern aviation industry, today, U.S. airports lag far behind and many rural airports need repair.&nbsp; Only 9 percent of roads outside ports are in good or very good condition and the American Society of Civil Engineers gives America’s Inland Waterways infrastructure a D+. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework meets this challenge by investing $16.3 billion in port infrastructure and $25 billion in airports to address repair and maintenance backlogs, reduce congestion and emissions near ports and airports, and drive electrification and other low-carbon technologies. Modern, resilient, and sustainable port, airport, and freight infrastructure will help American farmers and ranchers sell their goods around the nation and world by removing bottlenecks and expediting commerce and reduce the environmental impact on neighboring communities.</p>



<p><strong>Build Electric Transmission Infrastructure in Rural America. </strong>Power outages cost the U.S. economy up to $70 billion annually. For example, the recent Texas power outages caused estimated losses of up to $90 billion for the state. At times, rural communities can be without power for days during these outages. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework meets this challenge by making the single largest investment in transmission in American history.&nbsp; It creates a Grid Development Authority at the Department of Energy to enable a national, clean energy power grid and funds to support activities that reduce the impacts to the electric grid and communities from extreme weather, wildfire, and natural disasters. It deploys long distance, high voltage transmission to enhance reliability and resilience, lower costs, and integrate the highest value clean energy resources. It invests in research and development for advanced transmission and electricity distribution technologies, and smart grid technologies that deliver flexibility and resilience. And, it invests more than $22 billion in demonstration projects and research hubs for next generation technologies like advanced nuclear reactors, carbon capture for industrial plants, and green hydrogen.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joe Biden Appoints Nine Members to President’s Council of Governors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/08/president-joe-biden-appoints-nine-members-to-presidents-council-of-governors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 19:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden appointed nine governors as members of the Council of Governors for two-year terms. The bipartisan Council of Governors serves as the lead forum to strengthen partnerships between the Federal government and State governments to better protect our nation from threats to our homeland security and all types of hazards. The Council focuses&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden appointed nine governors as members of the Council of Governors for two-year terms. The bipartisan Council of Governors serves as the lead forum to strengthen partnerships between the Federal government and State governments to better protect our nation from threats to our homeland security and all types of hazards. The Council focuses on matters of homeland security; homeland defense; civil support; synchronization and integration of state and Federal military activities in the United States; and other matters of mutual interest, including those involving the National Guard. Federal-state cooperation is critical to protecting communities given the evolving challenges and threats facing our country, which range from extreme weather to domestic and international terrorism to a global pandemic. The Council of Governors will closely coordinate with the Biden-Harris administration to bolster preparedness, resilience and response on behalf of all Americans in times of need.<br><br>The Council includes leaders across the Federal government: the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security, the Deputy Assistant to the President for Intergovernmental Affairs, the Commander of U.S. Northern Command, the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Homeland Defense and Global Security, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, and the Chief of the National Guard Bureau. Other key Federal officials such as the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) are regular participants.<br><br><strong>President’s Council of Governors:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, Co-Chair</li><li>Ohio Governor Mike DeWine, Co-Chair</li><li>Delaware Governor John Carney</li><li>Louisiana Governor John Bel Edwards</li><li>Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer</li><li>Oregon Governor Kate Brown</li><li>Utah Governor Spencer Cox</li><li>Vermont Governor Phil Scott</li><li>Wyoming Governor Mark Gordon</li></ul>



<p>The nine Governors will join Tennessee Governor Bill Lee on the council. Governor Lee’s term expires in 2022.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Transnational Criminal Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/07/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-transnational-criminal-organizations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations declared in Executive Order 13581 of July&nbsp;24, 2011, under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13863 of March 15, 2019, is to continue in effect beyond July 24, 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The activities of significant transnational criminal organizations have reached such scope and gravity that they threaten the stability of international political and economic systems.&nbsp; Such organizations are becoming increasingly sophisticated and dangerous to the United States; they are increasingly entrenched in the operations of foreign governments and the international financial system, thereby weakening democratic institutions, degrading the rule of law, and undermining economic markets.&nbsp; These organizations facilitate and aggravate violent civil conflicts and increasingly facilitate the activities of other dangerous persons.</p>



<p>The activities of significant transnational criminal organizations continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.  For these reasons, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations declared in Executive Order 13581, under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13863.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Transnational Criminal Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/07/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-transnational-criminal-organizations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 24, 2011, by Executive Order 13581, the President declared a national emergency with respect to transnational criminal organizations pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 24, 2011, by Executive Order 13581, the President declared a national emergency with respect to transnational criminal organizations pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by the activities of significant transnational criminal organizations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On March 15, 2019, by Executive Order 13863, the President took additional steps to deal with the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations in view of the evolution of these organizations as well as the increasing sophistication of their activities, which threaten international political and economic systems and pose a direct threat to the safety and welfare of the United States and its citizens, and given the ability of these organizations to derive revenue through widespread illegal conduct, including acts of violence and abuse that exhibit a wanton disregard for human life as well as many other crimes enriching and empowering these organizations.</p>



<p>The activities of significant transnational criminal organizations continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of&nbsp;the United States.&nbsp; For these reasons, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13581 of July 24, 2011, under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13863 of March&nbsp;15, 2019, must continue in effect beyond July 24, 2021.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1&nbsp;year the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations declared in Executive Order 13581.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>July 7, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/07/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-hong-kong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.  In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the situation in Hong Kong declared in Executive Order 13936 of July 14, 2020, is to continue in effect beyond July 14, 2021. <br><br>The situation with respect to Hong Kong, including recent actions taken by the People&#8217;s Republic of China to fundamentally undermine Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat, which has its source in substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.  Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13936 with respect to the situation in Hong Kong. <br>                               </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,<br><br>JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/07/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-hong-kong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 14, 2020, by Executive Order 13936, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 etseq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&#160;States constituted by the situation with respect to Hong Kong. &#160;&#160; The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 14, 2020, by Executive Order 13936, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et</em><em>seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States constituted by the situation with respect to Hong Kong. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The situation with respect to Hong Kong, including recent actions taken by the People&#8217;s Republic of China to fundamentally undermine Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States. &nbsp;For this reason, the national emergency declared on July 14, 2020, must continue in effect beyond July 14, 2021. &nbsp;Therefore, in accordance with section&nbsp;202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13936 with respect to the situation in Hong Kong.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.<br>                             </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>July 7, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the Benefits of the Build Back Better Agenda for Working Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/07/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-benefits-of-the-build-back-better-agenda-for-working-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[McHenry County CollegeCrystal Lake, Illinois 1:46 P.M. CDT THE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Edith.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)  Please.  Please, be seated. Mr. President &#8212; what he hadn’t told you today: He had to delay his vacation to be here today.  (Laughter.)  He heard Biden is coming.  He goes, “Oh, my God, when&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">McHenry County College<br>Crystal Lake, Illinois</p>



<p>1:46 P.M. CDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Edith.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)  Please.  Please, be seated.<br><br>Mr. President &#8212; what he hadn’t told you today: He had to delay his vacation to be here today.  (Laughter.)  He heard Biden is coming.  He goes, “Oh, my God, when is he coming?”  (Laughter.)  But &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; so he could show me around McHenry County College.<br><br>I’m glad to be here with great Illinois leaders.  I want you all to &#8212; you know, America is back.  America is back.  (Applause.)  And in no small part because of the men and women that I serve with. <br><br>Governor Pritzker, stand up, man.  Stand up.  (Applause.)  This is a good man. <br><br>If you really want someone in a foxhole with you when you’re in trouble, you want Senator Tammy Duckworth.  Tammy.  (Applause.)<br><br>And the guy I rely on more than anyone else in the United States Senate &#8212; and I’ve served with him for years; we have a lot in common in terms of losses as well as gains &#8212; is Dick Durbin.  Dick.  (Applause.)<br><br>And Congresswoman Underwood, who got me a passport to her town.  (Applause.)  Her mom and dad are mildly proud with good reason.  (Laughter.)  Good reason.  Actually, her mom looks like her sister.  (Laughter.) <br><br>Last week, I was up in Wisconsin to talk about a bipartisan agreement to modernize American infrastructure and, in the process, create millions of good-paying jobs.  That’s not my estimate &#8212; that’s Wall Street estimates; that’s everybody’s estimate.  Millions of good-paying jobs.  Not $7, not $8, not $10, not even $15 an hour.  Good prevailing-wage jobs.  (Applause.)<br><br>And here’s what it means for Illinois: You’ve got, like many states &#8212; all states &#8212; you’ve got 230- &#8212; 2,374 bridges and over 6,200 miles of highway that are in disrepair.<br><br>As a result, every driver in this state pays a hidden tax<br>of about $600 per year in wasted time and wasted fuel because of the nature of the roads and bridges &#8212; and, by the way, you’re better than a lot of states &#8212; not to mention the challenge of getting to work or getting to the daycare center on time to avoid that late fee when you pick up your child.<br><br>Your governor has an ambitious infrastructure plan, and under a bipartisan infrastructure agreement, we’re going to make the biggest investment in roads and bridges since the construction of the Interstate Highway System, literally creating millions of good-paying jobs.  (Applause.)<br><br>And God willing, we’re not going to have 40 &#8212; 40 weeks of “This is Infrastructure Week.”  (Laughter.)  Remember those?<br><br>Think what it will mean to McHenry’s entrepreneurial agricultural program if we can get products more easily to Chicago.  Think about how much easier life will be when it’s quicker to drive on Randall Road.  (Laughter.)<br><br>Look, this agreement also allows us to replace every lead pipe and service line in America, benefitting 10 million homes.  (Applause.)  It’s going to address &#8212; it’s going to address lead exposure to 400,000 of our schools and daycare facilities where children drink that water.  This would be the largest investment in clean drinking water in American history when we pass it.<br><br>In every &#8212; 1 in every 10 people in Illinois lacks access to high-speed Internet.  The bipartisan agreement that Dick and others have made sure we’re getting &#8212; the agreement allows us to connect every American to reliable, high-speed, affordable Internet &#8212; every single American, rural and urban.  And, by the way, those of you who are parents, who had kids at home, tell me what Internet means this last year.  (Laughter.)  If they’re school age.  <br><br>Well, from 2010 to 2020, Illinois experienced 49 extreme weather events &#8212; although I heard today from the senator north of here that there &#8212; a Republican senator &#8212; there is no global warming.  Just so you know, there’s no such thing.  (Laughter.) <br><br>But those weather events cost this state roughly $50 billion in damages.  And we’re going to up upgrade the electric grid to make it more resilient to extreme weather and other threats.<br><br>There’s a lot more the agreement is going to do to encourage the physical and ensure &#8212; the physical infrastructure lays the foundation for a strong, durable, and sustainable competitive economy.<br><br>But what I want to talk to you about today is human infrastructure.  It’s essential to that foundation, as well.  To truly win the 21st century and once again lead the world, to truly build an economy from the bottom up and the middle out, to truly deal everybody in this time, we need to invest in our people.  We need to invest in our people.<br><br>That’s why, in addition to the bipartisan infrastructure agreement that I believe we’re going to get done, I’m here to make the case for the second critical part of my domestic agenda.  It’s a combination of parts of my American Jobs Plan that were essential and not included in the bipartisan infrastructure plan, as well as my American Families Plan. <br><br>In Washington, they call it a “reconciliation bill.”  That’s a fancy way of saying, with a filibuster that our friends on the other side use constantly &#8212; more than ever been used in history &#8212; it means you got to get 60 votes to get anything done.  We’re 50-50 Senate with a Vice President who happens to be a Democrat.<br><br>And back in the campaign, you know, I said we’re going to build back, and we’re going to build back better.  Not just &#8212; we can’t just build back; we got to build back better.<br><br>And today, I want to outline some of the key pieces of this Build Back Better agenda and what’s it going to do for the people of Illinois and the people of the United States.<br><br>It’s about a country, once again, that inspires and leads the world with the opportunities we provide, the cures we discovery, the technolog- &#8212; that we discover &#8212; the technologies we pioneer, and industries we create.  You know, and a nation that leads the world in combatting the existential threat of climate change.<br><br>The Build Back Better plan &#8212; agenda starts with education.  You know, one of the reasons why we were the leading country in the world for so long, and still on the edge, is because we’re the first nation &#8212; industrial nation in the world to require &#8212; to allow 12 years of free education back at the turn of the 20th century.  But everybody is caught up.<br><br>At the time, they were debating what should be education in America.  The argument was there should be 12 years of free education.  And that’s what’s got us ahead.  That’s what had us leap ahead of the rest of the world.<br><br>But as (inaudible) today, everybody is caught up.  Does anybody think, in the 21st century, with the change that’s taking place in technology and across the board, that 12 years of education is enough to be able to live a middle-class life?  I don’t think so.<br><br>And so, the fact of the matter is we’ve decided &#8212; I’ve decided we should have a minimum of 14 years of education.  Fourteen years of education &#8212; which I’ll explain in a second.<br><br>You know, as the First Lady &#8212; I’m Jill Biden’s husband, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but as Jill would say &#8212; and she’s a full-time community college professor while being the First Lady &#8212; she often says, &#8220;Any nation that out-educates us is going to out-compete us.&#8221;  Any nation that out-educates us is going to out compete us. <br><br>That’s why I want to guarantee an additional four additional years of public education for every person in America, starting with providing two years of universal, high-quality preschool for three- and four-year-olds, building &#8212; (applause) &#8212; building on what the governor has been doing here in Illinois.  (Applause.)<br><br>In the last 10 years, studies out of the great universities &#8212; study of a high-quality program here in Chicago &#8212; found that low-income children participating in preschool were 47 percent more likely to earn an associate’s degree or higher, and get through school without any difficulty.  We have to build on that foundation for future success.  And then I want to add two years of free community college for everyone.  (Applause.) <br><br>And we can afford it.  I’ll tell you how. <br><br>That can boost the earnings of a high school graduate with low-wage jobs by nearly $6,000 a year on average.<br><br>The average annual cost of a two-year degree in Illinois is $4,200.  Under my proposal, that cost would be zero.  (Applause.)<br><br>But it’s not just tuition that’s expensive; as was pointed out, living expenses, housing, meals, transportation.  And that’s why I propose to increase a maximum Pell Grant &#8212; which, if you are below a certain income, you qualify for a Pell Grant &#8212; from about $6,500 to $8,000 a year.  (Applause.)  And that will fill it out. <br><br>I know &#8212; I know that here at McHenry, you have a dual enrollment program so students from places like Woodstock High School and other high schools, you get credit for taking college classes here.  Well, my plan will &#8212; will provide resources to expand programs like the one you have here.<br><br>My plan will also do more to invest in high-quality job training and apprenticeships in fast-growing sectors like public health, childcare, manufacturing, information technology, clean energy so that all Americans can get the skills that employers want that lead to good middle-class and &#8212; I was &#8212; I make no apology &#8212; union jobs.  (Applause.)<br><br>It would also &#8212; it would also make strategic investments in teachers &#8212; in the teacher pipeline.  Because even before the pandemic, our school system was 100,000 teachers short here in America, particularly in high-demand areas.<br><br>Our children are the kite strings that lift our national ambitions aloft, and our teachers are the ones that help them<br>believe they can do anything.  I bet every one of your success can name the teacher that helped change your life.  I bet every one &#8212; every one of us.  There’s somebody who came along and made us believe in ourselves.  That’s the really sec- &#8212; the secret of teachers.<br><br>My plan will reduce student debt for future teachers, double the size of the annual federal scholarships for future teachers.<br><br>We’ll also support $100 billion in school infrastructure improvements, including community college, to make sure that they are safe and healthy places for learning, and that all students &#8212; with the labs and technology they need to be able to compete in the 21st century.<br><br>Of course, an ability to take these jobs often depends on the availability of childcare.  As a single father, when I was first got to the Senate, I had two young boys who had just lost their mom and their sister in an automobile accident.  If I hadn’t had the family I have &#8212; my sister, best &#8212; my younger sister, my best friend, and my brother, and my mom help out &#8212; I couldn’t have done it.  But not everybody has that kind of support.   <br><br>I just toured your Children’s Learning Center.  It’s an amazing resource.  Students and faculty can have their children cared for.  Students can earn their associate degrees in early childhood education as well.  High-quality childcare options should be the rule, not the exception.<br><br>So, on my way in here, I met with Mike Sayre, who wrote me a letter about his struggle to find affordable childcare, and he wanted me to &#8212; he wanted to know what my plans were.  Well, Mike, I hope you know now.  Here we are.<br><br>My plan is to provide access to quality, affordable childcare with more childcare centers in community college campuses with new and upgraded childcare facilities all across the country. (Applause.)<br><br>Businesses &#8212; businesses will get a full tax credit to build on-site facilities.  And the reason they want to do that is not just to be nice.  Business &#8212; because studies show when there’s an on-site childcare center, businesses have less employee turnover, less absenteeism, and higher productivity.  It’s overwhelmingly in their interest to do it.<br><br>Middle-class families will pay no more than 7 percent of their income for high-quality childcare for children up to age five.  And the most hard-pressed working families won’t have to pay a dime.<br><br>My plan will also invest in childcare workforce with better wages, benefits, and training opportunities.<br><br>Look, we’re also going to give parents the option to take up to an $8,000 tax credit to cover childcare expenses, if that’s the preferred route.  That’s good for families and it’s good for our economy, and it will create more jobs.<br><br>My plan will also provide up to 12 weeks of paid family leave for medical &#8212; (applause) &#8212; up to 12 weeks of paid family leave.  Look, we’re one of the few major economies in the world that doesn’t cover paid family and medical leave. <br><br>And the most difficult moments some will ever face:<br>No one should have to choose between a job and a paycheck and take caring of someone you love &#8212; a parent, a spouse, a child.<br><br>Look, we will tackle the maternal mortality crisis, as well, that impacts on Black and Native American mothers disproportionately.  And what &#8212; and I want to thank Congresswoman Underwood for her leadership in this area.  (Applause.)  For real.<br><br>As I’ve said again and again, people who really need a tax break in this country are America’s working families.  It’s time they get a tax break.<br><br>So, my Build Back Better agenda would extend the expanded Child Tax Credit we passed under my American Rescue Plan.  Those of you who have children under the age of seven [six], you’re going to get &#8212; and depending on your income &#8212; your income taxes &#8212; you’re going to get a cash payment back.  Up to now, guess what?  You get $2,000 to declare a dependent.  If you have two children, you get $4,000 off a $10,000 tax bill.  It’s important.<br><br>But if you don’t have enough &#8212; you don’t have enough &#8212; you don’t make enough money to be able to have &#8212; to owe that kind of tax, you don’t get a tax credit, you don’t get anything.  Well, under this proposal, guess what?  You’re in a situation where if you have a child under the age of <s>seven</s> [six], you get back $3,600 in cash.  In addition to that, those of you who are in that situation are going to start to see that coming in by the end of this month, on a monthly basis.  It can change the lives of people. <br><br>Starting next week, families will begin to receive one of the largest-ever single-year tax cuts aimed to families with children.  And every child under age 6 is $3,600; every child between 6 and 17 is $3,000.  It’s not as a credit against your taxes, but a direct payment.  You’ll get cash.  Cash.  That’s what you’ll get.<br><br>For example, a middle-class family with two children can expect to receive $7,200.  You’ll get the first half &#8212; the $3,600 &#8212; paid out at $600 a month between July and December, and you’ll get the rest between January and Tax Day.<br><br>With this one tax cut, every study shows that childcare &#8212; childcare is cutting poverty in ha- &#8212; by 40 percent.  Families with children who qualify for this, it cuts poverty by 40 percent.<br><br>So, let’s extend the tax cut at least through 2025, and let’s expand &#8212; (applause) &#8212; let&#8217;s expand free meals for millions more children in schools, with the assistance during the summer months when they don’t have access to those school meals. <br><br>We support families with children.  We also need to provide greater dignity for our nation’s senior citizens who care for them. <br><br>Look, there are hundreds of thousands of older adults<br>and people with disabilities who need home- and community-based care services.  They qualify for it under Medicaid, but there&#8217;s a backlog of thousands of people.  But one study showed that $3,000 spent helping a senior stay in their home by providing &#8212; it saves the country more than $20,000 a year in medical costs. <br><br>At the same time, more than 1.5 million Americans work in homecare.  They&#8217;re disproportionately women, women of color, and immigrants, and those jobs are among the lowest paid in our economy.  One in six homecare workers lives in poverty.  We need to do better on both sides of the equation. <br><br>My plan expands homecare for older and disabled Americans,<br>while improving jobs and pay for homecare workers who care for them.<br><br>And here&#8217;s the deal: You save a lot of money if you don’t have to go to a home.  Keeping people in their own home, mentally and every other way, is a benefit &#8212; a significant benefit for the community, as well as cost. <br><br>We also need to continue to make healthcare more affordable.  When we lowered premiums and expanded coverage for the American Re- &#8212; in my American Rescue Plan, more than 1.5 million people signed up for what used to be called &#8220;Obamacare.&#8221;  I want to make these premium reductions permanent so we can get even more people covered.<br><br>We need to deal with the shortage of affordable housing in America.  Over 10 million renters in this country pay more than half their income for the rent on their apartment, and the lack of affordable housing prevents people from moving to communities where there are more opportunities.<br><br>So we’re going to make historic investment in affordable housing, increasing and improving the housing supply by building and rehabilitating more than 2 million homes, especially in places that need more housing.<br><br>And we need to invest not just in the physical and human infrastructure of today, we need to invest in the jobs and industries of tomorrow.<br><br>Three decades ago &#8212; and this always disturbs me, even just repeating it &#8212; three decades ago, the United States was number one in the world for a share of their GDP being invested in research and development.  We were number one in the world.  We&#8217;re now number eight [nine] in the world.  Number eight [nine] in the world.  China was number &#8212; or &#8212; excuse me, we’re &#8212; China was number nine [eight] in the world; now they’re number two in the world.<br><br>Folks, Democrats and Republicans agree we can’t afford to lose this race.  They came together in the Senate on an Innovation and Competition Act &#8212; that Dick was very much a part of &#8212; to help us grow the industries that win the jobs of the future.<br><br>We need to lay the foundation for the next generation of American jobs and American leadership in manufacturing and technology.<br><br>We&#8217;re going to invest in Historically Black Colleges and Universities and other Minority-Serving Institutions because while these schools may not have the endowments or the labs needed to generate these jobs, these students are just as capable of learning about all of the things that are going to provide the jobs of the future.  <br><br>And, of course, no challenge is as urgent as climate change.  Last week, I met with eight governors for a better part of an hour, all from the western states, Republicans and Democrats.  They’re facing extreme heat, record drought,<br>and a fire season that threatens to be much longer and more dangerous and more destructive than ever. <br><br>Last year, for example, more than 10 million acres burned in the West &#8212; 10 million acres &#8212; not counting the lives lost and homes lost.  More land than exists in my home state of Delaware and my neighboring state of Maryland combined.  So if a fire swept through and took out every single thing in the state of Delaware and Maryland.  The drought conditions, this year, are twice as bad.  You&#8217;ve seen the pictures.  Reservoirs that are 40 feet down, 50 feet down. <br><br>The extreme weather isn’t just in the West.  In Illinois, farmers downstate are dealing with more frequent droughts.  And two weeks ago, just south of here, you just had a nearly unprecedented tornado. <br><br>We can&#8217;t wait any longer to deal with the climate crisis.  We see it with our own eyes, and it&#8217;s time to act.<br><br>The bipartisan agreement we reached makes some major strides.  It&#8217;s going to allow the transition of thousands of old, for example, of diesel school buses and buses &#8212; city buses.  We&#8217;re going to change them to electric buses.  There are roughly a half a million of these iconic yellow school buses on the road today.  Ninety-five percent of them run on diesel, for example.   And diesel pollutes the air and is linked to asthma and other health problems, and it hurts our communities and it causes our students to miss school.<br><br>I&#8217;ll put Americans to work capping tens of thousands of abandoned oil and gas wells that are leaking methane.  It&#8217;s devastating.  And the wages to fill these &#8212; cap these wells are the same wages that it took to dig the wells, making people earn &#8212; be able to earn a prevailing wage to do it.  There’s thousands of them.<br><br>But we need to go further.<br><br>I want to provide tax cuts for businesses and consumers who invest in clean energy technologies like renewables, battery storage, next-generation aviation fuels, electric vehicles. <br>I want to set the clean electricity standard that moves us to a fully clean and reliable grid.<br><br>These steps are going to create good-paying union jobs and spur demand for domestic manufacturing, accelerating clean energy and clean cars, growing our capacity to build those technologies on factory floors with union workers, here in the United States.<br><br>And we create a new generation of jobs in clean energy and manufacturing.  And I also want to enlist a new generation of climate, conservation, and reliance workers &#8212; excuse me, resilience workers &#8212; like FDR did when the American work plan &#8212; preserving our landscape with a Civilian Conservation Corps.  It’s a similar thing.<br><br>We can put Americans to work strengthening public lands and waters, and making our communities &#8212; rural and urban &#8212; more resilient against extreme weather.  And we can take on the long-overdue work of advancing environmental justice by addressing pollution.<br><br>My plan is also going to give grants to spur innovative policies and land projects &#8212; lo- &#8212; excuse me, local projects, like installing community solar and storage and disadvanta- &#8212; in disadvantaged communities; replacing streetlights that are made in America with LED bulbs that cost a whole lot less and last a whole lot longer; making upgrades in homes and schools<br>and community centers to boost energy efficiency and cut electric bills.<br><br>Folks, I’ve laid out a lot of plans here, but that’s because it’s time, and we have to think bigger, and we have to act bolder, and we have to build back better.<br><br>When we passed the American Rescue Plan, the naysayers and the doubters said it wouldn’t work.  Well, we’ve created over 3 million jobs since I took office &#8212; more jobs in the first months of a presidential administration than any time in American history. <br><br>And last week, the Congressional Budget Office<br>doubled their projections of the 2021 economic growth from 3.2 percent to 7.4 percent, and the OECD thinks it could be higher.  That puts the America Rescue Plan &#8212; and our work is going to move forward to do a lot of things, including &#8212; we’re close to defeating the virus. <br><br>The last time energy &#8212; the economy grew at this rate was in 1984 and Ronald Reagan was telling us it was an American morning.  Well, this is going to be an American century.  (Applause.)<br><br>With my American Families Plan and the other elements of the Build Back Better agenda, experts and Wall Street analysts have said that we’ll create millions of good-paying jobs for years and decades to come, not just in the near term.<br><br>So, I’m going to be making the case to the American people until the job is done, until we bring this bipartisan deal home, until we meet the needs of families today and the economy of tomorrow.  And we can pay for it. <br><br>Let me give you a rough example.  This isn’t &#8212; you know, and by the way, the American &#8212; the &#8212; the plan for infrastructure is paid for.  It’s paid for.  And this plan that I&#8217;m talking about &#8212; which is really expensive if you add it all up &#8212; well, guess what?  The fact is that it’s paid for as well.  And let me tell you how we’re going to pay for it.<br><br>Some of the ways to pay for the rest of it is: The last couple of years, for example, 55 of the Fortune 500 companies making billions of dollars did not pay a single penny in taxes &#8212; not one single cent.<br><br>Well, I don’t want to punish anybody, but everybody &#8212; and I hope someday my grandchildren grow up to be billionaires.  That&#8217;d be wonderful, especially for a guy who for 36 years was listed as the poorest man in United States Congress.  (Laughter.) <br><br>But having said that, all kidding aside, everybody has to pay their fair share.  I&#8217;m not trying to gouge anybody, but, I mean, just get in the game. <br><br>If we put in place a minimum 15 percent tax on the profits of corporations, the ones that didn&#8217;t pay any tax, that would raise a quarter of a trillion dollars &#8212; $240 billion. <br><br>But there&#8217;s a loophole in the system called “stepped-up basis.”  That loophole goes: If I made a capital gains and I was a wealthy person, and I was going to cash in my stock, and I was going to have to pay a tax, I was going to make, you know, $400,000, and I was going to pay X amount of taxes &#8212; if, on the way to cash it in I get hit by a truck, God forbid, and died, and it was left to my daughter, there would be no tax paid.  It’s not an inheritance tax.  It was a tax due 10 seconds earlier. <br><br>We closed that loophole, and that saves us $400 billion a year &#8212; not a year &#8212; $400 billion over this period, which is enough to pay for the Child &#8212; Child <s>Care</s> Tax Credit. <br><br>If we end tax breaks for fossil fuels, and make polluters pay to clean up the messes they&#8217;ve made, that would raise $90 billion.  We’re not asking them to do anything that &#8212; that is unfair; we’re just not going to subsidize them anymore.  They&#8217;re doing well, thank &#8212; thank you.  And the messes they made, they should clean up. <br><br>Well, if we ask the top 1 percent &#8212; and I hope many of you are in the top 1 percent &#8212; maybe.  (Laughter.)<br><br>You know, that tax cut that was passed in 2017 was all &#8212; it raised the deficit by over $2 trillion &#8212; not a penny paid for, and it didn&#8217;t come back with anything.  That &#8212; that, in fact &#8212; that entire $2 trillion &#8212; the vast majority went to the top one-tenth of 1 percent of the American people. <br><br>One percent &#8212; you know, if we just &#8212; 1 percent &#8212; the folks in the top 1 percent, if they just paid their personal income state tax, the same as it was under President George Bush &#8212; George W. Bush &#8212; that would generate $13 billion a year.  It would raise the tax from what it is now, 35, to 39 percent.  It’s what it &#8212; I mean, it&#8217;s not like this idea where you’d listen to the guy that used to have his job that somehow we’re gouging people.<br><br>The fact of the matter is, a lot of you, if you&#8217;re &#8212; if you&#8217;re a plumber or a teacher, you&#8217;re probably paying 25, 26 percent.  Some of you be paying higher. <br><br>But, here, look: It&#8217;s enough to provide for &#8212; that one change &#8212; enough to provide for two years free community college for every student in America. <br><br>Now &#8212; (applause) &#8212; now, people say that one of the purposes of taxes is to also generate growth along with making sure that we can pay for our basic needs. <br><br>Well, let me ask you, what is more likely to grow the economy and enhance us: continuing the tax cut at 37 percent, or spending &#8212; having to pay 39-point &#8212; and a half percent, generating economic growth?  Because now you have a tax system that will allow millions of students to go to community college. <br><br>When I was with Barack as Vice President, he asked me to do a study.  And I spent &#8212; and I &#8212; your sister, Penny Pritzker, was part of my effort to taking care of it.  And the effort was simple.  It came along, and we said, “Okay, what do we…” &#8212; and we (inaudible) three hundred and, I think, forty-seven &#8212; don’t hold me to the exact number &#8212; of the CEOs of the Fortune 500 companies.  Said, “What do you need most?”  You know what they said to almost &#8212; to a person?  “I need a better-educated workforce.”  They&#8217;re not prepared to pay for it. <br><br>Imagine if we present the world a nation with a better educated workforce.  It helps everybody.  The point is, we can pay for our entire plan and make the tax system fairer for all Americans.  It&#8217;s about time.<br><br>There&#8217;s a lot of work ahead of us to finish the job, but we’re going to get it done.  We’re going to reimagine what our economy and our future could be, and show the world &#8212; just as importantly, we’ll show ourselves &#8212; that democracy &#8212; democracy can deliver for the people of Illinois and the people of America, and the world can lead again.  (Applause.) <br><br>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.  I know that&#8217;s a boring speech, but it&#8217;s an important speech. <br><br>God bless you all, and may God protect our troops. <br><br>Thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you.  Appreciate it. <br><br>And excuse my back.  I apologize.  I apologize.  Thank you.  (Applause.) <br><br>2:17 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden During a Tour of McHenry County College</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/07/remarks-by-president-biden-during-a-tour-of-mchenry-county-college/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 20:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[McHenry County CollegeCrystal Lake, Illinois 1:22 P.M. CDT Q Mr. President, Mitch McConnell says you&#8217;re in for a heck of a fight on this one. THE PRESIDENT: Mitch McConnell loves our programs. Did you see what Mitch McConnel said? He told me he wasn’t going to get a single vote in order to allow me&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">McHenry County College<br>Crystal Lake, Illinois</p>



<p>1:22 P.M. CDT</p>



<p>Q Mr. President, Mitch McConnell says you&#8217;re in for a heck of a fight on this one.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: Mitch McConnell loves our programs. Did you see what Mitch McConnel said? He told me he wasn’t going to get a single vote in order to allow me to get, with the help of everybody here, that $1.9 trillion tax cut &#8212; I mean, excuse me, program to &#8212; for economic growth.</p>



<p>Look it up, man. He&#8217;s bragging about in Kentucky: “It&#8217;s a great thing for Kentucky. It&#8217;s getting $4 billion to help poor.” It&#8217;s amazing. Check out Mitch McConnell. You can even see it on TV.</p>



<p>Anyway, thanks. Thank you.</p>



<p>1:22 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen Psaki Aboard Air Force One En Route Crystal Lake, IL</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/07/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-aboard-air-force-one-en-route-crystal-lake-il/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 18:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Crystal Lake, Illinois 11:13 A.M. CDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Welcome to our trip to Crystal Lake, Illinois.&#160; In Crystal Lake, the President will make the case for generational investments in human infrastructure and other critical priorities like clean energy that form his Build Back Better agenda, a combination of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Crystal Lake, Illinois</p>



<p>11:13 A.M. CDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Welcome to our trip to Crystal Lake, Illinois.&nbsp; In Crystal Lake, the President will make the case for generational investments in human infrastructure and other critical priorities like clean energy that form his Build Back Better agenda, a combination of the American Families Plan, and policies from the American Jobs Plan that aren’t included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework.</p>



<p>At McHenry County College, which has workforce development programs and a childcare center, the President will underline the specific game-changing impacts of the Buil- &#8212; his Build Back Better agenda.</p>



<p>He will argue that to build an economy from the bottom up and the middle out, we need to invest in our people by providing four additional years of public education to every student, increasing Pell Grants and investing in job training.</p>



<p>You’ll also hear him talk about the fact that, as a former single father, he will &#8212; he will stress that his plan is to help boost childcare affordability by building new childcare centers and ensuring that no middle-class family pays more than 7 percent of their income on high-quality care for children up to age five.</p>



<p>He will also note that the Build Back Better plan will invest in the childcaring workforce, provide parents with an up to $8,000 tax credit to cover their childcare expenses, institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, and extand [sic] &#8212; and extend the expanded Child Tax Credit from the Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>Finally, with over 10 million Americans currently paying over half of what they earn in rent, the President will cover how the Build Back Better agenda includes a historic investment in affordable housing &#8212; something I think you all haven’t heard him talk about that much yet &#8212; to address supply and building or rehabilitating more than 2 million homes.</p>



<p>One other item for all of you: Today we also announced three initiatives as part of the President’s forthcoming executive order, fulfilling his campaign promise to promote competition in labor markets in order to raise wages and make it easier for workers to change jobs and to move between states.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, roughly half of private sector businesses require at least some employees to enter non-compete agreements, affecting over 30 million people.&nbsp; This affects construction workers, hotel workers, many blue-collar jobs, not just high-level executives.&nbsp; He believes that if someone offers you a better job, you should be able to take it.&nbsp; It makes sense.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in keeping with his campaign promise, the executive order will call on the FTC to adopt rules that curtail non- compete agreements.&nbsp; His executive order will also call on the Federal Trade Commission to adopt rules that ban unnecessary occupational licensing requirements.&nbsp; Today, almost 30 percent of jobs in the U.S. require a license from attorneys and accountants to interior designers and hairdressers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While occupational licensing can serve important health and safety concerns, unnecessary or overly burdensome licensing can lock people out of jobs.&nbsp; This hugely affects military families in particular, over one third of whom work in a field requiring a license and who are subject to military-directed moves every year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, a little update for you on vaccine doses.&nbsp; Today we&#8217;re announcing we are sharing more doses with Latin America.&nbsp; One million Johnson &amp; Johnson doses will be headed to Bolivia on Thursday.&nbsp; One million doses of Pfizer will be sent to Paraguay.</p>



<p>Sorry, actual last thing: The Department of Education also released today nearly $6 billion in American Rescue Plan funds to six states and Washington, D.C., to support the safe reopening of K-through-12 schools.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lots going on.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of questions.&nbsp; Off the top, I know the midterms are a while away, but they come quicker than you expect, so can we talk politics a little bit, partly because the President has visited three top targeted congressional districts in the past week.&nbsp; Obviously, today is one of them.&nbsp; So, considering the party in power typically loses seats in a midterm, is part of the strategy right now to mitigate those potential losses?&nbsp; And does the White House see the President&#8217;s policies as swaying voters in the upcoming midterms?</p>



<p>Well, first, I would say that the President is visiting this district in Illinois today because Congresswoman &#8212; in part because Congresswoman Lauren Underwood has &#8212; is a registered nurse.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a champion for healthcare and expanding access to affordable healthcare.&nbsp; And that certainly is part of what&#8217;s under discussion and what is part of his Build Back Better agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will say that when the President put together his economic plans &#8212; his Build Back Better agenda, the American Rescue Plan, the American Jobs Plan, the American Families Plan &#8212; what he had in mind was governing for all Americans &#8212; Democrats, Republicans &#8212; and making clear that he was going to be the President for everyone, not just the people who voted for him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly the most effective role he can play as President, as Commander-in-Chief, and certainly as leader of the party, is to go out there and do what he does best, which is to be the “explainer-in-chief” and make &#8212; and lay out the specific plans and specific ways his plans, his proposals, and the agenda of the Democratic Party, but also his administration, are going to help people across the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on these cyberattacks, the RNC was just attacked by a likely Russian actor.&nbsp; And so, considering that reining in these cyberattacks was a central focus of the Putin summit, does the President still believe that that summit was a success considering we&#8217;ve seen two new Russia-linked cyberattacks in the last week?</p>



<p>And then, coming out of this interagency meeting that just happened, can you tell us a little bit more about what went on there and if there were any sort of clear retaliatory actions that the U.S. is considering in response to these attacks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; First, on the RNC report &#8212; because I think some of the reporting got a little ahead of where the administration is and where actual attribution is.&nbsp; I&#8217;d also note that the RNC put out a statement conveying this was a third-party vendor and that none of their data was accessed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we, of course, are investigating.&nbsp; The FBI, CISA are in touch with the RNC, and when &#8212; we will determine attribution and make a decision accordingly.</p>



<p>As it relates to the meeting that the President had earlier today, he met &#8212; the President and the Vice President, I should say, met this morning with our national security team as a part of an internal update briefing on our across-whole-of-government effort to address ransomware attacks.</p>



<p>Now, I would remind all of you that ransomware attacks are not new; they long predated this administration.&nbsp; What is new is this level of engagement at the &#8212; at a high level &#8212; at the highest level, ongoing high-level engagement from our national security officials with the Russian government, and expert-level talks about the cyber and ransomware attacks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in this meeting, they provided an update on their ongoing work: surge capacity, resilience and reporting, addressing payment systems, and our ongoing efforts to combat ransomware.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We don&#8217;t have anything new to report in terms of attribution, nor do we have anything to preview in terms of operational actions or considerations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we do continue &#8212; what we did &#8212; they did discuss is the fact that the President reserves the right to respond against any ransomware networks and those that harbor them.&nbsp; That continues to be his policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what did the President mean today when he said, at departure, that he would “deliver” this message to Putin?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think the question was &#8212; I can&#8217;t remember what the context &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The question was, “What’s your message to Putin?”&nbsp; And he said, “I’ll deliver it to him.”</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think he wasn&#8217;t going to share with all of you what he just discussed in a private briefing.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the RNC asked the administration for assistance at all?&nbsp; Have you been in &#8212; has the administration &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The FBI and CISA have been in touch with the RNC, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can I ask for an update on OPEC?&nbsp; Do you have any new details about outreach from the administration &#8212; who&#8217;s been doing that?&nbsp; Do you still feel encouraged, like you did yesterday, as the talks continue to drag out?&nbsp; And just a general kind of status check on how things are going.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I certainly understand your question.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any update from yesterday.&nbsp; Just to reiterate: While we&#8217;re not a party of OPEC, we are in touch with key participants in these discussions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re encouraged that they&#8217;re continuing, but we don&#8217;t have any update on the status.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Still don&#8217;t expect the President to get involved directly at any point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any expectation of that at this point, or prediction (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I go back to cyber just for one second?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned payment systems, and I know that you’re looking into whether &#8212; you know, how to approach this &#8212; how ransoms are paid, and whether they should be paid in that entire question.&nbsp; But given the role that cryptocurrencies are playing in that, is that an area that you&#8217;re looking into for further investigations?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, that’s a part of ransom payments.&nbsp; And I should just say that part of this is there&#8217;s been ongoing work led by Deputy National Security Advisor Anne Neuberger and others across the government to consider what has long been a range of issues as it relates to ransomware attacks.&nbsp; And certainly cryptocurrency, the role of cryptocurrency, the role of payment systems is a part of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Surge capacity &#8212; the importance of partnering but also encouraging the private sector to harden their own protections &#8212; that&#8217;s all part of it.&nbsp; And this was a internal, you know, somewhat standard update, but one with an across-the-government representation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more on that.&nbsp; So, sanctions are one of the tools that you&#8217;ve used against Russia.&nbsp; You used them in response to election interference issues.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering, if this is something that we see happening with the RNC &#8212; another leg of Russia attempting to interfere in the political process here &#8212; do you still see sanctions as a viable tool for dealing with that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say, on the RNC piece, I think it&#8217;s really important to asse- &#8212; to speak to where we are in this moment, which is the RNC has put out a statement conveying this was a third-party vendor.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve said none of their data was accessed.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s not that at this point.&nbsp; We&#8217;re investigating.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll conclude the investigation and make an assessment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of operational considerations, obviously it&#8217;s not in our interest to preview those or preview our punches, as I like to say.&nbsp; The President has a range of options should he determine to take action.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Afghanistan: How is the U.S. going to continue its civilian &#8212; its civil and humanitarian support for the country if the Taliban continues its march?&nbsp; Is there a plan to work with the Taliban?&nbsp; Is there &#8212; how do you do it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, there are ongoing political negotia- &#8212;</p>



<p>(Turbulence on the plane.)</p>



<p>Ooh, okay.&nbsp; Oh, okay, let&#8217;s see how this happens here.&nbsp; Everyone is okay on the plane &#8212; happy to report &#8212; currently.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Alex has been teaching me.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve flown a little, but everyone seems fine.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Okay, sorry.&nbsp; To get back to your question: So, there are a number of efforts that will be underway; one are political negotiations.&nbsp; Certainly, the State Department would provide an update of when those will reconvene, but we certainly expect and hope and are supportive of the continuation of those political discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the reasons that the President made the decision he did is because he does not feel there&#8217;s a military solution for a 20-year war.&nbsp; Has &#8212; has long felt there was not a military solution.&nbsp; Diplomatic negotiations.</p>



<p>Two, as he reiterated when Afghan leaders were here just a couple of weeks ago, we will continue to provide, as you said, humanitarian assistance, security assistance.&nbsp; We intend to continue to have a diplomatic presence on the ground in Kabul, even after we bring the servicemen and women home at the end of August.&nbsp; So, that is a mechanism for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say, three, obviously, as you know, we&#8217;re going to continue to work with partners in the region to plan for our own CT preparations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On vaccination: Yesterday, you talked about door knocking, which is a pretty standard thing, and it was picked up in the far-right sphere as, you know, “the government is going to come to your door and make you get a vaccine.”&nbsp; I am wondering your reaction to that and what that type of messaging does for the efforts to, you know, convince people who might be hesitant to get vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I appreciate the question.&nbsp; Well, let me tell you what this is and what it is not.&nbsp; What this effort is is a continuation of what we have seen as an impactful effort that we&#8217;ve had by local public health officials and volunteers in a range of communities over the last month of action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve actually seen an impact &#8212; a positive impact of a range of steps we’ve taken in states like Florida, Mississippi, others where there have been lower vaccination rates.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been actually an increase by over 4 percent in Florida, over the last month, of adults.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;re doing is local officials are going to areas where there are lower vaccination rates and providing information on where people can get access to a vaccine, where they can go, that it&#8217;s free, that they can take time off of work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s up to individuals to decide whether they want to get vaccinated or not.</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;ve seen as a barrier all along, for months, has been access and information, and so we’re going to continue to deploy the tactic &#8212; tactics that we&#8217;ve seen effective over the last few months.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a lot of folks in the public health world have said that while they appreciate the voluntary nature, that you guys are &#8212; you know, what you just said, that it&#8217;s up to the individual to get vaccinated &#8212; they also think that the only way to get to, sort of, much larger numbers of vaccinated people is if there are mandates &#8212; whether those be mandates by private companies for their employees or universities or public schools or states that mandate for different kinds of, you know, healthcare workers or others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, when I asked you the question, you said you had no interest in the government &#8212; that the administration has no interest in encouraging that.&nbsp; I mean, is that really the position of the federal government, is that you do not want to encourage the kind of mandates that public health officials say would work?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, for clarity, that&#8217;s not currently the role of the federal government.&nbsp; And our role is to provide supply, provide information, provide public health experts.&nbsp; As &#8212; to your point, there are a number of private sector entities, universities, institutions that are starting to mandate, and that&#8217;s an innovative step that they will take and they should take.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not &#8212; and we&#8217;re not taking issue with that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But public health officials say that you guys are in a &#8212; and the President of the United States, with his bully pulpit and, you know, obviously taking not the kind of hands-off approach that Donald Trump took to federal (inaudible) &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say first &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; they want you to &#8212; they want you to be part of pushing these institutions to do that.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But, Mike, I think the important thing to remind everyone of is that, one, we have reduced the rate of COVID by 90 percent.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve reduced the death rate by 90 percent.&nbsp; Almost 70 percent of the adult population is vaccinated, and we&#8217;re continuing to press further.</p>



<p><a>There are institutions, there are private sector entities that will take this step.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not standing in their way.&nbsp; Those are innovative steps.&nbsp; Go forward and take steps that you feel are appropriate.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just talking about what the steps are, what the role is of the federal government.</a></p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You had said to me that you&#8217;re sort of trapped between &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) on the violence in Chicago?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The administration is sort of trapped between the people who are saying, “You need to do more; you need to mandate or you&#8217;re just not going to reach people,” and the people who are saying, “Oh, my God.&nbsp; The government is going to mandate this.”&nbsp; It seems like you&#8217;re kind of stuck in the middle.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; But I think what we continue to remember is what constructive role we can play as the federal government, and that includes continuing to use resources to get out into communities; to empower public health officials; to get accurate information out; to ensure people understand, as the CDC put out information earlier today or overnight, that 50 percent of the indivi- &#8212; of the cases are now, as a result of the Delta variant, higher in areas where there are lower vaccination rates.</p>



<p>That is the role where we&#8217;re going to spend our energy and our resources.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we get the White House reaction to the violence in Chicago &#8212; those three officers shot overnight, one of whom was an ATF agent?&nbsp; There&#8217;s an alderman in Chicago who is asking that the President come in the wake of what happened.&nbsp; He says, quote, “Our communities and police officers are under siege.”&nbsp; What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s message as we’re about to land there and he&#8217;s about to meet with the mayor of that city?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me first say that we are closely monitoring the situation in coordination with the Department of Justice and ATF.&nbsp; We stand ready to provide any assistance needed.&nbsp; Our thoughts go out to the two ATF agents and the Chicago Police Department officer who were wounded, as well as their families and fellow agents and officers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President has said many times, every time a law enforcement officer pins on their shield and walks out the door, they&#8217;re carrying a sacred responsibility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will note that, in terms of the efforts the President has underway to address the rise in violence we&#8217;ve seen over the last 18 months, including in Chicago, there are a number of steps that impact Chicago directly and specifically, including &#8212; his Rescue Plan is giving cities like Chicago &#8212; alone is getting almost $1.9 billion through the Rescue Plan.&nbsp; Cook County is getting over $1 billion.&nbsp; And the state government of Illinois is receiving an additional $8.13 billion.</p>



<p>As a part of our gun crime reduction strategy, Chicago is also taking part in a community violence intervention collaborative with 15 jurisdictions nationwide to help them invest in proven evidence-based, community-based strategies.</p>



<p>And Chicago is also one of the five cities we announced recently that&#8217;s going to be &#8212; we&#8217;re going to be working with &#8212; the Department of Justice is going to be working with in launching a gun trafficking strike force &#8212; there&#8217;s four other cities, I should say, nationwide &#8212; to help interrupt gun trafficking corridors that send crime into Chicago from across the city and state lines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will he visit?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Will he visit &#8212; our plans today have not changed in terms of our travel plans.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President spoken to Governor Pritzker or Mayor Lightfoot this week, following the extremely violent weekends?&nbsp; Has he &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to see both of them today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the bipartisan infrastructure plan &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; we still haven&#8217;t seen congressional scoring or legislative language, especially on the payfors.&nbsp; Is that a signal that, you know, they’re still in that, kind of, “coffee, late-night” area that you discussed before?&nbsp; Or might we a- &#8212; the alternate solution is that there&#8217;s been a problem with the scoring and it doesn&#8217;t quite add up?&nbsp; Is there a possibility that the payfors change in any way at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the order of events here, as I think you&#8217;re alluding to, is they need to write the legislation first, which they&#8217;re working on over the coming days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One on Haiti.&nbsp; I believe that you sent out a tweet &#8212; and I don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s happened in the past hour and a half, but I believe the U.S. Embassy in Haiti has not tweeted any form of tweet about what happened, and a lot of the Western embassies have.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m just checking to see if there&#8217;s any sort of, like, friction or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we put out a statement from the President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think the U.S. Embassy in Haiti should be putting out &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would ask the State Department that question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s an issue.&nbsp; We put out a statement from the President on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re about to land.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the U.S. been asked to help in Haiti?&nbsp; I mean, I know that you guys are providing whatever &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We stand prepared to assist.&nbsp; We&#8217;re certainly in touch, but obviously this is &#8212; this is still developing, and so we&#8217;ll assess what their needs are.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re ready to provide needs &#8212;&nbsp;you know, respond to the needs they ask for.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>11:31 A.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on the Visit of His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/07/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-visit-of-his-majesty-king-abdullah-ii-of-jordan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 18:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23395</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President and the First Lady look forward to welcoming His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan, Her Majesty Queen Rania, and His Royal Highness Crown Prince Hussein to the White House on July 19, 2021. His Majesty’s visit will highlight the enduring and strategic partnership between the United States and Jordan, a key security&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President and the First Lady look forward to welcoming His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan, Her Majesty Queen Rania, and His Royal Highness Crown Prince Hussein to the White House on July 19, 2021. His Majesty’s visit will highlight the enduring and strategic partnership between the United States and Jordan, a key security partner and ally of the United States. It will be an opportunity to discuss the many challenges facing the Middle East and showcase Jordan’s leadership role in promoting peace and stability in the region. President Biden looks forward to working with His Majesty to strengthen bilateral cooperation on multiple political, security, and economic issues, including the promotion of economic opportunities that will be vital for a bright future in Jordan.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
