<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 17:18:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Hong Kong’s Apple Daily</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-hong-kongs-apple-daily/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 17:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is a sad day for media freedom in Hong Kong and around the world. Intensifying repression by Beijing has reached such a level that Apple Daily, a much-needed bastion of independent journalism in Hong Kong, has now ceased publishing. Through arrests, threats, and forcing through a National Security Law that penalizes free speech, Beijing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>It is a sad day for media freedom in Hong Kong and around the world. Intensifying repression by Beijing has reached such a level that Apple Daily, a much-needed bastion of independent journalism in Hong Kong, has now ceased publishing. Through arrests, threats, and forcing through a National Security Law that penalizes free speech, Beijing has insisted on wielding its power to suppress independent media and silence dissenting views.<br> <br>Independent media play an invaluable role in resilient and prosperous societies. Journalists are truth-tellers who hold leaders accountable and keep information flowing freely—and that is needed now more than ever in Hong Kong, and in places around the world where democracy is under threat. Beijing must stop targeting the independent press and release the journalists and media executives that have been detained. The act of journalism is not a crime. <br> <br>People in Hong Kong have the right to freedom of the press. Instead, Beijing is denying basic liberties and assaulting Hong Kong’s autonomy and democratic institutions and processes, inconsistent with its international obligations. The United States will not waver in our support of people in Hong Kong and all those who stand up for the basic freedoms all people deserve.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Announces Initiatives to Promote Housing Stability By Supporting Vulnerable Tenants and Preventing Foreclosures</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initiatives-to-promote-housing-stability-by-supporting-vulnerable-tenants-and-preventing-foreclosures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 15:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Across America, a strong economic recovery is taking hold. Since President Biden took office, more than two million jobs have been created. The American Rescue Plan is working, jumpstarting the economy and getting Americans back to work. And critically, 70% of Americans ages 30 and older have received at least one dose of the COVID-19&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Across America, a strong economic recovery is taking hold. Since President Biden took office, more than two million jobs have been created. The American Rescue Plan is working, jumpstarting the economy and getting Americans back to work. And critically, 70% of Americans ages 30 and older have received at least one dose of the COVID-19 vaccine. In every state, jobs are up, the pandemic is in retreat, and American workers and families are looking ahead to a brighter future.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing a number of steps to keep people in their homes by protecting renters and homeowners who are still experiencing shocks from the pandemic and its economic fallout. Following the CDC’s decision to extend the eviction moratorium for one final month through July 31, 2021, the Administration is announcing a series of actions to help state and local governments prevent evictions. The Administration is also taking action to stabilize homeowners and support a return to a more stable housing market, including by extending the foreclosure moratorium for federally-backed mortgages by a final month, until July 31st.<br><br><strong><u>Biden-Harris Administration Actions to Help State and Local Governments Prevent Evictions</u></strong><br><br>The American Rescue Plan allocated an additional $21.5 billion for Emergency Rental Assistance (ERA) that can be used by renters to cover arrears and make landlords whole. This is on top of $25 billion allocated under the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021, bringing the total amount of ERA available to more than $46 billion and creating an economic and moral imperative for state and local governments to rise to the challenge of building a new infrastructure for getting emergency rental assistance to vulnerable renters and landlords. The Biden-Harris Administration’s&nbsp;<a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/FACT_SHEET-Emergency-Rental-Assistance-Program_May2021.pdf">May 7<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;guidance</a>&nbsp;has helped state and local governments move more funds to more renters in need. But state and local governments must do better. Money is available in every state to help renters who are behind on rent and at risk of eviction.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing a series of actions to help state and local governments prevent evictions and promote housing stability. The Administration is also calling for the acceleration of ERA funds to renters and landlords in need in addition to an all hands-on-deck effort by local governments, courts, community organizations, and the legal community to create alternatives to evictions.<br><br>Specifically, the Biden-Harris Administration is providing the following support and guidance to:<br><br><strong>Urge State and Local Courts to Participate in Eviction Diversion Efforts.</strong>&nbsp;Today, Associate Attorney General Vanita Gupta is sending a letter to state courts encouraging them to adopt anti-eviction diversion practices that will benefit families, tenants, landlords, and the courts themselves. Establishing diversion programs will help landlords and tenants reach agreement and access emergency rental assistance in addition to other available resources to keep families hard-pressed by the COVID crisis in their homes while helping make landlords whole. Avoiding legal action helps tenants and landlords avoid the costs of such action and relieves strain on the courts themselves. The Justice Department letter points to actions that courts can implement immediately to help confront this problem. The letter also directs courts to federal resources they can use to support diversion programs and to tools developed by the National Center for State Courts that can help judges ensure landlords and tenants have an opportunity to tap into available resources and mediate their dispute.<br><br><strong>Highlight that American Rescue Plan Funds for State and Local Governments and for Emergency Rental Assistance Can Be Used to Fund Eviction Diversion Plans, Including&nbsp;Counseling, Navigator, and Legal Services.</strong>&nbsp;The American Rescue Plan delivered critical and historic support to states and localities to help them address the COVID-19 public health emergency and its economic fallout. Today, the Treasury Department is making clear that states and localities, in partnership with their court systems, can tap two sources of Federal support for funding their eviction diversion efforts: the $350 billion Coronavirus State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds and billions of additional dollars available for housing stability services through the Emergency Rental Assistance Program.<br><br><strong>Convene a White House Summit for Immediate Eviction Prevention Plans.&nbsp;</strong>Effective prevention of unnecessary evictions through deployment of ERA funds requires local strategies that strongly encourage alternatives to evictions. Eviction diversion strategies, where local legal systems require landlords and tenants to seek mediation—a process that is particularly likely to be successful with the deployment of ERA funds—are among the most effective strategies for accomplishing that goal.&nbsp; The White House, in collaboration with the American Bar Association (ABA), Legal Services Corporation (LSC), and National Conference of Bar Presidents (NCBP), is convening local government, judicial, legal, and community leaders from 50 cities to develop community-specific solutions to provide vulnerable families access to counsel, divert evictions, and connect renters and landlords to available resources. Drawing on local leaders from across the court system, legal services and legal advocacy communities, philanthropy, non-profit services, and local government, the White House will support and facilitate coordination among these stakeholders in developing locally-tailored solutions that incentivize the use of emergency rental assistance and keep tenants stably housed, while also providing a model for the coordination required in communities across the country to fully address the eviction crisis.<br><br><strong>Accelerate and Broaden State and Local Delivery of Emergency Rental Assistance by Providing Clarity on Bulk Payments, Aiding Americans Experiencing Homelessness, and Overcoming Language and Disability Barriers.&nbsp;</strong>Building off the enhanced policies&nbsp;<a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/FACT_SHEET-Emergency-Rental-Assistance-Program_May2021.pdf">announced</a>&nbsp;on May 7, today, Treasury is highlighting promising practices of communities implementing effective rental assistance programs, as well as releasing new guidance to support states’ and localities’ rapid deployment of Emergency Rental Assistance to protect vulnerable families from the threat of eviction. Treasury’s guidance:</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Strongly encourages partnerships with courts to actively prevent evictions and develop eviction diversion programs.</u></strong>&nbsp;Emergency rental assistance can be used to help families at-risk of eviction remain in their homes, especially when programs work with courts to connect such families and their landlords with mediation and emergency rental assistance resources, engage providers of housing stability services for active support, and enter into agreements with courts to cover the costs of eviction diversion activities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Helps families experiencing homelessness gain access to assistance.</u></strong>&nbsp;For vulnerable families without a current rental obligation—necessary for emergency rental assistance eligibility—Treasury is creating a commitment letter process to help those families gain access to assistance. ERA can help families who have lost, or are at imminent risk of losing, their housing, to get stably housed by paying for relocation assistance, prospective rent, security deposits, and temporary hotel accommodations.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Drives towards equal access by removing language and cultural barriers in securing emergency rental assistance.</u></strong>&nbsp;Treasury is strongly encouraging grantees to provide culturally and linguistically-relevant housing stability services and to conduct outreach in multiple languages so that eligible families do not face unnecessary barriers to access. Grantees who cannot provide such services themselves should be engaging partners with the capacity to do so to ensure equal access to emergency rental assistance for all eligible households.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Provides a streamlined payment option for&nbsp;</u></strong><strong><u>utility providers and large landlords to make accessing emergency rental assistance on behalf of multiple tenants easier and more attractive.</u></strong>&nbsp;Treasury is clarifying how grantees may achieve economies of scale by obtaining information in bulk from utility providers and landlords with multiple units to help speed determination of eligibility of households and to bundle, in a single payment, approved amounts for the benefit of multiple tenants.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Pushes grantee coordination to reduce the confusion, burdens, and delays in providing assistance created by differences in locally-imposed requirements among programs operating in the same regions</u></strong>.&nbsp;Grantees providing services to overlapping or neighboring areas should collaborate to develop consistent or complementary policies to avoid unnecessary confusion or burdens for families or landlords seeking aid.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Lifts up grantees implementing effective practices to ensure that assistance quickly reaches the renters who need it most.</u></strong>&nbsp;Treasury is highlighting promising practices from the field, including successful examples of partnership with local court systems and legal services to divert evictions and prevent housing insecurity as well as programs taking advantage of options to reduce documentation barriers that keep eligible families from benefiting from ERA. This could include automating application processing and approaches for verifying income to simplify and speed eligibility determinations, such as leveraging fact-specific proxies like area median incomes.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ensure that the 30-day Eviction Notice Requirement for Federally-Backed Properties is Enforced</strong>. HUD/FHA and USDA will ensure that no landlord (public or private) whose underlying financing is backed by the federal government (e.g., HUD/FHA or USDA), purchased or securitized by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) or the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), or that is receiving assistance from the federal government may require a tenant to vacate their unit for non-payment of rent until 30 days after the landlord has provided the tenant with a notice to vacate.<br><br><strong>Make Clear the Fair Housing Act Must Be Followed.&nbsp;</strong>Evictions disproportionately affect communities of color, people with disabilities, women, and other members of protected classes. Tenants with disabilities who are facing eviction are entitled to reasonable accommodations in the eviction process. In some cases, in bringing eviction actions, housing providers may also engage in practices that violate the federal Fair Housing Act. The Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) is providing guidance to help prevent Fair Housing Act violations and collaborating with DOJ to publicize this guidance. Landlords and renters can visit hud.gov/fairhousing for details on guidance.<br><br><strong>Leverage Government Information Channels to Reach Vulnerable Tenants and Landlords:&nbsp;</strong>The administration is implementing a whole-of-government effort to raise awareness about emergency rental assistance, including tapping multiple federal agencies to take actions to inform tenants and landlords of available emergency rental assistance including:</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Publishing on Treasury’s website a list of more than 590 links to state, local and tribal government ERA programs.&nbsp;</u></strong>Treasury’s&nbsp;<a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/coronavirus/assistance-for-state-local-and-tribal-governments/emergency-rental-assistance-program/program-index">website</a>&nbsp;will also link to the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau’s (CFPB) interagency housing hub, where CFPB has published information about ERA designed to be easily accessible to consumers.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Lifting up</u></strong><strong><u>&nbsp;consumerfinance.gov/housing.</u></strong>&nbsp;The website is a one-stop, go-to resource for up-to-date information on their relief options, protections, and key deadlines for renters. Visit&nbsp;<a href="http://www.cfpb.gov/housing">cfpb.gov/housing</a>&nbsp;to learn more.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Conducting outreach to HUD grantees, HUD-assisted households, and housing providers who receive HUD assistance.</u></strong>&nbsp;HUD is working to encourage housing providers who receive HUD assistance to send information on the emergency rental assistance program in their community to tenants, ensuring HUD grantees are collaborating with the emergency rental assistance program in their community, and continuing to provide guidance that explains how the emergency rental assistance program can help HUD-assisted households.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Sharing program information with the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s SNAP beneficiaries and the Social Security Administration’s SSI recipients</u></strong><strong>.&nbsp;</strong>USDA will encourage State Departments of Social Services to share information on Treasury’s ERA and HUD’s Emergency Housing Vouchers with SNAP recipients. The Social Security Administration will support external outreach efforts by directly sharing information with SSI recipients as well as elevating awareness through their websites and social media platforms.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Conducting targeted outreach to vulnerable tenants.</u></strong>&nbsp;HUD is working closely with the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to step up outreach efforts to vulnerable tenants and inform them of federal assistance available to avoid eviction through extensive earned and paid media campaigns, close collaboration with state and local housing offices and public housing authorities, and the promotion of resources—such as toolkits and renter-oriented materials—for tenants and guidance to housing providers about eviction prevention best practices and emergency rental assistance.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Aligning philanthropic supports.</u></strong>&nbsp;Philanthropy can play a key role in supporting outreach efforts to vulnerable tenants and helping communities stand up new programs. HUD is developing a Memorandum of Understanding with Melville Charitable Trust (MCT) to build the capacity of community-based organizations, cities, states, and Tribes to administer federal relief dollars efficiently and equitably. MCT is the largest foundation in the U.S. devoted exclusively to preventing and ending homelessness. In this new collaborative partnership, MCT will coordinate the philanthropic sector to target new capacity building resources in communities disproportionately impacted by the pandemic to fill gaps in service of new federal programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Biden-Harris Administration Actions to Prevent Foreclosures</u></strong><br><br>In addition to the actions outlined to support tenants and landlords, today, the Biden-Harris Administration is also announcing efforts to support homeowners. Three federal agencies that back mortgages – the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), and Department of Agriculture (USDA) – will extend their respective foreclosure moratorium for one, final month, until July 31, 2021. The Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) will also announce that it has extended the foreclosure moratorium for mortgages backed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac until July 31, 2021.<br><br>Once the moratoria end, HUD, VA, and USDA will take additional steps to prevent foreclosures on mortgages backed by those agencies until borrowers are reviewed for COVID-19 streamlined loss mitigation options that are affordable, while FHFA will continue to work with Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to ensure that borrowers are evaluated for home retention solutions prior to any referral to foreclosure. <br><br>In addition, HUD, VA, and USDA will also continue to allow homeowners who have not taken advantage of forbearance to date to enter into COVID-related forbearance through September 30, 2021, while homeowners with Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac-backed mortgages who have COVID-related hardships will also continue to be eligible for COVID-related forbearance. Finally, HUD, VA, and USDA will be announcing additional steps in July to offer borrowers payment reduction options that will enable more homeowners to stay in their homes.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: New U.S. Government Actions on Forced Labor in Xinjiang</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-new-u-s-government-actions-on-forced-labor-in-xinjiang/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the recent G7 Summit in Cornwall, United Kingdom, the world’s leading democracies stood united against forced labor, including in Xinjiang, and committed to ensure global supply chains are free from the use of forced labor. The United States is translating these commitments into action. The Biden-Harris administration is taking additional steps to hold those&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>At the recent G7 Summit in Cornwall, United Kingdom, the world’s leading democracies stood united against forced labor, including in Xinjiang, and committed to ensure global supply chains are free from the use of forced labor. The United States is translating these commitments into action. The Biden-Harris administration is taking additional steps to hold those who engage in forced labor accountable and ensure that we continue to remove goods made with forced labor from our supply chains through actions by the Department of Homeland Security’s U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Department of Commerce, and the Department of Labor.<br><br>These actions demonstrate our commitment to imposing additional costs on the People’s Republic of China (PRC) for engaging in cruel and inhumane forced labor practices and ensuring that Beijing plays by the rules of fair trade as part of the rules-based international order. The United States believes that state-sponsored forced labor in Xinjiang is both an affront to human dignity and an example of the PRC’s unfair economic practices. The PRC’s use of forced labor in Xinjiang is an integral part of its systematic abuses against the Uyghur population and other ethnic and religious minority groups, and addressing these abuses will remain a high priority for the Biden-Harris administration. The systematic abuses go beyond forced labor to include sexual violence and large-scale forced detentions, and the PRC continues to commit genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang.<br><br>The PRC’s forced labor practices run counter to our values as a nation and expose American consumers to unethical practices. They also leave American businesses and workers to compete on an uneven playing field by allowing firms to gain advantage over their competitors by exploiting workers and artificially suppressing wages. The United States will not tolerate forced labor in our supply chains and will continue to stand up for our values and for U.S. workers and businesses. This includes maintaining support for the development of transparent and diverse clean energy supply chains at home free of forced labor — and supporting President Biden’s commitment to bold climate action, the domestic solar industry, and the jobs this vital industry creates.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) Issues Withhold Release Order (WRO): </strong>CBP has issued a WRO on silica-based products made by Hoshine Silicon Industry Co., Ltd., a company located in Xinjiang, and its subsidiaries. This WRO is based on information reasonably indicating that Hoshine used forced labor to manufacture silica-based products. As a result, personnel at all U.S. ports of entry have been instructed to immediately begin detaining shipments that contain silica-based products made by Hoshine or materials and goods derived from or produced using those silica-based products. CBP investigates allegations of forced labor in U.S. supply chains and will continue investigating allegations in the polysilicon industry and other industries in Xinjiang and elsewhere.<br><br>CBP’s forced labor investigations have produced six Withhold Release Orders in Fiscal Year 2021, including one on cotton and tomato products from the Xinjiang region, another on cotton products originating from the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps (XPCC), and one on the Dalian Ocean Fishing Co., Ltd. As demonstrated by the Dalian WRO, the United States is also taking action to combat the PRC’s use of forced labor beyond Xinjiang – including in the seafood industry. Currently, 35 of 49 active WROs are on goods from the PRC, and 11 WROs are on goods made by forced labor from Xinjiang.<br><br><strong>Department of Commerce Updates its Entity List: </strong>The Department of Commerce&#8217;s Bureau of Industry and Security added to the Entity List five PRC entities: Hoshine Silicon Industry (Shanshan); Xinjiang Daqo New Energy; Xinjiang East Hope Nonferrous Metals; Xinjiang GCL New Energy Material Technology, and XPCC— for participating in the practice of, accepting, or utilizing forced labor in Xinjiang and contributing to human rights abuses against Uyghurs and other minority groups in Xinjiang. This action, which follows the 48 PRC entities previously added to the Entity List for their connections to human rights abuses in Xinjiang, restricts the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of commodities, software, and technology subject to the Export Administration Regulations where such entities are a party to the transactions (e.g., end-user, purchaser, intermediate or ultimate consignee).<br><br><strong>Department of Labor Updates the “List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor”: </strong>The Department of Labor has published a Federal Register Notice updating its “List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor,” to include polysilicon produced with forced labor in the PRC. Every two years, the Department of Labor publishes an updated list of goods produced by child labor or forced labor in violation of international standards. This update is the first time a good has been added outside of that two-year cycle, highlighting its strong response to the severity of the ongoing human rights abuses against Uyghurs and other minority groups in Xinjiang. The report currently includes other products from the PRC that have links to forced labor in Xinjiang or by Uyghur workers transferred to other parts of the PRC, including cotton, garments, footwear, electronics, gloves, hair products, textiles, thread/yarn, and tomato products.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Meeting with Speaker Pelosi and Leader Schumer</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/readout-of-meeting-with-speaker-pelosi-and-leader-schumer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 02:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Speaker Pelosi and Leader Schumer met with Office of Management Budget Acting Director Shalanda Young, National Economic Council Director Brian Deese, and Domestic Policy Council Director Susan Rice to discuss the President’s legislative priorities, including the American Jobs Plan and the American Families Plan. They agreed that Congress must meet the President’s goal of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Speaker Pelosi and Leader Schumer met with Office of Management Budget Acting Director Shalanda Young, National Economic Council Director Brian Deese, and Domestic Policy Council Director Susan Rice to discuss the President’s legislative priorities, including the American Jobs Plan and the American Families Plan. They agreed that Congress must meet the President’s goal of investing in creating a generation of good paying jobs, addressing the climate crisis, and ensuring American workers and businesses can compete globally, while not raising taxes on anyone who makes under $400,000. They underscored the importance of extending the child tax credit, and investing in the care economy, including expanding child care, to help ensure that women can return to the workforce. They discussed the&nbsp;two-track&nbsp;approach, and the importance of a budget resolution to meeting the full range of the President’s priorities.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and Attorney General Garland on Gun Crime Prevention Strategy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/23/remarks-by-president-biden-and-attorney-general-garland-on-gun-crime-prevention-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 4:55 P.M. EDT&#160;ATTORNEY GENERAL GARLAND: Good afternoon, Mr. President. It’s good to be here with you, and with local elected and community leaders, and with representatives of law enforcement.&#160;Protecting our communities from violent crime is a top priority for the Department of Justice and one of our most important responsibilities.&#160;I&#8217;m glad the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>4:55 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>ATTORNEY GENERAL GARLAND: Good afternoon, Mr. President. It’s good to be here with you, and with local elected and community leaders, and with representatives of law enforcement.<br>&nbsp;<br>Protecting our communities from violent crime is a top priority for the Department of Justice and one of our most important responsibilities.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m glad the President brought us together today to discuss a subject of such importance to the public we serve. As our participants in today&#8217;s roundtable have noted, the increase in violent crime in 2020 and early 2021 is deeply troubling.<br>&nbsp;<br>That is why, last month, the Justice Department launched a comprehensive violent crime reduction strategy. This strategy is built around four principles: setting strategic enforcement priorities; fostering trust with and earning legitimacy in our communities; investing in community-based prevention and intervention programs; and measuring the results of these efforts through a decrease in violent crime, not merely by arrests and convictions, as if they were ends in themselves.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, we know that the lion&#8217;s share of violent crime reduction work is shouldered by our state, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement partners. Core to our strategy is targeted support of the critical work that you will be doing in the weeks and months ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Every one of our U.S. attorney&#8217;s offices is working with its local partners to establish an immediate plan to address the spike in violent crime that typically occurs during the summer. And the law enforcement components of the Department are making enhanced resources available to help prevent and disrupt violent crime, and to focus on the most dangerous, most violent offenders.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Department is also strengthening our Project Safe Neighborhoods &#8212; our cornerstone initiative that brings together law enforcement and community stakeholders to develop solutions to pressing violent crime problems.<br>&nbsp;<br>Community-led efforts are vital to preventing violence before it occurs. The Justice Department has available over $1 billion in funding through over a dozen grant programs that can be used to support evidence-based, community violence intervention strategies.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to say that&#8217;s what I found particularly useful in our discussion just a few minutes ago &#8212; was the fact that there are such evidence-based programs available. And I&#8217;m hoping that you will get together with us so that we can spread those across the country &#8212; as well, of course, funding your own.<br>&nbsp;<br>A properly functioning criminal justice system is essential to our efforts, as well. The Department has grant funding available to help cities resume court operations and services that were curtailed during the COVID-19 pandemic. That includes funding for technology and equipment for courts to address the backlog of cases and enhance access to justice.<br>&nbsp;<br>We know that an effective violent crime reduction strategy must also address the illegal trafficking of firearms and focus on keeping guns out of the wrong hands. And so the Department is delivering on the promises we made here at the White House in April.<br>&nbsp;<br>On May 7th, we issued a proposed rule to help address the proliferation of ghost guns. On June 7th, we issued a proposed rule to clarify that pistols equipped with certain stabilizing braces are subject to the same statutory restrictions as easily concealable, short-barreled rifles. And on the same day, the Department published model Extreme Risk Protection Order legislation for states to consider as they craft their own laws to reduce gun violence.</p>



<p>We are now taking further steps. First, we will hold gun dealers that break the rules accountable for their actions. Most federally licensed firearms dealers operate legally in selling guns to individuals who have passed background checks. But those dealers that willfully violate the law increase the risk that guns will fall into the wrong hands.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Absent extraordinary circumstances, ATF will initiate proceedings to revoke the licenses of dealers that willfully violate the law by failing to conduct required background checks, falsifying records, failing to respond to trace requests, refusing to permit ATF to conduct inspections, or transferring firearms to persons who are prohibited from owning them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, we are seeking funding to increase ATF&#8217;s dealer inspection capacity and improve its effectiveness. ATF has very limited inspection resources. The President&#8217;s Fiscal 2022 Budget requests resources to add inspection positions in every field division. The effectiveness of the enforcement program depends on the ability to identify and focus on those dealers that pose the greatest risk to public safety.<br>&nbsp;<br>Starting today, ATF will make clear to investigators in every field division that, as they prioritize inspections, they must consider the extent to which firearms sold by a dealer are later used in criminal activity.<br>&nbsp;<br>Third, we will improve information sharing with state, local, Tribal, and territorial partners to help bring more intelligence and law enforcement resources to bear &#8212; as well as with the public, to increase our own accountability.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, ATF has a point of contact in every field division to receive information from mayors, police chiefs, and other local leaders about firearms dealers they believe are acting unlawfully.<br>&nbsp;<br>And starting next month, ATA &#8212; ATF will begin sharing inspection data with the 16 states that license or regulate firearms dealers themselves.<br>&nbsp;<br>Also beginning next month, ATF will publicly post information about inspection frequency and outcomes disaggregated by field division, providing for enhanced transparency and accountability.<br>&nbsp;<br>Fourth, we are launching a concerted effort to crack down on gun traffickers. Yesterday, the Department announced that it will establish five new cross-jurisdictional law enforcement strike forces within the next 30 days. The strike forces will focus on addressing significant firearms trafficking corridors that fuel violence in New York, Chicago, Los Angeles, the San Francisco Bay Area, and Washington, D.C., as well as in cities and towns along the way.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Justice Department&#8217;s violent crime reduction strategy and our initiatives to stem the rising tide of illegal &#8212; illegal guns will save lives. But these steps alone will not solve the problem of violent crime. Success depends on all of us joining together: those of you in this room, the many like you across the country who are working to keep their communities safe, and the people of our communities themselves.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would now like to introduce President Biden, who has emphasized the importance of this issue and who has my gratitude for gathering us together today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: Thank you, General. Let me &#8212; before I begin, thank the participants in our roundtable today: two mayors &#8212; three mayors, chiefs of police, attorneys general, and community organizers who have been doing significant work in bringing down violent crime in their communities. There is no one &#8212; one answer that fits everything. And it&#8217;s about being engaged and multiple organizations being engaged.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I want to thank you for the time you spent with us today. And I warned you: I&#8217;m coming back at you again for more information. (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And we just met, as a I said, with a bipartisan group of mayors, law enforcement, and community leaders. And we discussed a comprehensive strategy that I&#8217;m releasing today to combat the epidemic of gun violence and other violent crime that we’ve been seeing in our country for far too long, that has spiked since the start of the pandemic over a year ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>Crime has &#8212; historically rises during the summer. And as we emerge from this pandemic with the country opening back up again, the traditional summer&#8217;s &#8212; summer spike may even be more pronounced than it usually would be.<br>&nbsp;<br>For folks at home, here’s what you need to know: I’ve been at this a long time and there are things we know that work that reduce gun violence and violent crime, and things that we don’t know about. But things we know about: Background checks for purchasing a firearm are important; a ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazines &#8212; no one needs to have a weapon that can fire over 30, 40, 50, even up to 100 rounds unless you think the deer are wearing Kevlar vests or something; community policing and programs that keep neighborhoods safe and keep folks out of trouble.<br>&nbsp;<br>These efforts worked. They saved lives. But over time, these policies were gutted and were woefully underfunded.<br>&nbsp;<br>In our conversation today, we talked about our strategy to supercharge what works while we continue to push the Congress to act on sensible gun violence legislation.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, we discussed cracking down, as you heard from the Attorney General, on rogue gun dealers. We know that if there is a strict enforcement of background checks, then fewer guns get into the hands of criminals. Background checks have thus far kept more than 3 million guns out of the hands of felons &#8212; convicted felons, fugitives, domestic abusers, and others prohibited from being able to purchase a gun. And there are still too many loopholes in that system.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, today, enough rogue gun dealers feel like they can get away with selling guns to people who aren’t legally allowed to own them.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I might add: The Second Amendment, from the day it was passed, limited the type of people who could own a gun and what type of weapon you could own. You couldn’t buy a cannon.<br>&nbsp;<br>Those who say the blood of lib- &#8212; &#8220;the blood of patriots,&#8221; you know, and all the stuff about how we&#8217;re going to have to move against the government. Well, the tree of liberty is not watered with the blood of patriots. What&#8217;s happened is that there have never been &#8212; if you wanted or if you think you need to have weapons to take on the government, you need F-15s and maybe some nuclear weapons.<br>&nbsp;<br>The point is that there has always been the ability to limit &#8212; rationally limit the type of weapon that can be owned and who can own it.<br>&nbsp;<br>The last time we had data on this issue of who is purchasing guns was more than 20 years ago. Five percent of gun dealers &#8212; it turns out, in the study we did &#8212; showed that 90 percent of illegal guns were found at the crime scenes sold by 5 percent of gun dealers. Five percent sold 90 percent of the guns found at crime scenes.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the &#8212; these merchants of death are breaking the law for profit. They&#8217;re selling guns that are killing innocent people. It’s wrong. It’s unacceptable. And as the Attorney General said, we&#8217;re going to crack down on those gun dealers and the violent criminals they knowingly arm.<br>&nbsp;<br>In April, I announced that the Justice Department is going to be issuing an annual report on gun trafficking so we can update that data.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, the Department is announcing, as I just did, a major crackdown on &#8212; to stem the flow of guns used to commit violent crimes. It’s zero tolerance for gun dealers who willfully violate key existing laws and regulations. Let me repeat: zero tolerance.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you willfully sell a gun to someone who is prohibited from possessing it, if you willfully fail to run a background check, if you willfully falsify a record, if you willfully fail to cooperate with the tracing requests or inspections, my message to you is this: We&#8217;ll find you, and we will seek your license to sell guns. We&#8217;ll make sure you can&#8217;t sell death and mayhem on our streets. It’s an outrage. It has to end, and we&#8217;ll end it. Period.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, we discussed disrupting illegal gun trafficking. Now, the gun lobby wants you to believe that cities that are the toughest gun &#8212; have the toughest gun laws still have the highest rates of gun violence, as was pointed out by the group we had today in our roundtable. They &#8212; the violence is so &#8212; they argue, &#8220;Why do you need those gun laws if they don’t work in cities that have tough laws?&#8221; Don’t believe it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Here&#8217;s the truth: Today’s conversation with Mayor Scott of Baltimore, for example, echoed what we know to be the case, and you hear it from mayors across the country. Mayors have the power to help shape and enforce the laws in their cities, but they can’t control the laws in neighboring cities and states, even though the gun legally bought there is &#8212; often ends up in their streets.<br>&nbsp;<br>Mayor Scott says that 80 percent of the guns in Baltimore were acquired outside the city &#8212; outside the city. There’s little he can do about that, so we have to act. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of our strategy, the Justice Department is creating five new strike forces to crack down on illegal gun trafficking in the corridors supplying weapons to cities like New York; Chicago; Los Angeles; Washington, D.C.; and the Bay Area. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>With these strike forces, local and federal law enforcement and prosecutors are going to be able to better coordinate the prosecution of illegal gun trafficking across city and state lines, so illegal guns sold from the back door of a gun shop in Virginia don’t end up at a murder scene in Baltimore. And if they do, then local and federal law enforcement can better coordinate to trace illegal gun sales back to the shady gun dealer and hold them accountable. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Police Chief Murray of the Baltimore [sic] &#8212; excuse me, Police Chief Merritt [sic] &#8212; Police Chief Murphy Paul of Baton Rouge, Louisiana, talked about how he’s coordinating more closely with the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms; the ATF; and the Federal Bureau of Investigation &#8212; the FBI &#8212; to help take on criminal organizations committing violent crimes in the city.<br>&nbsp;<br>This kind of coordination is essential to keeping the weapons of war out of the hands of dangerous criminals, fugitives, and gangs, as well as organized crime.<br>&nbsp;<br>Third, we discussed historic funding &#8212; we discussed historic funding for states, cities, and counties, and Tribes for law enforcement and crime prevention. You know, they&#8217;ve not only had to fight this pandemic, they&#8217;ve also had to deal with economic crisis that has decimated their budgets &#8212; forced them to cut essential services, including law enforcement and social services.<br>&nbsp;<br>And amid the COVID-19 pandemic, they&#8217;ve had to deal with a second public health crisis: gun violence. The American Rescue Plan, which we passed in the first 100 days of my administration, is providing much-needed, historic relief to bring back those law enforcement jobs and social service jobs. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Much of this relief has already arrived. The rest is on its way. And we&#8217;re now providing more guidance on how they can use the $350 billion nationally that the American Rescue Plan has available to help reduce crime and address the root causes. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, cities experiencing an increase in gun violence were able to use the American Rescue Plan dollars to hire police officers needed for community policing and to pay their overtime. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Mayors will also be able to buy crime-fighting technologies, like gunshot detection systems, to better see and stop gun violence in their communities. &nbsp;They can use the funding to scale up wraparound services for the residents as well, including substance abuse and mental health services that we know will make a difference in prevention of crime. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here&#8217;s another example that reminds me of the old saying my mom used to use. She’d say, “An idle mind is the devil&#8217;s workshop.” Well, school&#8217;s out for the summer. Teenagers are in tough neighborhoods, no &#8212; who are in tough neighborhoods &#8212; no jobs, more trouble. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We know summer job training &#8212; summer jobs, training, and recreation for young people work. They help make sure young people pick up a paycheck instead of a pistol. One study found a Boston summer jobs program for youth reduction reduced violent crimes by 35 percent in Boston.<br>&nbsp;<br>Another study found that a program that offers high school students in Chicago a good summer job and an adult mentor and behavioral therapy led to a 45 percent drop in violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>We can invest in more of these programs with the American Rescue Plan. And here’s another thing states, cities, counties, and Tribes can do with that funding: When someone finishes their time in prison, they can&#8217;t just give them &#8212; we can’t just continue to give them 25 bucks and a bus ticket. They end up right back where they started and got them in trouble in the first place &#8212; or no option for being able to provide for access to public housing or for schools or for &#8212; for mentors to help them find their way, and the stuff that prevents recidivism and helps them integrate in a society. That&#8217;s changing with guidance we’re issuing today.<br>&nbsp;<br>The American Rescue Plan funding can help formerly incarcerated people get skills training, apprenticeships, and work experience so they can gain stability and security and a chance for a better life, rather than going back to exactly what they left. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Attorney General Greenwald of New Jersey and Mayor Daniel- &#8212; and Mayor Daniella Levine Cava of Miami-Dade talked about their efforts to lift up those kinds of communit&#8211; their &#8212; the kinds of community programs that reduce gun violence, keep communities safe, and make real, positive difference in people&#8217;s lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>And for folks at home, the American Rescue Plan, which is a once-in-a-generation investment to reduce violence in America, is available. I&#8217;m proud of it. It means more police officers, more nurses, more counselors, more social workers, more community violence interrupters to help resolve issues before they escalate into crimes.<br>&nbsp;<br>It means we go after the people who flood our streets with guns and the bad actors who decide to use them to further terrorize the communities. &nbsp;It means saving lives. And Congress should in no way take away this funding. It’s already been appropriated. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, a few weeks ago, the bipartisan United States Conference of Mayors, the National League of Cities, National Association of Counties &#8212; they all came out forcefully against efforts to reclaim American Rescue Plan funds that have already been allocated to the state, cities, and counties, and Tribes. &nbsp;This is not a time to turn our backs on law enforcement or our communities. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Fourth, we discussed the need to support community violence intervention. &nbsp;These are local programs that utilize trusted messengers and community members and leaders to work directly with people who are most likely to commit gun crimes or become victims of gun crimes. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We know who they are. They intervene before it&#8217;s too late &#8212; these &#8212; these interrupters &#8212; turn down the temperature, halt the cycle of retaliation, connect people to social services. &nbsp;And it works. Community violence intervention programs have shown a reduction in violence of up to 60 percent in many places. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We heard from two community leaders that do this work. Eddie, thank you for coming from Chicago to &#8212; you&#8217;re really &#8212; quite frankly, it was impressive &#8212; your presentation. &nbsp;And &#8212; and DeVone Boggan from Richmond, California. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Eddie was formerly incarcerated for gun homicide, and DeVone lost his brother to gun violence. And Eddie worked as a violence interrupter. &nbsp;Now he runs a program that provides high-risk men with cognitive behavioral &#8212; cognitive behavioral therapy to help them react to the impulses by slowing down rather than following through on the violence. &nbsp;It puts them in &#8212; he &#8212; puts them in paid jobs to change their trajectory. &nbsp;The program has reduced sh- &#8212; has reduced shootings by 40 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>DeVone runs a program across California and six other states that enroll high-risk individuals in peace fellowships, complete with intensive mentoring and social services. It’s saving lives. In Sacramento, for example, 91 percent of participants stayed away from gun violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>States and cities should invest the American Rescue Plan funds in those kinds of anti-violent crime programs. And today, I’m announcing that the White House will be working with 15 jurisdictions that are doing exactly that &#8212; from Baltimore to Baton Rouge, and Memphis to Minneapolis &#8212; to build up their community violence intervention programs, starting this summer.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Mayor Steve Allender of Rapid City, South Dakota &#8212; a Republican and a former chief of police himself &#8212; joined us today and will be a part of this effort to help disrupt cycles of crime and violence in his community and nearby Tribal communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>We need more mayors to follow and I&#8217;m going to be pushing to keep &#8212; pushing for more of these proven programs, which are part of the American Jobs Plan and my budget.<br>&nbsp;<br>Fifth, and I’ll close with this: We talked about the lives we lost &#8212; have already been lost and the lives that we can save. We talked about how much pain and loss so many people have experienced and so many people have now accepted as their fate here in America. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have an opportunity to come together now &#8212; as Democrats and Republicans, as fellow Americans &#8212; to fulfill the first responsibility of government and our democracy: to keep each other safe. Enough.<br>&nbsp;<br>That means Congress passing sensible gun prevention, violence prevention initiatives is warra- &#8212; is &#8212; makes sense: background checks, ban on assault weapons, repeal of the liability shield for gun manufacturers.<br>&nbsp;<br>It means the Senate reauthorizing the Violence Against Women Act &#8212; my proudest legislative accomplishment &#8212; to close the so-called &#8220;boyfriend loophole&#8221; &#8212; its &#8220;boyfriend and stalking loophole&#8221; &#8212; to keep guns out of the hands of abusers. We added the provision saying, &#8220;If you have a stay-away order &#8212; you are stalking someone and you&#8217;re told that has to stop &#8212; you can&#8217;t own a weapon.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>Every single month, an average of 57 women are shot and killed by an intimate partner. We can help stop that.<br>&nbsp;<br>It means confirming my outstanding nominee for &#8212; to lead the AFT &#8212; excuse me, the ATF: David Chipman. It&#8217;s been without a leader for a while. The top job has been un- &#8212; unconfirmed for much too long. A career and distinguished ATF official for 25 years, David is eminently qualified for the job that we desperately need to fill.<br>&nbsp;<br>As Vice President, I pushed hard to lift the freeze on gun violence research at the C- &#8212; the Center for Disease Control, the CDC. Guess what? Why should they not be able to study gun violence and what causes it? But there&#8217;s been a block on it. I want to unfreeze that.<br>&nbsp;<br>As President, my budget doubles funding for the gun violence research at the CDC and the National Institutes of Health &#8212; the NIH &#8212; to study gun violence as a public health threat that it is.<br>&nbsp;<br>And while we keep pushing there, Vice President Harris and I also &#8212; and our entire administration are continuing to be &#8212; will continue taking action where we can. Let&#8217;s stop the proliferation of ghost guns, as we announced back in April with the Attorney General.<br>&nbsp;<br>We need to support the development of smart gun technologies. This doesn’t affect responsible gun owners or Second Amendment rights. It helps keep guns out of the hands of people who shouldn’t have them in the first place, from a child who accidentally picks up a &#8212; picks it up, to a burglar or violent criminal trying to steal it and use it.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we need to keep building on the gun violence and crime-prevention strategy we&#8217;re laying out today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, this shouldn’t be a red or blue issue; it’s an American issue. We’re not changing the Constitution; we&#8217;re enforcing it &#8212; being reasonable. We’re taking on the bad actors doing bad and dangerous things to our communities and to our country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Talk to most responsible gun owners and hunters. They’ll tell you there’s no possible justification for having 100 rounds in a magazine of a gun. Like I’ve said before: What do you think, the deer are wearing Kevlar vests?<br>&nbsp;<br>Responsible gun owners will tell you that there are too many people today who are able to buy a gun but shouldn’t be able to buy a gun.<br>&nbsp;<br>And these kinds of reasonable reforms have overwhelming support from the American people, including gun owners.<br>&nbsp;<br>The bottom line is this: Let&#8217;s show the world and show ourselves that democracy works and that we can come together as one nation. We can do this and save lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you. God bless you all. And may God protect our troops.<br>&nbsp;<br>And again, I thank you all for participating. But the bad news for you all is, I&#8217;m coming back. I need your continued help. So, thank you very, very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, General, thank you. Appreciate it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Mr. President, are you still holding out hope that Congress can pass another assault weapons ban?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: I never give up hope.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; How do you feel about the bipartisan infrastructure deal that&#8217;s been released?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: I&#8217;ll tell you that when I get the final numbers tonight.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Mr. President, what do you feel is the most effective thing that government can do to change the mindset of those who feel compelled to pull the triggers of these guns?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: By being engaged in a whole range of programs. We talked today &#8212; everything from mental health programs to engaging people early on and letting them know there is other options. Making sure that when a child is young, they have access to a real education, and they get started off on the right foot.<br>&nbsp;<br>Making sure that when someone gets out of prison, they&#8217;re not denied public housing, they don&#8217;t have to go back under the bridge where they were living before &#8212; that they&#8217;re able to get help for healthcare, et cetera, and reengaging them in the neighborhood, giving them some hope, some opportunity. And in the meantime, making sure that those folks who are taking advantage of them by taking advantage of their &#8212; their situation are, in fact, held accountable.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you all so much.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Once you take care of the voting rights bill, do you think it&#8217;s time to reform the filibuster?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: I think it&#8217;s time to pass the voting rights bill.<br>&nbsp;<br>5:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Lieutenant General Aviv Kohavi, Chief of the General Staff of the Israel Defense Forces</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-lieutenant-general-aviv-kohavi-chief-of-the-general-staff-of-the-israel-defense-forces/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Lieutenant General Aviv Kohavi, Chief of the General Staff of the Israel Defense Forces (IDF). Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s security and commitment to continuing to strengthen the defense partnership between the two countries. The officials discussed the challenges to security&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Lieutenant General Aviv Kohavi, Chief of the General Staff of the Israel Defense Forces (IDF). Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s security and commitment to continuing to strengthen the defense partnership between the two countries. The officials discussed the challenges to security and stability in the Middle East, including the threat posed by Iran’s malign activities in the region, and Mr. Sullivan affirmed the President’s commitment to ensuring that Iran never gets a nuclear weapon. The officials agreed on the importance of continuing and expanding bilateral consultations on the array of strategic challenges facing the region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on Infrastructure Negotiations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-infrastructure-negotiations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 23:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[White House senior staff had two productive meetings today with the bipartisan group of Senators who have been negotiating about infrastructure. The group made progress towards an outline of a potential agreement, and the President has invited the group to come to the White House tomorrow to discuss this in person. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>White House senior staff had two productive meetings today with the bipartisan group of Senators who have been negotiating about infrastructure. The group made progress towards an outline of a potential agreement, and the President has invited the group to come to the White House tomorrow to discuss this in person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, June 23, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/23/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-june-23-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:23 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI: Hi, everyone. Okay, just a couple of items for you at the top. President Biden believes that the surge in gun violence and violent crime that has affected communities across the country over the last year and a half is unacceptable. That&#8217;s why his&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:23 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Hi, everyone. Okay, just a couple of items for you at the top. President Biden believes that the surge in gun violence and violent crime that has affected communities across the country over the last year and a half is unacceptable. That&#8217;s why his administration is moving decisively to act with a whole-of-government approach.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris administration is announcing a comprehensive strategy to combat violent crime and gun violence that targets the crime itself, implements preventative measures that are proven to reduce violent crime, and attacks root causes, including by addressing the flow of firearms used to commit crimes.<br><br>Combined, this plan will stem the flow of firearms used to commit violence, including by holding rogue firearm dealers accountable for violating federal laws; support local law enforcement with federal tools and resources to help address violent crime; invest in evidence-based community violence interventions; expand summer programming, employment opportunities, and other services and support for teenagers and young adults; and help formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter their communities.<br><br>One of the key elements of this strategy is helping state and local governments fight gun violence and violent crime in their communities through the historic funding levels in the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>Today&#8217;s strategy builds on that by providing further guidance for states and cities to expand their ability to improve public safety in their communities. And we&#8217;ve already seen examples of what is happening around the country. In Philadelphia, Mayor Kenney is using funding from ARP to address gun violence, reform and improve the police department, and invest in violent interruption programs.<br><br>In Albuquerque, Mayor Keller plans to spend $3 million to expand the city&#8217;s gunshot detection system, and millions more to recruit police officers and refurbish station houses.<br><br>In Akron, Ohio, Mayor Horrigan has proposed $20 million to reduce community and youth violence through employment training and opportunities, as well as recreation assets.<br><br>I&#8217;d also note, today &#8212; and obviously the President will speak to all of this later this afternoon &#8212; today, the Vice President will hold a listening session with leading civil rights and voting rights groups from across the country following the Senate vote on the For the People Act just yesterday.<br><br>The meeting builds on the Vice President&#8217;s work to bring together a national coalition on voting rights to promote voter registration and engagement &#8212; engagement among Americans across the country &#8212; from Greenville, South Carolina, to Atlanta, Georgia &#8212; to protect our fundamental right to vote.<br><br>She will drive the message that the fight is not over and that the President and the administration remain committed to ensuring that all Americans have access to the ballot.<br><br>Finally &#8212; I do have one more thing &#8212; tomorrow, the President will travel to Raleigh, North Carolina &#8212; some of you may be on that trip &#8212; as our administration continues to work to continue encouraging vaccinations across the country, ensuring every American knows just how to ensure it is easy to get vaccinated.<br><br>While he&#8217;s there, he will highlight the importance of getting vaccinated and kick off a community canvassing event at the Green Road Park Community Center in Raleigh.<br><br>He will also tour a mobile vaccination unit and meet with frontline workers and grassroots volunteers who are the boots on the ground working to get people in their communities vaccinated.<br><br>Alex, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?<br><br>Q &nbsp;Thanks, Jen. First off, the Vice President&#8217;s office just announced that she will be visiting the border Friday. What can you tell us about the visit? And you have, in the past, defended the decision not to visit the border by anyone, really, in the &#8212; by President Biden or Vice President Harris. So what’s behind the, sort of, change of course?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Sure. First, I think many of you may have seen it, but just to reiterate the specific details &#8212; the Vice President will travel to El Paso, Texas, on Friday. She will be accompanied by Department of Homeland Security Secretary Ali Mayorkas.<br><br>Earlier this year, as you all know, the President asked the Vice President to oversee our diplomatic efforts to address the root causes of migration from El Salvador to Guatemala and Honduras. And, as a part of this work, she recently traveled to Guatemala and Mexico last month to have those discussions. And this trip to the border on Friday will be a part of this effort.<br><br>I will note that I&#8217;ve also said here, from this podium &#8212; and she has also said &#8212; that when it was the right time, she may go to visit the border. And so, this trip on Friday, which is being done in coordination with the Department of Homeland Security &#8212; Secretary Mayorkas is, of course, joining her on this trip, you know, and the planning and timing of it was done in coordination with them &#8212; is &#8212; is part of the coordinated effort between her office, her work, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Health and Human Services to continue to address the root causes and work in coordination to get the situation under control.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Sure. And then on voting rights: The President’s statement yesterday said he&#8217;ll have more to say on this next week.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of what we should expect from the President on voting rights? And you also have said that there are other avenues for protecting voting rights. What do those look like?<br><br>Then I&#8217;m going to take another stab at this &#8212; I know you&#8217;ve been asked this five different ways, but &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; does the President believe that the filibuster is &#8212; defending the filibuster is worth more. and more important than protecting voting rights?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, let me say &#8212; as the Vice President said yesterday and I&#8217;ll just reiterate &#8212; the fight to improve and expand access to voting is far from over. And the President, as he noted in his statement yesterday and as you just touched on, will be speaking to this next week. And this is a continuation of his efforts to use the bully pulpit to elevate this issue, as he did just last week when he marked Juneteenth, and also as he did in Tulsa, Oklahoma, just a few weeks before that.<br><br>So I expect you &#8212; we’ll have more to preview as we get closer. But I can tell you that what you should expect to hear from him is that there are many ways to work across the country &#8212; with activists, with states, with legislators &#8212; using every lever at our disposal to expand access, improve access to voting for people across the country.<br><br>He&#8217;ll talk about some of the ways that he wants to continue to do that. He&#8217;ll also reiterate his view that it&#8217;s a fundamental right and that people across the country should be able to exercise that to decide who they want to be their mayor, who they want to be their congressman, who they want to be their President. And everybody who supports democracy, who supports equality, who supports justice should be supporting improvements to our voting rights laws.<br><br>Q&nbsp; And one more last one on this conversation around crime.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp; How should the American people measure success for President Biden on crime? Should they be looking for a reduction in crime in their localities? Or, I mean, what exactly is he aiming for in announcing these new policies today?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, that certainly is the goal, of course. But I would say, Alex, that what the President has watched closely is that there has been, of course, an increase in violent crime &#8212; gun violence, specifically, in a lot of communities &#8212; over the last 18 months.<br><br>He&#8217;s obviously taken a number of steps over the past couple of months to work to address that. This is a continuation of that in his view. And part of that is empowering local police communities and making sure that local communities have the funding they need to &#8212; to support efforts by the local police. It also means taking steps to address the prevalence of gun violence across the country.<br><br>So, of course, his objective is to take steps &#8212; steps he can do, as the President of the United States, using the tools he has at his disposal &#8212; to empower local communities, get them the resources they need, and ensure we&#8217;re putting laws in place that reduce gun violence.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. Can you tell us a little bit more about what the Vice President will be doing at the border? Is she visiting a detention center or a facility for migrant children? And how much access will the press have to whatever sites she tours while she’s there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: They&#8217;re all great questions. Obviously, they just made this announcement. I&#8217;m sure they will have more details to share with you. I just don&#8217;t have any more to share with you at this particular moment on what she&#8217;ll be doing specifically there.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Okay. And then can you tell us a little bit more about this decision for the U.S. to seize website domains used by Iranian state TV? What led to that decision and why now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: It&#8217;s a Department of Justice decision and action, so I would point you to them.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Is there any concern that this could hamper negotiations over Iran&#8217;s nuclear program?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: We are still at the point in those discussions &#8212; we just finished the sixth round. Obviously, all of the negotiators are back in their capitals, having discussions, as is appropriate.<br><br>We see advantage to us in moving toward a diplomatic solution. We hope others who have seats at the table do as well. But, again, this was an action by the Department of Justice, not &#8212; not coordinated with other aspects of our negotiations.<br><br>Q&nbsp; And then what can you tell us about the talks that took place on the Hill yesterday over the bipartisan infrastructure proposal? Were those fruitful discussions? And where does that go from here? Is the President going to be hosting any of those senators here at the White House in the coming days?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: If we continue to make progress in these discussions, then the President looks forward to welcoming members to the White House before the end of the week. We&#8217;ll see.<br><br>There were a couple rounds &#8212; there were two rounds of discussions yesterday. And I know you&#8217;re all aware of this &#8212; or many of you who cover this closely &#8212; but there was one in the afternoon; there was another one last night. Additional progress was made last night.<br><br>This afternoon, Steve Ricchetti, Louisa Terrell, Brian Deese are all back up on the Hill right about now having continued discussions about the path forward. That&#8217;s one track where we are moving forward on these bipartisan negotiations. And we assess, as we conclude each round, what the next step should be.<br><br>So, again, if we make progress and if we assess that &#8212; that it is the appropriate time to bring these officials &#8212; these elected officials to the White House, the President looks forward to doing that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Thank you, Jen. So, about today&#8217;s announcement: Why is the Vice President visiting the border this week when, earlier this month, she dismissed a trip like that, saying it would be a “grand gesture”?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: She also said in an interview with NBC that she would be open to going to the border if it was an appropriate time. She said that after she said that, so that&#8217;s important context as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Okay. And, important context: I&#8217;ve got the NBC interview right here. She was talking about how she hasn&#8217;t been to the border; she hasn&#8217;t been to Europe either. So, does she think that these two things are the same?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: And, again, Peter, I think she also said in the same interview that she would be open to going to the border at an appropriate time. And what I&#8217;m conveying to you is that, while, as a part of her assignment, she has, of course, hosted a number of bilateral engagements &#8212; she&#8217;s visited the Northern Triangle; she&#8217;s taken &#8212; made a number of announcements about how to address root causes &#8212; that she&#8217;s going &#8212; was going to assess, with the Department of Homeland Security and with the administration, when it was the appropriate time to go.<br><br>And I will note that we&#8217;re at this point in part because we&#8217;ve made a great deal of progress. And if you look just to a couple of months ago, when 6,000 children were in Border Patrol facilities, we&#8217;re now at the point where there&#8217;s far less than 1,000.<br><br>If you look to just a couple of months ago, when there were children who were waiting in Border Patrol facilities for more than 100 hours &#8212; and they were certainly overcrowded &#8212; now it&#8217;s less than 30 hours.<br><br>In April, there were 22,000 kids in HHS facilities, and now that number is 14,000.<br><br>Is there still more work to do? &nbsp;Absolutely. That&#8217;s the purview of Secretary Mayorkas. But it&#8217;s important every component of our government is coordinated.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Was it important for the White House to have her seen at the border before former President Trump has a trip there next week?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: We made an assessment within our government about when it was an appropriate time for her to go to the border.<br><br>Q&nbsp; And then just one about the crime today. You mentioned expanding &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: The crime prevention roll out.<br><br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; crime prevention, yes. (Laughter.) Not the crime. But there is a lot of crime in big cities. How do you reduce &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Much of it caused by gun violence, would you agree?<br><br>Q&nbsp; Yes. So, how do you reduce gun violence by expanding employment opportunities, including summer jobs for young people?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, there&#8217;s several components of this proposal. One of them is an initial set of actions on gun violence &#8212; or an additional set, I should say, of steps on gun violence, which the President feels are important to get guns off the streets, make sure they are not in the hands of people illegally, many of whom are playing a role in violent crime across the country. That&#8217;s part of his objective.<br><br>He also wants to provide &#8212; as we&#8217;ve seen has been effective in communities across the country &#8212; incentives and alternatives for young people in communities where that has shown to be an effective step.<br><br>Q&nbsp; So is the thought there basically that somebody &#8212; some criminal who has been committing crimes with limited interruption or interference from police for the last couple of weeks or months is going to stop this easy life of crime if they have a summer job?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, I think the President believes that we shouldn&#8217;t &#8212; we shouldn&#8217;t allow access to guns to those criminals who are currently illegally buying them from some dealers across the country, and part of his announcement is taking steps to do exactly that.<br><br>But part of his announcement is also ensuring there’s specific guidance to communities across the country to ensure that they have funding to get more community police around the country, something that was supported by the American <s>Jobs</s> [Rescue] Plan, that was support- &#8212; that was voted into law by Democrats just a couple of months ago. Some might say that the other party was for defunding the police; I&#8217;ll let others say that, but that&#8217;s a piece.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Would you concede there is a political calculation to having the Vice President visit the border before Donald Trump goes and with a drumbeat from Republicans who have counted the days that she has not visited the border? Isn&#8217;t there a political decision in the timing of this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, Kelly, I would say that we have no way to predict what President &#8212; former President Trump will say when he ha- &#8212; when he goes to the border. We can only guess. But I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re &#8212; our view is that the Vice President making a trip to the border with the Secretary of Homeland Security to assess and take a look at progress that&#8217;s been made is going to prevent or change what the former President of the United States says when he goes to the border in a couple of days.<br><br>Oh, go ahead. Did you have another question? Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Senators, including Senator Tester, are saying that they believe they&#8217;re at really the, kind of, razor&#8217;s edge &#8212; a moment with deciding to payfors &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; for infrastructure: Can they go forward? Do you feel that there is the possibility of some kind of a development within the next 24 hours? Would you agree with that sense of the timing? And is there anything new that the White House has offered for paying for these infrastructure programs that we have not learned of from you before?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, there&#8217;s no question &#8212; as you know, it&#8217;s much easier to negotiate with Congress when they&#8217;re in session. So we&#8217;re certainly hoping to make progress over the next couple of days. I&#8217;m not going to put a 24 or 48 &#8212; there&#8217;s a couple more days in the week, and we&#8217;re hopeful to make progress.<br><br>If we see progress continue to be made between our discussions with our members of our senior team and members, then we look forward to welcoming Democrats and Republicans here to the White House to meet with the President.<br><br>In terms of what we would offer: The President has offered a range of ways to pay for these proposals. And we&#8217;ve also taken &#8212; we had so many options of how to pay for these proposals we&#8217;ve even taken some of our own proposals off the table, including ensuring that individual &#8212; individuals pay a higher rate for this specific negotiation&nbsp;and also raising the corporate rate for this specific negotiation, even though we&#8217;re keeping it on the table for later on &#8212; to be very clear.&nbsp;<br><br>But the bottom line &#8212; it&#8217;s pretty clear and simple to the President. The choice for him on the payfors is: Are you going to ask Americans who are just trying to go to work &#8212; just trying to drive their cars to work, drop their kids off at school &#8212; to pay more through the &#8212; through a gas tax? Or should &#8212; should the wealthiest Americans pay what they owe in taxes? To him, that&#8217;s a pretty clear, no-brainer choice. That&#8217;s part of the discussion though.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Thanks. Back to the President&#8217;s crime prevention announcement today: You&#8217;ve noted that violent crime has been up over the last 18 months and several years. So what specifically prompted the President to come out and make this announcement today?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, there&#8217;s a policy process that has been underway for the last couple of weeks and months even. We&#8217;ve had a series of announcements, as you know, over the past several months, on gun violence prevention. Obviously, there was funding in the American Rescue Plan to support keeping cops on the street. And there were several components that were just prepared to be announced.<br><br>Q&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve made clear you&#8217;re tackling this, you know, as a gun issue. The President has urged Congress to take action on this. We have seen very little movement on the Hill. It&#8217;s been years since we&#8217;ve seen sweeping gun reforms out of Washington.<br><br>What is the President&#8217;s message then to Americans who are concerned about rising crime in their communities? In order to achieve real progress, do they have to wait for Congress to act?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, the President would certainly like to see Congress act on universal background checks, on an assault weapons ban, a number of the pieces of legislation that are currently &#8212; I shouldn&#8217;t say &#8220;working their way through Congress,&#8221; but are currently alive in Congress.<br><br>But he&#8217;s not going to wait. And his message to the American people is: He&#8217;s going to take steps that he has the power to take as President to reduce gun violence, to put in place measures that will reduce the likelihood of criminals having access to guns on the streets. There are authorities you have &#8212; any President has. And he&#8217;s going to take steps to do that, even as he pushes for legislation to move forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp; So, beyond the announcements today, he is preparing or considering additional steps that could tackle some of these issues?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, I think we&#8217;re going to focus on the announcements he&#8217;s making today, a lot of which are on gun violence and gun violence prevention measures. I don&#8217;t have anything beyond that to preview, but there are some significant steps he&#8217;s certainly announcing this afternoon.<br><br>Q&nbsp; And just one more question on how the funding for all of this works. You know, you&#8217;re allowing state and local governments to reallocate some of the COVID-19 relief funds to hire more police officers, invest in other areas to combat this rise in crime. But when Republicans pitched that idea to try and pay for some &#8212; an infrastructure plan, the White House said that money was already allocated. So what&#8217;s &#8212; what&#8217;s the difference here?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, the money was always allocated in state and local authority &#8212; to state and local governments. One of the authorities they could always have taken was to ensure there were more cops on the beat, more police in place, and that&#8217;s something we have always said was a part of the plan and the proposal. I don&#8217;t know why Republicans oppose that or why that would have prompted them to vote against the package.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Just to follow up on Mary&#8217;s first question, public safety can be a potent political issue. To what degree, if any, has the politics played a role in the decision to really try and get out in front of things today?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, the President has been very consistent in his views over the course of decades. He has never been for defunding the police. He has always been a supporter of ensuring there are &#8212; that local community policing is funded and adequately supported by the federal government. He&#8217;s also been a longtime advocate, for decades, and leader on addressing gun violence. So this is actually a continuity of his leadership on these issues over the course of decades.<br><br>Now, he has taken steps since President on each of these issues as well, including supporting funding &#8212; proposing funding in his own budget for community policing &#8212; and this is just an opportunity to put additional meat on the bones.<br><br>Q&nbsp; And then, two more quick ones. You&#8217;ve answered this before, but just to make sure I understand red lines in the elusive search for payfors that are amenable to everybody: User fees on electric vehicles, is that in the same category as indexing the gas tax from your guys&#8217; perspective in these negotiations?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Yes, we are not for a Ford F-150 tax. I&#8217;m not sure why others are.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Good framing. And then, quickly, given the tempo of some of the Taliban offensives that we&#8217;ve seen in Afghanistan, are there contingency plans at work right now to either move troops out faster or, perhaps more importantly, embassy officials &#8212; folks that we plan &#8212; the U.S. plans to keep on the ground if they advance much quicker than perhaps was initially thought?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I would say that our Department of Defense is overseeing an orderly withdrawal of our troops from Afghanistan and doing that at a pace that, in their view, will keep &#8212; ensure their safety and ensure we are doing it in a way that&#8217;s effective and in a coordinated manner with the government.<br><br>I will say that while, in general, we are seeing elevated attacks on ANDSF and Afghan government versus a year ago, we have not seen an increase in attacks on our military presence since February 2020. And we also assess that, had we not begun to draw down, violence would have increased against us as well after May 1st, because that was what the Taliban was clearly conveying. So the status quo, in our view, was not an option.<br><br>In terms of personnel and others on the ground, that&#8217;s certainly something that our State Department and our team takes very seriously and assesses whether there is a need to take any additional action. And I would certainly refer &#8212; defer to them on any additional preview they&#8217;d do on that front.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Thank you, Jen. We understand that the administration plans to replace the Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac&#8217;s federal regulator after the Supreme Court ruling that has now made it easier for the President to install his preferred overseer. Do you have a comment on that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: That&#8217;s correct, given the Supreme Court ruling this morning. But I don&#8217;t have any timeline for you on when that nomination will be made.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Is there &#8212; is there &#8212; are there any preferred candidates?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t have any candidates to preview. When we&#8217;re ready to announce one, we will announce one.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Okay. And any comment on the &#8212; on Russia firing warning shots and dropping bombs to chase a British warship out of waters Moscow now claims that &#8212; in the Black Sea that they claim belongs to Russia?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: I would point you to the British. We don&#8217;t have any more comment on it from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp; And one question on voting rights. We&#8217;ve been kind of talking to a lot of voting rights and civil rights activists who are saying that the President isn&#8217;t just simply doing enough on the issue and is betraying Black voters who actually helped him &#8212; get him &#8212; get into the office by not doing absolutely everything he can. And he&#8217;s instead spending his time negotiating infrastructure with Republicans. How would you respond to that criticism?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Who was saying that?<br><br>Q&nbsp; A lot of civil rights activists and voting activists.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Like who?<br><br>Q&nbsp; We&#8217;ve spoken to several groups and outfits. I mean, I can reach out to you with names after the briefing. And &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Sure. That sounds good.<br><br>Okay. Go ahead. (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. A number of lawmakers have asked the administration to extend the federal moratorium on evictions which expires at the end of the month. Is that something the administration is considering? And why or why not?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Sure. Well, let me first say that that would be a decision &#8212; the decision to extend the eviction moratorium will be made by the CDC, based on public health conditions. And we certainly wouldn&#8217;t get ahead of their assessment.<br><br>As you know, the moratorium &#8212; the eviction moratorium expires on June 30th &#8212; 30th. Hence, I think, your question. It was always intended to be temporary. And the President remains focused on ensuring that Americans who are struggling, through no fault of their own, have an off-ramp once it ends. Hence, we&#8217;ve also worked to take additional steps to ensure people are getting the support they need to stay in their homes, whether they are renters or homeowners.<br><br>But we&#8217;d certainly defer to the CDC on their decision and their timeline.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. The Miami Police Chief, Art Acevedo, expressed concern, disappointment that his association wasn&#8217;t invited to the discussion. He &#8212; his association represents dozens of the largest city police forces: the Major Cities Chiefs Association. I just wanted to ask why the group wasn&#8217;t invited, considering the role that they would likely be part of it.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, I think, as we were putting together the roundtable that the President is taking part in today, we tried to have a diverse group of individuals representing a range of interests from across the country who have all played an active and vital role in addressing crime and crime prevention across the country.<br><br>It is not meant to diminish anyone, including the individual you mentioned. And I&#8217;m sure we will be closely engaged with them and others who are not a part of this roundtable.<br><br>Q&nbsp; One more question on &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; the crime and gun prevention effort. This effort involves redirecting some of the relief aid (inaudible). It gives wide latitude for spending that money in certain areas. But the Biden administration largely opposed redirecting relief funds for infrastructure projects. There were some limited exceptions: water and sewer. But why was it not okay for infrastructure or limited for infrastructure, but it is more okay for this area? This &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: I think this is similar to the question Mary just asked. I mean, it has always been the case that ensuring funding was used by state and local authorities to keep cops on the beat was always a part of what was allowed in the parameters of the spending. And that is something that a number of communities, as I outlined at the beginning, did take the steps to do. So this is just giving additional guidance on how to use the funds.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. On the meeting later today between Chuck Schumer and Nancy Pelosi and White House officials: What is the White House&#8217;s message to them going to be with regard to the infrastructure talks? Are you going to insist on continuing going down the bipartisan route? Or is this going to be a decision point where they may sort of kick the tires and go ahead with reconciliation on that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, we&#8217;ve always seen this &#8212; or seen this for some time, I should say &#8212; not always &#8212; as a two-track strategy. Right? So there are different discussions and negotiations happening today.<br><br>One track &#8212; the American Jobs Plan, or big components of it &#8212; is a part of the infrastructure negotiations that we&#8217;re discussing &#8212; Steve Ricchetti, Louisa Terrell, Brian Deese &#8212; right now with members who are part of that bipartisan discussion.<br><br>Later tonight is a discussion that will also include Shalanda Young, also includes Susan Rice and others. That&#8217;s a part &#8212; a discussion, in part, about the budget reconciliation process &#8212; the second track. And that track will include the American Families Plan and components that are not a part of the negotiation.<br><br>So we&#8217;ve been saying two tracks. Today is an example of two tracks actually moving forward at one time in one day.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Which track is moving more smoothly right now? (Laughter.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI: They&#8217;re both moving at a rapid pace. You know, they&#8217;re both moving. We &#8212; we know that, one, we&#8217;re at a later stage, obviously, in the bipartisan negotiations. You all know that. And obviously, we want to make progress over the next couple of days.<br><br>We&#8217;re in an earlier stage of the budget reconciliation progress &#8212; process. That&#8217;s because that&#8217;s how that process works. But it&#8217;s important to keep both tracks going.<br><br>Q&nbsp; And then just one more for you on &#8212; I just wanted to follow up if you had any answer from yesterday what &#8212; about whether President Biden discussed interest rates with the Fed Chairman Powell and other financial regulators.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: I just &#8212; the interest rates, as you know, are the &#8212; under the purview of the Federal Reserve. I gave you an asses- &#8212; an overview of what was discussed in the meeting and don&#8217;t have anything else to add to that.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Afghanistan?<br><br>Q&nbsp; On the For the &#8212; thanks, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp; On the For the People Act that &#8212; you said this week that it would be the fight of this presidency. The President said last night the fight is not over. Now that the Senate has put itself in the record, how do you see this fight playing out in the 117th Congress on the floor? Is it going to be won on the floor before the end of this Congress?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: We&#8217;ll see. I don&#8217;t think we can assess that quite yet. And I think what&#8217;s important to know is that the President is going to keep fighting for federal legislation. The Vice President is going to keep fighting for federal legislation. Leader Schumer and others have also made clear, I think, on the floor last night: They&#8217;re going to continue to look for paths forward.<br><br>We will &#8212; we will see what that looks like, but we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re still assessing that in the coming days.<br><br>What the President will also talk about though, next week, is &#8212; not that fight &#8212; but also what we can do in states around the country, what we can do through a range of the authorities that the federal government has. Because for all of these, our objective is to make it easier to vote, make it more accessible to vote. And there&#8217;s a lot of ways to do that, even as we&#8217;re continuing to fight for federal legislation.<br><br>Q&nbsp; I want to ask you another question about the border. You said that a lot of &#8212; a great deal of progress has been made.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Border Patrol statistics show something close to 900,000 interactions or encounters on the southwest border so far this fiscal year, 170,000-odd per month the last three months. Is that where you&#8217;re measuring progress? You spoke of the unaccompanied minors, but what about the influx of people? The Vice President was tasked with the diplomatic efforts there. Has that been successful? And how are you measuring that success?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I think the Vice President has made a number of announcements about coordinated efforts with countries in the region, in the Northern Triangle, through her leadership in that area. And we&#8217;ll &#8212; we&#8217;ll be able to assess over time what it looks like in terms of migration numbers.<br><br>I was pointing to the fact that, a couple of months ago, we were looking at very overcrowded Border Patrol facilities, we were looking at kids waiting for far too long in those facilities, and there being a timeline of getting kids to vetted family members that wasn&#8217;t up to our &#8212; up to our bar. There has certainly been progress made in that regard, but the work is ongoing.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. My colleagues are reporting that the U.S. intelligence community concluded last week that the government of Afghanistan could collapse as soon as six months after the American withdrawal is completed. What is your reaction to that? And do you think that would also factor into speeding up an evacuation, especially for Afghans who helped the U.S.?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, let me first say, on SIVs &#8212; on Special Immigrant Visas &#8212; and these are individuals who have played an incredibly courageous role in helping the United States at various times over the course of our recent history: We are processing and getting people out at a record pace. We are working with Congress right now to streamline some of the requirements that slow this process down, and we&#8217;re doing the kind of extensive planning for potential evacuation should that become necessary.<br><br>So we are continuing to evaluate what our options are there, continuing to take steps forward. And certainly, we want to take every step we can take from the federal government to treat all of these courageous individuals as they deserve.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Is there a reaction on that intelligence community&#8217;s assessment at all &#8212; that the government could collapse within six months of the U.S. withdrawing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t have any more assessment beyond the intelligence community.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Follow-up on the Afghanistan, please?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Mm-hmm. Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Yes. As you know, President Ghani will be here on Friday.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp; While President Ghani and Dr. Abdullah Abdullah are visiting Washington, D.C., Taliban has still continued their attack all over Afghanistan. Do you think that President Biden is committed to a stronger, long-term support for Afghan people, especially Afghan military? Because Afghan people have high expectations from this trip &#8212; the President of Afghanistan.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: I wouldn&#8217;t say I don&#8217;t anticipate &#8212; the timeline for withdrawal is not going to change by September, which, of course, is overseen by our Department of Defense. A part of their discussion on Friday will certainly be the President reiterating his commitment to work with the government of Afghanistan to continue to provide humanitarian support, over-the-horizon security &#8212; you know, work that &#8212; that he committed to when he made this announcement. And I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;ll discuss this during their meeting on Friday.<br><br>Go ahead. Francesca, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got a couple. I&#8217;ve got a couple for you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Firstly, on the &#8212; on the Vice President&#8217;s trip to&nbsp;the border, why does the White House view this as the appropriate time for that visit?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, I think, Francesca, the decision on the timing was made in coordination with the Department of Homeland Security. As we&#8217;ve said from the beginning, we didn&#8217;t want to have anyone visit at a time where it&#8217;d be disruptive to efforts and progress being made on the ground, but they made that assessment. And she had said, just a few weeks ago, that she&#8217;d be open to going to the border if &#8212; at the appropriate time.<br><br>Q&nbsp; And earlier today the White House announced that 15 jurisdictions would participate in its community violence intervention program.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Do you anticipate that list expanding to include other cities &#8212; like Kansas City, which has grappled with gun violence and has been engaged with the White House on this issue?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: That&#8217;s a great question. And you&#8217;re right that it was 15 cities that we announced &#8212; or 15 jurisdictions that we announced this morning. Those jurisdictions stepped &#8212; or we will announce &#8212; I guess, I should say, &#8220;later this afternoon&#8221; &#8212; they stepped forward to join the collaborative because they&#8217;re committed to using these strategies as a tool to reducing the scourge of gun violence.<br><br>They have also designated a portion of their American Rescue Plan state and local funding &#8212; or another source of public funding &#8212; to support CVI efforts and have committed to city leadership and infrastructure, such as leading local efforts through an Office of Neighborhood Safety. We&#8217;re calling for more cities to follow these jurisdictions&#8217; lead, and, certainly, we&#8217;d welcome engagement and a desire to follow those trends as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp; And lastly, is the White House worried that its non-infrastructure agenda is being stymied to the point that it could have a negative impact on Democrats competing in next year&#8217;s elections?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: You mean our budget reconciliation process we&#8217;re meeting about today?<br><br>Q&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m talking about the $15 minimum wage, voting rights. There&#8217;s ongoing disputes over childcare, other elements of the Families Plan, immigration reform. There&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s a number of different things.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: I will say that the American Families Plan is a part of the budget reconciliation discussion and process. That&#8217;s an historic investment in childcare, and community college, and universal pre-K &#8212; a number of areas that are a huge, huge priority to the President, as well as many Democrats.<br><br>I think, ultimately, I&#8217;m not going to assess, 18 months from the midterm elections, what that looks like. But the most important topics on the Ameri- &#8212; minds of the American people are COVID and the economy, and we&#8217;re certainly moving forward on all fronts.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Thank you, Jen. First, a question on Afghanistan. The Afghani leaders who are coming to meet with the President on Friday are going to want specifics about U.S. support to secure the governance and human rights gains that have been fraught for the last 20 years there. Can the President guarantee that those gains won&#8217;t be lost?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: The President can guarantee that we will continue to support humanitarian assistance; support for progress &#8212; human rights progress that&#8217;s been made on the ground; and a range of investments the United States have made that we&#8217;ve already committed to continuing.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Has he determined how much money that is needed?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Over the course of time? That&#8217;s going to be done on kind of a year-by-year assessment.<br><br>Q&nbsp; In the next year then, is there any sort of estimate there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Beyond our budget? I don&#8217;t have anything more beyond our budget.<br><br>Q&nbsp; On crime, I just wanted to ask quickly if you could give us any details about who helped shape the President&#8217;s crime plan. You know, was there was input from various activists, perhaps from the Floyd family?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: It was certainly driven, of course, by the President of the United States, who oversees all of our policies here, and driven by policy leaders within the government &#8212; from Susan Rice, Cedric Richmond, a number &#8212; there&#8217;s obviously economic components &#8212; Gene Sperling, Brian Deese. And they certainly do assess and engage with a range of activists and leaders around the country, but I don&#8217;t have any more detail to read out for you.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Jen, just one more.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Oh, yeah. Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Just really quickly: On the Vice President, there&#8217;s a lot of discussion today about the Vice President&#8217;s role in immigration, but I was wondering if you could outline any of her involvement, in the last few moments, on infrastructure &#8212; a different topic that is, sort of, in the closing stage right now. Has her portfolio there, sort of, gotten lower as other things have risen, or can you just give us the, sort of, state of play?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Sure. Well, I would say that the negotiations are primarily being led at a staff level by Louisa Terrell, Steve Ricchetti, and Brian Deese. And again, if we&#8217;re at the point where we&#8217;ve made enough progress, the President will invite them here, and I&#8217;m sure the Vice President would be a part of that. But they&#8217;ve really been led at the staff level over the past couple of days. And if there&#8217;s calls that warrant the Vice President or the President making, certainly they would make them. But that&#8217;s really what the action &#8212; where the action has been over the last several days.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Thanks. Just to follow on my colleague&#8217;s question about the eviction moratorium &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; there&#8217;s some reporting that there&#8217;s a one-month extension that&#8217;s going to come out pretty soon. I know you said you don&#8217;t want to ahead of the CDC, but the CDC is punting all of our questions back to you. So is there anything you &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: That&#8217;s confusing. Sorry.<br><br>Q&nbsp; It is. (Laughter.) Is there anything you can tell us about whether a one-month extension is to be expected?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t have anything I can confirm for you from here today.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Okay. And then, on guns: All advocates are saying there should be gun czar. Is that something that&#8217;s still being considered by the White House: one person that&#8217;s responsible and spearheading this work on gun reform?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: The President is responsible.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Yes. Thank you, Jen. For some months, lawmakers of both parties have been asking the administration to prohibit polysilicon from coming into the country from China because it&#8217;s being made in Xinjiang. It&#8217;s a key material, as you may know, for solar panels.<br><br>So, is there some concern that prohibiting that from China could hurt the President&#8217;s net zero goals? Or what are you looking at doing, in regards to this, from the human rights perspective?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, let me say that, in Cornwall, just two weeks ago, G7 countries committed to ensuring that global supply chains are free from the use of forced labor. And they&#8217;re &#8212; which was a significant statement and agreement among G7 countries.<br><br>And so, as a part of that, you can expect that the United States will continue to hold those who engage in forced labor accountable and that we will continue to remove goods made from local forced labor from our supply chains.<br><br>As you also know, and I think this is the root of your question, we also remain committed to making progress internationally &#8212; glo- &#8212; domestically and internationally on addressing the climate crisis. But we think we can certainly do both.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have anything yet to announce as it relates to specific products &#8212; or substances, I should say &#8212; that are planned, but we&#8217;ll see if we have more on that in the coming days.<br><br>Q&nbsp; We have to gather for the event.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Oh, okay. Great. We have to gather for the event.<br><br>Thanks, everyone, so much. Have a great day. See you tomorrow.<br><br>2:01 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces 17 Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/president-biden-announces-17-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 20:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 17 individuals to serve in key roles: Michael Carpenter, Nominee for U.S. Representative to the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), with rank of Ambassador Claire Cronin, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ireland Jack Markell, Nominee for Representative&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 17 individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Michael Carpenter, Nominee for U.S. Representative to the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), with rank of Ambassador</li><li>Claire Cronin, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ireland</li><li>Jack Markell, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, with rank of Ambassador</li><li>Cindy Hensley McCain, Nominee for U.S. Representative to the United Nations Agencies for Food and Agriculture, with rank of Ambassador</li><li>Homer Wilkes, Nominee for Under Secretary for Natural Resources and the Environment, Department of Agriculture</li><li>Raymond Limon, Nominee for Vice Chair of the Merit Systems Protection Board of Directors</li><li>Max Vekich, Nominee for Member of the Federal Maritime Commission</li><li>Stacey Brandenburg, Nominee for Trustee of the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation</li><li>Robert Garcia, Nominee for Trustee of the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation</li><li>Kamilah Forbes, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</li><li>Christopher Morgan, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</li><li>Ismael Ahmed, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</li><li>Kinan Azmeh, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</li><li>Huascar Medina, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</li><li>Jake Shimabukuro, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</li><li>Constance Williams, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</li><li>Fiona Whelan Prine, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Michael Carpenter, Nominee for U.S. Representative to the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), with rank of Ambassador</u></strong></p>



<p>Michael Carpenter is the Managing Director of the Penn Biden Center for Diplomacy and Global Engagement at the University of Pennsylvania.&nbsp; He is a former Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Russia, Ukraine and Eurasia, and previously was Special Advisor for Europe and Eurasia in the Office of the Vice President.&nbsp;&nbsp; He also served as Director for Russia in the National Security Council.&nbsp; A former Foreign Service officer, Carpenter served in the Department of State as Deputy Director of the Office of Russian Affairs, Special Assistant for the Under Secretary for Political Affairs, Political-Military officer in the Office of European Security and Political Affairs, and Advisor on Regional Conflicts in the Office of Caucasus Affairs and Regional Conflicts.&nbsp; He served overseas in Barbados, Slovenia and Poland.&nbsp;&nbsp; He has received numerous professional distinctions, including the Jamestown Foundation Distinguished Service Award and fellowships from the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation and the International Research &amp; Exchanges Board.&nbsp; Carpenter earned a B.A. at Stanford University, and an M.A. and Ph.D. at the University of California, Berkeley.&nbsp; He speaks Polish, Slovenian, Czech, French and German.</p>



<p><strong><u>Claire Cronin, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ireland</u></strong></p>



<p>Claire Cronin currently serves as a Representative, and as Majority Leader, in the legislature of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts. During her service as a legislator, Cronin was also Vice Chair, and then Chair, of the Committee on the Judiciary. As Chair of the Committee Cronin was the architect of significant pieces of legislation, including major criminal justice reform and police reform. Cronin has also served since 2003 as a Mediator/Arbitrator for Commonwealth Mediation in Brockton, MA. Prior to her election as Representative, Cronin maintained the Law Office of Claire Cronin in Brockton, Massachusetts.&nbsp; Earlier she was first a law clerk, and then an Associate Attorney at Wynn &amp; Wynn, P.C. in Raynham, Massachusetts.&nbsp; Before that she worked in Liaison and Constituent Services in the Office of Massachusetts Governor, Edward King.&nbsp; Cronin earned her B.A. from Stonehill College and her J.D. degree from Suffolk University.&nbsp; She is the recipient of multiple honors and awards including the Jewish Community Relations Council Legislative Leadership Award (2020) and the Emerge Massachusetts 2020 Woman of the Year.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jack Markell, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, with rank of Ambassador</u></strong></p>



<p>Jack Markell, a former Governor and State Treasurer of Delaware, is the President of Jack Markell Consulting, LLC.&nbsp; He is a former Senior Vice President of Comcast Corporation and Nextel Communications.&nbsp; He also has served as Chair of the National Governors Association, President of the Council of State Governments, and Chair of the Democratic Governors Association.&nbsp; Markell earned a Bachelors Degree in Development Studies and Economics at Brown University and an M.B.A. at the University of Chicago.</p>



<p><strong><u>Cindy Hensley McCain, Nominee for U.S. Representative to the United Nations Agencies for Food and Agriculture, with rank of Ambassador</u></strong></p>



<p>Cindy Hensley McCain is Chairman and Director of the Hensley Beverage Company in Phoenix, Arizona.&nbsp; She chairs the Board of Trustees and is a member of the Human Trafficking Council at the McCain Institute for International Leadership at Arizona State University.&nbsp; She is a Member of the Leadership Council at the Too Small to Fail Initiative in New York City, in addition to leadership roles in numerous other civic and philanthropic organizations. McCain is also Co-Chair of the Arizona Human Trafficking Council, and a member of the Phoenix Mayor’s Human Trafficking Task Force. McCain received her Bachelor’s and Master’s degrees at the University of Southern California.</p>



<p><strong><u>Homer Wilkes, Nominee for Under Secretary for Natural Resources and the Environment, Department of Agriculture</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Homer Wilkes, a native of Port Gibson, Mississippi, currently serves as Director of Gulf of Mexico Ecosystem Restoration Team.&nbsp; He is one of the five Federal Executive Council member to oversee the rebuilding of the Ecosystem of the Gulf of Mexico after the BP Oil Spill of 2010.&nbsp; He served as the Acting Associate Chief of USDA/Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) in Washington during the period of 2010-2012.&nbsp; Dr. Wilkes&#8217; tenure with the United States Department of Agriculture span’s over 41 years. During his tenure he has served as State Conservationist for Mississippi; Chief Financial Officer for NRCS in Washington, DC; Deputy State Conservationist for Mississippi; and Chief of Administrative Staff for the South Technical Center for NRCS in Fort Worth, Texas.</p>



<p>Dr. Wilkes also served as Naval Supply Officer in the United States Navy Reserves from November 1984 – Aprl-2007.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He received his Bachelors, Master of Business Administration, and Ph.D. in Urban Higher Education from Jackson State University.&nbsp; He also successfully completed the USDA Senior Executive Service Candidate Development Program (SES CDP) through American University’s Key Executive Leadership Certificate in Public Policy. Dr. Wilkes and his wife Kim, currently reside in Ridgeland, MS. They have three sons, Justin, Austin, and Harrison.&nbsp; He enjoys fishing, restoring antique vehicles and family activities.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Raymond Limon, Nominee for Vice Chair of the Merit Systems Protection Board of Directors</u></strong></p>



<p>Raymond A. Limon is the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Human Capital and Diversity, and Chief Human Capital Officer, and he is a career member of the Senior Executive Service at the Department of the Interior (DOI).&nbsp; His Directorate provides strategic human capital; safety/health; and training policies and services for the Department’s 70,000 plus employees serving in over 350 occupations and 2,400 locations.&nbsp; Before joining DOI, Limon led the State Department’s Civil Service HR Management office.&nbsp; Ray has also served as the Chief Human Capital Officer at AmeriCorps (or the Corporation for National and Community Service), and chaired the Small Agency Human Resources Council, representing approximately 100 Federal agencies and organizations.&nbsp; He was also an attorney at the U.S. Office of Personnel Management (OPM) Office of General Counsel specializing in employment litigation and policy review; and he served as OPM’s Director of the Office of Administrative Law Judges (ALJs), where he managed the government-wide personnel system for ALJs.&nbsp; Limon received his J.D. from Indiana University, Bloomington, and he is a former Peace Corps Volunteer (Honduras).</p>



<p><strong><u>Max Vekich, Nominee for Member of the Federal Maritime Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Max Vekich a native of Aberdeen, Washington and the son to a father who was an army Staff Sergeant in the Pacific, Philippines, and Korea, with the Sixth and later the Second Infantry Divisions and mother who managed the production of Landmines and hand grenades at Lamb’s Grays Harbor.</p>



<p>Vekich is a former elected official at the State House and won four straight terms to the Washington State House of Representatives.&nbsp; When elected I was the youngest Democrat in the State House.&nbsp; I served as chair of three committees during my tenure: Agriculture, Trade &amp; Economic Development and Commerce &amp; Labor.&nbsp;The Washington Historical Society recognized his efforts by awarding him the Robert Gray Medal. In 2004 Vekich moved to Seattle for work.&nbsp; He was promoted to “Supercargo” in 2005 where he worked in all Washington State Ports.&nbsp; In the public arena, he stayed engaged on matters of Port infrastructure and operations and&nbsp; was lured back into politics in 2009 as a candidate for Port of Seattle Commission.&nbsp; Vekich garnered 185,000 votes as a runner up.&nbsp; Since then, the Northwest Seaport Alliance, which he advocated for, has come into being combining Seattle and Tacoma container operations. He has weighed in on numerous port issues, like the reactivation of Terminal 5, which will be a reality in 2022.</p>



<p>Vekich is married to Marcee Stone, they have three adult children and four grandchildren.</p>



<p><strong><u>Stacey Brandenburg, Nominee for Trustee of the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation</u></strong></p>



<p>Stacey M. Brandenburg is a distinguished privacy and technology lawyer, currently practicing as a shareholder at ZwillGen PLLC. Brandenburg has focused her career on emerging legal issues surrounding technology, including privacy, data, and consumer protection. She previously served as an attorney in the Federal Trade Commission’s Division of Privacy and Identity Protection, and now works with clients to navigate new regulations and implement best practices for their consumer-facing policies and activities. Brandenburg also developed and taught a seminar on privacy law as an adjunct professor at American University’s Washington College of Law.</p>



<p>Brandenburg has a long history with the Truman Foundation and believes strongly in its mission – a 1995 Truman Scholar from Georgia, she spent a year working for the Foundation before law school, where she helped nurture and sustain the Scholar community and its programming.&nbsp; She has continued to support the Foundation’s efforts through Friends of the Truman Foundation.&nbsp;Brandenburg is a graduate of New York University Law School and the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, where she was a John Motley Morehead Scholar. Brandenburg is married to Derek Ludwin, and they have two children — Andrew and Elizabeth.</p>



<p><strong><u>Robert Garcia, Nominee for Trustee of the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Robert Garcia is an educator and the 28th Mayor of Long Beach.&nbsp;Mayor Garcia immigrated to the United States at age 5 and was raised in Southern California. The Mayor, a college and university educator, holds an M.A. from the University of Southern California and an Ed.D. in Higher Education from Cal State Long Beach, where he also earned his B.A. in Communications. Mayor Garcia leads a city made up of nearly 500,000 residents, 6,000 city employees, an airport and the second largest container seaports in the world. He is focused on making the City of Long Beach a leader in education, public health and climate protection. As Mayor, he has championed progressive education policy, launched an aggressive climate plan, supported workers by increasing wages; and fought to expand and protect rights for immigrants, the LGBTQ+ community and women — including appointing a female majority to serve on city commissions for the first time in history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During the COVID-19 pandemic, Mayor Garcia launched a national model for COVID-19 testing and vaccinations. His city became the first jurisdiction in the State of California to vaccinate public school teachers, which allowed one of the largest school districts in the state to reopen campuses. Mayor Garcia was the first mayor in the country to rollout a comprehensive city economic recovery plan — the Long Beach Recovery Act — to reinvigorate the economy, build a healthier community and get people back to work. To date, 99% of all senior residents in Long Beach have been vaccinated and the city has been hailed by Governor Newsom and national news outlets as a model for its public health and economic response.&nbsp;He is married to Matthew Mendez Garcia, a professor of political science at California State University, Long Beach.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kamilah Forbes, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>Kamilah Forbes is an esteemed award-winning director and producer for theater and television who currently serves as the Executive Producer at the world-famous Apollo Theater. Forbes is noted for having a strong commitment to the development of creative works by, for, and about the Hip-Hop generation. In addition to her work at the Apollo, Forbes’ directing credits include <em>By the Way, Meet Vera Stark,</em> written by two-time Pulitzer prize-winning writer Lynn Nottage; <em>The Blood Quilt,</em> written by Katori Hall; and <em>Sunset Baby,</em> by MacArthur Genius recipient Dominique Morisseau. She has also worked as associate director on the Tony Award-winning <em>A Raisin in the Sun</em>, and Emmy Award-winning “The Wiz Live” for NBC. Other Broadway credits include <em>The Mountaintop</em> and <em>Stick Fly.</em>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Forbes’ most recent directorial work, “Between the World and Me” aired as a special event on HBO and HBO Max in November 2020. Her directorial work on “Between the World and Me” has brought her a host of acclaim and recognition, including a nomination for Best Direction for an NAACP Image Award and a Critics Choice Award nomination.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Throughout her career Forbes has won numerous awards for both directing and producing, including the 2019 NBTF Larry Leon Hamlin Producer Award, a Root 100 Award, an NAACP Image Award, a Helen Hayes and Barrymore Award, and an Audelco. Forbes’ recent projects include directing the sold-out world premiere, tour, and theatrical adaption of Ta-Nehisi Coates’ New York Times best-selling novel <em>Between the World and Me</em>, which premiered at the Apollo Theater in 2018 and returned for encore performances in 2019. In addition to her work at the Apollo Theater, Forbes is set to direct the Broadway premiere of Soul Train alongside producer Questlove, playwright Dominique Morisseau, and choreographer Camille A. Brown.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Christopher Morgan, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>Christopher K. Morgan is a choreographer, educator, facilitator, curator, and arts administrator. Known as a thoughtful advocate for cultural integrity, inclusivity, and diverse representation in the studio and on stage, his Native Hawaiian ancestry and wide-ranging international performance career influence all aspects of his work. As Executive Artistic Director of Dance Place in Washington, D.C., Morgan stewarded the organization through the triple pandemics of 2020 maintaining the entire staff with no layoffs or furloughs, while continuing to pay artists and teachers.</p>



<p>Since 2006 Morgan has directed Art Omi: Dance, an annual collaborative residency for international choreographers in New York, where he created an utterly unique international cultural exchange program. Frequently sought as a speaker and grants reviewer, he has been at the forefront of national discussions on equity in the arts. He currently serves on the board of the National Performance Network, is a member of the Association of Performing Arts Professionals’ Equitable Partnership Working Group, and on the Association of Performing Arts Professionals 2022 Conference Planning Committee. Born in Orange County, CA, he resides in Takoma Park, MD with his husband, opera director Kyle Lang.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ismael Ahmed, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>Ismael Ahmed most recently served as the Associate Provost for Metropolitan Impact at the University of Michigan-Dearborn. In this position, Ahmed was responsible for connecting academic initiatives for 9,000 students and 540 full and part-time faculty with over 500 community, business, and governmental partners. Prior to that, he served in Governor Jennifer M. Granholm&#8217;s administration as Director of the Michigan Department of Human Services, the state&#8217;s second-largest department. He co-founded the Arab Community Center for Economic and Social Services (ACCESS) in 1971 and was appointed executive director in 1983, growing it into a national human service and advocacy agency with affiliates in 24 cities.</p>



<p>The son of first-generation immigrants, Ahmed is co-founder of The Arab American National Museum in Dearborn and serves as an executive member of its advisory board. Since 1984, he has lead Detroit&#8217;s Concert of Colors – one of the largest world music festivals in the United States – which he co-curates and co-chairs. He also produces and hosts “This Island Earth” on WDET Public Radio Detroit, where he conducts multi-cultural music &amp; arts programs with music and guests that represent culture from across the planet.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kinan Azmeh, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>Originally from Damascus, Syria, Kinan Azmeh brings his music to all corners of the world as a soloist, composer and improviser. Notable appearances include the Opera Bastille, Paris; Tchaikovsky Grand Hall, Moscow; Carnegie Hall and the UN General Assembly, New York; the Royal Albert hall, London; Teatro Colon, Buenos Aires; Der Philharmonie, Berlin; the Library of Congress, the Kennedy Center, Washington DC; the Mozarteum, Salzburg, Hamburg’s Elbphilharmonie; and in his native Syria at the opening concert of the Damascus Opera House.</p>



<p>He has appeared as a soloist with the New York Philharmonic, the Seattle Symphony, the Bavarian Radio Orchestra, the West-Eastern Divan Orchestra, the Qatar Philharmonic and the Syrian Symphony Orchestra among others, and has shared the stage with such musical luminaries as Yo-Yo Ma, Daniel Barenboim, Marcel Khalife, John McLaughlin, Francois Rabbath Aynur and Jivan Gasparian.</p>



<p>Azmeh serves as artistic director of the Damascus Festival Chamber Players, a pan-Arab ensemble dedicated to contemporary music form the Arab world.&nbsp; He has also been playing with the Silkroad Ensemble since 2012, whose 2017 Grammy Award-winning album “Sing Me Home” features Azmeh as a clarinetist and composer. Azmeh is a graduate of New York’s Juilliard School as a student of Charles Neidich, and of both the Damascus High institute of Music where he studied with Shukry Sahwki, Nicolay Viovanof and Anatoly Moratof, and Damascus University’s School of Electrical Engineering. Azmeh earned his doctorate degree in music from the City University of New York in 2013.</p>



<p><strong><u>Huascar Medina, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>Huascar Medina is the 7th Poet Laureate of Kansas. He currently works with the Kansas Creative Arts Industries Commission reimagining and developing innovative programming for the poet laureateship. He is a peer facilitator for Mid-America Arts Alliance’s Artist INC program. Artist INC is dedicated to the professional development of artists of all disciplines in the Midwestern region and connects them to the resources, tools, and opportunities necessary to build entrepreneurial skills and strengthen their artistic practice. As Literary Editor for seveneightfive magazine, he provides a platform for Kansas writers by reviewing and spotlighting their work. He is the host and creator of Kansas is Lit on KSEF-DB, an online radio show specifically created to increase the visibility and reach of Kansas writers. He serves as a Staff Editor at South Broadway Press out of Denver, Colorado. He is also an Op-Ed writer at Kansas Reflector, a nonprofit news organization providing in-depth reporting and diverse opinions to all Kansans. Medina proudly serves on the ArtsConnect board and Kansas Book Festival council. He takes pride in the rise of Midwest artists and has dedicated himself to the emergence of “The Prairie Renaissance”.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jake Shimabukuro, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>Jake Shimabukuro is a career ukulele player who wide experience in the arts. Hefirst gained notice in the late 19902 with the popular musical group Pure Heart . After the group dissolved, his fame as a solo artist spread throughout Hawaii and eventually to Japan. There, in 2001, Shimabukuro signed a historic deal with Epic Records/Sony Music, which formed the basis of a career punctuated by a string of hit albums and standing room audiences.</p>



<p>Shimabukuro has also played with world-renowned orchestras and at prestigious venues such as the Hollywood Bowl, Lincoln Center, and Sydney Opera House, and at music festivals including Bonnaroo, SXSW and Fuji Rock Festival. He has also performed for Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II.</p>



<p>Shimabukuro continues to write and record, while maintaining an international concert schedule of 140 live performances a year. He is a loving husband and proud father of two boys. In addition to balancing his career with family, Shimabukuro also remains firmly rooted in his commitment to community, frequently performing at schools in Hawaii and overseas to urge kids to “say no to drugs” and inspire them to find their passion. In the process, Shimabukuro has served as a Pied Piper in the booming popularity of the ukulele, spreading his belief that the world would be a better place if everyone played the ukulele.</p>



<p><strong><u>Constance Williams, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>Constance Hess Williams has deep and varied experience as an entrepreneur and consultant in the private sector and as an elected official in the public sector. She graduated from Barnard College with a B.A. in English and earned her M.B.A. from The Wharton School of the University of Pennsylvania. Following graduation from college, Williams worked in New York as an editorial assistant at Doubleday &amp; Company, answered viewer mail at NBC, and began a photographic stock house.&nbsp; After she married and moved to Philadelphia, Williams worked for Running Press, as a consultant for the Wharton Small Business Development Center and as a program officer for the&nbsp; Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships. With a background in publishing, marketing, and small business and financial consulting, Williams was the economic development and small business coordinator for Pennsylvania’s 13th Congressional District</p>



<p>Williams is widely known throughout her community for her strong record of involvement with a special focus on education, the arts, and economic development across broadly diverse regional organizations. She served as the Chair of the Board of The Philadelphia Museum of Art and is now Chair Emerita.&nbsp; She was also a trustee of the National Museum of American Jewish History,&nbsp; Steppingstone Scholars Inc. Barnard College, The Episcopal Academy, The Baldwin School, and Pine Manor College&nbsp; and The Kimmel Center of Performing Arts in Philadelphia.&nbsp; She is a Distinguished Daughter of Pennsylvania.</p>



<p>Williams resides in Haverford, Pennsylvania with her husband, Sankey Williams. They have two daughters and five grandchildren.</p>



<p><strong><u>Fiona Whelan Prine, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>Fiona Whelan Prine brings an expansive viewpoint to the American roots music community as President of Oh Boy Records, the country’s second-oldest independent record label still in operation. In that role, she oversees the multiple Grammy Award-winning recordings and publishing copyrights of her late husband, American songwriter John Prine. She also serves as Founder and President of the newly established Hello in There Foundation. As one of Nashville’s most prominent and dedicated philanthropists, Whelan Prine has volunteered countless hours on behalf of Thistle Farms, a global nonprofit social enterprise dedicated to helping women survivors recover and heal from poverty, prostitution, trafficking, and addiction. Through unique annual fundraising events, often with an appearance by John Prine, her initiatives have helped raise more than $3 million for the organization. In the last year alone, her community involvement has raised more than $1 million for important social causes, including those related to the Covid-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Born and raised in Ireland, Whelan Prine is the eldest of six daughters born to Donal and Mary Whelan. She served as Business Manager for Windmill Lane Studios in Dublin, considered Ireland’s premiere recording studio. Whelan Prine met John while working there with artists such as U2, Van Morrison and many others, and they later married in Nashville, Tennessee, where together they raised their three sons. Whelan Prine received her U.S. citizenship in 2004.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 19:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21771</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; &#160;Sharon L. Cromer, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of The Gambia. &#160; &#160; &#160;Troy Damian Fitrell, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Sharon L. Cromer, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of The Gambia.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Troy Damian Fitrell, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Guinea.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Guy T. Kiyokawa, of Hawaii, to be an Assistant Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Enterprise Integration), vice Melissa Sue Glynn, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Kathleen S. Miller, of Virginia, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense. &nbsp;(New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Marc Ostfield, of Pennsylvania, a Career Member of the Senior Executive Service, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Paraguay.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;David M. Prouty, of Maryland, to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board for the term of five years expiring August 27, 2026, vice William J. Emanuel, term expiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Kenneth Lee Salazar, of Colorado, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the United Mexican States.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Julianne Smith, of Michigan, to be United States Permanent Representative on the Council of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;C.B. Sullenberger, III, of Texas, for the rank of Ambassador during his tenure of service as Representative of the United States of America on the Council of the International Civil Aviation Organization.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Cynthia Ann Telles, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Costa Rica.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;David M. Uhlmann, of Michigan, to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, vice Susan Parker Bodine.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Celeste Ann Wallander, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense, vice Robert Story Karem.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
