<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 17:59:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Marine One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 17:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 10:59 A.M. EDT Q    Mr. President, have you made a decision about how you will handle the Khashoggi killing when you go to Saudi Arabia? THE PRESIDENT:  The same way I’ve been handling it.  I’m not going to meet with &#8212; I’m not going to meet with MBS; I’m going to an international&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>10:59 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>Q    Mr. President, have you made a decision about how you will handle the Khashoggi killing when you go to Saudi Arabia?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The same way I’ve been handling it.  I’m not going to meet with &#8212; I’m not going to meet with MBS; I’m going to an international meeting.  And he’s going to be a part of it, just like there were people part of the discussion today.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, how concerned are you about the three Americans who are reportedly missing in Ukraine?  Have you been briefed?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I have been briefed.  We don’t know where they are.</p>



<p>But I want to reiterate: Americans should not be going to Ukraine now.&nbsp; I’ll say it again: Americans should not be going to Ukraine now.&nbsp; They should not be going to Ukraine.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What will the consequences be for oil companies if they don’t boost supplies?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, look, one of the things that has happened is that the price of gasoline exceeds the price based on the barrel of oil costs right now.&nbsp;&nbsp;So if you get &#8212; based on what a barrel of oil costs on average, it should not be this high.&nbsp; They’re making exorbitant profits &#8212; number one.</p>



<p>Number two, I’ve contacted them &#8212; my team has &#8212; to ask what their plans are and to give any suggestions they have.&nbsp; They have over 9,000 leases &#8212; 9,000.&nbsp; They can drill until they’re &#8212; until (inaudible) won’t have it.&nbsp; But they’re not doing it &#8212; number two.</p>



<p>Number three, I think we’re going to be in a position where we’re going to &#8211;</p>



<p>Oh.&nbsp; (The First Lady approaches the President.)</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; We got to go!</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) two billion people in India are waiting for you to visit India.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ve been to India twice, and I’ll be back to India.&nbsp; And my relations are very good.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>11:01 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the Major Economies Forum on Energy and&#160;Climate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-major-economies-forum-on-energy-and-climate/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 16:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55801</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[8:34 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, John.&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; And thank you for, whatever time zone you’re in, making the time to be here.&#160; I appreciate it very much.&#160;You know, we’re meeting today at a moment when &#8212; where there’s urgent global issues impacting all of our nations, demand our immed- &#8212; and they&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>8:34 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, John.&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; And thank you for, whatever time zone you’re in, making the time to be here.&nbsp; I appreciate it very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, we’re meeting today at a moment when &#8212; where there’s urgent global issues impacting all of our nations, demand our immed- &#8212; and they all demand our immediate action and our close cooperation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Russia’s brutal and unprovoked assault on its neighbor, Ukraine, has fueled a global energy crisis and has sharpened the need to achieve long-term, reliable energy security and stability.<br>&nbsp;<br>And with Russia’s war driving up inflation worldwide, threatening vulnerable countries with severe food shortages, we have to work together to mitigate the immediate fallout of this crisis.<br>&nbsp;<br>In the United States, I’m using every lever available to me to bring down prices for the American people.&nbsp; And our nations are working together to stabilize global energy markets, including coordinating the largest release from the global reserve &#8212; from global oil reserves in history.<br>&nbsp;<br>But the critical point is that these actions are part of our transition to a clean and secure long-term energy future. And the good news is climate security and energy security go hand in hand.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, back in March, the European Commission &#8212; with President von der Leyen leading the effort &#8212; and I announced the U.S.-EU Task Force on Energy Security to help the EU rapidly reduce its dependence on Russian gas and reduce the EU’s overall demand for gas by ramping up clean energy technologies.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ll bolster our energy security and improve the affordability and reliability of energy around the world and reduce our greenhouse gas emissions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Because we cannot &#8212; we cannot afford to let the critical goal of limiting global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius slip out of our reach.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the science tells us that the window for action is rapidly narrowing &#8212; rapidly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Glasgow was just the kickoff for a decade of ambition, action, and innovation.&nbsp; And we look toward COP27.&nbsp; We have to &#8212; we have to dedicate ourselves, as we look forward to it, to delivering on existing goals and undertaking additional efforts to boost our progress.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I urge these countries that &#8212; those countries that have not yet gone to set a 2030 emissions target to align with the Paris temperature goal, to strengthen their targets for COP27.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, we need new initiatives to accelerate our progress toward our goals and bolster our resilience.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here’s what the United States is proposing to maximize efficiency and reduce emissions across the energy, transportation, and agricultural sectors.&nbsp; I hope that many of you will &#8212; will join us in these efforts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>First, we should build upon the success of the Global Methane Pledge &#8212; now more than 115 countries strong.&nbsp; To do that, we’re announcing the Global Methane Pledge Emer- &#8212; excuse me &#8212; Energy Pathway to ramp up the speed at which we reduce methane leaks from the oil and gas sector, and also helping bridge our energy needs.<br>&nbsp;<br>Each year, our existing energy system leaks enough methane to meet the needs for the entire European power sector.&nbsp; We flare enough gas to offset nearly all of the EU’s gas imports from Russia.&nbsp; And so, by stopping the leaking and flaring of this super-potent greenhouse gas, and capturing this resource for countries that need it, we’re addressing two problems at once.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, we’re investing in innovation and hastening the scale-up of new technologies like carbon capture and advanced nuclear and clean hydrogen.&nbsp; The International Energy Agency says we need 90 billion dollars’ worth of demonstration projects for this decade.&nbsp; And thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that was passed here in the United States, we’re stepping up with a $21.5 billion contribution toward this goal.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, we’ve launched a multibillion-dollar effort to create hydrogen hubs all around the country.&nbsp; And using the Defense Production Act, in our system, to boost the manufacturing of electrolyzers, which are used to produce clean hydrogen.&nbsp; We’ve done &#8212; we’re doing both these things.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our Department of Energy also just issued a loan guarantee to construct one of the world’s largest clean hydrogen storage facilities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I challenge us, together, to hit the full $90 billion target by the Global Clean Energy Action Forum that the U.S. is hosting in September in Pittsburgh.<br>&nbsp;<br>Third, Russia’s war is driving up prices of gas &#8212; everybody knows that &#8212; hurting people in all our countries.&nbsp; It’s an immediate problem that I suspect all of you and I know I’m working every day.<br>&nbsp;<br>Over the long run, we can remove the pain of volatile gas prices and reduce transportation emissions by putting more zero-emission cars on the road.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In the United States, we’re building a nationwide network of 500,000 electric vehicle charging stations.&nbsp; We’re strengthening our supply chains for the critical materials that go into those batteries.&nbsp; And we’ve set a goal of ensuring that half of all passenger cars sold in the United States in 2020 will be zero &#8212; 2030, I should say &#8212; will be zero emission.&nbsp; I urge all of you to join us in a similar goal.<br>&nbsp;<br>Fourth, if ocean-based shipping were a country, it would be the eighth-largest emitter in the world.&nbsp; It’s critical we do more to promote zero-emission fuels and green shipping corridors in this sector.&nbsp; And it seems to me we ought to be able to do that.&nbsp; That’s why the United States and Norway are launching the Green Shipping Challenge to fully decarbonize shipping by 2050.<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, Russia’s war in Ukraine is worsening food insecurity, in part due to the skyrocketing price of fertilizer. Fertilizer production relies on natural gas, but more than 50 percent of nitrogen fertilizers are lost globally every year due to waste.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So today, the United States is launching a new Global Fertilizer Challenge.&nbsp; Let’s aim to raise at least $100 million toward increasing fertilizer efficiency and developing alternatives by COP27.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And to keep strengthening our adaptation efforts, this year, the United States is going to partner with Egypt on the Adaptation in Africa event to deliver concrete initiatives that are going to improve people’s lives and build resilience in &#8212; to a changing climate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These are all achievable goals, in my view.&nbsp; And if we all commit to doing our part, we’ll get it done.&nbsp; And if we do, we’ll unlock an incredible opportunities for all our people around the world: more growth, more innovation, more good-paying jobs that support working families, greater food security for communities around the world, and we’ll finally break our dependence on the volatile energy markets and high gas prices.<br>&nbsp;<br>So thank you all again for taking the time to &#8212; this morning, today, tonight &#8212; whatever the timeframe it is &#8212; for what &#8212; and joining us.&nbsp; So let’s keep this challenge &#8212; let&#8217;s keep doing what we &#8212; what we&#8217;ve been doing.&nbsp; Challenge ourselves to do more, because we can.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you all so very much for listening.&nbsp; I&#8217;m anxious to hear what you all have to say.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, John.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>8:42 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on FDA Authorization of the First COVID-&#8288;19 Vaccines for America’s Youngest&#160;Kids</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/statement-by-president-biden-on-fda-authorization-of-the-first-covid-19-vaccines-for-americas-youngest-kids/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 15:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today is a day of huge relief for parents and families across America. Following a rigorous scientific review, the Food and Drug Administration has authorized the first COVID-19 vaccines for kids under the age of five. As early as next week, pending recommendations from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), parents will finally be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today is a day of huge relief for parents and families across America. Following a rigorous scientific review, the Food and Drug Administration has authorized the first COVID-19 vaccines for kids under the age of five. As early as next week, pending recommendations from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), parents will finally be able to get their youngest kids the protection of a safe and effective COVID-19 vaccine.<br><br>We are the first country to protect our youngest children with COVID-19 vaccines, offering safe and highly effective mRNA doses to children as young as six months old. My administration secured vaccine doses for America’s youngest children and now with FDA’s authorization, we will begin shipping millions of vaccine doses for kids to thousands of locations parents know and trust—including pediatricians’ offices, children’s hospitals, and pharmacies. As doses are delivered, parents will be able to start scheduling vaccinations for their youngest kids as early as next week, with appointments ramping up over the coming days and weeks.<br><br>Thanks to my administration and partners across the country, we have come a long way in our fight against COVID these past 17 months. The vaccines, treatments and other tools my Administration has made widely available are protecting the American people from serious illness, keeping them out of the hospital, and bringing down daily deaths due to COVID-19 by 90 percent.<br><br>Today’s decision will help build on this progress, giving parents much-needed relief and peace of mind and helping our nation continue to move forward safely. We look forward to hearing from the CDC on its recommendations.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Launches the Talent Pipeline Challenge: Supporting Employer Investments in Equitable Workforce Development for Infrastructure&#160;Jobs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-launches-the-talent-pipeline-challenge-supporting-employer-investments-in-equitable-workforce-development-for-infrastructure-jobs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 14:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is kicking off a summer-long Talent Pipeline Challenge to fill high quality jobs that will help rebuild our infrastructure and supply chains here at home, and continue our transition from a historic economic recovery to steady and stable growth in the years ahead. This is a nationwide call to action for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is kicking off a summer-long Talent Pipeline Challenge to fill high quality jobs that will help rebuild our infrastructure and supply chains here at home, and continue our transition from a historic economic recovery to steady and stable growth in the years ahead. This is a nationwide call to action for employers, education and training providers, states, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, and philanthropic organizations to make tangible commitments that support equitable workforce development in three critical infrastructure sectors: Broadband, Construction, and “Electrification” (EV Charging Infrastructure and Battery Manufacturing). These commitments will complement the Federal government’s investment in workforce development and help ensure there are trained workers who are ready to meet the demands of implementing the historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, as the country transitions from a historic economic recovery to stable and steady growth that works for working people.</p>



<p><strong>Employers.</strong> The Talent Pipeline Challenge will encourage employers to partner with and hire skilled workers from at least one training provider in each region in which the employer has operations, such as a registered apprenticeship program or a community college with a diverse student population. As part of this pledge, employers can partner with national or regional intermediaries or training providers to build, scale, or support local training models to recruit, train, or hire workers in their sector. Training partnerships will build on pathways to quality jobs for women, people of color, and underserved workers— including those from rural and Tribal communities and communities with persistent poverty. As part of this goal:</p>



<ul><li>Employers and training providers are encouraged to include a community-based organization working with women and under-represented groups in the training partnership.</li><li>Employers already partnered with a registered apprenticeship program may consider investing in a quality pre-apprenticeship program that sends its graduates directly into a registered apprenticeship program.<br></li><li>Employers are encouraged to invest in the resources and supports like tuition assistance, child care, transportation costs, and emergency aid that are often barriers for workers to participate in training.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Training Providers.</strong> The Talent Pipeline Challenge will encourage training providers, unions, and other intermediaries, including labor-management skills programs, community colleges, industry associations, philanthropic organizations, and worker centers, to commit to:</p>



<ul><li>Partner with employers to create or bring to scale skills training programs, coupled with wraparound services like transportation assistance and child care, that will prepare workers for in-demand jobs.</li><li>Help to recruit regional and local employers from the three infrastructure sectors into the Talent Pipeline Challenge—including through regional convenings.</li><li>Work with employer partners to identify, recruit, and support local women and workers of color so they will be employed in infrastructure jobs, including workers from communities with persistent poverty, and rural and Tribal communities.</li><li>Provide grant funding for employer-training-provider partnerships and to defer costs of advanced skills training, particularly for underserved workers.</li></ul>



<p><strong>State and Local Governments.</strong> The Talent Pipeline Challenge is calling on state, local, Tribal, and territorial governments to commit to:</p>



<ul><li>Use federal funding to invest in workforce development efforts in these critical sectors, including:<ul><li>American Rescue Plan (ARP) State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds toward job training and other assistance to workers negatively affected by the pandemic.</li><li>Bipartisan Infrastructure Law grant funding, where possible and legally permissible, to support workforce development aligned to project labor needs.</li><li>State Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA) Reserve dollars to fund place-based labor-management partnerships in infrastructure sectors, with apprenticeships and pre-apprenticeship opportunities.</li></ul></li><li>Serve as a regional convenor of employers, training, and community partners to identify workforce needs and develop a regional workforce training plan.</li><li>Make a model employer commitment, prioritizing hiring of workers and small businesses in their community for state and local projects and developing diverse hiring goals.</li><li>Encourage contractors, where permissible under applicable law, to use local/economic hiring preferences to expand the diversity of the talent pool and build local talent.<br></li><li>Adapt career and technical education plans (i.e., Perkins State Plan) to meet new workforce needs created by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Administration Actions to Support Infrastructure Workforce Development<br></strong><br>The Administration is undertaking a wide range of actions to support workforce development related to the three industries highlighted in the Talent Pipeline Challenge. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law includes over $800 million in dedicated funding for job training, as well as additional investments where agencies may encourage the use of the funds for training. Agencies are including, where possible, workforce development as an allowable activity in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law programs and identifying funds both within the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, like funds from large federal-aid highway investments, and through other funding streams— like ARP’s State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds and Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA) funding — that can be invested in workforce training programs. The Department of Labor (DOL) is working to align federal workforce investments in registered apprenticeships and workforce programs at community colleges to meet infrastructure workforce needs. The Administration will also work to support state and local partnerships seeking to leverage WIOA funding to support workforce training as well as wrap-around services.<br></p>



<p><em><strong>ADDITIONAL DETAILS:</strong></em></p>



<p><strong>Administration Actions to Support Infrastructure Workforce Development</strong></p>



<p>Specific actions include:</p>



<ul><li>DOL announced an additional $50 million in Strengthening Community Colleges Training grants available to support the development and expansion of high-quality workforce training programs at community colleges. These grants will enable community colleges – individually or collectively – to proactively address equity gaps and meet the skills development needs of local employers and workers, including for infrastructure- related fields.</li><li>The Department of Commerce’s (DOC) Internet for All program’s Notice of Funding Opportunities (NOFOs) prioritize high labor standards and protections, as well as workforce development initiatives, to ensure there is a trained, diverse workforce ready to support the programs. In particular, the Broadband Equity, Access, and Deployment (BEAD) NOFO makes workforce development an eligible use of grant funds, and requires a highly-skilled workforce, which can be fulfilled through use of graduates of registered apprenticeships or other joint labor-management training programs. The NOFO also requires Eligible Entities to develop a plan for ensuring an available and highly skilled workforce in order to receive their funds.</li><li>The Department of Energy (DOE), in consultation with DOL, is providing $5 million to support a national battery workforce sectoral strategy, leading to national training standards and industry-recognized credentials.</li><li>DOE’s Solar Energy Technology Office, with Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding, is supporting quality pre-apprenticeships for clean energy construction careers.</li><li>DOL is developing, in collaboration with the Department of Transportation (DOT), DOE, and DOC, guidance that will encourage federal agencies and workforce system stakeholders —like American Job Centers (AJCs) and workforce boards, industry associations, worker centers, unions, and employers—to partner on infrastructure projects, share labor market information and expertise, and to shape workforce development activities to reflect proven strategies and practices that deliver sustainable, equitable outcomes.</li><li>In March, DOT and DOL signed a memorandum of understanding (MOU) that will help facilitate efforts between the two agencies on workforce and job quality. The MOU will leverage the individual and combined resources and expertise of both agencies to ensure the actions necessary to meet common goals related to expanding equitable access to quality jobs for workers and communities in the development and modernization of American infrastructure.</li><li>In March, DOT released the NOFO for the Low and No Emissions Bus program. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides the first-ever dedicated investment in our transit workforce to support the transition to clean technologies like battery electric buses. Five percent of grants under the program – up to $280 million over five years – will be used to fund workforce development training, including registered apprenticeships and other labor-management training programs, to train and upskill transit workers to maintain and operate zero emission vehicles and related charging infrastructure.</li><li>Last week, DOT and DOE released their proposed minimum standards for EV Charging. The standards emphasized strong workforce standards such as the Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP) to increase the safety and reliability of chargers while creating and supporting good-paying, highly skilled union jobs in communities across the country.</li></ul>



<p>Over the course of the summer, the Administration will collaborate with employers and other critical stakeholders to encourage action on new or existing workforce efforts. Agencies will also highlight best practices to address infrastructure talent pipeline needs.</p>



<p><em><strong>COMMITMENTS UNDERWAY:</strong></em></p>



<ul><li>Wilmington, Delaware is leveraging the Fiscal Recovery Funds from ARP to expand their Howard High School of Technology workforce development program – funding high school and adult job training in construction, plumbing, HVAC, and more. The city has also committed to using their local workforce for ARP funded neighborhood revitalization projects and is assisting local contractors in obtaining information and participating in ARP-funded projects. Wilmington is connecting graduates from the Howard High School training program to jobs with local employers working on local revitalization projects, and soon Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funded infrastructure projects – helping residents get access to these good jobs and helping employers access the talent they need to successfully complete these government projects.</li><li>Washington D.C. is expanding its D.C. Infrastructure Academy with Fiscal Recovery Funds from ARP to meet the need for skilled infrastructure professionals. The Infrastructure Academy offers high-quality training in infrastructure jobs under one roof and gives D.C. residents the opportunity to gain skills and secure good infrastructure jobs. The program recruits, trains, screens, and supports job placement of residents to fulfill the needs of the D.C. infrastructure industry, matching graduates to infrastructure jobs with leading companies in these high-demand fields.</li><li>Since 2012, the Electrical Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP) has trained and certified thousands of electricians throughout the country in the installation of electric vehicle supply equipment. 1,200 qualified electricians from populations traditionally underrepresented in the field have received scholarships to complete the program. Both IBEW and The Superior Group, a national electrical and technology construction and engineering firm headquartered in Columbus, Ohio, are partnering with EVITP to increase the number of certified electricians to meet growing demand.<ul><li>IBEW will aim to have a total of 10,000 EVITP certified electricians by August.</li><li>The Superior Group will increase the number of certified electricians in its ranks by 50. Additionally, The Superior Group is committed to attracting more than 100 potential new employees from underserved communities in Central Ohio by the end of 2022.</li></ul></li><li>Solely owned by a Black woman for 30 years, McKissack &amp; McKissack is a national architecture, engineering, program, and construction management firm. McKissack &amp; McKissack offers tuition assistance, technical lectures, reimbursement for membership fees, professional development programs, licenses, and certifications, and other opportunities that grow employee skills and increase individual earning power. It strives for these initiatives to attract and retain talent— especially from underserved communities.</li><li>Siemens, which will produce one million EV chargers by 2025, is taking a number of steps to build the pipeline of workers to fill the jobs that will be created. Siemens is developing technical training pathways and building talent pipelines with more than 100,000 academic institutions nationwide. They are also investing $37 million annually in employee training programs. And, Siemens recently started an apprenticeship program at their expanded manufacturing facility in Spartanburg, South Carolina.</li><li>The Building Pathways Building Trades Pre-Apprenticeship Program, launched in 2011 by the Building and Construction Trades Council of the Metropolitan District, prepares women, people of color, and other underserved Boston metro area residents to enter a union Registered Apprenticeship program – an effective “learn and earn” model providing pathways to the middle class. In addition to creating opportunities to access and prepare for building trades apprenticeships and family-sustaining careers in the construction industry, Building Pathways also educates middle and high school students about career opportunities in the building trades. Building Pathways has prepared and placed hundreds of Boston area residents for careers in union construction, with graduates comprised of over 90 percent people of color and over 55 percent women.</li><li>Wilson Community College in Wilson, North Carolina will pilot the Fiber Broadband Association’s Optical Telecom Installation Certification program. The program was designed with industry professionals to fill an existing fiber technician skills gap, and consists of 144 hours of combined class and lab instruction, provided through Wilson Community College. The program will eventually include a 2,000-hour apprenticeship at Greenlight Community Broadband and other regional broadband partners. The Fiber Broadband Association plans to replicate this model with community colleges and providers across the country.</li><li>The philanthropic community has also stepped up to support these efforts. The Families and Workers Fund has committed $1 million in aligned funding to help advance good jobs and diverse talent pipelines. This funding will focus on building the capacity of community-based nonprofits to scale innovative models for helping workers achieve economic mobility and career advancement and to participate in federal funding opportunities. Additionally, philanthropies are committing $250,000 to train workers in EVITP, including $150,000 from the Hewlett Foundation, which is committed to enhancing broad public benefits of the clean energy transition.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Father&#8217;s Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/17/a-proclamation-on-fathers-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 14:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55748</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every year on Father&#8217;s Day, we honor the men who help shape our character through their love, guidance, and devotion.  Dads and father figures across the country sacrifice so much to support their families and to ensure that their children can lead fulfilling lives.  &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; I remember my own father, who instilled in me some of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>     Every year on Father&#8217;s Day, we honor the men who help shape our character through their love, guidance, and devotion.  Dads and father figures across the country sacrifice so much to support their families and to ensure that their children can lead fulfilling lives. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I remember my own father, who instilled in me some of the most important values that guide me to this day.&nbsp; He taught me to treat all people with dignity, and that there is no higher calling than to be a good parent.&nbsp; He informed the way that I raised my own children &#8212; and how they continue to raise theirs.&nbsp; Just like my father, dads all over our country help teach their kids a sense of right and wrong that stays with them their entire lives.&nbsp; We owe these wonderful fathers a great deal of respect and gratitude.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For many of us, Father&#8217;s Day is an opportunity to pause and remember the fathers, stepfathers, father figures, grandfathers, brothers, and children that we have lost &#8212; but who are never gone.&nbsp; Too many of us know a dad who was lost too soon or a father who has lost a child.&nbsp; The pain runs deep, but we draw strength from knowing that our loved ones will always remain with us.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Like so many Americans, I am thankful for the precious time I have had both as a son and as a father.&nbsp; The unique challenges of the last few years have reminded us to cherish the time we have with our dads &#8212; learning more from them, showing them more gratitude, and showering them with more love.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration is dedicated to supporting our Nation&#8217;s fathers and families.&nbsp; We provided historic funding to help parents access child care during the pandemic, and we continue to fight for lower costs and higher quality child care for the long term. &nbsp;We are working to ensure that parents can access paid leave as they welcome a new child or care for a sick loved one. &nbsp;Additionally, we are working tirelessly for safer communities so that all fathers can raise their children in flourishing neighborhoods.&nbsp; From my own personal experience as a&nbsp;single dad, I know how critical support is when raising a family. &nbsp;That is why we remain committed to helping single parents ensure that their children have equal opportunities to thrive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Father&#8217;s Day, we pay tribute to the dads, stepdads, grandfathers, and father figures who lift us up on their shoulders so that we can reach our full potential.&nbsp; We express our gratitude for all that they sacrifice on our behalf. &nbsp;We honor the contributions they make every day to strengthen their families and our Nation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, in accordance with a joint resolution of the Congress approved April 24, 1972, as amended (36 U.S.C. 109) do hereby proclaim June 19, 2022, as Father&#8217;s Day.&nbsp; I&nbsp;direct the appropriate officials of the Government to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on this day.&nbsp; Let us honor our fathers, living and deceased, and show them the love and gratitude they deserve.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this seventeenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Juneteenth Day of Observance,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/17/a-proclamation-on-juneteenth-day-of-observance-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55751</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; After the Union Army captured New Orleans in 1862, slave owners in Confederate states migrated to Texas with more than 150,000 enslaved Black persons. &#160;For 3 years, even after President Abraham Lincoln issued the Emancipation Proclamation, enslaved Black Americans in Texas remained in brutal bondage, immorally and illegally deprived of their freedom and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; After the Union Army captured New Orleans in 1862, slave owners in Confederate states migrated to Texas with more than 150,000 enslaved Black persons. &nbsp;For 3 years, even after President Abraham Lincoln issued the Emancipation Proclamation, enslaved Black Americans in Texas remained in brutal bondage, immorally and illegally deprived of their freedom and basic dignity.&nbsp; On June 19, 1865 &#8212; over 2 years after President Lincoln declared all enslaved persons free &#8212; Major General Gordon Granger and Union Army troops marched to Galveston, Texas, to enforce the Emancipation Proclamation and free the last enslaved Black Americans in Texas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Those who were freed from bondage celebrated their long-overdue emancipation on June 19.&nbsp; Today, our Nation commemorates Juneteenth: &nbsp;a chance to celebrate human freedom, reflect on the grievous and ongoing legacy of slavery, and rededicate ourselves to rooting out the systemic racism that continues to plague our society as we strive to deliver the full promise of America to every American.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This Juneteenth, we are freshly reminded that the poisonous ideology of racism has not yet been defeated &#8212; it only hides.&nbsp; Our Nation continues to mourn the 10 lives senselessly taken in Buffalo, New York, and grieve for the families who have lost a piece of their soul.&nbsp; As we confront the awful reality of yet another gunman massacring innocent people in the name of hatred, racism, and fear, we must meet this moment with renewed resolve.&nbsp; We&nbsp;must stand together against white supremacy and show that bigotry and hate have no safe harbor in America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Juneteenth is a day to reflect on both bondage and freedom &#8212; a day of both pain and purpose.&nbsp; It is, in equal measure, a&nbsp;remembrance of both the long, hard night of slavery and subjugation, as well as a celebration of the promise of a brighter morning to come. &nbsp;On Juneteenth, we remember our extraordinary capacity to heal, to hope, and to emerge from our worst moments as a stronger, freer, and more just Nation. &nbsp;It is also a day to&nbsp;celebrate the power and resilience of Black Americans, who have endured generations of oppression in the ongoing journey toward equal justice, equal dignity, equal rights, and equal opportunity in America.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last year, I was proud to sign bipartisan legislation establishing Juneteenth as our newest Federal holiday, so that all Americans can feel the power of this day, learn from our history, celebrate our progress, and recognize and engage in the&nbsp;work that continues. &nbsp;Great nations do not ignore their most painful moments &#8212; they face them. &nbsp;We grow stronger as a country when we honestly confront our past injustices, including the profound suffering and injustice wrought by slavery and generations of segregation and discrimination against Black Americans.&nbsp; To heal, we must remember.&nbsp; We must never rest until the promise of our Nation is made real for all Americans.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The emancipation of enslaved Black Americans was not the end of our Nation&#8217;s work to deliver on the promise of equality &#8212; it was only the beginning.&nbsp; On Juneteenth, we recommit to our shared work to ensure racial justice, equity, and equality in America.&nbsp; We commemorate the centuries of struggle and progress led by abolitionists, educators, civil rights advocates, lawyers, activists, trade unionists, religious leaders, public officials, and everyday Americans who have brought our&nbsp;Nation closer to fulfilling its promise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As my good friend, the late Congressman Elijah Cummings, said, &#8220;Our children are the living messengers we send to a future we will never see.&#8221;&nbsp; Together as a Nation, let us continue our work together to build a country we are all proud to pass along to our children &#8212; one where the foundational promises and ideals of America ring true for every child and every family.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 19, 2022, as Juneteenth Day of Observance. &nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to acknowledge and condemn the history of slavery in our Nation and recognize how the impact of America&#8217;s original sin remains.&nbsp; I call on every American to celebrate the emancipation of all Black Americans and commit together to eradicate systemic racism and inequity that can never be tolerated and must always be fought against.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this seventeenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the White&#160;House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and Abuse&#160;Launch</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/readout-of-the-white-house-task-force-to-address-online-harassment-and-abuse-launch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 13:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, the Gender Policy Council and National Security Council launched the White House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and Abuse. The Task Force was established through a Presidential Memorandum signed on Thursday. Following remarks by Vice President Harris, Attorney General Merrick Garland, and U.S. Surgeon General Vivek Murthy, senior Administration officials heard from a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, the Gender Policy Council and National Security Council launched the White House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and Abuse. The Task Force was established through a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/16/memorandum-on-the-establishment-of-the-white-house-task-force-to-address-online-harassment-and-abuse/">Presidential Memorandum</a> signed on Thursday. Following remarks by Vice President Harris, Attorney General Merrick Garland, and U.S. Surgeon General Vivek Murthy, senior Administration officials heard from a panel of survivors and experts, who shared personal stories and recommendations on online harassment and abuse.<br><br>Survivors and experts highlighted the offline impact of online abuse, ranging from psychological distress and additional negative health impacts, to self-censorship, disruptions to education and economic loss, as well as experiences of other forms of physical and sexual violence. Participants noted that online harassment and abuse disproportionately impacts women, girls – especially women and girls of color – and LGBTQI+ individuals.&nbsp; Participants also provided concrete recommendations to prevent and respond to online harms. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Senior Administration officials reaffirmed the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to preventing and addressing gender-based violence wherever it occurs, including online. They <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/16/fact-sheet-presidential-memorandum-establishing-the-white-house-task-force-to-address-online-harassment-and-abuse/">outlined key actions</a> the Administration is already taking to address online harassment and abuse, and explained that the Task Force will provide a blueprint for action within 180 days with recommendations on additional steps the federal government can take. This blueprint will include a focus on expanding research to better understand the impact and scope of the problem, improving prevention efforts, increasing support for survivors, and strengthening accountability for offenders and technology platforms. Recommendations will also address the nexus between online misogyny, radicalization, and violence.&nbsp;<br><br>Following yesterday’s launch, the Task Force will hold roundtables to hear from survivors, advocates, legal experts, law enforcement and other stakeholders in the coming weeks and months.&nbsp; The Task Force is co-chaired by the White House’s Gender Policy Council and National Security Council and members include Cabinet officials, senior White House leadership, and the heads of department and agencies with policy and programmatic responsibilities key to preventing and addressing online harassment and abuse. &nbsp;<br><br>External Participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Sloane Stephens, U.S. Open Tennis Champion, survivor and mental health advocate</li><li>Francesca Rossi, survivor and victim advocate/Licensed Clinical Social Worker</li><li>Matthew Herrick, survivor and advocate</li><li>Mary Anne Franks, Cyber Civil Rights Initiative, Professor, University of Miami Law School</li><li>Carrie Goldberg, victim rights attorney</li><li>Melissa Diaz, Chief, San Diego County District Attorney’s Office Family Protection Division</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  President&#160;Biden to Galvanize Global Action to Strengthen Energy-Security and Tackle the Climate Crisis through the Major Economies Forum on Energy and&#160;Climate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-galvanize-global-action-to-strengthen-energy-security-and-tackle-the-climate-crisis-through-the-major-economies-forum-on-energy-and-climate/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden today will reconvene leaders of the Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate (MEF) to galvanize actions that will strengthen energy security, enhance the resilience of global food security, and tackle the climate crisis. &#160;These actions are all the more urgent following Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, which has disrupted energy markets, strained&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden today will reconvene leaders of the Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate (MEF) to galvanize actions that will strengthen energy security, enhance the resilience of global food security, and tackle the climate crisis. &nbsp;These actions are all the more urgent following Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, which has disrupted energy markets, strained economies with rising prices, and threatened vulnerable countries with severe food shortages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At today’s meeting, President Biden’s third MEF convening since taking office, world leaders will raise ambitions and followed the United States leadership, joining new efforts and initiatives aimed at tackling the climate crisis while advancing energy-security and food-security, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Global Methane Pledge Energy Pathway</strong>: Tackling methane leaks from the oil and gas sector by capturing wasted gas and bringing it to market — bolstering our energy-security and climate goals;</li><li><strong>Collective 2030 Zero-Emissions Vehicle Goal and Green Shipping Challenge: </strong>Putting more zero-emission vehicles on the road and decarbonizing ocean-based shipping — reducing emissions in the transport sector while breaking our dependence on volatile oil markets and prices;</li><li><strong>Clean Energy Technologies Demonstration Challenge:</strong> Speeding the commercialization of new technologies — enabling us to break dependence on other unabated, volatile fossil fuels and advance the clean energy transition; and</li><li><strong>Efforts to Enhance Food Security:</strong> Increasing fertilizer efficiency and alternatives — reducing agriculture emissions while bolstering global food security.</li></ul>



<p>The major economies that compose the MEF together account for roughly 80 percent of global GDP and global greenhouse gas emissions.&nbsp; Leader-level MEF meetings convened by President Biden in April and September 2021 contributed to the progress achieved at the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Glasgow (COP 26), where new commitments and initiatives brought the world much closer to keeping a 1.5-degree Celsius limit on warming within reach.</p>



<p>The MEF meeting will continue President Biden’s consistent engagement with leaders since Glasgow to further accelerate climate action, including at the recent meeting of the Quad, the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit, the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity, and this month’s Summit of the Americas.</p>



<p>Citing a recent round of international scientific assessments urgently underscoring the narrowing window for decisive action, President Biden will urge leaders to step up their climate efforts and to achieve further progress at COP 27 this November in Sharm el-Sheikh, Egypt.&nbsp; He will emphasize that the market disruptions triggered by the Ukraine crisis underscore the urgency of accelerating the clean energy transition — to alleviate both climate and energy security risks — and enhancing the resilience of the global food system.</p>



<p>To this end, several countries are expected to announce new 2030 emission targets as part of their nationally determined contributions (NDCs) under the Paris Agreement, with many intending to strengthen their existing 2030 NDC targets before COP 27.&nbsp; Leaders will also join collective efforts launched by President Biden across the energy, transportation and agriculture sectors, as described below.</p>



<p>The President will underscore that as we come together to reduce emissions, we must also continue to drive progress on adaptation.&nbsp; To this end, President Biden and Egyptian President Abdel Fattah El-Sisi will announce that the United States and Egypt will partner on an Adaptation in Africa event, focusing on tangible steps to improve people’s lives and build climate resilience.</p>



<p><strong><u>GLOBAL METHANE PLEDGE ENERGY PATHWAY:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Increasing Energy Security and Reducing Near-Term Warming by Capturing Flared, Vented, and Leaked Methane in the Oil and Gas Sector</em></strong></p>



<p>Every year, the world flares, vents, or leaks an amount of natural gas equivalent to over one-third of Russia’s annual gas production.&nbsp; At the same time, the International Energy Agency (IEA) estimates that nearly half of the oil and gas sector’s methane emissions can be captured and utilized at no net cost. &nbsp;Methane emissions account for more than half of net warming to date, and rapidly reducing them is the most effective strategy to avoid near-term warming.&nbsp; Stronger action in the oil and gas sector is the fastest and most cost-effective way to cut global methane emissions, with the potential to avoid nearly 0.1-degree C of warming by mid-century—equivalent to eliminating the greenhouse gas emissions of the entire road transport sector.&nbsp; These steps have the dual benefit of increasing global gas supplies from existing production, simply by capturing gas that is otherwise wasted and bringing it to market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the September 2021 MEF meeting, the United States and the European Union invited other countries to join them at COP 26 in launching the Global Methane Pledge (GMP) to reduce global anthropogenic methane emissions at least 30 percent below 2020 levels by 2030. &nbsp;And today, building on the success of the GMP, the United States and the European Union invited countries to join the new GMP Energy Pathway, to advance global climate progress.&nbsp; The GMP Energy Pathway aims to encourage all nations to capture the maximum potential of cost-effective methane mitigation in the oil and gas sector, and to eliminate routine flaring as soon as possible, and no later than 2030.&nbsp; Participating countries commit to support these efforts by providing new technical and financial resources and/or by enhancing domestic project and policy action.&nbsp; The initiative will bring together some of the most significant global gas producers and consumers in the world.&nbsp; To support the GMP Energy Pathway, the United States will provide $3.5 million in technical assistance through the Global Methane Initiative, and intends to support a transfer of at least $1.5 million remaining in the Pilot Auction Facility to the World Bank Global Gas Flaring Reduction Partnership.</p>



<p>Domestically, the U.S. is continuing its progress in reducing oil and gas methane emissions across the value chain, supporting American gas companies in cutting emissions and saving consumer costs.&nbsp; Building upon the new source performance standards and emissions guidelines proposed in November 2021, the Environmental Protection Agency will issue a supplemental proposed rule for public comment in 2022 to reduce methane and other air emissions from new and existing oil and gas facilities.&nbsp; The Department of Interior is evaluating new regulations to reduce the wasteful flaring and venting of gas produced on public lands.&nbsp; The Department of Transportation is developing a comprehensive set of safety-related regulations that aim to reduce methane emissions from gas pipeline systems that stretch from production-related gathering lines, through trunk line transmission pipelines, and into local distribution pipelines.&nbsp; In addition, new funding provided under the Bipartisan Infrastructure law is enabling the Department of Transportation to spend $1 billion on replacing unsafe and leaking gas distribution pipelines.</p>



<p><strong><u>CLEAN ENERGY TECHNOLOGIES DEMONSTRATION CHALLENGE: </u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Raising $90 Billion for High-Priority Demonstration Projects This Decade</em></strong><strong><em></em></strong></p>



<p>Achieving net-zero emissions by 2050 requires developing and scaling innovative clean technologies not yet commercially available.&nbsp; The IEA’s <em>Net Zero by 2050</em> roadmap identifies at least $90 billion in public investments needed by 2026 for large-scale clean energy technology demonstration projects around the world to be completed this decade. &nbsp;Investing in the first several commercial-scale demonstrations of transformative technologies during this decade will enable their large-scale deployment to achieve global net-zero emissions by midcentury in every sector of the economy, including heavy industry and long-distance transport.&nbsp; Targeted technologies could include, for example, clean hydrogen, carbon dioxide removal, grid-scale energy storage, industrial decarbonization and carbon capture, advanced nuclear, advanced clean fuels, and next-generation offshore wind.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the MEF meeting, the President will challenge other countries to join the United States in supporting a collective goal to reach the $90 billion in public investment recommended by the IEA.&nbsp; These public investments will leverage additional private investments and advance innovative technologies already in demand by the world’s largest companies through the First Movers Coalition launched by the United States and the World Economic Forum.&nbsp; The President will invite interested countries to come prepared to announce specific investment levels at the Global Clean Energy Action Forum that the United States is hosting this September in Pittsburgh, along with preliminary action plans identifying how they will deploy these technologies to promote an inclusive and equitable transition.</p>



<p>Under the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law signed by President Biden, the United States is devoting $21.5 billion to high-priority clean technology demonstration projects.&nbsp; And just last week the President invoked the Defense Production Act to boost manufacturing of electrolyzers that will be used to produce clean hydrogen and the Department of Energy recently issued a loan guarantee to construct one of the world’s largest clean hydrogen storage facilities.</p>



<p><strong><u>COLLECTIVE 2030 ZERO-EMISSION VEHICLE GOAL:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Reducing Emissions and Dependence on Volatile Oil Markets by Accelerating Zero-Emissions Vehicle Deployment</em></strong></p>



<p>Achieving net zero will require a profound transformation of other sectors, including transportation.&nbsp; To keep a 1.5 C limit within reach, the global market share of zero-emission vehicles (ZEVs) must reach at least 50 percent of new light-duty vehicle sales by 2030.&nbsp; In some advanced economies, transportation is the single-largest emitting sector and vehicle purchases are causing rapid emissions growth in many developing economies.</p>



<p>Accelerating the deployment of ZEVs will also have the additional benefit of reduced oil dependence — enhancing energy security and insulating economies from price volatility driven by geopolitical and other supply disruptions.&nbsp; Accelerated ZEV deployment will also improve public health by reducing emissions of conventional pollutants.</p>



<p>With the support of automakers, labor, and states, President Biden earlier this year set a goal of ZEVs – including battery electric, fuel cell electric, and plug-in hybrid vehicles – achieving 50 percent of all new light-duty U.S. vehicle sales in 2030.&nbsp; At the MEF, the President will invite participants to join the United States in a collective goal of 50 percent ZEVs by 2030.&nbsp; By accelerating action in key markets, this collective goal will help speed a fully global transformation of the automotive sector.&nbsp; Other countries are invited to join the ZEV deployment goal on the road to COP 27.</p>



<p>To advance this goal in the United States, the Environmental Protection Agency and Department of Transportation have, working closely together, finalized stronger vehicle standards through 2026 and are now considering ambitious standards to at least 2030.&nbsp; The Biden Administration is also implementing the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to deploy $7.5 billion in funding for a national network of electric vehicle chargers and more than $7 billion to build a strong domestic battery supply chain and create high-quality jobs.</p>



<p><strong><u>GREEN SHIPPING CHALLENGE:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Catalyzing Action This Decade to Decarbonize Ocean-Based Shipping</em></strong></p>



<p>Emissions from the shipping sector are significant, rising, and on a trajectory incompatible with the goals of the Paris Agreement.&nbsp; If shipping were a “country,” it would be the world’s eighth-largest emitter.&nbsp; At COP 26, many countries, recognizing the urgency of reducing emissions from the shipping sector, joined the Declaration on Zero Emission Shipping by 2050 and the Clydebank Declaration supporting the establishment of green shipping corridors.&nbsp; The United States will also announce that it is co-leading the Zero-Emission Shipping research Mission in Mission Innovation together with Norway and Denmark. &nbsp;Further efforts on shipping decarbonization followed at the recent Our Ocean Conference co-hosted by the United States and Palau.</p>



<p>To build on these efforts, the United States and Norway will announce the launch of a Green Shipping Challenge for COP 27.&nbsp; This initiative encourages governments, ports, maritime carriers, cargo owners, and others in the shipping value chain to come forward with concrete steps that will help put the international shipping sector on a credible pathway this decade toward full decarbonization no later than 2050.&nbsp; These could include, for example, steps to produce zero-emission fuels; develop zero-emission bunkering and recharging capabilities; deploy low- or zero-emission vessels; and create, or provide financial and technical support for green shipping corridors.&nbsp; President Biden will invite leaders to express their support for the Green Shipping Challenge and to announce specific actions under the initiative at COP 27.</p>



<p><strong><u>GLOBAL FERTILIZER CHALLENGE:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Strengthening Food Security and Reducing Agriculture Emissions by Advancing Fertilizer Efficiency and Alternatives</em></strong><strong><em>&nbsp;</em></strong><strong><em></em></strong></p>



<p>Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine has shocked the global food system, showing just how vulnerable it is to disruption.&nbsp; Wheat and fertilizer prices have increased more than 40 percent in some regions, exacerbating food insecurity concerns globally.&nbsp; Even before the invasion, food and fertilizer prices were rising as a result of the combined effects of the COVID-19 pandemic, climate-related impacts, armed conflicts, and low supply-chain resilience. &nbsp;Climate-driven food security shocks will continue to cause food scarcity and suffering if steps are not taken to increase food system resilience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Inability to access fertilizer hampers agricultural productivity in many low-income countries, while in most major economies, more than 50 percent of fertilizers do not reach the intended crop.&nbsp; A 10 percent reduction in global fertilizer loss and waste would free up more than the total amount of mineral fertilizer used by all African countries. &nbsp;In addition, nitrogen fertilizer production consumes up to 4 percent of global natural gas supply; increasing fertilizer efficiency in the short term and transitioning to more affordable alternatives in the medium term will reduce natural gas dependence.&nbsp; Steps to increase the adoption of innovative, alternative, and efficient fertilizer and cropping practices will alleviate pressure on fertilizer and natural gas supplies, increase fertilizer availability, lower nitrous oxide emissions, and reduce food insecurity globally. &nbsp;</p>



<p>In recent months, as part of a continuing effort to add resilience to the agriculture and food supply chains, the United States has established a $500 million program to support innovative and sustainable U.S. fertilizer production and has strengthened support to farmers for the use of precision agriculture and other techniques to improve fertilizer use efficiency.</p>



<p>To spur broader efforts, President Biden will invite countries to join the United States in launching the Global Fertilizer Challenge with the goal of raising $100 million in new funding by COP 27.  The Global Fertilizer Challenge will support innovative research, demonstrations, and training to help countries with high fertilizer usage and loss adopt efficient nutrient management and alternative fertilizers and cropping systems.  It will be implemented in partnership with the Agriculture Innovation Mission for Climate, which now has over 200 government and non-government partners.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Delivering Progress on the Biden-&#8288;Harris Lead Pipe and Paint Action&#160;Plan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-delivering-progress-on-the-biden-harris-lead-pipe-and-paint-action-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Six months since the President and Vice President unveiled the Biden-Harris Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan, the Administration has taken swift action and made quick progress. The Biden-Harris Administration has announced more than $4 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funds and annual appropriations that can be used to begin replacing all of America’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Six months since the President and Vice President unveiled the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/16/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-lead-pipe-and-paint-action-plan/">Biden-Harris Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan</a>, the Administration has taken swift action and made quick progress. The Biden-Harris Administration has announced more than $4 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funds and annual appropriations that can be used to begin replacing all of America’s lead pipes while mobilizing additional resources and tools to get rid of lead, ensure Americans can drink clean water, and live in healthy homes.</p>



<p>Today, to continue momentum implementing the action plan, Vice President Harris, Housing and Urban Development Secretary Marcia Fudge, and Environmental Protection Agency Administrator Michael Regan are in Pittsburgh to provide an update on the Administration’s commitment to addressing lead pipes and paint, including through announcing $500 million for states and local government to reduce lead exposure and build healthier homes. States and localities can begin applying for the awards, which will target disadvantaged communities in line with the President’s Justice40 Initiative.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris believe no child, no family, and no American should drink water with lead or be exposed to lead paint in their homes. That’s why they made replacing lead pipes a centerpiece of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and why Vice President Harris visited AFL-CIO to release an action plan that helps ensure federal, state, and local resources are moving quickly. Together, their leadership, vision, and actions are removing lead from water and homes, creating good-paying jobs, and supporting the low-income and communities of color disproportionately impacted.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>Outlined below is how the Administration is making critical progress on the Biden-Harris Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan:</em></p>



<p><strong><u>Tackling Lead Pipes and Paint with Historic Investments</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>Today, the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) is making $500&nbsp;million available for states and local governments to protect children and families from lead-based paint and other home health hazards, targeting the awards to disadvantaged communities, in line with the Justice40 Initiative, by including rating points based on the percentage of the area the grant will target that are disadvantaged communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>In March, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) issued a memorandum to guide collaborative implementation with state, local, and Tribal partners water infrastructure funding through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, including $2.9 billion for lead service line replacement in 2022. EPA’s memo provided technical guidance to states on the disadvantaged community definitions and EPA oversight of the state programs. Working collaboratively, EPA and state SRF programs continue to make progress towards Justice40.</li></ul>



<ul><li>In May, EPA announced that it is making available $ 7.28 billion in new federal grant funding for the Drinking Water State Revolving Fund (DWSRF). This funding can be used for loans that help drinking water systems install treatment for contaminants, improve distribution systems by removing lead service lines and improve system resiliency to natural disasters such as floods.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>In May, EPA issued a new funding memorandum to guide the distribution of $154 million in FY22 Tribal water infrastructure funding from the BIL to support access to safe drinking water and wastewater management in Tribal communities, including projects to replace lead pipes.</li></ul>



<ul><li>In February, EPA announced $20 million in available grant funding to assist communities and schools with removing sources of lead in drinking water. This grant funding, and additional funding through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will help make rapid progress on the goal of addressing lead and removing lead pipes across the country.</li></ul>



<ul><li>In April, the Village of Elberta, Michigan received $3.4 million in grant and low-interest loans from USDA, leveraging an additional $2 million in state assistance, to improve their water system and remediate lead. Approximately, 79 percent of the service laterals in the water distribution system are known or suspected to contain lead.&nbsp;&nbsp;USDA has an additional $23.8 million in projects containing lead remediation that are nearing approval and other applications in development.</li></ul>



<ul><li>In March, USDA provided a $350,000 award to the City of Linwood, Kansas for their Water System Improvements Project.&nbsp;&nbsp;Leveraging $499,586 in HUD’s Community Development and Block Grant funds and $150,000 in applicant contribution, this project will enable the City of Linwood to replace approximately 75 cast iron service lines that may contain lead joints and to make other necessary improvements to the distribution system.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>In March, EPA issued a Request for Applications for approximately $100 million in federal funding through the Environmental Finance Center (EFC) Grant Program. A major priority for this program is to provide technical support to disadvantaged communities across the country. Selected technical assistance providers will help communities develop and submit project proposals, including State Revolving Fund (SRF) applications for Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding to reduce lead in drinking water.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Schools and child care facilities are also accessing funds for projects to replace lead lines and remediate lead plumbing, pipes, and paint. In March, the Anson Madison Water District in Maine received a $6 million low-interest loan and $3.5 million grant to mitigate lead exposure for 3,700 residents, including at two area high schools and other educational institutions. In January 2022, USDA’s Rural Development obligated $9.5 million to Columbus County, North Carolina, for the construction and cost overrun of a new replacement school facility housing Pre-K through 8th grade. This new facility replaces two school facilities ranging from 60-94 years old with asbestos in almost all flooring and lead paint throughout – ensuring the new facility meets all code requirements.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>In January, the Department of the Treasury adopted the final rule for the $350 billion State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds, which provides for an expanded set of eligible lead remediation uses, including replacement of faucets and fixtures in schools and daycares, and confirms recipients’ ability to use funds for the replacement of lead services lines. The final rule took effect on April 1, 2022. Already, recipients of the State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds, authorized by the American Rescue Plan, are investing more than $60 million in lead remediation projects. Some examples of this include:&nbsp;<ul><li>The City of Toledo, OH plans to replace all private lead service lines in the city (approximately 3,000 lines) at no cost to homeowners. Additionally, the City will replace many public lead service lines co-located with private lines.&nbsp;</li></ul><ul><li>The City of Buffalo, NY has budgeted $10 million for an expansion of the City’s ROLL program so that at least an additional 1,000 homes can have their lead water service lines replaced. The City has already successfully replaced the lines in 500 homes and this expanded capacity will more than double its impact.</li></ul><ul><li>The City of Pittsburgh, PA has budgeted $17.5 million to partner with the Pittsburgh Water and Sewer Authority to complete projects to remediate lead in drinking water.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Making It Easier to Access Funding</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>In line with the Office of Management and Budget’s commitment to make existing sources of federal funding for lead pipes accessible to the public, in March, the President Biden’s FY23 Budget request included a summary of all the sources funding for lead pipes across the federal government.&nbsp;</li><li>In May, EPA and partners across the federal government announced a renewed Tribal Infrastructure Task Force to improve federal government coordination efforts to deliver water infrastructure and financial assistance to American Indian Tribes and Alaska Native Villages.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Removing Lead in Federally-Assisted Housing</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>HUD’s Office of Public and Indian Housing will soon issue a FY22 notice of funding opportunity (NOFO) for its Lead-Based Paint Capital Fund grant program that will support control of lead-based paint hazards in public housing.</li></ul>



<ul><li>HUD’s Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes is developing a plan for removing lead service lines from HUD-assisted housing when a public water system is replacing a water main (in the street) but is not removing the service lines at the same time.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Remediating Lead in Schools and Child Care Centers&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>The Department of Health and Human Service’s (HHS) Administration for Children and Families (ACF) and EPA are collaboratively developing a series of three training webinars on lead testing and remediation in drinking water throughout child care and early childhood facilities using the 3-Ts (Training, Testing, Taking Action). The webinars will provide presentations from HHS and EPA, alongside interactive tools, and case studies.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>HUD’s Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes&nbsp;continues to partner with 289&nbsp;state, tribal, and local governments on their implementing on 349 grants that use its funds to make homes of low-income children and their families lead-safe and healthy.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Closing Gaps in Childhood Lead Testing&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) is working with Pediatric Environmental Health Specialty Units (PEHSU) to raise awareness and serve as a place for lead referrals and screening. The PEHSUs are a group of environmental health specialists who provide medical information and advice on environmental conditions that influence reproductive and children’s health. PEHSUs are academically based, typically at university medical centers.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>CDC and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) are also planning a state-to-state learning webinar to showcase the efforts of two to three states that have undertaken efforts to increase blood lead screening rates. CDC and CMS will identify examples and a platform to share approaches, best practices, and lessons learned, and encourage coordination across state agencies, to consider implementation of levers to increase blood lead screening rates.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Developing New Regulations to Protect Communities from Lead in Drinking Water</u></strong></p>



<ul><li>EPA is advancing the regulatory process to develop a new proposed rule, the Lead and Copper Rule Improvements. EPA intends to propose requirements that, along with other actions, would result in the replacement of all lead service lines as quickly as is feasible. EPA also intends to consider opportunities to strengthen tap sampling requirements and explore options to reduce the complexity and confusion associated with the action level and trigger level, with a focus on reducing health risks in more communities. The goal of these potential lead service line replacement regulatory improvements—coupled with non-regulatory actions—is to more equitably protect public health.</li></ul>



<ul><li>EPA announced in May that it is seeking input from stakeholder groups on the forthcoming Lead and Copper Rule Improvements proposal. EPA is inviting small businesses, governments, and not-for-profit organizations to participate as Small Entity Representatives for a Small Business Advocacy Review Panel. EPA accepted nominations for the panel until May 18, 2022.&nbsp;At the same time, EPA is implementing the Lead and Copper Rule Revisions (LCRR) to help ensure that lead service line inventories are developed by public water systems by 2024.</li></ul>



<ul><li>To further protect children from lead, EPA is working to revise the 2021 Dust Lead Clearance Levels and the related 2019 Dust Lead Hazard Standards final rules. These rules provide important provisions to protect children from exposure to lead dust on floors and windowsills. The hazard standards are used to identify a dust-lead hazard and the clearance levels are used to demonstrate adequate clean-up after abatement activities. These apply to pre-1978 homes and child-care facilities. The courts sent the previous Administration’s 2019 rule back to EPA to redo to ensure the levels are protective. EPA currently plans to propose revisions to these rules in FY 2023.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 3613 and S.&#160;4160</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/16/bill-signed-h-r-3613-and-s-4160/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 22:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 3613, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 202 Trumbull Street in Saint Clair, Michigan, as the Corporal Jeffrey Robert Standfest Post Office Building; Thank you to Representatives McClain, Bergman, Huizenga, Meijer, Moolenaar, Upton, Walberg, Andy Levin, Stevens, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, June 16, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 3613, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 202 Trumbull Street in Saint Clair, Michigan, as the Corporal Jeffrey Robert Standfest Post Office Building;</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives McClain, Bergman, Huizenga, Meijer, Moolenaar, Upton, Walberg, Andy Levin, Stevens, and Dingell for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 4160, the &#8220;Supreme Court Police Parity Act of 2022,&#8221; which authorizes the Marshal of the Supreme Court and Supreme Court Police to protect immediate family members of the Chief Justice, any Associate Justice, or any officer of the Supreme Court.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Cornyn and Coons for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
