<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 23:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden to U.S. Air Force Personnel and Families Stationed at Royal Air Force Mildenhall</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-to-u-s-air-force-personnel-and-families-stationed-at-royal-air-force-mildenhall/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 23:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Royal Air Force MildenhallMildenhall, United Kingdom 8:45 P.M. BST THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, Mildenhall! Colonel, thank you for that introduction and your service leading this team in such a difficult time.  Because we know that it’s the whole family who serves; I also want to Melissa.   I know &#8212; I know your next assignment at U.S.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Royal Air Force Mildenhall<br>Mildenhall, United Kingdom</p>



<p><br>8:45 P.M. BST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, Mildenhall!<br><br>Colonel, thank you for that introduction and your service leading this team in such a difficult time.  Because we know that it’s the whole family who serves; I also want to Melissa.   I know &#8212; I know your next assignment at U.S. Transportation Command starts soon.  So congratulations, and thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>And, Sydney, you&#8217;re 14 years old.  When I was 14 &#8212; please, at ease.  I keep forgetting I&#8217;m President.  (Laughter.)  When I was 14 years old, I would have been &#8212; I mean this sincerely &#8212; scared to death to stand up in front of a microphone, in a large crowd or small crowd.  See, when I was a child, I used to stutter badly &#8212; for real.  I had great difficulty speaking in front of other people.  And &#8212; so I expect that when you&#8217;re President, you’ll remember me.  (Laughter.)  You&#8217;ll remember me.   You’re, really, quite a polished young woman.  Thank you.<br><br>And, you know, it&#8217;s got to be hard to have your dad deployed to Afghanistan.  And I also know how proud you are of him and your mom, Chief Master Sergeant, for being part of the leadership team here.<br><br>Our son Beau served as a U.S. attorney for a while in &#8212; in Kosovo for a while.  Matter of fact, they erected a war monument to him.  And &#8212; and then he went on and he joined the National Guard.  Gave up his job as attorney general of the State of Delaware so he can go with his unit to Iraq for a year.  And when he got promoted to Major, I said, “Beau, you&#8217;re now a field-grade officer.”  I was in and out of Iraq and Afghanistan about 28 times.  And I said, “You&#8217;re now a field-grade officer.”  He said, “Dad, I have no illusions.  I know who runs the military: chief master sergeants.”  (Laughs.)  (Applause.)  So, I just want you to know we know.  Okay? <br><br>Thank you for your incredible dedication and service.  And, you know, I want to thank you all &#8212; all of you &#8212; all your families &#8212; for the sacrifices they&#8217;ve made.  And congratulations to having just a wonderful child.<br><br>There’s an awful lot of history at this base, a proud history for the British people &#8212; the bravery and heroism of the Royal Air Force pilots fighting to defend their nation.<br><br>I’m sure everyone here knows the history, but just six hours after Britain and France declared war on Germany in 1939, three Wellington bombers took off from Mildenhall and bombed Nazi battleships. <br><br>And over the course of World War Two, out of this base, RAF bombers dropped nearly 28,000 tons of bombs on Nazi Germany, flying more than 8,000 sorties.  This base has been a significant source of British air power &#8212; a proud, proud history of a proud nation. <br><br>But I also know there’s also an awful lot of American Air Force pride in this room tonight.  World War Two was when the U.S. Army Air Force formed the 100th Bombardment Group. <br><br>And, by the way, my &#8212; just so you know &#8212; although my uncle, who was killed in World War Two in New Guinea was Army &#8212; he was the Army Air Corps.  He got shot down in a reconnaissance flight.  And he would &#8212; he&#8217;s looking down and thinking, “All these years, my God, what this Air Force has become.”  It&#8217;s incredible. <br><br>The 100th also ran more than 8,000 sorties into hostile territory and supported operations from D-Day to the Battle of the Bulge, where another uncle of mine served.<br><br>And when they first arrived in the UK in ’43, the unit took such heavy losses, it earned the moniker that has been passed down to this day: “The Bloody Hundredth.”  The Bloody Hundredth.  <br><br>So let me hear it for the 100th Air Wing &#8212; Air Refueling Wing, AKA &#8212; known as the “The Bloody Hundredth.”  (Applause.)<br><br>And what about the 352nd Special Operations Wing?  (Applause.) <br><br>There&#8217;s Team &#8212; Team Reconnaissance.  Members of the Air Mobility Command.  (Applause.)<br><br>Do we have any folks from the 48th Fighter Wing, over from RAF &#8212; (Applause.)  By the way &#8212; I think maybe.<br><br>The 501st Combat Support Wing from RAF Alconbury.  (Applause.)<br><br>And this may be a historic first for an Air Force base, but I hear there just might be a few members of the United States Army here tonight with us.  (Applause.)  Come on, man.<br><br>To all of you airmen and soldiers, I want to just say thank you.  We owe you.  We’re so damn proud of you.  So proud.  And I only wish my Major was here to thank you as well.  Thank you &#8212; everything you do, for everything you are. <br><br>There’s nothing that Jill and I enjoy more than spending time with our troops and their families, wherever we go in the world.<br><br>I had the great honor of being in and out of Afghanistan and Iraq well over 27, 28 times.  I think Jill is the only Second Lady in American history who has gone into a warzone &#8212; into Baghdad with me as well. <br><br>You&#8217;re the best &#8212; you’re the best of our country.  That&#8217;s not hyperbole.  You&#8217;re the ones who sign up and run toward danger when duty calls.  Less than 1 percent of Americans make the choice that you make &#8212; that you made.  But the rest of us &#8212; the other 99 percent of us &#8212; we owe you.  We owe you big.<br><br>I’ve long said that, as a nation, we have many obligations,<br>but we only have one truly sacred obligation &#8212; only one &#8212; and that’s to properly prepare and equip the women and men we send into harm’s way, and to care for you and your families, both while you’re deployed and when you come home.<br><br>And now that I have the incredible honor of serving as your Commander-in-Chief, I believe that even more strongly.  You know &#8212; and I want to give an extra special thank you to all the families. <br><br>As you heard from Jill, we Bidens are a proud military family, and we know there&#8217;s not just the person who wears the uniform who serves; the whole family has to step up, the whole family makes sacrifices.  There&#8217;s a famous Irish poet who said, “They also serve who only stand and wait.”<br><br>I watched all those months Beau was in Kosovo.  And then I watched all those &#8212; that year he was in &#8212; in Iraq.  She would stand at that sink, leaving for school, drinking her coffee, and I could see her lips moving, saying that prayer, hoping that car never drove up in front of the house, hoping you never got that phone call. <br><br>And that&#8217;s even more true this past year during the lockdowns and safety precautions to curb the spread of COVID-19.  Everyone in this room knows that our military families are essential &#8212; essential to our strength.<br><br>It’s the key reason Jill relaunched Joining Forces: to make sure we’re doing everything we can to support our military spouses and children, and their mothers and fathers as well, just like they support all of you.<br><br>You know, you not only did an amazing job keeping COVID-19 under control on the base; you took care of each other and your mental health throughout the initiatives like your Spouse-to-Spouse Connection and your Wellness Advocacy Team.  (Cheers.)  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  As you all know, this is a team sport. <br><br>And my mother would kill me if she were here.  She&#8217;d say, “Joey, you shouldn’t have…&#8221; &#8212; I should’ve turned around and apologized for by back to you.  I apologize.  (Laughter.)  I haven’t figured out how to turn in 360 yet.  (Laughter.)<br><br>But, folks, thousands of hours spent volunteering to make sure everyone got through this.  It was so important.<br><br>I know that these last 15 months added a lot of new pressure, but all of you rose to the task together as one team &#8212; Team Mildenhall.  And you never let up on your mission.<br><br>And I’m so proud to be here with all of you to kick off my first overseas trip as President.  I&#8217;ve been in and out of here many, many times.  I’ve visited well over 100 countries as President or as Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee &#8212; or I meant as Vice President or Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee.  This is my first overseas trip as President of the United States. <br><br>I&#8217;m heading to the G7, then to the NATO Ministerial, and then to meet with Mr. Putin to let him know what I want him to know.  (Laughter and applause.)<br><br>And at every point along the way, we’re going to make it clear that the United States is back and democracies of the world are standing together to tackle the toughest challenges and the issues that matter most to our future; that we’re committed to leading with strength, defending our values, and delivering for our people.<br><br>America is better positioned to advance our national security and our economic prosperity when we bring together like-minded nations to stand with us.  These nations that have shed blood alongside of us in defense of our shared values.  Our unrivaled network of alliances and partnerships that are the key to American advantage in the world and have been.  They&#8217;ve made the world safer for all of us, and they are how we are going to meet the challenges of today, which are changing rapidly.  We&#8217;re going to meet it, though, from a position of strength. <br><br>Our alliances weren&#8217;t built by coercion or maintained by threats.  They&#8217;re grounded on democratic ideals and a shared vision of the future and where every voice matters &#8212; (applause) &#8212; where the rights &#8212; where the rights of all people are protected. <br><br>It’s the same reason so many of you signed up to serve, to proudly defend and honor the democratic values that are the wellspring of our national strength. <br><br>If our British friends will excuse me quoting the Declaration of Independence &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; America is unique in all the world in that we are not formed based on geography, or ethnicity, or religion, but on an idea &#8212; an idea.  The only nation in the world founded on the notion of an idea. <br><br>“We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men and women are created equal, endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights,” including “life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.”  We mean it.  No nation can defeat us as long as we stick to our values. <br><br>It&#8217;s our American creed.  It’s what makes us who we are.  And it’s what draws friends and partners to our side.  And for hundreds of years, American patriots have fought, and sometimes died, defending those values.<br><br>Folks, look, I&#8217;m often quoted by the press as saying, “America leads not by the example of its power, but by the power of our example.”  All of you &#8212; our service members stationed around the world &#8212; you are the solid steel spine of America around which alliances are built and strengthened year after year. <br><br>These partnerships have hardened and have been hardened in the fire of war, and generations of Americans and service members who fought them, like the original Bloody Hundredth and those <s>RFA</s> [RAF] pilots, and their shared mission in World War Two &#8212; flying, fighting, winning.  It was done together. <br><br>These bonds of history and shared fi- &#8212; sacrifice run deep and are strong, based on values.  And they endure. <br><br>The connections and camaraderie between our troops, this community of American citizens stationed in the UK &#8212; U.S. visiting forces and families, 20,000 strong &#8212; are not only warriors, you’re diplomats and you’re bridge-builders.  You are the essential part of what makes up this Special Relationship between Great Britain and the United States. <br><br>Over the next few days, as I said, I&#8217;ll be participating in meetings with many of our closest partners at the G7 in Cornwall, and then on to Brussels and NATO Summit of the EU &#8212; and the EU Summit. <br><br>This diplomacy is essential, because no single nation acting alone can meet all the challenges we face today because the world is changing.  To quote another Irish poet, he said, “The world&#8217;s changed, changed utterly.  A terrible beauty has been born.” <br><br>We&#8217;re in a different place than we were 10 years ago &#8212; a better position but a different place.  We have to build the shared future we seek: a future where nations are free from coercion or dominance by more powerful states; where the global commons &#8212; the seas, the air, the space &#8212; and space &#8212; remain open and accessible for the benefit of all. <br><br>To tackle this century&#8217;s most pressing challenges, we have to do it together.  We have to end COVID-19, not just at home &#8212; which we&#8217;re doing &#8212; but everywhere.  There&#8217;s no wall high enough to keep us safe from this pandemic or the next biological threat we face &#8212; and there will be others.<br><br>It requires coordinated, multilateral action.  We must all commit to an ambitious climate action if we&#8217;re going to prevent the worst impacts of climate change, limiting global warning [sic] &#8212; warming to no more than 1.5 degrees Celsius, and lead the global &#8212; the global transition to clean energy technology. <br><br>You know, when I went over in the Tank in the Pentagon, when I first was elected Vice President, with President Obama, the military sat us down to let us know what the greatest threats facing America were &#8212; the greatest physical threats.  And this is not a joke: You know what the Joint Chiefs told us the greatest threat facing America was?  Global warming.  Because there&#8217;ll be significant population movements, fights over land, millions of people leaving places because they’re literally sinking below the sea in Indonesia; because of the fights over what is arable land anymore. <br><br>With the G7, we plan to launch an ambitious effort to support resilience and development around the world by investing in high-quality, high-standard physical, digital, and health infrastructures. <br><br>We have to make sure that new technologies and norms of conduct in cyberspace are established, including addressing the growing threat of ransomware attacks that are governed by our democratic values, not by the autocrats who are letting it happen. <br><br>These are all critical national security issues in 2021, and we&#8217;re going to be driving this agenda together with our G7 partners.<br><br>In Brussels, I will make it clear that the United States’ commitment to our NATO Alliance and Article 5 is rock solid.  It&#8217;s a sacred obligation that we have under Article 5.<br><br>The U.S. and the UK are both founding members of NATO &#8212; the strongest military and political alliance in the history of the world.  And that&#8217;s not hyperbole.<br><br>Our troops have stood shoulder-to-shoulder around the world, including serving bravely in the mountains of Afghanistan for the past 20 years.<br><br>Our NATO Allies have had our backs when it mattered, just like we&#8217;ve had theirs when it’s mattered.  And now we need to modernize our Alliance, investing on our critical infrastructure, our cyber capabilities, and to keep us secure against every threat that we’ve faced over the last decade, and the new challenges we&#8217;re about to face as well.<br><br>With the European Union leaders, I&#8217;ll discuss how the United States can work with Europe to address the full range of issues that require the full strength of our transatlantic partnership, including working together to shape the new rules for the 21st century economies. <br><br>And only after these meetings with our closest democratic partners to develop a common agenda and renewed purpose, I’ll travel to Geneva to sit down with a man I&#8217;ve spent time with before: President Vladimir Putin. <br><br>We&#8217;re not seeking conflict with Russia.  We want a stable, pretictable [sic] &#8212; predictable relationship.  Our two nations share incredible responsibilities, and among them ensuring strategic stability and upholding arms control agreements.  I take that responsibility seriously. <br><br>But I&#8217;ve been clear: The United States will respond in a robust and meaningful way when the Russian government engages in harmful activities.  We&#8217;ve already demonstrated that.  I&#8217;m going to communicate that there are consequences for violati- &#8212; for violating the sovereignty of democracies in the United States and Europe and elsewhere. <br><br>I&#8217;m going to be clear that the Transatlantic Alliance will remain vital &#8212; a vital source of strength for the UK, Europe, and the United States.  And I’m going to make sure there&#8217;s no doubt as to whether the United States will rise in defense of our most deeply held values and our fundamental interest. <br><br>Here&#8217;s why this all matters so much right now: I believe we&#8217;re at an inflection point in world history &#8212; the moment where it falls to us to prove that democracies will not just endure, but they will excel as we rise to seize the enormous opportunities of a new age. <br><br>We have to discredit those who believe that the age of democracy is over, as some of our fellow nations believe.  We have to expose as false the narrative that decrees of dictators can match the speed and scale of the 21st [century] challenges. <br><br>You know and I know they’re wrong.  But it doesn&#8217;t mean we don&#8217;t have to work harder than ever to prove that democracy can still deliver for our people.<br><br>For the many who think things are changing so rapidly, democracies cannot get together and form a consensus to respond like autocrats can, but you know better than anyone that democracy doesn&#8217;t happen by accident.  We have to defend it.  We have to strengthen it, renew it. <br><br>And I know that the American people are up to this job.  I know because I look around this hangar and what I see is I see America.  I see America &#8212; people of different backgrounds coming together in a share mission.  Our democracy has never been perfect.  Never been perfect.  But Americans of all races, religions, sexual orientation, immigrants, Native Americans all have spilled their blood to defend the values that we talk about.<br><br>Generation after generation of American heroes have signed up to be part of the fight because they understand the truth<br>that lives in every American heart: that liberation, opportunity, justice is far more likely to come to pass in a democracy than in the emerging autocracies in the world.<br><br>I promise you that’s what this is going to be all about for your generation and those of your children.  And here’s what else I know beyond a doubt: There is not a single thing &#8212; nothing &#8212; nothing beyond America’s competence to accomplish when we do it together, when we do it as one people.  You’re proof of that.  You’re proof of that every single day.  Your bravery, your decency, your honor, your commitment to duty. <br><br>You can send more fuel through a boom of a KC-135R in eight minutes than a civilian gas pump can pump in 24 hours, and you do it in midair, and it’s all a normal day for this team.  So don’t tell me we can’t win our race to the future across the board. <br><br>We’re the country that cracked the physicals and the physics of human flight, then crashed through the sound barrier, then put a man on the Moon and flew a helicopter on Mars.  I could go on and on and on.  There is nothing, nothing, nothing beyond our capacity.<br><br>So, I want to thank you again for welcoming Jill and me today.  It’s great to be here in the UK, but it’s greater being here and seeing you first.  Seeing all of you is the best possible way to start this trip. <br><br>Let me end where I began: by saying “thank you.”  I mean it from the bottom of my heart.  I give you my word.  Thank you all for what you do.  Thank you all for your understanding that we’re a nation based on values.  Thank you all for protecting us all. <br><br>May God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.  Thank you, and God bless.  (Applause.) <br><br>9:09 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen Psaki and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Suffolk, England</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/09/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-suffolk-england/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Suffolk, England 6:56 P.M. BST&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Okay.&#160; Okay.&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; We are on our way, almost arriving on the President’s first foreign trip.&#160; We have a very special guest for our gaggle today.&#160; Our National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, will take some questions, and then once you’re done with that,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Suffolk, England</p>



<p>6:56 P.M. BST<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; We are on our way, almost arriving on the President’s first foreign trip.&nbsp; We have a very special guest for our gaggle today.&nbsp; Our National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, will take some questions, and then once you’re done with that, I’m happy to take some as well.&nbsp; But you may have mostly for him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, do you want to talk a little bit about the President’s plan for boosting the global vaccine supply?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I do not want to get ahead of the President, who will be speaking to this issue tomorrow.&nbsp; And we’ll be able to talk about additional steps the United States is taking to help donate more doses to poor countries around the world and also to leverage what the United States is doing to help get the world’s democracies to increase their commitment to supplying vaccines to the developing world to help end this pandemic once and for all.&nbsp; But that announcement that he will make, he will &#8212; I will let him make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then the G7, we’ll make a combined announcement on this issue, and it won’t simply be about vaccines &#8212; though vaccines will be a part of it &#8212; but it will be a comprehensive plan to help end this pandemic as rapidly as possible.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the incentive for doing this?&nbsp; Is this about countering China and Russia?&nbsp; The President has talked about their vaccine diplomacy.&nbsp; Why is he trying to rally Western democracies, in particular, on this issue?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’d say three things about this:<br>&nbsp;<br>First, the President is focused on helping to vaccinate the world because believes it is the right thing to do; it’s what Americans do in times of need.&nbsp; When we have the capacity, then we have the will, and we step up and we deliver.&nbsp; And he said in his joint session that we were the arsenal of democracy in World War Two, and we’re going to be the arsenal of vaccines over the course of the next period to end this pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, it’s the smart thing to do, because if variants continue to proliferate and get worse, ultimately one could break through.&nbsp; And he wants to make sure we end the pandemic before that happens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, third, he does want to show &#8212; rallying the rest of the world’s democracies &#8212; that democracies are the countries that can best deliver solutions for people everywhere.&nbsp; And that goes for COVID-19, it goes for climate change, it goes for economic recovery, and it goes for the basic human rights and human dignity of all people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about the working groups that are being launched to reopen travel within the G7?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We’ve established two working groups of experts &#8212; public health experts: one with the United Kingdom and one with the European Union.&nbsp; The point of these working groups is to share data and set out both milestones and criteria to enable a reopening of travel between our two countries as swiftly as possible, consistent with public health guidance.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we expect any announcement on that front, during the trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think the working groups will have finished their work by the time the trip is through.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not currently anticipating any specific announcements because we&#8217;re being guided by science; we&#8217;re being guided by what the public health experts tell us is the right condition and the right timeframe for reopening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect that the EU&#8217;s refusal of the vaccine patent waiver to be a point of contention between the President and the other leaders?&nbsp; Is the President going to push them to waive &#8212; patent waivers?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t anticipate contention on the issue of vaccines.&nbsp; I anticipate convergence, because we&#8217;re all converging around the idea that we need to boost vaccine supply in a number of ways: sharing more of our own doses &#8212; and we&#8217;ll have more to say on that; helping get more manufacturing capacity around the world &#8212; we&#8217;ll have more to say on that; and, of course, doing what&#8217;s necessary across the chain of custody from when the vaccine is produced to when it gets in someone&#8217;s arms in the rural developing world, and we&#8217;ll have more to say on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I don&#8217;t foresee any clash or contest between the U.S. and our democratic partners on this issue.&nbsp; I see a unity of effort and a unity of commitment.&nbsp; And I think the results are going to end up speaking for themselves.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How prominent is the conversation with Putin going to be on Syria humanitarian aid passage and keeping that route to Idlib open?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, second, on that: With the decision to end the sanctions waiver for the American oil company that was operating there, that Russia very much against, was that sort of a fig leaf or playing out something for Putin to sort of smooth the talks on that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Syria will be on the agenda, and our position on the humanitarian access issue is well understood.&nbsp; We believe there has to be cross-border humanitarian access to save lives.&nbsp; And so that certainly will be something that the two presidents discuss.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to get into the details on it at this point because we want to give space for those conversations to play out in the run-up to Geneva and then between the two presidents.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve got nothing more for you today on the oil field issue in eastern Syria.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can you talk about strategic stability being a key part of the discussion?&nbsp; How are you defining that?&nbsp; Is it in the traditional nuclear arms control definition?&nbsp; Is it the mix of arms control/cyber vulnerabilities for the (inaudible)?&nbsp; Is it something broader involving the way the Russians are acting on their borders?&nbsp; What’s your concept?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We believe the starting point for strategic stability talks should be the very complex set of nuclear arms issues that face our two countries.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve extended New START for five years.&nbsp; But what comes after that, how do we deal with the fact that the INF Treaty is no more, how do we deal with our concerns about Russia&#8217;s new nuclear systems, and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) deployed you mean, but that Putin keeps showing.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; (Inaudible) development.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; And these are issues that we have raised publicly and we&#8217;ve raised privately with the Russians.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the starting point.&nbsp; Whether additional elements get added to strategic stability talks in the realm of space or cyber or other areas, that&#8217;s something to be determined as we go forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, there&#8217;s been an uptick in ransomware attacks recently.&nbsp; Is that going to be a point of discussion when the President meets with President Putin?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, 100 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What can you do about it?&nbsp; I mean, is retaliation on the table, off the table?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, our basic view on this is that all ransomware attacks are crimes.&nbsp; They should be prosecuted to the full extent of the law, and every responsible nation should take action against the criminals who are conducting them and should not harbor them in any way.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Ransomware attacks against critical infrastructure are of an even higher order of magnitude of concern for us, whether that&#8217;s about a pipeline or meat supply or a hospital system or other areas of critical infrastructure.&nbsp; The President will talk to President Putin about our concerns on this front.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We do not judge that the Russian government has been behind these recent ransomware attacks, but we do judge that actors in Russia have.&nbsp; And we believe that Russia can take and must take steps to deal with it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;m not going to be in the business of telegraphing our punches publicly or issuing threats publicly; I&#8217;m just going to say that we believe Russia has a responsibility.&nbsp; And, of course, any country that doesn&#8217;t act, then the United States will have to consider what its options are, following that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What do you think is causing the uptick?&nbsp; Why do you think now?&nbsp; Why do you think there&#8217;s been an uptick in attacks now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first of all, let&#8217;s be clear that this is not strictly a U.S.-Russia issue.&nbsp; Ireland has faced the &#8212; a catastrophic attack on its healthcare system.&nbsp; The JBS attack started in a computer system; it came from Russia, hit first a computer system in Mexico, affected Australia and Canada, as well as the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is a global problem and it&#8217;s being driven by a variety of factors, including increasing technical capability, and also, unfortunately, including the fact that many elements of the private sector globally have not brought their cybersecurity standards up to snuff.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of our messages has been &#8212; to the private sector in the United States and globally &#8212; that it is &#8212; it&#8217;s very important to lock your house, to make sure that it is more difficult for these criminals to get inside and hold them hostage or disrupt their operations.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think the President will discuss the Nord Stream pipeline with the German chancellor and/or the Russian president?&nbsp; Will it come up?&nbsp; Do you expect them to raise it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I expect Nord Stream 2 will come up in conversations with the Germans.&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t want to negotiate publicly on this issue.&nbsp; They understand well our concerns.&nbsp; But we do want to talk to them about what the implications of this pipeline are for energy security in Europe and for Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, what is the message that President Biden will deliver to Prime Minister Boris Johnson on Brexit and the Northern Ireland &#8212; the Good Friday Agreement?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; President Biden has been crystal clear about his rock-solid belief in the Good Friday Agreement as the foundation for peaceful coexistence in Northern Ireland.&nbsp; That agreement must be protected, and any steps that imperil or undermine it will not be welcomed by the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Johnson taking steps to imperil it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to characterize that at this point.&nbsp; I&#8217;m only going to say that President Biden is going to make statements in principle on this front.&nbsp; He&#8217;s not issuing threats or ultimatums; he&#8217;s going to simply convey his deep-seated belief that we need to stand behind and protect this protocol.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What else does he want to talk to Boris Johnson about?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;ll be talking to Boris Johnson about COVID-19; about climate change, as the UK is hosting COP26 in Glasgow later this year; about their joint commitment to developing an infrastructure financing mechanism for the developing world that is climate friendly, high standards, and transparent.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll talk to him about Afghanistan and our collective desire to maintain a strong embassy security &#8212; or embassy presence in Afghanistan after the troop drawdown.&nbsp; And, of course, there&#8217;s a whole global set of issues, from the Indo-Pacific to the Middle East, that the two leaders will cover.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, finally &#8212; you&#8217;ll see this when they meet tomorrow &#8212; there&#8217;ll be a refresher of the Atlantic Charter, which is now 80 years old.&nbsp; So there will be an updated statement of principles between the U.S. and the UK as free societies and free peoples speaking out about what we believe in in this 21st century.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, the President has talked about personal relationships in driving foreign policy.&nbsp; He had this meeting 10 years ago with Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; What did he learn from that meeting, and what is he bringing from that meeting?&nbsp; And has he been reflecting on it at all in the preparation for this upcoming meeting?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Bottom line: He believes you need to be clear, direct, and straightforward in every aspect of the engagement with Vladimir Putin, and that&#8217;s what he intends to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he ever consider having a joint press conference with him?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he &#8212; did the President ever consider having a joint press conference with Putin, or was it out of the question from the start?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I will defer to my press colleagues about the individual modalities of the press-related issues.&nbsp; But he does want to have an opportunity after that meeting to read it out and speak about his impressions and what he sees as the way forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you tell us what your views are on the 232 tariffs that remain in place?&nbsp; Do you expect them to come in and &#8212; like, do you think that those 232 tariffs are a national security issue?&nbsp; That was the guise or umbrella under which they were imposed in the first place.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, you know, in a real spirit of constructive engagement, the U.S. and the EU have agreed to a pause in the escalation of tariffs in response to the 232.&nbsp; That has given time and space for a negotiation to hopefully produce an outcome that meaningfully addresses the problem of Chinese overcapacity.&nbsp; And we regard that as a serious challenge that affects both Europe and the United States and must be dealt with effectively.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe there&#8217;s an outcome possible on this trip, or is that a longer-term discussion?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s going to take some time to work out, which is why that stand-down on the tariffs was so important &#8212; because it gives us the time and space for us to be able to (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;But you&#8217;re not rolling back tariffs? &nbsp;You’re not rolling back tariffs? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; (Shakes head no.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak a little bit about Iran and what the President will ask President Putin, in terms of supporting the JCPOA?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Russia is a member of the P5+1.&nbsp; The American negotiating team is working with the Russian negotiating team in Vienna.&nbsp; They have worked together in a productive and constructive way, to a large extent.&nbsp; And so this will be an opportunity for the two presidents to be able to consult on where we think we are in those talks and what needs to be done to get them across the line.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on Iran &#8212; just continuing on that same line: The Secretary has frequently said we need something longer and stronger, and so forth.&nbsp; Do you have any reason to believe that after &#8212; if you get the agreement that is now basically in blue, that the Iranians have any interest in going to something that is longer and stronger?&nbsp; And what is that evidence?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t underestimate the difficulty of any nuclear negotiation with the Iranians, since we&#8217;ve been through them.&nbsp; But we do believe that there is scope for follow-on negotiations to deal with what &#8212; to build on the JCPOA once we are back in it.&nbsp; And we believe the Iranians will ultimately be prepared to engage in those negotiations.&nbsp; There are things for them to gain, because there are many aspects of our sanctions that are &#8212; are not necessarily part of the original JCPOA.&nbsp; And, of course, we retain all of the right and capacity to take additional steps if they&#8217;re not prepared to negotiate in good faith.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’ve talked before about the ransomware side.&nbsp; But, you know, a few months ago, if this meeting was happening, it would have been pretty much all about SolarWinds and state-sponsored actions.&nbsp; So is that now behind you, having done the sanctions and whatever unseen activities?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the President&#8217;s message on that?&nbsp; What kind of guardrails might use that (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have had the opportunity to engage with the Russians, through several channels, on the SolarWinds issue, both before and after we imposed costs in response to it.&nbsp; But that doesn&#8217;t mean that issue is behind us, of course. &nbsp;The issue of state-sponsored cyberattacks of that scope and scale remains a matter of grave concern to the United States.&nbsp; It will be a topic of conversation between the presidents.<br>&nbsp;<br>And us talking ransomware is not going to come to the exclusion of us talking about the cyber threat in multiple other domains.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) him to some understanding with Putin, to some understanding of what&#8217;s off limits.&nbsp; Can you tell us a little bit about that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to leave that to the two presidents to discuss for now.&nbsp; You know, sort of, depending on how that conversation goes at the highest level and where we come out, we will be in a better position to be able to talk about our expectations, as well as our capacities at that point.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t want to front-run that today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has there been any developments on Airbus during this time at all?&nbsp; The Airbus dispute &#8212; the Boeing Airbus dispute.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp;&nbsp;I&#8217;m not going to say one way or the other on that.&nbsp;&nbsp;All I will note is that the negotiations are ongoing, that we also there bought space with the mutual stand-down on tariffs as well that runs out much sooner than the 232.&nbsp;&nbsp;And so, I think there has been good progress in those negotiations, but I&#8217;m making no promises about what might happen over the course of the (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jumping ahead to the NATO meeting, does the President feel the need to restate U.S. support for Article 5?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, of course.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will he do that in Brussels?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; He feels the need to restate support for Article 5 as often as he is able to do so, because for him, it&#8217;s an article of faith &#8212; for President Joe Biden and for the United States of America.&nbsp; And so he will proclaim that loudly and proudly, as he just did with the Secretary General when he was in town a couple of days ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, you know, he&#8217;s not just going to speak about principle; he&#8217;s going to speak about the practicalities of what&#8217;s required to make Article 5 real, including the work that needs to be done between now and 2030 on every aspect of transatlantic defense and security.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, in the last G7, there was not a communiqué because of disagreements between President Trump and the other leaders.&nbsp; Can we expect a communiqué at this G7?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to jinx it, but yes, I think you can expect a communiqué at this G7.&nbsp; And &#8212; you know.&nbsp; But you never know.&nbsp; I hope so.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right, I’m going to let Jake go back.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you can speak a little bit more about the format of<br>the bilaterals between President Biden and Putin, that would be great.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I mean, what I can tell you is we&#8217;re still discussing, so we don’t have a final conclusion yet.&nbsp; That what I can confirm for you is that you will have the opportunity to ask questions of President Biden.&nbsp; And we certainly hope that you&#8217;ll also have the opportunity to ask questions of President Putin.&nbsp; What that format looks like, we&#8217;ll know in the next couple days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so it’s still being negotiated with the Russians?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Still being &#8212; still being discussed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it’s still two bilats &#8212; a small and an extended one?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s right.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Talk about infrastructure a little bit.&nbsp; We saw the statement.&nbsp; Has the President now decided to go it only with Democrats to pass the bill?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So I talked to the President about this, this morning, and his view is that there are multiple paths forward.&nbsp; He feels it&#8217;s encouraging to see multiple proposals put out there, both from Republicans in the House and the Problem Solvers Caucus, as well as a bipartisan group that&#8217;s working on a proposal.&nbsp; Both will have increased numbers over what we&#8217;ve seen and been negotiating to date.&nbsp; Those are all positive steps.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, Steve, we&#8217;re also &#8212; the Senate is also moving forward with a budget process.&nbsp; That, by the way, is how government should work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an opportunity to move, through that vehicle, a bunch of his bold economic ideas, as well as corporate tax reform &#8212; something that, of course, will pay for a number of his proposals but also something that will make us more competitive and he thinks is long overdue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President, with Senator Capito, pivoted to talking about a 15 percent minimum corporate tax as opposed to a 28 percent corporate tax rate.&nbsp; Of course, they’re not mutually exclusive, but is he resetting at all, now that he&#8217;s pivoting to the bipartisan group?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has always felt that corporate tax reform and raising the corporate rate to 28 percent &#8212; which he proposed and is in his budget, as you know &#8212; is something that is good for &#8212; good for our competition, good for our economy, good for workers in this country, and also will help pay for proposals.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you also know, the 15 percent minimum tax was an additional proposal that he put forward in the American Jobs Plan and also is in his budget.&nbsp; But it is a proposal that would not violate the red line the Republicans have put forward on the 2017 tax cuts.&nbsp; So, that, which would help pay for proposals, as well as the IRS going after individuals to ensure they&#8217;re paying for &#8212; they’re paying their fair share and they&#8217;re paying what they owe &#8212; are payfors that do not violate the 2017 taxes.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why he reelevated those.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think those corporate tax changes are more or less likely with this bipartisan group of senators than they were with Senator Capito’s group?&nbsp; Are they more on the table or less on the table?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll certainly see.&nbsp; But our view and the President&#8217;s view is that they should be on the table for all of them because they do not violate their red line; because &#8212; unless they feel that these corporations shouldn&#8217;t pay any taxes at all.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just suggesting they should pay 15 percent, which isn&#8217;t even what the tax rate he&#8217;s proposing for most corporations around the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did the President spend any time on the flight over, or even in the short time between when he woke up this morning, getting to talk to people and do some of this reach-out that he said he&#8217;s going to be doing on infrastructure, while (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m not sure even any of his close friends would like a call from him at 6:00 a.m.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But he will certainly be engaged on this trip with his domestic agenda, including having conversations with Democrats and Republicans back at home.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On this trip, he was primarily focused on having discussions with his national security team about the foreign trip &#8212; his first foreign trip overseas &#8212; but he will be having those conversations.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll keep you abreast of those.&nbsp; He&#8217;s also asked his Jobs Cabinet to run point and be closely engaged with all of these members of both parties who are interested in being part of the infrastructure negotiations moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know you guys &#8212; I know he can walk and chew gum, or whatever metaphor you want to use, but is there any disappoint, just not having that done before getting started with this also very important agenda item?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that what we see are a number of signs of progress.&nbsp; One, the Senate just passed a China competition bill just yesterday.&nbsp; We&#8217;re eager for the House to move forward on that; that&#8217;s a positive step forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>While we&#8217;re on this plane &#8212; on this flight, Congressman DeFazio is helping oversee the markup of the Surface Transportation bill that has a great deal of overlap with the American Jobs Plan. &nbsp;And in addition to the Senate moving forward on a budget process that can be a vehicle for his economic ideas and corporate tax reform, we&#8217;ve also seen multiple options of proposals come forward in a bipartisan manner.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;s quite familiar with the fact that this process can take &#8212; it takes some patience at times; that there are going to be moments where we&#8217;re near death, and then it comes back.&nbsp; That&#8217;s always how policymaking, lawmaking, bill making happens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And &#8212; but he&#8217;s been encouraged by the progress, encouraged by the interest by not just Republicans and Democrats in the country, but also in Congress, on working together to get an infrastructure bill passed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say what Jake meant by a “refresher” of the transatlantic charter?&nbsp; &nbsp;Can you tell us a little bit more about that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; It will be something that we will put out.&nbsp; it will update the charter that, as he noted, is several decades old &#8212; I believe is what he said.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll put that out publicly and it will &#8212; you know, it will confirm and be clear &#8212; and will be consistent with what our challenges are today and opportunities today.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll put that out publicly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk to us about what can we expect with the bilat with President Erdoğan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, this is a relationship, obviously a NATO partner, where there are areas where we feel it&#8217;s important to continue to constructively work together where there&#8217;s opportunity, and also areas where we have strong disagreement.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an opportunity to have that face-to-face diplomacy, which the President felt was important to do as a priority bilateral meeting during his first trip overseas.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what are the specific issues?&nbsp; Like, Syria or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure they will discuss issues of regional security; issues, of course, that are impacting the global community, including the economy, including COVID-19.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more, I&#8217;m sure, as we get closer to the bilateral meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he going to have bilats with other leaders at the G7, or, like, pull-asides individually?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He will certainly have pull-asides.&nbsp; I will look back at the schedule and what we’ve confirmed publicly.&nbsp; As you all know, from covering these international summits, there are &#8212; the schedules are quite packed, but there is an opportunity often to have, kind of, pull-aside conversations, and he&#8217;ll look for the opportunity to do that on the ground as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s rumors that he&#8217;s going to be having a pull-aside with the Belarusian opposition leader. &nbsp;Is that correct?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not seen &#8212; I am not aware of that plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On infrastructure &#8212; back to infrastructure: Leader Schumer suggested that the bill could possibly pass partially through reconciliation, partially through bipartisan.&nbsp; Is that something that the administration is open to?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I mean, the point is it&#8217;s moving on several paths.&nbsp; So even as we negotiate an infrastructure bill &#8212; right? &#8212; or portions of the American Jobs Plan, it’s already moving forward on several fronts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then there are components of the Amer- &#8212; of the President’s proposals, including the extension of the Child Tax Credit, making pre-K universal, making community college free, that are not a part of the negotiations now, so they would be natural components that would be added into a budget process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Jen, a couple of weeks ago, we heard the President agreeing to the statement that President Putin is a killer.&nbsp; Do you think that’s going to make things awkward coming into the summit?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has known President Putin for a long time.&nbsp; He has never held back in voicing his concerns or issues where their behavior is not aligned with democratic values, and he will certainly be straightforward in doing that in this meeting as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is not about friendship.&nbsp; It’s not about trust.&nbsp; It’s about what’s in the interest of the United States.&nbsp; And, in our view, that is moving toward a more stable and predictable relationship.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the China bill, you now have to get to the House.&nbsp; What’s the strategy there?&nbsp; It looks like that may be a tougher climb than the Senate.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That &#8212; that may be the case.&nbsp; Look, the President was certainly encouraged by the fact that it passed the Senate.&nbsp; We’ve seen concerns expressed publicly by some members of the House, including some high up.&nbsp; And we’re going to take a look at what the legislation looks like, hear their concerns.&nbsp; We’ll be engaged, of course, in discussing how we can move this forward, you know, from a staff level.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a schedule for that, or not?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have a schedule or a timeline to predict.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the global minimum tax &#8212; some of the Republicans came out against it this week.&nbsp; Does that complicate the plan at all?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On the world stage?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; No &#8212; yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, our view is that this is in the interest of America’s competition of our economy, of the global economy to have that global minimum tax, and felt it was a very positive sign that there was agreement among finance ministers at the G7.&nbsp; So we are encouraged by that, and, you know, it’s a positive sign.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) the EU and U.S. have a &#8212; their draft statement, as of now, includes a reference to the origins &#8212; the investigation into the origins of the coronavirus.&nbsp; Why is the U.S. seeking, sort of, support from European allies on this issue of getting to the bottom of where that virus came from?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that even as we pursue our own 90-day review, and &#8212; where we are going to tap into every resource we have available in the U.S. government, we also recognize that in order to send a clear message to China and to the WHO, of course, who’ve been a constructive partner, that it’s important that they are transparent, that they release all the available data, that we move forward on the second stage of this investigation.&nbsp; Doing that from a united front and doing that in partnership with our European partners is a vital part of this process.&nbsp; So, it’s an indication of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will there be a similar line in the G7 communiqué?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything to predict for you on that quite yet.&nbsp; You’ll know soon enough.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you comment again on the vaccine patent waiver?&nbsp; The U.S. has just joined the G20 &#8212; I’m sorry, the APEC &#8212; to support the patent waivers.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the President be pushing this issue with European leaders who prefer to do compulsory licensing instead?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is an ongoing process that our ambassador &#8212; our USTR ambassador is running point on.&nbsp; It’s a long process, as you know &#8212; several months to negotiate what the best format will look like.&nbsp; Whether it’s coming up &#8212; going to come up in conversations, I’m sure we can &#8212; that will be reflected in readouts.&nbsp; But I would suspect we will leave it at the level of the U.S. ambassador.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the President doesn’t plan to put his diplomatic weight behind a patent waiver?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has certainly spoken about his support on the waiver.&nbsp; He believes it’s import- &#8212; an important component of addressing the global threat of COVID.&nbsp; And he will continue to play a constructive role.&nbsp; But I don’t have anything to preview for you or predict in terms of how it will come up in these conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>All right, thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Have a good landing.<br>&nbsp;<br>7:25 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nomination Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/09/nomination-sent-to-the-senate-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION&#160;SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Jayme Ray White, of Washington, to be a Deputy United States Trade Representative (Western Hemisphere, Europe, the Middle East, Labor, and Environment), with the rank of Ambassador, vice Michael N. Nemelka. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION&nbsp;SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jayme Ray White, of Washington, to be a Deputy United States Trade Representative (Western Hemisphere, Europe, the Middle East, Labor, and Environment), with the rank of Ambassador, vice Michael N. Nemelka.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Five Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/09/president-biden-announces-five-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following five individuals to serve in key roles: Amanda Howe, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Mission Support, Environmental Protection Agency Guy Kiyokawa, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Enterprise Integration, Department of Veterans Affairs Damon Smith, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of Housing and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following five individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Amanda Howe, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Mission Support, Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Guy Kiyokawa, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Enterprise Integration, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Damon Smith, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>William Eugene Holloway, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the National Institute of Building Sciences</li><li>Javier Ramirez, Nominee for Director of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service</li></ul>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Amanda Howe, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Mission Support, Environmental Protection Agency</span></strong><br>Amanda Howe is a career public servant, helping lead progressive change in government, politics, and the non-profit sector. She served in the role of Chief Operating Officer for the Kamala Harris For The People presidential campaign in 2019 and for the Democratic National Committee before, during, after President Barack Obama’s 2012 re-election campaign. In the past year, she’s been a senior advisor to the President of Everytown for Gun Safety and for the Maya Wiley for Mayor campaign in New York City. Howe served as Deputy and then Acting Chief of Staff to New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio, and after, as a consultant to the city, helped plan the first-ever ticker tape parade for a women’s team for the U.S. Women’s Soccer Team World Cup win and for the official visit of Pope Francis and his procession through Central Park.  She served as Vice President of the non-profit American Council on Renewable Energy in Washington, D.C.  In Virginia, Howe served as Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Trade for then-Governor Mark R. Warner and led the planning for then-Governor Tim Kaine of the Virginia portion of the most recent official visit to the U.S. of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Phillip in 2007. Howe holds a bachelor’s degree in political science from Dalhousie University in Nova Scotia.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Guy Kiyokawa, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Enterprise Integration, Department of Veterans Affairs</span></strong><br>Mr. Guy Kiyokawa is currently the Deputy Director of the Defense Health Agency (DHA), Falls Church, VA. The DHA is a joint Combat Support Agency supporting Army, Navy, and Air Force medical services, and it administers the TRICARE Health Plan providing worldwide medical, dental and pharmacy programs to more than 9.6 million uniformed service members, retirees and their families. Prior to his selection to the Senior Executive Service in 2015, Mr. Kiyokawa completed a 29-year career in the United States Army with leadership experience in multiple roles ranging from aeromedical evacuation pilot to health facility engineering to healthcare administration.  He culminated his career as the Chief of Staff for the newly formed Defense Health Agency, and retired at the rank of Colonel in 2015.<br><br>Mr. Kiyokawa was born and raised in Honolulu, Hawaii. He holds a Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering from the University of Southern California, and is a 1995 graduate of the US Army-Baylor University Program with a Master’s Degree in Health Administration.  Mr. Kiyokawa graduated from the U.S. Army War College in Carlisle Barracks, PA where he completed the War College Fellowship with the Department of Veterans Affairs in Washington, DC.  He currently resides in Vienna, Virginia with his wife and three kids.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Damon Smith, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of Housing and Urban Development</span></strong><br>Damon Smith currently serves as the Principal Deputy General Counsel at the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD).  He joined the Biden-Harris Administration after serving as Senior Director of Advocacy and Counsel at the Credit Union National Association (CUNA), representing the nation’s cooperatively-owned, not-for-profit credit unions in housing, telecommunications and financial security matters.  Prior to joining CUNA, Smith was a Partner at Jenner and Block LLP in Washington, D.C. where he provided counsel to companies facing complex compliance, government regulation and enforcement matters.<br><br>Smith previously served as the Senior Counsel and Acting General Counsel at the U.S. Department for Housing and Urban Development during the Obama-Biden Administration, where he provided legal and policy guidance on a range of programs and activities and set the Department’s litigation strategy and regulatory agenda. Before his government service, he taught property and local government law as an Associate Professor at Rutgers-Camden Law School and a Visiting Professor at the American University Washington College of Law.  Smith began his legal career as a real estate Associate at Arnold &amp; Porter in Washington, D.C., and worked prior to law school as an urban planner in East St. Louis, Illinois and St. Louis, Missouri. <br><br>Smith is a graduate of Harvard Law School and holds a bachelor’s degree in English and a master’s degree in urban planning from the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign<br><br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">William Eugene Holloway, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the National Institute of Building Sciences</span></strong><br>Bill Holloway is Vice President, Principal, and Director of Delaware Operations for Bernardon, an award-winning regional architecture, interior design and landscape architecture firm with offices in Wilmington, Delaware and West Chester and Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Spanning 39 years of practice, his professional accomplishments include significant projects in the public works, institutional, and healthcare markets. Among Holloway’s notable projects are the Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Train Station in Wilmington, the restoration of the historic Old State House in Dover, Delaware, and renovations to over twenty-seven facilities for the Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia.  Currently, Holloway is working on a major addition to the Delaware Division of Public Health Laboratory in Smyrna, Delaware.<br><br>In recognition of his service to the profession of Architecture, the American Institute of Architects (AIA) named him a Richard Upjohn Fellow at the national level for his service on the Institute’s board.  In honor of his successful tenure as president of AIA Delaware, Holloway was made a member of the chapter’s G. Morris White Society.  He was also voted to be accepted to the membership of the Carpenters’ Company of the City and County of Philadelphia, a prestigious organization of builders, architects, and engineers originally chartered in 1724.<br><br>Bill earned his Bachelor of Architecture degree from The Pennsylvania State University where he was awarded the College of Arts &amp; Architecture Medal for Creative Achievement and the Alpha Rho Chi Medal for leadership, service and merit in architecture.  He is also quite proud of his years as a member of the sousaphone rank in the Penn State Blue Band. In the community and beyond, Bill serves as a longtime member of the Executive Board of the Del-Mar-Va Council Boy Scouts of America; a member of the Easter Seals Society of Delaware and the Eastern Shore Board of Trustees; and a member of the executive committee of the New Castle County Chamber of Commerce.  Bill also continues his avocation in music as a member of the Aldersgate Brass Ensemble. Bill and his wife of 37 years, Cathy, reside in Chadds Ford, Pennsylvania and together they have two adult children, Megan Holloway and Ben Holloway, both of Wilmington, Delaware.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Javier Ramirez, Nominee for Director of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service</span></strong><br>Javier Ramirez began his FMCS career as a Commissioner in 2005 and is currently the Executive Manager of the Division of Agency Initiatives.  This office bears responsibility for the Office of Conflict Management &amp; Prevention, Office of Strategy &amp; Development, the Center for Conflict Resolution and Education, the FMCS Institute for Conflict Management, and the DC and Northern Virginia (HQ) Commissioners.  <br><br>Javier mediated disputes in all sectors of the economy (except air and rail) in professions such as the performing arts, public safety, professors, hospitality, hospitals, manufacturing, and packing houses.  Javier facilitated and mediated multi-party disputes in manufacturing, construction, and education.  He was on the facilitation team for several regulatory negotiations, including the Department of Energy (DOE) negotiations that resulted in the largest energy-saving rule in DOE history.  Javier also trained and successfully facilitated parties in various collaborative bargaining models.  Notably, Javier collaborated with colleagues to create the FMCS Affinity Bargaining model.  He represented the agency in international tri-partite training efforts in Bangladesh and trained all New Zealand labor mediators on collaborative bargaining. Javier has been the recipient of multiple FMCS performance awards in recognition of his work, including the Director’s Award.<br><br>Additionally, Javier is regularly asked to present at national and regional conferences on conflict management topics.  He guest lectured on labor relations and dispute management at the University of Illinois, University of Colorado Boulder, National Defense University, Cornell, and other universities.<br><br>Prior to FMCS, Javier spent over fourteen years in labor relations, negotiating contracts and resolving disputes in areas such as immigration, contract administration, communication, staffing, and politics at the federal, state, and local level.  His efforts have been featured in Rolling Stone, Chicago Tribune Magazine, and Chicago Lawyer Magazine; cited in the New York Times Best Seller Fast Food Nation; and recognized by the College of Labor and Employment Lawyers.<br><br>Javier enjoys the performing arts or exploring the great outdoors with his wife and two adult children.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Executive Order Protecting Americans’ Sensitive Data from Foreign Adversaries</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-protecting-americans-sensitive-data-from-foreign-adversaries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 14:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden Administration is committed to promoting an open, interoperable, reliable and secure Internet; protecting human rights online and offline; and supporting a vibrant, global digital economy. Certain countries, including the People’s Republic of China (PRC), do not share these values and seek to leverage digital technologies and Americans’ data in ways that present unacceptable&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden Administration is committed to promoting an open, interoperable, reliable and secure Internet; protecting human rights online and offline; and supporting a vibrant, global digital economy. Certain countries, including the People’s Republic of China (PRC), do not share these values and seek to leverage digital technologies and Americans’ data in ways that present unacceptable national security risks while advancing authoritarian controls and interests.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to further address the ongoing national emergency declared in E.O. 13873 of May 15, 2019 with respect to the threat posed to the United States’ information and communications technology and services (ICTS) supply chain. President Biden revoked and replaced three E.O.s that aimed to prohibit transactions with TikTok, WeChat, and eight other communications and financial technology software applications; two of these E.O.s are subject to litigation. In their place, this E.O. directs the use of a criteria-based decision framework and rigorous, evidence-based analysis to address the risks posed by ICTS transactions involving software applications that are designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons that are owned or controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction of a foreign adversary, including the People’s Republic of China, that may present an undue or unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States and the American people.<br><br>Specifically, the E.O. the President signed today:<br><br><strong>Enables&nbsp;the U.S. to take strong steps to protect Americans’ sensitive data:&nbsp;</strong>This E.O. revokes&nbsp;and replaces&nbsp;E.O.s 13942, 13943, and 13971.&nbsp;The new E.O. directs the Department of Commerce to instead evaluate foreign adversary connected software applications under the rules published to implement E.O. 13873 and take action, as appropriate.<br><br><strong>Provides criteria for identifying software applications that may pose unacceptable risk:</strong> This E.O. provides criteria for consideration, consistent with the criteria set forth in E.O. 13873 and the implementing regulations, for identifying and evaluating ICTS transactions involving foreign adversary connected software applications that may pose an unacceptable risk to U.S. national security and the American people. For example, ICTS transactions involving software applications may present a heightened risk when the transactions involve applications that are owned, controlled, or managed by persons that support foreign adversary military or intelligence activities, or are involved in malicious cyber activities, or involve applications that collect sensitive personal data.<br><br><strong>Develops further options to protect sensitive personal data and address the potential threat from certain connected software applications:</strong> This E.O. directs the Department of Commerce, in consultation with other U.S. departments and agencies, to make recommendations to protect against harm from the sale, transfer of, or access to sensitive personal data, including personally identifiable information and genetic information – to include large data repositories – to persons owned or controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, foreign adversaries. Additionally, the Department of Commerce will make recommendations for additional executive and legislative actions to further address the risk associated with foreign adversary connected software applications.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on Protecting Americans’ Sensitive Data from Foreign Adversaries</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/09/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-protecting-americans-sensitive-data-from-foreign-adversaries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 14:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), I hereby report that I&#160;have issued an&#160;Executive Order addressing the threat from certain connected software applications designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a foreign&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.), I hereby report that I&nbsp;have issued an&nbsp;Executive Order addressing the threat from certain connected software applications designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a foreign adversary, to include the&nbsp;People&#8217;s Republic of China, among others.<br><br>I have determined that additional consideration must be given in&nbsp;addressing the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13873 of May 15, 2019 (Securing the Information and Communications Technology and Services Supply Chain), including the threat posed by certain connected software applications designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a foreign adversary.<br><br>I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Sincerely,<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Protecting Americans’ Sensitive Data from Foreign Adversaries</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/09/executive-order-on-protecting-americans-sensitive-data-from-foreign-adversaries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 14:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act&#160;(50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.), and section 301 of title 3, United&#160;States Code, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act&nbsp;(50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq.</em>), and section 301 of title 3, United&nbsp;States Code,</p>



<p>I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of&nbsp;America, find that it is appropriate to elaborate upon measures to address the national emergency with respect to the information and communications technology and services supply chain that was declared in Executive Order 13873 of May 15, 2019 (Securing the Information and Communications Technology and Services Supply Chain). &nbsp;Specifically, the increased use in the&nbsp;United States of certain connected software applications designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned or controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, a foreign adversary, which the Secretary of Commerce acting pursuant to Executive Order 13873 has defined to include the People&#8217;s Republic of China, among others, continues to threaten the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States.&nbsp; The Federal Government should evaluate these threats through rigorous, evidence-based analysis and should address any&nbsp;unacceptable or undue risks consistent with overall national security, foreign policy, and economic objectives, including the preservation and demonstration of America&#8217;s core values and fundamental freedoms.</p>



<p>By operating on United States information and communications technology devices, including personal electronic devices such as smartphones, tablets, and computers, connected software applications can access and capture vast swaths of information from users, including United States persons&#8217; personal information and proprietary business information. &nbsp;This data collection threatens to provide foreign adversaries with access to that information.&nbsp; Foreign adversary access to large repositories of United States persons&#8217; data also presents a&nbsp;significant risk.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In evaluating the risks of a connected software application, several factors should be considered.&nbsp; Consistent with the criteria established in Executive Order 13873, and in addition to the criteria set forth in implementing regulations, potential indicators of risk relating to connected software applications include: &nbsp;ownership, control, or management by persons that support a foreign adversary&#8217;s military, intelligence, or proliferation activities; use of the connected software application to conduct surveillance that enables espionage, including through a foreign adversary&#8217;s access to sensitive or confidential government or business information, or sensitive personal data; ownership, control, or management of connected software applications by persons subject to coercion or cooption by a foreign adversary; ownership, control, or management of connected software applications by persons involved in malicious cyber activities; a lack of thorough and reliable third-party auditing of connected software applications; the scope and sensitivity of the data collected; the number and sensitivity of the users of the connected software application; and the extent to which identified risks have been or can be addressed by independently verifiable measures.</p>



<p>The ongoing emergency declared in Executive Order 13873 arises from a variety of factors, including the continuing effort of foreign adversaries to steal or otherwise obtain United States persons&#8217; data.&nbsp; That continuing effort by foreign adversaries constitutes an unusual and extraordinary threat to&nbsp;the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States. &nbsp;To address this threat, the United States must act to protect against the risks associated with connected software applications that are designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned or controlled by, or&nbsp;subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, a foreign adversary.</p>



<p>Additionally, the United States seeks to promote accountability for persons who engage in serious human rights abuse. If persons who own, control, or manage connected software applications engage in serious human rights abuse or otherwise facilitate such abuse, the United States may impose consequences on those persons in action separate from this order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Accordingly, it is hereby ordered that:</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section 1.</span>  <span style="text-decoration: underline">Revocation of Presidential Actions.</span>  The following orders are revoked:  Executive Order 13942 of August 6, 2020 (Addressing the Threat Posed by TikTok, and Taking Additional Steps To Address the National Emergency With Respect to the Information and Communications Technology and Services Supply Chain); Executive Order 13943 of August 6, 2020 (Addressing the Threat Posed by WeChat, and Taking Additional Steps To Address the National Emergency With Respect to the Information and Communications Technology and Services Supply Chain); and Executive Order 13971 of January 5, 2021 (Addressing the Threat Posed by Applications and Other Software Developed or Controlled by Chinese Companies).</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 2.</span>  <span style="text-decoration: underline">Implementation.</span>  (a)  The Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the heads of executive departments and agencies (agencies) shall promptly take steps to rescind any orders, rules, regulations, guidelines, or policies, or portions thereof, implementing or enforcing Executive Orders 13942, 13943, or 13971, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, including the Administrative Procedure Act, 5 U.S.C. 551 <em>et seq.</em>  In addition, any personnel positions, committees, task forces, or other entities established pursuant to Executive Orders 13942, 13943, or 13971 shall be abolished, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law.<br>     (b)  Not later than 120 days after the date of this order, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of other agencies as the Secretary of Commerce deems appropriate, shall provide a report to the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor with recommendations to protect against harm from the unrestricted sale of, transfer of, or access to United States persons&#8217; sensitive data, including personally identifiable information, personal health information, and genetic information, and harm from access to large data repositories by persons owned or controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, a foreign adversary.  Not later than 60 days after the date of this order, the Director of National Intelligence shall provide threat assessments, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide vulnerability assessments, to the Secretary of Commerce to support development of the report required by this subsection.<br>     (c)  Not later than 180 days after the date of this order, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the heads of other agencies as the Secretary of Commerce deems appropriate, shall provide a report to the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor recommending additional executive and legislative actions to address the risk associated with connected software applications that are designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned or controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, a foreign adversary.  <br>     (d)  The Secretary of Commerce shall evaluate on a continuing basis transactions involving connected software applications that may pose an undue risk of sabotage or subversion of the design, integrity, manufacturing, production, distribution, installation, operation, or maintenance of information and communications technology or services in the United States; pose an undue risk of catastrophic effects on the security or resiliency of the critical infrastructure or digital economy of the United States; or otherwise pose an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons.  Based on the evaluation, the Secretary of Commerce shall take appropriate action in accordance with Executive Order 13873 and its implementing regulations.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 3.</span>  <span style="text-decoration: underline">Definitions.</span>  For purposes of this order:<br>     (a)  the term &#8220;connected software application&#8221; means software, a software program, or a group of software programs, that is designed to be used on an end-point computing device and includes as an integral functionality, the ability to collect, process, or transmit data via the Internet;<br>     (b)  the term &#8220;foreign adversary&#8221; means any foreign government or foreign non-government person engaged in a long-term pattern or serious instances of conduct significantly adverse to the national security of the United States or security and safety of United States persons;<br>     (c)  the term &#8220;information and communications technology or services&#8221; means any hardware, software, or other product or service primarily intended to fulfill or enable the function of information or data processing, storage, retrieval, or communication by electronic means, including transmission, storage, and display;<br>     (d)  the term &#8220;person&#8221; means an individual or entity; and<br>     (e)  the term &#8220;United States person&#8221; means any United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 4.</span>  <span style="text-decoration: underline">General Provisions.</span>  (a)  Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>          (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>          (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>     (b)  This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>     (c)  This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. &nbsp;</p>



<p><br>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; June 9, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before Air Force One Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George&#8217;s County, Maryland 8:26 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; You dropped your phone.&#160; You dropped your phone.&#160; Watch out for the cicadas.&#160; I just got one &#8212; it just got me. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; What’s your main goal today when you get over there? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Strengthening the alliance and make it clear to Putin&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Andrews<br>Prince George&#8217;s County, Maryland</p>



<p>8:26 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You dropped your phone.&nbsp; You dropped your phone.&nbsp;<br><br>Watch out for the cicadas.&nbsp; I just got one &#8212; it just got me.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What’s your main goal today when you get over there?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Strengthening the alliance and make it clear to Putin and to China that Europe and the United States are tight, and the G7 is going to move.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you expect to come out with a vaccine strategy for the world?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I have one and I’ll be announcing it.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect that Putin will be able to work out any kind of understanding with you on the cyberattacks?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Who knows at this point.&nbsp; It’s going to be a subject of our discussion.<br><br>8:27 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the United States’ Commitment to Open Investment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-united-states-commitment-to-open-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 23:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20061</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Open Investment Policy of the United States is a pledge to treat all investors fairly and equitably under the law. As Governors, CEOs, and other public and private sector leaders come together at the 2021 SelectUSA Summit this week, I want to reiterate my administration’s commitment to ensuring that the United States remains the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Open Investment Policy of the United States is a pledge to treat all investors fairly and equitably under the law. As Governors, CEOs, and other public and private sector leaders come together at the 2021 SelectUSA Summit this week, I want to reiterate my administration’s commitment to ensuring that the United States remains the most attractive place in the world for businesses to invest and grow, thus creating jobs here at home, strengthening supply chains across the country, and deepening our relationships with allies and partners.<br><br>America has the most productive workforce in the world. We have an unmatched business environment strengthened by our culture of innovation and entrepreneurship, outstanding educational institutions, and commitment to transparency, protection of intellectual property, flexible and efficient capital markets, and the rule of law. We believe that our country – and our world – are safer, more resilient, and more prosperous because of the investment of foreign-owned companies in the United States.<br><br>As we continue to advance our agenda to revitalize American manufacturing, build an inclusive 21st century workforce, and maintain our competitive edge, the United States welcomes foreign investment. Today, U.S. subsidiaries of foreign-owned companies directly employ almost 8 million Americans and help boost U.S. innovation by investing $70 billion in research and development. They contribute to all sectors of the U.S. economy and are responsible for nearly 24% of all U.S. goods exports.<br><br>We will always protect our national security, and certain foreign investments will be reviewed by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States for this purpose. But, we will also maintain a level playing field. As the United States faces increasing competition for the jobs and industries of the future, we will remain the destination of choice for investors around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, Deputy Director of the National Economic Council Sameera Fazili, and Senior Director for International Economics and Competitiveness Peter Harrell, June 8, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/08/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-deputy-director-of-the-national-economic-council-sameera-fazili-and-senior-director-for-international-economics-and-competitiveness-peter-harrell-june-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 23:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:15 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Happy Tuesday.&#160; So, we have two very special guests with us again today.&#160; As you know, the Biden-Harris administration &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to let you all settle in here.&#160; Okay.&#160; All right.&#160; Great.&#160; Okay.&#160; So, as you all know, today, the Biden-Harris administration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:15 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Happy Tuesday.&nbsp; So, we have two very special guests with us again today.&nbsp; As you know, the Biden-Harris administration &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to let you all settle in here.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>So, as you all know, today, the Biden-Harris administration announced key findings from the reviews directed by the President&#8217;s executive order on America&#8217;s supply chains.&nbsp; The executive order, signed February 24th, directed a whole-of-government approach to assessing vulnerabilities in and strengthening the resilience of critical supply chains.<br><br>So, here to discuss the immediate actions we will be taking to promote economic security, national security, and create good-paying union jobs by strengthening American supply chains are repeat guests &#8212; back for the second time; they had so much fun the first time &#8212; Deputy Director of the National Economic Council Sameera Fazili and Senior Director of International Economics and Competitiveness at the NSC Peter Harrell.<br><br>Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, Sameera.&nbsp; You’re kicking us off.<br><br>DEPUTY DIRECTOR FAZILI:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; And thank you, Jen.&nbsp; It is good to be back here at the end of this whole-of-government review that we just undertook of America&#8217;s supply chains, following President Biden&#8217;s direction back in February.<br><br>We said from the beginning that our approach to supply chain policy needs to be an integral part of the President&#8217;s overarching economic strategy to grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out.<br><br>We also said that we were not going to simply be writing reports in this 100 days that were going to sit on a shelf; we are going to be taking action to address specific supply chain vulnerabilities.&nbsp; I think today&#8217;s reports make both those things crystal clear.&nbsp;<br><br>To achieve supply chain resiliency, we need to build back better by leveraging America&#8217;s greatest strengths:<br><br>First and foremost, American workers.&nbsp; Decades of focusing on labor as a cost to be managed and not an asset to be invested in have weakened our domestic supply chains, undermined wages and union density for workers, and also contributed to companies&#8217; challenges finding skilled talent.&nbsp;<br><br>We must focus on creating pathways for all Americans to access well-paid jobs with a free and fair choice to join a union and bargain collectively.<br><br>Second, our diversity.&nbsp; We need to unlock the full potential of the American people, including making economic opportunities available across our country and for women and for people of color.<br><br>Third, our small businesses.&nbsp; To build a diverse and healthy ecosystem of suppliers, we must rebuild our small- and medium-sized business manufacturing base that has borne the brunt of the hollowing out of U.S. manufacturing.<br><br>Fourth, our alliances.&nbsp; We need to diversify our international suppliers and reduce geographic concentration risk.&nbsp; For too long, the U.S. has taken certain features of global markets &#8212; especially the fear that companies and capital are going to flee to wherever wages, taxes, and regulation are the lowest &#8212; as inevitable.&nbsp; The pandemic laid bare the challenges of this approach, and we need to change it.&nbsp; We are committed to working with partners and allies to decrease the vulnerabilities in our collective supply chains.<br><br>And finally, fifth, our imagination.&nbsp; Our approach to supply chain resilience needs to look forward to emerging threats, from cybersecurity to climate issues.&nbsp; And so we are future-proofing and building back better.<br><br>Second, it&#8217;s clear from these reports that we need to take action.&nbsp; And today, we made a series of announcements to that effect, including on pharmaceuticals.<br><br>The Department of Health and Human Services is going to be using its Defense Production Act authority and funding appropriated under the President&#8217;s American Recovery Plan to invest $60 million in advanced pharmaceutical manufacturing technologies and R&amp;D.<br><br>On advanced batteries, the Department of Energy will take steps to advance its support for battery research, manufacturing, and processing.&nbsp; This is going to include new rules to ensure that companies that develop new products based on federal R&amp;D funding manufacture those products in the U.S., so what is invented in America will also be made in America by American workers.&nbsp;<br><br>On critical minerals and materials like lithium and rare earths that are essential in our fight to combat the climate crisis, we will be announcing a comprehensive strategy that includes increases in sustainable U.S. production and processing, and working with allies and partners to increase sustainable global supply and reduce reliance on geopolitical competitors.&nbsp;<br><br>Across all of our domestic and international efforts on minerals, we will maintain a commitment to adhere to the highest environmental, labor, and social sustainability standards, and support robust community engagement in the process, including Tribal consultations here in the U.S.<br><br>On semiconductors, the Department of Commerce will double down on their ongoing work to convene industry and work with allies and partners to increase transparency, communication, and trust throughout the semiconductor supply chain.<br><br>Finally, as we move to focus on our one-year reviews, the Department of Agriculture is announcing more than $4 billion in a robust suite of Build Back Better initiatives focused on building a more fair, competitive, distributed, and resilient food supply chain and food system.<br><br>Third, we need to be nimble and be able to address emerging supply chain issues at the same time as we&#8217;re continuing this work on these longer supply chain resiliency strategies.&nbsp; And that is why today we are launching a new Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force to tackle near-term bottlenecks in the semiconductor, homebuilding and construction, transportation, and agricultural and food industries.&nbsp;<br><br>This task force is going to be led by three Cabinet Secretaries &#8212; Secretaries Buttigieg, Raimondo, and Vilsack &#8212; and will bring in all-of-government approach to addressing the near-term supply and demand mismatches we are seeing in these sectors as the economy reignites.<br><br>They will be collaborating closely with industry, labor, and other stakeholders to surface solutions, share best practices, and take actions.&nbsp; And we at the White House are going to be their partners by their side.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be NEC, DPC, CEA, NSC &#8212; all of us working with them.<br><br>Throughout our work on supply chains, we have been heartened to see the bipartisan support for supply chain security and resiliency, including when the President started this review by meeting with a bipartisan group of senators in the Oval Office.<br><br>We look forward to working with Congress as we move these ideas into action.<br><br>And before I turn it over to my colleague and friend Peter Harrell, I want to note that our report&#8217;s findings reinforce the President&#8217;s call for making a once-in-a-generation investment in our nation&#8217;s production and innovation infrastructure.&nbsp; Those investments proposed in the American Jobs Plan and the American Families Plan will strengthen the public systems that connect manufacturing, researchers, workers, and small businesses, and will help unleash the power and ingenuity of the private markets to drive towards national resiliency.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; Peter?<br><br>MR. HARRELL:&nbsp; Good afternoon. &nbsp;Thanks, Sameera.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a pleasure for me to be here this afternoon.&nbsp; This is a signature initiative for President Biden.&nbsp; He is focused on supply chain resilience since his campaign, when he promised, almost a year ago, that if elected, he would direct his administration to expand investments in U.S. manufacturing and to take other steps to strengthen the resilience of U.S. supply chains.<br><br>Earlier today, pursuant to Executive Order 14017 that President Biden signed in February, we released publicly 250 pages of reports, assessing supply chain vulnerabilities and making recommendations, including immediate actions to address them.<br><br>Earlier this morning, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and National Economic Council Director Brian Deese convened a meeting of many members of the Cabinet here at the White House, in the Roosevelt Room, to discuss the recommendations in this report and for the Cabinet members to commit to taking action across the U.S. government to implement those recommendations and other critical steps to address supply chain resilience.<br><br>While the President&#8217;s supply chain initiative has identified a number of vulnerabilities, I want to stress that our work has also found that the United States is well positioned to rebuild our productive capacity in key sectors and to strengthen our innovative leadership.&nbsp; We&#8217;re confident that working together with Congress, industry, labor, and other stakeholders, we can chart a new path that emphasizes resilience, security, broad-based growth, and sustainability.<br><br>As Sameera mentioned, the President and the entire administration welcome the strong bipartisan support that exists on Capitol Hill for strengthening American supply chain resilience.<br><br>Sameera highlighted a number of the domestically focused specific actions that the administration announced earlier today.&nbsp; I want to briefly discuss just a few of the actions that we&#8217;re taking internationally.<br><br>As Sameera said, America&#8217;s allies and partners are a great strength of our nation, and we must work in partnership with them on supply chain resilience.&nbsp; We&#8217;re announcing today a commitment from the U.S. Development Finance Corporation to increase high standards overseas investments in U.S. allies and partners and projects that strengthen supply chains.<br><br>We&#8217;re also asking the U.S. Export-Import Bank to develop a proposal for a new domestic finance window that would, if approved by EXIM’s board, provide financing to build manufacturing facilities and infrastructure here in the U.S. that will support U.S. exports of critical products, which will help our allies and partners.<br><br>We&#8217;re going to be increasing our diplomatic work with our allies and partners on supply chain security.&nbsp; Supply chain security will feature prominently on the agenda for President Biden&#8217;s trip to Europe starting later this week, including at the U.S.-EU Leaders Summit scheduled for early next week, and was already a major element of President Biden’s summits earlier this spring with key U.S. allies in Asia.<br><br>We&#8217;re also recommending that President Biden host a global forum at the head-of-state level to convene key global leaders to strengthen supply chain cooperation.<br><br>Finally, we know that as we strengthen cooperation with our allies and partners, we also have to push back against unfair trade practices by competitor nations that have hollowed out the U.S. industrial base and undermine our supply chain security.&nbsp;&nbsp;We&#8217;re launching a U.S. Trade Representative-led supply chain trade strike force to identify unfair trade practices that undermine U.S. supply chains and to identify specific trade actions we can bring to combat those practices.<br><br>We&#8217;re also asking the Commerce Department to evaluate a Section 232 action on neodymium magnets &#8212; which are essential to motors and a range of defense and industrial applications &#8212; to identify tools to reduce our foreign dependency.&nbsp; This would demonstrate the type of targeted but tough action we expect the trade strike force to deliver.<br><br>I want to thank members of the Cabinet and their staff who contributed to these reports and actions.&nbsp; The initiative represents an immense amount of work, and we know we have much more in the weeks and months ahead.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll be working to implement all of the recommendations summarized in the report, and carrying forward the work to a second phase directed by EO 14017, which is already underway and consists of broad studies of the supply chain risks of six key industrial base sectors.&nbsp; Those industrial base sector supply chain reports will be due next February, on the year mark of Executive Order <s>1417</s> [14017].&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s been an honor for all of us to work on this initiative, and I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll be talking about it with you regularly as our work goes forward.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, and we look forward to a couple of questions.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, Phil.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I think probably for Sameera, can I flesh out a little bit the Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force?&nbsp; Obviously, you guys believe what&#8217;s happening right now is transitory.&nbsp; But these mismatches exist; they&#8217;re creating near-term problems.&nbsp; Do you expect this task force to be coming up with ideas and proposals in real time?&nbsp; Are they reporting at a specific clip?&nbsp; Kind of, how do you expect this to work to try and address these things that are problems right now?<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp; Well, one, I want everyone to remember and recognize that these are, kind of, good problems to be having.&nbsp; At this time last year, we had bare grocery shelves and we had people going hungry.&nbsp; And thanks to the President&#8217;s American Rescue Plan, we have people finally able to be out there moving again, visiting families this summer, and going out to eat.&nbsp;<br><br>So, these are &#8212; these are good problems to be having and to be working &#8212; working on right now.&nbsp; We&#8217;re thankful for that and the success of our COVID vaccination strategy.&nbsp;<br><br>But I think what you just saw us do right now is a 100-day sprint around four products.&nbsp; And when we say we&#8217;re going to take sprints and take actions, we mean a sprint and we mean action.&nbsp; And so, here, our Cabinet Secretaries, who are in the lead, you’ll see in the days and weeks ahead, they’re going to be bringing together all stakeholders to really diagnose the problems, understand what&#8217;s going on out there in these markets, and see what actions can be taken to close those vulnerabilities.<br><br>We recognize that, in some instances, those actions are going to be actions that the private sector, other stakeholder groups, they need to be the ones taking action.&nbsp; The answer is not always government taking the action here.&nbsp; But we are &#8212; we have learned in our work with the semiconductor, kind of, producers and users that when you bring people together, you help them increase trust, increase transparency, and stimulate a lot of learning that sparks action.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; April.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is for Sameera and Peter.&nbsp; Sameera, you used the word “weakened.”&nbsp; And as we&#8217;re talking about supplies, I&#8217;m looking at the link with inflation.&nbsp; What should the American consumer be looking for now as we’ve come up with this report and the weaknesses that you&#8217;ve talked about as it relates to inflation?&nbsp;<br><br>And then, Peter, for you: You used the words, “vulnerability.”&nbsp; With putting “weakened” and “vulnerability” together, there&#8217;s some kind of economic parallel with this.&nbsp; Where are we economically in this nation?&nbsp; What is our status? &nbsp;We are staving off, or have been trying to stave off depression. &nbsp;Where are we economically?&nbsp; Are we still in recession &#8212; a deep recession?&nbsp; Where are we?&nbsp; If you can answer both of those questions.<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; Look, I think where we are economically is the U.S. is clearly the engine of global growth right now.&nbsp; Our economy has reignited, and the rest of the world is being buoyed by our successes here.<br><br>So the economy is fundamentally in a position of strength, but this President has consistently said that what we need to do is take this moment to build back better.&nbsp;<br><br>So when we talk about weaknesses and vulnerabilities in this report, we&#8217;ve identified structural, long-term problems that have built up over time in our economy, and that is why this President has been out there calling for Congress to take action on his American Jobs Plan and American Families Plan &#8212; because what we need now is a transformational investment to make sure we can actually grow from the bottom up and the middle out.<br><br>Peter, do you want to &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about inflation?<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; Peter.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about the issue of inflation, though, that’s (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; Oh, you know, on these supply chain bottlenecks that we&#8217;re seeing, these &#8212; some of these &#8212; these price dislocations, these temporary increases in delivery time &#8212; we fully expect these bottlenecks to be temporary in nature and to resolve themselves over the next few weeks.&nbsp; Like, if &#8212; again, these are good problems to be having.&nbsp; Demand came back much quicker than even companies expected.&nbsp; I think the success of our vaccination campaign surprised many people, and so they weren&#8217;t prepared for demand to rebound in this way.&nbsp; But we still expect this to be transitory in nature.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to keep an eye on it, but we think it should resolve in the next few months.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the status &#8212; and the status of where we are economically?&nbsp; Recession, staving off depression, deep recession &#8212; where are we?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I mean, I think &#8212; I think Sameera addressed that.&nbsp; I just want to &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, she said &#8212; okay, strength.<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; Strength.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, good.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Josh.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask a little bit more about the semiconductor portion of this?<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; I mean &#8212; and I’ll point you to, on Friday, the OECD report.&nbsp; We’re, like, the one advanced economy that, I think, our growth projections are above where we were at the pandemic.&nbsp; Was it 6.9?&nbsp; So &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Josh.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On semiconductors: How do you plan to balance funding or support for foreign manufacturers &#8212; allies, partners &#8212; and domestic manufacturers?&nbsp; Is there going to be a preference given to domestic, or is there a risk that this could, you know, support foreign manufacturers in a way that actually undercuts the domestic industry?&nbsp; How, if at all, do you plan on balancing that?<br><br>MR. HARRELL:&nbsp; So, I think we are taking an all-of-the-above strategy to semiconductor manufacturing and expanding semiconductor manufacturing, both here in the United States and abroad.<br><br>As you know, the President has called for Congress to appropriate at least $50 billion to strengthen semiconductor manufacturing here in the United States, including both leading-edge semiconductors and also some of the more mature semiconductors where we&#8217;re seeing current shortages for automotive manufacturing and industrial applications.<br><br>Generally speaking, consistent with the proposal in Congress, we would expect to encourage both foreign and American companies to invest here in the United States.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;re already seeing some announcements of that where we&#8217;ve seen announcements from Intel, from Samsung, from GlobalFoundries, from a whole range of both foreign and American companies to expand capacity here.<br><br>But it isn&#8217;t just from an overall strategy; that money is going to be about attracting capacity here in the United States. But from our overall strategy, it&#8217;s not only about expanding capacity here in the United States, it&#8217;s also about working with allies and partners.&nbsp; Yesterday, for example, Bosch, the major European automotive supplier, opened a new automotive semiconductor factory in Germany.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to help alleviate some of the global shortages we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp;<br><br>So while that money is going to lead to greater production here in the United States, and we&#8217;re expecting to see a major increase in production over the next couple of years, this is also an area where we see opportunities to work with allies and partners.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you would treat an investment in the U.S., in a semiconductor plant, equally, whether the investor was a foreign company or an American one?<br><br>MR. HARRELL:&nbsp; So we expect that the incentives will be available on a competitive basis to both foreign and American companies.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not here to get into the specifics of exactly how the program will be implemented, if Congress, in fact, passes &#8212; passes it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, finally, can you talk a bit about the trade strike force?&nbsp; What are they tasked with doing or able to do that USTR doesn&#8217;t do already?<br><br>MR. HARRELL:&nbsp; So I think the trade strike force is a vehicle to leverage a number of our existing trade tools, but to really focus them on supply chain vulnerabilities.&nbsp; You know, we have &#8212; as we looked across the four products that we are releasing reports on today, we saw example after example where an unfair foreign competitor action had led to the hollowing out of a supply chain for a key U.S. product.&nbsp;<br><br>And these are all often very specific things those foreign governments are doing.&nbsp; So what this is going to do is harness and focus the government agencies involved in trade enforcement on how do we use our trade tools to strengthen &#8212; to combat unfair trade practices that impact supply chains and to strengthen U.S. supply chains.&nbsp; And I think the neodymium magnet &#8212; 232 &#8212; we&#8217;re asking Commerce to evaluate is an example of that.<br><br>Through our reports, we identified a very specific product where there&#8217;s a very specific supply chain vulnerability, and we&#8217;re getting the task force to look at that.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Brian.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I guess, the Disruption Task Force &#8212; are you all going to be looking at ransomware attacks?&nbsp; And how will you deal with it internationally?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; On ransomware?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; The Disruption Task Force is focused on semiconductors, lumber and construction &#8212; or homebuilding and construction materials; it&#8217;s not going to focus on ransomware and cybersecurity.&nbsp; We have a whole &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So how will you deal with that?<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; &#8212; other process in place, led by our National Security Council, that addresses cybersecurity risks and issues.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, internationally, you&#8217;ll deal with that how?<br><br>MR. HARRELL:&nbsp; So I think you saw, the other day, Deputy National Security Advisor Neuberger talk about some of the steps that the administration is taking to address ransomware.&nbsp; She is leading a process to identify and close vulnerabilities that we face from ransomware.<br><br>One of the sets of issues we have been looking at in our supply chain review, both on these four products and in our year-long industrial base, is cybersecurity risks to our supply chains.&nbsp; Clearly, cybersecurity risks can disrupt supply chains.&nbsp; But Ms. Neuberger is leading the, sort of, focus response to the ransomware issue.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that’ll be two siloed &#8212; two different things?&nbsp; Or are they working together (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; I would not say it&#8217;s siloed.&nbsp; We work very closely.&nbsp; I think Peter and I being up here shows you how closely the National Economic Council and National Security Council work together on issues where it makes sense for us to come together.&nbsp; And so, on cybersecurity, you have seen us behind the scenes working together to figure out how we can leverage our tools and our convening power to have a full government response repeatedly.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, last one.&nbsp; Right in the middle.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the administration unbundle &#8212; work on unbundling large contracts to ensure that Black-owned companies can compete for them?<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; So, we are very focused on trying to make sure that our Build Back Better agenda &#8212; sorry, it&#8217;s hard to see &#8212; is it okay if I stand here &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. FAZILI:&nbsp; &#8212; to be able to look &#8212; yeah.&nbsp; I relate.&nbsp; &nbsp;I relate.&nbsp;<br><br>No, we are &#8212; we are really focused on making sure that as we talk about diversifying supplier bases here in these reports, that we are not just talking about small businesses but<br>we&#8217;re talking about disadvantaged businesses as well, and minority-owned businesses.&nbsp; And so, you&#8217;ve seen in our American Jobs Plan that we put proposals in there related to small business and strengthening small business.&nbsp; And we know that an important piece of that is leveraging federal procurement and power of the government to support those businesses.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Christian has been very eager in the back.&nbsp; Go ahead, Christian.&nbsp; Last actual one.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You talked about the Export-Import Bank and some of the financing that is going to be done to shore up industrial manufacturing here in United States.&nbsp; Under the previous administration, though, China was one of the top destinations of U.S. export-import financing.&nbsp; An overwhelming majority of that money actually went to state-owned enterprises.&nbsp; Is the administration looking at anything in terms of financing that goes to some of these industries overseas?&nbsp; Shouldn&#8217;t, you know, the priority be making certain that money stays here?<br><br>MR. HARRELL: &nbsp;So that&#8217;s actually exactly the proposal we&#8217;re asking the Export-Import Bank&#8217;s board to evaluate: is a new window that would foster direct EXIM Bank financing for the construction and manufacturing in infrastructure here in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, they have a longstanding set of programs that finance the export of products made in the United States to foreign buyers.&nbsp; But, actually, it&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re asking them to look at is ways to expand the financing for construction and investment here in the U.S.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you both so much for joining us.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp; Always welcome.<br><br>MR. HARRELL:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We love to talk about supply chains in here.&nbsp;<br><br>Okay, just two more items for all of you at the top.&nbsp; Yesterday, in Guatemala City, following a bilateral meeting with the Guatemalan President, the Vice President announced a new effort to partner with Guatemala around security, economic development, and anti-corruption.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, in Mexico, the Vice President will hold a bilateral meeting with President Obrador.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll discuss our economic relationship, security cooperation, and stemming migration.&nbsp; The Vice President and President Obrador will witness the signing of a memorandum of understanding between the United States and Mexico to establish a strategic partnership to cooperate on development programs in the region.&nbsp; And the Vice President will also meet with labor leaders, women entrepreneurs, and U.S. embassy staff before she returns to the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>One last item for all of you.&nbsp; We have more good news on the global fight against COVID-19.&nbsp; Today, the Mastercard Foundation and Mastercard pledged to make a $1.3 billion contribution to help make critical progress in providing vaccines to people across Africa, in partnership with the Africa Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.&nbsp; This is a significant commitment to acquire COVID-19 vaccines for at least 50 million people, and to build long-term manufacturing and equitable distribution capacity, which will further enable efforts to provide vaccines and strengthen the continent’s ability to prepare for future pandemics.&nbsp;<br><br>This is a welcome addition to our announcement last week that approximately 5 million of our first tranche of COVID-19 vaccines will be shared with African countries, in coordination with the African Union.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Which vaccines?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Which vaccines?&nbsp; They&#8217;re providing funding &#8212; a contribution of funding to ensure that these vaccines are provided to Africa.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have the &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So it’s up to them whichever vaccines they take?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s, again, funding to the Africa CDC &#8212; version of the CDC.&nbsp; So it will be distributed through there.<br><br>With that, Darlene, why don’t you kick us off.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Have the President and Senator Capito had their conversation yet?&nbsp; And what can you tell us about it, if they have?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They have not had a conversation yet, but they will have a conversation this afternoon.&nbsp; And the President looks forward to continuing the discussion with the senator.&nbsp; He appreciates her good-faith engagement over the last few weeks.&nbsp; I would reiterate, as was noted in the statement we put out last week, that while the President came down by quite a bit in his proposal &#8212; from his initial proposal &#8212; on the American Jobs Plan, the latest offer that we had seen from Senator Capito&#8217;s group did not meet the essential needs of our country to restore roads and bridges, prepare us for a clean energy future, and create jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>So today they&#8217;ll have a discussion about what more there is to discuss, I guess, and what the path looks like for it.&nbsp;<br><br>I will also note that the President will also speak with other senators this afternoon &#8212; still finalizing who those will be, and we&#8217;ll have readouts of that as well &#8212; who have been engaged in discussions about a bipartisan infrastructure proposal &#8212; engaged with each other.&nbsp; So he&#8217;ll have those discussions as well.&nbsp; I expect we&#8217;ll have a readout, as I noted.<br><br>We&#8217;re encouraged by these discussions and see them as an additional viable path forward.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll ask members of his Jobs Cabinet &#8212; or he&#8217;s already asked them, I should say, to remain engaged in the days ahead, the period of time when he&#8217;s on his foreign trip &#8212; although, of course, he&#8217;ll remain engaged from there as well &#8212; with all members who are interested in working together on making a historic investment in infrastructure.<br><br>And just third piece I would note, Darlene, as we&#8217;re kind of &#8212; since you asked about the President engagement &#8212; he&#8217;s also going to stay closely engaged with Democratic leadership about the path forward, especially in light of the markup on the Surface Transportation bill happening tomorrow in the House and the interest by Speaker Pelosi, Leader Schumer, and other leaders in Congress on moving forward &#8212; and certainly an interest in doing that.&nbsp;<br><br>Finally, last thing I would note is the expected passage later today of the U.S. Innovation and Competitiveness Act in the Senate this afternoon, which is a down payment on the President&#8217;s proposed investment in R&amp;D to make us more competitive, as well as the important work with Senator &#8212; that Senator Wyden has undertaken on clean energy tax credits, a priority the President shares.<br><br>So I would just note, as I&#8217;ve stated many times before in here, there are a number of paths for moving the President&#8217;s bold ideas forward.&nbsp; We&#8217;re moving on all of them full speed ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more question.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since the President is the head of the Democratic Party, would he support legislation that is now on the governor&#8217;s desk in Nevada that would move Nevada to first place in the presidential primary process, up from third place?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I certainly understand the interest, but I&#8217;m not going to weigh in on the order of a presidential primary contests from here.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Mary.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the infrastructure talks, Senator Capito has said she is not going to be coming to this conversation armed with a new offer.&nbsp; As you note, the President has rejected the Republicans’ latest counteroffer.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t seem that he&#8217;s willing to come down any further.&nbsp; So, are we at an impasse here?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly don&#8217;t see it that way.&nbsp; He&#8217;s looking forward to discussing the path forward with Senator Capito.&nbsp; He sees her as an important and viable partner as we look to how we&#8217;re going to get his bold ideas signed into law.&nbsp;<br><br>And again, I&#8217;d note that there&#8217;s also Democrats and Republicans &#8212; as you have seen and many of you have reported on &#8212; who are discussing what &#8212; how they can work together on what a path forward would look like, where there might be more investment in clean energy jobs, and might be a higher number than what we&#8217;ve seen by the proposals to date.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, there are a lot propo- &#8212; a lot of paths forward.&nbsp; And he looks forward to discussing what they look like with Senator Capito and others this afternoon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President, though, willing to offer any other concessions in these negotiations, or is it safe to say that you view the ball as being in the Republicans’ court here?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think this is &#8212; as any negotiation is, it&#8217;s about both sides looking to see how much they can come to the other side, and how much you have to give.&nbsp; The President has come down by about a trillion dollars; that&#8217;s quite a bit.&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;d like to see more.&nbsp; But there are a number of opportunities and paths to have these discussions, moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to &#8212; just broadly, if you could explain a little bit more how the President has been preparing for this big trip tomorrow.&nbsp; How much time has he been spending in briefings?&nbsp; Just, sort of, how has he been getting ready for this upcoming trip?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I will say that he&#8217;s been getting ready for 50 years.&nbsp; He has been on the world stage.&nbsp; He&#8217;s known a number of these leaders for decades, including President Putin and including a number of the leaders he&#8217;ll see at NATO and he&#8217;ll see at the G7.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, this is an important opportunity for him to see them in person, and there&#8217;s nothing like face-to-face engagement in diplomacy.&nbsp; And for him, somebody who, as you&#8217;ve seen &#8212; the fact that he&#8217;s welcomed in Democrats and Republicans to the Oval Office, that&#8217;s just an indication of how much he feels that format is effective.&nbsp;<br><br>So, he&#8217;s been engaging with his team, talking about what bilateral conversations he&#8217;ll be having; where there are opportunities; where there are moments to voice the United States’ concern, where necessary.&nbsp; But again, he&#8217;s &#8212; he&#8217;s got quite a &#8212; several decades of experience to build on here.&nbsp; So, you know, he&#8217;ll be relying on that in the &#8212; in &#8212; during his trip.<br><br>Go ahead, Phil.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Granholm, on Sunday, said that it was frustrating that a pathway for a bipartisan deal hadn&#8217;t come to fruition yet.&nbsp; Does the President share that frustration at this point?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say the President has a benefit of 36 years in the Senate, where he has seen that the sausage-making is messy.&nbsp; It takes time.&nbsp; There are ups and downs on the roller coaster.&nbsp; We&#8217;re right in the middle of the sausage-making right now.&nbsp;<br><br>And the President&#8217;s view is that it&#8217;s a good sign that there are several viable paths forward, that we are having good-faith conversations, of course, with Democrats and our Democratic colleagues and partners, but also with a number of Republicans.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a good sign.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, the House is moving forward with marking up key components of the American Jobs Plan.&nbsp; So, the fact is this train is moving on several tracks.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we know these larger packages, larger proposals often move forward.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re encouraged by the variety of options.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And along the lines of sausage making, given the scale of the President&#8217;s ambitions with his proposals he’s put on the table, is the real reason that he&#8217;s still in bipartisan negotiations right now because moderate Democrats are saying, “We need to stay in bipartisan negotiations right now”?&nbsp; Or does he think something can come of them?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President wouldn&#8217;t be spending his time engaging in hours of discussions with Republicans if he didn&#8217;t think something could come from it.&nbsp; Now, we can&#8217;t predict what the final outcome is, and we&#8217;re keeping &#8212; his only lines in the sand &#8212; as you know, Phil &#8212; are inaction and raising taxes on Americans making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp;<br><br>We know there is &#8212; there are a lot of Democrats who are eager to move forward, as are we.&nbsp; But we think there are a lot of paths forward where we can &#8212; where it&#8217;s worth continuing to pursue bipartisan discussion.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; About the Vice President’s trip: Why is it then that when the Vice President is asked if she has plans to visit the border, she says, “We’ve been to the border,” even though she has not, as Vice President?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as the Vice President, she does speak for the actions of the people in the administration she certainly helps oversee.&nbsp; I expect that sometime she may go to the border, Peter.&nbsp; But as you know, what her focus has been, what the assignment is specifically, is to work with leaders in the Northern Triangle.&nbsp; She&#8217;s on a trip doing exactly that, exactly what the President asked her to do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, as we understand it though, her main focus is to try to address the root causes of migration.&nbsp; Did somebody decide here that it would not be helpful for her to go to the border and talk to people who just migrated here?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think that at some point she may go to the border.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see.&nbsp; But she&#8217;s in the Northern Triangle now to have discussions with leaders, with community leaders, with civil society leaders, with the embassy about how we can work together.&nbsp; And obviously she&#8217;s made a couple of announcements already &#8212; probably more to come before she comes back to the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And she described though &#8212; you said she might go to the border &#8212; she described a trip to the border yesterday as a “grand gesture.”&nbsp; Why?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, Peter, again, I think her focus of this trip is on meeting with leaders, having a discussion about how to address corruption, how to address the root causes, how to work together to address humanitarian challenges in these countries.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what she&#8217;s doing on the ground, and I&#8217;m sure she&#8217;ll report back to the President when she returns.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to follow up with the border in a second, but let me ask you, if I can: On infrastructure, you laid out some of the conversations that the President is having including, sort of, his message to some of the Democrats on Capitol Hill right now to, sort of, get a little better detail there.&nbsp; Would the President support &#8212; does he want Democrats to more actively pursue the process of reconciliation as an option?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, I would say that the Democrats are already moving forward on marking up components of the bill.&nbsp; And Democratic leadership has been clear that they want to move forward on infrastructure and making a historic investment in infrastructure.&nbsp; There’ll be a discussion about the mechanics of that, you know, over the course of the coming days.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more to read out once those discussions have been had.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, again, in terms of, like, the timeframe for those decisions to be made, obviously the message to Democrats is, “Keep going” and “We might need you”?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, look, I think, to be clear: The President is always going to continue to pursue opportunity to work with Republicans, regardless of what mechanics are moving forward in the House.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to keep pursuing those opportunities.&nbsp; And we fully expect that there will be several pathways that are moving on different channels as we look to how we&#8217;re going to get this American Jobs Plan passed.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As it relates to the border right now, we heard from the Vice President yesterday where her message was very simple and blunt.&nbsp; She said to those migrants who would be considering coming &#8212; she said, “Do not come.”&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, there&#8217;s some progressive Democrats, among other critics, who&#8217;ve been frustrated by that &#8212; Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez perhaps, most prominently saying, “It was disappointing to see.”&nbsp; She said, among other things, that “seeking asylum at any U.S. border is a 100 percent legal method of arrival.”&nbsp; What does the White House say to those progressive Democrats, among others, who were frustrated by the message the White House is delivering?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, of course it is.&nbsp; And one of our focuses and the priorities of the President and the Vice President is to improve asylum processing at the border, to work with a range of Democrats &#8212; and, hopefully, Republicans &#8212; because, in history, it&#8217;s been a bipartisan effort to get immigration reform passed, to make &#8212; ensure there&#8217;s a more viable pathway to citizenship and a better processing at the border.<br><br>What the Vice President was simply conveying is that there&#8217;s more work to be done, that we don&#8217;t have these systems in place yet, it&#8217;s still a dangerous journey, as we&#8217;ve said many times from here and from many forums before, and we need more time to get the work done to ensure that asylum processing is where it should be.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last question about the Senate report &#8212; bipartisan Senate report as relates to what happened on January 6th.&nbsp; Obviously, it addressed the security planning and response failures.&nbsp; We know that that&#8217;s held up on Capitol Hill right now.&nbsp; Your reaction to that?&nbsp; And what, if anything, more the White House can do as it relates to those security failures in terms of planning and the like?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me just reiterate that of course the events of January 6th were an assault on our democracy and the rule of law.&nbsp; And the President has been outspoken in calling for a full and independent investigation to what transpired.<br><br>As it relates to the report, our team is currently reviewing the report and its findings to inform our ongoing efforts to ensure something like that could never happen again and what role, of course, the federal government can play.&nbsp; There are many roles, as you know, that the report seems to surface on what officials on Capitol Hill could do.&nbsp; And we want to assess how we can be a good partner in this effort moving forward.<br><br>I would also note that on his first full day in office, he asked his team to launch a review on how we can improve the federal government&#8217;s response to the threat of domestic terrorism, something he also touched on when he was in Tulsa last week.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be releasing that broader strategy soon, as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The FDA has still not cleared the 60 million AstraZeneca doses that are part of the President&#8217;s commitment to share 80 million doses overseas by the end of June.&nbsp; Is there any concern that the administration will not get that approval from the FDA in time?&nbsp; And if that were the case, will the U.S. then make up for those 60 million doses with other available vaccines in order to meet the President&#8217;s deadline of the end of June?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we, as you know, can&#8217;t predict or expedite the timeline here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the FDA who will make that decision about when those doses will be approved, if and when they will be approved.&nbsp;<br><br>We do remain committed to ensuring that we meet our commitment of 80 million doses &#8212; getting those out to the global community by the end of June &#8212; which is, again, five times more than any other country and 13 percent of our own supply.&nbsp; It&#8217;s only June 8th, so we have quite a bit of time.&nbsp; But we remain committed to that. &nbsp;And obviously if the FDA approves AstraZeneca doses, then that will be a component of that supply.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just, as the pooler, a question on behalf of our colleagues at The Canadian Press, as well as Global News. &nbsp;On the timeline for reopening the U.S.-Canada border: Canada has said it will look to take a phased approach.&nbsp; Does the White House see an announcement happening in concert, or is the U.S. prepared to ease those restrictions on its own?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we would make a decision about the Canada border based on the guidance of our health and medical experts.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sure that when that decision is made, we would communicate through diplomatic channels.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to predict about the timeline.<br><br>Go ahead, Mara.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve mentioned how long the President has spent in the Senate.&nbsp; He&#8217;s talked himself about how timing and sequencing things are really key to presidential leadership.&nbsp; Does he have an objection to starting with H.R.4 instead of H.R.1?&nbsp; In other words, why not do the John Lewis Act first?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think he is quite open to what Democratic leadership feels is the viable path forward, and we’ll work closely with them in coordination.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But there&#8217;s a difference of opinion on that &#8212; on what would be the best one to go forward.&nbsp; Democratic leadership is (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to be &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to be the arbiters of that, but we will discuss with them.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re leaving that to them.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will discuss with them as we &#8212; as we look ahead what the right path forward is.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, and my second question, just on infrastructure: In terms of the people he&#8217;s speaking to this afternoon, will one of them be Mitt Romney?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; we will give readouts of who he’s spoken with once we&#8217;ve completed those calls.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this moment.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he ever spoken to Mitt Romney?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Has he ever spoken time in his life?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, since he’s been President.&nbsp; No, since he’s been President.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; He&#8217;s spoken with a number of Republicans.&nbsp; As you know, we don&#8217;t read them all out.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to read out for you, but he has, obviously, in different circumstances, has had (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of these different paths and different groups, this group that he&#8217;s going to talk to &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; this afternoon, is this the first time that he&#8217;s starting to, kind of, reach out to them?&nbsp; He&#8217;s been really focusing on Capito up until now.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s right.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been engaged with a range of Democrats and Republicans, including members who have been in conversation through this group at a staff level.&nbsp; He&#8217;s obviously had discussions with a number of them about how he moves his ideas forward.&nbsp; So I wouldn&#8217;t make it as firm as a first time.&nbsp; But certainly discussing this as a viable path forward at his level, at this point in the process, you know, would be an indication of how we see this as a viable path.<br><br>Go ahead, (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, just to follow up on the question on voting rights, you said yesterday that we will stay lockstep with the Democratic leadership on that path forward.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what Pelosi said in her letter today is that the H.R.4 is not going to be ready until the fall.&nbsp; So are you &#8212; and to focus &#8212; just to focus effort on the Senate passing H.R.1.&nbsp; So are you okay with that kind of timeframe, if that &#8212; even if that means that basically this issue languishes until the fall?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, we don&#8217;t see it as languishing.&nbsp; Obviously, the President has asked the Vice President to lead this effort.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll give you a bit of an update that, in addition to, of course, engaging with federal efforts on the federal level to move legislation forward, she&#8217;s also going to use the power of the White House to convene key stakeholders.&nbsp; And she&#8217;ll be hosting several events next week when she returns from her trips &#8212; just to give you an indication of how quickly and how focused we will be on these efforts.&nbsp; And she&#8217;ll fight for our key bills and also to register voters under the President&#8217;s historic executive order, as well as advocate for Democratic principles.<br><br>So, I will say, we&#8217;re going to work, of course, with Democratic leadership on both &#8212; on both, even with their disagreements about the &#8212; the &#8212; what the order of events should be here.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re not going to wait for that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to use the White House as a convener.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to use the bully pulpit.&nbsp; Obviously, when the President was in Tulsa just last week, he talked about voting rights very passionately and forcefully.<br><br>I&#8217;ll also note that we&#8217;re also continuing to work to implement the executive order that the President signed into law early on in his administration, and that executive order uses every authority available to make voting easier, more accessible, and more fair.&nbsp; It directs agencies to expand access to voter registration and election information, assist states under the National Voter Registration Act, improves and modernizes Vote.gov, increases federal employees’ access to voting, analyzes barriers to voting for people with disabilities, increases voting access for duty &#8212; active-duty military and other voters overseas.&nbsp;<br><br>So I would just note that we are not relying on just one option here.&nbsp; Of course, federal legislation is something he will continue to press for, but we&#8217;ll use the bully pulpit, we&#8217;ll use our convening power, we’ll continue to press through on implementing this executive action as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On a separate issue &#8212; there was a report this morning about, basically, IRS records showing that very wealthy Americans have evaded paying income tax, almost altogether in certain circumstances.&nbsp; One, do you have any reaction just to that as a factual matter?&nbsp; And, two, are you concerned about that just from a leak standpoint?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me take the second part first because I think that&#8217;s important.&nbsp; Any unauthorized disclosure of confidential government information by a person with access is illegal, and we take this very seriously.&nbsp;<br><br>The IRS commissioner said today that they are taking all appropriate measures, including referring the matter to investigators.&nbsp; And Treasury and the IRS are referring the matter to the Office of the Inspector General &#8212; the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration, the FBI, and the U.S. Attorney&#8217;s Office for the District of Columbia, all of whom have independent authority to investigate.&nbsp;<br><br>So, obviously we take it very seriously.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to comment on specific unauthorized disclosures of confidential government information.<br><br>I can tell you that, broadly speaking, we know that there is more to be done to ensure that corporations, individuals who are at the highest income are paying more of their fair share, hence it&#8217;s in the President&#8217;s proposals, his budget, and part of how he&#8217;s proposing to pay for his ideas.&nbsp;<br><br>April, go ahead.&nbsp; And, sorry, I’ll come back to you.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to &#8212; I want to follow back up on voting rights &#8212; on matters of voting rights.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This President has based his administration on equity and equality.&nbsp; And now the issue of voting rights is in our face.&nbsp; We are voting without the full protections of the 1965 Voting Rights Act because of Shelby v. Holder, but it&#8217;s also unraveling because of states.&nbsp; And the person that seems to be holding it up is Joe Manchin.&nbsp;<br><br>Is the President planning to specifically speak with him about voters &#8212; not including it with infrastructure or anything &#8212; is he planning on speaking with him specifically on voting rights, particularly after this morning&#8217;s virtual meeting with civil rights leaders who say the conversation will continue?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that it was encouraging to see Senator Manchin meeting with civil rights groups today. The meeting shows that both are serious and recognize the importance of the issue.&nbsp; We certainly know the seriousness that many civil rights groups take with voting rights and the importance of moving this forward.&nbsp; And as indicated in both of their readouts, as you said, April, they will continue the discussion.<br><br>I would certainly expect that when the President has a conversation with Senator Manchin the next time, they&#8217;ll talk about voting rights.&nbsp; And &#8212; but often when he speaks with members, he talks about a range of issues &#8212; some where you work together; some where you disagree.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, understanding the history of how presidents decide to lean in, he&#8217;s got Vice President Harris putting this in her portfolio.&nbsp; But when will the President begin to lean?&nbsp; And is there a moment where he has to, himself, lean in on this?&nbsp; Because if it doesn&#8217;t happen before the next elections, it looks like it could be a done deal.&nbsp; Voting rights are (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, April, you were with the President in Tulsa last week.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You heard how passionately he spoke about voting rights, how central this is to how he views his presidency, his leadership, the future of our democracy.&nbsp; I mean, that was central to the message he delivered in a speech that was widely covered, that was reflecting on a moment in history that hasn&#8217;t requi- &#8212; it hasn&#8217;t been given the attention that it certainly deserves.&nbsp;<br><br>I certainly would not say we&#8217;re waiting.&nbsp; As I noted, we&#8217;re going to continue to press for federal action, for action to move forward on a bill that the President would love to sign into law.&nbsp;<br><br>We certainly know we can&#8217;t do that with a magic wand. That&#8217;s not how democracy works for good reason.&nbsp; But the President also signed this executive action early on &#8212; a very expansive and powerful executive action &#8212; because he wanted to &#8212; did not want to delay a moment in ensuring that we were taking more steps to assist states, to improve and modernize Vote.gov, to increase federal employees’ access to voting, to analyze barriers to voting for a range of people.&nbsp; And that was an action he took early on.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to implement now.<br><br>And I&#8217;ll also note that the Vice President asking his Vice President &#8212; his partner &#8212; to play a role in leading this &#8212; something that she also asked for, just to be clear &#8212; asked to do &#8212; it sends a message about what a priority this is to the President.&nbsp; They have regular lunches.&nbsp; They engage &#8212; she&#8217;s the first in the room and the last in the room.&nbsp;<br><br>And she&#8217;s going to not hesitate either &#8212; not delay either, I should say.&nbsp; When she comes back from her trip, she&#8217;ll be convening people and she will be elevating these issues as well from her platform.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Weijia.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The Family Reunification Task Force has reported that of the about 3,900 children who were separated from their families, it does not have a confirmed record of reunification for 2,127 children.&nbsp; Can you explain what that means that they don&#8217;t have a record of reunification?&nbsp; Does the administration know where these children are?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first &#8212; as you know, Weijia, from covering this &#8212; and I know another &#8212; a number of others have &#8212; one of the challenges that they walked into &#8212; or we walked into &#8212; is the lack of data.&nbsp; And that &#8212; we knew that would take some time to ensure that we were handling the data and handling the reunification process as carefully as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>I would note that, through the support of NGOs, 1,779 children were reunified with their parents in the United States under past court orders.&nbsp; Over the last 30 days, through the task force and NGO coordination, seven additional children were reunited with their fami- &#8212; parents, bringing the total number of reunified children to 1,786.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of where we go from here, I mean, I would certainly point you to the task force for what their terminology means.&nbsp; We know there&#8217;s a challenge with data, a challenge with matching that to what we have access to.&nbsp; But beyond that, I would certainly point you to Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you don&#8217;t know if the administration is aware of where these children are?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not what I said.&nbsp; What I said was the Department of Homeland Security oversees the task force, and I would certainly point you to them to give you more of a clear definition of exactly what they mean by “mismatched data” so you have all the information you&#8217;re looking for.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And one more &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the Justice Department.&nbsp; President Biden has accused his predecessor of using it as his own personal law firm.&nbsp; Is he disappointed that the DOJ is siding with Trump in his claim that he can&#8217;t be sued for defamation for remarks that he made about an alleged rape case?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that the President strongly believes in the independence of the Department of Justice.&nbsp; We were not consulted &#8212; the White House was not consulted, I should say more specifically &#8212; by the Department of Justice on the decision to file this brief or its contents.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So does he believe that that independence still exists, even though the DOJ is defending the former President?&nbsp; The firewall between &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure what you mean by your question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he believe that the DOJ defending the former President in this case still maintains that independence between the executive branch and the DOJ?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think what I was referring to is allowing for the Department of Justice to make decisions and announcements about ongoing, you know, court filings and legal actions.&nbsp; So independence as it relates to how the &#8212; this President views and approaches the Department of Justice.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But does it upset him?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Does it &#8212; I think the President has been pretty clear, as Weijia started her comment conveying, about his view about the pres- &#8212; his view about his predecessor’s comments, about his predecessor’s language, and about his predecessor’s approach, and his engagement in that regard.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what can he do?&nbsp; What can he do about it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think I have anything more to speak to you on, Brian &#8212; on active litigation.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Josh.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask &#8212; there was a series of web outages this morning &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that were linked to a company called Fastly.&nbsp; Is there any indication that it&#8217;s anything other than just failure with that company?&nbsp; And specifically, is it a potential national security issue?&nbsp; Have you look into whether there&#8217;s a potential external group behind it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, Fastly, I know, put out a statement about it.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more from the federal government on the leak &#8212; on the outage.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then pivoting to the G7, the President has talked about the need to push the G7 to boost vaccine &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; availability overall.&nbsp; Can you speak to what he&#8217;s considering?&nbsp; Prime Minister Johnson, for instance, has talked about the need to vaccinate the world in its entirety by the end of 2022.&nbsp; Other European leaders are not going quite so far.&nbsp; Does the President have a view on what specific target the G7 should take?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I expect we&#8217;ll have more in the coming days, Josh, so stay tuned.&nbsp; Jake did say he expected that you all will hear more at the G7.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of that too much.&nbsp;<br><br>But what I would say is that the United States is &#8212; we&#8217;re headed into the G7 in a position of strength, with 64 percent of our adult population vaccinated; in a position to donate more doses to the world than any other country around the world.&nbsp; But we certainly know this needs to be a global effort, and it will be a discussion at the G7, and we&#8217;ll have more to say in the coming days.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more on infrastructure.&nbsp; Given the &#8212; you know, what Senator Capito said today to reporters &#8212; kind of throwing cold water on progress between her and the President on talks &#8212; would you say the administration has become more willing to pursue reconciliation to pass the infrastructure package than maybe a week ago or two weeks ago?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that there are always &#8212; there&#8217;s always been a range of paths to get the President&#8217;s bold ideas passed into law.&nbsp; He&#8217;s having a conversation with Senator Capito this afternoon, as well as individual conversations with other members who have been working in a bipa- &#8212; bipartisan manner, to see what the path forward looks like.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s also closely in touch with Democratic leadership.<br><br>So, I&#8217;m not here to rule out options, but I&#8217;m not here to rule in new options either.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have &#8212; we&#8217;ll have more to say after he has these calls later this afternoon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, one more.&nbsp; The White House said over the weekend it was unaware of the DOJ gag order on the New York Times.&nbsp; Can you assure us that there are no other gag orders on other news organization related to some of these investigations?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the Department of Justice has made clear that was their third and final notification that they were offering.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the information they also shared with us.&nbsp; But they&#8217;ve shared it publicly.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so there would &#8212; to your understanding, there&#8217;s no other gag orders?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They made clear &#8212; they indicated that this was their last effort &#8212; their last notification that they needed to offer.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; So I have a question that&#8217;s a little infrastructure, a little climate.&nbsp; Senator Sheldon Whitehouse was tweeting yesterday, saying that he was anxious about the future climate-related legislation.&nbsp; And he said, &#8220;Climate has fallen out of the infrastructure discussion, as it took its bipartisanship detour.&nbsp; It may not return.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>Then he went on to say, &#8220;I don’t see the preparatory work for a close Senate climate vote taking place in the administration.&#8221;&nbsp; Has the White House reached out to the senator?&nbsp; And also, does he have cause for concern on the future of climate-based legislation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I promise you we are certainly in touch with his team, and perhaps even on an individual basis as well, but I don&#8217;t have anything to read out for you.&nbsp; But I can just tell you that we are in close touch with nearly every member of Congress who is working on these legislation moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say that &#8212; what I would point out to you is that one of the &#8212; one of the pieces we conveyed when &#8212; when we put out a statement last week about how the President could not accept the offer that was put out by Senator Capito and her group, even though those conversations are happening in good faith, was the fact that it didn&#8217;t do enough to invest in our clean energy future.&nbsp;<br><br>And there are areas of effort that are moving forward.&nbsp; I mentioned Senator Wyden&#8217;s effort to move forward on clean energy tax credits.&nbsp;<br><br>The President views this bill as a jobs bill.&nbsp; He also believes it&#8217;s a clean energy jobs bill and it has an opportunity to invest in industries of the future.&nbsp; So, certainly, it is close to his heart.&nbsp; It remains an area he&#8217;s committed to and one he will continue to fight for as we have these discussions moving forward.<br><br>Q &nbsp;And then I just had another on the Vice President visiting the border or not visiting the border. &nbsp;Republicans and conservatives are, you know, going crazy on Twitter, sending pictures &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They&#8217;re worked up.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; sending videos &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve seen it.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; of her interview with Lester Holt, you know, saying, &#8220;I&#8217;m not…&#8221; &#8212; you know, &#8220;I&#8217;ve not been to Europe, either.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>Does the President think there is a scenario in which she should visit the border?&nbsp; And also, the mounting criticism from conservatives, does that &#8212; would that ever factor into a decision to send her down there?&nbsp; I mean, don&#8217;t they have a point that if she has this task in front of her, should she not see the &#8212; the end cause as well as the root cause of migration?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, as I said to Peter: At some point, she may go to the border.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any trips to preview for you or predict or a timeline for that.&nbsp;<br><br>But what I would reiterate is that her assignment was to work with countries and leaders in the Northern Triangle to address root causes, address corruption, ensure we&#8217;re working together to address humanitarian concerns.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say, we&#8217;re not taking advice from former President Trump or most of the Republicans who are criticizing us on this, given they were all sitting there while we created this problem we walked into, both at the border and with the movement of migration that has been growing over the last year.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re not taking our guidance and advice from them.&nbsp; But if it is constructive and it moves the ball forward for her to visit the border, she certainly may do that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I have two questions on infrastructure.&nbsp; You said the White House is moving ahead on all three paths on infrastructure, including the third path, which was listening to other lawmakers who have ideas &#8212; I believe that&#8217;s how you characterized it.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m just trying to clarify &#8212; and this was asked a little bit earlier: I mean, are you referring to the bi- &#8212; bipartisan group that consists of Senators Manchin, Sinema, Romney, and Portman?&nbsp; And if current talks with Senator Capito and her group don&#8217;t progress, is there a point when you stop negotiating with that group in favor of this other group of Republicans and Democrats?&nbsp; Is that how you&#8217;d see it working?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say we&#8217;ll leave it to them to determine what groups they may or may not want to join.&nbsp; But they&#8217;re not &#8212; it&#8217;s not a closed group.&nbsp; We would welcome anyone who wants to join that group and be a part of these discussions moving forward.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Members of the press?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; see where it heads.&nbsp; Members of the press, I&#8217;ll leave it to them to determine.&nbsp; I think you have to be an elected member of the Senate.&nbsp; So, unless that&#8217;s your pathway moving forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you are engaging with them though already?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>And then my second question is: What specific proposals did the White House agree to bring down or eliminate in its latest infrastructure counteroffer that reduced the cost from $1.7 trillion to $1 trillion in new spending?&nbsp; Does funding &#8212; specifically, does funding for caregiving remain in the president&#8217;s latest offer?&nbsp; And if it does, I mean, is it still the $400 billion price tag?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Caregiving remains a huge priority &#8212; investing in caregiving &#8212; to the President.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to outline any more specific details, other than to convey that it&#8217;s an area that continues to fight for, to advocate for, and one that he&#8217;d like to be signed into law as part of a package moving forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But does that mean it&#8217;s not part of what you&#8217;re negotiating right now with Republicans?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, that&#8217;s not what I said.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any more details to outline for you.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, Jen &#8212; sorry.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll go &#8212; sorry, we’ll go to you next.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The chief of Russia&#8217;s space agency is threatening to pull out of the International Space Station unless the United States lift sanctions against two companies that are related to the space station.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House response to that?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a really interesting question and I didn&#8217;t know much about it before you asked this question, so I&#8217;ll probably have to talk to our national security team.&nbsp; I will say that working together on issues of space and issues related to space is one area where we have worked together, historically, with the Russians on.&nbsp; And I’d have to dig more into what those sanctions are for.&nbsp; I’m not aware of a consideration of that, but I&#8217;ll check with our national security team.<br><br>Go ahead, Yamiche.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much, Jen.&nbsp; A follow-up to Weijia’s question: In four months, the Family Reunification Task Force has reunited about 36 families.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering what the White House makes &#8212; what the President makes of the ACLU saying it hopes the government increases that pace?&nbsp; Does the President want to see this go faster?&nbsp; Are there any explanations for maybe why it needs to go slower?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly do, as I think any member of the Family Reunification Task Force would want to as well.&nbsp; And one of the challenges has been what we walked into, which was a lack of data or tracking for a number of these kids that were separated from their parents when they came across the border over the last few years.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a huge data challenge.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re not going to reconnect them with families where it&#8217;s not properly verified &#8212; right? &#8212; because we know there&#8217;s a history over the last several years of, you know, kids being connected with pa- &#8212; with individuals who had malintent.&nbsp;<br><br>So, that&#8217;s a factor, Yamiche.&nbsp; We wish &#8212; of course, everybody wants it to go faster.&nbsp; Everybody wants &#8212; in this administration, everybody wants these kids to be reunified with their family members and with verified family members.&nbsp; But, you know, we&#8217;re working with a challenging issue related to data that we knew would be the case from the beginning.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think that pace is going to be the pace?&nbsp; Or do you think it will get quicker?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would certainly point you to them &#8212; the members of the task force and the Department of Homeland Security, who are much more in depth about where the status is, where the challenges are, and what the holdups are.&nbsp; And we can certainly invite one of them to come and speak to you at the appropriate time as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then I wanted to ask about &#8212; I know there’s the COVID task force, but, in some ways, when you look at southern states, they are lagging, particularly, when it comes to vaccination rates.&nbsp; I wonder if the President has any sort of plan specifically targeted to southern states and whether or not that will impact whether or not he moves back to 70 percent goal that he set up for July 4th?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Yamiche, you are right that there are different age groups, there are different demographic groups, there are different geographic groups in the country where we haven&#8217;t seen the pace as fast as others.&nbsp; So, while it&#8217;s very high &#8212; the vaccination rate &#8212; at this point among seniors, and even pretty high &#8212; over 70 percent &#8212; for people 40 and older &#8212; still young, I will note &#8212; it is &#8212; it is not where it needs to be in people under 40 and certain states around the country.<br><br>What we&#8217;re trying to do and what we just launched this past weekend is this massive, one-month campaign to incentivize &#8211;right? &#8212; people getting vaccinated.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working with the private sector.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to barbershops.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working with, you know, donuts and beer and all sorts of incentives to get young people and people vaccinated who have been either hesitant, resistant, or just didn&#8217;t want to take the step to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re going to continue charging through the finish line to &#8212; in pursuit of our 70 percent goal.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen 13 states meet that goal.&nbsp; It&#8217;s ultimately up to some &#8212; some &#8212; these states and some individuals to get vaccinated to meet it in a state-by-state basis.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one last question: There are some progressives who are calling Joe Manchin &#8212; Senator Manchin &#8212; &#8220;the new Mitch McConnell,&#8221; saying he&#8217;s an obstructionist, saying that he&#8217;s standing in the way of the Biden agenda.&nbsp; I wonder what the President makes of that.&nbsp; Is he worried about progressives alienating Senator Manchin?&nbsp; Or does he agree with some of the things that they&#8217;re saying about standing in the way of his agenda?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think we&#8217;re not going to &#8212; we&#8217;re going to leave the name-calling to others.&nbsp; The President considers Senator Manchin a friend.&nbsp; He disagrees with him on voting rights and &#8212; and the &#8212; the bill that the senator has expressed he won&#8217;t support.&nbsp;<br><br>The President will continue to advocate for the importance of that moving forward and the reasons why that it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s important and vital for our democracy.&nbsp; But, you know, we&#8217;ll continue to seek ways we can work with Senator Manchin even in &#8212; while we have areas of disagreement.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just wonder if you think it’s &#8212; the name-calling &#8212; is it alienating the senator?&nbsp; Is it worrisome that you&#8217;re hearing Democrats say that about Senator Manchin, calling him &#8220;the new Mitch McConnell&#8221;?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that problematic?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to &#8212; to Senator Manchin’s personal &#8212; the personal impact on Senator Manchin.&nbsp; He&#8217;s obviously proud of his independent streak.&nbsp; He&#8217;s spoken to that, including in an op-ed piece this weekend.&nbsp;<br><br>I also &#8212; we also understand the passion that many feel for voting rights; for the importance of making voting easier, more accessible.&nbsp; We share that passion.&nbsp; So, we understand that manifests itself in lots of ways.&nbsp; But, I point you to Senator Manchin if he&#8217;s &#8212; if he has feelings hurt.&nbsp; I suspect he has a stronger backbone than that.&nbsp;<br><br>But thank you everyone so much.&nbsp; Look forward to &#8212; I guess I won&#8217;t see you for a while.&nbsp; Those of you who are coming on the trip, we&#8217;ll see you on the trip.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; See you there.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.<br><br>2:19 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
