<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 21:50:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Virtual Celebration of Afro-Latino&#160;Heritage</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/26/readout-of-white-house-virtual-celebration-of-afro-latino-heritage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 21:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, as part of Black History Month programming, the White House hosted a virtual Celebration of Afro-Latino Heritage, where Administration officials highlighted how President Biden has prioritized equity and diversity in his Administration. The program consisted of two panels and remarks from Ambassador to Spain Julissa Reynoso, Senior Advisor to the President and Director of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, as part of Black History Month programming, the White House hosted a virtual Celebration of Afro-Latino Heritage, where Administration officials highlighted how President Biden has prioritized equity and diversity in his Administration. The program consisted of two panels and remarks from Ambassador to Spain Julissa Reynoso, Senior Advisor to the President and Director of the White House Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond, Dean of the USC Rossier School of Education Dr. Pedro Noguera, as well as a spoken word by writer Melania Luisa Marte.</p>



<p>Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute CEO Marco Davis moderated a discussion focused on Afro-Latino representation with Chair of the National Endowment for the Arts Dr. Maria Rosario Jackson; Director of the Office of Intergovernmental and External Affairs at the Department of Health and Human Services Marvin Figueroa; and Hispanic Association on Corporate Responsibility CEO Cid Wilson. White House Senior Advisor for Public Engagement Carissa Smith later moderated a second discussion focused on achieving Black wellness, the theme for this year’s Black History Month, with Deputy Director for Energy Justice, Shalanda Baker, at the Department of Energy, and Acting National Director of the Minority Business Development Agency, Miguel Estién, from the Department of Commerce. Administration officials shared accomplishments from the first year of the Biden-Harris Administration and participants shared their own experiences as leaders in the Afro-Latino community.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on U.S. Support for the People of&#160;Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/26/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-u-s-support-for-the-people-of-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 05:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47919</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (February 25, 2022) 3:07 P.M. EST MODERATOR:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; And again, thank you for joining us for today’s background call on U.S. support for the people of Afghanistan. Today’s briefing is on background and attributable to “senior administration officials.”&#160; The briefing is embargoed until its conclusion. For your awareness only and for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(February 25, 2022)</p>



<p>3:07 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; And again, thank you for joining us for today’s background call on U.S. support for the people of Afghanistan.<br><br>Today’s briefing is on background and attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The briefing is embargoed until its conclusion.<br><br>For your awareness only and for not reporting, our senior administration officials are [senior administration officials].&nbsp; Again though, that’s for your information only; again, for the purposes of this call, they will be “senior administration officials.”<br><br>With that, I’ll turn it over to our senior administration official number one to give some opening remarks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you very much, and thank you all for joining us.<br><br>Over the course of the last several months, one area of focus for the Biden administration has been on ensuring that the Afghan people have access not only to humanitarian assistance but also to the ability to conduct regular commercial activity.<br><br>In order to make sure that the humanitarian crisis doesn’t get worse, one of the things we know that is critical is ensuring that the economy is able to function.&nbsp; And later today, we’re going to issue a new General License to expand authorizations for commercial and financial transactions in Afghanistan, including with Afghanistan’s governing institutions.</p>



<p>Treasury’s License authorizes all transactions involving Afghanistan and its governing institutions that would otherwise be prohibited by U.S. sanctions, to the extent required.&nbsp; However, it does not authorize financial transactions to the Taliban, Haqqani Network, associated entities, and any blocked individual who is in a leadership role of a governing institution in Afghanistan.</p>



<p>The License will ensure U.S. sanctions do not stand in the way of transactions and activities needed to provide aid and support the basic human needs of the people of Afghanistan.&nbsp; It reflects our deep commitment to support the people of Afghanistan during this ongoing humanitarian and economic crisis.</p>



<p>While sanctions relief alone cannot reverse longstanding structural challenges and the flight of technocratic and government experts due to the Taliban’s mismanagement, it can ensure that sanctions do not prevent economic activity that the people of Afghanistan rely on to meet their most fundamental needs.</p>



<p>This GL is in addition to the six other previously issued General Licenses, which also support the provision of humanitarian aid and support for basic human needs to the people of Afghanistan.<br><br>Today’s action is just the latest step in the Biden administration’s efforts to help address the substantial challenges facing Afghanistan’s economy.&nbsp; The administration has acted in full recognition of the challenging economic reality on the ground.</p>



<p>As many of you know, prior to the Taliban’s takeover, Afghanistan was dependent on external aid, receiving approximately $8.5 billion in grants each year, which financed 75 percent of public expenditures.&nbsp; Moreover, more than half of these foreign transfers were for military and security needs and have been terminated.</p>



<p>The poverty rate in 2020 stood at nearly 50 percent, and only 10 to 20 percent of Afghan adults had bank accounts.&nbsp; An underdeveloped financial sector also held back growth.&nbsp; Prior to 2021, Afghanistan’s loan-to-GDP ratio stood around 3 percent &#8212; the lowest in the world.</p>



<p>Overall, the IMF estimates that Afghanistan faces an economic contraction of up to 30 percent.</p>



<p>Our goal here is to make sure that we do everything we can to make sure that money is flowing to the Afghan people to help alleviate the humanitarian crisis that they face, but also to allow the commercial activity in Afghanistan to happen in order to build a (inaudible) cycle that will reinforce the livelihoods of the Afghan people.<br><br>In order to do this, it’s critical that Afghan institutions be put in a position where civil servants are allowed to function, including at the central bank, where we have made clear that in order for the international community to engage with the central bank, it’s important that it establishes independence, bring in a third party to validate that independence, and get the kind of technical assistance that is needed to ensure that they are able to put in place basic standards for the prevention of illicit finance, similar to what was done prior to August of 2021.</p>



<p>Our goal ultimately is to make sure that Afghanistan is a place where economic activity can happen and investments can happen in the long-term future of Afghanistan.&nbsp; This is why the U.S. government has partnered with NGOs to facilitate the provision and aid and financial resources to support humanitarian activities in Afghanistan.<br><br>Treasury and our interagency partners are working with the multilateral development banks, including the World Bank and Asian Development Bank, to provide substantial economic assistance to the people of Afghanistan.</p>



<p>In January, the administration announced an additional $308 million in USAID humanitarian assistance for Afghanistan, bringing total U.S. humanitarian aid for Afghanistan and Afghan refugees in the region to more than $780 million since October.</p>



<p>In December, the United States and other donors to the World Bank-administered Afghanistan Reconstruction Trust Fund decided to transfer $280 million.</p>



<p>To UNICEF &#8212; $100 million &#8212; 100 million of those dollars will go towards helping with things like paying teachers who have long needed support.</p>



<p>The World Food Programme will get another $180 million of that money.</p>



<p>These funds will enable UNICEF to provide essential health services, as well, to 12.5 million people, including 1 million vaccines, and allow the World Food Programme to provide food assistance to 2.7 million people in Afghanistan.</p>



<p>Treasury and our interagency partners are working to make additional resources available for the multilateral development banks, which together with the support &#8212; with support in December should result in approximately $1.75 billion in support from the multilateral development banks to meet critical basic human needs of the Afghan people.</p>



<p>Going forward, Treasury and the Biden administration will continue to apply rigorous sanctions to the Taliban and their collaborators until they halt their repressive actions, while providing necessary exemptions to facilitate the flow of legitimate aid to the Afghan people.<br><br>Our overall goal here is to ensure that the Afghan economy can function in the way that alleviates the humanitarian crisis and provides for opportunity going forward.<br><br>With that, let me turn it over to my colleague.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thank you very much, [senior administration official].  Hello, everybody.  This is the individual mentioned.<br><br>I want to zoom out just a bit and tick through a few of the efforts that we have to, sort of, place this General License in a broader context.<br><br>So, overall, I think the fundamental point I would make to you is that the most urgent priority animating both American diplomacy, as well as American decision-making on Afghanistan, is to meaningfully address the humanitarian and economic crises underway in Afghanistan.<br><br>There are too many Afghans starving today, too many Afghans who are cold.  We all need to act faster.  And that goes for the World Bank.  It goes for the region.  It goes for the Taliban as well.<br><br>But as [senior administration official] mentioned &#8212; as my colleague mentioned, we contributed over half a billion in humanitarian aid between August and December of last year.  We&#8217;ve already announced $308 million to a $4.4 billion appeal that the U.N. announced in January.<br><br>We&#8217;re very pleased that the United Kingdom, together with OCHA, will be hosting a pledging conference later in March. <br><br>We&#8217;re very glad that the OIC held an Extraordinary Ministerial in Islamabad, that they announced a trust fund that will be managed by the Islamic Development Bank.  And we hope that that trust fund results in pledges from OIC members as well.<br><br>As my colleague mentioned, we&#8217;re in very close touch with the World Bank.  We&#8217;re pleased that nearly $300 million is already supporting the health sector out of the Afghanistan Reconstruction Trust Fund. </p>



<p>There&#8217;s an upcoming board meeting where I think there will be an additional large amount under consideration by the board as well.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve worked with the private sector, particular actors in Europe, to see shipments of hundreds of millions of dollars into Afghanistan explicitly for the purpose of helping humanitarian relief efforts scale up.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m pleased to say that the Taliban have not interfered in the delivery of those dollars in any way to date, although we will watch it very closely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re in close touch right now with the World Bank and UNOPS on the establishment of something they&#8217;re calling a &#8220;humanitarian exchange facility,&#8221; which, for folks who follow this issue closely will know, could help to provide more general liquidity in the economy, including Afghanis&#8217;.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, I&#8217;d say that the President&#8217;s February 11th executive order, I think, was pretty widely misunderstood to begin with.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen some much more accurate coverage since then, but, fundamentally, that action was about protecting and preserving for the Afghan people $3.5 billion in assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, there&#8217;s an ongoing court process, and that court has not made any decisions on awards to litigants.&nbsp; But we were very glad to move ahead with an action that will protect and preserve for the Afghan people $3.5 billion in assets.</p>



<p>And then relatedly and finally, I&#8217;ll say that we have a range of really tough problems when it comes to fundamentally easing the economic crisis underway that we can&#8217;t solve by ourselves, and some are frankly unsolvable.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll just mention two.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first is that Afghanistan&#8217;s central bank lost a lot of capacity after the March military takeover by the Taliban.&nbsp; We saw some of the senior-most technocrats from that institution leave the country.&nbsp; And as a result, some of the functions that international financial institutions look to to ensure that their correspondent relationships are protected either atrophied or, in some cases, disappeared altogether.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, rather than just admire the problem, we have been engaging with technocrats at the central bank intensively since November and have made specific recommendations on measures and steps they can take to enhance both capacity as well as independence, and to stand up an AML/CFT architecture that, again, has largely disappeared.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the final thing I would say is that, you know, when we talk to banks &#8212; both foreign banks as well as American banks &#8212; they are reticent to engage in this market not just for concerns about our sanctions posture &#8212; it&#8217;s a matter of profitability.</p>



<p>They have shareholders.&nbsp; Afghanistan is not a profitable place to do business at the moment.&nbsp; And so, what I would tell you is that, as we take this action today, it&#8217;s incumbent on the Taliban to pursue policies that will attract investment to the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I look forward to questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, can you hear me?&nbsp; Hello?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Yes, we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, great.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry to be dense about this, but I&#8217;m having a hard time understanding what these new measures actually do that wasn&#8217;t being done before.&nbsp; You know, you said it will make it easier for civil servants that are not blocked persons to operate.&nbsp; Does that mean that you&#8217;re going to lift all restrictions on dealings with civil servants like central bank officers and the people beneath them and just anybody who&#8217;s not actually on the list as a &#8220;blocked person&#8221; or be free to engage in banking transactions?&nbsp; Is that what this does?&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I just &#8212; I don&#8217;t quite get the sort of shape of it.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, Karen, so let me just try and make it as clear as possible.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re saying is that the government of Afghanistan, as well as the country of Afghanistan isn&#8217;t blocked.&nbsp; If, before August of 2021, you were working closely with an Afghan civil servant in the DAB or in the Finance Ministry or in the Ministry of Education, you can continue doing that.&nbsp; You can continue to make regular payments as long as they are not going to the benefit of the Taliban, the Haqqani network, or named individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what we&#8217;re doing here is clarifying our stance, which is taking what we had done with regard to humanitarian assistance, in terms of the GLs, and largely matching that in terms of commercial activity, and clarifying that people can go back to doing exactly what they&#8217;ve been &#8212; what many have already been doing, but making it very clear that you can continue to make commercial transactions in Afghanistan, as well as transactions with government individuals who aren&#8217;t blocked.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for having this call.&nbsp; With respect to the frozen Afghan government accounts, you recently said there were &#8220;ongoing discussions&#8221; about the best use for about half the assets &#8212; the $3.5 billion.&nbsp; And you said that the money could be used to recapitalize the Afghan central bank?&nbsp; Can you give us an update on that situation &#8212; on those discussions?&nbsp; Have you made any kind of decision about recapitalizing the Afghan central bank?&nbsp; And can you say who&#8217;s involved with those discussions?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, maybe I can talk to the economics, and then I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk a little bit about some of the ongoing discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the truth of the matter is that the humanitarian situation is clearly interrelated with the economic situation on the ground.&nbsp; Getting the banking sector functioning is critical to this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think part of what we would like to do is make sure that the DAB is in a position where they can take back on normal central bank activity.&nbsp; And much of that is, frankly, in the hands of the Taliban.</p>



<p>Our General License puts them in a position where you can go back to interacting with Afghan government officials.&nbsp; But in order for the international community to be willing to interact with the DAB, they&#8217;re going to have to establish their independence, bring in a third party to help monitor that, and get back in some of &#8212; get in people to help with technical assistance given the number of technical officials who have left the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I think one of the things we&#8217;re thinking through with my colleagues in the U.S. government and a number of our international partners and allies is how can we support the Afghan banking sector and the economy in order to make sure they can operate in a way that supports the Afghan people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk a little bit about those discussions.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, this was one thing that I thought some of the early coverage got wrong.&nbsp; And to be to be very clear, and I know I&#8217;ve said this before, but: No decisions have been made regarding specific uses of this $3.5 billion.&nbsp; And as we move ahead, a couple of things are happening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number one, we&#8217;ve begun discussions with a number of countries &#8212; I&#8217;m not in a position to share today with which countries &#8212; but regarding the establishment of a temporary financing mechanism. <br><br>And I think, as we look to set up that mechanism, we&#8217;re looking to be absolutely sure that &#8212; on its governance, as well as the potential uses of this money, which is, you know, Afghan reserves and for the benefit of the Afghan people &#8212; that we are talking to professional Afghans in this space, people who have served in leadership positions of the central bank, of the finance ministry; folks who&#8217;ve been technocrats; folks who have a strong opinion, as Afghans, about what would be a responsible use of these funds.<br><br>And so I&#8217;m not in a position today to get into more detail.  I think it&#8217;s a completely legitimate question to say, you know, who are those folks?  I hope we&#8217;re in a position to share that in the coming weeks, but I&#8217;m not in that spot today.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think the one thing that I will say is that we&#8217;re thinking broadly about how we address the humanitarian crisis and not in a narrow way.&nbsp; And we know that the humanitarian crisis is related to broader macroeconomic concerns.&nbsp; So working closely with [senior administration official] and others, we&#8217;re thinking through how best, in consultation with those that [senior administration official] mentioned, to address the broader economic challenges that Afghanistan faces.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; To clarify, just to make sure that I have a grasp of what you&#8217;re announcing today: If you&#8217;re an investor or a private company, you can work with Afghan civil servants again and not be penalized.&nbsp; Is that an accurate summation?<br><br>And then secondly, is this an iteration of what you &#8212; of what the Treasury put out earlier this month, in terms of licensing for humanitarian assistance and NGOs?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The simple answer is yes.&nbsp; And I think one of the things that we tried to do was we put out the humanitarian guidance because we had talked to a number of NGOs, and what they told us was they needed formal guidance, given their concerns about working in Afghanistan.&nbsp; And as we had conversations with commercial actors, people who were doing business there or small business in Afghanistan, they told us it would be helpful for us to provide more guidance that was similar to that for commercial activity as well.&nbsp;<br><br>So we also wanted to clarify that it&#8217;s possible for you to continue working with civil servants in Afghanistan.&nbsp; The key is to ensure that what you&#8217;re doing and the resources that you&#8217;re providing aren’t providing material support to people who are sanctioned.&nbsp;<br><br>So, if the individual is a civil servant who was working in the Afghan government in August of 2021, you can continue doing the same work you were doing with them at that point today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I do not understand one particular thing.&nbsp; It seems that you are saying that the General License will permit ordinary dealings with Afghan civil servants so long as those dealings do not ultimately provide material support to or inure to the benefit of specific designated Taliban or Haqqani Network figures.&nbsp;<br><br>But given the fact that the Taliban essentially is now the governing authority, how is it that permitting people to do ordinary transactions with civil servants does not intrinsically inure to the benefit of and potentially provide material support to members of the Taliban and/or the Haqqani Network?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Money is fungible.&nbsp; How can these transactions not indirectly, if not directly, benefit the Taliban and Haqqani Network officials who are in power?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s a great question, and I&#8217;ll turn it over to my colleague in a moment.&nbsp; But this isn&#8217;t the only country in which we have this kind of situation.</p>



<p>In Burma, where we have sanctioned members of the junta, people are still permitted to do business with government entities there as well.&nbsp; And the thing that we&#8217;re tr- &#8212; the thing that we are doing here is we are making a careful, consideration here, where we are saying that you cannot provide material support to certain sanctioned individuals but we don&#8217;t want to cut off the country of Afghanistan, the people of Afghanistan from the resources they need to live and to try and address the economic and humanitarian crisis there.&nbsp;<br><br>This is something that we&#8217;ve been able to do in other situations and in other countries using our sanctions regime.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re going to do here in Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br><br>But let me turn it over to my colleague to also respond.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, thank you very much.&nbsp; I mean, one thing &#8212; I think when you dig into the mountain of paper that will be released as attached to this GL, you&#8217;ll see a lot of this in black and white, and that&#8217;ll be helpful.&nbsp;<br><br>So the General Licenses is one thing.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see some very helpful Treasury FAQs.&nbsp; I&#8217;d say the second FAQ just gives very practical examples of what this &#8212; what this license now authorizes.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see statements by folks, including Secretary Blinken, where we make clear that this License is aimed at facilitating a broad range of commercial activity in Afghanistan that benefits the Afghan people.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;ll also make clear that, while sanctions on the Taliban remain in place, this action facilitates private companies and aid organizations working with Afghan governing institutions and paying customs, duties, fees, and taxes, even if those institutions are headed by sanctions &#8212; sanctioned individuals.&nbsp;<br><br>So I think a lot of the questions we&#8217;ve all gotten are around whether or not they can deal with sanctioned ministry &#8212; or ministries headed by sanctioned individuals, and this License makes very clear that they can.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, and I think I’ll just say it again that this is not something that we haven&#8217;t done in other sanctions programs that the Department of Treasury operates.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve able to do it in a way that allows us to allow government institutions to function while making sure that the benefit &#8212; that money is not provided and material support is not provided to sanctioned individuals.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hello, everybody.&nbsp; Just wanted to let everyone know that we&#8217;ve officially run to the end of our time.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, first and foremost, I want to thank everyone for joining us, again, for this call this afternoon.&nbsp; The call is on background and attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The embargo will be lifted at the conclusion of the call.&nbsp;<br><br>3:31 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 25,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/25/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-25-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 04:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:37 P.M. EST MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; All right, I just have one item for all of you at the top, which is the week ahead.&#160; And I know there are a few topics to discuss today during our time together. &#160; On Monday, the President will host a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:37 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; All right, I just have one item for all of you at the top, which is the week ahead.&nbsp; And I know there are a few topics to discuss today during our time together. &nbsp;</p>



<p>On Monday, the President will host a celebration to mark Black History Month.&nbsp; He will be joined by the Vice President, Black members of the historically diverse Cabinet, members of the Congressional Black Caucus, state and local elected officials, civil rights leaders, and Divine Nine leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Tuesday, as you are all tracking, the President will deliver his first State of the Union Address.&nbsp; We will have more of his address to preview in the coming days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Wednesday, the President and the First Lady will travel to Superior, Wisconsin, to discuss how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law delivers for the American people by rebuilding roads and bridges and creating good-paying union jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on Thursday, the President will hold a Cabinet meeting.</p>



<p>With that, Zeke, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The EU, earlier today, agreed to hold &#8212; put in place sanctions and asset freezes on the Russian President Vladimir Putin and the Russian foreign minister.&nbsp; Is the United States going to follow suit?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Following a televisi- &#8212; a telephone conversation President Biden held with European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen and in alignment with the decision by our European Allies, the United States will join them in sanctioning President Putin and Foreign Minister Lavrov and members of the Russian national security team.&nbsp; I expect we&#8217;ll have more specific details out later this afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And additionally, can you detail the level of support the United States government is currently providing operationally to the Ukrainian military and intelligence services as they try to fend off the Russian invasion?&nbsp; Is the U.S. continuing to send weaponry into Ukraine?&nbsp; Is it providing intelligence on Russian movements and tactical communications and the like?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, without getting into too many specific details that are sensitive for a range of reasons, we are continuing to deliver on the security assistance package that was announced earlier last fall.&nbsp; All of that has not been delivered yet.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to provide that assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, we are &#8212; we remain in very close touch, of course, with &#8212; with President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; I think you may have just seen the readout that we just put out that included the President spoke with him earlier today again.&nbsp; And we are in very close touch, from our national security team, with members of his team as well.&nbsp; And we continue to &#8212; to consider a range of options to provide additional assistance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And President Zelenskyy, last night, said he was &#8220;target number one&#8221; of the Russian military.&nbsp; Does the United States have &#8212; sort of have a warning to Russia in the event that &#8212; in the event they were to target the Ukrainian president or attempt to capture him or to physically harm him?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Do we have a warning to them?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A warning to Russia, yes &#8212; specifically regarding the head of state.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say that we have been warning for months that &#8212; for weeks, if not months &#8212; that Kyiv falling, that attempts to overturn the leadership of Ukraine is very much in the aspirations of President Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So his &#8212; their attempts to do exactly that and their continued progress in moving toward Kyiv and moving toward Ukrainian leadership is aligned with what we have predicted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, going after the head of state would be a significant, horrific act by Russian leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we remain in contact, as you all have seen from the readout we provided, with President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; He&#8217;s made clear that he&#8217;s still in Ukraine, proudly and courageously standing up in the face of the Russian attack.&nbsp; And we are &#8212; certainly continue to be concerned about the ongoing Russian assault on the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on a different topic: The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention right now is announcing new federal mask guidelines that &#8212; including, under them, 70 percent or so of Americans right now live in areas where they are no longer recommended to wear masks indoors in public settings.</p>



<p>Is that guidance that will be followed here in the White House as Washington, D.C., is now not an area recommended anymore for wearing masks indoors.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, we are evaluating our protocols.&nbsp; Obviously, this guidance is just going out now as we speak.&nbsp; I believe Dr. Walensky continues to provide a briefing call with some of your colleagues right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>D.C. currently has a mask mandate until March 1st.&nbsp; We have always followed the most stringent guidelines &#8212; that has typically been the CDC.&nbsp; So, we will plan to follow that.&nbsp; And in the meantime, we will &#8212; we are evaluating our protocols here at the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On President Zelenskyy, did &#8212; in President Biden&#8217;s phone call with him, did it come up whether &#8212; did President Biden bring up whether President Zelenskyy &#8212; he thinks he should leave the country or not for his own safety?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is not &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any additional details to provide.&nbsp; President Zelenskyy continues to serve as President of Ukraine.&nbsp; He continues to do that courageously in the face of attacks from Russian military.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This was a call for the President to reiterate our strong support for him, for the Ukrainian people, and to reiterate and condemn the actions of the Russians.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;And on sanctioning Putin and Lavrov: Yesterday, President Biden had said that that was on the table.&nbsp; What changed between yesterday and today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it has been under consideration and on the table for some time, as you know.&nbsp; And as I just conveyed, the President&#8217;s strong view and strong principle from the beginning of this conflict &#8212; and even before, I should say &#8212; has been to take actions and steps in alignment with our European partners, and this is certainly evidence of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just finally, on that one: What does sanctioning Putin himself do in this &#8212; in the opinion of this administration?&nbsp; A lot of analysts have said that this is more of a symbolic move than anything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, without getting into any specific details &#8212; I know you&#8217;re not exactly asking me this, but sort of &#8212; about financial assets, et cetera &#8212; I will leave that to others to speak to &#8212; certainly, the United &#8212; this step that we are doing in alignment and in coordination with Europeans just sends a clear message about the &#8212; the strength of the opposition to the actions by President Putin and the direction in his leadership of the Russian military.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Just wanted to ask &#8212; continuing the questions on sanctions &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, we saw that the Italian government and the German government both expre- &#8212; said very clearly that they would not veto a move to remove Russia from the SWIFT transaction system.</p>



<p>Can you say a word about how quickly you think something like that would happen and whether you believe that that would be another productive tool and perhaps another moment &#8212; you know, symbolic or, rather, an important measure?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, again, the President&#8217;s principle is doing &#8212; taking steps in alignment.&nbsp; We are stronger together, especially as we stand in the face of the Russian military&#8217;s actions and &#8212; and their invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>As it relates to SWIFT, we&#8217;ve never taken that off the table, of course, and I&#8217;m certainly not taking it off the table today.&nbsp; So, certainly, there&#8217;ll be ongoing discussions about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, SWIFT is a messaging service that connects 11,000 banks.&nbsp; And many would argue that there are ways that &#8212; that Russia &#8212; the Russian leadership could get around that over the course of time, but it certainly remains an option on the table.</p>



<p>In terms of the timeline, I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We were &#8212; also reported today that China has actually increased its reserves as opposed to releasing reserves, which could help, perhaps, with the energy price increases that we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; Have you had &#8212; you know, what do you &#8212; what do you think of that move?</p>



<p>And then also, has there been any further communication? Does President Biden intend to talk to President Xi?&nbsp; Or can you say a word about what &#8212; what you&#8217;re doing in terms of trying to convince the Chinese to be supportive?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would note that, also today, the I- &#8212; the IEA had an informal meeting where they discussed options they could take over the coming days and weeks to help address any volatility in the global markets and, you know, the heightening of price volatility.</p>



<p>And certainly, that meeting today was a chance to consult and continue coordination with partners on global energy supply and security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also continuing conversations that we have had from here with partners over the past day.&nbsp; Secretary Granholm spoke with French, German, EU, and UK counterparts yesterday and will continue those conversations.</p>



<p>As it relates to China, you know, I would say that the President&#8217;s view, of course, is that now is the time for leaders of the world to not just speak out clearly against President Putin&#8217;s flagrant aggression and to stand with the people of Ukraine, but this is not a moment for evo- &#8212; equivocation or hiding or waiting to see what happens next.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is already clear what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; And as a part of that, it&#8217;s also important to be a part of the effort to mitigate and minimize the impact on global markets and gloi- &#8212; global oil markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I don&#8217;t have any additional conversations to read out for you.&nbsp; But I would say, certainly, we all want to be a part of the solution here and stand up in the face of aggression to help address the problems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you saying that China is, in fact, equivocating?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;All I&#8217;m saying is that every country should think about what side of history they want to be on here, and they have the ability to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When did President Biden make the final decision to sanction President Putin?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It was made &#8212; it&#8217;s been on the table for some time, but through coordination and discussion with our European partners over the last day or so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he decided in the last 24 hours that he was going to do that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, it&#8217;s been on the table for some time.&nbsp; His priority and his focus has been on taking steps in coordination.&nbsp; And obviously, that decision was made over the course of the last 24 hours and in partnership with our European counterparts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does it include a travel ban, by chance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I believe that would be a part of the U.S. component.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So President Putin would be banned from traveling here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is more details of it that, again, will be out later today.&nbsp; There are very limited examples of this being done, as you all know, but that is a standard part.&nbsp; But again, there&#8217;ll be more details we will have available later today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another question on travel.&nbsp; The UK is banning civilian Russian aircraft from its airspace, saying that no aircraft on a service owned, operated, or chartered &#8212; chartered by a person connected with Russia shall fly in their airspace.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Is the United States planning to do the same?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of that being in the plans, but I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And another question.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen these predictions from the Defense Department, from the State Department about Kyiv falling to Russia.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve made clear that they believe that is in Putin&#8217;s sights and that he wants to overthrow the government there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If that happens, what does the U.S. do?&nbsp; What is the response and the role that the United States takes after something like that happens?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just reiterate, as we&#8217;ve been warning for months, that Kyiv falling is a real possibility.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve continued to see Russia&#8217;s progression, even as we&#8217;ve seen resistance on the ground, Russians&#8217; military continu- &#8212; Russia&#8217;s military continues to advance toward Kyiv.&nbsp; So there is that real possibility. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just not going to get into, at this point, hypotheticals of what that will look like or what our response would be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I just want to follow up on the Putin sanctions again &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; based on what you&#8217;ve said so far.&nbsp; So, was this decision to coordinate with Allies meant to show unity, meant to show that Putin is a pariah?&nbsp; Or do you think it will actually have an impact on Putin in practice, given the uncertainty about the extent and location of his wealth?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, I understand what you&#8217;re asking; I&#8217;m just not going to get into specifics about his financial assets from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, I think what is important and what we are hoping the world takes away from this is the unity through which the United States, President Biden is working with our European partners and Allies.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Without getting into details, can you even say if this will or will not impact him, other than showing that he&#8217;s, you know, an outlier?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to get into his personal financial assets.&nbsp; That&#8217;s typically not something we would do from here.&nbsp; But I would note, again, that the steps that were taken yesterday and announced yesterday &#8212; sanctioning the 10 largest financial &#8212; 10 of the largest financial institutions in Russia, accounting for a huge percentage of their banking capacity, what &#8212; of their financial system capacity, I should say &#8212; and even the anticipation of that has had enormous impact on Russia, whether it&#8217;s the currency &#8212; the Ruble &#8212; that has fallen, the markets, skyrocketing inflation in Russia.</p>



<p>And we also have taken steps to sanction oligarchs around President Putin &#8212; people who have benefited from corruption and cronyism in the system &#8212; and even their family members to prevent them from having the capacity to move around their assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the Supreme Court today &#8212; news of the day: It was exactly two years ago today that the President made a pledge that he would nominate a Black woman to the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Did he factor the timing of that into his decision to announce it today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then can you share any details about the process &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; now that it&#8217;s over?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Finally, we&#8217;re free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Like, you know, how long the interview or interviews were, what they talked about, what led the President to choose Judge Jackson over the other candidates.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, I will share with you the details that we&#8217;re comfortable sharing at this point in time.  And obviously, Judge Jackson will have &#8212; be filling out a range of questionnaires.  She will be testifying.  She will be considered by the full Senate, and she will be asked a range of questions there.<br><br>The President interviewed Judge Jackson, Judge Childs, and Judge Kruger on Monday, February 14th, in person.  He made his final decision and called Judge Jackson last night &#8212; last evening.  I would note it was after the press briefing last evening.<br><br>The President called Leader Schumer, Senator McConnell, Speaker Pelosi, and Whip Clyburn &#8212; all separately &#8212; this morning to inform them of his decision.<br><br>I&#8217;d also note that the Vice President has been very engaged not just in the decision-making process, as the President talked about during his remarks, but she called former President Obama and former President Clinton as well.  And she has also been calling a range of members of Congress as a part of the announcement process.<br><br>Q    Just one more.  Did he personally call Kruger and Childs to let them know that he had chosen Judge Jackson?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any other details on that.&nbsp; But I can tell you that he called Judge Jackson to offer her the &#8212; to tell her he was going to nominate her last evening.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The State Department just said, about the U.S. and Russia, that there are still some areas in which the fulfillment of our national security priorities and imperatives require us to engage and coexist.&nbsp; How is it that we are still engaging and coexisting with the Russians?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, I would say diplomacy around the world requires us to engage with countries, even where we have strong disagreements, strong opposition, strong condemnation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been very outspoken and taken actions against China&#8217;s human rights abuses, but we have worked with them in other capacities.&nbsp;<br><br>We are working &#8212; Russia is a part of the P5+1, as we&#8217;re working and making progress on an Iran nuclear deal.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question that achievement of that would make the world safer.&nbsp;<br><br>So it is our responsibility.&nbsp; And &#8212; and diplomacy means engaging even with countries where you have strong disagreement and strong opposition.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just so that we can understand, then, the approach: That means that you guys will sit here and sanction Vladimir Putin and then send diplomats to go sit on the same side of the table with the Russians to hash out the Iran deal.&nbsp; Is that what&#8217;s happening?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s right, Peter, but I don&#8217;t know why you sound so skeptical.&nbsp; What our job here in the United States and from any government is to take steps that are in the interest of the American people and the United States of America.&nbsp; And part of that is &#8212; would certainly be reducing Iran&#8217;s capacity and ability to have a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s no question about that.&nbsp; Russia is a part of the P5+1.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a report in The New York Times that you guys kept asking China to help you stop Russia from invading Ukraine and they didn&#8217;t.&nbsp; So, what have you guys done throughout this slow-moving Russia crisis that has worked?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In what capacity?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, the President talked to Putin.&nbsp; He talked to the G7.&nbsp; He threatened sanctions.&nbsp; He put sanctions in place.&nbsp; Now he says the sanctions are going to take 30 days or about a month.&nbsp; Do you guys think that people in Ukraine have about a month?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, let me just take a step back and explain to everyone how diplomacy works and how our approach from the United States has worked.&nbsp;<br><br>What the President has done is he has built a global coalition to stand up in the face of President Putin and President Putin&#8217;s aggression and invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; What he has done is he has rallied the world, our European partners &#8212; even at cost to them, in some capacities &#8212; to put in place significant sanctions, historic sanctions that would have a enormous impact on the Russian financial sector.&nbsp;<br><br>It is President Putin&#8217;s choice to go to war and invade Ukraine.&nbsp; That is what he has done.&nbsp; It is our choice and our responsibility and the role of the President and the United States to rally opposition and make sure they feel significant pain from that choice.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what we have done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I understand that you&#8217;re saying that these sanctions will have an impact on Russia, but what good does that do these people in Ukraine who are seeing the news and these U.S. intel assessments that Kyiv is going to fall any day?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, first of all, we are the largest provider of humanitarian assistance, of security assistance in the world to the Ukrainian &#8212; to the Ukrainian government, which still stands and support &#8212; and the biggest supporter of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; And we will continue to be.&nbsp; And we are leading this global effort to stand up against the aggression of President Putin.&nbsp;<br><br>And so we are doing &#8212; the President is doing nearly everything in his power to lead the world and stand up against the actions of President Putin.<br><br>What he will not do is send U.S. troops to fight in Ukraine, because he is not going to put the American public, the American people, or the United States in a position of fighting a war with Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I can ask you about &#8212; we&#8217;ve been watching a lot of pictures play out from overseas.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen anti-war protesters rounded up and arrested in Moscow and elsewhere throughout Russia.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen awful pictures coming from throughout Ukraine, including one today that was dramatic of a Russian tank literally rolling over a Ukrainian civilian vehicle.&nbsp; Can you just give us a sense &#8212; is the President watching this happen?&nbsp;&nbsp;His reaction to this?&nbsp; His message to those anti-war protesters?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I mean, it&#8217;s &#8212; there are &#8212; it&#8217;s horrific to watch.&nbsp; It&#8217;s heart wrenching to watch.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve all seen the images &#8212; the President, the Vice President, members of our national security team.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it almost doesn&#8217;t matter how much you&#8217;ve been through or how many conflicts you&#8217;ve watched over time &#8212; and he has unfortunately watched many in a variety of national security roles &#8212; to feel heartbroken by what you&#8217;re seeing in &#8212; happen in Ukraine, in a sovereign country that is &#8212; is having its right to exist threatened by Russia &#8212; the aggressor in this case.<br><br>You know, I would say our message to the Ukrainian people continues to be that we stand with you; we support you; we are going to do everything &#8212; humanitarian assistance, economic assistance, continue to provide security assistance and rally the world to condemn the actions of President Putin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to the anti-war protesters in Russia?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think we would say that we are &#8212; we are amazed by your courage &#8212; your remarkable courage in standing up against what President Putin is doing.&nbsp; It is not easy to protest in many scenarios, but it&#8217;s certainly not easy to protest against the actions of an autocratic leader.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what these protesters are doing.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s a large room; I&#8217;ll ask only one last question, which is &#8212; as a relates to the Supreme Court &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; following up on the questions here: The President wanted it to be a bipartisan process.&nbsp; He’s met with many Republicans &#8212; Chuck Grassley, the top Republican on Senate Judiciary Committee; three Republicans helped confirm Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson in the spring of last year.&nbsp; One of them, Lindsey Graham, today said, among other things, that this selection “means the radical left has won President Biden over yet again.”&nbsp; The White House&#8217;s response?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what&#8217;s most important for everybody to know and understand is more about Judge Jackson&#8217;s record.&nbsp;<br><br>And what was very compelling to &#8212; and to go back to Weijia’s question &#8212; sorry, I didn&#8217;t answer this part &#8212; what was compelling to the President &#8212; I talked to him about &#8212; with him about this this morning, and you heard him lay this out in great detail in his remarks: You know, Judge Jackson is someone who very much is in the mold of Justice Breyer, having even clerked for him.&nbsp; She talked about that during his remarks.&nbsp; When she was confirmed as a district judge in 2013, Judge Breyer praised her for being a wise decision and swore her in, and even parts of their biography overlap &#8212; time on the Sentencing Commission, time as a federal judge.<br><br>But it&#8217;s also how she has approached her role as a judge that was very compelling to the President.&nbsp; She&#8217;s issued opinions without regard to partisan considerations.&nbsp; She&#8217;s ruled in favor of Republicans and Democrats.&nbsp; She&#8217;s ruled for and against the government, regardless of whether the government is led by a Democratic president or a Republican president.&nbsp; Litigants, lawyers, and judges across the ideological spectrum appreciate her ability to be an impartial adjudicator.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what you want as a judge.&nbsp; She&#8217;s even clerked for three different federal judges who were appointed by presidents of different political parties.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I would just note all of that to suggest that, you know, anyone who is already ruling her out, without even meeting with her, engaging with her, and reviewing her extensive record as a fair and just judge, you know, there may be other reasons for that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Does the U.S. &#8212; do you have any update on the hostages that were reported to be taken at Chernobyl (inaudible) yesterday &#8211;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In Chernobyl?&nbsp; I unfortunately don&#8217;t have an update on that from here at this point.&nbsp; I can check for you after the briefing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the U.S. have any plans to speed up the refugee processing for Ukrainians that do want to come to the U.S., as they did with Afghans that wanted to come to the U.S.?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s a slightly different circumstance, I will say, because our assessment is that the majority of refugees will want to go to neighboring countries in Europe, many of which have already conveyed publicly that they will accept any refugee who needs a home, whether it&#8217;s Poland or Germany, and there are probably others who have made those comments.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we are really working in close lockstep with our European counterparts about what the needs are and how to help, from our end, meet those needs.&nbsp; We &#8212; that certainly means an openness to accepting refugees from Ukraine but also making sure that all of these neighboring countries who are willing to welcome these refugees, you know, have our support in that effort.</p>



<p>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I know the White House has said it won&#8217;t be sending &#8212; the U.S. won&#8217;t be sending troops into Ukraine to rescue Americans who are still there, so what is the U.S. doing about Americans who are still left in Ukraine as the situation gets more dire?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; I will first start by saying that we have been warning for months now about the dire circumstances developing in Ukraine and conveying very directly to American citizens they should leave.&nbsp; We have also been in touch, from the State Department, with every American we can reach.&nbsp; I would point you to them for more specifics on that.&nbsp; And we continue to have the capacity to, you know, help them in a range of ways, even as we don&#8217;t have a diplomatic presence in Ukraine in th- &#8212; I mean, we don&#8217;t have people in the country right now, obviously, but they are in neighboring countries.<br><br>I would really point you to the State Department for any more specifics.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the President is obviously now going to be in Delaware this weekend.&nbsp; Can you share what he will be doing there?&nbsp; Will he be traveling with members of his national security team?&nbsp; Will he be receiving regular updates on Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; He will have a meeting with members of his national security team tomorrow in Delaware.&nbsp; I will note that, while every president can work from anywhere they are, because that is how presidencies are equipped, he is traveling to Delaware for the memorial service of a family member.&nbsp; And he will be &#8212; that is why he&#8217;s traveling there this weekend.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on that question: Does the President have special secure facilities in Wilmington?&nbsp; We know that, obviously, at Camp David that is something available.&nbsp; Given the national security crisis, is that something that is also available?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has the capacity to make a secure call from anywhere he is, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, on the Supreme Court: How important is it to the President that the &#8212; Judge Jackson receives bipartisan support if she is confirmed?&nbsp; And how much political capital and time and energy is he personally going to put into getting Republican support for her nomination?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think, Tyler, let me flip this around a little bit for you and just say the President&#8217;s view is that when you look at somebody like Judge Jackson, who has &#8212; is extraordinarily qualified, has impeccable credentials; she has been lauded by former Speaker of the House, Paul Ryan, who said on her behalf last &#8212; when she was put forward last year, “I know she&#8217;s clearly qualified.  But it bears repeating just how qualified she is… Our politics may differ, but my praise for Ketanji intellect, for her character, for her <s>intellect</s> [integrity] is unequivocal.” <br><br>That she is somebody who has &#8212; and I would also note, that former D.C. District Judge Thomas Griffith, appointed by President George W. Bush, publicly supported her D.C. Court nomination.  And she received a bipartisan letter of support from individuals who co-clerked along Judge Jackson.<br><br>So I think the bar here should not be what is the President going to do &#8212; of course, he&#8217;s going to engage with Democrats and Republicans; you&#8217;ve seen him operate in that way to date &#8212; it is what are Republicans going to do, in terms of considering an eminently qualified judge that the President has nominated, who, by many standards, has exhibited &#8212; has shown herself to issue opinions without regard to partisan considerations and ruled in a way that certainly anyone, regardless of their political affiliation, would be proud to see.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one more quick one on the State of the Union.&nbsp; How much is that speech being changed by the Russia-Ukraine crisis?&nbsp; Can you just give us a little bit of a preview about what we may hear from the President on Tuesday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I certainly understand the question, but I can&#8217;t give you a preview of a speech four days from now quite yet about &#8212; and how it will address a developing conflict.</p>



<p>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, President Biden stated from the outset and you&#8217;ve reiterated today that he won’t send U.S. troops to Ukraine to fight Russians.&nbsp; Given the high stakes, you know, President Biden yesterday said Russia has aspirations beyond Ukraine.&nbsp; Why isn’t this a fight worth sending U.S. troops for?&nbsp; Why, in your as- &#8212; in &#8212; why has the President assessed that shouldn&#8217;t be an option?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first, it&#8217;s important to note that we have certainly made clear, not just by words but by actions, that we are going to continue to support and even plus up our support for NATO defense operations.&nbsp; And there was an announcement yesterday of an increase of additional 7,000 troops.&nbsp; And obviously, there was a significant announcement made today by NATO.&nbsp; We are firm &#8212; we will firmly stand behind our Article 5 obligations.&nbsp;<br><br>But I would say, as it relates to sending U.S. troops into Ukraine, the President &#8212; the role of the President of the United States &#8212; any president &#8212; is to make an assessment about what is in the interests of the United States, our national security interests, the American people, and certainly weigh very heavily how we&#8217;re leading the global community.&nbsp; But it is not in our interest to be in a war with Russia.&nbsp; And so, no, we are not sending U.S. troops to Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But by stating up front that this is not an option, didn’t President Biden take away what could have been a threat to deter Putin from invading and to further push into Ukraine?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the President believes he has a responsibility to be very direct with the American people about what his intentions are and what his intentions are not, and that is his first priority as President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, what was the White House&#8217;s reaction to President Zelenskyy, today, in a video address, saying that Ukraine has, quote, “been left alone to defend itself against Russia”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, as you know, the President spoke with President Zelenskyy and made clear to him during that conversation that he &#8212; and he commended his brave leadership, his brave actions, the brave actions of the Ukrainian people who are fighting to defend their country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He also conveyed our ongoing economic, humanitarian, and security support that we will continue to provide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that is hardly standing on the sidelines.&nbsp; We are providing &#8212; again, the largest provider of security, economic, humanitarian assistance of any country in the world.&nbsp; And we will continue to support President Zelenskyy and the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the White House doesn’t think he&#8217;s been left alone?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;ll leave it at that.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks a lot, Jen.&nbsp; Does the administration have any plans to offer TPS to Ukrainians who are in the United States or who en- &#8212; who might end up coming to the United States?&nbsp; Does it support the idea?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there &#8212; it&#8217;s a process that would be overseen by the interagency through &#8212; go through an interagency process, led by the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; I know there are many advocates for that, but I don&#8217;t have an update on the process or if it will happen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What plans does the administra- &#8212; and on &#8212; in regard to refugees &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what plans does the administration have to take in &#8212; for the United States to take in some refugees in the United States?&nbsp; Have there been any planning discussions, perhaps with refugee groups, to prepare this?&nbsp; Do you &#8212; do you have an anticipated number of how many refugees may come to the U.S.?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an updated &#8212; an anticipated number to project.&nbsp; What I will convey to you is that we are always in constant contact with the refugee organizations, who do incredible work around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I would also reiterate that what we&#8217;ve seen happen over the last couple of days is countries like Poland, Germany, and others in Europe make clear that they are going &#8212; they are opening their arms to welcome refugees from Ukraine.&nbsp; Those are neighboring countries.&nbsp; So we do anticipate the vast majority will want to go to countries in Europe.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you do anticipate that some would come to the United States?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are open to that, yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And if I could ask one more.&nbsp; Senator Coons floated the idea of 10 billion &#8212; a $10 billion emergency supplemental package.&nbsp; Just, does the administration support that proposal?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are having ongoing conversations with Congress about additional assistance to Ukraine. &nbsp;Our OMB leadership is having those conversations.&nbsp; And so, I will leave it to them to put out any updated specific number from our end, but they&#8217;re &#8212; those are underway.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why doesn’t President Biden want to talk to Vladimir Putin right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because he&#8217;s invading a sovereign country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he &#8212; isn&#8217;t he going to be potentially invading that for years on end?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that a moment where a leader is beginning and in the middle of invading a sovereign country is not the moment where diplomacy feels appropriate.&nbsp; It does not mean we have ruled out diplomacy forever.&nbsp; Obviously, the President remains open to engaging on &#8212; at a leader-to-leader level, but this is not the moment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And why are you guys waiting to apply maximum pressure on Russia with &#8212; you know, sanctions on everything?&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t seem &#8212; you know, are you guys waiting for Kyiv to fall?&nbsp; Or (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sanctions on everything?&nbsp; How do you mean?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In &#8212; like sanctions on all Russian &#8212; you know, all Russian transactions and on oil and gas.&nbsp; Sort of &#8212; like do you think that Americans are not willing to take a hit at the gas pump?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well &#8212; well, I would say there&#8217;s a couple of principles through which the President has approached sanctions.&nbsp; One is maximizing the impact on Russian leadership and on the Russ- &#8212; Russian financial system so that there will be a particular squeeze.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve obviously taken steps already that have gone far and above what have ever been done &#8212; what has ever been done in the past.&nbsp; If you look at just 10 &#8212; the 10 financial institutions that we sanctioned, they hold a &#8212; you know, a huge percentage of &#8212; they are about 80 percent of the Russian banking sector.&nbsp; That is a significant step that was announced yesterday.</p>



<p>The export controls step that was announced yesterday means that they will be &#8212; they won&#8217;t have the ability to get access to the technology that &#8212; and semiconductors and AI &#8212; that President Putin desperately wants to continue to innovate his economy moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also &#8212; of course, Europeans are also looking at &#8212; European countries are also looking at some of their reliance on Russia, whether it&#8217;s for energy or other purposes, and they&#8217;re making their own decisions about diversifying.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I noted a little bit earlier, the Ruble remains about 10 percent weaker year to date and the worst-performing emerging market currency in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what should be clear here is that there are already huge impacts.&nbsp; There is already an enormous squeeze on the Russian financial system and economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we are also &#8212; what the President is also focused on as a principle is not &#8212; is taking steps and making sure we are minimizing the impact on the American people, on the global economic system.&nbsp; And we, of course, weigh that, as we have a responsibility to do.&nbsp; And we want to, first and foremost &#8212; I should have said this first &#8212; take these steps, united with our partners and Allies in Europe.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the administration have any message to American companies that do business in Russia with entities that are not necessarily on the sanction list?&nbsp; Would you like to see U.S. citizens not buy Russian products?&nbsp; Would you like to see U.S.-based CEOs not look for business in Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re not trying to hurt the people of Russia or the Russian people.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to que- &#8212; squeeze the financial system and sector to make sure there are significant consequences for the actions of the president.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So understanding there&#8217;s no plan for Presidents Biden and Putin to speak, is there any line of communication between the White House and the Kremlin right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have additional details on that at this point in time.&nbsp; Obviously, our national security team has a range of means of communicating with the Russians.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Then should we take what you said earlier in your answer to mean that the President won’t speak with Putin unless Putin de-escalates or withdraws?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, it&#8217;s not the appropriate moment right now.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t give you &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to give you a “forever and ever” because that&#8217;s not how he feels. But they’re actively invading Ukraine.&nbsp; They are moving on the capital.&nbsp; They are looking to overturn leadership.&nbsp; This is not the moment for President Biden to have a diplomatic conversation with President Putin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on refugees.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been noted that the EU response to Ukrainian refugees has been quite different to the response to refugees from other nations, and I wonder what the White House view is on that, given that some countries like Poland and Hungary were actively trying to keep out many refugees largely from the Middle East.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think I have any further comment on that from here about the decisions of other countries and where they accept refugees from.&nbsp; What I can speak to is what our approach is here in the United States.&nbsp; And obviously, we have welcomed with open arms tens of thousands of Afghan refugees.&nbsp; And certainly, while it may be &#8212; to go to the earlier question &#8212; that the majority of refugees from Ukraine go to Europe, we are certainly open to accepting refugees from Ukraine as well.&nbsp; That is our policy and our approach and certainly what we will continue to implement.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just following up on the question and your discussion of sanctioning oil and gas and &#8212; and understanding that the President in any decisions he makes around sanctions or any other actions to take against Russia is thinking about the American people, is there a point at which he would consider doing that?&nbsp; That &#8212; that &#8212; is that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Like the energy sector?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Ener- &#8212; is the energy sector at some level on the table as Putin gets even more aggressive?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, you know, there are also some other countries that are &#8212; have worked for carveouts &#8212; for instance, Italy and luxury goods.&nbsp; What is the U.S. view of those kinds of exceptions being made for things that are maybe a lot less essential, as much as we might like them, than oil and gas?&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Speaking for yourself.&nbsp; So I would say, on the energy sector, no option is off the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, to go back to the princi- &#8212; some of the principles here, our sanctions are designed to harm Russia&#8217;s economy, not our economy, and that&#8217;s a key balance that we&#8217;re clearly trying to strike.&nbsp; And I think when Daleep &#8212; as Daleep has been in here a few times over the last week, he has conveyed we do risk assessments &#8212; right? &#8212; and impact assessments, and that&#8217;s a part of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The other factor here on the energy sector is that starting out with energy or &#8212; could actually benefit President Putin and pad his pockets because, given high oil and gas prices, cutting off Russian oil and gas could drive prices up to Putin&#8217;s benefit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that&#8217;s obviously a factor as well, but it&#8217;s not off the table.&nbsp; But we look at a range of issues.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of how &#8212; what other countries have sought as far as carveouts of areas that they&#8217;re not sanctioning, does the administration have a view of that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think &#8212; I think &#8212; look, our focus right now is that we are working in close coordination and in lockstep with our European counterparts.&nbsp; It does not mean everything is identical; it is not identical.&nbsp; But what you have seen across the board is very strong, impactful sanctions that the shared hope is that they will have significant economic and financial consequences.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you &#8212; does the administration have an estimate of how many Russian deaths or casualties there have been in Ukraine at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have that assessment from here.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t expect we would have that assessment from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So the Ukrainians have this number &#8212; 3,800 &#8212; that they&#8217;ve been putting out &#8212; or 2,800 that they&#8217;ve been putting out today.&nbsp; Do you have any sense of the accuracy or the order of magnitude or (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I don&#8217;t have any assessment from here and I don&#8217;t anticipate we would.&nbsp; I know that the Department of Defense is providing &#8212; is doing regular or daily, nearly, briefings on kind of the movements and what they&#8217;re seeing on the ground, but I don&#8217;t believe even they were able to make an assessment of casualties earlier today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more quick question on the Supreme Court process.&nbsp; You mentioned three candidates that he interviewed in person.&nbsp; Just want to make sure: The &#8212; the only three candidates he interviewed in person?&nbsp; Did he interview any candidates virtually?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Those are the candidates he interviewed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay, thank you.&nbsp; And &#8212; yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Did you have another one?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, no, no.&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, Jen.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Jen, does the White House stand by the support you guys gave to Brazil to become a global partner in NATO after President Bolsonaro met last week with President Putin.&nbsp; And still, President Bolsonaro didn&#8217;t condemn the invasion.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, as I said in relation to a question a little bit earlier, I mean, our view and our &#8212; our push for every country in the world is to stand up, in this moment, and decide what &#8212; where you stand, where you want to be in history as the history books look back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that doesn&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything in terms of our change of &#8212; our view of our overarching relationship.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, can I just follow up on that question in terms of building a global coalition against &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Russia, right?&nbsp; I mean, India, for example &#8212; a Quad member &#8212; it&#8217;s the only Quad member that&#8217;s not implementing export controls for example.&nbsp; I think the President yesterday mentioned that that issue still hasn&#8217;t been resolved.&nbsp; Is he planning to call &#8212; call Prime Minister Modi?&nbsp; I think Prime Minister Modi called President Putin yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just, can you speak more broadly, in terms of bringing all these other partners that maybe, you know, are not Europe, but, you know, the Quad, as well as perhaps ASEAN members who are pretty ambivalent and cautious about condemning the Russian invasion?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say some were, but I wouldn&#8217;t say the majority were.&nbsp; And we continue to engage with the Indians, with other ASEAN partners on both what we&#8217;re seeing on the ground, our continued condemnation of the actions of President Putin in Ukraine.&nbsp; And we will continue to push others to follow suit.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to follow up, Delta announced today that they&#8217;re suspending codesharing with Aeroflot.&nbsp; Did the White House have anything to do with this decision?&nbsp; And are you urging other American companies to &#8212; urge them to do the same?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a decision by a private sector company.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any more comments on it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on the State of the Union, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you preview a little bit on the foreign policy portion of the President&#8217;s State of the Union?&nbsp; I mean, obviously, with the crisis in Ukraine, I know that you &#8212; you&#8217;re not going to be able to preview that.&nbsp; But just in general &#8212; now with Ukraine, before that with the Afghanistan withdrawal &#8212; what can the President say to show that his foreign policy doctrine is succeeding?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, without previewing the State of the Union, which we&#8217;ll do later this evening &#8212; or later this weekend &#8212; sorry, it&#8217;s kind of all one day that&#8217;s running together &#8212; we will do later this weekend, I expect.&nbsp; So, look at &#8212; look ahead to that or we&#8217;ll have more to say later this weekend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, it&#8217;s also &#8212; as it relates to Russia-Ukraine: You know, we are unfortunately still in the middle of this conflict.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; We&#8217;re in the middle of an active invasion.&nbsp; So I just can&#8217;t give you a preview of what that will look like in the State of the Union.</p>



<p>As it relates to how the President views his approach to foreign policy: You know, the President has ran &#8212; ran for President wanting to return America&#8217;s seat at the world, wanting to return to a time where other leaders around the world could trust the word and the commitments of the United States.&nbsp; And what you have seen, over the last few months, is the President deliver on exactly that.&nbsp; He has been leading the effort in the world to stand up to Russia, stand up to the efforts, the aggression, the invasion of a sovereign country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While I&#8217;m not going to get into the specifics of what is going to be in the State of the Union, that&#8217;s exactly what he said he would do when he was running.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, so the President said he&#8217;s doing everything he can to bring down energy prices &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; gas prices here in the U.S.&nbsp; Is on the table then &#8212; or is he considering reversing some of the policies and regulations that he put into place that constricts the long-term supply of it to let Europe be more reliant on the U.S. for oil and natural gas?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean like LNG exports or something like that?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; LNG &#8212; LNG exports, but also oil prices &#8212; allowing &#8212; you know, opening up drilling again, reversing the ban on leases on federal lands.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what&#8217;s important to note here &#8212; and I talked about this a little bit yesterday &#8212; is that there are a range of available oil leasing sites that oil companies are not utilizing, so you should ask them about that.</p>



<p>You know the President&#8217;s view on reducing our dependence on foreign oil.&nbsp; And actually, his view is that this makes that case even stronger and diversifying the range of means of energy production everywhere around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As it relates to LNG exports, I don&#8217;t have anything new on that.</p>



<p>Our focus right now is on working with &#8212; or engaging with a range of countries &#8212; I mentioned Japan yesterday &#8212; and having conversations with others who may have the availability of supply &#8212; natural gas supply that was coming from the United States to provide to Europe in this time where they need it.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re seeing some encouraging developments on that front.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more thing on OPEC.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; OPEC is making moves now to get ready to include Iranian oil in &#8212; if the U.S. is successful with the Iran nuclear deal.&nbsp; Would the President then welcome Iranian oil coming into the U.S. to lower gas prices?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we&#8217;re not quite at the point of a final deal on the nuclear deal.&nbsp; So, we will talk about that if we get to that point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You talked a couple times about the U.S. engaging in diplomacy with Russia going forward.&nbsp; When he announced the sanctions today against Putin and Lavrov, the British Prime Minister told NATO leaders that there could be &#8220;no normalization&#8221; with Russia after the attack on Ukraine.&nbsp; Does this administration share that view?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, in this moment, the &#8212; I&#8217;ve conveyed pretty clearly the President has no intentions at this moment to engage with President Putin.&nbsp; He was just sanctioned.&nbsp; We just made a decision in coordination &#8212; in close lockstep with the Europeans to sanction him; a head of state &#8212; that is a very rare step to take.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, obviously, we&#8217;ve issued significant sanctions that cover 80 percent of the financial sector.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, no, we&#8217;re not in a business-as-usual moment at this point in time.&nbsp; And, obviously, de-escalation would help return us to a state where that could proceed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the White House, right now, believe that President Zelenskyy is safe in Kyiv?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are in close touch with him.&nbsp; While I&#8217;m not going to give you updates on his security state, we &#8212; certainly, the President just spoke with him earlier today, and he continues to be the President of Ukraine.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; In regards to the new CDC guidance on the pandemic, which, of course, will then be the, you know, the new Biden administration guidance: What is the &#8212; what will the message be to Americans in regards to these new metrics and this &#8212; the new guidance as to where we are in the pandemic?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, if you look at the specific of them, we&#8217;re &#8212; we are moving &#8212; the President &#8212; we have talked a little bit about how we want to move to a time and a place where we are &#8212; you know, have the tools needed so that COVID and the pandemic do not disrupt our daily lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, they&#8217;ll have &#8212; there&#8217;s more &#8212; the President has been talking to his COVID team about exactly that.&nbsp; This is a part of that process, and we&#8217;re moving forward in that process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a result of these &#8212; this announcement today and these updated recommendations, today more than half the country &#8212; 70 percent of Americans &#8212; live in areas where the CDC no longer recommends universal masking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, if people want to wear a mask, because they&#8217;re immunocompromised, because they have concerns about their safeties and their &#8212; safety in their communities, they should have the ability to do that.&nbsp; But that is certainly a step forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know that &#8212; this is part of that process.&nbsp; And I expect we&#8217;ll have more to say soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there concern that this might imply or have folks think that then, therefore, the pandemic is over and can eschew all caution?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then secondly or kind of added on to that, are you confident that there will be an ability to reverse course if things get bad again?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, if nobody is saying it&#8217;s &#8212; &#8220;it means it&#8217;s over,&#8221; including anybody who has a big platform, for example, then that &#8212; we&#8217;re not concerned about that.&nbsp; That is not what we&#8217;re conveying from here, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we are conveying from here and what the CDC is conveying is that America is in a stronger place today as a nation.&nbsp; We have more tools ever &#8212; than ever before to protect ourselves from COVID-19: vaccination, boosters, treatments, testing, high-quality masks, improved ventilation.&nbsp; Over 200 million people are vaccinated.&nbsp; Nearly 100 million Americans have been boosted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the CDC is providing public health guidance that has a couple of different clear levels so that people can understand what their recommendation is as it relates to wearing a mask.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what this is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are still people dying every day of COVID.&nbsp; There are still immunocompromised populations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we are trying to work towards is a period of time where we are &#8212; where COVID is not disrupting our daily lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just wanted to know &#8212; you said that the President has done everything in his power.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen the sanctions, shoring up the NATO eastern flank, all of that.&nbsp; But no troops &#8212; you repeated that.&nbsp; Doesn&#8217;t that also send a message to Vladimir Putin &#8212; clearly, it hasn&#8217;t stopped him &#8212; that other nations in the region that are not NATO members are also free game for him since he&#8217;s not going to have that stop?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think the crippling sanctions that the President has issued &#8212; or approved and we announced yesterday &#8212; that cover 80 percent of the financial sector, that are having an impact already on the financial sector there or steps that the President has taken, including export &#8212; banning export controls; or steps he&#8217;s taken to sanction oligarchs and to rally the world to take not only significant financial steps, but also to treat President Putin as a pariah send a message that there&#8217;s a free walk for anything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, President Putin is isolating himself further.&nbsp; He&#8217;s &#8212; if his objective here is to &#8212; as his stated objective is to divide NATO, if his stated objective is to divide the West, it&#8217;s having the opposite effect.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t think that would be our assessment.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May I just &#8212; just a quick question on cyberattacks.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The NATO Secretary General, again, said that he would view a cyberattack on a NATO member &#8212; this time talking about NATO members &#8212; as something that would be under Article 5.&nbsp; Is that the view of the United States also, that a cyberattack on NATO &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I answered this yesterday, and I said that it would be up to NATO members to determine what that looks like and what any response would look like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President been in touch with &#8212; before or after the decision today &#8212; with Congressman Clyburn?&nbsp; He, of course, was a big boost &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, he called him this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve said &#8212; you&#8217;ve said that the U.S. &#8212; we don&#8217;t go to war against Russia (inaudible) Russia is heavily armed.&nbsp; The U.S. is heavily armed.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m just wondering if you&#8217;re not being pragmatic here with Russia.&nbsp; Are we not being pragmatic to recognize that it may not be in the interest of the U.S. for Ukraine to be a member of NATO, which is the key request from Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m understanding your question.&nbsp; Is it &#8212; are you asking me if &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it &#8212; is it in the interest of the U.S. for Ukraine to be a member of NATO?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is up to every country to determine what alliances they want to join or not join.&nbsp; And that is not a pressure point we issue from the United States.&nbsp; And we &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you &#8212; can you &#8212; can you confirm &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; think it&#8217;s important for that to remain open.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you confirm that you are looking for a job at CNN or MSNBC?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have more than enough on my plate here.&nbsp; So, you can&#8217;t get rid of quite yet.&nbsp; Sorry, Peter, for you on that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I will see you all on Monday.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, do you have more as &#8212; when you might brief us on the State of the Union?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we might have more on Sunday is my expectation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>4:28 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/25/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-and-section-614a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 04:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the following authorities, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section 614(a)(3) and section 652 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), in order to provide immediate military assistance to Ukraine:</p>



<p>(1) &nbsp;the authority under section 614(a)(1) of the FAA to determine whether it is important to the security interests of the United States to furnish up to $250 million in assistance without regard to any provision of law within the purview of section 614(a)(1) of the FAA; and</p>



<p>(2) &nbsp;the authority under section 506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $350 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on his Nomination of Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson to Serve as Associate Justice of the U.S. Supreme&#160;Court</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/25/remarks-by-president-biden-on-his-nomination-of-judge-ketanji-brown-jackson-to-serve-as-associate-justice-of-the-u-s-supreme-court/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cross Hall 2:02 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Today, as we watch freedom and liberty under attack abroad, I’m here to fulfill my responsibilities under the Constitution to preserve freedom and liberty here in the United States of America.  And it’s my honor to introduce to the country a daughter of former public school teachers, a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cross Hall</p>



<p>2:02 P.M. EST<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Today, as we watch freedom and liberty under attack abroad, I’m here to fulfill my responsibilities under the Constitution to preserve freedom and liberty here in the United States of America. <br> <br>And it’s my honor to introduce to the country a daughter of former public school teachers, a proven consensus builder, an accomplished lawyer, a distinguished jurist &#8212; one of the nation’s most &#8212; on one of the nation’s most prestigious courts.  My nominee for the United States Supreme Court is Judge Ketanji Jackson.<br> <br>You know, four weeks ago, when a member of the Court &#8212; a friend of mine; we used to work together in the Senate &#8212; Justice Stephen Breyer, announced his retirement, I said then choosing someone to serve on the United States Supreme Court is one of the most serious constitutional responsibilities a President has.  And I mean it. <br> <br>I promised the process would be rigorous, that I would select a nominee worthy of Justice Breyer’s legacy of excellence and decency &#8212; someone extremely qualified, with a brilliant legal mind, with the utmost character and integrity, which are equally as important.<br> <br>And that I would bring this decision &#8212; to this decision my perspective as a lawyer; a former Constitutional law professor; chairman of the Judiciary Committee for many, many years; and &#8212; I’m almost reluctant to say it &#8212; someone who has presided over more Supreme Court nominations than almost anyone living today, which makes me 28 years old &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; I started doing it when I was 32 &#8212; and who has devoted much of my career to thinking about the Constitution and the role of the Supreme Court.<br> <br>With that perspective, I carefully studierd [sic] the re- &#8212; studied the records of candidates.  I’ve invited senators of both parties to offer their ideas and points of view, and I’ve met with a number of them. <br> <br>As a result, because I truly respect not only the consent &#8212; I know they give consent, but it says &#8212; the Constitution says ”advice and consent,” and I sought the advice of Democrats and Republicans. <br> <br>I’ve consulted with leading legal scholars and lawyers.<br> <br>And I’ve been fortunate to have the advice of the &#8212; Vice President Harris &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; an exceptional lawyer, a former Attorney General of California, and a former member of the Senate Judiciary Committee.<br> <br>And during this process, I looked for someone who, like Justice Breyer, has a pragmatic understanding that the law must work for the American people.  Someone who has the historical perspective to understand that the Constitution is a resilient charter of liberty.  Someone with the wisdom to appreciate that the Constitution protects certain inalienable rights &#8212; rights that fall within the most fundamental personal freedoms that our society recognizes.<br> <br>And then, someone with extraordinary character, who will bring to the Supreme Court an independent mind, uncompromising integrity, and with a strong moral compass and the courage to stand up for what she thinks is right.<br> <br>For too long, our government, our courts haven’t looked like America.  And I believe it’s time that we have a Court that reflects the full talents and greatness of our nation with a nominee of extraordinary qualifications and that we inspire all young people to believe that they can one day serve their country at the highest level.<br> <br>I’ve admired these traits of pragmatism, historical perspective, wisdom, character in the jurists nominated by Republican presidents as well as Democratic presidents. <br> <br>And today, I’m pleased to introduce to the American people a candidate who continues in this great tradition.<br> <br>Judge Jackson grew up in Miami, Florida.  And by the way, the mayor of Miami &#8212; a Republican &#8212; endorsed you; I thought that was interesting.  Her parents grew up with segregation but never gave up hope that their children would enjoy the true promise of America.<br> <br>Her parents graduated from Historic Brac- &#8212; Black Colleges and become public school teachers &#8212; her mom, a principal; her Dad, a teacher, who later went back to school and became a lawyer representing that very school district &#8212; that school board.<br> <br>Judge Jackson describes finding her love for the law from an apartment complex at the University of Miami where her dad was attending law school.  She’d draw in her coloring book at the dining room table, next to her dad’s law books.<br> <br>She grew up to be a star student &#8212; elected mayor of her junior high school and president of her high school class, where she was a standout &#8212; she was a standout on the speech and debate team.<br> <br>And it was after a debate tournament that took place at Harvard when she was in high school that she believed she could one day be a student there.  There were those who told her she shouldn’t set her sights too high, but she refused to accept limits others set for her. <br> <br>She did go on to Harvard undergraduate school, where she graduated magna cum laude.  She went into &#8212; to attend Harvard Law School, where she was a top student and editor of the prestigious Law Review.<br> <br>Then she applied for a highly competitive and coveted clerkship on the United States Supreme Court, and she was selected.<br> <br>The justice who thought that she was worthy of this high honor was a young lawyer.  It was none other than Justice Stephen Breyer, who’s seat I am nominating her to fill. <br> <br>Not only did she learn about being a judge from Justice Breyer himself, she saw the great rigor through which Justice Breyer approached his work.  She learned from his willingness to work with colleagues with different viewpoints &#8212; critical qualities for &#8212; in my view, for any Supreme Court Justice.<br> <br>Now, years later, she steps up to fill Justice Breyer’s place on the Court with a uniquely accomplished and wide-ranging background.<br> <br>She has served both in public service as a federal public defender &#8212; a federal public defender and in private law practice as an accomplished lawyer in pr- &#8212; with a prestigious law firm.<br> <br>If confirmed, she will join Justice Sotomayor as the only other member of the United States Supreme Court who has experience as a trial court judge –- a critical qualification, in my view.<br> <br>And once again following in the footsteps of her mentor, Justice Breyer, she would become the only member of the Court who previously served as a member of the United States Sentencing Commission.<br> <br>And she brings an additional perspective to the Court as well.  She comes from a family of law enforcement, with her brother and uncles having served as police officers.<br> <br>That’s one reason, I expect, why the Fraternal Order of Police &#8212; the national organization &#8212; today said, and I quote, “There is little doubt [that] she has the temperament, the intellect, and the legal experience, and family background to have earned this appointment.”  And they went on to say they are confident she will, quote, “approach her future cases with an open mind and treat issues related to law enforcement fairly and justly.”<br> <br>Incredibly, Judge Jackson has already been confirmed by the United States Senate three times.<br> <br>First, to serve on the U.S. Sentencing Commission &#8212; a bipartisan, independent commission we help &#8212; I helped design to reduce the unwarranted disparities in sentencing and promote transparency and fairness in the criminal justice system. <br> <br>On the commission, Judge Jackson was known for working with Democrats and Republicans to find common ground on critical issues.<br> <br>Second, she was concerned by &#8212; confirmed by the United States Senate with bipartisan support on the federal district court to administer justice with the special rigors and fairness that come with presiding over trials. <br> <br>And third, she was confirmed with a bipartisan Senate vote to serve on U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia,  considered the second most powerful court behind the Supreme Court itself and the court she once argued cases before as a distinguished advocate. <br> <br>And when Judge Jackson was nominated to this Circuit Court, one of its distinguished retired members, Judge Thomas Griffith, a former general counsel of Brigham Young University and a George Bush appointee to that court said he backed her “enthusiastically,” hailing her &#8212; hailing her “exemplary legal career in both public and private practice” and, he went on to say, her “careful approach” as a trial court judge.<br> <br>Judge Jackson’s service on the District Circuit Court of &#8212; for the D.C. Circuit Court of Appeals is another superb qualification for service on the Supreme Court.<br> <br>Three of her &#8212; of the current Supreme Court Justices also served with the D.C. Circuit judges where Judge Jackson now serves.<br> <br>Her opinions are always carefully reasoned, tethered to precedent, and demonstrate refrect &#8212; respect for how the law impacts everyday people.  It doesn’t mean she puts her thumb on the scale of justice one way or the other, but she understands the broader impact of her decisions.<br> <br>Whether it’s cases addressing the rights of workers or government service, she cares about making sure that our democracy works for the American people.<br> <br>She listens.  She looks people in the eye &#8212; lawyers, defendants, victims, and families.<br> <br>And she strives to ensure that everyone understands why she made a decision, what the law is, and what it means to them.  She strives to be fair, to get it right, to do justice. <br> <br>That&#8217;s something all of us should remember, and it&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve thought about throughout this process.  And as a matter of fact, I thought about it walking over here with her.<br> <br>One floor below, we have several displays celebrating Black History Month.  One of them includes the judicial oath of office taken and signed by Justice Thurgood Marshall himself &#8212; an oath that will be once again administered to a distinguished American who will help write the next chapter in the history of the journey of America &#8212; a journey that Judge Jackson will take with her family. <br> <br>I hope I don&#8217;t embarrass him, but her husband, Patrick &#8212; a surgeon &#8212; Dr. Patrick, stand up.  Let them see who you are.  There you go.  They met when they were undergraduate students at Harvard, and he&#8217;s a distinguished cancer surgeon at Georgetown. <br> <br>And like so many women in this country, Judge Jackson is a working mom.  She had her eldest child, Talia, when she was a private lawyer in practice.  She had her second child, Leila, when she served as U- &#8212; on the U.S. Sentencing Commission.  Stand up, Leila.  I asked Leila, when I showed her through the office, whether she&#8217;d like to be president.  She looked, &#8220;No, I don&#8217;t know about that.&#8221;  (Laughter.)  There&#8217;s other things that &#8212; anyway, Leila, you&#8217;re welcome to be here.  Thank you so much. <br> <br>And welcome your sister, who&#8217;s up in school in Rhode Island now. <br> <br>I have children and grandchildren.  Let me tell you, Judge, you&#8217;re always a mom.  That&#8217;s not going to change no matter what you&#8217;re doing.  You&#8217;re on &#8212; whether you&#8217;re on the Supreme Court or not. <br> <br>And I&#8217;ve always had a deep respect for the Supreme Court and judiciary as a coequal branch of the government, and I mean it.  The Court is equally as important as the presidency or the Congress.  It&#8217;s coequal. <br> <br>So, today, I&#8217;m pleased to nominate Judge Jackson, who will bring extraordinary qualifications, deep experience and intellect, and a rigorous judicial record to the Court. <br> <br>Judge Jackson deserves to be confirmed as the next justice of the Supreme Court.  I&#8217;ve met with the chairman and ranking members of the Senate Judiciary Committee, Senator Dick Durbin, Senator Chuck Grassley, and my hope is that they will move promptly, and I know they&#8217;ll move fairly. <br> <br>Judge Jackson, congratulations.  And the podium is yours.  Let me pull this out for you.  How &#8212; where is &#8212; there you go.  (The President adjusts the podium.)  You got it?  The button &#8212; okay.  See?  Presidents can&#8217;t do much.  Thank you.<br> <br>JUDGE JACKSON:  Thank you, Mr. President.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Thank you very much, Mr. President.  I am truly humbled by the extraordinary honor of this nomination.  And I am especially grateful for the care that you have taken in discharging your constitutional duty in service of our democracy with all that is going on in the world today. <br> <br>I also offer my sincerest thanks to you as well, Madam Vice President, for your invaluable role in this nomination process. <br> <br>I must begin these very brief remarks by thanking God for delivering me to this point in my professional journey.  My life has been blessed beyond measure, and I do know that one can only come this far by faith.<br> <br>Among my many blessings &#8212; and indeed, the very first &#8212; is the fact that I was born in this great country.  The United States of America is the greatest beacon of hope and democracy the world has ever known. <br> <br>I was also blessed from my early days to have had a supportive and loving family.  My mother and father, who have been married for 54 years, are at their home in Florida right now, and I know that they could not be more proud. <br> <br>It was my father who started me on this path.  When I was a child, as the President mentioned, my father made the fateful decision to trans- &#8212; to transition from his job as a public high school history teacher and go to law school.  Some of my earliest memories are of him sitting at the kitchen table, reading his law books.  I watched him study and he became my first professional role model. <br> <br>My mother, who was also a public high school teacher, provided invaluable support in those early days, working full-time to enable my father&#8217;s career transition while also guiding and inspiring four-year-old me.<br> <br>My only sibling &#8212; my brother, Ketajh &#8212; came along half a decade later, and I am so proud of all that he&#8217;s accomplished. After graduating from Howard University, he became a police officer and a detective on some of the toughest streets in the inner city of Baltimore.  After that, he enlisted in the Army, serving two tours of duty in the Middle East.  I believe that he was following the example set by my uncles who are in law enforcement. <br> <br>You may have read that I have one uncle who got caught up in the drug trade and received a life sentence.  That is true, but law enforcement also runs in my family.  In addition to my brother, I had two uncles who served decades as police officers, one of whom became the police chief in my hometown of Miami, Florida. <br> <br>I am standing here today by the grace of God as testament to the love and support that I&#8217;ve received from my family. <br> <br>I have also been blessed with many dear friends, colleagues, mentors, law clerks.  I could not possibly name all of the people to whom I owe great thanks.  But I must mention specifically the three brilliant jurists for whom I had the privilege of serving as a law clerk at the outset of my legal career: U.S. District Judge Patti Saris in Massachusetts, U.S. Court of Appeals Bruce &#8212; Judge Bruce Selya in Rhode Island, and last but certainly not least, Associate Justice Stephen Breyer of the Supreme Court of the United States. <br> <br>Justice Breyer, in particular, not only gave me the greatest job that any young lawyer could ever hope to have, but he also exemplified every day in every way that a Supreme Court Justice can perform at the highest level of skill and integrity while also being guided by civility, grace, pragmatism, and generosity of spirit. <br> <br>Justice Breyer, the members of the Senate will decide if I fill your seat, but please know that I could never fill your shoes. <br> <br>To my dear family, those who are here with me now and those who are watching from home, I am forever indebted to you for your love and support. <br> <br>To my beloved husband, Patrick, thank you for being my rock today and every day for these past 26 years.  I love you.<br> <br>To my daughters, Talia and Leila, you are the light of my life.  Please know that whatever title I may hold or whatever job I might &#8212; may have, I will still be your mom.  That will never change. <br> <br>There are so many other people I would love to be able to address and to thank, but time is short.  So, let me end by sharing an interesting coincidence that has actually meant a great deal to me over the years. <br> <br>As it happens, I share a birthday with the first Black woman ever to be appointed as a federal judge: the Honorable Constance Baker Motley.  We were born exactly 49 years to the day apart. <br> <br>Today, I proudly stand on Judge Motley&#8217;s shoulders, sharing not only her birthday but also her steadfast and courageous commitment to equal justice under law. <br> <br>Judge Motley&#8217;s life and career has been a true inspiration to me as I have pursued this professional path.  And if I am fortunate enough to be confirmed as the next Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of the United States, I can only hope that my life and career, my love of this country and the Constitution, and my commitment to upholding the rule of law and the sacred principles upon which this great nation was founded will inspire future generations of Americans. <br> <br>Thank you again, Mr. President, for this extraordinary honor.  (Applause.)<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I forgot to introduce the First Lady, Dr. Jill Biden, and the Second Gentleman.  I &#8212; that seems strange to say that, but the Second &#8212; Doug is &#8212; Emhoff.  They&#8217;re both here as well.  So, thank you.  <br> <br>Thank you all.  (Applause.)<br> <br>2:22 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of the President on the NATO Summit and Call with President&#160;Zelenskyy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/25/statement-of-the-president-on-the-nato-summit-and-call-with-president-zelenskyy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 20:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today I met with fellow leaders from our NATO Allies to discuss our shared commitment to collective defense and Transatlantic security. As President Putin threatens the very foundations of international peace and security, NATO is once again demonstrating that it stands for freedom and democracy. As I said yesterday, the United States will defend every&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today I met with fellow leaders from our NATO Allies to discuss our shared commitment to collective defense and Transatlantic security. As President Putin threatens the very foundations of international peace and security, NATO is once again demonstrating that it stands for freedom and democracy.</p>



<p>As I said yesterday, the United States will defend every inch of NATO territory. Our commitment to Article 5 is ironclad. I have ordered the deployment of additional forces to augment our capabilities in Europe to support our NATO Allies. And I strongly welcome the decision to activate NATO’s defensive plans and elements of the NATO Response Force to strengthen our collective posture, as well as the commitments by our Allies to deploy additional land and air forces to the eastern flank and maritime forces from the High North to the Mediterranean.</p>



<p>We were joined today by our close partners Sweden, Finland, and the European Union. President Putin has failed in his goal of dividing the West. NATO is as united and resolute as it’s ever been, and NATO will maintain its Open Door to those European states who share our values and who one day may seek to join our Alliance. As we navigate this crisis, we pledged to work even more closely together in our defense of freedom and the democratic values that imbue our Alliance with purpose and power.</p>



<p>Immediately after the NATO Summit, I spoke with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine. I commended the brave actions of the Ukrainian people who were fighting to defend their country. I also conveyed ongoing economic, humanitarian, and security support being provided by the United States as well as our continued efforts to rally other countries to provide similar assistance.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/25/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47897</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Jay Shambaugh, Nominee for Under Secretary for International Affairs, Department of the Treasury William Duncan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of El Salvador Lesslie Viguerie, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Jay Shambaugh, Nominee for Under Secretary for International Affairs, Department of the Treasury</li><li>William Duncan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of El Salvador</li><li>Lesslie Viguerie, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kyrgyz Republic</li><li>Denis Udall, Nominee for Trustee of the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation</li><li>Tess Udall, Nominee for Trustee of the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Jay Shambaugh, Nominee for Under Secretary for International Affairs, Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Jay Shambaugh is a Professor of Economics and International Affairs at the George Washington University. His area of research is macroeconomics and international economics. His work includes analysis of the interaction of exchange rate regimes with monetary policy, capital flows, and trade flows as well as studies of international reserves holdings, country balance sheet exchange rate exposure, the cross-country impact of fiscal policy, the crisis in the euro area, and regional growth disparities.</p>



<p>Shambaugh served as a Member of the White House Council of Economic Advisors (CEA) from 2015-2017. Earlier, he served on the staff of the CEA as a Senior Economist for International Economics and then as the Chief Economist. He also spent three years as the Director of the Hamilton Project at the Brookings Institution. He is a Research Associate at the National Bureau of Economic Research and Non-Resident Senior Fellow in Economic Studies at Brookings. Prior to joining the faculty at George Washington, Shambaugh taught at Georgetown and Dartmouth and was a visiting scholar at the International Monetary Fund. He has published a book on exchange rate regimes, edited a number of policy related books, and published in many leading economics journals. Shambaugh received his Ph.D. in economics from the University of California at Berkeley, an M.A. from the Fletcher School at Tufts, and a B.A. from Yale University.</p>



<p><strong><u>William Duncan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of El Salvador</u></strong></p>



<p>William H. Duncan, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as a Senior Inspector in the Office of the Inspector General, U.S. Department of State. Previously, he served as Consul General in Monterrey, Mexico. Prior to that, he served as Deputy Chief of Mission at U.S. Embassy Mexico City, Mexico. A Foreign Service officer since 1992, he has also served at U.S. Diplomatic Missions in Asunción, Madrid, Baghdad, Mexico City, Bogotá, San Salvador, and Matamoros. His domestic assignments include the Offices of Andean Affairs, Mexican Affairs, East African Affairs, and Central American Affairs, as well as the State Department Operations Center. Duncan has received numerous performance awards, including a Presidential Meritorious Service award and four Senior Foreign Service Performance awards.</p>



<p>A native of Louisiana, Duncan has a Bachelor’s Degree and a Juris Doctor from the University of Arkansas. He speaks Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lesslie Viguerie, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kyrgyz Republic</u></strong></p>



<p>Lesslie Viguerie, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the U.S. Department of State’s Deputy Assistant Secretary for Central Asian and Pakistan Affairs within the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs. Previously, he was Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Tashkent, Uzbekistan, and Minister-Counselor for Political Affairs at the U.S. Embassy in New Delhi, India. In Washington, DC, he was Director for Europe and Asia in the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs, and Director for Central Asia in the Bureau of South and Central Asia Affairs. Previous overseas assignments include Deputy Political Counselor for the U.S. Embassy in New Delhi, Senior Director of the Interagency Rule of Law Section for the U.S. Embassy in Kabul, and External Political Relations Chief for the U.S. Embassy in Moscow.</p>



<p>A native of Virginia, Viguerie is the recipient of numerous State Department performance awards, including a Senior Foreign Service Performance award. Viguerie is a graduate of The George Washington University (B.A.) and Catholic University of America (J.D.) and is a member of the District of Columbia Bar Association. He speaks Russian, Hindi, and Portuguese.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Denis Udall, Nominee for Trustee of the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation</u></strong></p>



<p>Denis Udall is the Director of Strategic Partnerships with the George Lucas Education Foundation where he manages the strategic direction of the Foundation’s priorities related to project based-learning. Previously, Udall was a program officer at the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation for eight years where he managed strategy and grantmaking related to a wide range of areas, including improving the quality of curriculum and instructional materials, California education policy, and classroom and school-level formative assessment. During his tenure at the Walter S. John Foundation, Udall focused on vulnerable, disconnected youth. Udall has also had a 10-year history with Outward Bound including helping to found Expeditionary Learning (now EL Education), a national school improvement network, and the New York City Outward Bound Center, Outward Bound’s first urban center. Udall is the founder of the North Oakland Community Charter School. He received an Ed.M. from the Harvard Graduate School of Education.</p>



<p><strong><u>Tess Udall, Nominee for Trustee of the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation</u></strong></p>



<p>Tess Udall is a sixth generation Coloradan, born and raised in the foothills of Boulder. Udall is currently a law student at the University of Colorado, where she is specializing in environmental law with an emphasis on native communities and civil rights. While at Colorado Law, she has interned with the Colorado Attorney General’s Office, served as a student clerk for Chief Justice Brian Boatright of the Colorado Supreme Court, and is currently a student attorney in the Getches-Green Natural Resources and Environmental Law Clinic.</p>



<p>Udall previously served as Chief of Staff to the COO of the Retail and Rental Division at Vail Resorts. Udall also worked on strategic partnerships and client relations at Guild Education, a Denver education startup redefining the future of work. Earlier in her career, Udall served in the Obama-Biden White House in various roles in the Chief of Staff’s Office, on the Scheduling and Advance team, and for First Lady Michelle Obama. Udall graduated from the University of Virginia with a degree in Foreign Affairs and Sociology.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Nominates Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson to Serve as Associate Justice of the U.S. Supreme&#160;Court</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/25/president-biden-nominates-judge-ketanji-brown-jackson-to-serve-as-associate-justice-of-the-u-s-supreme-court/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 15:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden will announce his intent to nominate Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson as Associate Justice of the U.S. Supreme Court. Currently a judge on U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit, Judge Jackson is one of the nation’s brightest legal minds.  If confirmed, she will be the first Black woman to serve on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden will announce his intent to nominate <a href="/kbj/">Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson</a> as Associate Justice of the U.S. Supreme Court. Currently a judge on U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit, Judge Jackson is one of the nation’s brightest legal minds.  If confirmed, she will be the first Black woman to serve on the Supreme Court.<br><br>Since Justice Stephen Breyer announced his retirement, President Biden has conducted a rigorous process to identify his replacement.  President Biden sought a candidate with exceptional credentials, unimpeachable character, and unwavering dedication to the rule of law.  He also sought a nominee—much like Justice Breyer—who is wise, pragmatic, and has a deep understanding of the Constitution as an enduring charter of liberty.  And the President sought an individual who is committed to equal justice under the law and who understands the profound impact that the Supreme Court’s decisions have on the lives of the American people.<br><br>As the longtime Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, the President took seriously the Constitution’s requirement that he make this appointment “by and with the Advice and Consent of the Senate,” seeking the advice of Senators in both parties.  He studied the histories and case records of candidates, consulted legal experts, and met with candidates.<br><br>A former clerk for Justice Breyer, Judge Jackson has broad experience across the legal profession – as a federal appellate judge, a federal district court judge, a member of the U.S. Sentencing Commission, an attorney in private practice, and as a federal public defender. Judge Jackson has been confirmed by the Senate with votes from Republicans as well as Democrats three times.  </p>



<p>Judge Jackson is an exceptionally qualified nominee as well as an historic nominee, and the Senate should move forward with a fair and timely hearing and confirmation.<br><br><strong>Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson</strong><br>Judge Jackson has devoted the majority of her career to serving the public—as a U.S. Sentencing Commission lawyer and commissioner; as a federal public defender; and as a federal judge. Judge Jackson currently serves on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit. From 2013 to 2021, she served as a United States District Judge for the District of Columbia. She has been confirmed by the Senate on a bipartisan basis three times – twice as judge and once to serve on the U.S. Sentencing Commission.<br><br>Judge Jackson was born in Washington, D.C. and grew up in Miami, Florida.&nbsp; Her parents attended segregated primary schools in the South, then attended Historically Black Colleges and Universities.&nbsp; Both started their careers as public school teachers and became leaders and administrators in the Miami-Dade County Public Schools.&nbsp; When Judge Jackson told her high school guidance counselor she wanted to attended Harvard, the guidance counselor warned that Judge Jackson should not to set her sights “so high.” That didn’t stop Judge Jackson. She graduated <em>magna cum laude </em>from Harvard College, then attended Harvard Law School, where she graduated <em>cum laude</em> and was an editor of the <em>Harvard Law Review</em>.</p>



<p>After law school, Judge Jackson served in Justice Breyer’s chambers as a law clerk.&nbsp; Judge Jackson served as a federal public defender from 2005 to 2007, representing defendants on appeal who did not have the means to pay for a lawyer.&nbsp; If confirmed, she would be the <em>first</em> former federal public defender to serve on the Supreme Court.</p>



<p>Prior to serving as a judge, Judge Jackson followed in the footsteps of her mentor Justice Breyer by working on the U.S. Sentencing Commission—an important body, bipartisan by design, that President Biden fought to create as a member of the U.S. Senate.&nbsp; Her work there focused on reducing unwarranted sentencing disparities and ensuring that federal sentences were just and proportionate.</p>



<p>Judge Jackson lives with her husband, Patrick, who serves as Chief of the Division of General Surgery at Georgetown University Hospital, and two daughters, in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Watch President&#160;Biden&#8217;s First State of the Union&#160;Address</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2022/02/25/how-to-watch-president-bidens-first-state-of-the-union-address/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 13:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tuesday, March 1, 2022, 9 PM EST Where can I watch the State of the Union livestream? To watch the State of the Union speech live, visit WH.gov/sotu. Tune into the official social media streams of the White House for President Biden&#8217;s State of the Union address. YouTube:&#160;President Biden’s First State of the UnionTwitter: @WhiteHouse&#160;or @POTUSFacebook:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center is-style-large-text">Tuesday, March 1, 2022, 9 PM EST</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2>Where can I watch the State of the Union livestream?</h2>



<p>To watch the State of the Union speech live, visit <a href="/sotu">WH.gov/sotu</a>. Tune into the official social media streams of the White House for President Biden&#8217;s State of the Union address.</p>



<p>YouTube:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mVIXLQrC9rE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">President Biden’s First State of the Union</a><br>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/whitehouse">@WhiteHouse</a>&nbsp;or <a href="https://twitter.com/potus">@POTUS</a><br>Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/WhiteHouse/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">White House on Facebook</a></p>



<p>The White House feed will include ASL interpretation for accessibility.</p>



<h2>When does the State of the Union start?</h2>



<p>The President will address a Joint Session of Congress at the United States Capitol on Tuesday, March 1, 2022 at 9 PM EST.</p>



<h2>Is this President Biden&#8217;s first State of the Union?</h2>



<p>It will be President Biden&#8217;s first State of the Union speech, and his <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/04/29/remarks-by-president-biden-in-address-to-a-joint-session-of-congress/">second address to a joint session of Congress</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki and Deputy National Security Advisor for International Economics and Deputy NEC Director Daleep Singh, February 24,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/24/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-international-economics-and-deputy-nec-director-daleep-singh-february-24-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 04:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47837</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 5:35 P.M. EST MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, back by popular demand.&#160; If he decides he&#8217;s not going to be an economic expert anymore, he might have a future in our business or in our &#8212; in the press office. So back &#8212; Daleep is back.&#160; He&#8217;s going to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>5:35 P.M. EST</p>



<p><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, back by popular demand.&nbsp; If he decides he&#8217;s not going to be an economic expert anymore, he might have a future in our business or in our &#8212; in the press office.</p>



<p>So back &#8212; Daleep is back.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to give some brief comments at the top, take a few questions.&nbsp; Then we’ll do some briefing after then.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll just say at the top: For anyone who needs to leave for TV, feel free to go.&nbsp; It’s all fine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will turn it over to Daleep now.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Good to see all of you again, but this a briefing I never wanted to give.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d like to start by saying: The prayers of the entire world are with the people of Ukraine today as they suffer an unjustified, unprovoked, and premeditated attack by the Russian military forces.</p>



<p>President Biden has said from the start of this crisis: If Putin chooses to invade, the cost to Russia will be immediate and profound &#8212; to its financial system, to its economy, to its technology base, and to its strategic position in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the world has now witnessed, Putin has made his choice. He rejected diplomacy and chose war.&nbsp; And today, the President has announced our response.</p>



<p>Because of Putin’s choices, his flagrant violation of international law, and his utter disregard for the principles that underpin peace and security across the world, we will now ensure his decision is remembered as a strategic failure.</p>



<p>Today, we imposed an unprecedented package of financial sanctions and export restrictions in lockstep with our Allies and partners that will isolate Russia from the global financial system, shut down its access to cutting-edge technology, and undercut Putin’s strategic ambitions to diversify and modernize his economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me walk you through a few specifics, then I&#8217;ll be happy to take questions.</p>



<p>On financial sanctions: I stood at this podium on Tuesday and said we would impose the most severe sanctions ever levied on Russia if Putin proceeded with the invasion.&nbsp; Today, we&#8217;re following through.&nbsp; We will impose sanctions on Russia&#8217;s two largest financial institutions &#8212; Sberbank and VTB &#8212; which together hold more than half of the Russian banking system’s assets &#8212; over $750 billion in total.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For VTB, we will freeze all of its assets touching the U.S. financial system and prohibit U.S. persons from doing any business with the bank.&nbsp; For Sberbank, we will sever its access to the U.S. financial system.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll also freeze the assets of and prohibit any business dealings with three additional Russian banks with combined assets of over $70 billion.</p>



<p>We’ll also restrict U.S. investors from providing debt or equity financing for 13 of the most critical Russian state-owned enterprises, which combined have estimated assets nearing $1.5 trillion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, we&#8217;ll also impose sanctions on the executives at these state-owned institutions, as well as additional Russian elites who are complicit in Putin&#8217;s kleptocracy and their family members.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those who’ve shared in the Kremlin&#8217;s corrupt gains and stored their wealth in yachts and luxury condos and fancy cars will now share in the pain of these measures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of the financial impact, as I said, these are the most impactful and significant sanctions the U.S. has ever taken.&nbsp; But financial sanctions are just one part of our response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also unveiling today an expansive and unprecedented set of export restrictions developed in historically close coordination with the European Union, Australia, Japan, Canada, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, and Taiwan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These new measures include sweeping restrictions on Russian military end users to impair Putin&#8217;s military capabilities and will also deny exports across Russia to sensitive, cutting-edge technology, primarily targeting Russia&#8217;s defense, aerospace, and maritime sectors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In total, the United States and our partners will effectively be cutting off more than half of all high-tech imports going into Russia.&nbsp; This includes curbing Russia&#8217;s access to advance semiconductors and other foundational technologies that Russia needs to diversify and modernize its economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Working in tandem, these financial sanctions and the export controls will undercut Putin’s aspirations to project power on the world stage.&nbsp; And those impacts intensified dramatically just today.</p>



<p>The Russian stock market plunged over 30 percent at one point before being halted by local regulators.&nbsp; Russia&#8217;s currency, the Ruble, weakened to its weakest value on record against the Dollar before the Central Bank intervened.&nbsp; And the price the market is charging the Russian government to borrow is now above 15 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These impacts over time will translate into higher inflation, higher interest rates, lower purchasing power, lower investment, lower productive capacity, lower growth, and lower living standards in Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To be clear: This is not the outcome we wanted.&nbsp; It&#8217;s both a tragedy for the people of Ukraine and a very raw deal for the Russian people.&nbsp; But Putin’s war of choice has required that we do what we said and to ensure this will be a strategic failure.</p>



<p>Finally, let me just say a few words about the impact of Russia’s choices on the U.S.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve intentionally scoped our sanctions to deliver severe impact on the Russian economy while minimizing the cost to the U.S., as well as our Allies and partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To be clear: Our sanctions are not designed to cause any disruption to the current flow of energy from Russia to the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve carved out energy payments on a time-bound basis to allow for an orderly transition of these flows away from sanctioned institutions, and we&#8217;ve provided other licenses to provide for an orderly winddown of business.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me just stop there and take your questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Real quick, I guess that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just had a real quick question.&nbsp; You said it would take some time before it affects the economy and inflation.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the timetable?&nbsp; How long do you think it will take until you have demonstrable results?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Well, look, these are &#8212; these are costs that build over time.&nbsp; And as I mentioned, I think, last Friday, any leader, whether you&#8217;re an autocrat or a small-“d” democrat, has to pay attention to the living standards of your country.&nbsp; And already, we&#8217;re seeing the effects of these measures in the signaling that we provided over the last three months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before these sanctions were implemented, inflation in Russia was 8.7 percent, the government&#8217;s borrowing costs had spiked above 10 percent, the Ruble had lost almost 15 percent of its value.&nbsp; And today, those costs escalated dramatically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, it&#8217;s going to be up to President Putin to decide, ultimately, how much cost he&#8217;s willing to bear.&nbsp; What we control is to make sure this will be a strategic failure &#8212; not just because of the sanctions but also because of the export controls; because of Europe&#8217;s accelerated diversification away from Russia, in terms of its energy supply; due to our fortification of NATO&#8217;s eastern flank; and due to the renewed energy and unity and determination by the West to stand up for our values and advance our principles.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But to confirm: You&#8217;re in it for the long haul, right?&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; I mean, your &#8212; until you see the results that you want?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; We understand that these costs will accumulate over time.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Memoli.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve just laid out all of the actions that the U.S. and our Allies have taken at this point.&nbsp; As you understand, the questions, though, at this point, are about the actions you have not yet chosen to take at this point, specifically the SWIFT system and sanctioning President Putin specifically himself.&nbsp;<br><br>What are the triggers at this point?&nbsp; Are there actions that President Putin might still take that you&#8217;re expecting that would trigger those sanctions?&nbsp; Or what are the potential complications, especially about sanctioning Putin personally?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; So, I m- &#8212; I understand there are a lot of questions about SWIFT and about sanctioning President Putin and lots of other measures that could be mentioned.&nbsp; But let me &#8212; let me say this: I think today was a demonstration that we mean what we say.&nbsp; We delivered on what we said we would do, in terms of imposing costs.&nbsp; So when we say all options are on the table and that we&#8217;re prepared to continue to ratchet costs higher, it would be a mistake to doubt that resolve.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me &#8212; let me also step back and say that when we consider which sanctions to apply, we&#8217;re not cowboys and cowgirls pressing a button to impose costs; we follow a set of principles.&nbsp; We want the sanctions to be impactful enough to demonstrate our resolve and to show that we have the capacity to deliver overwhelming costs to Russia.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, we want them to be responsible, to avoid even the perception of targeting the average Russian civilian and, of course, unwanted spillovers back to the U.S. or the global economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number three, we want to stay coordinated.&nbsp; And so, we calibrate our sanctions to maximize the chance that we move in lockstep with our Allies and partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number four, they should be flexible so that we can escalate or de-escalate depending on facts on the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And lastly, as I mentioned before, they have to be sustainable.&nbsp; These sanctions work over the long term.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what will guide our design.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; MJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In light of the sanctions that were announced against individuals and entities in Belarus, can you tell us whether there are sanctions against any other countries that are being seriously considered at the moment?&nbsp; And what is the line that a nation would need to cross in this conflict for them to recei-&nbsp; &#8212; be on the receiving end of sanctions from the U.S.?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp;Well, the Belarus measures were about delivering costs to a country that aided and abetted what we saw yesterday and overnight.&nbsp; But I have nothing else for you in terms of other countries being targeted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; JJ.</p>



<p>Oh, did you have a question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, definitely.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I didn’t (inaudible) &#8212; I was confusing the arms here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Daleep.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll come back to you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about the &#8212; some of the carve-outs.&nbsp; There are general licenses for more than a dozen areas &#8212; agriculture, energy &#8212; and you just said that the importance is to limit the impact on Americans.&nbsp; But I was hoping that you could say &#8212; is there a percentage that you could share of the number of exemptions that make up the overall transactions?&nbsp; So, the general licenses, how many &#8212; how many tran- &#8212; what percentage of the transactions are under those licenses?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; I would refer you to Treasury and OFAC for the &#8212; for the details on what exactly is being exempted and the percentage of business that would be included.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, could you say &#8212; is it a third?&nbsp; Is it a half?&nbsp; I mean, is it a small percentage?&nbsp; Is it a high percentage?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; I would go back to the principles of our design.&nbsp; The measures themselves and the exemptions are balanced so that we can deliver overwhelming costs while not having unintended consequences.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s the &#8212; that&#8217;s the principle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as to the specifics, I&#8217;d refer you to Treasury.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But wouldn&#8217;t the &#8212; wouldn&#8217;t the oil be a large percentage, I mean, considering how important it is to &#8212; to Russia&#8217;s bottom line?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Well, look, where we have an asymmetric advantage is in foreign capital and cutting-edge technology.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s where we&#8217;re &#8212; that&#8217;s where we&#8217;re delivering the most concentrated impact.</p>



<p>When it comes to energy: This is the one area &#8212; this is the one area where Russia has systemic importance in the global economy.&nbsp; We know it&#8217;s the second-largest natural gas producer in the world.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also the second-largest crude oil producer in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s not to say that we have a dependence on Russia; Russia depends on those revenues just as much as the world needs its energy.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re not going to &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to do anything which causes an unintended disruption to the flow of energy, as the global economic recovery is still underway.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Two quick questions, Daleep.&nbsp; One, if Putin takes Kyiv, does that trigger additional sanctions &#8212; specifically that scenario?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; I’m not going to speculate on particular hypotheticals.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And you mentioned the timeline &#8212; you’ve been asked about the timeline.&nbsp; The President said, in one of the answers to his questions today, said, “Let’s have a conversation in [a] month” to see if these sanctions are working.&nbsp; But my question is: What happens in the meantime?&nbsp; Russia is taking over parts of Ukraine &#8212; major parts of Ukraine as we speak.&nbsp; So the world just sits back and watches that happen until these sanctions take effect?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Look, we can&#8217;t dictate Putin&#8217;s actions.&nbsp; What we can do is what&#8217;s within our control and to make sure this is going to be a strategic failure for Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, over the course of the next month, what you can expect is that we&#8217;ll see an intensifying negative feedback loop in Russian markets &#8212; and I&#8217;ve described the elements of that.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see record capital outflight &#8212; capital &#8212; record capital outflows.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see a weaker currency.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see higher inflation.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see lower purchasing power.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see lower investment.</p>



<p>And that negative feedback loop &#8212; the velocity of it &#8212; is going to be determined by Putin&#8217;s own actions.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s what you should expect on the financial sanctions front.</p>



<p>On export controls, what you can see is that, over time, this is going to atrophy Russia&#8217;s capacity to diversify outside of just oil and gas, and to modernize the strategic sectors that Putin himself has said he wants to develop: aerospace, defense, IT, lasers, sensors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These sectors all depend on foundational technologies designed and produced by the West.&nbsp; You will begin to see a chilling effect take hold in Russia as those inputs are denied.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Weijia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; For weeks now, administration officials have repeatedly said &#8212; yourself included &#8212; that these sanctions are meant to deter and prevent Putin from moving forward, from acting.&nbsp; Can you help us understand why the President said today that no one expected the sanctions to prevent anything from happening?</p>



<p>And then secondly, a quick one on Putin sanctions: Without talking about when you might trigger them, can you help us understand what harm they would do to him personally if you were to sanction Putin?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Look, on your first question, we don&#8217;t usually engage in hypotheticals up here at this podium, but let&#8217;s play this out.&nbsp; Had we &#8212; had we unleashed our entire package of financial sanctions preemptively, I think a couple things might have happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number one, President Putin might have said, &#8220;Look, these people are not serious about diplomacy.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not engaging in a good-faith effort to promote peace.&nbsp; Instead, they&#8217;re escalating.&#8221;&nbsp; And that could provide a justification for him to escalate and invade.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secondly, he could look at it as a sunk cost.&nbsp; In other words, President Putin could think, &#8220;I&#8217;ve already paid the price.&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t I actually take what I paid for, which is Ukraine&#8217;s freedom?&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s what we wanted to avoid.</p>



<p>Look, ultimately &#8212; ultimately, the goal of our sanctions is to make this a strategic failure for Russia.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s define a little bit of what that means.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Strategic success in the 21st century is not about a physical land grab of territory.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what Putin has done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this century, power &#8212; strategic power is increasingly measured and exercised by economic strength, by technological sophistication, and your story &#8212; who you are, what your values are, can you attract ideas and talent and goodwill.&nbsp; On each of those measures, this would be a failure for Russia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; but &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Singh, I keep asking &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you these same questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I didn’t &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Simon, she&#8217;s not done yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Excuse me.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let Weijia finish.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; On President Putin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But did you &#8212; but is it fair to say no one expected the sanctions to prevent anything?&nbsp; You certainly expected that, right?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Look, we &#8212; we signaled as clearly as we could what was coming if Russia proceeded with an invasion.&nbsp; You know, as I mentioned before, economic costs of this severity generally matter to any leader because of the effect it has on &#8212; on his people&#8217;s living standards.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this case, Putin made the wrong choice.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; JJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Singh, (inaudible).&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; JJ.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I keep asking you the same question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get &#8212; JJ is asking a question, Simon.</p>



<p>Go ahead, JJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on SWIFT, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How do we assure that these sanctions don’t really affect ordinary &#8212; ordinary people in Russia?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The UK has been pressuring Allies to still reject Russia from the SWIFT system.&nbsp; Can you say if the U.S. is still intensely working to pressure Allies to do the same?&nbsp; How intensely are you guys pursuing that?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t comment on what the UK&#8217;s position is.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to speak to that.&nbsp; But what I&#8217;ll say is the sanctions measures we imposed today, I think, without question, were the most consequential ever levied on Russia and arguably the most consequential ever levied in history, if you look at the aggregate financial impact on Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that&#8217;s why we took the measures that we did.&nbsp; And we did so because we could move in lockstep with our Allies and partners.&nbsp; And because we think the spillover effects will be manageable.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What I&#8217;m still &#8212; I&#8217;m trying to figure out &#8212; if this is still a realistic live round, is the U.S. really still making an intense effort for this?&nbsp; Or is it essentially &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; &#8220;This&#8221; being SWIFT?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SWIFT, right.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Well, look, again, I&#8217;m just going to repeat: All options are on the table, and we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re prepared to ratchet costs higher at a time and place of our choosing.&nbsp; And, you know, President Putin should take that seriously after what he saw today.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Michael.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Singh, how do you ensure that these sanctions don’t really affect ordinary people in Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Simon &#8212; Simon &#8212; Michael &#8212; let Michael ask his question.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Michael.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I keep asking the same question, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just two questions.&nbsp; First, if you were to sanction Vladimir Putin, do you know where his money is?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Not going to comment on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, secondly, if &#8212; what is the message to Russia at this point on what it would take to roll back &#8212; relieve some of the sanctions that you&#8217;ve put in place today?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Look, the road to diplomacy is always open.&nbsp; Diplomacy is never dead.&nbsp; But in the current circumstance, in the immediate aftermath of an invasion, that &#8212; that option is not available.&nbsp; Right now, we&#8217;re imposing severe consequences on Russia for its decisions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If there were to be a shift in Russia&#8217;s strategic choices that upheld core principles of respecting your neighbors&#8217; borders, respecting your neighbors&#8217; sovereignty, allowing countries to have the freedom to set their own course and their own destiny, that would be a different situation, but that&#8217;s not where we are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tyler.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You suggested that there are things that still remain on the table, but as you walked through the hypothetical scenarios of trying to keep diplomacy open, you said that they have now crossed the line.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if you&#8217;re saying there is still more on the table, do expect things to get worse in the coming days, that Russia will continue to move forward?&nbsp; Is that the intelligence?&nbsp; I know you guys have been quite transparent about the intelligence you have.&nbsp; Are you keeping things back because you think the situation is going to get worse?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Well, I think we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve been transparent in &#8212; to a remarkable degree.&nbsp; And one aspect of that transparency is by saying we can&#8217;t get into President Putin&#8217;s head.&nbsp; And so, your question requires me to speculate on &#8212; on how he&#8217;s thinking about next steps.&nbsp; And I simply can&#8217;t do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But just in terms of U.S. intelligence and the way that you are planning out the different sanctions you have and keeping things on the table, is that a sense that it will get worse, because you want to hold things back?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Look, our job is to be prepared and manage risks &#8212; all manner of risks.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve been doing over the past three months as this crisis intensified.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue doing that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Last one, from Steve.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up &#8212; follow up from Franco, the &#8212; targeting the Russian energy industry is totally off the table.&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re saying, Daleep?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; What I&#8217;m saying is that our measures were not designed to disrupt in any way the current flow of energy from Russia to the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, we have also said we are going to cut off Russia&#8217;s access to cutting-edge technology.&nbsp; That technology can be used across many sectors.&nbsp; And so, as it relates to Russia&#8217;s long-term productive capacity, we are seeking to degrade that capacity, but nothing &#8212; nothing in the short term, as it relates to energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Daleep.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you for joining us.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>Okay, I know it&#8217;s late, but we will get to as many people as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just wanted to note a couple of things at the top for all of you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One, USAID put out an announcement that they&#8217;ve deployed a DART, or Disaster Assistance Response Team, to respond to humanitarian needs in Ukraine.&nbsp; This DART team, which is currently based in Poland, is working closely with European Allies and partners who will be on the frontlines of their response.&nbsp; The team will lead the U.S. government&#8217;s humanitarian response to help address critical needs caused by Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The DART comprises 17 disaster experts from USAID who are assessing the situation, identifying priority needs to scale up assistance inside Ukraine, and working with partners to provide rapidly needed assistance to communities affected by the conflict.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know a number of you have also asked me and we&#8217;ve tried to provide as much detail as possible about how the President has spent his time over the last period since last evening.&nbsp; I think we put out a few details, but just to reiterate for all of you:</p>



<p>He closely monitored the events on the ground from both the Oval Office and then back in the Residence over the course of last evening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We put out a few details last night, including the fact that he spoke repeatedly with his National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan.  He also spoke with his U.S. U.N. Ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, before she gave that powerful speech at the U.N. last night.  He received a briefing from Secretary Austin, Chairman Milley, Secretary Blinken, and his National Security Advisor around 11:00 p.m., approximately, last evening, as well.  And as you know, he also spoke with President Zelenskyy.  He continued to monitor closely into the wee hours last night. </p>



<p>This morning, as you all know, he engaged &#8212; or he met for just about an hour with his national security team, which included both a full table in the room and full members from the Cabinet, from the national security team on the screen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During that meeting, as is standard, he received an update from, of course, Defense, intel, his diplomatic team about the status on the ground.&nbsp; And he has, of course, remained closely engaged with them through the course of the day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, he also had a G7 meeting that lasted a couple of hours this morning.&nbsp; And he also spent an hour this afternoon on the phone with the leaders &#8212; leaders in Congress &#8212; Democratic and Republican leaders in Congress, briefing them on the situation on a secure call, briefing them on the situation on the ground, answering questions they had as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that has been his day to date.&nbsp; And he is continuing, of course, to focus on other priorities as President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But why don&#8217;t we go to you, Zeke?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just picking up on that, has the President made any additional foreign leader calls today?&nbsp; Has he spoken to President Zelenskyy since their call late last evening?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There has not been another call to President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; I expect, as you have seen over the past several days, he will continue to have calls with leaders.&nbsp; We will keep you abreast as those happen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with the U.S. government saying that it believes that the Russian objective right now is to, quote, &#8220;decapitate&#8221; the Ukrainian government, does &#8212; does the U.S. believe that President Zelenskyy, at this moment, is safe?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to get into security &#8212; security questions, but we are in touch with President Zelenskyy, and we are working to provide him a range of support.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And President Zelenskyy, in addition to calling for the West to impo- &#8212; to cut Russia off from SWIFT, also proposed or called for &#8212; demanded, I think, is the word he used in a tweet that the U.S. and its Allies impose a no-fly zone over Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know the President has said that he won&#8217;t put U.S. boots on the ground in Ukraine to fight Russia.&nbsp; Is &#8212; is Ukrainian airspa- &#8212; is Ukrainian airspace in play?&nbsp; Is that something that has &#8212; the subject of any discussions?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve certainly seen &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen &#8212; we&#8217;ve certainly seen his &#8212; his tweet &#8212; or his request via tweet.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have an update on that request.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is that &#8212; that’s not off the table?&nbsp; A no-fly zone is not off the table?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t have any update on it at this point in time or status of the discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Just a follow-up on troops, fast, and a few cyber questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect NATO to call up a major response force? And how many U.S. troops could be called to help in that effort?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s really up to NATO.&nbsp; As you know, we have a number of troops &#8212; thousands of troops that are on call.&nbsp; But that is a decision to be made by the NATO Alliance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said if Putin pursues cyberattacks against our companies, our critical infrastructure, we are prepared to respond.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So just clarifying: Does that, first, mean that there has not been any evidence of any cyberattack from Russia against any American companies at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not that we have identified or attributed at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you explain &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I mean, aside from past ones that you are (inaudible) tracking.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I guess I mean in the last &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; 24 hours.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you explain more of the White House&#8217;s thinking on, kind of, this debate in Washington about whether a cyberattack against a NATO Ally would trigger an Article 5 response &#8212; a response from the Alliance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that, again, is up to the NATO Alliance to determine, but, obviously, a cyberattack does constitute an attack, so that would certainly be a point of discussion among the NATO members.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, one more really fast.&nbsp; On the US- &#8212; USAID disaster response that you just mentioned, a 17-person team &#8212; is that enough?&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;re talking about &#8212; we&#8217;ve heard you guys talk about the potential of hundreds of thousands of refugees &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You&#8217;re absolutely right.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s an important point.&nbsp; But what I &#8212; what we&#8217;re trying to do here is provide any incremental update on the status of what our work is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll just note, and you may be fully aware of this &#8212; but in terms of humanitarian assistance, we have been the biggest provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine; we&#8217;ve provided over $52 million in humanitarian assistance to Ukraine in the past year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve committed additional funding and supplies to humanitarian organizations.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a specific need and therefore a focus on support services, food, clean water, hygiene, shelter, trauma, primary healthcare.&nbsp; Our prepare &#8212; and we are prepared to certainly provide a significant amount more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is just one step &#8212; obviously, less than 24 hours after the events of last night, and we will continue to plus up from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, there are a number of protests within Russia itself.&nbsp; Are you monitoring this?&nbsp; What&#8217;s your message to them?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there certainly are.&nbsp; And I know, with everything going on, this may not have caught everybody&#8217;s attention.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me just note that, you know, today we&#8217;re seeing Russian people in the streets, open letters from leading Russian journalists, cul- &#8212; and cultural figures denouncing President Putin&#8217;s war of choice, and reports of Russian mothers concerned about the reckless deployment of their sons to this fratricidal war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s important to remember back in 2014 when they didn&#8217;t even acknowledge that they were sending Russian soldiers, they didn&#8217;t even acknowledge when there were body bags coming back from Ukraine into Russia.&nbsp; And there is an outcry in the streets by Russian people, by &#8212; by more Russian people than I think many would expect.&nbsp; So, despite Putin&#8217;s crackdown at home, dissenting views remain, and I think that&#8217;s important to note.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To publicly protest against President Putin and his war is a deeply courageous act.&nbsp; Their actions show the world that, despite the Kremlin&#8217;s propaganda, there are Russian people who profoundly disagree with what he is doing in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, one more.&nbsp; Speaker Pelosi is talking about sending $600 million in lethal aid to Ukraine.&nbsp; Is this something you support?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are in conversations with Congress.&nbsp; And I mentioned the President spoke with leaders just earlier this afternoon.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an exact number, but those are ongoing conversations about what needs the Ukrainians have on the ground in a variety of categories: security, humanitarian, other economic assistance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the U.S. have any analysis to indicate that there is dissent or division within Putin&#8217;s government?&nbsp; Or is it your understanding that Putin&#8217;s government is united in this war?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s an interesting question, MJ.&nbsp; And without getting into intelligence, which obviously we look at &#8212; I mentioned, obviously, Russians protesting in the streets.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not exactly what you asked about.&nbsp; But if you watched the meeting the Pres- &#8212; President Putin had with members of his national security team the other day, it was quite striking the back-and-forth he had with his intel chief in that meeting.&nbsp; And the analysis of that is &#8212; certainly can be done in an open-source manner, given it was quite public.&nbsp; But I will leave outside analysis to give further assessment of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as you know, we are seeing Ukrainians start to flee the country.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the U.S. prepared to accept Ukrainian refugees?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are, but we &#8212; we certainly expect that most, if not the majority, will want to go to Europe, in neighboring countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we are also working with European countries on what the needs are, where there is capacity &#8212; Poland, for example, where we are seeing a &#8212; an increasing flow of refugees over the last 24 hours &#8212; or through its flow of individuals, I should say &#8212; out of Ukraine, what their needs are.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been talking and engaging with Europeans about that for some time now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So part of what you&#8217;re doing is to prepare for the United States to accept refugees?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President is certainly prepared for that.&nbsp; But I would just note that because there are a number of European countries neighboring Ukraine who have expressed an openness to it, we would anticipate many of them would want &#8212; would want to go to European countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; quick question.&nbsp; The President, of course, has repeatedly said that American troops will not enter Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any scenario that has been discussed where that decision might be reconsidered?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has no intention of sending U.S. troops to fight in Ukraine.&nbsp; That has not changed.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This was asked to the President earlier, but I don’t think we got a full answer.&nbsp; Yesterday, Vladimir Putin said that &#8212; he warned if others got involved, they&#8217;ll suffer&nbsp; &#8220;consequences that you have never encountered in your history.&#8221;&nbsp; Does the U.S. understand that as a threat of using nuclear weapons?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we can&#8217;t, obviously, get into the mind of President Putin as much as he said that, nor do we know all the specific details about his strategic posture, but we don&#8217;t see any increased threat in that regard at this point in time.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on some of the cyber questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know that you and others have talked about how the government is on alert for the potential of a cyberattack.&nbsp; But can you share &#8212; like are there any specific steps that are being taken that you can share that the U.S. is doing to protect the infrastructure, power grid, U.S. banks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say: One, we&#8217;ve been &#8212; there&#8217;s been efforts that have been ongoing for some time since the beginning of the administration to harden the private sector and work with the private sector in partnership to harden their cybersecurity protections.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve actually seen a great deal of progress made in the financial sector.&nbsp; It&#8217;s one of the stronger sectors in terms of protections, from a cyber front, that we see out there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s been ongoing for several months.&nbsp; Obviously, when there are moments like this where we continue to watch and look for what the potential is, we will &#8212; we continue to re- &#8212; to engage closely with a range of industries about what they need to do about the potential threats.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something that happens, obviously, privately and through a range of agencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I can see if there&#8217;s anything more specific that we can read out to all of you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And just real &#8212; just, real quick, one follow-up.&nbsp; President Biden said they are &#8212; that the U.S. is prepared if an attack comes (inaudible).&nbsp; Would &#8212; pardon me &#8212; he said “prepared to respond.”&nbsp; Would that response be a &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A cyberattack you&#8217;re talking about?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A cyberattack, yes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would that be an equivalent cyberattack against Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say that the President reserves the option to respond in any manner of his choosing: overt or covert &#8212; &#8220;seen or unseen,&#8221; as we like to say in more available English.  But I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics of what that looks like.  He has a range of options.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; On oil prices and the SPR.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the administration have an oil price in mind that would trigger another release from the SPR?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think &#8212; not that we&#8217;re going to get into detail or &#8212; from here, JJ.&nbsp; I understand, certainly, the question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What you heard the President talk about today, and I can just reiterate a little bit, is that what has been ongoing &#8212; both from the President, who has been very engaged in this, having conversations with leaders in the Middle East and other parts of the world, as well as many members of his national security team &#8212; taking whatever steps we can to mitigate the impact on the global oil markets.&nbsp; And, obviously, that means increasing supply.&nbsp; Obviously, a coordinated released from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve would be part of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of what that looks like or the specifics, I&#8217;m just not in a position to get into more details at this point.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; If the worst happens and Russia either reduces the flow of natural gas or cuts off energy altogether to Europe, does the administration have a good idea for how long households in Europe could last under that kind of circumstance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an assessment of that from here.&nbsp; I can certainly check with our economic team.</p>



<p>One thing I will say &#8212; that one of the steps we&#8217;ve been taking &#8212; obviously, natural gas shortages and supply is a &#8212; it is an enormous regional issue, one that would hugely impact Europe more than here, of course.&nbsp; One of the steps we&#8217;ve been focused on and been taking is engaging with partners who have &#8212; who may have ex- &#8212; excess LNG supply, like countries in Europe &#8212; Japan, for example, where they had &#8212; where we would &#8212; were planning to give them some, and now they&#8217;re going to divert it to Europe.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve been working to help mitigate any impact of a further invasion and a shortage in Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some of the activity that we&#8217;ve seen today in Ukraine &#8212; some of the clashes have been in and around Chernobyl.&nbsp; Does the United States have an assessment of the risk of a radioactive release?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, I do have one actual update on that as well.&nbsp; There&#8217;s also been &#8212; there was also a report out &#8212; so let me speak to this first, just so I don&#8217;t forget &#8212; about hos- &#8212; hostages around there as well, so let me speak to that first.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are outraged by credible reports that Russian soldiers are currently holding the staff of the Chernobyl facilities hostage.&nbsp; This unlawful and dangerous hostage-taking, which could upend the routine civil service efforts required to maintain and protect the nuclear waste facilities, is obviously incredibly alarming and greatly conserming [sic] &#8212; concerning.&nbsp; We condemn it, and we request their release.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of a further assessment, I don&#8217;t have anything more on that from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you gave a readout of how the President spent the past 24 hours or so.&nbsp; First, I wanted to ask about his call with President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; Did he indicate if he was still in Kyiv?&nbsp; Did he identify his location at this point?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are aware of where he is located.&nbsp; And we are in touch with him.</p>



<p>I would say on that call, what &#8212; what they discussed is President Zelenskyy&#8217;s request for the President to be &#8212; to condemn the actions of President Putin and the Russians and to engage with other global leaders about it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what he&#8217;s done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen a number of statements today from former presidents &#8212; President Obama, President Bush &#8212; and also saw former President Trump on television talking about this.&nbsp; Has the President &#8212; you mentioned, during the Afghanistan drawdown, he had been in contact with his predecessors.&nbsp; Has he been in touch with any of his predecessors during this?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has not been today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, in terms of another domestic priority that was potentially included in his meetings today, given the situation &#8212; his time and focus and attention on Supreme Court &#8212; excuse me, on Ukraine &#8212; will this affect the timing of his Supreme Court announcement?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We &#8212; we are still on track to make an announcement before the end of the month.&nbsp; We have to do a lot of things around here at the same time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on the cyberattacks and Article 5 question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you said that it&#8217;s up to NATO to decide, but from a U.S. perspective, would any cyberattack against a NATO Ally trigger Article 5 or would there be a measure for what counts?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, this is the conversation we would have with our NATO Allies and partners.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have more ad- &#8212; anything in addition to add to it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just to follow up on the Supreme Court: I know you said you&#8217;re on track, but has he made a final decision, given they are basically two days left before the end of the month?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not a &#8212; not a final final.&nbsp; No offer has been &#8212; no job offer has been made.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Just a couple.&nbsp; Are there any concerns or indications at this point that Russia had prepared for the sanctions that you&#8217;re putting in place and developed, preemptively, ways to block that impact?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s an interesting question.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; and some of it is hard because it&#8217;s hard to get into the minds of President Putin and the oligarchs around him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the steps we tried to take is to &#8212; you know, as we were &#8212; as we were contemplating the individuals we were going to sanction, we &#8212; we sanctioned family members as well, because what we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; the tactics they&#8217;ve used in the past is they&#8217;ve moved money around and resources around to family members.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve tried to address that on the front end.</p>



<p>In terms of the banking and the financial sector, I mean, it accounts for such a large percentage of how they do business, that that is &#8212; it would be a difficult thing for them to plan and plot against.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you look to just even the anticipation of the potential sanctions, as Daleep was mentioning, you know, the Ruble is the worst-performing currency in the world right now.&nbsp; Their inflation is &#8212; has skyrocketed.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re even seeing in their markets the anticipated impact even before today, and that&#8217;s even before the actual squeeze on the financial sector in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it feels to me it would be a little hard to plan around and plot around, given the significance of what was done today and the fact that when we &#8212; sanctioning 10 &#8212; 10 of Russia&#8217;s financial institutions and these export control measures, which essentially cuts President Putin off from semiconductors and access to a range of technology he wants for the future, those are difficult things to plan ahead for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And then, I guess, secondly, does the administration have any assessment for how China is reacting to this at this point &#8212; whether they are willing to provide support to Russia and how much?&nbsp; And has there been any kind of contact there to kind of attempt to move them off of any support?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, in terms of what impact they can have, I mean, China only accounts for about 15 percent of &#8212; China and Russia &#8212; I&#8217;m not sure; you can double check me on this &#8212; about 15 percent of the global economy.&nbsp; If you look at G7 partners, in the U.S. and Europe, it&#8217;s about 50 percent.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So they cannot cover what the impact of the sanctions that have been announced in coordination with Europe would &#8212; how they would impact Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I think from our perspective, as it relates to China, while I can&#8217;t get into the heads of what their thinking is, you know, this is a really &#8212; a moment for China, for any country to think about what side of history they want to stand on here.&nbsp; And, you know, that is certainly the &#8212; the case that we would make publicly and privately.</p>



<p>I think you saw that Secretary Blinken spoke with his counterpart just a couple of days ago.&nbsp; You know, the President is certainly open to speaking with his counterpart.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any prediction of that at this point in time or a timeline.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Over the past couple of weeks as you&#8217;ve been sending the alarm on this, you&#8217;ve put the sanctions package together, done &#8212; conducted diplomacy with the Russians and the rest of the world.&nbsp; How did the Ukrainian government use that time since they&#8217;ve been initially warned that this was a likelihood?&nbsp; Did they use that time wisely to prepare?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tell me more about what you mean, exactly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you&#8217;re seeing reports from the streets in Russia of &#8212; sorry, in Ukraine of people being surprised.&nbsp; You had, obviously, local and national leadership in Ukraine telling people to stay calm, to remain &#8212; to go to work even a day before the invasion began.&nbsp; So, were they properly prepared?&nbsp; And was there more that they could have done in the leadup?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think it&#8217;s not particularly constructive for us to give an assessment of that.&nbsp; What &#8212; what I can tell you is that our focus has been on providing up-to-date &#8212; what has turned out to be quite accurate and transparent information about what the &#8212; President Putin has &#8212; was preparing to do, which is invade Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have been very clear with American citizens who were there.&nbsp; We have been clear with our European partners for months now, including Ukrainian leadership.&nbsp; So that has been what our focus has been.&nbsp; And, you know, we will remain a strong support &#8212; supporter and partner of President Zelenskyy and Ukraine moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Following up on the sanction question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have heard for weeks that these sanctions were, at least in part, a part of a strategy that was based on deterrence &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; as well as prevention.&nbsp; Today, with the President&#8217;s comment that &#8220;no one expected the sanctions to prevent anything from happening,&#8221; moving forward, do you expect this slate of sanctions to prevent any further advancement or aggression from Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that later in the &#8212; later in the back-and-forth or the press avail, he also said, when asked, &#8221; If sanctions cannot stop President Putin, what penalty can?&#8221; And he said, &#8221; I didn&#8217;t say sanctions couldn&#8217;t stop him.&#8221;&nbsp; Which leads me to believe that&#8217;s not exactly what he meant.&nbsp; He also went on to say &#8221; The threat of the sanctions and imposing the sanctions and seeing the effect of the sanctions are two different things.&#8221;</p>



<p>And the way we look at this, broadly speaking &#8212; and Daleep touched on this a little bit &#8212; is that we do see them as having a deterrent impact, right?&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean they&#8217;re 100 percent foolproof.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if you &#8212; if there&#8217;s a 95 percent chance of Russia invading without the threat of sanctions, and there&#8217;s a 60 &#8212; I&#8217;m making up these percentages just to make a point &#8212; but &#8212; and a 65 percent chance that they will with them, you&#8217;re obviously going to go with the threat of sanctions because you want to reduce the threat of an invasion.&nbsp; So, there is a deterrent.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen the deterrent impact work at times.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note, though, that we are very clear-eyed about the fact that President Putin not just a few days ago &#8212; I mean, he gave the speech a few days ago where he questioned the legitimacy of Ukraine as a sovereign country.  He&#8217;s also talked about how the breakup of the Soviet Union was the worst thing that&#8217;s happened &#8212; that&#8217;s a paraphrase &#8212; in recent &#8212; you know, in decades of history.  So, we are clear-eyed about his ambition. </p>



<p>But what the other part of it that we are quite focused on is the consequences.&nbsp; And the way we see it is &#8212; you know, as we&#8217;ve touched on a little bit &#8212; inflation is skyrocketing, the Ruble is the worst-performing currency in the world.&nbsp; It was his decision to go to war.&nbsp; It&#8217;s our choice to make him pay a price &#8212; same with the global community &#8212; and we believe these consequences are also going to have an impact.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that &#8212; just at the risk of repeating your question as well: I mean, the President did also say, you know, let&#8217;s check in in a month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q    And there has been some questions about time here.  It seems like this is a strategy to use these sanctions to put pressure on Russia to eventually discourage them to pull out &#8212; or to force them to pull out this &#8212; this advance.  So, what is the timetable here, you think, for when the Russian government will start actually feeling the impact of these sanctions and possibly pull out?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, in many senses, they&#8217;re already feeling the impact.&nbsp; I mean, look at where the Ruble is. Look at where inflation is.&nbsp; Look at where the markets are in Russia.</p>



<p>In terms of how Putin will feel the impact, we just sanctioned a range of oligarchs around him.&nbsp; We sanctioned 10 financial institutions.&nbsp; These are all &#8212; these are all significant, enormous steps that are going to have an impact on him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of the moment by moment, I can&#8217;t give you an assessment of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp; Just off topic.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just &#8212; there&#8217;s been a lot of questions about refugees in the region.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For Ukrainians that are in the country, is the U.S., especially after yesterday, considering TPS or any sort of protections?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; As you know, that&#8217;s a decision that would be made through an interagency process led by the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have any prediction of that.&nbsp; I mean, I don&#8217;t have any kind of prediction of that at this point in time.&nbsp; Obviously, these &#8212; these events are just unfolding as we speak.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that process hasn&#8217;t started?&nbsp; That conversation hasn&#8217;t &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give you any specifics on an internal process.&nbsp; But I would just say, again, it&#8217;s an interagency process.&nbsp; And, right now, we&#8217;re, of course, in the middle of an invasion and a &#8212; and a &#8212; you know, a war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Earlier you had you have to do a lot of things at the same time.&nbsp; One of those things, of course, is the State of the Union next week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you tell us how the President this week has been preparing for that, how much time he spent on the speech, and how he&#8217;s juggling that with this very busy schedule that you laid out earlier tonight?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, absolutely.&nbsp; So, in addition to obviously being very closely engaged and leading the effort on the U.S. response to the Russia &#8212; to Russia &#8212; the Russian military invasion of Ukraine, the President has been working with speechwriters, working with pol- &#8212; members of his policy team to finalize details of his State of the Union, doing &#8212; starting to do some readthroughs &#8212; not too many, yet.&nbsp; I expect those will increase in the days ahead.&nbsp; I expect we won&#8217;t have too much of a preview for you.&nbsp; Maybe tomorrow, but maybe &#8212; more likely this weekend.</p>



<p>He&#8217;s also been engaging with his COVID team, talking about where we are in the state of the pandemic, what&#8217;s next in the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He has been working closely with his economic team on &#8212; and receiving updates on the supply chain, the implementation of the Infrastructure Bill.</p>



<p>So, even as we have all been understandably focused on the conflict in Ukraine, the President has been very hard at work on a range of issues that are vital to the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you touched on my follow-up.&nbsp; ABC is reporting that the White House is revamping the COVID strategy now that hospitalizations are on the decline.&nbsp; Should we expect the President to roll that out in the speech next Tuesday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any preview for you on timeline or format.&nbsp; But the President has been working and engaged with his COVID team for some time now, and we&#8217;re making strong &#8212; strong progress on moving toward a time when COVID is no longer a crisis.</p>



<p>The COVID team has been spending a lot of time and energy, including with the President, working with experts inside and outside government, local public health officials, and governors. &nbsp;And this work is broader than one piece of guidance.</p>



<p>How we look at it is we&#8217;re preparing to stay ahead of the virus, protecting our most vulnerable, keeping our country open.&nbsp; And that is &#8212; and that is going to look at everything from &#8212; the CDC is obviously reviewing mask guidance, but also how we&#8217;re going to ensure that vaccines, boosters, tests, treatments, and other &#8212; and other important components of our medicine cabinet are available to the American people.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I had a couple of questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, sure.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;ll go to you next.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I had a couple of questions.&nbsp; First a follow-up about some of the humanitarian needs you&#8217;ve been talking about.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;ve talked about how much money and supplies are going to be going, but how are you going to ensure that those supplies get to the Ukraine?&nbsp; Is there going to be some sort of airdrop?&nbsp; And would the President consider putting U.S. boots on the ground for humanitarian needs to make sure they get to the people that need it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we do have, fortunately or unfortunately, a fair amount of experience on providing humanitarian assistance in conflict zones, and we typically work &#8212; and USAID, specifically, has a great deal of experience with that &#8212; working with trusted third-party entities; obviously, the government, which remains in power.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s a range of ways that we would provide assistance.</p>



<p>In terms of other mechanisms, I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then another question for you, and this has been happening while you&#8217;ve been up at the podium, so &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m not trying to ambush you &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but I wanted to give you a chance to respond.&nbsp; Senator Ted Cruz is speaking at CPAC, and you came up.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He called you, quote, unquote, &#8220;Peppermint Patty,&#8221; and has encouraged people to boo you.&nbsp; So, I wanted to &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Don&#8217;t tell him I like Peppermint Patty.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I &#8212; so I&#8217;m not going to take it too offensively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You just did.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Senator Cruz, I like Peppermint Patty.&nbsp; I&#8217;m a little tougher than that, but there you go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Yeah, so back to the President&#8217;s comments earlier today.&nbsp; So, he did say to give it a month to see if these sanctions work.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; However, you know, under Russia&#8217;s current assault, Ukraine clearly might not have a month or even weeks.&nbsp; So, is it fair to say that he is conceding Ukraine to Putin?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing about the President&#8217;s strategy or approach or leadership in the world &#8212; building a coalition of the majority of countries, you know, in the Western world, to stand against the actions of President Putin &#8212; that suggests that he is ceding anything.</p>



<p>You saw him lay out a set of historic sanctions today that will maximize pain on Russia.&nbsp; Yes, as we&#8217;ve &#8212; as we&#8217;ve conveyed, they&#8217;re meant to have a squeeze over the course of time, but we&#8217;re already seeing an impact on the financial markets, on the currency, on inflation in Russia.&nbsp; And there is a &#8212; there are &#8212; unfortunately, the Russian people are going to feel the pain of that.</p>



<p>So, I would say the President is going to continue, as he has for weeks now, to work in close lockstep with European partners to continue to press &#8212; to press from the global community for de-escalation as a relates to the events in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; If President Zelenskyy is in danger of being killed or captured and put on some sort of a show trial, would President Biden send U.S. troops in on a rescue mission to get him out?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, we are in touch with President Zelenskyy, who is an important partner.&nbsp; We support him.&nbsp; He is the leader of Ukraine, of gov- &#8212; the President of Ukraine, but I&#8217;m not going to get into security steps.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; There&#8217;s this talk about a possible forecast for financial pain, particularly at the gas pump &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for Americans.&nbsp; The President said today, &#8220;The notion that this is going to last for a long time is highly unlikely.&#8221;&nbsp; Would he try to ensure that by lifting some of the restrictions that he&#8217;s put in place on the energy industry or rethinking some projects like the Keystone Pipeline?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, the Keystone Pipeline is not flowing, so I&#8217;m not sure how that would solve anything.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also plenty of oil leases that are not being tapped into by oil companies, so you should talk to them about that and why.</p>



<p>But what the President is talking about is &#8212; we certainly understand &#8212; and he said this today, right? &#8212; it may have been in response to your question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t remember.&nbsp; But if there&#8217;s an invasion of another country by a big country, there&#8217;s going to be impacts on the markets.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And we certainly anticipated that, and we anticipate that as it relates to the global oil market as well.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s why the President, for weeks now, has been engaging with a range of big global suppliers &#8212; some in the Middle East, others &#8212; to see what we can do to ensure there is supply out there in the market to reduce the impact on the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the U.S. is one of the Russian oil industry&#8217;s best customers &#8212; hundreds of thousands of barrels per day.&nbsp; Would the President ever consider ordering U.S. companies to stop importing Russian oil?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any prediction of that at this point, Peter.&nbsp; We announced some significant sanctions today.&nbsp; Our objective is to ensure there is the greatest pain &#8212; economic pain on Russia and not on the Russian people, but on President Putin, and to minimize the impact on the American people, including companies here in the United States.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the President said that he thinks that Putin is go and try to expand back the Soviet Union.&nbsp; So, is this &#8212; do you all think this is act one in a multiple-country invasion?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to make a prediction of that, but we certainly think he has grander ambitions than Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to clarify that same point: Does he believe that President Putin is going to absorb Ukraine into Russia when he says that President Putin wants to &#8220;reestablish the…Soviet Union&#8221;?&nbsp; Is that what he&#8217;s saying?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think he believes that &#8212; as we all do &#8212; that President Putin has more &#8212; has grander ambitions in Ukraine.&nbsp; Hence, the military campaign is continuing.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll do this more tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>6:23 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
