<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 20:25:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>ICYMI:  President&#160;Biden Pushes Forward on Tackling Climate Crisis Despite Supreme Court’s Attempt to Take Country&#160;Backwards</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/01/icymi-president-biden-pushes-forward-on-tackling-climate-crisis-despite-supreme-courts-attempt-to-take-country-backwards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 20:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, in response to the Supreme Court’s ruling in West Virginia v. EPA, President Biden issued a statement on his unwavering commitment to “continue using lawful executive authority, including the EPA’s legally-upheld authorities, to keep our air clean, protect public health, and tackle the climate crisis” and “tackle environmental injustice, create good-paying jobs, and lower&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, in response to the Supreme Court’s ruling in <em>West Virginia v. EPA</em>, President Biden issued a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-supreme-court-ruling-on-west-virginia-v-epa/">statement</a> on his unwavering commitment to “continue using lawful executive authority, including the EPA’s legally-upheld authorities, to keep our air clean, protect public health, and tackle the climate crisis” and “tackle environmental injustice, create good-paying jobs, and lower costs for families building the clean energy economy.”<br><br>Vice President Harris <a href="https://twitter.com/VP/status/1542631060789293058">emphasized</a> that while “the Supreme Court’s misguided ruling aims to take our country backward,” through “executive authority, legislation, and state and local action, we must charge forward.” National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy <a href="https://twitter.com/ginamccarthy46">stressed</a> that even though the Supreme Court is “siding with extreme special interests that want to dismantle our right to clean air,” President Biden will “keep moving us forward, using every tool we can to tackle the climate crisis,” and EPA Administrator Michael Regan <a href="https://twitter.com/EPAMichaelRegan/status/1542656005644902401">made clear</a> that the agency “will move forward using our Clean Air Act authority, consistent with the law, to set greenhouse gas standards for power plants.”<br><br><em>Read more about how the Biden-Harris Administration is pressing ahead:</em><br><br><strong>Time: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6192857/biden-climate-scotus-west-virginia/">&#8216;We Have to Be Creative.&#8217; How the Biden Administration Is Responding to the SCOTUS Climate Setback</a><br>[Justin Worland, 6/30/22]<br><br>Gina McCarthy, President Joe Biden’s national climate advisor . . . was surprisingly optimistic—not that the ruling would go the Administration’s way, but rather that the White House could chart a path to slash emissions even if it didn’t. <strong>“We’ve set very solid goals, we’re making significant progress on the transition to clean energy,” she told TIME on June 28. “And that is not going to live and die by the Supreme Court’s decision.”</strong> To meet the White House’s goals, she said, the Administration needs to get “creative” and find novel ways to galvanize the energy transition. That includes . . . the Administration’s engagement with the private sector, use of its own purchasing power, and use of the Defense Production Act to accelerate the production of domestic clean energy technology, she says.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>PBS NewsHour:</strong><a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/amp/show/epa-administrator-michael-regan-discusses-supreme-court-ruling-on-climate-change">EPA Administrator Michael Regan discusses Supreme Court ruling on climate change</a><br>[Interview, 6/30/22]</p>



<p>EPA Administrator Michael Regan: “Let me be clear. It doesn&#8217;t take us out of the game. <strong>We still will be able to regulate climate pollution. And we&#8217;re going to use all of the tools in our toolbox to do so </strong>. . . One tool that we will continue to look at is the authority that was in question with the Supreme Court. Again, that tool is still available. We have just lost some flexibility there . . . But it does not prevent us from continuing to make progress. And so we will have to be vigilant in terms of focusing on climate change pollution . . . We&#8217;re going to use every tool in the toolbox that we have to set and implement environmental standards that meet our obligation to protect all people and all communities from environmental harm.”<br><br><strong>Gina McCarthy on CNN:</strong><a href="https://twitter.com/TheLeadCNN/status/1542642048016293889">The Lead with Jake Tapper</a><br>[Interview, 6/30/22]</p>



<p>National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy: “We are not giving up, we’re actually going to double down. And we know that <strong>we have the legal authority, and frankly we have the mandate of the people in the United States and across the world</strong> who want to address this challenge of climate change and do it in a way that makes positive improvements in our lives.”<br><br><strong>Gina McCarthy on NPR:</strong><a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/07/01/1109275642/has-the-supreme-court-tied-the-biden-administrations-hands-on-climate-change">Morning Edition</a><br>[Interview, 7/01/22]</p>



<p>National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy: “The Court hasn’t tied our hands on climate change . . . <strong>it was a very disappointing decision, but it did not strip away the ability for EPA to regulate greenhouse gases</strong> . . . and more broadly, people should understand that this President didn’t come into office thinking that EPA was the sole way in which we could move forward on climate change . . . He recognized that special interests for decades have been funded by fossil fuel companies to really wage a long-term campaign to strip away all these environmental protections that keep our water and our air clean . . . but that’s why the President said we’re not just going to rely on EPA, we’re going to have a whole-of-government approach . . . we’re leaving no stone unturned . . . to invest in a clean energy future.”</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at Richmond and Henrico Health District&#8217;s East&#160;Clinic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/01/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-richmond-and-henrico-health-districts-east-clinic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 20:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56738</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Richmond, VA We’re here in Richmond because the President and I—and the entire Administration—care about this community. We care about your families and we want to make sure that everyone has the information they need to stay safe. So, I want to speak to the moms and dads for just a moment.  You know, when&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Richmond, VA</p>



<p>We’re here in Richmond because the President and I—and the entire Administration—care about this community. We care about your families and we want to make sure that everyone has the information they need to stay safe. So, I want to speak to the moms and dads for just a moment. </p>



<p>You know, when you become a parent, there’s a moment that we all go through: You look at that baby, with eyes like saucers and the tiniest fingers. And you feel an overwhelming sense of love, deep in your bones, and absolute terror.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because you know that this fragile life is depending on you. And from that moment on, you see dangers that you never even noticed before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we buy baby gates and cover our electrical outlets. We wrestle them into car seats no matter how much they complain. We make them eat their vegetables and slather them in sunscreen while they fight us with the strength of a linebacker! And after bedtime, when we’re exhausted from the day, we carefully close their bedroom door and feel a pang of gratitude.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because in that rare quiet, we know that everything is OK. That they are healthy and growing—that we are OK.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Parents, we do absolutely everything to protect our kids. And in this pandemic, you did.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many of you had to go through birth without your own parents there to help you recover. You had to quarantine with your newborn and without the friends and neighbors who could come over and give you a few hours to yourself. You wrestled tiny masks onto children who couldn’t understand them; you weighed the risk of going to crowded areas or traveling to see loved ones.</p>



<p>And you waited. You waited to feel the same relief you saw in families of older children. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I know it’s been hard. But you’ve done an amazing job. You’ve protected your baby and carried your family through this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now, that relief is finally here: a vaccine for our youngest children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s been thoroughly reviewed and rigorously tested. It’s safe and effective. It’s free. And it’s available for every child in this country, as young as six months old. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, even though so many parents have been waiting for this day, I know you may have questions. So talk to your pediatrician. Get the answers that you need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you decide that this vaccine is right for your child, go to vaccines.gov to find a vaccine site near you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Parents, this is your choice—and we want you to have all of the information you need to make it.</p>



<p>Parenthood and worrying go hand-in-hand. And I can’t promise you that the dangers of the world are going to become any less frightening—just wait until your kids start driving!&nbsp;</p>



<p>But with this vaccine, we can take away at least one of those worries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From the day your sweet, fragile, little baby was born, you have made the choice, again and again, to keep your child safe. This is your choice too. So, make the decision to protect your children with the same vaccine that has already saved millions of lives. Because nothing is more important than our children’s health.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s up to us to keep them safe—and with this vaccine, we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/01/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 19:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the Secretary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section&nbsp;506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $50&nbsp;million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Appointments to Boards and&#160;Commissions</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/01/president-biden-announces-key-appointments-to-boards-and-commissions-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 19:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles: Mohamed Hag Magid, Commissioner, United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Elizabeth Hirsh Naftali, Commission Member, United States Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad Michael Lozman, Commission Member, United States Commission for the Preservation of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Mohamed Hag Magid, Commissioner, United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</li><li>Elizabeth Hirsh Naftali, Commission Member, United States Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad</li><li>Michael Lozman, Commission Member, United States Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad</li><li>Roselyne Chroman Swig, Commission Member, United States Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad</li><li>Lesley Weiss, Commission Member, United States Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad</li></ul>



<p><strong>United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</strong><br>The United States Commission on International Religious Freedom is an independent, bipartisan U.S. federal government commission created by the 1998 International Religious Freedom Act that monitors the universal right to freedom of religion or belief abroad. USCIRF uses international standards to monitor religious freedom violations globally, and makes policy recommendations to the President, the Secretary of State, and Congress. USCIRF Commissioners are appointed by the President and Congressional leaders of both political parties.<br><br><strong>Mohamed Hag Magid, Commissioner, United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</strong><br>Imam Mohamed Magid is the Executive Religious Director of All Dulles Area Muslim Society Center in Sterling, Virginia. He is the Chairman of International Interfaith Peace Corps and the former President of the Islamic Society of North America. He serves on the advisory board of the Peaceful Families Project and as Co-President of Religions for Peace. Magid is also the Co-Founder of the Multifaith Neighborhood Network, which focuses on building bridges between Muslim, Evangelical Christian, and Jewish communities.<br><br>His main focuses are promoting religious freedom, preventing violence against women, and preventing violence and hate in our societies. Magid works with The United Nations Development Programme in training Imams to deal with violence and extremism against religious minorities in East and West Africa.<br><br><strong>United States Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad</strong><br>The U.S. Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad was established in 1985 to ensure that sites important to populations impacted by Nazism, communism, and the Cold War would be preserved for future generations. The Commission’s mission is to identify, protect, and preserve cemeteries, monuments, and historic buildings in Eastern and Central Europe that are associated with U.S. heritage. The work recognizes that the population of the United States is mostly comprised of immigrants and their descendants, and that the United States has an interest in the preservation of sites in other countries related to the heritage of these Americans.<br><br><strong>Elizabeth Hirsh Naftali, Commission Member, United States Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad</strong><br>Elizabeth (Liz) Hirsh Naftali runs and owns a commercial real estate company in Los Angeles’ Fashion District. She has served on the board of Oakwood School in North Hollywood since 2002 and was the Board Chair from 2012 to 2015. She also currently serves on the board of the IKAR Shul in Los Angeles and the RAND Corporation Center for Middle East Public Policy.<br><br>In 2007, Hirsh Naftali developed BIG Giving, a philanthropic branch of the company she co-founded, BIG Shopping Centers, that primarily supports educational, developmental, and co-existence programs for Jewish and Arab children across Israel. She remains active in her philanthropy in Israel working with the Tel Aviv Foundation and Babylonian Jewry Museum. At the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic in the spring of 2020, Hirsh Naftali started the Make More Masks Campaign, producing and distributing over 100,000 masks to keep those most vulnerable in our communities safe.<br><br><strong>Michael Lozman, Commission Member, United States Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad</strong><br>Dr. Michael Lozman is a practicing orthodontist in Latham, New York. He has taught in the Graduate Department of Orthodontics at New York University School of Dentistry and has served in numerous professional leadership positions including on the Board of Governors of the New York State Dental Society and as President of the New York State Society of Orthodontics.<br><br>In 2001, Lozman founded an organization to bring college students to Eastern Europe to restore Jewish cemeteries that were destroyed during the Nazi era. To date, the organization has completed the restoration of fifteen Jewish cemeteries, ten in Belarus and five in Lithuania. Lozman also founded the Capital District Jewish Holocaust Memorial, Inc. and is working to develop a Holocaust memorial in the capital area of New York. Lozman has lectured in several countries, and he has been noted for his Holocaust educational activities.<br><br><strong>Roselyne Chroman Swig, Commission Member, United States Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad</strong><br>Roselyne Chroman Swig is Founder and President of ComCon International, as well as Founder of Roselyne C. Swig Artsource. She was appointed Director of the U.S. Department of State Art in Embassies Program by President Clinton. Swig has devoted decades to philanthropic and community service efforts at the local, national, and global levels with a focus on women’s empowerment, social welfare, fine art, political advocacy, and education. She is Founder of the advocacy group Partners Ending Domestic Abuse and Founder and Member of Bayview Alliance.<br><br>Swig is National V.P. Emeritus of AIPAC, Lifetime Trustee of Shalom Hartman Institute, and Trustee Emeritus at Mills College. She served as President and Trustee Emeritus of SF Art Institute, President of Berkeley Art Museum and Pacific Film Archives, Chair of the Contemporary Jewish Museum, President Emeritus of Jewish Community Federation of SF Peninsula, Marin, and Sonoma Counties, President of SF Arts Commission, and Co-Chair of the National Gallery of Art Collector’s Committee, among others.<br><br><strong>Lesley Weiss, Commission Member, United States Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad</strong><br>Lesley Weiss is Deputy Director of the National Coalition Supporting Eurasian Jewry. In this role, she coordinates democracy initiatives, community education and outreach efforts, and promotes advocacy on behalf of Jewish communities in Eastern Europe and Eurasia. She monitors compliance by the governments of the region in the areas of religious and cultural rights and works closely with the governments and the Jewish communities on the restitution and preservation of Jewish communal property, combating anti-Semitism, and Holocaust awareness. Weiss represents the National Coalition Supporting Eurasian Jewry at Organization for the Security and Cooperation in Europe meetings and numerous other international conferences throughout Europe, Central Asia, and Israel on the Holocaust, anti-Semitism, and international religious freedom.<br><br>Weiss is also a member of the U.S. delegation to the International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance. In 2013, President Obama appointed Weiss Chair of the U.S. Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad, where she served until 2017.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Thirteenth Operation Fly Formula Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/01/president-biden-announces-thirteenth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 19:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 6.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Reckitt Mead Johnson Enfamil Stage 1 infant formula base powder July 12, 14, and 19 Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 6.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Reckitt Mead Johnson Enfamil Stage 1 infant formula base powder July 12, 14, and 19</em></p>



<p><br>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Reckitt Mead Johnson infant formula base powder from Singapore to Chicago, Illinois via flights on July 12, 14, and 19.This delivery will include over 418,000 pounds of Reckitt Mead Johnson Enfamil Stage 1 infant formula base, the equivalent of approximately 6.2 million 8-ounce bottles. Upon its arrival, this powder will be transferred to a Wanamingo, MN facility for conversion to final product that will be made available in the coming weeks. The product will be available at national and regional retailers.  </p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Reckitt Mead Johnson can export additional infant formula into the U.S.&nbsp;By mid-July, Reckitt Mead Johnson plans to bring approximately 66 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Enfamil Stage 1 infant formula base powder into the U.S. market.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. By July 3, Operation Fly Formula will have transported more than 37.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents to the U.S.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Governors on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/01/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-governors-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden convened nine Democratic Governors from across the country to discuss efforts to defend reproductive rights. These Governors collectively represent tens of millions of women. They are each taking action to protect access to abortion care, including by: announcing funding for reproductive health care services; educating the public; supporting the codification of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden convened nine Democratic Governors from across the country to discuss efforts to defend reproductive rights. These Governors collectively represent tens of millions of women. They are each taking action to protect access to abortion care, including by: announcing funding for reproductive health care services; educating the public; supporting the codification of the right to access an abortion into state law and state constitutions; issuing executive actions to defend patients, including out-of-state patients, providers, and third parties; and even taking action <a href="https://www.gov.ca.gov/2022/06/24/west-coast-states-launch-new-multi-state-commitment-to-reproductive-freedom-standing-united-on-protecting-abortion-access/">together</a> to support abortion access. These steps by Democratic Governors are critical as states enact and enforce laws to ban abortion and criminalize their citizens in the wake of the Supreme Court’s decision in <em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization, </em>which overturned <em>Roe v. Wade</em>.</p>



<p>In the meeting, the President highlighted the impact the decision will continue to have on the health and safety of millions of women. He reiterated <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/24/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-actions-in-light-of-todays-supreme-court-decision-on-dobbs-v-jackson-womens-health-organization/">his Administration’s commitment</a> to defend women’s freedom to travel for lawful abortion care, as well as access to critical, FDA-approved medications for reproductive health care, including medication abortion and contraception. The President made clear that the filibuster should not stand in the way of restoring <em>Roe</em> into federal law. And he warned of Congressional Republican efforts to pass a nationwide ban on abortion.</p>



<p>The President thanked the Governors for their work on this issue, and told them his Administration looks forward to continued partnership to protect access to reproductive health care.</p>



<p>The conversation was moderated by Jennifer Klein, Director of the White House Gender Policy Council. Governors from today’s meeting included:</p>



<ul><li>Governor Kate Brown, Oregon</li><li>Governor Roy Cooper, North Carolina</li><li>Governor Kathy Hochul, New York</li><li>Governor Jay Inslee, Washington</li><li>Governor Ned Lamont, Connecticut</li><li>Governor Dan McKee, Rhode Island</li><li>Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham, New Mexico</li><li>Governor Jared Polis, Colorado</li><li>Governor J.B. Pritzker, Illinois</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2022 Annual Report to Congress on White House Staff</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/01/2022-annual-report-to-congress-on-white-house-staff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 18:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since 1995, the White House has been required to deliver a report to Congress listing the title and salary of every White House Office employee. Consistent with President Biden’s commitment to transparency, this report is being publicly disclosed on our website as it is transmitted to Congress. 2022 Annual Report to Congress on White House&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since 1995, the White House has been required to deliver a report to Congress listing the title and salary of every White House Office employee. Consistent with President Biden’s commitment to transparency, this report is being publicly disclosed on our website as it is transmitted to Congress.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/July-1-2022-Report-Final.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2022 Annual Report to Congress on White House Staff</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on Florida’s “Don’t Say Gay” Law Taking&#160;Effect</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/01/statement-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-floridas-dont-say-gay-law-taking-effect/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 15:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, some of Florida’s most vulnerable students and families are more fearful and less free. As the state’s shameful “Don’t Say Gay” law takes effect, state officials who claim to champion liberty are limiting the freedom of their fellow Americans simply to be themselves. Already, there have been reports that “Safe Space” stickers are being&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, some of Florida’s most vulnerable students and families are more fearful and less free. As the state’s shameful “Don’t Say Gay” law takes effect, state officials who claim to champion liberty are limiting the freedom of their fellow Americans simply to be themselves. Already, there have been reports that “Safe Space” stickers are being taken down from classrooms. Teachers are being instructed not to wear rainbow clothing. LGBTQI+ teachers are being told to take down family photos of their husbands and wives—cherished family photos like the ones on my own desk.<br> <br>This is not an issue of “parents’ rights.” This is discrimination, plain and simple. It’s part of a disturbing and dangerous nationwide trend of right-wing politicians cynically targeting LGBTQI+ students, educators, and individuals to score political points. It encourages bullying and threatens students’ mental health, physical safety, and well-being. It censors dedicated teachers and educators who want to do the right thing and support their students. And it must stop.<br> <br>President Biden has been very clear that every student deserves to feel safe and welcome in the classroom. The Department of Education will be monitoring this law, and any student or parent who believes they are experiencing discrimination is encouraged to file a complaint with the Department’s Office for Civil Rights. Our Administration will continue to fight for dignity and opportunity for every student and family—in Florida and around the country.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Recipients of the Presidential Medal of&#160;Freedom</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/01/president-biden-announces-recipients-of-the-presidential-medal-of-freedom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56641</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden named seventeen recipients of the Presidential Medal of Freedom. The Presidential Medal of Freedom is the Nation’s highest civilian honor, presented to individuals who have made exemplary contributions to the prosperity, values, or security of the United States, world peace, or other significant societal, public or private endeavors. President Biden&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden named seventeen recipients of the Presidential Medal of Freedom.</p>



<p>The Presidential Medal of Freedom is the Nation’s highest civilian honor, presented to individuals who have made exemplary contributions to the prosperity, values, or security of the United States, world peace, or other significant societal, public or private endeavors.</p>



<p>President Biden has long said that America can be defined by one word: possibilities. These seventeen Americans demonstrate the power of possibilities and embody the soul of the nation – hard work, perseverance, and faith. They have overcome significant obstacles to achieve impressive accomplishments in the arts and sciences, dedicated their lives to advocating for the most vulnerable among us, and acted with bravery to drive change in their communities – and across the world – while blazing trails for generations to come.</p>



<p>The awards will be presented at the White House on July 7, 2022.</p>



<p>The following individuals will be awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom:</p>



<p><strong><u>Simone Biles</u></strong></p>



<p>Simone Biles is the most decorated American gymnast in history, with a combined total of 32 Olympic and World Championship medals. Biles is also a prominent advocate for athletes’ mental health and safety, children in the foster care system, and victims of sexual assault.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sister Simone Campbell</u></strong></p>



<p>Sister Simone Campbellis a member of the Sisters of Social Service and former Executive Director of NETWORK, a Catholic social justice organization. She is also a prominent advocate for economic justice, immigration reform, and healthcare policy.</p>



<p><strong><u>Julieta García</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Julieta García is the former president of The University of Texas at Brownsville, where she was named one of&nbsp;<em>Time</em>&nbsp;magazine’s best college presidents. Dr. García was the first Hispanic woman to serve as a college president and dedicated her career to serving students from the Southwest Border region.</p>



<p><strong><u>Gabrielle Giffords</u></strong></p>



<p>Former Congresswoman Gabby Giffords was the youngest woman ever elected to the Arizona State Senate, serving first in the Arizona legislature and later in the U.S. Congress. A survivor of gun violence, she co-founded Giffords, a nonprofit organization dedicated to gun violence prevention.<strong></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Fred Gray</u></strong></p>



<p>Fred Gray was one of the first black members of the Alabama State legislature since Reconstruction. As an attorney, he represented Rosa Parks, the NAACP, and Martin Luther King, who called him “the chief counsel for the protest movement.”</p>



<p><strong><u>Steve Jobs</u></strong><strong> </strong>(posthumous)</p>



<p>Steve Jobs (d. 2011) was the co-founder, chief executive, and chair of Apple, Inc., CEO of Pixar and held a leading role at the Walt Disney Company. His vision, imagination and creativity led to inventions that have, and continue to, change the way the world communicates, as well as transforming the computer, music, film and wireless industries.</p>



<p><strong><u>Father Alexander Karloutsos</u></strong></p>



<p>Father Alexander Karloutsos is the former Vicar General of the Greek Orthodox Archdiocese of America. After over 50 years as a priest, providing counsel to several U.S. presidents, he was named by His All Holiness Ecumenical Patriarch Bartholomew as a Protopresbyter of the Ecumenical Patriarchate.</p>



<p><strong><u>Khizr Khan</u></strong></p>



<p>Khizr Khanis a Gold Star father and founder of the Constitution Literacy and National Unity Center. He is a prominent advocate for the rule of law and religious freedom and served on the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom under President Biden.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sandra Lindsay</u></strong></p>



<p>Sandra Lindsayis a New York critical care nurse who served on the front lines of the COVID-19 pandemic response. She was the first American to receive a COVID-19 vaccine outside of clinical trials and is a prominent advocate for vaccines and mental health for health care workers.</p>



<p><strong><u>John McCain</u></strong> (posthumous)</p>



<p>John McCain (d. 2018) was a public servant who was awarded a Purple Heart with one gold star for his service in the U.S. Navy in Vietnam. He also served the people of Arizona for decades in the U.S. House of Representatives and U.S. Senate and was the Republican nominee for president in 2008.</p>



<p><strong><u>Diane Nash</u></strong></p>



<p>Diane Nash is a founding member of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee who organized some of the most important civil rights campaigns of the 20<sup>th</sup> century. Nash worked closely with Martin Luther King, who described her as the “driving spirit in the nonviolent assault on segregation at lunch counters.”</p>



<p><strong><u>Megan Rapinoe</u></strong></p>



<p>Megan Rapinoeis an Olympic gold medalist and two-time Women’s World Cup champion. She also captains OL Reign in the National Women’s Soccer League. She is a prominent advocate for gender pay equality, racial justice, and LGBTQI+ rights.</p>



<p><strong><u>Alan Simpson</u></strong></p>



<p>Alan Simpson served as a U.S. Senator from Wyoming for 18 years. During his public service, he has been a prominent advocate on issues including campaign finance reform, responsible governance, and marriage equality.<br></p>



<p><strong><u>Richard Trumka</u></strong><strong> </strong>(posthumous)</p>



<p>Richard Trumka (d. 2021)was president of the 12.5-million-member AFL-CIO for more than a decade, president of the United Mine Workers, and secretary-treasurer of the AFL-CIO. Throughout his career, he was an outspoken advocate for social and economic justice.</p>



<p><strong><u>Wilma Vaught</u></strong></p>



<p>Brigadier General Wilma Vaughtis one of the most decorated women in the history of the U.S. military, repeatedly breaking gender barriers as she rose through the ranks. When she retired in 1985, she was one of only seven women generals in the Armed Forces.</p>



<p><strong><u>Denzel Washington</u></strong></p>



<p>Denzel Washington is an actor, director, and producer who has won two Academy Awards, a Tony Award, two Golden Globes, and the 2016 Cecil B. DeMille Lifetime Achievement Award. He has also served as National Spokesman for the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America for over 25 years.</p>



<p><strong><u>Raúl Yzaguirre</u></strong></p>



<p>Raúl Yzaguirre is a civil rights advocate who served as CEO and president of National Council of La Raza for thirty years. He also served as U.S. Ambassador to the Dominican Republic under President Barack Obama.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at a DNC Finance&#160;Reception</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/30/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-a-dnc-finance-reception/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 03:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Private ResidenceLos Gatos, California THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Shannon, for all that you are, for the work that you are doing, for the work that everyone here is doing to fight for so much of what is right now at stake. Kevin, Coco, to your whole family: Thank you for hosting us.  And to everyone&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Private Residence<br>Los Gatos, California</em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Shannon, for all that you are, for the work that you are doing, for the work that everyone here is doing to fight for so much of what is right now at stake.<br> <br>Kevin, Coco, to your whole family: Thank you for hosting us.  And to everyone here, I see some longstanding friends, and we&#8217;ve been in this fight together, many of us &#8212; I&#8217;m a proud Bay Area kid &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we have been in this fight together, so many of us, for quite some time. <br> <br>And I think sometimes, because we are so committed, it can feel as though this is never going to end.  Will we ever get there, the place we are determined to go?  And if we get there, how long can we be there before things erode or turn back?  And it can be extremely dispiriting.  It can make us sad.  It certainly can make us angry.<br> <br>But, you know, many of you have heard me say this &#8212; many years I&#8217;ve been saying this.  And it&#8217;s to paraphrase Coretta Scott King.  And she famously said: The fight for civil rights &#8212; which of course is the fight for equality, for freedom, for liberty, for justice &#8212; the fight for civil rights must be fought and won with each generation. <br> <br>And I think she had two points in mind when she said that.  One is that it is the very nature of this fight that we collectively have been in on the variety of issues that Shannon just articulated and more.<br> <br>I mean, I just &#8212; I was telling Kevin and Shannon and Coco, I just, very proudly, held as the Vice President of the United States of America, at the official residence of the Vice President of the United States of America, a Pride reception at the house &#8212; (applause) &#8212; where we talked about our trans kids, where we talked about what is happening in terms of “Don&#8217;t Say Gay” in Florida and all over this country.<br> <br>But all of that to say, this fight that we have been in, so many of us for so long, what she said &#8212; Coretta Scott King &#8212; is that it must be fought and won with each generation, because she understood it&#8217;s the very nature of this fight that whatever gains we make, they will not be permanent.  It&#8217;s the nature of it.  It&#8217;s the strength of it in that we know when we do it, it empowers, it uplifts.  But there is also, coexistent with the strength of it, fragility &#8212; meaning that if we are not vigilant, we certainly can&#8217;t take it for granted; we must be vigilant.<br> <br>And so the second point, I think, of her admonition is then: Understanding it won&#8217;t be permanent, understanding we must be vigilant, understanding it is the nature of it &#8212; point number two &#8212; do not despair.  Do not be overwhelmed.  Do not give up.  It&#8217;s just the nature of it.<br> <br>I look at my friend, our Lieutenant Governor Eleni Kounalakis &#8212; (applause) &#8212; who is an extraordinary fighter.  She&#8217;s here with us today.  And I think about all the warriors that we have.  All of us, we’re built for this.  We&#8217;re built for this.<br> <br>But I too &#8212; you know, we read and &#8212; we read &#8212; many of us read the leaked opinion.  And then, when it happened &#8212; you know, when you know something is going happen and then it happens, it’s just a different thing altogether.<br> <br>I was actually on Air Force Two, flying from Washington, D.C., to go to Illinois &#8212; Aurora, Illinois &#8212; to meet up with Lauren Underwood, a member of Congress &#8212; (applause) &#8212; who I worked with when I was in the Senate, when, in the Senate, I sponsored the Maternal Health Act and the Momnibus that is all about recognizing the fact that in this nation of ours, we have the distinction &#8212; the sad distinction of having one of the highest rates of maternal mortality of any so-called developed nation.<br> <br>So, Lauren and I, for years, have been working on this issue.  And I&#8217;m very proud that as Vice President, I&#8217;ve been able to, for the first time in the history of our country, put this issue on the stage of the White House &#8212; this issue of maternal mortality &#8212; to say: States, instead of two months of Medicaid coverage for postpartum, it should be 12 months; to say &#8212; (applause) &#8212; that we need to recognize the bias that is in the healthcare delivery system, which results in the fact that Black women are three times more likely to die in connection with childbirth, Native women twice as likely, rural women one and a half times likely.  And so let&#8217;s deal with that.<br> <br>All of this stuff we&#8217;ve been working on. <br> <br>So I was on Air Force Two to go meet Lauren.  In my plane, I had Dick Durbin, the Chair of the Senate Judiciary Committee, a great longstanding fighter.  And I guess, as fate would have it, this was who I was with and this is where I was when on the TV, on the plane, they announced that the Court had made the decision on Dobbs.  The irony of it, right?<br> <br>And like all of us, it was &#8212; it knocked the wind out of us<br>that the United States Supreme Court would, for the first time in our nation, in the history of jurisprudence, take a constitutional right that had been recognized and take it from women.<br> <br>I know we all feel so strongly about this.  You know, my mother &#8212; many of you knew her &#8212; was &#8212; she had two goals in her life: to raise her two daughters and end breast cancer.  My mother was a researcher, a scientist.  She fought for women&#8217;s health her entire life.  I grew up, from a young child, listening to her battle to ensure the dignity of women in the healthcare delivery system.<br> <br>And we look at what just happened, and we understand what it means not just theoretically, not just in the context of history, but as Shannon and I have discussed just before we came out, rightly, in the context of all these young women, girls &#8212; women &#8212; who are in a state of utter fear right now, feeling alone and isolated, not to mention what is happening with these proponents of these pieces of legislation in that decision who are daring to insinuate that there would be some righteous judgment associated with the predicament and the decisions women must make.<br> <br>I gave a speech when we first heard about the leaked opinion.  I was at EMILY&#8217;s List.  And I said, and I&#8217;ll keep saying: How dare they.  How dare they.  (Applause.) <br> <br>So, we must fight. <br> <br>You all probably heard that the President, rightly, today said the filibuster will not stand in the way of what we need to get done.  (Applause.)  And so that is part of it. <br> <br>And then part of it is what we need to do in terms of the assistance and the care that we will give those who are in need.  We, as Californians, luckily have leadership who understand the crisis and the issue and the need for all of us to step out and be there for those in need.<br> <br>But we&#8217;re also going to have to focus on what&#8217;s happening in these other states &#8212; not one part of our battle to the exclusion of the other.<br> <br>And that brings us to part of why we are here today, which is to support the DNC and its work, because elections matter.  Elections matter.  Federal elections matter.  Who&#8217;s in Congress, if we&#8217;re going to get the Women&#8217;s Health Act passed, if we&#8217;re going to pass voting rights &#8212; that matters.  (Applause.)<br> <br>If we&#8217;re going to pass, now that the Court came down with this decision in terms of the EPA &#8212; if we&#8217;re going to get meaningful legislation passed on greenhouse gas emissions and what we know is an absolute crisis in the world.  Elections matter.<br> <br>State elections matter.  Who is governor, who is lieutenant governor, who is attorney general, who is secretary of state &#8212; that matters.<br> <br>Local elections matter.  In these states that are talking about criminalizing women and their care providers, who is DA matters; who is sheriff matters; who is mayor who appoints the police chief matters.<br> <br>So we got a lot of work to do.<br> <br>But I want to stress that in the midst of these crises, we really do have to remember that we are up for this fight.  Because the alternative is not an option.  It is truly not an option to be overwhelmed. <br> <br>We have to be unified and stand together, understanding what we stand for as Democrats.  Because I do believe, when you know what you stand for, you know what to fight for.  (Applause.)  Yes.<br> <br>So we stand &#8212; we stand for equality.  We stand for unity.  We stand for freedom.  We stand for extending the Child Tax Credit, which, in its first year, brought child poverty down by at least 40 percent in our country.  (Applause.) <br> <br>We stand for a childcare tax cut that we got passed in the ARP, the American Rescue Plan, which is an $8,000 tax cut to help families pay for school supplies and medication for their children.  We stand for that.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We stand for building up infrastructure, which is why we got the first, in generations, Bipartisan Infrastructure Law passed.  Do you know what that does?  I&#8217;ve been traveling around the country in places like Michigan &#8212; I mean, all over the country &#8212; dealing with the fact that, in particular, in poor communities and communities of color, our babies, our children are drinking water out of lead pipes.  We got that bill passed.  We&#8217;re putting billions of dollars to eradicate and get lead out of pipes within 10 years.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Elections matter.<br> <br>We got extreme amount of funding put in on the issue of high-speed Internet.  Well, why is that important?  The pandemic highlighted the fact that we have vast disparities in this country based on the access to meaningful education for the children of America.  And among the inflection points on that issue, one of them is access to high-speed Internet and affordability of high-speed Internet.  So we have done that now, where we will be able to ensure that all families have access and affordable high-speed Internet, in particular for their children. <br> <br>These are some of the things that we have accomplished.  And there is more.<br> <br>Did y&#8217;all see somebody get sworn in today?  (Applause.) (Laughs.)  Her name is Justice Ketanji Brown Jackson! (Applause.) <br> <br>Elections matter. <br> <br>I&#8217;ve been traveling around the globe.  I met with President Zelenskyy two days before Russia, in an unprovoked hostile act, invaded Ukraine.  I have spent time with President Macron.  I have hosted Angela Merkel while she was chancellor, and sat down to meet with Chancellor Scholz.<br> <br>I just recently convened, at the Summit of the Americas, the prime ministers and presidents of the Caribbean nations.<br> <br>We have raised $1.2 billion to focus on the northern Central American countries of Honduras and Guatemala and El Salvador, investing, in particular, in women in those countries to address the needs that they have there so people don&#8217;t feel they have to flee their home.<br> <br>Elections matter.<br> <br>Because if President Joe Biden weren&#8217;t there, I promise you &#8212; because I have witnessed it &#8212; I do not believe NATO would have come together as it did, that we would have been able to convene the EU, as we did, to make a statement about a collective priority around international norms and rules that must be maintained, including the international rule and norm of sovereignty and territorial integrity that no nation can use violence to change the borders and invade another country.<br> <br>Elections matter.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And there is more work to do.  We&#8217;re still fighting to get affordable childcare.  We have been proposing working families shouldn&#8217;t spend more than 7 percent of their income in childcare.<br> <br>We saw how many millions of women during the pandemic had to leave the workforce.  Direct connection between availability and affordability of childcare and women in the workforce. <br> <br>We still have work to do.  We need paid family leave.  (Applause.) <br> <br>We need paid and affordable homecare.  So many, in particular women, but individuals who are in what we call the sandwich generation, raising their children and taking care of their elderly parents and trying to pay the bills.<br> <br>We still have work to do.  We need to pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Act and the Freedom to Vote Act.  (Applause.) <br> <br>We have work to do.<br> <br>I was one of the authors of the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act.<br> <br>We have more work to do.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And then, by my count, if I&#8217;m correct, Jaime &#8212; 131 days<br>we will have a midterm election.  And on every level we have just discussed, the outcomes may be determined.<br> <br>Now, I know some people are saying, “Stop talking to us about the elections.  We know.”  Don&#8217;t trivialize the significance of it.  We can&#8217;t afford to.  We cannot afford to.  We got a lot we need to get done.  There is no question.  That is not the only thing, and it is not the elixir.<br> <br>But I am, as the Vice President of the United States, the President of the Senate.  And I will tell you, I run back and forth from my office in the West Wing to the Capitol to break tie votes.  Why?  Because we have a 50-50 Senate &#8212; 50 Republicans and then fif- &#8212; well, 48 Democr- &#8212; she thought I was going to say something else.  (Laughter.)  No, two in- &#8212; two independents who caucus with the Democrats.  (Laughter.)  Forty-eight plus two.   (Laughter.)  And we &#8212; we believe we can actually change those numbers in this election.  (Applause.)<br> <br>A hundred and thirty-one days, we&#8217;re looking at the House.  We have to, at the very least, hold on to the numbers there.<br> <br>But I was also &#8212; Jaime, I was looking at &#8212; and you&#8217;ll correct me &#8212; but I just did a quick review and jogged my memory about even just &#8212; you remember the 2010 midterms?  And we all remember that.  By my count, there were, I think &#8212; what was it? &#8212; something like 60 seats that were in a toss-up.  And this time, I think we have about 20.  Something like that.  It&#8217;s a much smaller number. <br> <br>So one could argue, I think fairly, it&#8217;s very doable.<br>It&#8217;s very doable.  Because all the resources have to go into fewer races.<br> <br>And, you know, I was &#8212; I was talking again, before we came in, about this dynamic.  So, you know, the question then becomes how are we going to win.  Right?  And I think part of it is to make clear, again, what we stand for as Democrats and, therefore, what we fight for. <br> <br>But also, just check this out for a moment: The American Rescue Plan &#8212; okay? &#8212; height of the pandemic.  We come in as an administration.  People are out of work.  Small businesses are folding.  Right?  The childcare piece &#8212; the Child Tax Credit, child poverty &#8212; that bill, which the President eventually was able to get through, you understand that not one Republican voted for it.  Not one.  Child Tax Credit &#8212; tax cut &#8212; $8,000 tax cut &#8212; child tax cut for childcare expenses.<br> <br>The &#8212; I sat there.  I presided.  It was very important to me to, again, leave the White House and go to the Senate, even though, you know, we knew it was probably not going to work out, to preside over the vote on the Women &#8212; Women&#8217;s Health Act.  Not one Republican voted for it. <br> <br>You can go down the list and see that they don&#8217;t only obstruct and not support what is helpful.  They actually don&#8217;t have a plan.  And, you know, while we talk about the things we need to do more, we also have to see what we&#8217;re up against.<br> <br>There &#8212; there&#8217;s no bipartisanship, except for the infrastructure, that&#8217;s happening on things that should be non-debatable.<br> <br>I asked my team to do a Venn diagram and &#8212; and show me the states where we&#8217;re seeing legislation come out that is anti-choice, anti-LGBTQ, anti-voting rights.  It&#8217;s an interesting diagram.  (Laughter.)  It tells you a whole lot.<br> <br>The intersection on voting rights and abortion &#8212; I think there were at least 11 states clearly.  Right?  So they say, “We&#8217;re going to send it to the states, and then the states and then the people in the states can vote for what they want.  Oh, but meanwhile, we&#8217;re making it more difficult for you to vote.”<br>Right?<br> <br>They talk about liberty and freedom &#8212; freedom of choice, freedom to marry, freedom to make a decision about contraception.<br> <br>So there are clear choices in this election coming up &#8212; very clear choices.  We have to stay active.  We have to demand the most and the best from ourselves.  And we have to see the power that we have right now, at the very least over the next 131 days, to change the outcome of this election in a way that can have impact. <br> <br>I know every year, every election we say this is the biggest one.  But, man, I mean, this Court just took a constitutional right from the women of America. <br> <br>So with that, I say: Let&#8217;s fight.  We know what we have to do.  Let&#8217;s stand together.  We are of common purpose.  We know what we stand for, and we know what we&#8217;re fighting for.  Because, ultimately, we&#8217;re not fighting against anything, we&#8217;re fighting for something.<br> <br>And truly, if you were to pull out on a macro level, we are fighting for the democracy of America.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So with that, I thank you all very much.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>                               END                 4:14 P.M. PDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
