<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 10:23:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/26/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-chancellor-olaf-scholz-of-germany-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 10:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany ahead of the G7 Leaders’ Summit. President Biden expressed appreciation for the Chancellor’s leadership of the G7, and the importance of coordinating responses to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, climate, and economic and democratic resilience. The leaders underlined their commitment to Ukraine’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany ahead of the G7 Leaders’ Summit. President Biden expressed appreciation for the Chancellor’s leadership of the G7, and the importance of coordinating responses to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, climate, and economic and democratic resilience. The leaders underlined their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, as well as their continued provision of military, economic, humanitarian, and diplomatic support to help Ukraine defend its democracy against Russian aggression. The leaders also discussed efforts to alleviate the impacts of Russia’s war in Ukraine on global food and energy security. The President welcomed Germany’s historic commitment to significantly boost defense spending and meet its NATO commitments, which will strengthen the Alliance’s long-term deterrence and defense posture. Finally, the leaders also discussed the challenges posed by China and our shared commitment to provide transparent and high-standard solutions to address global gaps in key infrastructure.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Chancellor Scholz of the Federal Republic of Germany Before Bilateral Meeting &#124; Krün,&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/26/remarks-by-president-biden-and-chancellor-scholz-of-the-federal-republic-of-germany-before-bilateral-meeting-krun-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56293</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[10:46 A.M. CEST&#160;CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&#160; So, it’s very good to have you here.&#160; (Inaudible) we can really do important things (inaudible) special time.&#160;PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, there’s a lot to do.&#160; And I want to compliment you on stepping up as you did when you became chancellor and moving in the way that you &#8212; had a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>10:46 A.M. CEST<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; So, it’s very good to have you here.&nbsp; (Inaudible) we can really do important things (inaudible) special time.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, there’s a lot to do.&nbsp; And I want to compliment you on stepping up as you did when you became chancellor and moving in the way that you &#8212; had a great impact on the rest of Europe to move, particularly as it related to Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you’re &#8212; you’re one of our fastest and closest allies in the world, and we got to make sure we have this &#8212; us all staying together.&nbsp; You know we’re going to continue working on the economic challenges we face, but I think we can get through all this &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; and come out stronger.<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; And the good message is that we all made it to stay united, which obviously Putin never expected.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; And that was in no small part because of you &#8212; no small part because of you.&nbsp; Seriously.&nbsp; Because there was a lot of discussion of whether or not, in the transition &#8212; how it was going to work.&nbsp; But you’ve done an incredible job.&nbsp; I want to thank you for it.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have to stay together &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; because Putin has been counting on, from the beginning, that somehow NATO would &#8212; and the G7 would splinter.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we haven’t, and we’re not going to.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we can’t let this aggression take the form it has and get away with it.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>10:49 A.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications John Kirby En Route Munich,&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/25/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-nsc-coordinator-for-strategic-communications-john-kirby-en-route-munich-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 18:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Munich, Germany 11:21 A.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Welcome to our trip to Europe &#8212; G7 and NATO. I’m going to pass it over to John Kirby, who is going to lay out what we’re going to be doing tomorrow and on this trip, and take any questions that you all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Munich, Germany</p>



<p>11:21 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Welcome to our trip to Europe &#8212; G7 and NATO. I’m going to pass it over to John Kirby, who is going to lay out what we’re going to be doing tomorrow and on this trip, and take any questions that you all may have. And then he’ll depart and then I’ll take over and take whatever other questions you have.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Hey, everybody. Just a couple of things right at the top here.</p>



<p>Obviously, we’re all horrified by the mass shooting in Oslo today, targeting the LGBTQI+ community there. And our ho- &#8212; our hearts, obviously, go out to all the families of &#8212; of the victims; the people of Norway, which is a tremendous ally; and of course the LGBTQI+ community there and around the world, quite frankly. And we stand in solidarity with our close ally, Norway, and the community in Norway and all who have been devastated by this senseless act.</p>



<p>I do want to add that we’ve been in touch with the Norwegian government to offer our condolences and &#8212; and also to offer any support that they might need as they continue to investigate this.</p>



<p>Now, for the G7, just &#8212; I just want to go over tomorrow, just the broad brushstrokes. I know you guys have been informed on background about all the things that we’re going to be doing.</p>



<p>But the President has got a very busy day. Before the summit starts, he’ll have a bilateral meeting with German Chancellor Olaf Scholz. They&#8217;ll do a signals check before the summit, and they&#8217;ll continue to closely coordinate, as they have been, on supporting Ukraine, holding Russia accountable, and, of course, other important priorities between the two of us.</p>



<p>President Biden obviously appreciates Germany&#8217;s close partnership. They are a strong NATO Ally. You saw us all come together when it come to &#8212; when it came to putting in place significant sanctions against Russia, making Putin pay cons- &#8212; cons- &#8212; costs for his invasion, and, of course, providing security assistance to Ukraine. And Germany very recently, as you know, stepped up in providing lethal weapon systems to Ukraine. So they have been very, very important in that.</p>



<p>After that bilat, the President will participate in the actual summit. The first session is going to be focused on the global economy. And you can be sure that leaders are going to be talking about core problems that are on the top of mind for all of us across the board, like rising prices, supply chain disruptions, all exacerbated by this war in Ukraine and by Mr. Putin&#8217;s decision.</p>



<p>But we should also recognize the U.S. is positioned to weather these challenges because of the strong economic leadership in the United States &#8212; President Biden specifically &#8212; and the policies and investments that he is putting in place.</p>



<p>The second session of the day is going to be on global infrastructure. And right after that, the President and other G7 leaders will formally launch their Global Infrastructure Partnership.</p>



<p>As we said before, and I spoke about this from the podium the other day, the G7 leaders have agreed to explore, last year, an alternative to infrastructure models that sell debt traps to low- and middle-income partner countries, and advance U.S. economic competitiveness and our national security.</p>



<p>So you’ll hear about how the President is moving forward on that line of effort tomorrow, along with other announcements on some new flagship pro- &#8212; projects. I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of them specifically today.</p>



<p>So, again, a very full day for the first day in &#8212; in Germany. And the President is very much looking forward to it.</p>



<p>Q John, looking ahead to the rest of the trip, can you read out any other bilats the President is expected to have? Will he meet with President Erdoğan of Turkey, particularly as the NATO accession issue comes up later in the week?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I think you can expect that the President will have multiple bilateral discussions. I mean, obviously, he&#8217;s starting out with the Chancellor &#8212; German Chancellor tomorrow. But I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the schedule. And we&#8217;ll &#8212; we&#8217;ll let you know as they come up and, of course, read them out to you. But I don&#8217;t have anything specific with any other leader today to talk about.</p>



<p>Q And then in terms of the economic meeting, are you expecting any deliverables out of that, particularly as we’ve seen rising inflation in the United States and around the world? Any agreements from the G7 leaders on that?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: You know, I think you will see some announcements coming out of these meetings. Again, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the specifics here. But as I mentioned right at the top, I mean, a large focus of the G7 and the leaders are going to be, you know, how to not only manage the challenges in the global economy as a result of Mr. Putin&#8217;s war, but how to also continue to hold Mr. Putin accountable and to make sure that &#8212; that they&#8217;re &#8212; that he is &#8212; and he &#8212; that &#8212; that he is being subjected to cost and consequences for what he&#8217;s doing.</p>



<p>So there will be some announcements. There will be some &#8212; some muscle movements. But I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of that right now.</p>



<p>Q Hey, John, on &#8212; on the &#8212; another topic in the global economy session: China &#8212; which you guys have said there will be strong language condemning their non-market practices. Should we expect any deliverables there or any actions taken? Or will this be essentially just the G7 condemning what has been condemned many times before?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Well, again, without getting ahead of deliverables &#8212; you&#8217;re going to get tired of hearing me say that, but it’s true &#8212;</p>



<p>Q Will there be any deliverables?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: But, look, China will be a significant focus here for the G7, and the impact that China&#8217;s coercive, economic practices, use of forced labor, intellectual theft &#8212; all those are front and center for the nations of the G7. And I think you&#8217;re going to see China very much at the forefront as the G7 goes on. But I don’t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of anything specific.</p>



<p>Q On &#8212; there is one thing you haven&#8217;t mentioned so far, which is climate change. Climate change is a big topic for the G7.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Yes.</p>



<p>Q But at the same time, so are rising energy costs. So how are you going to articulate those two, you know, challenges without watering down some climate commitments?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Well, there&#8217;s no watering down of climate commitments. I just talked about day one. I mean, climate is clearly going to be age- &#8212; on the agenda here at the G7. And the President has been a leader here on the search for clean energy solutions, because we&#8217;ve all seen, just in the last three months, the &#8212; the impact of &#8212; of reliance on fossil fuel and &#8212; and Russia&#8217;s weaponizing of that fossil fuel on &#8212; on the global economy.</p>



<p>Obviously, Americans are feeling this at home too, which is exactly why the President not only wants to, in the moment we&#8217;re in, hold Russia accountable for what he&#8217;s doing in Ukraine and try to find some relief &#8212; immediate relief. That&#8217;s why he pushed so hard and is an advocate for a federal gas tax holiday &#8212; to find some immediate relief &#8212; but also to move towards clean energy solutions that reduce the dependence on fossil fuel and reduce the dependence on Russia.</p>



<p>And so, even as we&#8217;re looking at long-term clean energy solutions, we&#8217;re also doing all we can to increase supply globally of things like natural gas and &#8212; and oil.</p>



<p>Q German Chancellor Scholz has signaled that he wants to roll back the G7’s commitment to end investment in fossil fuels overseas. Is that something that the United States would support on a temporary basis?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Yeah, I &#8212; I’m not going to get ahead of the discussions here at the G7. Our position last May was &#8212; and the President was clear &#8212; that &#8212; that he &#8212; he did not feel like these &#8212; these investments were the right course of action. I know of no such change to that policy.</p>



<p>Q And on the infrastructure initiative that&#8217;s clearly aimed at countering China&#8217;s Belt and Road Initiative, which is quite large in volume, do you have dollar figure in mind for how much you can &#8212; how much, you know, the United States and other allies can produce in terms of infrastructure?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I think you&#8217;ll hear more about this as the G7 goes on. And tomorrow is the day that they&#8217;re going to get together and talk about the global infrastructure partnership.</p>



<p>Again, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President here. But there are &#8212; I think you can expect them to explore a range of different opportunities and initiatives to allow low- and middle-income countries to address their own infrastructure and development problems better. And it&#8217;ll be a range; it&#8217;ll be a mix of federal funding, as well &#8212; as well as grants, as well as private-sector investments.</p>



<p>Again, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President, but I do think you&#8217;ll &#8212; tomorrow you&#8217;ll be able to get a much clearer picture of just how many opportunities there are and how many &#8212; how much resour- &#8212; how much resource &#8212; how many resources &#8212; let me try that again &#8212; G7 leaders are going to be willing to apply to that problem.</p>



<p>Q Can I follow up on the GIP and then move us over to the Mideast? So, first of all, on the GIP, the Global Infrastructure Partnership, what is the difference between that and Build Back Better World, other than the name? Are there any tangible differences?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: This is a months-long effort here by the administration to work with leaders around the world to try to come up with, again, more innovative and creative alternatives for these low- and middle-income countries to foster their own economic development and their infrastructure needs.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re much less worried about what it&#8217;s called than we are about what it does for these countries.</p>



<p>Q On Iran, Josep Borrell says talks might begin in, quote, “coming days.” Do we know when that might happen? And now that Iran is enriching uranium, are you worried that this round of talks might be like a make-or-break?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Well, we still &#8212; we still believe in getting back into the JCPOA. And I can&#8217;t speak to the status of where the negotiations are right now, but there&#8217;s &#8212; nothing has changed about our position that a nuclear deal is the best way to prevent Iran from achieving nuclear weapons status. And we want to get them back into compliance.</p>



<p>Q And then finally, on the Mideast trip, is Saudi-Israeli normalization a goal of this trip? And if so, what does that roadmap look like?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Let&#8217;s not get ahead of ourselves. That trip is not until next month. But the United States has been very clear that we support normalization between Israel and Arab countries in the region, that these are obviously discussions that these sovereign nations have to have, but we&#8217;re fully in support of the Abraham Accords and normalization efforts.</p>



<p>Q John, on Chinese &#8212; on the Chinese buying Russian oil and gas, will there be any discussion of that at the G7? And will there be any sort of acknowledgement of concern that President Putin still seems to be able to fund his war machine?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I think a big focus tomorrow is going to be &#8212; at least the first session &#8212; dedicated to the global economic issues here caused by the war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>And again, without getting ahead of ourselves here, I think leaders are going to be looking for ways to do two things: one, continue to hold Mr. Putin accountable and to increase the costs and consequences of his war on him and his economy; and, two, minimizing as much as possible the effect of these rising oil prices and the way he has weaponized energy on nations, particularly on the continent but also around the world.</p>



<p>Q India is also participating at the invitation of Germany. India is another one of the countries that is purchasing cheap Russian oil. Is there &#8212; are you at all &#8212; you know, are you seeing any movement on the part of India to sort of be more supportive of the global effort to hold Putin accountable?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: We’re glad that India is coming. There’s lots to discuss on the agenda with India. We have a very deep partnership with them, even in the defense world.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll let Indian leaders speak for themselves here, but obviously, what President Biden is focused on, what the administration is focused on is making sure that the costs keep rising for Mr. Putin, that it&#8217;s harder for him to wage war. And obviously, we want to see all nations participate in those kinds of efforts.</p>



<p>Q John, we know this is coming on the heels of the Dobbs decision. You know, Macron, Trudeau both put out statements. The Secretary of State put out a statement. Obviously, there&#8217;s interest outside of America in this decision. Is the President worried at all that this is going to take away or overshadow at all the G7? And what&#8217;s his message going to be to leaders that are wondering what, you know, America is doing in that decision?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: The President is not worried about that at all. There is, as I just said, just on day one alone &#8212; I mean, there is a robust agenda of issues here to talk about at the G7 and then follow on at the NATO Summit.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s real national security issues here that have to be discussed. And the President is not at all concerned that that the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision is going to take away from that at all.</p>



<p>And I think his message to leaders around the world is exactly the same message that he gave to the American people yesterday.</p>



<p>Q Can I go back to Russian oil for a second, though? That price cap on Russian oil that Secretary Yellen has been negotiating or pushing for &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t want to get ahead of deliverables, but maybe you can give us a hint of how confident you are that the leaders will endorse &#8212; all the leaders, because there was some, you know, holdouts &#8212; all leaders will endorse this at the summit.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I think what I can tell you is that all leaders are &#8212; we believe all leaders are going to be committed to those two things that I mentioned before: one, continuing to hold Mr. Putin accountable and make it even more painful for him to prosecute this war, as well as looking for ways to minimize the effect of rising oil prices and the profits that Mr. Putin continues to get from those oil prices on other nations around the world, including the United States.</p>



<p>Q John, are you satisfied with the amount of weapons that countries that have stocks of older-generation weapons have been giving to Ukraine? I mean, the U.S. is drawing down its stocks of weapons that can be transferred to Ukraine, on which they can be trained, but other countries have more stocks.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: So, a couple of things there. Two weeks ago, the Secretary of Defense held another Ukraine Contact Group, this time in Brussels &#8212; 50 nations. That&#8217;s the most that we&#8217;ve ever done, and we&#8217;ve had three iterations. Fifty nations showed up &#8212; not just from Europe, not just NATO Allies, but from around the world &#8212; Middle East and the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>And a large number of those nations are contributing security assistance, weapons, to Ukraine. Now, they&#8217;re doing what they can. Every nation has to make a decision about what they can afford to provide because they have their own national security needs. But I think &#8212; you know, I&#8217;d point you back to what Secretary Austin said at the end of that. I mean, it was impressive to see how many nations are willing to pull down from their own inventories or even to contract for additional systems.</p>



<p>Now, look, in the very early weeks of the war, there was a significant and, I think, right focus on making sure that Ukraine was getting systems that they were trained on, knew how to use, had them in their inventory already &#8212; ex-Soviet stuff. There&#8217;s still a need for that. I mean, they still are using those systems.</p>



<p>And so, Secretary Austin is &#8212; why he’s doing the Contact Group is to continue to talk to nations around the world to see what else they can provide.</p>



<p>But also now, because the war is now stretched into its third month, it&#8217;s becoming much more about artillery in the Donbas, the long-range fires. The United States has been willing to step up and provide other Western or American systems to Ukraine, to allow them to carry on in the Donbas. And that requires a little bit of training, right? That means you got to take some Ukrainian soldiers out of the fight.</p>



<p>So we want to make sure that we strike the right balance here, that they&#8217;re getting systems that they&#8217;re used to as well as systems that they need, without unnecessarily decrementing their combat readiness in the field.</p>



<p>But every nation that&#8217;s providing stuff, they&#8217;ve got to do it in accordance with their own national security interests as well. And I would say the short answer to your question is: Yes. We&#8217;re impressed, we&#8217;re grateful, we&#8217;re satisfied that nations around the world, not just &#8212; not just in the region, are coming forward and providing Ukraine as much as they can.</p>



<p>And there&#8217;s &#8212; and look, this is going to be an iterative, ongoing conversation. We&#8217;re going to continue to have these contact groups. We&#8217;re going to continue to talk to nations. We&#8217;re obviously going to continue to talk to Ukrainians about what they need every day.</p>



<p>Q A question on natural gas, maybe. Gazprom has started reducing its supply to Europe and Germany. And Germany has warned that it could, you know, interfere with their plans to replenish the reserve before winter.</p>



<p>So, two questions. First, do you believe the Russians when they say this is &#8212; this cuts are for technical reasons? And second question: Is there anything the United States can do right now or in the coming weeks to help the Europeans?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I won&#8217;t &#8212; well, on the first question, we think this is just a piece of Mr. Putin’s willingness to weaponize now energy. And I don&#8217;t think we take any Russian claim at face value here with respect to what&#8217;s going on.</p>



<p>And I &#8212; again, I think &#8212; I won&#8217;t get ahead of where we&#8217;re going on G7, but, clearly, alternative energy is going to be on the docket here for the next couple of days.</p>



<p>I got to go. I’m going to let Karine finish.</p>



<p>Q John, (inaudible) food security?</p>



<p>Q A follow-up on landmines?</p>



<p>Q Food security obviously a huge &#8212; food security &#8212; getting the grain out. Are you expecting any &#8212; what’s the nature of the conversations between the U.S. government and Russian counterparts about trying to secure ways of getting that grain out? Does that place at the U.N.? Is that taking place bilaterally?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: So, I know of no bilateral discussions with the Russians on food security. But we are obviously &#8212; it will be on the agenda here at the G7. We’re working very hard with allies and partners to try to get that grain out of Ukraine. We’ve been able to increase shipments of it through the West by rail. But, obviously, that&#8217;s not the most efficient way to do this. It&#8217;s a perishable commodity.</p>



<p>We&#8217;d like to see the blockade, which is essentially in place by the Russians in the Black Sea, lifted. We know that Turkey is talking to Russia about some options there. We welcome those efforts.</p>



<p>But, you know, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s very much on President Biden’s mind.</p>



<p>Q A landmine question. Just very quickly: With the U.S. &#8212; the new U.S. policy on landmines, does this change the weapons that are going to be sent to Ukraine? Because you were sending a number of Claymore mines. And are you satisfied that those munitions have been used responsibly and in accordance with the law by Ukrainian soldiers?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I know of no shipments of U.S. Claymore mines to Ukraine. But separate and distinct, the Claymore mines are not covered by the Ottawa Convention because they have to be triggered with a person. They’re &#8212; they’re &#8212; the way they&#8217;re constructed is they have to be manually triggered by an operator, so they are not subject to the Ottawa Convention.</p>



<p>Okay? Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>Q Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: All right. I don&#8217;t have anything else. I don&#8217;t have anything as a topper, so shoot away. Go.</p>



<p>Q Karine, the White House has talked a lot in the last six months, longer, about preparing for the fall of Roe. On the Supreme Court ruling yesterday, the President didn&#8217;t announce any executive actions. He didn&#8217;t announce any specific plans or proposals on his part to try to protect women&#8217;s rights to abortion, both &#8212; so, why is there a seeming lack of urgency from the President on this issue?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: So, I &#8212; Zeke, I have to tell you, I disagree with the premise of your question there. There’s been a lot of urgency from this President and from this White House on how &#8212; on the next steps of &#8212; especially now that we know that the decision was made yesterday.</p>



<p>Look, the President &#8212; two hours after we learned about the decision, the President gave a &#8212; gave remarks &#8212; powerful, passionate remarks to the American public and laid out two concrete steps on how to move forward &#8212; how to move forward and really fight for women&#8217;s rights and women&#8217;s freedom.</p>



<p>And those two concrete steps that he laid out &#8212; one had to deal with HHS and making sure that we make FDA-approved medication available to women and protect that right; the other one was he gave his executive authority to the Department of Justice to make sure that we defend women who travel to &#8212; as they make decisions on their own healthcare.</p>



<p>And those two are very concrete, big steps. I know those &#8212; that&#8217;s using his executive authority. I know people are asking about executive actions. The President is going to continue to find solutions. He&#8217;s going to continue to talk to leading groups. He&#8217;s going to continue to talk to legal experts on what he can do from his &#8212; you know, his own executive perch, if you will.</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s going to &#8212; the conversation is going to continue to happen. That&#8217;s not going to stop.</p>



<p>I do want to share what the group &#8212; the offices are in the White House and who&#8217;s been involved with this, because it&#8217;s been around-the-clock type of response in looking into how to move forward.</p>



<p>So, the White House senior officials, including from the Gender Policy Council, Office of Public Engagement, Office of Intergovernmental Affairs, Office of Political Strategy and Outreach, and the Office of the Vice President engage in dozens of formal meetings and private conversations on reproductive rights with over 200 stakeholders, including the leadl- &#8212; leading national organizations fighting to protect women&#8217;s constitutional right to keep her &#8212; her healthcare decisions to herself and doctors.</p>



<p>We have met with patients, medical providers, policy and legal experts, as I just mentioned, women&#8217;s rights groups and reproductive rights advocates, state legislators, faith leaders, political figures, and private sectors. And we have been doing that since we learned about the leaked document.</p>



<p>So, this has been a priority for this administration. And we will continue to see what else we can do.</p>



<p>Q Karine, just to follow up on that real quick: The challenge of that &#8212; the President yesterday announced that the administration will fight for those things &#8212; traveling across state lines and the FDA-approved medication for abortion &#8212; except, right now, in a number of states, those actions are punishable by civil or lega- &#8212; or criminal penalties, depending on the specific states and if the law is there.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s not &#8212; does the President believe that his sort of saying that HHS or the Department of Justice will fight for it means these women should do it? If women were to take those drugs right now, (inaudible) if somebody were to help them travel across state lines in some states, that could expose them to significant liability today. What’s the President doing to protect them right now?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: So that’s why he’s asked the Department of Justice to step in. Look, this is not &#8212;</p>



<p>Q (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: So, you know, state laws restricting the right to travel will undoubtedly be challenged &#8212; right? &#8212; in court. So that is &#8212; we understand. So, the DOJ will look to support the right to travel in appropriate cases.</p>



<p>Look, the Attorney General’s statement yesterday made it clear that the &#8212; that bedrock of constitutional principles support women’s freedom to seek care in states where abortion remains legal. So, they &#8212; they are going to step in where they can to defend women who may have to make decisions for themselves &#8212; should be making decisions for theirselves on their health.</p>



<p>So that is the executive authority that the President used, and that is what the Department of Justice laid out in a very long statement that they did yesterday on how they’re going to go about that.</p>



<p>Look, this is &#8212; you know, this is a scary time. We understand that. What happened yesterday with the decision from the Supreme Court is un- &#8212; is extreme. That decision is extreme.</p>



<p>This is about a constitutional right that was provided by the Supreme Court almost 50 years ago. And &#8212; and it was done &#8212; the judge that wrote that decision almost 50 years ago &#8212; it was a 7-2 decision &#8212; that was done by a judge who was appointed by President Nixon.</p>



<p>So, this &#8212; this constitutional right has been around, you know, with Democratic presidents and Republican presidents. And the President understands that we got to continue to fight.</p>



<p>So, the other part that we are trying to say as well is, yes, the President can use executive authority. We can look to see what other &#8212; what executive action we can take.</p>



<p>But the reality is we have to get Congress to act to restore Roe, to make it law of the land.</p>



<p>And if that can&#8217;t happen, the American public has to use their voice. And in light of this decision, they have to use their voice at the ballot box. And this is how we can turn this around.</p>



<p>But yesterday, again, he laid out two concrete solutions &#8212; or two concrete steps, I should say &#8212; to move forward. And we&#8217;re going to continue to see what else we can do.</p>



<p>Q A lot of people watching this ruling are concerned that it could be a slippery slope leading to limited access to contraception and to other rights that &#8212; that Americans currently enjoy. Is the White House concerned about that? And if so, how are you preparing and what are you going to do?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: We are concerned about that. If you look at what &#8212; what Justice Thomas said &#8212; he wrote expli- &#8212; explicitly that “In future cases, we should reconsider all of this Court&#8217;s substantive due process precedents.”</p>



<p>So make no mistake: Congressional &#8212; congressional Republicans have &#8212; have made it clear; Republican leaders &#8212; national Republican leaders have made it clear they are going to go after &#8212; they&#8217;re going to go after women&#8217;s reproductive healthcare across the country and beyond. That&#8217;s what we heard from them yesterday.</p>



<p>And so, we&#8217;re going to continue to stand up. We&#8217;re going to continue to fight against that. We&#8217;re going to continue to tell people to use their voice.</p>



<p>And so, look, the way that we &#8212; again, the way that we get to a solution here, the way that we get to really resolving this is for Congress to act.</p>



<p>Yes, the President is going to continue to look at solutions. He&#8217;s going to continue to figure out what else we can do, continue to talking to groups, getting that legal &#8212; legal expertise on what he can do from &#8212; from his executive authority.</p>



<p>But we have to make sure that &#8212; the American public has to make sure that they use their voice. And not only that, the decision that &#8212; that they made &#8212; the decision that the Court made on Roe v. Wade is out of step. It’s out of step with majority of the American public. A majority of the American public support Roe &#8212; support Roe v. Wade.</p>



<p>Q Karine, the President &#8212; you know, you talk about bringing the President out on the road, taking him on the road; he likes to connect with the American people. Will he dedicate some travel specifically to this issue, to reach out to young voters, to women who are outraged and &#8212; and frustrated? Where will he go? What are &#8212; you know, what are some of the messages that he could be bringing? And how soon could we see him start to take those kinds of trips?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I don&#8217;t have anything to read out to you specifically on a strategy &#8212; a strategic strategy around the decision that was made by the Court yesterday. But what I can say, and the President spoke about this very forcefully: He vehemently disagrees with the decision that the Court made yesterday.</p>



<p>He&#8217;s going to continue to fight for women&#8217;s rights. He&#8217;s going to continue to fight for freedom &#8212; for their freedom. And also, even when we heard the leaked decision &#8212; this is kind of to your question &#8212; a couple of weeks ago, he had warned that it wouldn&#8217;t &#8212; they would not just stop at women&#8217;s &#8212; women&#8217;s reproductive rights. He warned that.</p>



<p>And now, what we saw from Judge Thomas should be chilling. It should be very chilling to people. But this is an opportunity to take action. And that&#8217;s what the President did yesterday. He did a call to action for the American public.</p>



<p>Q (Inaudible) &#8212; I mean, I was asking about trips, travel. Any trips, travel?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I just don&#8217;t have anything to &#8212; to lay out for you at this time. Clearly, we&#8217;re going to the G7 and NATO. It&#8217;s going to be for the next five days. We&#8217;ll get back on Thursday. And ma- &#8212; hopefully after that, we&#8217;ll have more to share on specific travel. Just right now, I don&#8217;t have anything to lay out.</p>



<p>Q Karine, you just said that the decision of the Supreme Court does not reflect what the American &#8212; the majority of Americans want. And polls also show that, you know, the &#8212; the credibility of the &#8212; the opinion that Americans have after the Supreme Court is now very poor. So is it time, in the President&#8217;s view, to think about reforming the Court? And if so, what changes would he like to see?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: So, I know I&#8217;ve &#8212; I’ve been asked &#8212; I was asked this question yesterday, and I&#8217;ve been asked it before &#8212; and I think the President himself &#8212; about doing &#8212; about expanding the Court. That is something that the President does not agree with. That is not something that he wants to do.</p>



<p>There was a commission that was put together about how to potentially move forward with the Court &#8212; reform the Court. I don&#8217;t have anything more to share from any &#8212; any final decision that the President has made.</p>



<p>I do want to say, though &#8212; you know, we talk about the popul- &#8212; I was talking about the popularity of how much Americans support Roe v. Wade. Never &#8212; this is the &#8212; this is the most support that Roe &#8212; Roe v. Wade has gotten ever.</p>



<p>I mean, it is &#8212; it has such a majority popularity. And so for the Court to have made this extreme ruling is so out of step. It’s so out of step not only with this decision, but it&#8217;s also so out of step with the Constitution.</p>



<p>Q Karine, the fact that you haven&#8217;t yet identified, even after this leaked decision, executive actions that you could take, does that sort of just reflect that there isn&#8217;t anything more, even after more talks with legal scholars, that you can do on this?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I think the way &#8212; I think the way to look at this &#8212; he did use executive authority. And that matters &#8212; right? &#8212; because he&#8217;s the President of the United States and using executive authorities to protect, you know, contraception for women and make sure they have that accessible to them &#8212; FDA-approved medication &#8212; is very important. I think that is something that&#8217;s going to be meaningful for many, many women across the country.</p>



<p>And secondly, to be able to have the DOJ defend women who are going to have to now travel to get &#8212; you know, after they make decisions on their own &#8212; their own health decision, I think, is actually really important. And again, we talked to legal experts about this.</p>



<p>We talked to other leading &#8212; leading groups in the &#8212; reproductive rights organizations. And so, these are two things that we thought were two concrete steps.</p>



<p>And so, you know, this is, again, a &#8212; first steps. We&#8217;re going to continue to see what else we can do.</p>



<p>But I guess what I&#8217;m trying to say about the executive actions is that nothing could make &#8212; could fill the hole that this decision has made with now upending Roe, which is what the Court did. The only way to make that whole again is for Congress to act, is Congress to restore Roe and make it a &#8212; you know, a law of the land. That is actually the best way to do that.</p>



<p>Q And on that, what is the President&#8217;s reform on &#8212; position on filibuster reform? He says, you know, “Elect more Democrats.” Let&#8217;s say he got two more Democrats in the Senate who would be okay with killing the filibuster on this issue so he had 50. Would he then support that stance?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, look, if we got more &#8212; more members of Congress, more &#8212; more members of Congress who support Roe, then the thinking would be that we would be able to pass a law to get that done. I don&#8217;t think the &#8212; I don&#8217;t think the filibuster would play a role there.</p>



<p>But that&#8217;s what we have to do. We got to make sure that we elect more members, or we have more members come in to &#8212; come in to Congress that can actually make a difference here.</p>



<p>I’ve got to be careful, because I can&#8217;t talk about &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; elec- &#8212; as you know. So I’ve got to be careful of what I say.</p>



<p>But the point that I&#8217;m making is: I hear &#8212; I hear you &#8212; I hear your point about the filibuster. But I think if &#8212; if we&#8217;re able to &#8212; if Americans are able to use their voice at the ballot box, bring in more members into Congress that support this issue, then there is movement that we can make. There is a way that we can restore Roe. And that is the most important thing that we can do.</p>



<p>Yes, can the President use &#8212; continue to use executive authority? We will see what else he can do. But, honestly, to fill that hole, we got to &#8212; we got to take action. And that&#8217;s what the President was trying to do.</p>



<p>Q Karine, can I ask you an Afghanistan question? Sorry. So the earthquake there has caused so much damage. And there&#8217;s some movement, again, for people to &#8212; to please release some of those funds, some of the central bank currency funds. Can you say what the U.S. position is on that and whether there&#8217;s any movement on that in light of the humanitarian catastrophe?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Are you talking about the &#8212; the assets in Ukraine? Yeah.</p>



<p>Q The assets &#8212; yeah. Not in Ukraine, in Afghanistan.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I’m sorry, I meant to say Afghanistan. There&#8217;s so much going on in the world. I apologize.</p>



<p>So, in signing an executive order several months ago, the President took a significant step to preserve these funds and ensure they go toward benefiting the people of Afghanistan.</p>



<p>If the President hadn’t taken this action, the funds would have remained tied up for years. So we are energized across the U.S. government &#8212; energized across the U.S. government to get these funds moving.</p>



<p>We are urgently working to address complicated questions about the use of these funds to ensure they benefit the people of Afghanistan and not &#8212; not the Taliban. So that is a focus of ours.</p>



<p>But the President is not going to wait to help the people of Afghanistan recover and rebuild their &#8212; from their devastating earthquake, as I mentioned much earlier in the week.</p>



<p>USAID and our partner humanitarian organizations are already providing immediate assistance on the ground where it&#8217;s needed the most.</p>



<p>Q Karine, if I could, back on the abortion issue, what do you think the decision means for the standing of the U.S. overseas, particularly in parts of the world where you&#8217;re trying to promote women&#8217;s rights?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, it&#8217;s a very good question, because what we saw &#8212; again, what we saw yesterday was extreme. It was an extreme decision on &#8212; on the American public&#8217;s constitutional right &#8212; a right that was given by that same Court almost 50 years ago.</p>



<p>You know, the &#8212; the administration has restored its commitment to advance women&#8217;s health both at home and abroad, revoking harmful global gag rule, as you know, and restoring funding to the United Nations Population Fund.</p>



<p>This administration will continue its work to advance women&#8217;s health and reproductive rights around the world, consistently with existing law. So we are going to continue to have those relationships, those leader-leader relationships that the President has.</p>



<p>Look, we&#8217;ve heard from a lot of the leaders already. I know some of them have put out statements &#8212; very vocal &#8212; about what they have seen from this decision in the last 12 &#8212; I’m losing track of time &#8212; 12, 24 hours &#8212; and &#8212; and giving &#8212; offering support to the American people.</p>



<p>But this is not going to &#8212; I don&#8217;t think this stops the work that the President is going to do or wants to do or looking to do with leaders.</p>



<p>Q But is it harder to get the message across if other parts of the world are going to turn around and say, “Well, look what&#8217;s happening in your own backyard”?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I &#8212; I mean, I don’t think it’s &#8212; I don’t think it’s necessarily harder. The President &#8212; the President has his own career and reputation to stand on. Right? He has been a senator, he has been a Vice President, and he has been a President that has been able to unify the country &#8212; not the country, the world, especially as we look at what is happening in Ukraine with Russia&#8217;s invasion.</p>



<p>So, you know, we&#8217;re going to G7. We&#8217;re going to NATO. People have said that NATO is the &#8212; is the most unified that they&#8217;ve ever seen, at least in modern times, in most recent times. And a lot of that was due to this &#8212; due to this President. I don&#8217;t think that goes away. I don&#8217;t think that does at all.</p>



<p>So, if anything, it just highlights the work that needs to continue to be done.</p>



<p>Q The DNC Chairman yesterday called the Supreme Court “illegitimate” after the decision. One, is that something that the President agrees with? And two, does he think that that&#8217;s a winning message for the Democrats going into 2022?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: So I can&#8217;t speak for the DNC. I can only speak for the President. And the President &#8212; you know, when the President commented about the decision, about the Court&#8217;s ruling, it was about the decision. He sees the Court, obviously, as legitimate. And he respects the Court.</p>



<p>He does believe that this particular ruling that they &#8212; that they made yesterday is extreme and is out of step. And he is going to continue to call that out.</p>



<p>But, you know, this is a President that was the Chair of the Judiciary Committee for &#8212; for many, many years when he was a senator. He oversaw many &#8212; many nominations for the Supreme Court. It is a court that he highly respects, but it is &#8212; it should be &#8212; right? &#8212; this is America &#8212; we should be able to speak out or speak &#8212; or have a &#8212; you know, have a disagreement.</p>



<p>And this is not just a disagreement, obviously, but this is what we saw. That decision was indeed stunning, and it was extreme and incredibly unfortunate. It is going to devastate so many lives, taking that constitutional right away for so many people across the country.</p>



<p>Q Karine, you said a couple of times that the Court gave the right to an abortion to women 50 years ago.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: But what I mean is that &#8212; what I mean is that they gave that constitutional right. Right? When that seven &#8212; 7-2 decision, Roe v. Wade, it was a constitutional right. Roe v. Wade was a constitutional right that was provided almost 50 years ago, and they took that constitutional right away.</p>



<p>Q So the President doesn&#8217;t believe that a right to abortion is in &#8212; is sort of &#8212; is built on the right to privacy enshrined in the Constitution, and ratification is only &#8212; it only came about at Roe?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, the President believes in pri- &#8212; in women’s privacy. He believes in a woman&#8217;s consti- &#8212; in a woman&#8217;s right to make their own choice. He believes that they should have their own freedoms to make their own decision.</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re saying is that decision that was made is going to &#8212; with that decision, things are going to, across the country, change so quickly because of that decision in states. And that is unacceptable.</p>



<p>If you think about, in some states, women&#8217;s &#8212; women will not be able to make a decision on how to protect their own lives. If you are a woman or a girl and you are raped, you will have to bear your child&#8217;s rapist [rapist’s child]. If you are a doctor, you could be criminalized for providing care. I mean, that is &#8211;those are the things that he spoke to himself directly in his speech.</p>



<p>And so he&#8217;s going to continue to fight for women&#8217;s rights. He&#8217;s going to continue to fight for their freedom. And he&#8217;s going to see what else he can do, as an executive authority, to see what other steps that we can do to move forward in protecting women.</p>



<p>Q Karine, you mentioned that the President has managed to rally NATO Allies and create unity overseas, but he clearly hasn’t in the United States. Is he frustrated by that? Is he going to be trying anything new ahead of the midterms?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: No, that’s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a good question. Look, when the President decided to run in 2019 &#8212; of April of 2019, he talked about redeeming the soul of this nation. Right? And two years prior to that, we saw what happened in Charlottesville. We saw the ugliness that was marching down the streets of Charlottesville. And he wrote &#8212; he wrote an op-ed and talked about that very personally. And when there was an opportunity for him to do something about that in a real profound way, he decided to run for President.</p>



<p>And in many ways &#8212; you know, he won with 81 million votes. Many people elected him because they believed he could bring the country together. And I think what the President understands is that we are in a very divided, politicized political environment at this time, and it&#8217;s going to take a lot more work. We are just not there yet.</p>



<p>Q Does he have any new strategies to achieve that? Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Well, he&#8217;s going to &#8212; I think he&#8217;s going to &#8212; look, let me &#8212; let&#8217;s step back for a second. We were able &#8212; this morning, the President was able to do something that hadn&#8217;t been done in almost 30 years, which is sign a bipartisan gun reform legislation.</p>



<p>So both sides were able to come together and really address an epidemic in this country. That matters, I think. And so he signed that into law. And it’s &#8212; and it’s &#8212; and then, hopefully, it will save lives.</p>



<p>And so, you know, when it comes to, you know, other &#8212; other issues that we see around the country, yeah, there&#8217;s going to be a lot of work that needs to be done. There&#8217;s going to be still &#8212; we still need to figure out how we&#8217;re going to bring the country together. This is not something that he&#8217;s not aware of; he&#8217;s very clearly aware of that.</p>



<p>And so he&#8217;s going to continue to have to do the work as President.</p>



<p>Q Karine, there&#8217;s evidence showing that states are starting to segregate along political lines. Are you concerned that this decision could accelerate that move; that, in essence, the trigger states and states that follow on &#8212; I mean, there&#8217;s talk about something like 26 states could eventually pass such laws. Are you concerned that we could see a country that is geographically divided along these lines, where, basically, states that ban abortion and punish women are fundamentally more Republican and that you see an outflow, a kind of a great migration out of people who are more progressive and liberally minded?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, look, the President said this yesterday: We are &#8212; we are going to see some nightmare scenarios. These &#8212; we&#8217;re going to see some devastating consequences because of the decision that the Court made.</p>



<p>That is not hypothetical. That is just the facts as you look across the states and also the legislation that have been coming out, the bills have been coming out, out of the state &#8212; the state houses.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why the President made it very clear yesterday that he&#8217;s going to continue to fight. He&#8217;s going to continue to call for action as it relates to Congress, as it relates to the American public using their voice at the ballot box. And he&#8217;s going to continue to talk to leading organizations &#8212; and not just him, but also his team. I laid out offices that have been working since day one of the leaked document. And we&#8217;re going to see what else we can do.</p>



<p>But we believe &#8212; we put forward two concrete steps. You know, we&#8217;re going to try to see what else we can do. But, you know, the President talked about this: We are going to see some nightmare scenarios, sadly, because of this decision. I mean, this is a 50 &#8212; almost 50-year &#8212; almost five-decade decision that has been overturned and upended.</p>



<p>Q Karine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Yeah.</p>



<p>Q One more on the gas tax holiday. Since the President called on Congress on Wednesday, has there been any movement or indication whatsoever that Congress is going to prioritize that when they&#8217;re back from recess? It doesn&#8217;t really seem like the important folks on the Hill are where you are on this. So I&#8217;m just trying to figure out how you&#8217;re going to try to get this done.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, let &#8212; just let me just reiterate: The President &#8212; you know, the President called for the suspension of federal gas tax, a gas tax &#8212; gas tax holiday, because he felt that this was the most simplest, easiest way to deal with a &#8212; an issue for the American public of high gas prices at the pump. And he felt &#8212; he felt that 90 days was, you know, an easy thing to do, because the American public &#8212; you know, this is the time that they drive the most: during the summer.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re still talking to &#8212; to answer your question, we’re still talking to Congress. I don&#8217;t have anything more to share with you as &#8212; as far as a priority for them. We&#8217;re going to have this conversation.</p>



<p>But the President made very clear what he believed this could do and giving that little bit of breathing room for the Americans as they travel, as they go to work, as they are trying to live their lives every day, especially this summer when it&#8217;s incredibly active.</p>



<p>Q Don&#8217;t you risk missing that window, I mean, given that, you know, Congress is out now? And &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, here’s the thing: Look, Congress can act on this anytime. It&#8217;s actually very simple to do.</p>



<p>Q If they want to.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: If &#8212; well, we&#8217;re going to continue to have that conversation and, you know, see if we can make that a priority. But this is not a difficult thing to do. That&#8217;s why we keep saying it&#8217;s straightforward and easy. It is actually not a difficult thing to do, and we&#8217;re going to continue to call on them to do (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q Just one on abortion &#8212;</p>



<p>Q The President’s Sherpa is &#8212;</p>



<p>Q Sorry. Karine, just some activists are pushing for abortion clinics to be built on federal lands in conservative states. Is this an option that the administration is considering?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I just don&#8217;t have anything else to share. We&#8217;re going to continue to look at what other options we have. I don&#8217;t have anything to share on that specific question.</p>



<p>Q Karine, one last one &#8212;</p>



<p>Q The President’s &#8212;</p>



<p>Q When the President went to the G7 a year ago, he came with ambitious COVID vaccine donation goals for the rest of the world. The U.S. is falling short on that because it doesn&#8217;t have the money to help countries administer and transport and store those vaccines safely.</p>



<p>Is the President worried that by failing to meet those commitments &#8212; in part because of Congress, in part because of other reasons &#8212; that U.S. credibility on the global stage around public health will be called into question?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, look, I’d have to look into where we are specifically on our international assistance on COVID. I know that we have been the country that&#8217;s provided the most &#8212; a leader &#8212; than any other country. It is a commitment. It has come up in every international trip that he&#8217;s had. COVID has always been a part of the agenda.</p>



<p>But I would disagree with &#8212; with your premise of the question.</p>



<p>Look, the President has &#8212; if you look at where we are currently as a country and the economic strengths that we have, a lot of &#8212; a lot of that is because of what the President did on day one, which is present a comprehensive strategy to get people vaccinated.</p>



<p>And now we have more than 200 million people who are vaccinated. We&#8217;re getting zero to five vaccinated. It&#8217;s about 18- &#8212; you know, there’s, zero to five, 18 million young people. The hope is to do everything that we can to get vaccinated.</p>



<p>So, if anything, he has shown leadership right here in this country on everything that he has done to make sure that &#8212; that folks &#8212; that the American public have access to vaccines and boosters. And so, we have shown our leadership here.</p>



<p>I can see what else I have for you on where we are with conversations at the G7 and our deliverables on this subject particularly. But this has always been part of an agenda in every &#8212; every trip that he&#8217;s done. And I think the President, we believe, and I don&#8217;t &#8212; and I would argue others across the globe believe, that we have been a leader in this.</p>



<p>Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>12:11 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Oslo&#160;Shooting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/25/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-oslo-shooting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 18:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The horrific shooting in Norway this morning has been felt around the world. The United States strongly condemns this act of terror. We stand in solidarity with the families of the victims, the diverse and strong LGBTQI+ community of Oslo, our close NATO ally Norway, and all who have been devastated by this senseless act. The United States&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The horrific shooting in Norway this morning has been felt around the world. The United States strongly condemns this act of terror. We stand in solidarity with the families of the victims, the diverse and strong LGBTQI+ community of Oslo, our close NATO ally Norway, and all who have been devastated by this senseless act. The United States has been in touch with the Norwegian government and offered to provide assistance. We remain committed to continuing to partner with Norway to advance a more equitable and just world for all, free from violence and discrimination.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Signing of S.2938, the Bipartisan Safer Communities&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/25/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-s-2938-the-bipartisan-safer-communities-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 15:11:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 8:36 A.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning, folks.&#160; Yesterday, I spoke about the Supreme Court’s shocking decision striking down Roe v. Wade.&#160; We’ve had a lot of discussion about that in our whole household.&#160; We think it’s a &#8212; anyway. Jill and I know how painful and devastating a decision is for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>8:36 A.M. EDT<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning, folks.&nbsp; Yesterday, I spoke about the Supreme Court’s shocking decision striking down Roe v. Wade.&nbsp; We’ve had a lot of discussion about that in our whole household.&nbsp; We think it’s a &#8212; anyway.</p>



<p>Jill and I know how painful and devastating a decision is for so many Americans &#8212; and I mean so many Americans.&nbsp; The decision is implemented by states.&nbsp; My administration is going to focus on how they administer it and whether or not they violate other laws, like deciding to not allow people across state lines to get public health services.&nbsp; And we’re going to take actions to protect women&#8217;s rights and reproductive health.</p>



<p>This morning, though, I&#8217;m here &#8212; we&#8217;re here to &#8212; on a critical issue: gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I&#8217;m about to sign into law a bipartisan safety legi- &#8212; gun safety legislation.&nbsp; And time is of the essence.&nbsp; Lives will be saved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When we return from Europe, Jill and I will be hosting an event in the White House on July 11th to mark this historic achievement with members who voted for these families and the families who, in fact, were victimized by the gun shooting that we&#8217;ve seen this so &#8212; so incredible to see so much of it of late.</p>



<p>And advocates have worked really hard to do something about it.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been at this work for a long, long time, and I know how hard it is, and I know what it takes to get it done.&nbsp; It was there &#8212; I was there 30 years ago, the last time this nation passed meaningful gun safety laws.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m here today for the most significant law to be passed since then, since &#8212; for the last 30 years.</p>



<p>I&#8217;d like to thank the leaders and members of the House and Senate for working together to get this done.&nbsp; I especially want to thank the families that Jill and I &#8212; many of whom we sat with for hours on end across the country.&nbsp; So many we&#8217;ve gotten to know who lost their souls and &#8212; to an epidemic of gun violence.&nbsp; They lost their child, their husband, their wife.&nbsp; Nothing is going to fill that void in their hearts, but they led the way so other families will not have the experience and the pain and trauma that they had to live through.</p>



<p>From Columbine to Sandy Hook, to Charleston, Orlando, Las Vegas, Parkland, El Paso, Atlanta, Buffalo, Uvalde, and for the shootings that happen every day in the streets that are mass shootings &#8212; and we don&#8217;t even hear about them, the number of people killed every day in the streets &#8212; their message to us was: “Do something.”&nbsp; How many times we heard that?&nbsp; “Just do something.”&nbsp; For God&#8217;s sake, just do something.</p>



<p>Well, today, we did.&nbsp; While this bill doesn&#8217;t do everything I want, it does include actions I&#8217;ve long called for that are going to save lives.&nbsp; It funds crisis intervention, including red-flag laws.&nbsp; It keeps guns out of the hands of people who are a danger to themselves and to others.&nbsp; And it finally closes what is known as the “boyfriend loophole.”&nbsp; So if you assault your boyfriend or girlfriend, you can&#8217;t buy a gun or own a gun.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It requires young people ages 18 to 21 to undergo enhanced background checks.&nbsp; It includes the first-ever federal law that makes gun trafficking and straw purchases distinct federal crimes for the first time.&nbsp; It clarifies who needs to register as a federally licensed gun dealer, and run background checks before selling a single weapon.</p>



<p>You know, this is &#8212; also provides historic funding to address the youth mental health crisis in this country, especially &#8212; especially the trauma experienced by the survivors of this gun violence.</p>



<p>Look, you know, it invests in antiviolence programs that work &#8212; that work directly with the people who are most likely to commit these crimes or become victims of gun crimes.&nbsp; Today, we say more than “enough.”&nbsp; We say more than “enough.”&nbsp; It&#8217;s time &#8212; when it seems impossible to get anything done in Washington, we are doing something consequential.&nbsp; If we can reach compromise on guns, we ought to be able to reach compromise in other critical issues, from veterans’ healthcare to cutting-edge American innovation, and so much more.</p>



<p>I know there&#8217;s much more work to do, and I&#8217;m never going to give up.&nbsp; But this is a monumental day.&nbsp; God bless us with the strength to continue to work to get the work that’s left undone done, and the lives lost that can&#8217;t be saved that obviously are gone but will be an inspiration for us to do more.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m now going to sign this bill into law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(The bill is signed.)</p>



<p>God willing, it’s going to save a lot of lives.&nbsp; Thank you all so very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, will you take a couple questions?</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Congratulations.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>I have a helicopter waiting for me to take off.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have plenty of time to talk about a lot of this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think the Supreme Court is broken, in your view?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think the Supreme Court has made some terrible decisions.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>8:42 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: S. 2089 and ​S.&#160;2938</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/25/bills-signed-s-2089-and-s-2938/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 13:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Saturday, June 25, 2022, the President signed into law: S. 2089, the &#8220;Keep Kids Fed Act of 2022,&#8221; which extends certain flexibilities for child nutrition programs and provides temporary increases in reimbursement rates for school meals and meals provided at child care centers; Thank you to Senators Debbie Stabenow and John Boozman and Representatives&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Saturday, June 25, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>S. 2089, the &#8220;Keep Kids Fed Act of 2022,&#8221; which extends certain flexibilities for child nutrition programs and provides temporary increases in reimbursement rates for school meals and meals provided at child care centers;</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Debbie Stabenow and John Boozman and Representatives Bobby Scott and Virginia Foxx for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 2938, the &#8220;Bipartisan Safer Communities Act,&#8221; which enhances certain restrictions and penalties on firearms purchases; promotes evidence-based best practices for school safety; authorizes grants to expand access to mental health services; and appropriates emergency funding for mental health resources and school safety measures;</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Murphy, Cornyn, Sinema, Tillis, as well as Senate and House leadership, and the many other Congressional leaders on these issues who helped bring this bill to passage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson of the National Security Council’s Virtual Roundtable with Human Rights Activists for LGBTQI+ Pride&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/24/readout-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-of-the-national-security-councils-virtual-roundtable-with-human-rights-activists-for-lgbtqi-pride-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 01:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56273</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Principal Deputy National Security Advisor Jon Finer participated in a virtual roundtable with leading LGBTQI+ human rights activists from around the world as part of the broader White House celebration of Pride Month.  Mr. Finer emphasized the Biden-Harris Administration’s strong commitment to protecting and defending LGBTQI+ human rights globally, in line with President Biden’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Principal Deputy National Security Advisor Jon Finer participated in a virtual roundtable with leading LGBTQI+ human rights activists from around the world as part of the broader White House celebration of Pride Month.  Mr. Finer emphasized the Biden-Harris Administration’s strong commitment to protecting and defending LGBTQI+ human rights globally, in line with President Biden’s February 2021 Memorandum on this issue and June 15<sup>th</sup> Executive Order on Advancing Equality for LGBTQI+ Individuals.  Participating activists highlighted the resilience of the LGBTQI+ community in the face of both incremental gains and increasing repression in various contexts, as well as sustained societal discrimination, violence, and criminalization. Activists also highlighted increasing online attacks and state surveillance as a priority concern.  Mr. Finer was joined by Jessica Stern, U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons; Jay Gilliam, USAID Senior Coordinator for LGBTQI+ Issues; and senior members of the National Security Council staff. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Australia, Japan, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, and the United&#160;States on the Establishment of the Partners in the Blue Pacific&#160;(PBP) </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/24/statement-by-australia-japan-new-zealand-the-united-kingdom-and-the-united-states-on-the-establishment-of-the-partners-in-the-blue-pacific-pbp/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new initiative for more effective and efficient cooperation in support of Pacific Island priorities The Pacific Islands region is home to nearly a fifth of the Earth’s surface and many of its most urgent challenges, from the climate crisis to the COVID-19 pandemic to growing pressure on the rules-based free and open international order.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>A new initiative for more effective and efficient cooperation in support of Pacific Island priorities</em></p>



<p><br>The Pacific Islands region is home to nearly a fifth of the Earth’s surface and many of its most urgent challenges, from the climate crisis to the COVID-19 pandemic to growing pressure on the rules-based free and open international order. It was in this context that the Pacific Islands Forum, the premier driver of regional action, <a href="https://www.forumsec.org/2050strategy/#:~:text=The%202050%20Strategy%20for%20the%20Blue%20Pacific%20Continent&amp;text=It%20is%20a%20regional%20strategy,Pacific%20people%2C%20place%20and%20prospects.&amp;text=Pacific%20Leaders%20recognize%20that%20building,cultural%2C%20environmental%20and%20economic%20integrity">committed</a> to organize its members “as one collective if we are to address our increasingly common challenges.”<br><br>As our countries—<strong>Australia, Japan, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, </strong>and <strong>the United States</strong>—continue to support prosperity, resilience, and security in the Pacific, we too must harness our collective strength through closer cooperation. To that end, our governments dispatched high-level officials to Washington, D.C. on June 23 and 24 for consultations with Pacific Heads of Mission and other partners, including France, as well as the European Union in its observing capacity. These meetings followed discussions with Pacific partners, including with the Pacific Islands Forum Secretariat; they remain ongoing, including with other partners engaged in the region. Today, our five countries launched an inclusive, informal mechanism to support Pacific priorities more effectively and efficiently: <strong>thePartners in the Blue Pacific (PBP).</strong><br><br>This new initiative builds on our longstanding commitment to the region. Australia and New Zealand are of the region and members of the Pacific Islands Forum; Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States are founding Dialogue Partners. Our countries maintain close people-to-people ties to and are longstanding development partners with the Pacific Islands, reflected in our combined $2.1 billion in development assistance for the region. We are united in our shared determination to support a region that benefits the peoples of the Pacific. We are also united in how we realize this vision—according to principles of Pacific regionalism, sovereignty, transparency, accountability, and most of all, led and guided by the Pacific Islands.<br><br>With these principles at its core, the Partners in the Blue Pacific aims to: </p>



<ol><li><strong>Deliver results for the Pacific more effectively and efficiently.&nbsp;</strong>Together and individually, our five countries will enhance our existing efforts to support Pacific priorities, in line with the Pacific Islands Forum’s upcoming 2050 Strategy for the Blue Pacific Continent. To do so, we will work with Pacific partners. We will map existing projects and plan future ones, seeking to drive resources, remove duplication, and close gaps, which will avoid greater burdens and lost opportunities for Pacific governments and Pacific people. In parallel, each of our governments will continue to increase the ambition of our individual efforts in the region.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Bolster Pacific regionalism.&nbsp;</strong>The PBP will forge closer connections with Pacific governments and with the Pacific Islands Forum, by facilitating stronger and more regular engagement with our governments. We will further elevate Pacific regionalism, with a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum at its center, as a vital pillar of the regional architecture and of our respective approaches in the region.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Expand opportunities for cooperation between the Pacific and the world.</strong>&nbsp;The PBP will encourage and facilitate greater engagement with the Pacific by any other partner that shares the Pacific’s values and aims to work constructively and transparently to benefit the people of the region. As it develops, the PBP will remain inclusive, informal, and open to cooperating with additional partners similarly invested in and committed to partnership with the Pacific Islands. Globally, the PBP will identify opportunities to expand Pacific participation in international fora.</li></ol>



<p>At every stage, we will be led and guided by the Pacific Islands. We will seek Pacific guidance on the PBP’s selection of its lines of effort and its flagship projects. In meetings in Washington, including at Blair House, our governments and Pacific Heads of Mission discussed diverse areas in which to deepen cooperation, including the climate crisis, connectivity and transportation, maritime security and protection, health, prosperity, and education. We commit to continuing to engage with Pacific governments as well as with Pacific-led regional institutions, particularly the Pacific Islands Forum; we will align our work with outcomes from the upcoming Pacific Islands Forum Leaders meeting in Suva, Fiji. Later this year the United States intends to invite Partner countries’ foreign ministers to convene and review our progress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the NALEO 39th Annual&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-naleo-39th-annual-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 23:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SwissotelChicago, Illinois THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, NALEO!  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)   Have a seat.  Have a seat.  Good afternoon. Oh, it’s so good to &#8212; look at this wonderful, big crowd.  It’s so good to be back together under the same roof, isn’t it?  Yeah, it’s good to see everyone.  And I hope we all walk away&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Swissotel<br><em>Chicago, Illinois</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, NALEO!  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)   Have a seat.  Have a seat.  Good afternoon.<br> <br>Oh, it’s so good to &#8212; look at this wonderful, big crowd.  It’s so good to be back together under the same roof, isn’t it?  Yeah, it’s good to see everyone. <br> <br>And I hope we all walk away from days like this and moments like this when we go back to the places where we work every day, often being one of the only like us in a room or who has had the life experience we’ve had &#8212; I think these are moments that are very important to remember that we are not alone.  There are all of us who are in these rooms together, even if we don’t see each other at a particular moment.  So, it’s a good time to be together.  So, thank you all.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And I want to thank Ricardo and Mara for that kind introduction and for your leadership of this organization during an unprecedented time during these years of the pandemic and so many crises that we have been facing as a country.<br> <br>And, of course, I am honored to be here with the board of directors of NALEO and so many of our nation’s leaders.<br> <br>Before I start speaking as I planned to speak, I do want to speak briefly about the decision from today’s United States Supreme Court decision in the Dobbs case.  <br> <br>Here is what I believe that decision means: For nearly 50 years, we have talked about what Roe v. Wade protects.  Today, as of right now, as of this very minute, we can only talk about what Roe v. Wade protected.  Past tense. <br> <br>The great aspiration of our nation has been to expand freedom.  It is something so many of us has spent our careers fighting for.  But the expansion of freedom clearly is not inevitable, and it certainly is not something that just happens &#8212; not unless we defend our most fundamental principles. <br> <br>The strength of our nation has always been that, despite the odds and the obstacles, we push to move forward; that we are guided by what we see that can be, unburdened by what has been.  And I know everyone in this room understands this and has, in many ways, lived a life that illustrates this. <br> <br>And so, because, of course, NALEO has been fighting to move our nation forward for nearly 50 years on other critical issues and the issues that fundamentally are about the ideals and aspirations of our nation, I am honored to be with you here today. <br> <br>And I also want you to know that I bring you greetings from President Joe Biden &#8212; because we are grateful, yes.  (Applause.)  We are grateful for the work of this organization and its members to galvanize policy members and leaders, to mobilize, to organize, and to do that work on behalf of the Latino community and, by extension, the entire nation &#8212; all of that work being in pursuit of progress and our collective ability for our nation to achieve its ideals.  So, I thank you all.<br> <br>I have always felt a special connection to this organization, as Ricardo said.  And, yes, as a proud daughter of California &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; (applause) &#8212; many of us the daughters and sons of California &#8212; I am proud that NALEO, of course, was founded by a great Californian, Edward Roybal.  And we must always remember him.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And throughout my career, I have worked alongside many of the leaders of this organization, including, of course, our collective friend and my dear friend, now-Senator Alex Padilla, who served &#8212; (applause) &#8212; yes, he and I served together many years.  I was mostly based in the Bay Area.  He was in Los Angeles.  But then, as we were coming up, we both ended up as state constitutional officers when he was Secretary of State and I was Attorney General of California. <br> <br>And I partnered with so many of NALEO members on so many issues that range from supporting small businesses, to immigration reform, to voting rights, education, and so many more issues.<br> <br>And over the years, as Ricardo said, I have spoken with this organization many times.  But I am honored that this is the first time that I, in person, am speaking with you as Vice President of the United States.  (Applause.) <br> <br>So, I believe &#8212; in fact, I know &#8212; there is a common characteristic among us all: We all serve because we believe in the magnificence of our nation and its potential.  We all believe in fighting to achieve our nation’s highest ideals, knowing, as I said earlier, they don’t just happen.  We don’t just achieve them by being, we achieve them by being committed to reaching those ideals.<br> <br>We all believe in a future where the promise of liberty and justice is made real for all Americans.  We believe in a future where hard work pays off, where families can get ahead and stay ahead.  We believe in a future where every child can reach their God-given potential.<br> <br>We believe that all communities have a right to be safe and healthy. <br> <br>And we believe that anyone should be able to have a dream and achieve that dream &#8212; a future where immigrants have the opportunity to have what they deserve in terms of a pathway towards citizenship. <br> <br>We believe in a nation and in a future where protecting the freedom to vote is not a partisan issue. <br> <br>We believe that women should be able to make decisions about their own bodies without government interference.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And so, you know, when the President and I took office, our country, as we all remember, was headed in the wrong direction.  Just think: We were facing a pandemic that was out of control.  We had a situation that, in that pandemic, it’s important to note, it was particularly devastating in terms of its impact on the Latino community, especially among those who were frontline workers and essential workers and farmworkers, so many of whom were, in terms of the essential workers, DREAMers.  We remember how folks risked their own health and the health of their families to keep safe communities and to keep our country running.<br> <br>Remember, our nation also faced &#8212; and we can talk about current day as well &#8212; but then, in particular, we faced a historic economic challenge as a result of the pandemic.<br> <br>But together with you, the President and I were not deterred.  With your partnership &#8212; remember &#8212; it was a difficult road but we got folks vaccinated.  We reopened our schools and kept people in their homes. <br> <br>Together, because of our collective work, we achieved record job creation, record labor participation, and the largest single-year drop in Latino unemployment in recorded history.  (Applause.)<br> <br>In addition, we have assembled the most diverse administration in the history of our country.  And I should note, we have appointed the most Latino leaders ever to Cabinet-level position.  (Applause.)<br> <br>In addition, we expanded the Child Tax Credit, such that so many children &#8212; and in particular, the Latino child poverty rate hit a new record low last year. <br> <br>Because of the once-in-a-generation Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we lowered the cost of high-speed Internet for nearly 40 percent of households in America. <br> <br>Because we invested in small businesses, business owners across the country kept their doors open and Latino entrepreneurs started new companies at a higher rate last year than at any other point in the last decade.<br> <br>In fact, just recently I was in Monrovia, California &#8212; many of the Californians know where that is.  (Applause.)  California.  (Laughter.)  Just joking.  I got jokes, okay.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>So, I was there in Monrovia, and I was visiting this incredible small business &#8212; it’s a woman small-business owner, and it was &#8212; the business is called Dream Big Children’s Center.  And its owner, her name is Cristina Cordeiro.  We talked for quite some time.  Her mother was there.  And we talked about her inspiration, which is her mother was a great caregiver.  Right?  She grew in a community where we care about the children.<br> <br>And so, she created this business that parents would rely on to provide daily therapy to children with special needs.  And if you can imagine, this &#8212; especially during the pandemic, for all of us who have children in our lives &#8212; it was incredibly critical, especially during those many, many months of the pandemic, that we would have access to the needs of services for our children.  So, it was very critical that she stayed open during the pandemic.<br> <br>Fortunately, because of funding she received through our administration’s American Rescue Plan, she was not only able to continue providing services in her community, but she was able to grow her business.  And since the start of the pandemic, she has opened 50 &#8212; or two new locations with 50 new employees. <br> <br>And I mention that because, during the course of the last couple of years &#8212; and in particular in the last year and half after we passed, together with your help, the ARP &#8212; I’ve met so many small-business owners who have seen success &#8212; and the kind of success that I know NALEO and this organization and its members have been fighting for, understanding that so much of the economic health and vitality of our communities has been centered in the small businesses, in men and women who are invested in their community; who understand the community &#8212; the language of the community, the culture of the community, the needs of the community &#8212; and are, therefore, best suited to actually uplift the community economically and in every other way.<br> <br>And together, because of the work that we have done, in particular with the ARP, we’ve been able to do that and we’re seeing results.<br> <br>And so, whether it is my work in the United States Senate or the work that we did, in terms of in the Senate, helping small businesses access capital, or the partnership, together, that we had to get the Restaurant Revitalization Fund included in the ARP, we are seeing that small businesses are starting to thrive in our country, and with a particular emphasis on women- and minority-owned small businesses.<br> <br>So, I want to thank you all for the work you’ve done in that regard as well.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So with that being said, we also know that people are still hurting.  There is no question that we still face a number of serious challenges.  And today then, I’d like to talk about three of the issues which I believe are among the priorities of us in this room: one, lowering costs for families, building a fair and humane immigration system, and protecting people from gun violence.  <br> <br>So, first, I think we all agree and know inflation is still too high.  We are seeing higher prices at the store because supply chains slowed down dramatically during the pandemic and higher prices at the gas pump, in large part because of Putin’s unprovoked war in Ukraine.  And families across our nation, in particular working families, are feeling the effect.  <br> <br>I know you know the President and I are using every tool at our disposal to lower costs, including the cost of gas, childcare, eldercare, and prescription drugs like insulin &#8212; which we should be capping, by the way, at $35 a month.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And as leaders of the communities that you represent, you know that these are some of the costs that most matter to the families of our communities.  And we know that making essential needs more affordable will keep our country on a path to stable and steady growth.<br> <br>So, there is work that we still have to do.  But as we are looking at these issues, as we discuss the issue of inflation, let us agree that we cannot abandon our commitment to supporting families on the issue of childcare, on the issue of eldercare, on the issue of the cost of prescription drugs.  Because these are costs that are, without any question, also weighing down the ability of families to succeed and thrive.  And in large part, a lot of these issues are incumbent on elected leaders to solve, and they have the ability to solve.<br> <br>Speaking of, let’s talk about the second issue: immigration.  There’s still so much work to be done on that.  We have partnered, so many of us, over the years to fight to fix our country’s broken immigration system and, in particular, to fight for our Dreamers. <br> <br>When I was Attorney General of California, you probably remember that we, together, fought in the courts and spoke out when they ruled against DACA and DAPA.  When I was in the United States Senate, we worked together on legislation that would create a pathway to citizenship. <br> <br>And today, our administration continues to urge Congress to create a pathway not only for DREAMers, but also for individuals with temporary protected status and for farmworkers.  In fact, when I was in the Senate, I was proud to sponsor the Farm Worker Bill of Rights.  We &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.<br> <br>And so we issued a proposed rule that would preserve and fortify DACA.  Our administration and the Department of Justice continues to defend DACA in the courts.  In fact, just last week, on the 10th anniversary of DACA, I was again reminded of why we have to continue the fight.  I invited a group of DREAMers to come in and &#8212; and they came into the White House, to my West Wing office, and each of them was so committed to paying forward the opportunity that they received and the opportunity that they know that folks who are entitled to receive.  One of the DREAMers became a kindergarten teacher after college.  And today he is organizing a diverse coalition in support of a pathway towards citizenship.<br> <br>And I don&#8217;t need to tell anybody here: DREAMers are serving in our military, they are attending college, they are working in Fortune 100 companies.  I mentioned the number who were frontline workers who were sacrificing so much of their own lives and service to their community and perfect strangers.<br> <br>And it is a tragedy that we can&#8217;t pull this together as a nation and pass legislation, creating a legal pathway for them, for farmworkers, for TPS, and understanding what this means to families every day. <br> <br>We &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s not on the front page of the newspaper, necessarily, but it&#8217;s real; I don&#8217;t have to tell anybody here.<br> <br>These kids, their parents, so many blended families, mixed families, still every day are in fear about a knock at a door and what that might mean, whether a parent might come home at night.<br> <br>And I don&#8217;t need to tell anybody here this, because most of us are in the same situation: We are a nation of immigrants. Raise your hand if you have a parent that was not born in the United States &#8212; this room of leaders.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, as do we, these young people represent the promise of who we are as a country.  You know, I said to one of them &#8212; I said to one of the young leaders that were there that day, and I said, “You know, my mother came to the United States…” &#8212; and we’re in my West Wing office in the White House, and I looked at &#8212; I looked at him and I said, “You know, my mother came to the United States from India when she was 19 years old.  And I&#8217;m Vice President of the United States.”  (Applause.)  And he broke out in a big smile.  He said, “Okay, I got it.  I understand.”<br> <br>So, all of that to say that we have to keep fighting on this issue.<br> <br>The third issue that I know is our nation&#8217;s highest priority &#8212; one of them &#8212; is our responsibility to create safe communities and protect people from gun violence. <br> <br>What happened in Uvalde broke the hearts of our entire country.  We were all shaken to our core by the massacre of those 19 children &#8212; those babies &#8212; and their two teachers.  And we, of course, still remember and mourn the 23 lives senselessly taken by a white nationalist in El Paso three years ago. <br> <br>And our hearts are heavy when news breaks about similar vicious, hateful attacks at a grocery store in Buffalo, a synagogue in Pittsburgh, or a nightclub in Orlando.<br> <br>And, of course, there&#8217;s a through-line between these tragedies: an epidemic of hate that touches us all.  And, I believe, to combat hate we must speak truth about what fuels these attacks, and we must have the courage to take action that will save lives.<br> <br>I think many of us agree that our country needs sensible gun safety laws; that yesterday&#8217;s Supreme Court decision, which struck down one of those laws, defies common sense and defies the Constitution.  And we must protect people from the gun violence that claims countless lives every day in America, which is why the bipartisan gun safety bill that is on the way to the President&#8217;s desk is an important and necessary step.<br> <br>But we cannot stop.  We cannot stop here, and we must continue to do more.  Because, I mean, let&#8217;s be &#8212; let&#8217;s be real: No 9-year-old should be scared to go to school.  No 15-year-old should fear shopping for school supplies.  No 25-year-old should be scared to go with friends to a nightclub.  And no 86-year-old should be afraid to shop for groceries.  And no 18-year-old should be able to buy a weapon of war.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, I&#8217;ll end with this point: If there is one belief that I know everyone in this room shares it is our belief in the potential, in the promise, and the strength of our nation. <br> <br>We all choose to serve because we know our country is strong enough to overcome the challenges we face, because we believe it is our duty as public officials to work together in pursuit of progress.<br> <br>So let us always remember and let us remind others that we all have so much more in common than what separates us.  And let us renew then our commitment to fight for unity, especially in these days. <br> <br>Let us continue &#8212; and NALEO has done this so well over so many years &#8212; to understand the power and the beauty of building and reinforcing coalitions based on knowing how much we all have in common.  Because I believe that the only way to tackle the biggest problems, the biggest challenges that we as a nation face is to tackle them together.<br> <br>And NALEO, of course, knows this more than most &#8212; because, again, you have been bringing folks together for nearly 50 years.  And in those 50 years, you have used your collective voice to advocate for more equity, more opportunity, and more possibility for all communities.<br> <br>So with that, I am here to say the President and I are with you.  We stand with you every step of the way.  God bless you, and God bless the United States of America.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Supreme Court Decision to Overturn Roe V.&#160;Wade</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-supreme-court-decision-to-overturn-roe-v-wade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 20:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[C.W. Avery Family YMCAPlainfield, Illinois 2:23 P.M. CDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon, everyone.  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon. Well, first, I want to thank Senator Durbin.  I had the privilege of serving with him, as he mentioned, on the Senate Judiciary Committee.  And I can tell&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>C.W. Avery Family YMCA<br><em>Plainfield, Illinois</em></em></p>



<p>2:23 P.M. CDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon, everyone.  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.<br><br>Well, first, I want to thank Senator Durbin.  I had the privilege of serving with him, as he mentioned, on the Senate Judiciary Committee.  And I can tell you, Illinois, you are very, very well represented by Senator Dick Durbin.  He is an extraordinary leader, a great fighter for all of American and &#8212; all of America, and in particular for the people of Illinois.<br>So, thank you, Dick Durbin, and congratulations to your grandchild, for her honor today as well. <br><br>And I want to thank all the leaders for joining us today, and a special thank you, of course, to Lauren Underwood.  Where are you?  Lauren.  (Applause.)  I have seen you when the cameras are on and when the cameras are off.  She’s always fighting for the people of her district.  And all that you have done for our government, for the people of our country, and for Plainfield, I thank you for that.  I thank you for your partnership and your leadership.<br><br>So, as Senator Durbin mentioned, we traveled here today.  In fact, they both joined me, along with the Secretary, on Air Force Two.  And we traveled here from D.C. today to talk with you about maternal health, which should be one of our highest priorities as a nation.<br><br>And I had planned to speak about our strategy for improving care for pregnant women and mothers across our country.  And as you know, on the way here, however, we learned that the United States Supreme Court had rendered its decision in Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization.<br><br>Here’s what that decision means: For nearly 50 years, we have talked about what Roe v. Wade protects.  Today, as of right now, as of this minute, we can only talk about what Roe v. Wade protected.  Past tense. <br><br>This is a healthcare crisis, because understand: Millions of women in America will go to bed tonight without access to the healthcare and reproductive care that they had this morning; without access to the same healthcare or reproductive healthcare that their mothers and grandmothers had for 50 years.<br> <br>This is the first time in the history of our nation that a constitutional right has been taken from the people of America.  And what is that right? &#8212; some might ask.  It’s the right to privacy.<br> <br>Think about it as the right for each person to make intimate decisions about heart and home; decisions about the right to start a family, including contraception, such as IUDs and the morning-after pill; decisions about whether to have a child, including, as Senator Durbin mentioned, through in-vitro fertilization; decisions to marry the person you love &#8212; Obergefell v. Hodges, Loving vs. Virginia.<br> <br>This opinion also says, when your read it, that abortion is not deeply rooted in our nation’s history.  They offer that in the opinion as a foundation for the decision they rendered today.<br> <br>In holding that it is not deeply rooted in our history, today’s decision on that theory, then, calls into question other rights that we thought were settled, such as the right to use birth control, the right to same-sex marriage, the right to interracial marriage.<br> <br>The great aspiration of our nation has been to expand freedom, but the expansion of freedom clearly is not inevitable.  It is not something that just happens &#8212; not unless we defend our most fundamental principles; not unless we elect leaders who stand up for those principles.<br> <br>The strength of our nation has always been that we move forward. <br><br>Today, I invite all people to stand together in defense of one of the most fundamental ideals and principles that for generations, for centuries, I believe, we have held dear, which is that fundamental principle about the importance of liberty &#8212; to stand for liberty, to stand for freedom, to stand for self-determination, and for the right to privacy.<br> <br>You have the power to elect leaders who will defend and protect your rights.  And as the President said earlier today, with your vote, you can act, and you have the final word. <br> <br>So this is not over.  God bless you.  And God bless America.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END                 2:30 P.M. CDT</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
