<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 21:44:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-28/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 21:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Mark Gitenstein, of Washington, to be Representative of the United States of America to the European Union, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary. &#160; &#160; &#160;Lisa M. Gomez, of New Jersey, to be an Assistant Secretary of Labor, vice Preston Rutledge. &#160; &#160; &#160;Laura&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Mark Gitenstein, of Washington, to be Representative of the United States of America to the European Union, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Lisa M. Gomez, of New Jersey, to be an Assistant Secretary of Labor, vice Preston Rutledge.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Laura S. H. Holgate, of Virginia, to be Representative of the United States of America to the Vienna Office of the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Laura S. H. Holgate, of Virginia, to be Representative of the United States of America to the International Atomic Energy Agency, with the rank of Ambassador.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Erik Adrian Hooks, of North Carolina, to be Deputy Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency, Department of Homeland Security, vice Peter Gaynor, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Patricia Mahoney, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Central African Republic.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Julissa Reynoso Pantaleon, of New York, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Spain, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Principality of Andorra.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;William J. Valdez, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security, vice Claire M. Grady.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Peter Hendrick Vrooman, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Mozambique.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Adrienne Wojciechowski, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Agriculture, vice Kenneth Steven Barbic.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Importance of American&#160;Manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/28/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-importance-of-american-manufacturing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mack Lehigh Valley Operations&#160;Macungie, Pennsylvania 1:59 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, I&#8217;m not going to say anything; I just came to drive a truck.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And I&#8217;m not sure which one I want to drive.&#160; That one?&#160; There&#8217;s one back in the corner you can&#8217;t see.&#160; It&#8217;s the biggest damn pick-up truck you ever saw&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Mack Lehigh Valley Operations&nbsp;<br>Macungie, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>1:59 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to say anything; I just came to drive a truck.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not sure which one I want to drive.&nbsp; That one?&nbsp; There&#8217;s one back in the corner you can&#8217;t see.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the biggest damn pick-up truck you ever saw in your life.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I tell you what.&nbsp;<br><br>Please, everybody have a seat.&nbsp; Everybody have a seat.<br><br>Carlo, thank you. &nbsp;And, Carlo, I&#8217;m sorry about your mom. &nbsp;I really am. &nbsp;So many &#8212; so many people. &nbsp;Well over 630,000 Americans have lost their lives because of COVID. &nbsp;And the only thing I&#8217;m going to &#8212; and the press keeps wanting me to talk about COVID, but I’m going to mention this one thing.<br><br>We still have a lot of people not vaccinated.&nbsp; The pandemic we have now is a pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; So, please &#8212; please, please, please, if you&#8217;re not vaccinated, protect yourself and the children out there.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important.<br><br>And, Carlo, having been a significant consumer of healthcare myself and my family, I&#8217;ve often said this, and I mean it from the bottom of my heart: Thank your daughter for me.&nbsp; If there are any angels in heaven, they&#8217;re male and female nurses.&nbsp; Not &#8212; that&#8217;s the God&#8217;s truth.&nbsp; Doctors let you live; they make you want to live.&nbsp; Spent a lot of time in ICU, with my son on a table.&nbsp; Tell her, &#8220;Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#8221;&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And I want to thank Congresswoman Wild for the passport into her district.&nbsp; Where are you?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; As they say up in Scranton, she&#8217;s bragging on y&#8217;all.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t say &#8220;y&#8217;all&#8221; up there; they say that in Delaware.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You do because you got family from Alabama.<br><br>And you&#8217;ve been a tireless champion for the working men and women of the Lehigh Valley, helping us pass a tax cut for families with children that people are seeing now in their bank accounts, showing up in their bank accounts every month, and working with our administration to expand home care for seniors.&nbsp; We got a generation that&#8217;s a &#8220;sandwich generation&#8221; between the child and a mom or dad needing help.&nbsp; And they need help.&nbsp; Provide better pay for caregivers.<br><br>And I want to particularly thank Bobby Casey &#8212; he&#8217;s a great friend of mine &#8212; who champions this cause in the Senate for eldercare.<br><br>You know, John Mack started this iconic American company in 1890.&nbsp;&nbsp;But things didn’t really didn&#8217;t get off the ground until four years later when he brought his William &#8212; his brother William down from Scranton.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughter.)<br><br>So, it goes to show you: If you want to get things moving, bring a guy from Scranton to get it going.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)<br><br>Mind if I take my coat off?&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to take my coat off.<br><br>You know &#8212; and, folks, we’re getting things moving.&nbsp; We really are.&nbsp; You are.<br><br>When I started my campaign for President &#8212; and the Gov is still &#8212; Gov, I didn&#8217;t introduce you.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; No, you&#8217;re the governor of this state, and you&#8217;re one of the best governors in the country.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And you&#8217;re a good friend.<br><br>When &#8212; when I said I was running when I announced my campaign &#8212; and not many people took it seriously &#8212; I said I was running for three reasons: one, to restore the soul of this country &#8212; a sense of decency and honor; but, secondly, to rebuild the backbone of the country: hardworking, middle-class folks who built this country.&nbsp; And I want to point out: Unions built the middle class.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a joke.&nbsp; Unions built the middle class.<br><br>And, by the way, in case you regret anything, I just want you guys and women in union know that if it weren&#8217;t for the UAW in 1972, I never would have won.&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; We had the largest percentage of union workers of any state in the nation in Delaware back then, including Michigan, because we&#8217;re a small state and we had big plans.&nbsp; But, so &#8212; so, before you get upset, remember, you&#8217;re to blame why I got here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Look, folks, I think a lot of us come from similar backgrounds: moms, dads, brothers, sisters, family.&nbsp; People who get up every day, work hard, raise their families, pay their taxes, serve their communities, and serve their country.<br><br>And that’s why I moved so quickly to pass the American Rescue Plan shortly after I got in &#8212; elected.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Because we needed to act quickly and boldly to save jobs, save businesses, and save lives.&nbsp; And we did.<br><br>We added more than 600,000 jobs per month since I&#8217;ve taken office.&nbsp; That&#8217;s over 3 million jobs all told.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It&#8217;s the fastest job growth at this point in any administration on record because of you all.&nbsp;<br><br>We brought this economy back from the brink: checks in people&#8217;s pockets, shots in people&#8217;s arms, tax cuts for working families with children.&nbsp; And we designed our strategy not only to provide a temporary boost, but to lay the foundation for a long-term boom that brings everyone along.<br><br>Because when I arrived in office, we had a long time &#8212; it&#8217;s been a long time since the federal government had worked hard for working people.&nbsp; Things had been great for big corporations, great for the very wealthy, folks at the top.&nbsp; Those 55 major corporations for the past three years paid zero in federal taxes, making over $40 billion.&nbsp; They had no complaints.<br><br>But when I put my hand on that Bible on January 20th and took the Oath of Office, I made a commitment to the American people: We&#8217;re going to change the paradigm so working people could have a fighting chance again to get a good education, to get a good job and a raise, to take care of that elderly parent and afford to take care of their children, and stop losing hours of their lives stuck in traffic because the streets are crumbling, or waiting for slow, spotty Internet to connect them to the world.<br><br>That’s what the economy we’re building is all about.&nbsp; Because given half a chance &#8212; and think about this; I mean this from the bottom of &#8212; given half a chance, ordinary Americans &#8212; the people have never, ever, ever, ever let their country down, just given a half a chance.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I mean it.&nbsp;<br><br>You may have heard that, in Washington &#8212; and I was just on the phone &#8212; it looks like we reached a bipartisan agreement on infrastructure &#8212; a fancy word for bridges, roads &#8212; (applause) &#8212; transit systems, high-speed Internet, clean drinking water, cleaning up and caffing [sic] &#8212; capping the orphan wells, over thousands of them abandoned, and abandoned mines &#8212; and a modern, resilient electric grid to build.<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; A lot of those abandoned wells are leaking methane.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; The same union guys that dug those wells, they can make the same union wage capping those wells.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And I’m working with Democrats and Republicans to get this done, because while there’s a lot we don’t agree on, I believe that we should be able to work together on the few things we do agree on.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s important.&nbsp;<br><br>In addition to the physical infrastructure, I also put forward a thing called Build Back Better plan, with investments that are going to really &#8212; if I said to you, &#8220;You could have the following: We&#8217;re going to be &#8212; build you a lot of new roads and bridges, or I can make sure we&#8217;re going to educate your kids so we&#8217;re the best educated population in the world,&#8221; what do you think would most impact on the growth of America?&nbsp; You’d be the most educated nation in the world.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m insisting that we have universal pre-kindergarten, two years of free community college.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>All the studies show: No matter what background a kid comes from &#8212; whether they&#8217;re a single mom, a single dad who is on what we used to call &#8220;welfare,&#8221; are in trouble, or come from a middle-class household &#8212; the kid who comes from the background that&#8217;s deprived is going to hear, by the time they get to first grade, a million fewer words spoken.&nbsp; A million fewer spoken.&nbsp; What that means is they&#8217;re behind the eight ball from the start.&nbsp; And a lot more.&nbsp;<br><br>But we found out if you put kids in not &#8212; not daycare but in school at age three, four, and five, it increases by 58 percent the chance, no matter what their background, they&#8217;ll make it through high school and qualify to go on to community college.&nbsp;<br><br>Folks, we need more affordable childcare.&nbsp; There are a lot of women not working today because they can&#8217;t get &#8212; go back to their jobs because they have no one to take care of their children; they can&#8217;t afford it.<br><br>I was a single dad for five years when my wife and daughter were killed in an automobile accident, my two little boys were badly banged up.&nbsp; I commuted back and forth to Washington because I couldn&#8217;t dare leave and move to Washington because I didn&#8217;t have my family to help me take care of my kids.&nbsp; I was making a good salary &#8212; $42,000 a year then.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford care &#8212; daycare for my children.<br><br>Eldercare: How many of you know somebody, has a mom or dad that needs help just because they&#8217;re getting older and maybe still has their home but would rather stay in their home, increase their mental state, put them in a position where it&#8217;s better for their health, but you can&#8217;t figure out how to keep mom home alone, how to do it &#8212; or dad?&nbsp; Well, eldercare is a big piece of this.<br><br>Paid leave: We&#8217;re one of the only industrial countries in the world that you don&#8217;t get paid leave if you have a sick son, daughter, mother, father, wife, husband, to have some time to take care of that.<br><br>Bring more people into the workforce, enhance our productivity, raise wages, and bring down the cost for working families.<br><br>You know, I was born up in Scranton, and my dad worked up in Scranton.&nbsp; He was actually from Baltimore, but he worked in Scranton and met my mom (inaudible) dad moved there.&nbsp;<br><br>And when coal died, everything died in the Valley, so he had to leave and look for a new job.&nbsp; My dad used to have an expression when we got down to Wilmington.&nbsp; First thing he did &#8212; he got a job scrubbing the inside of boilers for a thing ca- &#8212; often called “COW” &#8212; the COW corporation.<br><br>We finally got to the place where &#8212; we get to the place after five years we could afford to buy a small house &#8212; actually, six years.&nbsp; My dad used to say, “Remember, Joey, a job is about a lot more than a paycheck.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about your dignity. It&#8217;s about respect.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about your place in the community.”&nbsp; I give my word to what he’d say.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s about being able to look your kid in the eye and say, “Honey, it’s going to be okay,” and mean it.<br><br>Because we know that trickle-down economics has never worked.&nbsp; But when working families do well, everybody does well, including the wealthy.&nbsp; Everybody.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I’m here to talk about a commitment that’s sacred to me and central to our efforts to keep things moving.&nbsp; It’s a straightforward solution: support and grow more American-based companies.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Put more Americans to work in union jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Strengthen American manufacturing and secure critical supply chains.&nbsp; And confront the climate crisis, which is all about jobs.<br><br>I can sum it up in two words: Buy American.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Buy American.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, what most people don&#8217;t know &#8212; no matter how informed they are, most people don&#8217;t know that for literally almost a century, there&#8217;s been a law on the books in America called the Buy America Act.&nbsp; It&#8217;s supposed to make sure that when your government spends your tax dollars in buying goods that they have to be goods that were built, purchased in America.<br><br>But the previous administration didn&#8217;t take it so seriously &#8212; in previous ones, not just the last one.&nbsp; They were quick to say, “You know, we have a lot of money to spend.&nbsp; We got to buy &#8212; the government is going to buy everything from buildings to aircraft carriers to trucks to whatever it is.&nbsp; But we can&#8217;t find an American company that can do it all, so we&#8217;re going to have to issue a waiver.&nbsp; We’ll hire the American company, but that American company is going to have a subsidiary overseas where non-American &#8212; Americans don’t work, where it’s much cheaper, they can make more money, and they’re going to say, “We have to have that as part of the chain of building the product.”<br><br>The result has been tens of billions of dollars didn’t go to jobs and businesses in communities like this one.<br><br>In recent years, “Buy American” has become a hollow promise.&nbsp; But my adma- &#8212; my administration is going to make “Buy American” a reality.&nbsp; And I’m putting the weight of the federal government behind that commitment with Made in &#8212; in the White House itself, we put in a Made in America Office to oversee &#8212; not in an agency, in the White House itself &#8212; to oversee these efforts.<br><br>In my first Cabinet meeting, I told all of the Cabinet members if their agency wants to issue a waiver &#8212; they’re buying forest &#8212; the Forest Department is buying trucks or hoses or whatever they need, okay?&nbsp; They’ve got to buy something that’s &#8212; all of it has been made in America.&nbsp;<br><br>And you can’t give exceptions.&nbsp; Because if you say, “We can’t find one that does &#8212; has…”&nbsp; They get their nozzles overseas because they don’t have anybody here who can make them, et cetera.&nbsp; I said, “If you’re going to give an exception, you got to tell the White House specifically why the exception.”&nbsp;<br><br>If they still want a waiver, they have to post the request on &#8212; publicly so American manufacturers all over the United States &#8212; and businesses &#8212; have a chance to look up now in a new facility and say, “Hey, they’re for companies that make nozzles.&nbsp; They’re looking for companies that make the following whatever.&nbsp; We make that.&nbsp; We make that.”&nbsp; And contact us.&nbsp; Then they can’t take the job overseas.<br><br>And today, we’re going to go further: We’re going to make the biggest enforcement changes to the Buy American Act in 70 years.&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, if you manufacture a vehicle &#8212; I expect you guys know about that &#8212; that gets purchased by the federal government, the law says that &#8212; and there’s about 600,000 vehicles the federal government owns, by the way, and replaces and buys &#8212; that “substantially all” of that vehicle &#8212; “substantially all” should be made in America.&nbsp;<br><br>But because of loopholes, over time, you know what “substantially all” means today?&nbsp; If 55 percent of it was made in America, you can go ahead and get all of the rest of it purchased other places.&nbsp; To me, 55 percent is not “substantially all;” it’s barely half.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is actually a double whammy.&nbsp; First, 55 percent is not high enough.&nbsp; And second, contractors don’t have to tell us the total domestic content of their products, they just have to tell us that they hit the threshold.&nbsp; Nobody checking.&nbsp; Well, they got a new sheriff in town.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re going to be checking.&nbsp; No, I’m serious.&nbsp; I am deadly earnest.<br><br>Today, I’m directing the Budget Office to issue a rule to raise the amount of domestic content required to be considered Made in America from 55 percent to 75 percent.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; “Substantially all” is going to mean substantially all.&nbsp;<br><br>And starting with critical products, instead of taking contractors at their word that they hit the threshold, we’re going to start making them give us the details so that we can do more to support American manufacturing.&nbsp;<br><br>We want to be the ones making the innovative parts of every product &#8212; the ones that will support more jobs and more small businesses.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, I had a tour today.&nbsp; A lovely lady showing me in the parts where &#8212; the second stop we made &#8212; she said, “Well, we’re having a little problem.&nbsp; We’re finding we don’t have the computer chips that we need to go into the engines, et cetera.”&nbsp; We basically don’t make them anymore in America.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I got together with a group of 20 Republicans and Democrats.&nbsp; We passed a new piece of legislation providing that South Korea and Taiwan open up plants here in the United States hiring American employees to make those computer chips so we’re not held hostage.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>In case you haven’t noticed, not only you but Ford Motor Company said they’re going to have to stop producing certain vehicles.&nbsp; They couldn’t get the chips.&nbsp; Couldn’t get the wafers.&nbsp;<br><br>And so I’m also directing my Budget Office to create new rules for critical products where we know we need stronger, more resilient domestic supply chains.&nbsp; We’re talking about components like semiconductors, pharmaceutical ingredients, advanced batteries, among other things.<br><br>We saw during the early days of the pandemic that the supply chain disruptions can put Americans’ lives and livelihoods at risk.&nbsp;<br><br>When we needed them most, we were short of protective equipment, we were short on ventilators and other essential health equipment.&nbsp; We couldn’t get the job done.&nbsp; We couldn’t take care of people.&nbsp; We were short on basic equipment.<br><br>I know a lot of you in this factory stepped up to make PPE at the time.&nbsp; That was a noble service, but it’s not a long-term solution.<br><br>Yes, we’ll keep trading with our allies, but we need to have a resilient supply chain of our own so that we’re never again at the mercy of other countries for critical goods ever again.&nbsp; Ever.<br><br>You know exactly what I’m talking about.&nbsp; Right here, you’ve seen production slowdowns.&nbsp; As I’ve said, you’ve had your hours cut because of the shortage of computer chips and semi-conductors.&nbsp;<br><br>These chips are in more than just vehicles; they enable so much of our modern lives &#8212; our smartphones, our televisions, our medical equipment.<br><br>That’s why we’re investing $50 billion to have the best chip manufacturing in the world come and build factories in the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And it passed the Senate, and it’s called the CHIPS Act, and it’s part of my Build Back Better plan.&nbsp; And it is bipartisan, as many Republicans are concerned about it as Democrats.<br><br>It’s not just semiconductors. &nbsp;With this rule, we’ll be able to buy medical products from companies like OraSure that are up &#8212; that are down the road in Bethlehem &#8212; or up the road in Bethlehem, I should say. &nbsp;I’m used to thinking from Scranton.<br><br>Their COVID-19 tests are being made right here, bringing good jobs along with it &#8212; meaning that we’re developing a homegrown capacity to respond to this pandemic and help prepare for the next one.<br><br>And, by the way, when I say “Buy in America,” I mean from all America.&nbsp; You know, we’re going to include communities that have historically been left out of government procurement, when more contracts are going to go Black and brown communities, Native Americans, small businesses, every state and territory, every industry that services and manufactures, and also agriculture.<br><br>Part of the problem is that a lot of companies don’t even know these opportunities exist to be part of this.&nbsp; And we’ve got to &#8212; and we got to know &#8212; I used to have a great friend &#8212; a friend who’s a great friend.&nbsp; He used to play for Providence College back in the days when they had great teams.&nbsp; His name was Pete McLaughlin, and he used to have an expression.&nbsp; And he wasn’t the &#8212; God love him.&nbsp; He passed away &#8212; needed a heart (inaudible).&nbsp;<br><br>But anyway, the point is that what Pete used to say &#8212; and academics weren’t his thing &#8212; he used to say something very streetwise.&nbsp; He said, “Joe, you got to know how to know.”&nbsp; You got to know how to know.&nbsp; You can walk into the Library of Congress, one of the greatest libraries in the world, and if you don’t know how to use the card catalog, figuratively speaking, it’s just all happenstance.&nbsp; You got to know how to know.<br><br>So we started a new manufacturing contracting office in the Small Business Administration to help small- and medium-sized businesses bid on these contracts.&nbsp; And my Department of Commerce is working to help government agencies connect with new domestic suppliers in every state.&nbsp; That’s how we’re going to build a future that’s made in America.<br><br>One more reason this is going to make a big difference:&nbsp; Each year, the federal government purchases more than $600 billion in goods and services<a>.&nbsp; </a>The Congress passes laws for purchasing things, and as President, I get to decide where we spend them and what we purch- &#8212; what &#8212; I mean, I purchase what was called for, but I get to &#8212; and I’m the one who makes the decision &#8212; the administration makes a decision on how to spend that $600 billion.<br><br>If American companies know that we’re going to be buying from them, they’re going to be more inclined to hire and make key investments in the future in their companies, like you’re doing here.<br><br>My Build Back Better plan has incentives for electric vehicle <s>adaptation</s> [adoption], for increasing the amount of clean energy our government buys.&nbsp; And these Buy American rules can help guarantee a reliable market.<br><br>I just saw the work you’re doing on the heavy-duty electric vehicles here, like electric garbage trucks.&nbsp; You know, there are more than 600,000 vehicles in the federal fleet, including the majority of &#8212; the largest portion of which are at the post office.&nbsp;<br><br>As we work to electrify them &#8212; as they run out, electrify them &#8212; we’re going to be making a market for vehicles with electric, supporting both the good jobs being created, as well as innovation we need to electrify our transportation sector and clean up our environment at the same time.<br><br>And we’ll be expanding my Made in America initiative to help cities, towns, and Tribes get a better deal when they buy a “Made in America” product.&nbsp; It helps the towns, the taxpayers, as well as all of you on the floor of this significant place.&nbsp; It really does.<br><br>There are a lot of folks out there who look at how fast and how dramatically the world is changing and world economies are changing.&nbsp; I mean, who would have thought that 20 years ago you’d be making electric garbage trucks here?&nbsp; Seriously, think about it.&nbsp; But they accept it as gospel that working folks aren&#8217;t going to &#8212; aren&#8217;t &#8212; are going to get left behind; they&#8217;re not going to be able to keep up.&nbsp;<br><br>Just the opposite.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the opposite.&nbsp; Hardworking Americans are the ones who are going to make it happen.&nbsp; We got to invest in you.&nbsp; We have the most productive workforce in the world here.&nbsp; Given half a chance, there’s not a single &#8212; single thing you can’t do.<br><br>So, I reject out of hand &#8212; I&#8217;ve been criticized for this for some time &#8212; but I reject out of hand this defeatist view that the forces of automation and globalization mean we can’t have good-paying union jobs in America.<br><br>And right here, on this factory floor, you’re making a product that are fighting climate change.&nbsp; That’s why when I hear &#8220;climate change,&#8221; I think jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>Our manufacturing future, our economic future, our solutions to the climate crisis are all going to be made in America, creating good jobs.&nbsp; This&#8217;s what it means to build back better.&nbsp;<br><br>We came out of this economic crisis &#8212; the worst since the Depression &#8212; stronger than when we went in.<br><br>America is one of the few countries of the world &#8212; when we get smacked and knocked down, we get up, we come back, and we come back better than we were before we got knocked down.&nbsp; Now, I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; Think about the &#8212; you know, the course of history in America.<br>And that’s why, in the American Rescue Plan that we passed shortly after I took office, we’re investing considerable sums that will go to cities and towns looking to build back stronger.<br><br>For example, towns in the southwestern part of this state can now apply for funds to cap those wells that are leaking methane, clean up abandoned coal mines, invest in bringing new employers into abandoned factories, and get help attracting them.<br><br>Let me close with this: Back in 2009, during the so-called &#8220;Great Recession,&#8221; the President asked me to be in charge of managing that piece &#8212; then-President Trump &#8212; excuse me, Freudian slip; that was the last President.&nbsp; He caused &#8212; anyway, that was &#8212; President Obama, when I was Vice President.&nbsp;<br><br>And the American auto industry, you remember, was on the rocks.&nbsp; And a lot of people, including a lot of Democrats, thought it wasn&#8217;t worth investing tra- &#8212; investing in them because the American worker wasn’t that good, and they were blah, blah, blah.<br><br>I remember the heat that I took &#8212; some of you may remember as well &#8212; when I stood up and stepped into the rescue of the American automobile industry.&nbsp; My name was often taken in vain on television shows a lot, because “Why is Biden so committed to the automobile industry?”&nbsp; Well, because the fundamental mistakes that were made weren’t made by the workers; they were made by management.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, a lot of the folks who said we shouldn’t rescue the American auto industry are the same folks who are saying, “We don’t need to buy American.”&nbsp; What those people never realized is, if you give an American worker just a chance &#8212; a fighting chance &#8212; there’s nothing they won’t do.&nbsp; And if you give American companies and communities the chance, there’s nothing they can’t build.&nbsp; Just look around.&nbsp;<br><br>From the steel that raised our cities to these trucks behind me that are going to carry the economy forward, to the workers who are the heart and soul and spine of this nation &#8212;&nbsp;American strength is here.&nbsp; It’s in this region.&nbsp; It’s you.&nbsp; It’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; It’s you.<br><br>And that’s why I’ve told every foreign leader &#8212; and I just got back from Europe meeting with heads of state.&nbsp; One said to me &#8212; I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And he said, “For how long?”&nbsp; A head of state.&nbsp; And I said, “You know, I want to tell you something: It’s never, ever, ever been a good bet to bet against America.&nbsp; We never fail when we decide we’re going to do something.”<br><br>So, today, I’m placing my bet on America.&nbsp; I know you all are going to make sure it pays off because it will pay off with good jobs, long-term employment, the ability for America to, once again, reassert its role as the most powerful economy in the world.&nbsp; And that is as important as the size of our military and as anything else we do.&nbsp; And if we think we’re not in a race, well, guess what?&nbsp; Take a look at China.&nbsp; Take a look at China.&nbsp;<br><br>I spent an awful lot of time with Xi Jinping, President of China &#8212; more than, I’m told, than any other world leader has.&nbsp; And he’s made it really clear he doesn’t think democracies can compete in the 21st century.&nbsp; And I spent over 25 hours alone with him over the period of the last five years &#8212; seven years.<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; Just come back from a conference with Putin.&nbsp; He thinks the same thing.&nbsp; Well, I got news for them: Autocracies will not succeed if we do what we can do as a democracy.&nbsp; Democracies.&nbsp;<br><br>And if you noticed, not a joke, a lot of the rest of the world is hedging their bets whether to move toward autocracy or stay with democracies.<br><br>We have it all, folks.&nbsp; We have everything that we need in this country to &#8212; not only today, but for my grandchildren &#8212; to be in a situation where we’re still the most powerful physically and most powerful economic nation in the world that treats other nations decently and maintains the peace.&nbsp; That’s who we are.&nbsp; That’s America.<br><br>We’re the most unique nation in the history of the world.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; By that I mean: Every other nation was put together based on ethnicity or religion, geography &#8212; but not America.&nbsp; America is the most unique nation in the world, and literally, we’re based on the ide- &#8212; an idea.&nbsp; An idea is what formed America.&nbsp; And the idea was &#8212; and it sounds corny, but it is absolutely true &#8212; no other nation has this as their organizing principle: “We hold these truths to be self-evident that all men and women are created equal…endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights…life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.”&nbsp;<br><br>We believe it.&nbsp; We’ve never accomplished it, but every generation that moved us closer and closer and closer to inclusion.&nbsp; That’s why America’s real power is not in the exercise of a military power, but people follow us because of our example.&nbsp; That’s why the rest of the world follows us.&nbsp;<br><br>It was about time we get back up and reassert who we are.&nbsp; This is the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, and God bless you all.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>2:32 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announced Three Key&#160;Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/president-biden-announced-three-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 20:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following three individuals to serve in key roles: Jainey Bavishi, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, Department of Commerce Chavonda Jacobs-Young, Nominee for Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics, Department of Agriculture Thea Kendler, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Export&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following three individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Jainey Bavishi, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, Department of Commerce</li><li>Chavonda Jacobs-Young, Nominee for Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics, Department of Agriculture</li><li>Thea Kendler, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Export Administration, Department of Commerce</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Jainey Bavishi, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, Department of Commerce</u></strong></p>



<p>Jainey&nbsp;K.&nbsp;Bavishi&nbsp;serves as the Director of the New York City Mayor’s Office of Climate Resiliency.&nbsp; In this role, she leads a cross-disciplinary&nbsp;team that prepares the city for the impacts of climate change through science-based analysis, policy, program, and project development, and capacity building. During the Obama Administration, Bavishi served as the Associate Director for Climate Preparedness at the White House Council on Environmental Quality and Director of External Affairs and Senior Policy Advisor at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).&nbsp;&nbsp;Bavishi&nbsp;also served as the Executive Director of R3ADY Asia-Pacific,&nbsp;focused on enhancing disaster risk reduction and resilience in the Asia-Pacific region,&nbsp;based in Honolulu, Hawaii.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Previously, she was the Founding Director of the Equity and Inclusion Campaign, a coalition of community-based leaders in the Gulf Coast region that focused on recovery from Hurricanes Katrina, Rita, Gustav and Ike, at the Louisiana Disaster Recovery Foundation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Bavishi&nbsp;has a Master’s degree in city planning from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and a Bachelor’s degree in public policy and cultural anthropology from Duke University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Chavonda Jacobs-Young, Nominee for Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics, Department of Agriculture</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Chavonda Jacobs-Young is the Administrator of the USDA Agricultural Research Service and currently serves as the Acting Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics and as Acting USDA Chief Scientist. Dr. Jacobs-Young is the first woman and person of color to lead this agency, which manages an annual budget of $1.82 billion.</p>



<p>During Dr. Jacobs-Young’s distinguished federal career, she has excelled in top-level positions in USDA. She led the Office of National Programs and the Office of International Research as the Agricultural Research Service Associate Administrator for Research Programs. As the founding Director of the Office of the Chief Scientist at USDA, she facilitated the coordination of scientific leadership across federal agencies within USDA, ensuring that the research and scientific information and data produced were held to the highest standards of scientific integrity. As Acting Director for USDA&#8217;s National Institute of Food and Agriculture, she provided leadership and funding for programs that advanced agriculture-related sciences. And as Acting Deputy Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics Mission Area, she oversaw Agricultural Research Service, National Institute of Food and Agriculture, National Agriculture Statistics Service, Economic Research Service, and Office of the Chief Scientist.</p>



<p>Dr. Jacobs-Young has also served as a senior policy analyst for agriculture in the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, where she supported the President&#8217;s Science Advisor and others within the Executive Office of the President during the Obama Administration on high priority agricultural scientific issues.</p>



<p>Dr. Jacobs-Young is a native of Augusta, Georgia. She received a B.S. degree in Pulp and Paper Science and Technology from North Carolina State University, where she was a three-time ACC track champion. She earned M.S. and Ph.D. degrees in Wood and Paper Science, also from North Carolina State University, becoming the first African American woman in the country to receive a Ph.D. in this field. She is also a graduate of American University&#8217;s Key Executive Program on Public Policy Implementation. In addition to her career, and community service, Dr. Jacobs-Young is committed to family. This year she will celebrate her 25th wedding anniversary to Arland Young and she is mom to Autumn and Arland, Jr.</p>



<p><strong><u>Thea Kendler, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Export Administration, Department of Commerce</u></strong></p>



<p>Thea Kendler is an experienced federal government attorney whose career focuses on national security and international trade law. As a trial attorney in the Department of Justice’s National Security Division, Counterintelligence and Export Control Section, Ms. Kendler partners with U.S. Attorney’s Offices and federal agents around the country to investigate and prosecute cases primarily involving export controls, economic espionage, and counterintelligence. Ms. Kendler frequently speaks to international audiences on strategic trade controls and conducts training for foreign government officials on best border security law enforcement practices.</p>



<p>Before joining the Justice Department in 2014, Ms. Kendler served as Senior Counsel in the Commerce Department’s Office of Chief Counsel for Industry and Security, providing legal advice on export controls regulations and enforcement to the Bureau of Industry and Security. Earlier in her career, she practiced in the International Trade section of the law firm Akin Gump Strauss Hauer &amp; Feld LLP, where she conducted internal investigations and represented corporate clients in export controls, antidumping and countervailing duty, and Customs proceedings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ms. Kendler graduated from the University of Pennsylvania Law School, where in her third year she received a Foreign Language and Area Studies (FLAS) grant from the U.S. Department of Education to further her Chinese study.&nbsp; Her undergraduate degree is from Princeton University with a concentration in the School of Public and International Affairs and certificates in East Asian Studies and Chinese Culture.&nbsp; While in college, she studied Chinese in Beijing, China, and Japanese in Kanazawa, Japan.&nbsp; Ms. Kendler is admitted to the New York and District of Columbia Bars.&nbsp; She lives in Bethesda, Maryland, with her husband and two children.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Bipartisan Infrastructure&#160;Deal</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-deal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 20:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am pleased to join a bipartisan group of United States Senators and announce our deal to make the most significant long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century. I want to thank the bipartisan group for working together and the committee chairs for raising their ideas and concerns with me, Vice&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I am pleased to join a bipartisan group of United States Senators and announce our deal to make the most significant long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century.</p>



<p>I want to thank the bipartisan group for working together and the committee chairs for raising their ideas and concerns with me, Vice President Harris, and members of the Cabinet.</p>



<p>This deal signals to the world that our democracy can function, deliver, and do big things. As we did with the transcontinental railroad and the interstate highway, we will once again transform America and propel us into the future.</p>



<p>This deal makes key investments to put people to work all across the country—in cities, small towns, rural communities, and across our coastlines and plains.</p>



<p>It will put Americans to work in good-paying, union jobs repairing our roads and bridges. It will put plumbers and pipefitters to work replacing all of the nation’s lead water pipes so every child and every American can turn on the faucet at home or school and drink clean water—including in low-income communities and communities of color that have been disproportionally affected by dangerous lead pipes.</p>



<p>Americans will build transmission lines and upgrade our power grid to be more resilient and cleaner. Americans will strengthen our infrastructure, like our levees, in the face of extreme weather like superstorms, wildfires, droughts, hurricanes, and heat waves.</p>



<p>American workers will make a historic investment to install the first-ever national network electric vehicle charging stations and undertake critical environmental clean-ups.</p>



<p>This bipartisan deal is the most important investment in public transit in American history and the most important investment in rail since the creation of Amtrak 50 years ago. It will deliver high speed internet to every American.</p>



<p>And, we’re going to do it without raising taxes by one cent on people making less than $400,000 a year—no gas tax increase and no fee on electric vehicles.</p>



<p>This agreement will help ensure that America can compete in the global economy just when we are in a race with China and the rest of the world for the 21<sup>st</sup> Century.</p>



<p>And, it comes at a critical time. We are emerging from this pandemic with an economy that is back from the brink. We are seeing the fastest job growth on record. We are experiencing the fastest economic growth in nearly four decades.</p>



<p>Everyone from unions to business leaders and economists left, right, and center believe the public investments in this deal will mean more jobs, higher productivity, and higher growth for our economy over the long term. Experts believe that the majority of the deal’s benefits will flow to working families.</p>



<p>Of course, neither side got everything they wanted in this deal. But that’s what it means to compromise and forge consensus—the heart of democracy. As the deal goes to the entire Senate, there is still plenty of work ahead to bring this home. There will be disagreements to resolve and more compromise to forge along the way.</p>



<p>But the bottom line is—the Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal is a blue-collar blueprint to rebuild America that will help make our historic economic recovery a historic long-term boom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Historic Bipartisan Infrastructure&#160;Deal</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/fact-sheet-historic-bipartisan-infrastructure-deal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 19:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25237</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the President and the bipartisan group announced agreement on the details of a once-in-a-generation investment in our infrastructure, which will be taken up in the Senate for consideration. In total, the deal includes $550 billion in new federal investment in America’s infrastructure. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal will grow the economy, enhance our competitiveness, create&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the President and the bipartisan group announced agreement on the details of a once-in-a-generation investment in our infrastructure, which will be taken up in the Senate for consideration. In total, the deal includes $550 billion in new federal investment in America’s infrastructure. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal will grow the economy, enhance our competitiveness, create good jobs, and make our economy more sustainable, resilient, and just.<br><br>The deal will create good-paying, union jobs. With the President’s Build Back Better Agenda, these investments will add, on average, around 2 million jobs <em>per year</em> over the course of the decade, while accelerating America’s path to full employment and increasing labor force participation.<br><br>President Biden believes that we must invest in our country and in our people by creating good-paying union jobs, tackling the climate crisis, and growing the economy sustainably and equitably for decades to come. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal will deliver progress towards those objectives for working families across the country. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal:</p>



<ul><li>Makes the largest federal investment in public transit ever</li><li>Makes the largest federal investment in passenger rail since the creation of Amtrak</li><li>Makes the single largest dedicated bridge investment since the construction of the interstate highway system</li><li>Makes the largest investment in clean drinking water and waste water infrastructure in American history, delivering clean water to millions of families</li><li>Ensures every American has access to reliable high-speed internet</li><li>Helps us tackle the climate crisis by making the largest investment in clean energy transmission and EV infrastructure in history; electrifying thousands of school and transit buses across the country; and creating a new Grid Deployment Authority to build a clean, 21<sup>st</sup> century electric grid</li></ul>



<p>The President promised to work across the aisle to deliver results for working families. He believes demonstrating that democracies can deliver is a critical challenge for his presidency. Today’s agreement shows that we can come together to position American workers, farmers, and businesses to compete and win in the 21st century.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Roads, Bridges, and Major Projects</span></strong><br><br>One in five miles, or 173,000 total miles, of our highways and major roads and 45,000 bridges are in poor condition. Bridges in poor condition pose heightened challenges in rural communities, which often may rely on a single bridge for the passage of emergency service vehicles. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal will invest $110 billion of new funds for roads, bridges, and major projects, and reauthorize the surface transportation program for the next five years building on bipartisan surface transportation reauthorization bills passed out of committee earlier this year.  This investment will repair and rebuild our roads and bridges with a focus on climate change mitigation, resilience, equity, and safety for all users, including cyclists and pedestrians. The bill includes a total of $40 billion of new funding for bridge repair, replacement, and rehabilitation, which<strong> is the single largest dedicated bridge investment since the construction of the interstate highway system</strong>. The bill also includes a total of $17.5 billion for major projects that are too large or complex for traditional funding programs but will deliver significant economic benefits to communities.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Safety</span></strong><br><br>America has one of the highest road fatality rates in the industrialized world. The deal invests $11 billion in transportation safety programs, including a new Safe Streets for All program to help states and localities reduce crashes and fatalities in their communities, especially for cyclists and pedestrians. <strong>It will more than double funding directed to programs that improve the safety of people and vehicles in our transportation system, including highway safety, truck safety, and pipeline and hazardous materials safety.</strong><br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Public Transit</span></strong><br><br>America’s transit infrastructure is inadequate – with a multibillion-dollar repair backlog, representing more than 24,000 buses, 5,000 rail cars, 200 stations, and thousands of miles of track, signals, and power systems in need of replacement. The deal invests $39 billion of new investment to modernize transit, and improve accessibility for the elderly and people with disabilities, in addition to continuing the existing transit programs for five years as part of surface transportation reauthorization.  <strong>This is the largest Federal investment in public transit in history, and devotes a larger share of funds from surface transportation reauthorization to transit in the history of the programs. It will repair and upgrade aging infrastructure, modernize bus and rail fleets, make stations accessible to all users, and bring transit service to new communities.</strong> It will replace thousands of transit vehicles, including buses, with clean, zero emission vehicles.  And, it will benefit communities of color since these households are twice as likely to take public transportation and many of these communities lack sufficient public transit options.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Passenger and Freight Rail</span></strong><br><br>Unlike highways and transit, rail lacks a multi-year funding stream to address deferred maintenance, enhance existing corridors, and build new lines in high-potential locations. The deal positions Amtrak and rail to play a central role in our transportation and economic future. <strong>This is the largest investment in passenger rail since the creation of Amtrak 50 years ago.</strong> The deal invests $66 billion in rail to eliminate the Amtrak maintenance backlog, modernize the Northeast Corridor, and bring world-class rail service to areas outside the northeast and mid-Atlantic. Within these totals, $22 billion would be provided as grants to Amtrak, $24 billion as federal-state partnership grants for Northeast Corridor modernization, $12 billion for partnership grants for intercity rail service, including high-speed rail, $5 billion for rail improvement and safety grants, and $3 billion for grade crossing safety improvements.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">EV Infrastructure</span></strong><br><br>U.S. market share of plug-in electric vehicle (EV) sales is only one-third the size of the Chinese EV market. The President believes that must change. The bill invests $7.5 billion to build out a national network of EV chargers. <strong>This is the first-ever national investment in EV charging infrastructure in the United States and is a critical element in the Biden-Harris Administration’s plan to accelerate the adoption of EVs to address the climate crisis and support domestic manufacturing jobs. </strong>The bill will provide funding for deployment of EV chargers along highway corridors to facilitate long-distance travel and within communities to provide convenient charging where people live, work, and shop.  Federal funding will have a particular focus on rural, disadvantaged, and hard-to-reach communities.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Electric Buses</span></strong><br><br>American school buses play a critical role in expanding access to education, but they are also a significant source of pollution. <strong>The deal will deliver thousands of electric school buses nationwide, including in rural communities, helping school districts across the country buy clean, American-made, zero emission buses, and replace the yellow school bus fleet for America’s children.</strong> The deal invests $2.5 billion in zero emission buses, $2.5 billion in low emission buses, and $2.5 billion for ferries. These investments will drive demand for American-made batteries and vehicles, creating jobs and supporting domestic manufacturing, while also removing diesel buses from some of our most vulnerable communities. In addition, they will help the more than 25 million children and thousands of bus drivers who breathe polluted air on their rides to and from school. Diesel air pollution is linked to asthma and other health problems that hurt our communities and cause students to miss school, particularly in communities of color and Tribal communities.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Reconnecting Communities</span></strong><br><br>Too often, past transportation investments divided communities – like the Claiborne Expressway in New Orleans or I-81 in Syracuse – or it left out the people most in need of affordable transportation options. In particular, significant portions of the interstate highway system were built through Black neighborhoods. <strong>The deal creates a first-ever program to reconnect communities divided by transportation infrastructure.</strong>&nbsp; The program will fund planning, design, demolition, and reconstruction of street grids, parks, or other infrastructure through $1 billion of dedicated funding.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Airports, Ports, and Waterways</span></strong><br><br>The United States built modern aviation, but our airports lag far behind our competitors. According to some rankings, no U.S. airports rank in the top 25 of airports worldwide. Our ports and waterways need repair and reimagination too. <strong>The bill invests $17 billion in port infrastructure and $25 billion in airports to address repair and maintenance backlogs, reduce congestion and emissions near ports and airports, and drive electrification and other low-carbon technologies</strong>. Modern, resilient, and sustainable port, airport, and freight infrastructure will support U.S. competitiveness by removing bottlenecks and expediting commerce and reduce the environmental impact on neighboring communities.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Resilience and Western Water Infrastructure</span></strong><br><br>Millions of Americans feel the effects of climate change each year when their roads wash out, airport power goes down, or schools get flooded. Last year alone, the United States faced 22 extreme weather and climate-related disaster events with losses exceeding $1 billion each – a cumulative price tag of nearly $100 billion. People of color are more likely to live in areas most vulnerable to flooding and other climate change-related weather events. <strong>The deal makes our communities safer and our infrastructure more resilient to the impacts of climate change and cyber attacks, with an investment of over $50 billion.</strong> This includes funds to protect against droughts and floods, in addition to a major investment in weatherization. The bill is the largest investment in the resilience of physical and natural systems in American history.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Clean Drinking Water</span></strong><br><br>Currently, up to 10 million American households and 400,000 schools and child care centers lack safe drinking water. <strong>The deal’s $55 billion investment represents the largest investment in clean drinking water in American history, including dedicated funding to replace lead service lines and the dangerous chemical PFAS (per- and polyfluoroalkyl).</strong> It will replace all of the nation’s lead pipes and service lines. From rural towns to struggling cities, the deal invests in water infrastructure across America, including in Tribal Nations and disadvantaged communities that need it most.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">High-Speed Internet</span></strong></p>



<p>Broadband internet is necessary for Americans to do their jobs, to participate equally in school learning, health care, and to stay connected. Yet, by one definition, more than 30 million Americans live in areas where there is no broadband infrastructure that provides minimally acceptable speeds – a particular problem in rural communities throughout the country. <strong>The deal’s $65 billion investment ensures every American has access to reliable high-speed internet with an historic investment in broadband infrastructure deployment, </strong>just as the federal government made a historic effort to provide electricity to every American nearly one hundred years ago.</p>



<p>The bill will also help lower prices for internet service by requiring funding recipients to offer a low-cost affordable plan, by creating price transparency and helping families comparison shop, and by boosting competition in areas where existing providers aren’t providing adequate service. It will also help close the digital divide by passing the Digital Equity Act, ending digital redlining, and creating a permanent program to help more low-income households access the internet.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Environmental Remediation</span></strong></p>



<p>In thousands of rural and urban communities around the country, hundreds of thousands of former industrial and energy sites are now idle – sources of blight and pollution. 26% of Black Americans and 29% of Hispanic Americans live within 3 miles of a Superfund site, a higher percentage than for Americans overall. Proximity to a Superfund site can lead to elevated levels of lead in children’s blood. <strong>The deal invests $21 billion in environmental remediation, making the largest investment in addressing the legacy pollution that harms the public health of communities and neighborhoods in American history, creating good-paying union jobs in hard-hit energy communities and advancing economic and environmental justice. </strong>The bill includes funds to clean up superfund and brownfield sites, reclaim abandoned mine land and cap orphaned gas wells.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Power Infrastructure</span></strong><br><br>As the recent Texas power outages demonstrated, our aging electric grid needs urgent modernization. A Department of Energy study found that power outages cost the U.S. economy up to $70 billion annually. <strong>The deal’s $73 billion investment is the single largest investment in clean energy transmission in American history</strong>.&nbsp; It upgrades our power infrastructure, including by building thousands of miles of new, resilient transmission lines to facilitate the expansion of renewable energy. It creates a new Grid Deployment Authority, invests in research and development for advanced transmission and electricity distribution technologies, and promotes smart grid technologies that deliver flexibility and resilience. It invests in demonstration projects and research hubs for next generation technologies like advanced nuclear reactors, carbon capture, and clean hydrogen.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Offsets</span></strong><br><br>In the years ahead, the deal will generate significant economic benefits. It is financed through a combination of redirecting unspent emergency relief funds, targeted corporate user fees, strengthening tax enforcement when it comes to crypto currencies, and other bipartisan measures, in addition to the revenue generated from higher economic growth as a result of the investments.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre Aboard Air Force One En Route Allentown,&#160;PA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/28/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-aboard-air-force-one-en-route-allentown-pa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Allentown, Pennsylvania 11:45 A.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &#160;I’ve never done this on the small plane before, so bear with me. &#160;Hey, everybody.&#160; Good to see everyone.&#160; Welcome to our flight to Lehigh, Pennsyl &#8212; Valley, today in Pennsylvania. As you all know, today we announced a proposed Buy American rule.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Allentown, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>11:45 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &nbsp;I’ve never done this on the small plane before, so bear with me. &nbsp;Hey, everybody.&nbsp; Good to see everyone.&nbsp; Welcome to our flight to Lehigh, Pennsyl &#8212; Valley, today in Pennsylvania.</p>



<p>As you all know, today we announced a proposed Buy American rule.&nbsp; The President believes that when we spend American taxpayer dollars, it should support American workers and business.</p>



<p>In Lehigh Valley today, he will talk about the importance of this Buy American policy to support and grow more American companies and put more American workers in good-paying union jobs, strengthen American manufacturing, and secure critical supply chains while confronting the climate crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During his trip, the President will visit the Lehigh Valley Operations manufacturing facility for Mack Trucks.&nbsp; There are more than 1,500 Mack trucks in the federal fleet, used by both military and civilian agencies.&nbsp; And the President will receive a briefing on the Mack Trucks’ electrical dump truck.</p>



<p>Every Mack truck built for the North American market gets its start at the companies cab and vehicle assembly plant in the lower Macu- &#8212; Macungie township &#8212; I know I messed that up; apologies to Pennsylvania and that township.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ability to build and sell these new trucks would be helped by the President’s proposed investment in Buy American production incentives for domestic electric vehicle manufacturing.</p>



<p>Today, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, CFBP [CFPB], is launching a new rental assistant finder for Americans who may be behind on their rent.&nbsp; You can go to ConsumerFinance.gov/RentHelp and input location information to find local rental assistance programs in the area and apply for assistance.</p>



<p>Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, billions of dollars in federal rental assistance is available to renters who are behind on housing costs and for landlords who have struggled during the pandemic.</p>



<p>Private-sector companies from PayPal and Square, Lyft, and GoFundMe, to nonprofits including United Way, the National Low Income Housing Coalition, and Bread for the World will join with the Biden-Harris administration to raise awareness for this new and important tool, as well as the resources available to assist tenants and landlords.</p>



<p>And as we announced last week, in June, over $1.5 billion was distributed to renters and landlords more than previous &#8212; the previous five months.</p>



<p>And with that, Josh, do you want to kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Two subject areas. &nbsp;First, we know that the administration is considering a vaccine mandate for federal employees.&nbsp; Can you give us any guidance in terms of how you&#8217;re defining federal employees?&nbsp; Does that include military, contractors? &nbsp;Would visitors to federal agencies also fall under that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, Josh, let me first say that, you know, our goal as a federal employer is to keep our employees safe and to also save lives.&nbsp; That is the number-one goal that we have here.</p>



<p>While no decision has been finalized, I will say that the attestation of vaccination for federal employees is one option under strong consideration.&nbsp; So, attestation &#8212; what we mean by that is confirming &#8212; which means confirming vaccination status or abiding by stringent COVID-19 protocols, like mandatory mask wearing, even in communities not with high or subsequent substantial spread, and regular testing.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also said requirements for vaccination may be under consideration for certain entities within the government.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates to preview on that front today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned that imposing a mask mandate could exacerbate divisions in the United States that have already been so present in terms of vaccination rates?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me just &#8212; like I said, they’re &#8212; right now we are &#8212; have many options that we&#8217;re looking under consideration.</p>



<p>But let me just step back, because I think &#8212; I want to take this opportunity, with the CDC mask guidance that was given &#8212; again, not a mandate, as you know, but a guidance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, yesterday the CDC did exactly what it was &#8212; it&#8217;s supposed to do.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sure you all saw &#8212; are tracking what the public health experts have said &#8212; said this as &#8212; said as much.&nbsp; The message is simple: If you are in an area where Delta is surging, you should mask up indoors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CDC has to adapt to the virus.&nbsp; And unfortunately, because not enough Americans have stepped up to get vaccinated, they had to provide new guidance to help save lives, especially for those immunocompromised and children, children who &#8212; especially those children who are 11 and under who do not have &#8212; are not able to get vaccinated at this time.&nbsp; So, this is critical.</p>



<p>Again, we want to make sure we&#8217;re saving lives.&nbsp; The CDC guidance was done nonpartisan. &nbsp;It was done as they are looking through guidance, and to really meet the moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re dealing with a virus, as you all know, that&#8217;s unprecedented.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no playbook for this virus.&nbsp; And again, we need to make sure that we&#8217;re saving lives.&nbsp; And we are going to continue to do everything that we can to make sure people are getting vaccinated.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, why would the White House be confident that people in these red zones now will listen to this new mask guidance if they&#8217;ve shrugged off the vaccination message from the White House, if they&#8217;ve shrugged off mask guidance before?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why are you so confident now?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, Karen, let me first say that the CDC is a &#8212; is a body that is highly respected.&nbsp; It is a body that people look towards.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re right &#8212; you know, we &#8212; we are &#8212; we are going to make sure that we go community by community.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure the CDC is going to have a communication &#8212; you know, kind of apparatus of communication with local governments on how to best do this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this was &#8212; this needed to happen.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; They are following the science.&nbsp; We have said this all along.&nbsp; The science is the North Star.&nbsp; We have to listen to public health experts.&nbsp; And, right now, again, we&#8217;re trying to make sure that we&#8217;re saving lives.</p>



<p>But, again, we need to make sure that people who are not vaccinated get vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. HAYES:&nbsp; We have to stop because we have to land.&nbsp; They&#8217;re making us sit down because we have to land.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; Sorry, guys.</p>



<p>11:52 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden on the Passing of Former Wyoming Senator Mike&#160;Enzi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-former-wyoming-senator-mike-enzi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For twelve years, I had the privilege of serving with Mike Enzi in the United States Senate. While we sat on different sides of the aisle, I always saw him first as a public servant who conducted himself with decency, honor, and integrity. The Eagle Scout and National Guardsman, the small business owner and small-town&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For twelve years, I had the privilege of serving with Mike Enzi in the United States Senate. While we sat on different sides of the aisle, I always saw him first as a public servant who conducted himself with decency, honor, and integrity.<br><br>The Eagle Scout and National Guardsman, the small business owner and small-town mayor, the state legislator who became a U.S. Senator — Mike never forgot where he came from, and never forgot the people of his beloved Wyoming who placed their trust in him election after election.<br><br>Jill and I are saddened to learn of his passing, and our prayers are with his wife Diana, their children and grandchildren, and his countless friends, colleagues, and staff.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Companies, Non-Profits, Government Agencies Answer Biden-&#8288;Harris Call: Make Combined Commitment to Alert Tens of Millions of Americans to Emergency Rental&#160;Assistance</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/fact-sheet-companies-non-profits-government-agencies-answer-biden-harris-call-make-combined-commitment-to-alert-tens-of-millions-of-americans-to-emergency-rental-assistance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25203</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Major companies, non-profits, and government agencies from the Social Security Administration to the Department of Veterans Affairs, to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention have answered the Biden-Harris Administration’s Call to Action to spread the word and alert Americans that emergency rental assistance is available.&#160; The combined commitments announced today – part of an&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Major companies, non-profits, and government agencies from the Social Security Administration to the Department of Veterans Affairs, to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention have answered the Biden-Harris Administration’s Call to Action to spread the word and alert Americans that emergency rental assistance is available.&nbsp; The combined commitments announced today – part of an ongoing all-out push to make sure tenants and landlords take advantage of federal rental assistance to help cover rent, utilities, and other housing costs and keep people in their homes – could reach tens of millions of Americans.</p>



<p>The continued call to action coincides with the launch of a new rental assistance finder produced by the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB). Americans who may be behind on rent can go to <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/coronavirus/mortgage-and-housing-assistance/renter-protections/find-help-with-rent-and-utilities/?utm_source=vanity&amp;utm_medium=outreach&amp;utm_campaign=renthelp">ConsumerFinance.gov/RentHelp</a> and input information on their location to find local rental assistance programs in their area and apply for assistance.</p>



<p>Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, billions of dollars in federal rental assistance is available to renters who are behind on&nbsp;housing costs,&nbsp;as well as landlords who have struggled during the pandemic. The Administration is building on a whole-of-government effort and engaging a wide variety of stakeholders to spread awareness of the CFPB’s new tool, as well as the resources available to assist tenants and landlords.</p>



<p>Emergency rental assistance is available to tenants in all 50 states, Washington, D.C., territories, and in Tribal areas, and will continue to be available after the expiration of the CDC eviction moratorium on August 1, 2021. The continued Call to Action builds on the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initiatives-to-promote-housing-stability-by-supporting-vulnerable-tenants-and-preventing-foreclosures/">groundwork laid over the past several months</a> by the Administration to engage renters and landlords, including hosting two virtual convenings with thousands of participants to share best practices on eviction prevention and build local plans of action, streamline guidance for the rental assistance program to make it easier and more efficient, and engage agencies across the federal government to help get the word out to households in need.</p>



<p>For more general information about the Emergency Rental Assistance program, <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/coronavirus/mortgage-and-housing-assistance/renter-protections/emergency-rental-assistance-for-renters/?utm_source=paypal&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=era_outreach">visit the unified federal housing assistance portal hosted by the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</a>.</p>



<p>Agencies across the federal government, non-profit groups, faith-based organizations, and private sector companies are responding to the Biden-Harris Administration’s call to action to raise awareness. We expect that these efforts will reach tens of millions of Americans.</p>



<p><strong>Private sector and non-profit commitments include:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>PayPal</strong>, where many pay their rent and monthly bills, will include messaging on emergency rental assistance and a link to the CFPB look-up tool in their PayPal and Venmo apps and on paypal.com.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Square, Inc.</strong> will provide information about the CFPB tool and emergency rental assistance on Cash App – a popular place to pay rent and bills that as of December 2020 had more than 36 million monthly transacting active customers &#8211; and on their Square Seller Community platform.</li><li><strong>GoFundMe </strong>will send direct emails to roughly 20,000 people who have recently started fundraising campaigns in the “food, rent, or monthly bills” category on the GoFundMe site.</li><li><strong>Lyft </strong>will spread the word about emergency rental assistance and the new CFPB tool via a blog post for the Lyft Community.</li><li><strong>Avail</strong>, a property management application that touches landlords and renters, will send emails directly to their users and will post a banner on their website with an anticipated reach of at least 21,000 people per week.</li><li><strong>Propel,</strong> a mission-driven financial technology company, will connect more than 5 million low-income families to resources to help them receive emergency rental assistance.</li><li><strong>National Apartment Association </strong>will send an alert to their 90,000 members nationwide.</li><li><strong>National Multifamily Housing Coalition </strong>will share the CFPB tool with their 10,000 members through emails and a newsletter.</li><li><strong>The National Low Income Housing Coalition </strong>will include a link to the CFPB tool on their website, place an article about the tool and emergency rental assistance in their newsletter which is distributed to 135,000 people, and will brief stakeholders on their weekly call.</li><li><strong>United Way</strong> will raise awareness through their state associations and by sharing the information with the United Way Financial Stability Cohort.</li><li><strong>The Arc</strong>, a non-profit dedicated to promoting and protecting human rights of people with intellectual and developmental disabilities, will send an email with the information to their 600 national chapters.</li><li><strong>Children’s Defense Fund </strong>will share the information with their state offices and will publish a blog post promoting the CFPB tool.</li><li><strong>Operation HOPE</strong>, a non-profit organization dedicated to poverty alleviation and financial inclusion for low and moderate-income youth and adults, will share the CFPB tool and information on emergency rental assistance with a network of over 180 community-based financial coaches and will include the information in their weekly news briefing which reaches over 60,000 people.</li><li><strong>Bread for the World</strong>, a faith-based organization dedicated to poverty and hunger alleviation, will host regional events throughout the country with local faith leaders and churches to educate them about emergency rental assistance.</li></ul>



<p>This Call to Action remains open to everyone – other companies, non-profits, faith-based organizations, and more can answer the Call to Action by leveraging their own communications channels to spread the word.</p>



<p><strong>Commitments from the Administration include:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Veterans Affairs </strong>is sharing the information in a newsletter that reaches 12 million veterans.</li><li><strong>The Social Security Administration </strong>is creating a new, special web page in both English and Spanish dedicated to emergency rental assistance and linking to the CFPB tool.</li><li><strong>The U.S. Department of Agriculture </strong>is building off of previous outreach efforts by sending letters to 65,000 people who live in USDA multi-family properties who are not receiving rental assistance; sharing information with Food Nutrition Service Regional Leads who will then share information with State Departments of Social Services that work with SNAP recipients; and holding a webinar in the coming weeks to provide background on emergency rental assistance.</li><li><strong>The Department of Health and Human Services</strong> is leveraging the communications channels of several of its operating divisions to spread awareness. Specifically: <ul><li>The Administration for Community Living (ACL) is sharing the information about emergency rental assistance with 200,000 community-based organizations that serve people with disabilities and older adults, many of whom are low income and at higher risk for eviction.</li></ul><ul><li>The Administration for Children and Families (ACF) is amplifying the existence of emergency rental assistance and the new CFPB tool with program grantees who can pass along information in the communities they serve.</li></ul><ul><li>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) is sharing the information about emergency rental assistance with healthcare providers and local health departments, and is putting the information on the CDC’s COVID-19 website.</li></ul><ul><li>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) is incorporating messaging around the CFPB tool and emergency rental assistance into call center scripts and will share with partners via their listserv.</li></ul><ul><li>Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) is promoting the CFPB tool and emergency rental assistance via the Maternal and Child Health Bureau and the Federal Office of Rural Policy.</li></ul><ul><li>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) is sending emergency rental assistance information to state offices of mental health and homelessness coordinators throughout the country that work with the Projects for Assistance in Transition for Homelessness (PATH) program. The PATH program provides support to individuals with serious mental illness who are experiencing homelessness.</li></ul></li><li><strong>The Department of the Treasury </strong>is sharing the CFPB tool with state and local governments and tribes who are administering emergency rental assistance programs.</li><li><strong>The Department of Housing and Urban Development</strong> is hosting webinars for non-profit groups and faith-based organizations and is developing their own website to distribute information on emergency rental assistance.</li><li><strong>The U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness </strong>is distributing information about emergency rental assistance through a newsletter that reaches over 34,000 people.</li><li><strong>The Census Bureau </strong>will share the CFPB tool and information on emergency rental assistance with members of their Census Counts and States Count lists. The Census Counts list includes over 60 national organizations with a deep investment in meeting the needs of marginalized communities and the States Count list includes partners in all 50 states plus the District of Columbia.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Security Memorandum on Improving Cybersecurity for Critical Infrastructure Control&#160;Systems</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/national-security-memorandum-on-improving-cybersecurity-for-critical-infrastructure-control-systems/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 13:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Protection of our Nation&#8217;s critical infrastructure is a responsibility of the government at the Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial levels and of the owners and operators of that infrastructure.&#160; The cybersecurity threats posed to the systems that control and operate the critical infrastructure on which we all depend are among the most significant and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Protection of our Nation&#8217;s critical infrastructure is a responsibility of the government at the Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial levels and of the owners and operators of that infrastructure.&nbsp; The cybersecurity threats posed to the systems that control and operate the critical infrastructure on which we all depend are among the most significant and growing issues confronting our Nation.&nbsp; The degradation, destruction, or malfunction of systems that control this infrastructure could cause significant harm to the national and economic security of the United States.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section&nbsp;1.</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Policy.</span>&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to safeguard the critical infrastructure of the Nation, with a particular focus on the cybersecurity and resilience of systems supporting National Critical Functions, defined as the functions of Government and the private sector so vital to the United States that their disruption, corruption, or dysfunction would have a debilitating effect on national security, economic security, public health or safety, or any combination thereof.&nbsp;<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.&nbsp;2.</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Industrial Control Systems Cybersecurity Initiative.</span>&nbsp; Accordingly, I have established an Industrial Control Systems Cybersecurity Initiative (Initiative), a voluntary, collaborative effort between the Federal Government and the critical infrastructure community to significantly improve the cybersecurity of these critical systems.&nbsp; The primary objective of this Initiative is to defend the United&nbsp;States&#8217; critical infrastructure by encouraging and facilitating deployment of technologies and systems that provide threat visibility, indications, detection, and warnings, and that facilitate response capabilities for cybersecurity in essential control system and operational technology networks.&nbsp; The goal of the Initiative is to greatly expand deployment of these technologies across priority critical infrastructure.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.&nbsp;3.</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Furthering the Industrial Control Systems Cybersecurity Initiative.&nbsp;</span> The Initiative creates a path for Government and industry to collaborate to take immediate action, within their respective spheres of control, to address these serious threats.&nbsp; The Initiative builds on, expands, and accelerates ongoing cybersecurity efforts in critical infrastructure sectors and is an important step in addressing these threats.&nbsp; We cannot address threats we cannot see; therefore, deploying systems and technologies that can monitor control systems to detect malicious activity and facilitate response actions to cyber threats is central to ensuring the safe operations of these critical systems.&nbsp; The Federal Government will work with industry to share threat information for priority control system critical infrastructure throughout the country.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Initiative began with a pilot effort with the Electricity Subsector, and is now followed by a similar effort for natural gas pipelines.&nbsp; Efforts for the Water and Wastewater Sector Systems and Chemical Sector will follow later this year.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Sector Risk Management Agencies, as defined in section&nbsp;9002(a)(7) of Public Law 116-283, and other executive departments and agencies (agencies), as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, shall work with critical infrastructure stakeholders and owners and operators to implement the principles and policy outlined in this memorandum.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.&nbsp;4.</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity Performance Goals.&nbsp;</span> Cybersecurity needs vary among critical infrastructure sectors, as do cybersecurity practices.&nbsp; However, there is a need for baseline cybersecurity goals that are consistent across all critical infrastructure sectors, as well as a need for security controls for select critical infrastructure that is dependent on control systems.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Pursuant to section 7(d) of Executive Order 13636 of&nbsp;February 12, 2013 (Improving Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity), the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce (through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology) and other agencies, as appropriate, shall develop and issue cybersecurity performance goals for critical infrastructure to&nbsp;further a common understanding of the baseline security practices that critical infrastructure owners and operators should follow to protect national and economic security, as well&nbsp;as public health and safety.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;This effort shall begin with the Secretary of Homeland&nbsp;Security issuing preliminary goals for control systems&nbsp;across critical infrastructure sectors no later than September&nbsp;22,&nbsp;2021, followed by the issuance of final cross-sector control system goals within 1 year of the date of this memorandum.&nbsp; Additionally, following consultations with relevant agencies, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue sector-specific critical infrastructure cybersecurity performance goals within 1 year of the date of this memorandum.&nbsp; These performance goals should serve as clear guidance to owners and operators about cybersecurity practices and postures that the American people can trust and should expect for such essential services.&nbsp; That effort may also include an examination of whether additional legal authorities would be beneficial to enhancing the cybersecurity of critical infrastructure, which is vital to the American people and the security of our Nation.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.&nbsp;5.</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline">General Provisions.</span>&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of&nbsp;Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with&nbsp;applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations, where funding assistance may be required to implement control system cybersecurity recommendations.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United&nbsp;States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on Improving Cybersecurity of U.S. Critical&#160;Infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/28/background-press-call-on-improving-cybersecurity-of-u-s-critical-infrastructure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[6:02 P.M. EDT&#160;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Thank you. &#160;Hey, everyone.&#160; Thank you for joining us on a 6:00 p.m. on a Tuesday evening.&#160; So, you’re joined by senior administration officials today to give you an embargoed preview of a step we’re announcing tomorrow to protect the cybersecurity of our critical infrastructure.&#160; This is embargoed until 9:00&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>6:02 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you. &nbsp;Hey, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us on a 6:00 p.m. on a Tuesday evening.&nbsp; So, you’re joined by senior administration officials today to give you an embargoed preview of a step we’re announcing tomorrow to protect the cybersecurity of our critical infrastructure.&nbsp; This is embargoed until 9:00 a.m. Eastern tomorrow, Wednesday, July 28.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just for your awareness and not for reporting, you’re joined by [senior administration official].&nbsp; I’m going to turn it over to [senior administration official] to kick us off.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; It’s good to be here with you today.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I’ll walk you through an update on our efforts to protect U.S. critical infrastructure from the growing, persistent, and sophisticated threats, and talk about the specific effort we will be rolling out tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, first, just to kind of put in context the administration’s overall approach to cybersecurity, as I’ve talked about in the past, our approach to addressing cyber threats have three lines of effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>First: Modernizing our defenses.&nbsp; Modernizing national defenses, federal government, state and local government critical infrastructure, incentives to the broader private sector, so that they’re modern enough to meet the threat.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second: Rebuilding our presence on the international stage.&nbsp; The work we’re doing to build coalitions &#8212; for example, to counter ransomware.&nbsp; The outreach we’re doing, you saw in the G7, where we brought countries together &#8212; the recent attribution of the Hafnium incident, MSS, with a very large number of countries joining us.&nbsp; We’re really putting a focus on collective defense and on moving out together with other countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, then, finally: Ensuring the nation is postured to compete.&nbsp; And that deals with ensuring we have all instruments of national power needed and the policies to enable their use as needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, today, I will preview a rollout we have tomorrow that further advances our efforts in the first category to modernize the nation’s defenses, specifically by defending critical infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, those of you who have reported on critical infrastructure know that federal cybersecurity regulation in the U.S. is sectoral.&nbsp; We have a patchwork of sector-specific statutes that have been adopted piecemeal, typically in response to discrete security threats in particular sectors that gained public attention.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our current posture is woefully insufficient given the evolving threat we face today.&nbsp; We really kicked the can down the road for a long time.&nbsp; The administration is committed to leveraging every authority we have, though limited, and we’re also open to new approaches, both voluntary and mandatory.<br>&nbsp;<br>Responsible critical infrastructure owners and operators should be following voluntary guidance as well as mandatory requirements in order to ensure that the critical services the American people rely on are protected from cyber threats.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, here is the new information:<br>&nbsp;<br>Tomorrow morning, the President will sign a National Security Memorandum on “Improving Cybersecurity for Critical Infrastructure Control Systems,” which addresses cybersecurity for critical infrastructure and implements long-overdue efforts to meet the threats we face.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the National Security Memorandum will direct the Department of Homeland Security’s CISA and the Department of Commerce’s NIST, in collaboration with other agencies, to develop cybersecurity performance goals for critical infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, it’ll formally establish the President’s Industrial Control System Cybersecurity Initiative.&nbsp; As you recall, the ICS initiative is a voluntary, collaborative effort between the federal government and the critical infrastructure community to facilitate the deployment of technology and systems that provide threat visibility, indicators, detections, and warnings.<br>&nbsp;<br>You’ll recall we launched the initiative in mid-April with an Electricity Subsector pilot, and already over 150 electricity utilities representing almost 90 million residential customers are either deploying or have agreed to deploy control system cybersecurity technologies.&nbsp; These are the technologies that, had they been in place, would have blocked what occurred at Colonial Pipeline in that they connect the operational technology side of the network to the IT side of the network.&nbsp; The action plan for natural gas pipelines is underway, and additional initiatives for other sectors will follow later this year.<br>&nbsp;<br>So this a public-private initiative effort with a focus to roll out these very specific technologies voluntarily, by the private sector, in close cooperation to really ensure we get those protections in place within the voluntary model that is in place for our cybersecurity for critical infrastructure today.<br>&nbsp;<br>The point we want to make is: The federal government cannot do this alone.&nbsp; Securing our critical infrastructure requires a whole-of-nation effort, and industry has to do their part.&nbsp; These may be voluntary, but we hope and expect that all responsible critical infrastructure owners and operators will apply them.&nbsp; We can’t stress it enough that they owe that to the Americans that they serve for these critical services to have more resilience.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as we’ve said, we’re exploring everything we can do to mandate strengthening of cybersecurity standards.&nbsp; You saw, last week, DHS’s Transportation Security Administration announced the second Security Directive for critical pipeline owners and operators.&nbsp; It will require owners and operators of pipelines that transport hazardous liquids and natural gas to implement a number of urgently needed protections, including implementing specific mitigation measures to protect against ransomware attacks and other known threats, IT and OT, within prescribed timeframes; developing and implementing a cybersecurity contingency and recovery plan; conducting an annual cybersecurity architecture design review.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, again, the federal government can’t do this alone, and securing our critical infrastructure requires a whole-of-nation effort.&nbsp; This National Security Memorandum, the ICS Cybersecurity Initiative, TSA’s Security Directives, and foundationally, the President’s Executive Order on Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity that he signed back in May all are parts of our focused and aggressive continuing effort to address these significant threats to our nation within that first line of modernizing defense of our cybersecurity &#8212; of the administration’s cybersecurity strategy.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, with that, I’ll pause, and I’m really looking forward to hearing your questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; So you said you&#8217;re exploring ways to mandate cyber protections for critical infrastructure.&nbsp; Do you think that the federal government does not have sufficient authorities right now?&nbsp; And do you need Congress to do something to give you those authorities to expand protections into sectors that don’t currently have it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, we have a patchwork of sector-specific statutes today that really have been adapted piecemeal.&nbsp; And we feel that the administration &#8212; the government&#8217;s responsibility is to feel confident that critical services that the American public rely on have the modernized defenses to ensure that they can continue to deliver the critical services they do.&nbsp; And the current patchwork of sector-specific statutes does not enable us to say we have confidence that there is cybersecurity thresholds in place with regard to practices and with regard to technology, governance, and practices.&nbsp; That is something that will likely require the Hill to partner with us to address.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re just beginning, you know, the first steps, and the first step is really articulating that today&#8217;s patchwork of sector-specific approaches, state-level approaches, certainly is not enabling us to meet the threat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I just &#8212; I&#8217;ll expand on that for a moment because I suspect many of you have that question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So essentially today, you know, there&#8217;s no strategic, coordinated requirement for the cybersecurity of critical infrastructure.&nbsp; To the extent, as I noted, there are mandatory cybersecurity requirements.&nbsp; They&#8217;re either sector specific &#8212; finance and chemical; they&#8217;re mandated under state or local law, like electricity ones; or they’re limited and piecemeal &#8212; water and bulk electricity are two that we’ve put a lot of work into studying in the last few weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, short of legislation, there isn&#8217;t a comprehensive way to require deployment of security technologies and practices that address, really, the threat environment that we face.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m curious, to the extent that these industries and sectors are aware that something might be coming from the administration, what sort of response and reaction have you gotten to the collaboration and the notion that they should be strengthening their defense along the lines of what the administration envisions?&nbsp; Do you anticipate any sort of pushback?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;That’s a really good question, Eric.&nbsp; Thank you for it.&nbsp; So, a big part of our approach has been actively engaging the private sector in new and innovative ways.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the President&#8217;s Industrial Control System Cybersecurity Initiative is a great example where, you know, we have the Department of Energy work very closely with the electricity subsector ISAC and identify the most critical utilities &#8212; those that serve the largest number of Americans, et cetera.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then we kicked off the pilot effort that saw, as I mentioned, over 150 electricity utilities and almost 90 million customers, you know, agreeing to deploy or having already deployed control system cybersecurity technologies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to that, we brought in a number of CEOs of utilities and pipelines to brief them on the threats so that they had the same information we had regarding the sense of urgency we feel to address the cybersecurity threat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think what we&#8217;re seeing &#8212; and I think &#8212; the final thing I would say is, in the executive order, as you saw, we really ate our own dog food in that the federal government said, &#8220;We&#8217;re going to roll out these five critical cybersecurity technologies, and we&#8217;re going to do it on a rapid timeframe.”&nbsp; Encryption rolled out, for example, within six months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I think we&#8217;re showing a willingness to do the work we need to do, and I think we&#8217;re showing a willingness to share information in new ways, come up with voluntary ways, but also making clear that given the criticality of the threat, we need to move with urgency and we need to look at all options &#8212; voluntary and mandatory &#8212; to achieve the rapid progress we need.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; I want to ask about, kind of, how you see this specific announcement having an impact, because I (inaudible) to understand it &#8212; I might be getting this wrong: Largely, this is an announcement about a voluntary public-private initiative, but it&#8217;s also kind of a larger commentary on where things are now from a standards and regulatory standpoint.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So is the idea in making this announcement to signal to these sectors that regulation could be on the way and so it&#8217;s best to start moving now in terms of their defenses?&nbsp; Or like &#8212; I&#8217;m trying to understand exactly what the purpose is, as far as your message.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; So, first, it&#8217;s the President.&nbsp; It’s the President using his position to say: Cybersecurity is a focus; we must move with urgency; the federal government cannot do this alone.&nbsp; You know, almost 90 percent of critical infrastructure in the U.S. is owned and operated by the private sector.&nbsp; And securing critical infrastructure needs a whole-of-nation effort.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So the first piece it says is: We are going to do our part by outlining performance controls that cover all critical infrastructure, that say these are the thresholds that we expect responsible owners and operators to go, and start moving there voluntarily, because that is the threshold that we as a government expect our private-sector owners and operators to meet.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And clearly, you know, we&#8217;re saying, as well, that the absence of a strategic, coordinated requirement to the cybersecurity of critical infrastructure and the absence of mandated cybersecurity requirements for critical infrastructure is what, in many ways, has brought us to the level of vulnerability we have today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re committed to addressing it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re starting with voluntary, as much as we can, because we want to do this in full partnership.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we&#8217;re also pursuing all options we have in order to make the rapid progress we need.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Evening.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; So, at the end of the Bush administration &#8212; not to, you know, date me going through briefings like this &#8212; there was a fairly similar discussion about public-private issues.&nbsp; And then, of course, in Congress, during the Obama administration, there was the failure of a cyber bill that was opposed, not merely on cybersecurity, obviously, but that would have sort of more mandated public-private elements.&nbsp; And then, in the Trump administration, there was the bulk-power order that came out, I think, just last year.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, my broader question to you is: What makes this effort different from the last three administrations trying to grapple with it, other than its comprehensiveness?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, specifically, can you tell us: Does the bulk-power order that that President Trump signed still exist?&nbsp; Did you learn from that, that it actually made any difference?&nbsp; Because that sounds to me like the closest experiment in this.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, thank you, David.&nbsp; Why is this night different from any other night?&nbsp; Well done.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say you are exactly right.&nbsp; You know, there have been multiple prior efforts to address &#8212; let&#8217;s &#8212; taking a step back &#8212; you know, multiple administrations have recognized that there are no mandated authorities to mandate cybersecurity requirements for critical infrastructure, and they&#8217;ve done their best within that.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I know, in my own career, I&#8217;ve led multiple public-private partnership efforts &#8212; right? &#8212; to try to do the kinds of things to get the sector to move.&nbsp; And there are various reasons why not: Sometimes it&#8217;s costly.&nbsp; Sometimes these sectors are regulated.&nbsp; So, unless public utilities commissions approve rate increases, they feel their costs aren&#8217;t recoverable.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that&#8217;s why, you know, we&#8217;ve tried a number of things here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I mentioned the ICS Initiative because that was where we really took a very innovative approach of identifying the most critical companies; engaging key leaders in the sector to help us; using the ISAC to bring companies together &#8212; you know, having this regular rhythm of weekly check-ins to really drive that progress.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re also saying &#8212; so that &#8212; so this NSM and the fact that it&#8217;s, you know, being announced by the President, in the context of TSA&#8217;s recent mandates that they occurred; in the context of our openly saying that we really are committed to addressing the limited and piecemeal regulation; in the context of the current environment where the threat is known and seen by critical infrastructure owners and private sectors.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, you look at Colonial Pipeline, you look at the JBS Foods, you look at Kaseya &#8212; there&#8217;s now a different threat.&nbsp; The threats that many people have talked about have become real.&nbsp; So, we believe these goals will be viewed differently, and we believe that we&#8217;re making clear that critical infrastructure should adopt these measures.&nbsp; The President is essentially saying, &#8220;We expect responsible owners and operators to meet these performance goals.&nbsp; We will look to you to implement this.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, we&#8217;re also going to be looking at all options, including working with the Congress to ensure that we can have the confidence we need to &#8212; that these critical services are protected for the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Hey, there.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; So, like, along the lines of &#8220;all possible options,&#8221; we all know the vast majority of ransomware attacks exploit vulnerabilities that have already been published in the National Vulnerability Database, and the issue is that operators haven&#8217;t implemented a patch.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think in a lot of cases, certainly the cases of &#8212; not necessarily critical infrastructure providers, but some infrastructure providers, like schools and hospitals, and possibly some critical infrastructure providers, they would say the reason they can&#8217;t implement the patches is because they can&#8217;t get the new operating system; they can&#8217;t get the new operating system because they don&#8217;t have the new hardware, and they need money.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, is there any efforts &#8212; is there any appetite to possibly award funds or grants for new IT modernization equipment to help some providers to meet these goals?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That’s a really good question &#8212; right? &#8212; because the goals &#8212; the cybersecurity performance goals are goals that they drive adoption &#8212; right? &#8212; of effective practices and control.&nbsp; And one great one could be critical patch &#8212; you know, critical vulnerabilities.&nbsp; Those with the higher CVE scores, you know, are patched within some set time period quickly, because of the risk there.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, you know, some of what we&#8217;ve been looking at is, for example &#8212; and I love your question &#8212; is for some regulated sectors: you know, public utility commissions, other entities.&nbsp; Who sets those rates so that they can recover costs?&nbsp;&nbsp; And, you know, similarly, FERC and some of the regulators &#8212; bringing them in, sharing the information regarding the threats, helping them understand so they&#8217;re a part of the story.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;ve been investing a lot of time in understanding the incentives and understanding the barriers and looking at what can be done across grants, across potential tax credits, across, potentially, you know, performance incentive mechanisms.&nbsp; Cyber insurance is a really interesting mechanism as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, each of those things we&#8217;re looking at and exploring &#8212; no announcements yet &#8212; but to really understand, you know, how to accelerate voluntary adoption.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this tonight.&nbsp; I apologize for asking something that&#8217;s not directly on topic, but we did hear from the President today on a number of cyber issues, and he made some pretty strong comments about Russia and how they&#8217;re already interfering in the 2020 &#8212; 2022 Midterm Elections.&nbsp; He called it &#8220;a clear violation of sovereignty.&#8221;&nbsp; So I wanted to ask you to expand on that, if you could, in what you’re seeing in terms of these Russian tactics for 2022 &#8212; what they&#8217;re doing, what response there has been, where that and what channels that response has been given.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Alex.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not prepared to speak more to that issue this evening, but we&#8217;ll be happy to at some point.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not prepared to speak to that more in detail.<br>&nbsp;<br>OPERATOR:&nbsp; I&#8217;m now happy to turn it back to [senior administration official] for any closing remarks.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining us today.&nbsp; Just a reminder that this call is embargoed until tomorrow, Wednesday, July 28th, until 9:00 a.m. Eastern.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you have any other questions or follow-ups, please feel free to reach out.&nbsp; Thank you for your time.<br>&nbsp;<br>6:20 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
