<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 13:30:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki Announcing President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of&#160;Singapore</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-announcing-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-lee-hsien-loong-of-singapore/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49705</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday March 29th, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of Singapore to the White House. The two Leaders will reaffirm the importance of the U.S.-Singapore Strategic Partnership. The President will review efforts to ensure a free and open Indo-Pacific and discuss Russia’s unjustified war against Ukraine with the Prime Minister. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday March 29<sup>th</sup>, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of Singapore to the White House. The two Leaders will reaffirm the importance of the U.S.-Singapore Strategic Partnership. The President will review efforts to ensure a free and open Indo-Pacific and discuss Russia’s unjustified war against Ukraine with the Prime Minister. The President also looks forward to deepening cooperation on a range of shared interests, including upholding freedom of the seas, advancing supply chain resiliency, addressing the crisis in Burma, and fighting climate change.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on the U.S. and the European Commission’s Task Force to Reduce Europe’s Dependence on Russian Fossil&#160;Fuels</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/25/background-press-call-on-the-u-s-and-the-european-commissions-task-force-to-reduce-europes-dependence-on-russian-fossil-fuels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 13:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49711</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:45 A.M. CET MODERATOR:&#160; Thanks so much for joining us, and I appreciate everyone&#8217;s flexibility.&#160; This call is going to be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&#160; Not for your reporting but just for your knowledge, on this call we have [senior administration officials]. As we said in invite for this call,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>10:45 A.M. CET<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much for joining us, and I appreciate everyone&#8217;s flexibility.&nbsp; This call is going to be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; Not for your reporting but just for your knowledge, on this call we have [senior administration officials].<br><br>As we said in invite for this call, this call will be embargoed until the call concludes.&nbsp; And you all have received a factsheet on this earlier in the morning, as well.&nbsp; And as usual, we’ll have some time for questions afterwards.&nbsp;<br><br>But with that, I will turn it over to [senior administration official].<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to say a few things about the energy agreement and then also the new transatlantic data privacy and security agreement as well.&nbsp;<br><br>So first, on energy: Today, President Biden and President von der Leyen are ushering in a new era of energy security for Europe.&nbsp;<br><br>As you all know, Putin’s war has highlighted an urgent need to reduce our dependence, Europe’s dependence on Russian fossil fuels.&nbsp; It’s very clear that Putin is continuing to use energy as a weapon to coerce and destabilize Europe.&nbsp; The task force we’re announcing today will hit hard at his ability to do this in the near term, and we’re working toward eliminating his ability to do so in the future.<br><br>So, the strategy that we’re announcing today to address the near term is to reduce demand for fossil fuels &#8212; natural gas in particular &#8212; and also filling in for natural gas that would have come from Russia in the very near term to avoid people getting cold this winter and next winter before clean energy is deployed at scale.<br><br>The President knows, and we’ve discussed at length, that the true path to energy security runs through clean energy.&nbsp; So that’s the second part of this agreement.&nbsp; The first part is getting Europe off Russian gas.&nbsp; The second part is getting Europe off gas altogether.&nbsp; And he’s committed to reducing our dependence on fossil fuels and reaping the climate, environmental, economic, and energy security benefits of moving decisively down that path.<br><br>With respect to the enhanced Privacy Shield agreement &#8212; you know, this trip has been all about unity.&nbsp; And when you have the unity that&#8217;s been forged between the U.S. and Europe, it creates a lot of trust and goodwill, and you can settle &#8212; you can settle issues that have been nagging at the relationship.&nbsp; And we did so with the Boeing-Airbus dispute &#8212; resolving that last summer, in June.&nbsp; We did so as well by lifting steel and aluminum tariffs in November.&nbsp; And this is another example of coming together on standards, on writing the rules of the road for data flows between Europe and the U.S.&nbsp; I mean, these data flows underpin the $7 trillion of commerce that takes place between the U.S. and the European Union.&nbsp;<br><br>And based on our shared &#8212; the shared importance we place on privacy, data protection, and rule of law, we&#8217;ve come together and we’ve now settled a dispute that&#8217;s been going on for over a year.&nbsp; Another example of why unity matters.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to forge our partnership even closer.<br><br>I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to say more about the energy deal.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; So today we announced a task force that will be led out of the White House and the Office of the President of the European Commission to support the EU’s objective to end its dependence on Russian fossil fuels as soon as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>[Senior administration official] mentioned the two lines of effort, and I want to underscore that both lines of effort focus on ensuring that the task force is working to ensure European energy security in the near term while also recognizing that a rapid clean-energy transition to renewable energy, and including energy efficiency, are key tools that we will need to avoid these shocks in the future, while advancing our shared climate objectives.<br><br>The task force and international partners will target additional LNG volumes to Europe of at least 15 bcm this year, with expected increases going forward.<br><br>The task force will also simultaneously focus on reducing overall gas demand, in line with our shared climate and clean energy objectives.&nbsp; This includes engaging with key stakeholders, including from the private sector, to target immediate reductions in gas demand that can be achieved through ramping up energy efficiency measures and accelerating renewable energy development and deployment.<br><br>The REPowerEU plan, developed by the European Commission and released on March 8th to phase out of their dependence of Russian fossil fuels well before 2030, estimates that many of these measures can produce even greater savings in the near term.<br><br>According to their estimate &#8212; their estimate is that energy savings in homes alone can save at least 15.5 bcm by the end of this year.&nbsp; And they estimate that accelerating wind and solar deployments and by frontloading that can replace about 20 bcm by the end of this year &#8212; with their goal of saving over 170 bcm a year by 2030 through the plans the EU made before the invasion, such as Fit for 55.<br><br>So we &#8212; as we support our European partners in the face of Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war of choice, we’re also strengthening their ability to meet their long-term objectives.<br><br>So with that, we’ll turn it over and take some questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; With that, why don’t we start with Mike Shear with the New York Times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi guys.&nbsp; Thanks for having the call.&nbsp; I guess I wanted to clarify &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen it reported this morning that this is a deal for the U.S. to provide 15 billion bcm to Europe.&nbsp; I just want to clarify, it&#8217;s not that the U.S. has that amount that it will sell to the EU or ship to the EU, but rather that it&#8217;s coming from &#8212; it&#8217;s an effort to find that amount from other countries.&nbsp;<br><br>And just as a sort of corollary to that: Isn&#8217;t it the case that the U.S. and many of the other nations around the world are already running full tilt?&nbsp; And so, how do you find that amount of LNG when the U.S. and many of the other providers don&#8217;t seem to have that kind of excess volume &#8212; at least right now?&nbsp; How do you find that in the short run?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Mike.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to start.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], please feel free to add in.&nbsp;<br><br>So, you know, Mike, we have close to doubled our LNG exports to Europe over the past three to four months.&nbsp; But we also arranged, over the course of the winter months, a number of swaps from our partners all over the world, particularly in Asia, to supply more LNG to Europe during its winter, particularly given its low inventory and storage levels this year.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re going to continue those efforts throughout 2022 &#8212; that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re committing to do &#8212; to hit the 15 bcm target.&nbsp;<br><br>And so this will involve a lot of diplomacy.&nbsp; We&#8217;re confident after talking with our partners, both in Asia but also in other parts of the world, that we can continue to hit that number.&nbsp; Basically, it continues at the rate at which we provided and arranged for LNG to be delivered to Europe through the past few months.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a continuation of the effort.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, over time, what Europe is doing is it&#8217;s committing to stable demand for U.S. LNG &#8212; 50 bcm &#8212; basically to execute on its goal of reducing energy dependence on Russia and removing it altogether before the end of this decade.&nbsp; And that will involve a lot of commitments by Europe to build the LNG import infrastructure, the distributional needs, the storage needs in order to transport that LNG to places where they have a real need to have gas.&nbsp; Gas imports rise over time to replace Russian imports.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to do so, as [senior administration official] said, in a way that advances our clean energy goals.<br><br>So the LNG import terminals and the pipelines can be built in a way that facilitate the use of renewable energy that could be retrofitted for hydrogen, and that&#8217;s going to be a big part of the second part of the strategy here &#8212; is getting us off gas altogether, particularly in Europe.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s go to Kayla Tausche with CNBC.<br><br>Kayla, you there?&nbsp; We can&#8217;t hear you.&nbsp; All right, you know, we will come back to you.<br><br>Next, why don&#8217;t we go to Jarrett Renshaw with Reuters.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for taking the call.&nbsp; Just &#8212; can you just clarify the additional volume part?&nbsp; Are we talking &#8212; is there an “all in” number here that the U.S. is committing (inaudible), a preexisting number plus the 15?&nbsp; So if we can get some clarification on that, that would be great.<br><br>And secondly, on the one hand, you&#8217;re talking about increased production, more natural gas flowing out of the U.S., and also at same time, looking to stop it flowing and stop the production of natural gas.&nbsp; What incentive do U.S. companies have to build out this infrastructure &#8212; U.S. natural gas companies?&nbsp; Wouldn&#8217;t they just &#8212; if the policy is to essentially shut them down at some point, what&#8217;s their incentive, given the length of these supply contracts that are needed to fund the infrastructure?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Good questions.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to start on this?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Happy to.<br><br>So, let me clarify: On &#8212; there is not an aggregate number.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; This is about &#8212; this is looking at &#8212; the Europeans actually do have an aggregate number, which is to reduce their reliance on Russian gas by the end &#8212; by well before 2030.&nbsp; And so, in the joint statement, they put 27 &#8212; “by 2027” is the target that they want to reduce that by.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s really their goal.&nbsp; That&#8217;s about &#8212; 155 bcm total is what they used from Russia in 2021.&nbsp; And so my understanding is that that&#8217;s their aggregate number, globally, that Europe is looking to aim to do.<br><br>And so the U.S. is trying to do our part and contribute to that.&nbsp; And as the President von der Leyen said today, 50 bcm &#8212; and also according to the International Energy Agency &#8212; that&#8217;s about a third of what they get from Russia today.<br><br>Regarding the question about the reducing gas demand, I should clarify that point.&nbsp; So, on that point, what we&#8217;re talking about are measures to reduce the demand for gas in the European system.&nbsp; Europe has identified things such as smart thermostats, or turning down your &#8212; degree of your home by one degree can save about 10 bcm.&nbsp; They&#8217;re looking at things like accelerating solar and wind deployment that reduce the demand for gas in the system.<br><br>The joint statement that we released today &#8212; we&#8217;ll be releasing today &#8212; talk about the infrastructure that will be built by the Europeans, on the European side, to be clean and renewable hydrogen-ready.&nbsp; That’s an example of where gas continues to move to Europe, but it&#8217;s done in a way that then contributes clean and renewable hydrogen in the future.<br><br>And so, again, these are the signals we&#8217;re trying to send to the marketplace about the role that gas plays going forward in the future.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about turning off the gas completely in the near term; it&#8217;s about making sure that it is low carbon, that the greenhouse gas intensity of the carbon and the gas over time is decreasing, aligned with our net-zero goals.&nbsp;<br><br>And if you look at technology that&#8217;s out there today, as well as we&#8217;re investing in both at home and overseas &#8212; like carbon capture, utilization, and storage &#8212; these are technologies that help reduce the carbon intensity of gas going forward and into Europe to be aligned with their strategy.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And just to add on a bit, Jarrett: On the first part of your question, if you look at what Russia currently ships to the EU in terms of LNG, it is about 15 bcm.&nbsp; Now, the pipes gas, as [senior administration official] referenced, is much larger; it&#8217;s 155 billion cubic meters.&nbsp;<br><br>So, in 2022 &#8212; you can think of why 15 &#8212; that’s the additional LNG we&#8217;re going to provide to Europe, and the idea is to get them off of Russian LNG in the very, very short term.&nbsp;<br><br>But then over time &#8212; your question was along the lines of, “What are you going to do with the infrastructure that&#8217;s built to supply additional gas?”&nbsp; And here, the important point to realize: These are not going to be stranded assets.&nbsp; The infrastructure that&#8217;s built in Europe &#8212; for example, in the distribution and the storage capacity, and even the powering of these LNG import facilities &#8212; the goal here is to build those facilities and build that infrastructure using renewable energy, using pipelines that could be used for hydrogen.&nbsp; And so, these aren&#8217;t going to be stranded assets; they&#8217;re going to be used for the clean energy infrastructure (inaudible) over time, well beyond 2030.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s try Kayla with CNBC again.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi guys.&nbsp; Can you hear me now?&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yep, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Sorry about that before.&nbsp; If the European demand remains stable, what is your understanding of how your plans to replace the remaining 100 billion-or-so cubic meters that it currently gets from Russia?&nbsp;<br><br>And just to put a finer point on it, exactly how much does the administration expect U.S. producers to increase drilling and fracking by, for the next decade, to meet this goal?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sorry, I couldn&#8217;t &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t hear that, Kayla.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; [senior administration official], I don&#8217;t &#8212; maybe it came through more clearly on your side.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Kayla, was your question &#8212; I think I caught some of it.&nbsp;<br><br>So, in terms of the additional 100 bcm of the 155, I would, you know, sort of direct you to the REPowerEU plan that they put out on March 8th, where they walk through a series of gas diversification measures, how they would electrify Europe, and how they would transform their industry, and to reach that &#8212; that full amount.&nbsp; And they have timeframes for that.&nbsp; And again, 2027, I believe, is their &#8212; is how they&#8217;re trying to pull that “by 2030” target forward.<br><br>But it&#8217;s everything from boosting biomethane, boosting the hydrogen production that’ll take place in (inaudible) by 2030, looking at solar rooftops, heat pump rollouts, frontloading wind and solar, and looking at EUI efforts around energy efficiency.&nbsp; And they did some of that add-up and aggregation to get to those volumes and those numbers.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s also where you see the European Commission talking about today, looking at an EU mechanism of pooling to ensure that they can fill storage, that they can ensure that they can work with member states around import infrastructure.&nbsp;<br><br>You saw Germany announced, I think about two weeks ago, that they&#8217;re looking to build two more import terminals, and they&#8217;re looking, I think, at a floating storage regasification unit in the near term for that.&nbsp;<br><br>So those are some measures on the hundred that I think that was your question.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of your question regarding what are we asking of U.S. production, I would &#8212; there, I would just take a look at what we have already permitted in the United States, what is already under construction.&nbsp; And this is really about where the market wants to take it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why hearing from the European Union today that they&#8217;re looking to work with their member states to ensure a stable demand of a specific volume through 2030 is really important to send a signal of where we&#8217;ve already permitted.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s various numbers out there, but there is a significant amount of volume of new production capacity from the United States that has already been permitted by the Department of Energy and others for build-out.&nbsp; And we also have two active facilities already under construction that&#8217;ll be probably ready by 2024, 2025.&nbsp;<br><br>So when you think about new volumes of production, I’d take a look at what we&#8217;ve already permitted and what&#8217;s already under construction.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And, you know, in our discussions &#8212; just to add on to [senior administration official]’s answer &#8212; in our discussions with the Europeans, you know, Russian gas has been very cheap for a long time, but it&#8217;s also quite obvious that it&#8217;s very risky.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, Europe wants to manage its risks in a better way, really with a portfolio approach.&nbsp; The U.S. is now the biggest supplier of LNG, so we&#8217;ll be a big part of it, but there&#8217;ll be other suppliers too.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve been working with producers of LNG across the world.&nbsp;<br><br>The point here is to replace an unreliable supplier of LNG with a much more reliable and secure partner in the U.S.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next, let’s go to Josh Wingrove from Bloomberg.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; And, you know, bear with us who &#8212; those of us who&#8217;ve been in the travel pool &#8212; in a fuzzy period of sleep.&nbsp; So, let me just make some clarity on this.&nbsp; Of the 15, how much of that do you think will come from the U.S., number one?&nbsp;<br><br>Number two, [senior administration official], you just mentioned the two existing facilities under production.&nbsp; Do you believe the U.S. needs more export facilities on top of that to service this goal and this vision?&nbsp; Or does the existing expansion and plan sort of meet that target?&nbsp;<br><br>And of the 15, if we don&#8217;t know how much is coming from the U.S., can we say how much is coming from Asia, for instance?&nbsp;<br><br>And, [senior administration official], we don&#8217;t really have a factsheet yet on what this data deal is.&nbsp; Can you tell us anything of what the terms of it &#8212; you know, what it&#8217;ll change for the U.S. or what it will change for Europe?&nbsp; Like, what was the &#8212; what is the deal itself?&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to take the first, and I&#8217;ll address the second question from Josh?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, of course.&nbsp; So, on the 15 &#8212; again, can&#8217;t speak to exactly where that 15 is coming from.&nbsp; (Inaudible) an active conversation among multiple parties, and again, where the market is looking to move those existing volumes.&nbsp; And so, you know, whether or not it&#8217;s a U.S. cargo or an Asian cargo, what have you, we don&#8217;t have those specifics to share with you today.&nbsp;<br><br>On your second question around U.S. exports and what&#8217;s under construction and what&#8217;s already in production today &#8212; and I&#8217;m trying to find the final number, and we’ll have to get back to you with it.&nbsp; But by my last check, we already &#8212; you know, again, what&#8217;s permitted for export terminals for construction today will get us to, I believe &#8212; and again, I don&#8217;t have the current number &#8212; but it&#8217;ll certainly be sufficient to meet the 50 demand coming out of Europe today &#8212; or by 2030.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I would say on that: Again, there&#8217;s a plentiful amount of export capacity looking to come online in the near future.&nbsp; And, really, what they&#8217;re looking is to reach final investment decision, or FID.<br><br>Over to you, [senior administration official].<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; On the second question, Josh, I mean, the problem we&#8217;ve been trying to solve for over a year now is that the European Court of Justice invalidated the previous so- called Privacy Shield, which allowed for data flow from Europe to the U.S.&nbsp;<br><br>And a couple of the primary concerns that have been raised involved potential surveillance of European consumers by our intelligence agencies.&nbsp; And so, that and a few other issues related to privacy and security were at the crux of the negotiations over the past year.&nbsp;<br><br>And without an agreement that dealt with the Court of Justice &#8212; the European Court of Justice’s issues with the previous Privacy Shield, it put at risk the data flow that takes place between our two economies.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s an especially big problem for small businesses and medium-sized businesses that can&#8217;t easily come up with a contract that provides comfort for those companies that are doing business in Europe.&nbsp;<br><br>And it really threatened &#8212; I mean, in today&#8217;s age, the digital flows between the U.S and Europe are so large that it really threatened a significant chunk of our trading relationship.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, we&#8217;ve now come to an agreement on how to deal with Europe’s concerns.&nbsp; And it really is based on a shared understanding of what privacy means in terms of data flow, what security should look like, what the rule of law &#8212; how it should operate.&nbsp; And that was really the basis on which we found compromise.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a really big deal, especially for small and midsize businesses that were at risk of losing their &#8212; losing their revenue flow from Europe.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next, let’s go to Tyler Pager with the Washington Post.&nbsp; And this is probably our last question because I think our speakers have to run to some other engagements.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And I had to jump on a little late, so I apologize if this question has already been asked.&nbsp; But in the factsheet, it says that, “This will also be done on the understanding that prices should reflect long-term market fundamentals and stability of supply and demand.”&nbsp; We had heard from some EU officials some grumbling about how much the European Union will have to pay.&nbsp; Has there been an agreement on pricing, either for this year or moving into the future?&nbsp; Any more detail you can provide on that?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, I mean &#8212; so the reference there is making the point that spot prices are really high right now.&nbsp; And so, the agreement is not to lock in those spot prices indefinitely, because those prices can change, and ideally they move lower as supplies go up.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s referencing long-term supply and demand fundamentals; that we shouldn&#8217;t just be looking to spot prices to strike a long-term agreement, which is what this is.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s the &#8212; that&#8217;s the intuition.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Well, thanks again, everyone, for joining today.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, this call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and embargoed until the call concludes, which will be momentarily.&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks again for joining, everybody.&nbsp; And talk to you all soon.&nbsp;<br><br>11:08 A.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen in Joint Press&#160;Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/25/remarks-by-president-biden-and-european-commission-president-ursula-von-der-leyen-in-joint-press-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[10:05 A.M. CET PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Today I’m proud to once again be standing together with President von der Leyen as we announce a new groundbreaking initiative between the European Union and the United States.&#160;First, we’re coming together to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian energy.&#160; Putin has issued Russia’s energy resources to coerce and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>10:05 A.M. CET</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Today I’m proud to once again be standing together with President von der Leyen as we announce a new groundbreaking initiative between the European Union and the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, we’re coming together to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian energy.&nbsp; Putin has issued Russia’s energy resources to coerce and manipulate its neighbors.&nbsp; That’s how he’s used it.&nbsp; He’s used the profits to drive his war machine.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that’s why, earlier this month, I announced the United States would ban all imports of Russian energy to make it clear that the American people would not be part of subsidizing Putin’s brutal, unjustified war against the people of Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>At the time, I noted that we were able to take those steps when others could not because the United States is a net energy exporter of energy, with a strong domestic industry.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the United States welcomed the European Union’s powerful statement earlier this month committing to rapidly reduce its dependence on Russian gas.</p>



<p>Today we’ve agreed on a joint game plan toward that goal while accelerating our progress toward a secure clean energy future.<br>&nbsp;<br>This initiative focuses on two core issues: One, helping Europe reduce its dependency on Russian gas as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And, secondly, reducing Europe’s demand for gas overall.<br>&nbsp;<br>To address the first point, the United States, together with our international partners, they’re going to &#8212; we’re going to work to ensure an additional 15 &#8212; one-five &#8212; 15 billion cubic meters of liquified natural gas &#8212; LNG &#8212; for Europe this year.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as the EU works to discontinue buying Russian gas well before 2030, it will also work to ensure additional EU market demand for 50 billion cubic meters of LNG from the United States annually by 2030.<br>&nbsp;<br>To accomplish this, the European Commission is going to work with the member states to store gas across the continent, to build more infrastructure to receive LNG, and to take steps to increase the efficiency of gas.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This build-out &#8212; this build-out will occur in a way that consists &#8212; is consistent with, not in conflict with, the zero &#8212; net-zero climate goal we &#8212; that we’re shooting for.&nbsp; It’s going to take some time to adjust gas supply chains and infrastructure as is built the last decade &#8212; for the last decade.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we’re going to have to make sure the families in Europe can get through this winter and the next while we’re building an infrastructure for a diversified, resilient, and clean energy future.<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, this crisis also presents an opportunity.&nbsp; It’s a catalyst &#8212; a catalyst that will drive the investments we need to double-down on our clean energy goals and accelerate progress toward our net-zero emissions future.<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s what the second part of this initiative is all about.<br>&nbsp;<br>The United States and the European Union are going to work together to take concrete measures to reduce dependence on natural gas &#8212; period &#8212; and to maximize the available &#8212; the avail- &#8212; the availability and use of renewable energy. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re going to accelerate widespread adoption of energy-efficient technologies and equipment, like smart thermostats, the work &#8212; that work to &#8212; and work to electrify heating systems all across Europe.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re going to invest in innovative solutions and technologies to make the switch from fossil fuels.<br>&nbsp;<br>And together, we’ll advance the use of clean and renewable hydrogen to reduce our carbon emissions.<br>&nbsp;<br>This &#8212; these steps will increase energy security, economic security, and national security.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’re going to stand up a joint task force to implement these changes and drive progress that will be co-chaired by representatives from the White House and the President of the European Union’s team &#8212; Commission’s team.<br>&nbsp;<br>Madam President, I know &#8212; I know that eliminating Russian gas will have costs for Europe.&nbsp; But it’s not only the right thing to do from a moral standpoint, it’s going to put us on a much stronger strategic footing.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’m proud to announce that we’ve also reached another major breakthrough in transatlantic data flows.&nbsp; Privacy and security are key elements of my digital agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>And today, we’ve agreed to unprecedented protections for data privacy and security for our citizens.<br>&nbsp;<br>This new agreement will enhance the Privacy Shield Framework; promote growth and innovation in Europe and the United States; and help companies, both small and large, compete in the digital economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just as we did when we resolved the Boeing-Airbus dispute and lifted the steel and aluminum tariffs, the United States and the EU are finding creative, new approaches to knit our economies and our people closer together, grounded on shared values.<br>&nbsp;<br>This framework underscores our shared commitment to privacy, to data protection, and to the rule of law.&nbsp; And it’s going to allow the European Commission to once again authorize<br>transatlantic data flows that help facilitate $7.1 trillion in economic relationships with the EU.<br>&nbsp;<br>So thank you again, Madam President, for your personal friendship, for your partnership, and above all, your leadership.<br>&nbsp;<br>All of this is bringing the European Union and the United States even closer together, and that’s a win for all of us.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I thank you all, and I’m now going to yield the podium to the President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me pull this out.&nbsp; (Pulls out the step stool.)&nbsp; Got to earn my salary here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Is it out enough?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Mr. President, Dear Joe, your presence here in Brussels this week &#8212; at the NATO summit, at the G7, and at our European Council &#8212; sends a very powerful message to the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>The transatlantic partnership stands stronger and more united than ever.&nbsp; And we are determined to stand up against Russia’s brutal war.&nbsp; This war will be a strategic failure for Putin.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our cooperation on the four successive waves of sanctions against Russia has been extraordinary and exceptional.&nbsp; The sanctions are now working their way deep into the Russian system, draining Putin’s resources to finance this atrocious war.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our work on sanctions also shows that when we act together, we’re stronger and we really can make a difference.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we are continuing to reinforce our cooperation in many strategic ways: on humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine; on energy; on fighting the threats against our democracies; on solving outstanding issues in the EU-U.S. cooperation, including in data protec- &#8212; protection and privacy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In a world faced with disorder, our transatlantic unity upholds fundamental values and rules that our citizens believe in.&nbsp; Let me focus first on refugees.<br>&nbsp;<br>Until now, around three and a half million people have left Ukraine, half of them children.&nbsp; Every second refugee is a child.&nbsp; And the numbers will keep rising.&nbsp; So, together, we are mobilizing massive resources to support those displaced by the conflict, be it in Ukraine or in the neighboring countries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Just this week, for example, I announced that the European Union will allocate an extra 3.4 billion euros for this purpose, and more will come.&nbsp; This demonstrates our deep support for Ukraine and its citizens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to tell the American people how grateful Europe is for their unwavering support.&nbsp; This support also extends to strengthening Europe&#8217;s energy security and independence from Russian fossil fuels.&nbsp; As you know, we aim to reduce this dependency on Russian fossil fuels and to get rid of it.&nbsp; And this can only be achieved through, of course, first of all, investment in renewables, but also through additional gas supplies, including LNG deliveries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we want, as Europeans, to diversify away from Russia, towards suppliers that we trust, that are friends, and that are reliable.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And therefore, the U.S. commitment to provide the European Union with additional at least 15 billion cubic meters of LNG this year is a big step in this direction because this will replace the LNG supply we currently receive from Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>And looking ahead, the United States and Europe will ensure stable demand and supply for additional at least 50 billion cubic meter of U.S. LNG until 2030.&nbsp; And if we look at that, this amount, 50 bcm per year, is replacing one third already of the Russian gas going to Europe today.&nbsp; So, we are right in &#8212; on track now to diversify away from Russian gas and towards our friends’ and partners’ reliable and trustworthy suppliers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We need to secure our supplies not just for next winter but also for the years ahead.&nbsp; And this is a &#8212; an important, a big starting point to do that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our partnership aims to sustain us through this war, to work on our independence from Russian fossil fuels, but it also focuses on building a greener future with climate neutrality.&nbsp; We will work together also with our energy-intensive industry.&nbsp; And the good news is that the infrastructure that we use for gas today can be used for clean hydrogen in the future.&nbsp; So, this investment we are doing right now is also an investment in the decarbonizing of our economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>The cooperation shows the power of our democracies.&nbsp; I particularly welcome that we will step up our respective action on strengthening democracies, the rule of law, the freedom of media in the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we also need to continue adapting our own democracies to a changing world.&nbsp; This is particularly true when it comes to digitalization, in which the protection of personal data and privacy has become so crucial.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And therefore, I&#8217;m very pleased that we have found an agreement in principle on a new framework for transatlantic data flows.&nbsp; This will enable predictable and trustworthy data flows between the EU and U.S., safeguarding privacy and civil liberties.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I really want to thank Commissioner Reynders and Secretary Raimondo for their tireless efforts over the past month to finish a balanced and effective solution.&nbsp; This is another step in our &#8212; strengthening our partnership.&nbsp; We managed to balance security and the right to privacy and data protection.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Mr. President, Dear Joe: Putin is trying to turn back the clock to another era &#8212; an era of brutal use of force, of power politics, of spheres of influence, and internal repression.&nbsp; I am confident he will fail.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are working together to forge a peaceful, prosperous, and sustainable future.&nbsp; And I know we will succeed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you very much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>10:18 A.M. CET&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement between the United&#160;States and the European Commission on European Energy&#160;Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/joint-statement-between-the-united-states-and-the-european-commission-on-european-energy-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 10:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49701</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PreambleThe United States and the European Commission are committed to reducing Europe’s dependency on Russian energy. We reaffirm our joint commitment to Europe’s energy security and sustainability and to accelerating the global transition to clean energy. In condemning in the strongest terms Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, we express our solidarity and support for Ukraine.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><strong>Preamble<br></strong><br>The United States and the European Commission are committed to reducing Europe’s dependency on Russian energy. We reaffirm our joint commitment to Europe’s energy security and sustainability and to accelerating the global transition to clean energy. In condemning in the strongest terms Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, we express our solidarity and support for Ukraine. We share the objective of addressing the energy security emergency – to ensure energy supply for the EU and Ukraine. We welcome the continued progress toward the physical integration of Ukraine with the EU energy markets. The energy security and sustainability of the EU and Ukraine are essential for peace, freedom and democracy in Europe.</p>



<p>Through the Joint European action for more affordable, secure and sustainable energy (REPowerEU), the EU confirmed its objective to reach independence from Russian fossil fuels well before the end of the decade, replacing them with stable, affordable, reliable, and clean energy supplies for EU citizens and businesses.</p>



<p>The United States and the EU are committed to meeting the goals of the Paris Agreement, achieving the objective of net zero emissions by 2050, and keeping a 1.5 degrees Celsius limit on temperature rise within reach, including through a rapid clean energy transition, renewable energy, and energy efficiency. These policies and technologies will also contribute to making the EU independent from Russian fossil fuels. Natural gas remains an important part of the EU energy system in the green transition, including by ensuring its carbon intensity decreases over time.</p>



<p>The United States and European Commission confirm our strategic energy cooperation for security of energy supply and reducing dependence on fossil fuels. We share efforts to make available stable, affordable, reliable and clean energy supplies to citizens and businesses in the EU and its neighbouring partner nations. In this framework, we establish an immediate cooperation to address the emergency energy security objective of ensuring appropriate levels of gas storage ahead of next winter and the following one. We will continue our close cooperation on other measures to accelerate the green energy transition, lower energy consumption and reduce dependence on fossil fuels.</p>



<p><strong>Task Force on Energy Security<br></strong><br>The United States and the European Commission will immediately establish a joint Task Force on Energy Security to set out the parameters of this cooperation and execute its implementation. The Task Force will be chaired by a representative from the White House and a representative of the President of the European Commission.</p>



<p>This Task Force will focus on the following urgent issues: &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The United States will strive to ensure, including working with international partners, additional liquified natural gas (LNG) volumes for the EU market of at least 15 bcm in 2022 with expected increases going forward.<br></li><li>The United States and European Commission will undertake efforts to reduce the greenhouse gas intensity of all new LNG infrastructure and associated pipelines, including through the use of clean energy to power onsite operations, the reduction of methane leakage, and the construction of clean and renewable hydrogen ready infrastructure.<br></li><li>The United States commits to maintaining an enabling regulatory environment with procedures to review and expeditiously act upon applications to permit any additional export LNG capacities that would be needed to meet this emergency energy security objective and support the RePowerEU goals, affirming the joint resolve to terminate EU dependence on Russian fossil fuels by 2027.<br></li><li>The European Commission will work with the governments of EU Member States to accelerate their regulatory procedures to review and determine approvals for LNG import infrastructure, to include onshore facilities and related pipelines to support imports using floating storage regasification unit vessels, and fixed LNG import terminals.<br></li><li>The European Commission will work with EU Member States and market operators to pool demand through a newly established EU Energy platform for additional volumes between April and October 2022. The European Commission will also support long-term contracting mechanisms and partner with the U.S. to encourage relevant contracting to support final investment decisions on both LNG export and import infrastructure.<br></li><li>The European Commission will work with EU Member States toward ensuring stable demand for additional U.S. LNG until at least 2030 of approximately 50 bcm/annum, on the understanding that the price formula of LNG supplies to the EU should reflect long-term market fundamentals, and stability of the cooperation of the demand and supply side, and that this growth be consistent with our shared net zero goals. In particular, price formula should include consideration of Henry Hub Natural Gas Spot Price and other stabilising factors.<br></li><li>The EU is preparing an upgraded regulatory framework for energy security of supply and storage. This will enhance certainty and predictability regarding security of supply and storage needs and ensure closer cooperation within the EU and its neighbouring partner nations. The European Commission has proposed regulation on energy storage to ensure that the existing storage infrastructure is filled up to 90% of its capacity by 1 November each year, with specific phase-in provisions for 2022. The European Commission will coordinate with the Member States and provide transparency with respect to available LNG capacity in EU terminals.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Commission will engage key stakeholders, including the private sector, to formulate immediate recommendations that will reduce overall gas demand through accelerating market deployment and utilization of clean energy technologies and measures in Europe and the United States such as:</li></ul>



<ul><li>Partnering on technologies and energy efficiency solutions such as ramping up demand response devices (such as smart thermostats) and heat pump deployment and installations, scaling procurement for clean energy equipment, investing in innovative technologies and fuel-switching away from fossil fuels.<br></li><li>Expediting planning and approval for renewable energy projects and strategic energy cooperation including in offshore wind technologies.<br></li><li>Developing a strategy to accelerate workforce development to support the rapidly deployment of clean energy technologies, including an expansion of solar and wind.<br></li><li>Collaborating to advance the production and use of clean and renewable hydrogen to displace unabated fossil fuels and cut greenhouse gas emissions, including by investing in technology development and supporting infrastructure.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The European Commission is working to advance measures that reduce gas consumption by maximizing renewable energy generation and utilization, including by reducing curtailment rates.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Commission are resolved to negotiate and then implement an ambitious emissions-based Global Arrangement on Steel and Aluminum Trade that incentives industrial decarbonization and lowers energy demand.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States and European Commission Announce Task Force to Reduce Europe’s Dependence on Russian Fossil&#160;Fuels</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/fact-sheet-united-states-and-european-commission-announce-task-force-to-reduce-europes-dependence-on-russian-fossil-fuels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen announced a joint Task Force to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian fossil fuels and strengthen European energy security as President Putin wages his war of choice against Ukraine. This Task Force for Energy Security will be chaired by a representative from the White&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen announced a joint Task Force to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian fossil fuels and strengthen European energy security as President Putin wages his war of choice against Ukraine.<br><br>This Task Force for Energy Security will be chaired by a representative from the White House and a representative of the President of the European Commission. It will work to ensure energy security for Ukraine and the EU in preparation for next winter and the following one while supporting the EU’s goal to end its dependence on Russian fossil fuels.<br><br>The Task Force will organize its efforts around two primary goals: (1) Diversifying liquefied natural gas (LNG) supplies in alignment with climate objectives; (2) Reducing demand for natural gas.<br><br><strong>Diversifying LNG Supplies in Alignment with Climate Objectives</strong></p>



<ul><li>The United States will work with international partners and strive to ensure additional LNG volumes for the EU market of at least 15 bcm in 2022, with expected increases going forward.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Commission will undertake efforts to reduce the greenhouse gas intensity of all new LNG infrastructure and associated pipelines, including through using clean energy to power onsite operations, reducing methane leakage, and building clean and renewable hydrogen-ready infrastructure.<br></li><li>The European Commission will prepare an upgraded regulatory framework for energy security of supply and storage, as well as working with EU Member States to accelerate regulatory procedures to review and determine approvals for LNG import infrastructure. The United States will maintain its regulatory environment with an emphasis on supporting this emergency energy security objective and the REPowerEU goals.<br></li><li>The European Commission will work with EU Member States toward the goal of ensuring, until at least 2030, demand for approximately 50 bcm/year of additional U.S. LNG that is consistent with our shared net-zero goals. This also will be done on the understanding that prices should reflect long-term market fundamentals and stability of supply and demand.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Reducing Demand for Natural Gas</strong></p>



<ul><li>The United States and the European Commission will engage key stakeholders, including the private sector, and deploy immediate recommendations to reduce overall gas demand by accelerating market deployment of clean energy measures.<br></li><li>Immediate reductions in gas demand can be achieved through energy efficiency solutions such as ramping up demand response devices, including smart thermostats, and deployment of heat pumps. The REPowerEU plan estimates that reductions through energy savings in homes can replace 15.5 bcm this year and that accelerating wind and solar deployment can replace 20 bcm this year, and through EU’s existing plans such as “Fit for 55” contribute to the EU goal of saving 170 bcm/year by 2030.<br></li><li>As global leaders in renewable energy, the United States and the European Commission will work to expedite planning and approval for renewable energy projects and strategic energy cooperation, including on technologies where we both excel such as offshore wind.<br></li><li>We will continue to collaborate to advance the production and use of clean and renewable hydrogen to displace unabated fossil fuels and cut greenhouse gas emissions, which will include both technology and supporting infrastructure.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Alaska Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-alaska-disaster-declaration-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 01:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Alaska and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and straight-line winds from December 25 to December 27, 2021. Federal funding is available to state, tribal,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Alaska and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and straight-line winds from December 25 to December 27, 2021.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe winter storm and straight-line winds in Fairbanks North Star Borough, Denali Borough, and the City of Nenana.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Thomas J. Dargan as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp;FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Greek Independence Day: A National Day of Celebration of Greek and American Democracy,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/24/greek-independence-day-a-national-day-of-celebration-of-greek-and-american-democracy-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 21:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA A PROCLAMATION In forming a Government that reflected the burgeoning spirit of America and united our young Nation around the core principles of liberty, justice, and the rule of law, our Founders looked to the birthplace of democracy &#8212; Greece.&#160;&#160;Decades after the American Revolution, the people&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">A PROCLAMATION</p>



<p>    In forming a Government that reflected the burgeoning spirit of America and united our young Nation around the core principles of liberty, justice, and the rule of law, our Founders looked to the birthplace of democracy &#8212; Greece.&nbsp;&nbsp;Decades after the American Revolution, the people of Greece came together to bravely affirm their commitment to democracy and declare their own independence from the Ottoman Empire.&nbsp;&nbsp;Today, as we mark the anniversary of Greek independence, we honor our countries&#8217; deep and historic bond &#8212; forged in the struggle for liberty and self-governance &#8212; and the many contributions of the modern Hellenic Republic which promote international peace and stability and uphold our shared values.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Greek bicentennial in 2021 was a year of celebration for Greece, for the Greek American community, and for the strong bilateral relationship between our two nations.&nbsp;&nbsp;The seeds of friendship planted long ago continue to bear fruit for both our people, with Greece and the United States standing together to defend democracy around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;A crucial ally in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, Greece promotes peace and prosperity in the Eastern Mediterranean, Black Sea, and Western Balkans regions, and the United States is grateful for Greece&#8217;s continuing hospitality to the United States Naval Support Activity Souda Bay on Crete.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Greece and the United States are standing together to confront the challenges of our time, from meeting the climate crisis and diversifying the region&#8217;s energy resources to proving that democracies deliver for our people and pushing back against the growing threat of authoritarianism.&nbsp;&nbsp;Through our ongoing Strategic Dialogue, Greece and the United States have increased cooperation across a range of critical issues, and last year&#8217;s update to our Mutual Defense Cooperation Agreement will boost our defense and security cooperation for years to come.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The deep political and historical bonds that unite Greece and the United States are further reinforced by strong ties of family and affection and by the estimated 3 million Americans of Greek descent across our Nation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Throughout my career, I have seen firsthand the courage and determination of the Greek American community, and these qualities have been an invaluable source of strength to our Nation over the past year.&nbsp;&nbsp;Greek Americans have been at the forefront of the fight against the COVID-19 pandemic and our efforts to vaccinate the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;And last November, as Greek Americans proudly celebrated the construction of the Saint Nicholas Greek Orthodox Church and National Shrine in Manhattan 20 years after the original church structure had been destroyed in the September 11th terrorist attacks, they embodied our shared values of perseverance, resilience, and hope for the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;As Greece and the United States look forward to what the next 200 years of partnership will bring, I am confident that our nations and our people will meet every challenge together.&nbsp;&nbsp;On this day, we recommit to the hard work ahead, to fortifying our democracies, and to reaffirming our ironclad friendship.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 25, 2022, as Greek Independence Day:&nbsp;&nbsp;<a>A National Day of Celebration of Greek and American Democracy.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to observe this day with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-fourth day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Readout by the United&#160;States and the European&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/joint-readout-by-the-united-states-and-the-european-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the European Council was joined by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States. The leaders discussed the coordinated and united response of the European Union and the United States to Russia&#8217;s unprovoked and unjustified military aggression in Ukraine. They reviewed their ongoing efforts to impose economic costs on Russia and Belarus, as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the European Council was joined by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States. The leaders discussed the coordinated and united response of the European Union and the United States to Russia&#8217;s unprovoked and unjustified military aggression in Ukraine. They reviewed their ongoing efforts to impose economic costs on Russia and Belarus, as well as their readiness to adopt additional measures and to stop any attempts to circumvent sanctions. Leaders discussed the urgent needs caused by Russia’s aggression, committed to continuing providing humanitarian assistance, including to neighboring countries hosting refugees, and underscored the need for Russia to guarantee humanitarian access to those affected by or fleeing the violence. Leaders welcomed the opening of international investigations, including by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court, and ongoing efforts to gather evidence of atrocities. In addition, leaders discussed EU-U.S. cooperation to reduce dependence on Russian fossil fuels, accelerate the transition to clean energy, as well as the need to respond to evolving food security needs worldwide. The leaders also concurred on the importance of strengthening democratic resilience in Ukraine, Moldova, and the wider Eastern partnership region. Finally, leaders underscored the importance of enhancing transatlantic security and defense, including through robust NATO-EU cooperation as described in the EU’s Strategic Compass.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by President&#160;Biden and President von der&#160;Leyen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/joint-statement-by-president-biden-and-president-von-der-leyen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are united in our condemnation of Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of aggression against Ukraine. We stand in solidarity with the Ukrainian people, who are bravely defending their homeland, and we call on Russia to end the brutal onslaught against its neighbor.&#160; We are united in our support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We are united in our condemnation of Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of aggression against Ukraine. We stand in solidarity with the Ukrainian people, who are bravely defending their homeland, and we call on Russia to end the brutal onslaught against its neighbor.&nbsp; We are united in our support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp; And we are united in our resolve to defend our shared values, including democracy, respect for human rights, global peace and stability, and the rules-based international order.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, we are continuing coordinated transatlantic efforts to support the Ukrainian people, impose severe costs on Russia for its unjustifiable actions, and strengthen the resilience of our democracies, economies, and societies. In particular,&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The United States and the European Union have strengthened and aligned their <strong>sanctions regimes</strong>, together with like-minded partners across the world. Additionally, efforts should be stepped up to coordinate responses against sanctions evasion.<br></li><li>We continue to mobilize and coordinate significant <strong>humanitarian relief</strong> to support people within Ukraine, those who have been forced to flee, and those affected by the severe impacts Russia’s war is causing around the world. This includes more than $1 billion in new humanitarian assistance the United States is prepared to provide on top of the nearly $300 million already contributed and €550 million from the EU.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Union are coordinating closely to ensure that their <strong>efforts on temporary protection and humanitarian admission, including resettlement or transfers,</strong> are complementary and provide much-needed support to Ukraine’s neighbors.<br></li><li>We are announcing new actions to bolster <strong>democratic resilience and defend human rights</strong> in Ukraine and neighboring countries.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Union are supporting the work of <strong>war crimes documentation experts</strong> who are gathering evidence on the ground in Ukraine.<br></li><li>We are taking further, concrete steps in our <strong>energy cooperation </strong>to ensure the security of supply and to reduce dependence on Russian fossil fuels.<br></li><li>In order to prevent a potential <strong>food crisis</strong> triggered by price hikes and disruptions to food supply sparked by Putin&#8217;s war in Ukraine, we intend to redouble our combined efforts to increase global food security and provide direct food aid, where warranted, to our partners worldwide.<br></li><li>We will advance our cooperation on <strong>cybersecurity</strong> through a variety of actions, from supporting the Government of Ukraine on cyber resilience and cyber defense to aiming to combat the abuse of virtual currency.</li></ul>



<p><strong>ANNEX – TRANSATLANTIC COOPERATION AND SUPPORT FOR UKRAINE<br></strong><br><strong>Imposing Additional Costs on Russia</strong><br><br>The United States and the European Union have strengthened and aligned their sanctions regimes, together with our like-minded partners across the world. Today, the United States is sanctioning more than 400 additional individuals and entities to align with measures taken by the EU and our allies and partners. This includes the Duma (Russia’s lower house of parliament) and 328 of its members, dozens of defense companies that fuel Putin’s war machine and sustain its military industrial base, and more than 20 financial elites, including the head of Russia’s largest financial institution. The Commission, in line with its competences, will continue to support further similar measures. Together, we should aim at holding accountable those responsible for the devastation and commit to imposing further costs on Russia until Putin ceases his aggression.<br><br>The United States and the European Union are jointly working to blunt Russia’s ability to deploy its remaining international reserves, including gold, to prop up its economy and fund its illegal war.<br><br>Additionally, as announced in today’s G7 leaders’ statement, we are establishing an initiative to monitor the full implementation of our sanctions measures and coordinate responses against sanctions evasion. This will ensure that Russia will not be able to backfill or find workarounds that undermine the effect of our sanctions.<br><br><strong>Providing Humanitarian Assistance to the Ukrainian People</strong><br><br>We reaffirm our deep support for the Ukrainian people, who are suffering from Russia’s devastating bombing of civilians and civilian infrastructure.&nbsp; We urge Russia to facilitate unhindered humanitarian access and permanent safe passage for civilians. We continue to mobilize humanitarian relief to support people within Ukraine and those who have been forced to flee.&nbsp;&nbsp;The United States and the European Union are responding to the humanitarian needs in Ukraine and in countries impacted by the situation in Ukraine. The United States and the European Commission are coordinating closely on the provision of aid, including a through a newly-established high-level dialogue and a U.S. government liaison in the EU’s Emergency Response Coordination Centre.&nbsp; Today, the United States is announcing it is prepared to provide more than $1 billion in new funding toward humanitarian assistance for those affected by Russia’s war in Ukraine and its severe impacts around the world over the coming months. The European Commission has made available EUR 550 million in emergency and humanitarian assistance and, through the Union Civil Protection Mechanism in cooperation with its partners, it has delivered almost EUR&nbsp;300 million worth of in-kind assistance.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Welcoming Ukrainians Fleeing Violence</strong><br><br>The European Union has generously welcomed almost three and a half million Ukrainians fleeing Russia’s violence, providing them food, shelter, school, and employment opportunities, paying particular attention to the plight of children and providing them protection for the time they need.&nbsp; The United States and the European Union are coordinating closely to ensure that their efforts on temporary protection and humanitarian admission, including resettlement, are complementary and provide much-needed support to Ukraine’s neighbors. Today, the United States is announcing plans to welcome up to 100,000 Ukrainians fleeing Russia’s aggression through the full range of legal pathways, including the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Partnering to Promote Democratic Resilience and Human Rights</strong><br><br>We steadfastly support the democratic aspirations and fundamental freedoms of the Ukrainian people. Today, we are announcing new commitments to bolster societal resilience and defend human rights in Ukraine and neighboring countries, including Moldova.<br><br>To support human rights defenders, anti-corruption watchdogs, journalists, and other members of civil society operating in and around Ukraine, the United States is launching the <em>European Democratic Resilience Initiative</em> (EDRI), which will provide at least $320 million in new funding to these groups and regional governments. The EDRI will support media freedom and counter disinformation, benefit the safety and security of activists and vulnerable groups, strengthen institutions and the region’s rule of law, and help ensure accountability for human rights abuses and violations of international law. And it will expand rapid response capabilities and technical assistance to build resilience to Moscow’s strategic corruption and kleptocracy.<br><br>The European Commission announced plans to reallocate funds from EU programmes to support civil society organizations, human rights defenders, journalists, and pro-democracy activists in Ukraine, Belarus and Moldova. In addition, the European Endowment for Democracy, with EU funding contributions, provided a significant number of emergency grants to contribute to saving and sustaining civic activism and media pluralism in Ukraine. It also opened a Centre for Ukrainian Activists (CUA) in Przemyśl, Poland, to provide support for activists and independent journalists in maintaining and sustaining their connections to their activities inside Ukraine.<br><br><strong>Promoting Accountability<br><br></strong>There should be accountability for any war crimes committed in Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;The United States and the European Union are supporting the important work of war crimes documentation experts who are gathering evidence on the ground in Ukraine. The coordination of documentation and evidence preservation efforts to ensure such accountability should be facilitated.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting Europe’s Energy Security<br></strong><br>We reconfirm our commitment to Europe’s energy security and to accelerating the global transition to clean energy. Energy security and sustainability for the EU and Ukraine are essential for peace, freedom and democracy in Europe.&nbsp; The EU has confirmed its objective to reach independence from Russian gas well before the end of the decade while working to ensure reliable, affordable, and clean energy supplies to citizens and businesses in the EU and its neighbourhood.&nbsp; The United States intends to partner with the EU on these efforts.&nbsp; We understand that the rapid transition to clean energy is essential to advancing EU independence from Russian fossil fuels and are committed to meeting the goals of the Paris Agreement, the objective of net zero emissions by 2050, and keeping a 1.5 degrees Celsius limit on temperature rise within reach. &nbsp;In line with this vision, the European Commission and United States will establish a joint Task Force to address the immediate energy security needs of the EU and accelerate the clean energy transition.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Securing Global Food Supplies</strong><br><br>We are deeply concerned by how Putin’s war in Ukraine has caused major disruptions to international food and agriculture supply chains and the threat it poses to global food security. We recognize that many countries around the world have relied on imported food staples and fertilizer inputs from Ukraine and Russia, with Putin’s aggression disrupting that trade.&nbsp; As the United States and EU comprise many of the world’s major agricultural producers and strong economies, we commit to redoubling our combined efforts to provide direct food aid and other forms of assistance, where warranted, and, to continue the necessary support for agricultural innovation and sustainable productivity growth to ensure global food security, while balancing enhancing climate resilience and reducing agricultural greenhouse gas emissions.<br><br>We are committed to working with partners to address the attendant supply challenges and maintaining strong, ruled-based, and open global markets for staple agricultural commodities that feed the world. Specifically, the United States, through Feed the Future and our nutrition commitments, is providing over $11 billion over the next five years to address food security threats and nutrition across the globe.&nbsp; Additionally, the United States will remain one of the top providers of humanitarian food and nutrition assistance globally, having contributed approximately $4.6 billion in humanitarian food and nutrition assistance in 2021.&nbsp; We are also identifying tools in the U.S. government’s existing food security tool kit and determining whether programs are fit for purpose for this situation and will make strategic adjustments as needed.<br><br>For the period 2021 &#8211; 2024, the EU is pledging at least EUR 2.5 billion for international cooperation related to nutrition.&nbsp; This international cooperation programme will support food systems in about 70 partner countries. The proposed EU Emergency Support Programme for Ukraine of EUR 330 million will secure access to basic goods and services for the Ukrainian population and also support Ukraine’s agricultural sector.<br><br><strong>Ensuring the Security of Cyberspace</strong><br><br>We are committed to advancing our cybersecurity cooperation, both in response to Russia’s illegal further invasion of Ukraine and in support of our longer-term strategic objectives.&nbsp; Together, we will enhance our efforts to coordinate cybersecurity assistance and provide Internet access to the Governments of Ukraine and Moldova, working with Member States and other likeminded partners. In the context of Ukraine and more generally, we will continue to reinforce responsible state behavior in cyberspace and to work together to increase cyber resilience in the face of destructive, disruptive, and destabilizing cyber activity by both States and non-State actors, while also working to hold accountable those responsible for such activity.<br><br>We will work towards establishing more structured cybersecurity information exchanges on threats and threat actors and deepen our cooperation on new cybersecurity technologies and standards.&nbsp; We are committed to our partnership in the Counter Ransomware Initiative to disrupt ransomware groups and reduce related threats to our citizens and businesses. We will enhance efforts to address the abuse of virtual currency; bolster cybersecurity resilience; increase partner capacity for detecting and responding to ransomware activity within their own borders; and work to jointly hold accountable states that act as safe havens for ransomware activity.<br><br><strong>Combatting Illicit Use of Digital Assets</strong><br><br>We intend to announce deeper collaboration to combat the illicit use of digital assets, including their potential misuse in evading multilateral sanctions imposed in response to Russia’s unprovoked military invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; Together, we intend to deepen our shared commitment to advance anti-money laundering and countering financing of terrorism (AML/CFT) for digital assets, consistent with the Financial Action Task Force (FATF) standards.<br><br>We will share best practices and coordinate capacity building efforts to help other countries implement AML/CFT frameworks for digital assets. We intend to form a transatlantic sprint between U.S. and EU government officials and, as appropriate, digital asset service providers, to expedite and increase sharing of financial intelligence on illicit use of digital assets. Finally, we will seek opportunities for joint actions against those who facilitate the misuse of digital assets for illicit activity.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and European Council President Charles Michel Upon Arrival at the European&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/24/remarks-by-president-biden-and-european-council-president-charles-michel-upon-arrival-at-the-european-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Europa Building Brussels, Belgium 7:19 P.M. CET&#160;PRESIDENT MICHEL:&#160; We are very pleased, dear President, dear Joe, to welcome you again in Brussels.&#160; Your presence here and your participation in this European Council meeting is a very strong signal.&#160;&#160;Our unity is rock solid, and we are very, very pleased to coordinate, to cooperate with you.&#160; These&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Europa Building <br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>7:19 P.M. CET<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT MICHEL:&nbsp; We are very pleased, dear President, dear Joe, to welcome you again in Brussels.&nbsp; Your presence here and your participation in this European Council meeting is a very strong signal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our unity is rock solid, and we are very, very pleased to coordinate, to cooperate with you.&nbsp; These are difficult times, challenging times, and we need to take the right and the intelligent decisions for the future and for the security, for the stability.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And thank you for this excellent cooperation and coordination.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I came to congratulate a man who just got reelected without opposition.&nbsp; I dream about that someday.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, look, from the very beginning, I was of the view: The single most important thing that we have to do in the West is be united.&nbsp; I’m not saying that &#8212; that’s not a euphemism.&nbsp; I mean it literally.&nbsp; Literally.<br>&nbsp;<br>I spent some time with Vladimir Putin back in November and December, and we had a conference in &#8212; in Switzerland, at the time.&nbsp; And it was clear to me, and it was to you, that his intentions were very different than benign intentions.<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of the things that he’s tried to do &#8212; his overwhelming objective &#8212; and I’ve been speaking about it for a year and a half.&nbsp; His overwhelming objective is to demonstrate that democracies cannot function in the 21st century &#8212; because things are moving so rapidly, they require consensus, and it’s too difficult to get consensus &#8212; and autocracies are going to rule.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a matter of fact, we’ve lost more democratic in- &#8212; democratic countries &#8212; fewer democratic countries today than there were 10 years ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, from the very beginning, my objective &#8212; and I had a great partner in this &#8212; was to see to it that we built total, complete unity among the major democracies of the world.&nbsp; I’m not joking about that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s why I called just a couple weeks ago and asked NATO to set up a new &#8212; a NATO meeting of the heads of state, and it was took &#8212; which took place today.&nbsp; And I fortunately am able to attend two other conferences.<br>&nbsp;<br>But my point is: unity.&nbsp; Unity.&nbsp; And the very thing that Putin has tried to do from the beginning &#8212; and I’ve been saying this since my days as Vice President of the United States &#8212; is to break up NATO &#8212; break up NATO.&nbsp; He’d rather face 30 independent countries than 30 united countries with the United States of America.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; I’m being deadly earnest.&nbsp; I believe that’s been his intention from the very, very beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, what I want to thank Michel for is the &#8212; Michel &#8212; is that the whole idea of the unity of Europe as a whole, not just NATO &#8212; the G7 and this organization &#8212; really matters.&nbsp; It’s the single most important thing that we can do to stop this guy who’s &#8212; in our country, we believe he’s already committed war crimes.<br>&nbsp;<br>But thank you very much for the time, and thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT MICHEL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you trust China?&nbsp; Do you trust China?<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Well, we’ll discuss China.&nbsp; I’ve spent some time with Xi Jinping.&nbsp; And I hope we’re going to get a chance to discuss China.</p>



<p>7:23 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
