<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 23:20:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Roundtable with CEOs of Electric Utilities to Discuss His Build Back Better&#160;Agenda</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-roundtable-with-ceos-of-electric-utilities-to-discuss-his-build-back-better-agenda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 23:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 2:40 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, let me begin by thanking all these utility executives for coming in today.&#160; I think this is the beginning of a &#8212; God willing, a new era in the generation of electricity and, fundamentally, clean up the environment.&#160; And I can&#8217;t tell you how much&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>2:40 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, let me begin by thanking all these utility executives for coming in today.&nbsp; I think this is the beginning of a &#8212; God willing, a new era in the generation of electricity and, fundamentally, clean up the environment.&nbsp; And I can&#8217;t tell you how much I appreciate you being here.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to make a few brief comments and then ask a couple questions.&nbsp; And, unfortunately, I have a &#8212; I have to go, not immediately but before we finish.&nbsp; And I want to apologize ahead of time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But thank you, thank you, thank you for being here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m afraid &#8212; as I said, I won&#8217;t be able to stay, but I wanted to come by to thank the utility sector CEOs for being here, you know, and hear from you at the top.</p>



<p>You know, you have some of the most important jobs in America right now: keeping electricity systems running and running reliably.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve spent too much time this last year flying in helicopters over areas of scorched earth that &#8212; because utilities were down, because of what&#8217;s going &#8212; I mean, it really is amazing.&nbsp; More &#8212; more territory is burned to the ground in the West Coast than the entire state of New Jersey in terms of square miles.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just stunning.&nbsp; Absolutely stunning.</p>



<p>And I want to thank you for what you&#8217;re doing to help get the word out about clean energy.&nbsp; And the component &#8212; one of the significant &#8212; the most significant component of my Build Back Better plan &#8212; and thank you for coming to speak on its behalf &#8212; it&#8217;s about building a clean energy future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re seeing incredible enthusiasm and support for the effort not just from you all, but around the country.&nbsp; I mean, there&#8217;s a real &#8212; people are &#8212; I guess when things got really bad, it made people realize, “My Lord, this is real.&nbsp; This is real, this climate change.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s about building that future &#8212; that clean energy future.&nbsp; And &#8212; and how many major announcements have we seen recently?&nbsp; Ford and GM, for example, building out their electric vehicle production, a total &#8212; a total, I think, investment of &#8212; I think it sold almost $18 billion &#8212; 11 and 7.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Union Pacific Railroad: I was recently out in &#8212; in Pennsylvania, in Pittsburgh, but &#8212; to see other parts of what was going on.&nbsp; But they &#8212; Union Electric &#8212; excuse me, the Union Pacific Railroad is buying electric locomotives that are being built in Erie, Pennsylvania.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just yesterday, Tritium announced a new facility in Tennessee that is going to build the electric chargers.&nbsp; They brought in someone to show us what they&#8217;re like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we&#8217;re &#8212; this legislation has already been passed.&nbsp; That’s 500,000 electric chargers on our highways.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to change the dynamic of how &#8212; not only how we travel, but the economy along the way as well, because &#8212;</p>



<p>Any rate, companies are investing in clean energy futures.&nbsp; And the world is betting on American workers to build it and the American people to buy it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, we&#8217;re investing in clean energy &#8212; as a stronger, more resilient grid; 100 percent clean electricity by 2035.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a major piece of the puzzle and one of the commitments that I made &#8212; we would try to do.</p>



<p>Like there rest of my Build Back Better plan, the clean energy companies of this plan are about lowering prices.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what this is all about.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about reducing family energy bills while protecting the grid from extreme weather and making power more reliable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s also about jobs.&nbsp; No one knows it better than all of you around this table: The investment is going to support the creation of hundreds of thousands of good-paying jobs all across the country and how it flows from this &#8212; what you&#8217;re all about to do, or God willing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s going to make us more economically competitive while reducing pollution and improving public health, and helping us meet the moment on climate change &#8212; the most important piece of it, in my view.</p>



<p>These investments are about today, and they&#8217;re also about the future.&nbsp; And we can do it without increasing the deficit or raising taxes on anyone making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp; And 17 Nobel laureates spontaneously &#8212; in economics &#8212; spontaneously wrote to me, telling me that they believed that this would ease long-term inflation.</p>



<p>And so, the CEOs know exactly why a clean energy future matters.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an incredible opportunity for our country.&nbsp; And &#8212; and they know how urgent it is to get this done.&nbsp; And there have been &#8212; you know, they&#8217;ve been key partners throughout this entire process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I&#8217;m grateful for their input, and I look forward to getting a full report from my team on the ideas discussed today.</p>



<p>But with your permission, I&#8217;d like to stick around a little bit and maybe ask a few questions.&nbsp; And again, I can&#8217;t tell you how &#8212;</p>



<p>Back up.&nbsp; Four years ago, when I was sitting talking about this issue, the question was, “No &#8212; no one is &#8212; you guys aren&#8217;t going to do this.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not going to happen.”&nbsp; No, I mean, for real.&nbsp; That was the nature of the discussion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you&#8217;re here saying you support this and you&#8217;re going to try to move if we can get this Build Back Better piece done.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;d like to start off with you, Pat, if I may &#8212; excuse me &#8212; mind me calling you Pat.&nbsp; I apolog- &#8212; you can call me Joe.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>You&#8217;re &#8212; PNM operates in New Mexico and Texas and powering 800,000 homes and businesses.</p>



<p>How is this Build Back Better initiative is going to deliver more reliable and affordable power and reduce costs for &#8212; if you &#8212; if we have it available to you to be able to get the tax benefits?</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:&nbsp; Well, Mr. President, thank you for the opportunity to speak.&nbsp; And thank you for your support of our clean energy future.</p>



<p>We started our clean energy journey some time ago in New Mexico, working with our governor, the environmental community, the business community, and our Indigenous communities, all who support clean energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’ll &#8212; this legislation is going to allow us to be carbon-free sooner, gives us renewable portfolio standards, allows us to securitize to keep costs down for customers, and very importantly, Mr. President, it provides for a just transition.</p>



<p>There is money in there for worker severance and retraining for the coal miners.&nbsp; We already take care of our coal plant employees at the utility.&nbsp; But it has money for economic development in there to revitalize the communities.&nbsp; So, working with economic development, Indian Affairs, and Workforce Solutions.&nbsp; Because when people move into the clean energy economy, they shouldn&#8217;t have to move away from their Tribal lands.&nbsp; And we are going to work to revitalize those communities so that they can participate in the clean energy future where they currently live.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These clean energy tax policies are going to be so helpful.&nbsp; New Mexico, unfortunately, is the third poorest state.&nbsp; And the areas that we serve in Texas are not the affluent areas of Texas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a regulated utility, we pass all of our tax savings directly back to our customers.&nbsp; And along with reliability in clean, affordable, it is really on the top of our priority list.</p>



<p>We have the number-three solar potential in the United States in New Mexico and the number-three onshore wind potential.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, having credits for that and for storage, which is critical to make sure that those resources can be stored &#8212; so we need them when we need them &#8212; and the building of the transmission to export those wind and solar resources to other states is also critical.&nbsp; So that transmission in solar &#8212; and storage &#8212; and wind is really going to help bring down the customer cost.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also looking to integrate more electric vehicles into the grid.&nbsp; I tell people: Once you drive an electric vehicle, you don&#8217;t want to drive an internal combustion engine anymore.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re quiet and quick.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:&nbsp; Oh, are they quick.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this will help us make the needed improvements in our grid at a lower cost.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on the corporate tax rate, when we keep that low, we also pass those savings back to our customers.&nbsp; And, unfortunately, any increases conversely get pushed back to customers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, President Biden, your support of clean energy and the clean energy tax policies will really allow us to accelerate that &#8212; making energy reliable, affordable, and cleaner sooner.</p>



<p>So, thank you so much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you.</p>



<p>One of the things that I spent some time in one of the very &#8212; this is how many years ago now?&nbsp; I guess three years ago &#8212; in a very large solar site in Nevada.</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:Yes.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And one of the things we were talking about at the time, and I met &#8212; it created a hell of a lot of jobs, but it will create more jobs if you can actually transmit that solar energy on a line to a destination that is one that can use it well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They &#8212; my team tells me that there is a &#8212; a capacity to, by further investment in machinery on the site, that it is going to be able to, through high voltage &#8212; HVDC tech, move that energy more quickly and lose less of it on the way.&nbsp; Is that right?</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:Absolutely.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And tell me how that &#8212; I mean, will &#8212; will you be in a better position to be able to &#8212; for your solar sites &#8212; be able to afford that with, in fact, you have the tax credits that are moving?</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:&nbsp; Yeah, the tax credits will make the more sophisticated transmission infrastructure much less expensive.&nbsp; And, again, we pass those savings all along to the consumers.&nbsp; And a lot of the solar &#8212; and where you cite solar fields &#8212; is not near what we call “load centers,” or big cities, so you need that transmission.&nbsp; And it is going to be absolutely critical to building our nation&#8217;s clean energy infrastructure.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, my wife and I, separately, spent a little bit of time with those Indigenous communities in &#8212; in New Mexico and other places.&nbsp; And it really makes a difference &#8212; it will make a difference for them in a big way, I think.</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And, you know, especially the Navajo Nation is embracing a clean energy future.&nbsp; They&#8217;re very thoughtful about how they move away.&nbsp; But they are very much looking forward to developing the solar potential on their lands.&nbsp; And we will be able to export that to other parts of the West that desperately need some more clean energy.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, as an aside, before I go to you, Nick, I was out in Colorado looking at the experimental efforts going on up there in the mountains.&nbsp; I was stunned.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m familiar with wind energy, because we tried very hard early on in the last administration I was in to promote that.&nbsp; And we had some blowback because people didn&#8217;t want to be able to see it and the like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They showed me a blade of a windmill that&#8217;s 100 yards long.&nbsp; My Lord.&nbsp; I mean, I looked at that and thought, “Holy Lord.”&nbsp; I mean, can&#8217;t fatho- &#8212; I think some of the press was with me on that trip.&nbsp; It was&nbsp;&#8212; it was astounding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you&#8217;re at AEP, Nick.&nbsp; You use a variety of traditional fuels to make power like coal, natural gas, and nuclear.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good to see you now expanding into wind and solar.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tell me a little bit about the expansion and the renewables &#8212; how that&#8217;s going for you.&nbsp; Is it going to reduce costs to customers?&nbsp; How &#8212; and how, if at all, does my initiative on Build Back Better, the over $500 billion we&#8217;re talking about for the energy side of this &#8212; of which, by the way, I think it&#8217;s about $200 billion in tax credits and another $100 billion for resilience.&nbsp; But talk to me about how &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. AKINS:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; how you&#8217;re making your decisions.</p>



<p>MR. AKINS:&nbsp; Well, first of all, Mr. President, a pleasure to be with you today to talk about these important issues.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve actually shed the light on a lot of the infrastructure needs of this country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, certainly, the grid is one of those areas that &#8212; that we find &#8212; and I grew up as a system operator.&nbsp; Forty years ago, I started as a system operator running power systems.&nbsp; So, for me, your focus on resiliency and reliability of the grid is extremely important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The addition of renewables in place today is having a substantial impact on the ability to save customers money.&nbsp; Matter of fact, we &#8212; this quarter, we&#8217;ll be putting in &#8212; operational &#8212; the largest wind power project in North America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Is that right?</p>



<p>MR. AKINS:&nbsp; About 1,000 megawatts in Oklahoma.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to save customers about $2.2 billion over the life of the agreement.&nbsp; So, certainly, it’s a huge benefit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for us, it&#8217;s really an opportunity to bring these kinds of resources in, lower costs to customers, and be able to move toward that clean energy future.&nbsp; So, as we look &#8212; as we look at that &#8212; we&#8217;ve looked at it across our territories.&nbsp; And now we have a plan by 2030 to put over 16,000 megawatts of generation like that in place.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s really an important opportunity for us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also partner extensively with Lonnie Stephenson, the IBEW, and the unions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re mapping that transition to those skills of the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly, partners like that and partners in the federal government can enable this &#8212; this industry to move much more quickly than we would have otherwise, particularly with the tax provisions; ITCs &#8212; investment tax credits; and so forth.&nbsp; Those have really produced benefits for consumers, because those costs &#8212; those benefits actually flow through to our consumers and contribute to the economy.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s a great opportunity for us to make that transition.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s a heck of an opportunity.&nbsp; One of the things &#8212; maybe when the press is still here &#8212; to talk a little bit about &#8212; you know, I was really excited back in, I guess it was probably two thousand and &#8212; don’t hold me to exact year &#8212; probably 2012, &#8217;13, &#8217;14.&nbsp; We were talking about major wind initiative off the eastern coast, the coast of the &#8212; on the East Coast.&nbsp; And they said there was a &#8212; you know, an effort to go off the coast of Delaware and off the coast of New Jersey.&nbsp; And I think it was &#8212; they were going to &#8212; I think it was able to power &#8212; don&#8217;t hold me to the number &#8212; like 800,000 homes in New Jersey.&nbsp; But there was a real blowback when people said, “I don&#8217;t want to see those things.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, remember, up in Nantucket area and Nantucket Sound and &#8212;</p>



<p>Tell me about &#8212; when you say you&#8217;re going to have this largest, essentially, wind farm in Oklahoma, what is the reception of the community with that?</p>



<p>MR. AKINS:&nbsp; Oh, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s been very, very positive, because &#8212; not only do they see the benefits of the clean energy, but also the job creations.&nbsp; But the benefits for customers are considerable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, where we run into some issues is &#8212; when there&#8217;s large-scale transmission, which you mentioned to Pat, we really do need to find ways to scope large transmission to get renewables to the &#8212; to the big cities.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a process that, obviously, your administration has been working on as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for us, it&#8217;s important to scope those projects, because the savings associated with renewables will actually pay for the transmission.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. AKINS:&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a key area for us to be able to continue to grow.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Are all of you &#8212; generic question: Are you getting less resistance when you start talking about wind and the windmills?&nbsp; I know they cause cancer.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Bad joke.&nbsp; I shouldn&#8217;t kid about that.&nbsp; I shouldn’t have kidded.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, I mean, people &#8212; I mean, what &#8212; what kind of resistance do you have to &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. ANDERSON:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; if you &#8212; if your using wind?</p>



<p>MR. ANDERSON:&nbsp; I can &#8212; I can speak to the arc in Michigan.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve done a lot of wind in Michigan.&nbsp; We have a pretty good wind regime there.&nbsp; It &#8212; it is what Nick said, that if you get in a community that&#8217;s highly mixed &#8212; where some benefit and some don&#8217;t &#8212; you&#8217;ll get resistance.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re in a community that&#8217;s more rural &#8212; where it becomes a part of their economy, their jobs, their income &#8212; the reception is quite high.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are actually at a transition point in Michigan where solar has now crossed over and is highly competitive with wind.&nbsp; So, I think after a long period of investment in wind, we&#8217;re now going to see our largest-scale investments in solar, and the reception to solar has been very high.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great addition to the tax base.&nbsp; Big construct- &#8212; billions of dollars of construction that plays out, and then the permanent jobs that follow.&nbsp; So we expect that to be a well-received renewable resource in the state.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I spent a fair amount of time, prior to the campaign &#8212; campaigning and since then &#8212; with some of the really entrepreneurial geniuses out in Silicon Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what they&#8217;re now talking about &#8212; and you all know, and I wonder how you view it &#8212; is the ability to store the energy when the wind&#8217;s not blowing and when the sun&#8217;s not shining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I was shown, for example, a &#8212; you could have &#8212; let&#8217;s say you were powered either &#8212; even it could be geothermal, for that matter.&nbsp; But you have a facility &#8212; a &#8212; it looks like &#8212; to me, it looked like a platform about this wide and about that thick that&#8217;s in your basement.&nbsp; And it stores energy when the wind&#8217;s not blowing up when the sun is not shining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Are you &#8212; do you &#8212; and I know you’re not making those, but how &#8212; has that increased the receptiveness of the idea of wind and solar or geothermal?</p>



<p>Yes, Lynn.</p>



<p>MS. GOOD:&nbsp; Yeah, I can respond, Mr. President.&nbsp; Again, thank you for having us join.&nbsp; But we see storage as an incredibly important part of the equation going forward &#8212; not only in people&#8217;s homes, but, frankly, on our system &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>MS. GOOD:&nbsp; &#8212; in order to strengthen it and make it capable of taking on more resiliency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as I look at the number of megawatts of renewables we&#8217;ll add, there&#8217;s a comparable number of storage megawatts we will also add over the next decades.&nbsp; And the tax credits that you have included would be an important part of lowering costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the infrastructure bill, under the Department of Energy, has a lot of investment in the R&amp;D necessary to advance that battery storage.&nbsp; So, we think there&#8217;s great potential for this.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I asked the question for a selfish reason.&nbsp; Because when I said &#8212; this is going to generate jobs well beyond your site.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so, there are going to be people manufacturing those battery storage facilities.&nbsp; People man- &#8212; I mean &#8212; so I mean, this has such a ripple effect that &#8212; God willing.</p>



<p>And what&#8217;s going to happen is, I predict &#8212; you know, right now, in some cases, China is ahead of us, but I think we&#8217;re going to end up having a significant export market as well that&#8217;s going to create thousands of good-paying jobs here in the United States.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be in our interests to have this, you know, move around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, you know, I hope that you all are going to look back on this 10 years from now and say, “Boy, that time we didn&#8217;t have any dinner at that dining room table.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; “It still worked.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I want to thank you all very, very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p> 3:01 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Introduction of the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-introduction-of-the-violence-against-women-act-reauthorization-act-of-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 22:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I applaud the bipartisan group of Senators who have joined together to introduce the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022 (VAWA), following passage last year of a bipartisan bill in the House of Representatives to renew and significantly strengthen this essential law.&#160; I am especially grateful to Senators Feinstein, Ernst, Durbin, and Murkowski&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I applaud the bipartisan group of Senators who have joined together to introduce the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022 (VAWA), following passage last year of a bipartisan bill in the House of Representatives to renew and significantly strengthen this essential law.&nbsp; I am especially grateful to Senators Feinstein, Ernst, Durbin, and Murkowski for their ongoing leadership and commitment. I commend the tremendous dedication of advocates and honor the courage and resilience of survivors who have been on the frontlines of advocacy efforts to improve laws and work toward creating a society where everyone has an opportunity to thrive without fear of violence or abuse.&nbsp; I urge the Senate to move quickly to get this passed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I first wrote and championed the original VAWA legislation, it helped break a dam of congressional and cultural resistance that too often saw domestic violence as a ‘family issue,’ with legal and social burdens placed on survivors rather than perpetrators.&nbsp; In the nearly three decades since its passage, the law has been reauthorized three times with broad bipartisan support.&nbsp; Each time, I have helped work to strengthen its protections — expanding access to safety and resources for all survivors, particularly those from marginalized communities. And while studies have shown that domestic violence and sexual assault rates have declined significantly since VAWA took effect, we know that we still have work to do.</p>



<p>The VAWA Reauthorization Act of 2022 will expand prevention efforts and protections for survivors, including those from underserved communities, and will provide increased resources and training for law enforcement and our judicial system.&nbsp; It will strengthen rape prevention and education efforts, support rape crisis centers, improve the training of sexual assault forensic examiners, and broaden access to legal services for all survivors, among other things.</p>



<p>Combatting domestic violence, sexual assault, dating violence, and stalking should not be a Democratic issue or Republican issue. It’s a matter of justice and compassion.&nbsp; I am grateful that this critical bipartisan bill is moving forward, and I look forward to Congress delivering it to my desk without delay.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 9,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/09/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-9-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 21:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:24 P.M. EST  &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:&#160; Okay.&#160; A couple of items for you at the top.&#160; Today, the President is hosting a roundtable of CEOs of electric utilities from all over the country to discuss his economic growth plan for the middle class &#8212; the Build Back Better Agenda &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:24 P.M. EST </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; A couple of items for you at the top.&nbsp; Today, the President is hosting a roundtable of CEOs of electric utilities from all over the country to discuss his economic growth plan for the middle class &#8212; the Build Back Better Agenda &#8212; which will lower energy costs for working families, create good-paying union jobs, and build a reliable clean-energy future as we tackle the climate crisis.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President and these executives will discuss &#8212; or they are discussing, I guess I should say &#8212; how investments to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and expand tax credits for clean energy and research &#8212; for research and development are necessary, overdue, and critical for increasing the resiliency of our electrical grid and essential to helping the pocketbooks of Americans around the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The executives and organizations attending this discussion operate key parts of America&#8217;s power grid, and they know that the best way to ensure future economic growth is to make long-term investments to combat the climate crisis, increase the competitiveness of our industries, and protect our electrical grid from extreme weather events.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Aamer, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, thanks.&nbsp; So, new CPI numbers come out tomorrow, and economists are forecasting an index of, I believe, 7.3 percent annually.&nbsp; And I was just wanting to ask: What do you see in the data right now that suggests inflation will fall quickly this year?&nbsp; And how confident are you that a decrease in inflation can occur without hurting demand in the economy?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me start with a little bit of a preview just so &#8212; well, we don&#8217;t know the numbers; I know there are projections &#8212; but just as people are preparing to look at these numbers and prepare to report on the numbers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, first, when we look at tomorrow&#8217;s data, what we&#8217;re looking at is recent trends in inflation.&nbsp; So, in November and December, price increases showed relative to the month before &#8212; slowed relative to the month before.&nbsp; And in January, they were down almost half from where they were in October.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s a sign of progress that the inflationary increases are increased &#8212; decreasing, I should say, month to month.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be looking at that wage growth compared &#8212; looking how wage growth compared to inflation in January as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is also coming out tomorrow is annual data &#8212; right? &#8212; which is, I think, what you&#8217;re talking about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And so, as we&#8217;re looking at that, we do &#8212; we expect a high year-over-year inflation rate reading in tomorrow&#8217;s data, given what we know about the last year &#8212; right? &#8212; and what we&#8217;ve seen over the last year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s because year-over-year data largely reflects the price increases over the last year, as we&#8217;ve already talked about and we know about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about the most recent trends, which I think is the important component for people to look at.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; There&#8217;s monthly, and then there&#8217;s also the annual data.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, above 7 percent, as I think some are predicting, would not be a surprise, even though we don&#8217;t know what the data is going to be &#8212; going to be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But looking at that reading of it as we prepare for tomorrow is still consistent with the path, in our view &#8212; to go to your question &#8212; that leading outside forecasters continue to project that inflationary- &#8212; inflation is expected to decrease over the course and moderate over the course of this year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, that continues to be outside projections, even as we&#8217;re preparing for the new data tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think there was another part of your question, but I wanted to explain what people should prepare for.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I guess, with the &#8212; just getting back to &#8220;How confident are you that a decrease can occur without hurting demand in the economy?&#8221; &#8212; was the second part of the question.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, as you know, the Federal Reserve has purview over &#8212; over taking the independent approaches they so choose to.&nbsp; And we certainly &#8212; as the President has said, he welcomes and supports their efforts to take steps &#8212; or their plans to take steps.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of our confidence: We, again, rely on what their projections are about the projection that inflation will come down, that it will moderate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we are also continuing to take steps to continue to grow the economy, continue to address the needs that the American people have in the economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if I could ask a question about &#8212; New York, today, was the latest to work on their mask mandates.&nbsp; Several states are now, it seems, well ahead of the federal government in explaining the path out of the pandemic.&nbsp; Is the President now falling behind states in explaining to Americans how are &#8212; we all can, sort of, resume our normal lives and get back to normalcy?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President has been clear on &#8212; has said that we are moving toward a time when COVID won&#8217;t disrupt our daily lives, a time when COVID won&#8217;t be a constant crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think you all heard him talk about that in his press conference two weeks ago.&nbsp; And that is something that &#8212; as Jeff Zients, I believe, just said during the COVID briefing earlier today &#8212; there&#8217;s an active and ongoing work plan to develop a path forward.&nbsp; And that is &#8212; there&#8217;s constant discussion about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think what you&#8217;re referring to, as it relates to New York &#8212; which is an important component, especially as Americans are consuming what it means and where we&#8217;re going of masks and what the mask guidance is &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Dr. Walensky was also on this COVID briefing that happened just earlier this morning.&nbsp; And what she conveyed on that briefing &#8212; I know there&#8217;s a lot going on, so you may not have all seen what she said, but &#8212; is that we certainly understand the need to be flexible.&nbsp; We want to ensure that public health guidance we&#8217;re providing meets the moment we&#8217;re in.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We recognize people are tired of the pandemic.&nbsp; They&#8217;re tired of wearing masks.&nbsp; I bet all of you are.&nbsp; I certainly know I am.&nbsp; We all understand that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But that &#8212; what our focus is on is looking at the data and science.&nbsp; So, there’s good &#8212; there are positive signs, as she referred to: cases and hospitalizations are falling.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking at all of the guidance based on the latest data and science.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; She also said &#8212; which is, I think, important for people to note &#8212; that we continue to &#8212; while we continue to recommend masking in areas of high and substantial transmission &#8212; which is basically the entire country at this point; that&#8217;s essentially everywhere &#8212; for indoor settings, we are evaluating rates of transmission.&nbsp; We&#8217;re evaluating and looking at data to see if any changes need to be made.&nbsp; And that is something, of course, the CDC continues to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I would say that we are internally discussing, of course, what it looks like to be in the phase of the fight against the COVID pandemic where it is not disrupting everyone&#8217;s daily lives; where people are moving on and living, you know, lives free of, hopefully, masks at some point and many of the restrictions that we&#8217;ve all been living through over the past two years.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But as the federal government, we have the responsibility to rely on data, on science, on the medical experts.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the President committed to during the campaign.&nbsp; They committed &#8212; they confirmed, during this briefing, they are continuing to evaluate and there&#8217;s ongoing discussions and work happening internally.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one last thing.&nbsp; The Pentagon has yet to commit to media embeds with U.S. troops that have and are deploying to the Baltics?&nbsp; Why?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is it consistent, just generally, with the administration&#8217;s pledge to transparency?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I just saw the reports about this.&nbsp; And I will acknowledge to you I have to dig into this a little bit further.&nbsp; I certainly understand the question and the desire to be embedded with troops and seeing what&#8217;s happening on the ground, just as many of you have reporters and outlets who are near the border or seeing what&#8217;s happening for yourselves the military buildup of troops.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So let me check into this and see if I can get back to all of you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Following up on that, does the White House generally support the notion of troops &#8212; embedding with U.S. troops around the world?</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly have in the past.&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p><a>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I know that the Trump administration took a different view.&nbsp; So, does this White House envision a return to the practice of U.S. journalists embedding with U.S. forces &#8212; when they&#8217;re in Eastern Europe, for example &#8212; in the nation&#8217;s interest?</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That has been our overarching approach, as you&#8217;ve seen over the last year.&nbsp; I&#8217;d have to check in to this specific question that Aamer has asked me and I think you&#8217;re following up on.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Great.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The White House has made it pretty clear there is no plan for a mass evacuation of American citizens in Ukraine.&nbsp; And, in fact, you and the President and others have suggested that Americans who are in Ukraine should leave now if they can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the same time, it&#8217;s been projected that Russia could overtake Kyiv in two days if it invades.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, what happens to Americans if they do get stranded in Ukraine?&nbsp; Should they understand that the U.S. is not coming to get them?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let&#8217;s just take a step back here.&nbsp; First, we don&#8217;t know that President Putin has made a decision to invade.&nbsp; We still don&#8217;t have a new assessment on that.&nbsp; Right?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m obviously not going to discuss intelligence reports, which I think you also referenced.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What I can tell you is that it&#8217;s not just that the President or I have been conveying this warning to U.S. citizens.&nbsp; This is something the State Department has been doing for weeks and weeks and weeks now.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know there have also been a range of reports out there about American citizens.&nbsp; As you all know, because we&#8217;ve discussed this before, U.S. citizens are not required to register their travel to a foreign country with us.&nbsp; And we don&#8217;t maintain a comprehensive list of U.S. citizens.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That said, the State Department does estima- &#8212; does estimates from time to time.&nbsp; And I know there have been much larger numbers out there.&nbsp; So I just wanted to reiterate for all of you that back in October, the State Department estimated there were at the time &#8212; so, months ago &#8212; about 6,600 U.S. citizens residing in Ukraine.&nbsp; Not much far- &#8212; not much larger than that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There have been &#8212; of course, there are periodic times &#8212; during the holiday season &#8212; where there are assessments of tourists and visitors and others.&nbsp; But in terms of citizens residing in Ukraine &#8212; many of which would be dual citizens.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, what people should understand is that the United States does not typically do mass evacuations.&nbsp; Of course, the situation in Afghanistan was unique for many reasons, including that it was the end of a 20-year war.&nbsp; We were bringing a war to an end; we were not trying to prevent a war, as we are certainly in this case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are a range of means that individuals and Americans can depart from Ukraine, and we&#8217;ve been encouraging them to do exactly that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what we have been &#8212; how we&#8217;ve been looking at this is much more &#8212; much more similar to what was ordered in Ethiopia or Kazakhstan in recent months, where the security circumstances on the ground warranted travel advisories and warnings from the State Department.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you explain how the process would work if U.S. citizens were able to make it by land to Poland or Romania?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the plan that&#8217;s being put in place to help them?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean if they cross the border?&nbsp; Well, there are &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If there is &#8212; if there is an invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there are still &#8212; I think what we are encouraging American citizens to do is depart now, obviously.&nbsp; There hasn’t been an invasion, and we don’t know that there has been a decision to invade.&nbsp; Obviously, we have a range of diplomatic presences &#8212; not only in Ukraine, but in neighboring countries &#8212; that are always available for U.S. citizens should they need assistance.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; HHS just put out a statement clarifying around some reports that crack pipes are not going to be part of the “safe smoking kits” that are funded by the administration.&nbsp; But can you clarify for us: Were they never a part of the kit or were they removed in response to this reporting and this pushback?&nbsp; Just &#8212; the language was unclear.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They were never a part of the kit; it was inaccurate reporting.&nbsp; And we wanted to put out information to make that clear.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, what is in the safe smoking kit?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A safe smoking kit may contain alcohol swabs, lip balm, other materials to promote hygiene and reduce the transmission of disea- &#8212; diseases like HIV and hepatitis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note that what we&#8217;re really talking about here is steps that we&#8217;re taking as a federal government to address the opioid epidemic, which is killing tens of thousands &#8212; if not more &#8212; Americans every single day, week, month of the year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We put out this statement, though, because there was inaccurate information out there &#8212; or I should say, HHS put out the statement because there was inaccurate information out there, and we wanted to provide clarification on the allowable uses for the HHS Harm Reduction program.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a change in policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This program, though, is focused on harm reduction strategies, including prioritizing the use of fentanyl test strips and clean syringes.&nbsp; And all of these harm reduction services that will be supported by these programs are intended to save lives from an epidemic that we know is devastating to communities across the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then &#8212; so just to put a final point on it, does the administration support any effort then to distribute drug paraphernalia like the types that we were hearing about?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We &#8212; the statement makes clear that we don&#8217;t support federal funding, indirect or direct, for pipes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And then on the safe injection sites that the DOJ is evaluating: Was this an ask from the White House that they review that policy?&nbsp; Because I know that, for years, DOJ has opposed efforts to open safe injection sites.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s under litigation, so I can&#8217;t speak to that.&nbsp; But what I can tell you and reiterate is that the White House is committed &#8212; as I will &#8212; as I would reiterate for you, many Democrats and Republicans, including Senator Cruz &#8212; to taking steps to address the opioid crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is not an issue that is inflicting just blue states.&nbsp; It is inflicting millions of Americans across the country, and it is important that we take steps to address it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, just final wrap of those two items: What would you say to critics who are concerned that the Biden administration is somehow encouraging illegal drug use?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think that it&#8217;s important to step back and remember &#8212; just to put a little more of a fine point on it &#8212; that we are losing an American life every five minutes to overdose.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have time for political games.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President is focused on saving lives through harm reduction programs.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re talking about here.&nbsp; They work in red states, and they work in blue states.&nbsp; We know they save lives; they help connect people to treatment and recovery.&nbsp; And they were endorsed this week by a bipartisan commission co-chaired by Senator Tom Cotton that examines steps we must take to address the devastating toll of overdoses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what I would say is: This is not a game.&nbsp; This is not a political game.&nbsp; This is an epidemic that is taking the life of five &#8212; of an American every five minutes, and we need to work in a bipartisan way to address it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Can I ask real quick about the masks?&nbsp; We had another state today dropping the indoor mask mandate as the CDC is confirming that their guidance is not changing.&nbsp; But these decisions that are being made at the local level, like you guys always talk about, are out of step with the science that is at the forefront of the CDC, of this White House.&nbsp; So why are we not hearing the same messaging criticizing states that are, you know, making these moves like we heard previously with, for instance, Ron DeSantis?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say there is a distinct difference between standing in the way, which Ron DeSantis did &#8212; or Governor DeSantis; I&#8217;ll give him his full title &#8212; of teachers, school administrators, and others taking steps to protect the students in their school communities.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a difference between standing in the way of it, threatening to pull back funding; and allowing for local school districts to make choices, which is what a number of these states are doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, quick follow-up on that.&nbsp; Does the administration risk looking out of touch with where the country is heading, in terms of lifting these mask mandates, if the CDC doesn&#8217;t revise its guidelines?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we understand where the emotions of the country are, right?&nbsp; People are tired of masks.&nbsp; I would say not even &#8212; if you look at the polling though, there&#8217;s also a huge chunk of people who still want masks.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s not even that specific.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just that, as you noted, there are some states that are moving towards rolling back or giving more choice to local communities about how they will implement these requirements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, again, from the federal government, what our responsibility to do is to abide by what the President committed to on the campaign, which is to listen to scientists, listen to data.&nbsp; That doesn&#8217;t move at the speed of politics; it moves at the speed of data.&nbsp; And they &#8212; Dr. Walensky committed to &#8212; conveyed &#8212; or, I should say, confirmed that they were evaluating this at the CDC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to just ask you about Russia.&nbsp; You were very careful in your wording when you were asked yesterday the extent to which the administration understands what happened between Presidents Macron and President Putin.&nbsp; Can you give us any more information today?&nbsp; To what extent has the administration been briefed, has the President been briefed directly on those talks, and &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President spoke with President Macron this morning, which I believe we confirmed?&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what does he understand about what came out of that meeting?&nbsp; Did &#8212; does he have the same sense of optimism that President Macron had when he left that meeting &#8212; that, yes, perhaps there had been a tiny bit of progress in terms of helping create an offramp for President Putin?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Kristen, the President spoke, as I noted, with President Macron earlier today.&nbsp; He, as you know, spoke &#8212; hosted the German Chancellor, and I expect he will speak when &#8212; with a number of other European counterparts as the week proceeds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;re looking at here, Kristen, is not reports out of a meeting but whether or not Russia is taking de-escalatory steps.&nbsp; They are not.&nbsp; They are taking escalatory, not de-escalatory, steps.&nbsp; We certainly hope that that changes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you, based on the intelligence that you have, do not share the same measured optimism that President Putin had coming out of that meeting?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, we&#8217;re looking at &#8212; we&#8217;re looking at actions here, and we have not seen de-escalatory actions by the Russians.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any imminent plans for President Biden to speak with President Putin?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As you probably are tired of hearing me say, but I&#8217;ll just repeat it: The President certainly values leader-to-leader engagement.&nbsp; He has spoken with President Putin, as you know, multiple times in the past, including in person.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if I could just ask you one question.&nbsp; Overnight, the President tweeted about this potential bill that has been proposed in Florida that would restrict school districts from encouraging discussion about sexual orientation or gender identity in public schools.&nbsp; The President tweeted out that he wanted them “to know that you are loved and accepted just as you are. I have your back.”&nbsp; What, if anything, can President Biden do &#8212; is he planning to do &#8212; if, in fact, that does pass?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, unfortunately, this is not the only bill or the only effort we&#8217;re seeing across the country to really regulate what students can or cannot read, what they can or cannot learn, and, most troubling, who they can or cannot be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I think you saw on the President&#8217;s treat &#8212; tweet, it&#8217;s cruel.&nbsp; It&#8217;s harmful.&nbsp; And, you know, it is certainly something that is not helping, you know, young people who are members of LGBTQI+ community who are already vulnerable, are already being bullied.&nbsp; I think the President felt it was important to speak out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of specific actions, you know, we&#8217;re going to continue to voice our strong views on this.&nbsp; It&#8217;s significant the President did that.&nbsp; And if there&#8217;s any additional steps, I&#8217;ll let you know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Back to Ukraine for a second.&nbsp; Tomorrow, it&#8217;s expected to be these &#8212; this Russia-Belarus military exercise.&nbsp; Is it the sense of this administration that what&#8217;s expected to be this massive show of force tomorrow and for the next few days after that could provide some sort of cover for an invasion?&nbsp; And is the White House and are its allies on any kind of heightened alert given what&#8217;s expected to happen?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t make a prediction of that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure your colleagues will ask the Pentagon that question.&nbsp; But I think as we look at the preparation for these military exercises, again, we see this as certainly more of an escalatory and not a de-escalatory action as it relates to those troops and the military exercises.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is happening at the border of Ukra- &#8212; at the border as well.&nbsp; So, that is certainly concerning to us, but I wouldn&#8217;t make a prediction of what it means in terms of invasion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And back to masks, not to belabor it &#8212; but in a matter of weeks, Americans have heard the White House say masks are so important you should get online and order yours for your family right now.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve got, now, this wave of states that are saying, “Actually, you don’t have to necessarily wear masks.&nbsp; We’re going to do away with some of these mandates.”&nbsp; And now you’ve got the CDC saying its guidance stands; “We&#8217;re going to review things, but the guidance stands.”&nbsp; Can you blame Americans for being confused and frustrated and having no idea who they should be listening to right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our guidance is consistently &#8212; has consistently been this: When you are in a high-transmission area, which is everywhere in the country, you should wear a mask in indoor settings, including schools.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are states that have rolled back their mask guidelines, that have given more flexibility to communities.&nbsp; They&#8217;re different; they&#8217;re just not uniform, what every state has done.&nbsp; And, certainly, we continue to advise and recommend abiding by public health guidelines.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But do you dispute that Americans are confused by what’s happening right now?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we should do everything we can to prevent them from being confused, so I&#8217;m restating what our policy is here, from the federal government, which is based on public health guidelines.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the CDC run the risk of becoming irrelevant in the minds of many Americans, given that their states are moving along &#8212; ahead without them?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think the federal experts on health and medical advice should be irrelevant to Americans at a time where we&#8217;re still facing a pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Negotiations on a Russian sanctions bill have stalled in Congress, or hit a bump.&nbsp; What is the latest White House thinking on that bill?&nbsp; What are some of the things you want to see emerge in the weeks ahead or days ahead?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, we believe it&#8217;s an important &#8212; important to show a united front to Russia and, hence, we&#8217;ve been doing a range of briefings with Democratic and Republican leadership and members and committees over the course of the last several weeks.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been gratified by the bipartisan support we&#8217;ve seen for the actions we&#8217;ve taken and will take if Russia further invades Ukraine.&nbsp; We welcome the bipartisan focus on Russia and Ukraine in Congress and think that a bipartisan bill would send a strong message to President Putin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s momentum building for a bill to bar lawmakers from owning stock.&nbsp; Does the White House believe that lawmakers should own stock?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me just, first, reiterate something many of you who covered the campaign may already be familiar with.&nbsp; But, one, President Biden believes &#8212; has never been somebody who&#8217;s owned and traded stock as a member of the Senate.&nbsp; He&#8217;s talked about that a lot throughout his career.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During the campaign, he committed to work with Congress to take steps to ensure that there wasn&#8217;t conflicts of interest that are being presented as &#8212; as this legislation is being discussed.&nbsp; And he also believes that all government agencies and officials, including independent agencies, should be held to the highest ethical standards.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s early in the legislative process, so I don&#8217;t have a new comment today on the specifics of this legislation.&nbsp; But I would just reiterate how the President has operated and conducted himself, as he has been in public life for just a few years now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Senator Manchin has talked about there&#8217;s no more Build Back Better bill publicly.&nbsp; Has the White House or your team ever considered rebranding the bill &#8212; a name change?&nbsp; Is that something that you&#8217;ve considered and you think would be beneficial?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Look, I think our objective is working with Democrats, Republicans &#8212; if they decide they&#8217;re for lowering the cost of prescription drugs, they&#8217;re welcome to join us in this effort &#8212; but to determine how much of the President&#8217;s Build Back Better agenda &#8212; whatever you call it &#8212; can be moved forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there is agreement on a number of big components, including with Senator Manchin, about the importance of lowering the cost of childcare, what burden that has on families across the country; about the importance of lowering the cost of healthcare; of making the tax system more fair; of negotiating &#8212; of allowing Medicare to negotiate the price of prescription drugs, something the President will be going to Virginia tomorrow to talk about.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, these discussions are ongoing.&nbsp; A lot of them, as the Pre- &#8212; you heard the President say at the press conference two weeks ago, are happening between members on the Hill &#8212; right? &#8212; to determine what they can have support for.&nbsp; And our staff and senior members of the team are engaged in those as well.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, given that the CDC guideline still remains that masking is recommended in schools, if you are a parent, a teacher, a student living in a state where that is no longer recommended, should you still follow the CDC guideline?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes?&nbsp; So, even if the state is not requiring that you wear masks in the schools?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, this is where we would advise any American to follow the CDC guidelines.&nbsp; And as Dr. Walensky said, and you referenced, they&#8217;re constantly evaluating &#8212; right? &#8212; because the data is changing, the science is changing.&nbsp; It certainly is positive that case numbers have come down, hospitalizations come down.&nbsp; And they look at all of that information.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s also important to note the difference between leaders who are saying, “We&#8217;re going to leave it up to localities, local school districts to make decisions.”&nbsp; No parent who wants to send their kid with a mask should be penalized.&nbsp; No teacher or &#8212; who wants to wear a mask should be penalized or school district who makes that choice should be penalized.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it &#8212; a lot of these decisions have been up to local school districts.&nbsp; In the past, we have made a &#8212; we have funded and we have made announcements about a number of mitigation measures, which we will continue to work with school districts to implement.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s been almost a month, I think, since President Biden addressed the issue of the pandemic in the form of a major speech.&nbsp; Why has it been that long since Americans have heard from him in, sort of, that kind of a setting about the pandemic?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, the President answered questions about the pandemic less than two weeks ago during a press conference.&nbsp; And, certainly, we have regular COVID briefings to provide the American people with an update on where things stand.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re currently, as I noted a little bit earlier, discussing what the next phase of the pandemic looks like.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an ongoing process. &nbsp;And the American people can expect to continue to hear from the President on it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would it be fair to say that the President believes the country is turning a corner on the pandemic?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t want to characterize, other than to convey that we look at hospitalization numbers &#8212; they&#8217;re coming down.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a good sign.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question about that.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are looking at all of the tools we have in our toolbox, which is &#8212; certainly puts us in a very different position than we were in a year ago, whether it&#8217;s the antiviral pills, the ability to send out masks and tests to Americans who want them, the fact that 75 percent of adults are vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is all good &#8212; these are all good signs, all good information.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re continuing to discuss and assess internally what the next phase might look like.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I&#8217;d like to ask you a question about a CNN investigation about the Kabul airport blast back in August.&nbsp; This investigation looked at medical records; it interviewed doctors in Kabul, victims, and witnesses; and it raises some questions about whether anyone was hit by gunfire, either by U.S. or British troops after the airport bomb blast.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re wondering: Should the Pentagon further investigate this matter?&nbsp; Or does the President believe that this matter is closed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know that my colleague John Kirby is going to brief later this afternoon, and CENTCOM has put out information on this.&nbsp; But I would really point you to them for further comment.</p>



<p>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I have a question about how the President is going to make the decision about changing the recommendation on masks.&nbsp; Is he totally determi- &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He will make the decision based on what the CDC advises.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Well, that’s what I wanted to ask.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the CDC calls the shots here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like he measures trade-offs &#8212; the economy, mental health, people&#8217;s behavior.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just when the CDC says it&#8217;s okay to do, that&#8217;s what will determine his decision, but he doesn&#8217;t take into account all these other factors?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what he has made the commitment to the American people on, back when he ran for President and we&#8217;ve tried to abide by, is that he would listen to &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; “Listen” is one thing.&nbsp; But &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Listen to the data, listen to the science.&nbsp; And, certainly, our health and medical team &#8212; obviously, the CDC is part of that, Dr. Fauci, other experts.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard though, I would note, Dr. Murthy and others talk about mental health impacts.&nbsp; So, I would point you to them to talk about all the factors.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re certainly going to listen to our doctors and medical experts.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What I’m trying to determine is what does “listen” mean.&nbsp; Does it mean that the CDC calls the shots here?&nbsp; Or, as these governors have done, does the President take into account the trade-offs?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, this is about public health.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not, like, just some kind of abstract thing in a vacuum.&nbsp; People &#8212; kids’ mental health is affected by wearing masks.&nbsp; Human behavior is part of this; the economy is part of this.&nbsp; Does he take those into account, or does he assume the CDC will do that for him?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, Mara, it&#8217;s also important to note that masks are effective at reducing transmission in schools and other places.&nbsp; And we know that from what the data has told us, right?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are a range of health and medical experts who advise the President and make determinations about how the CDC guidance will be changed.&nbsp; But that is what we rely on, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are a lot of doctors who are now signing statements saying it&#8217;s time to lift mask mandates, especially for kids.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand that, but we rely on the health and medical experts who work in the federal government, as we should, even as we account for and consult with outside experts.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You mentioned the President&#8217;s trip tomorrow to Virginia.&nbsp; Do you expect a new announcement of some sort on prescription drug prices?&nbsp; Or is it going to be kind of a familiar argument about the importance of his Build Back Better plan?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And he’ll be appearing alongside a vulnerable House Democrat.&nbsp; Will that type of travel, where he&#8217;ll be going out with Democrats facing tough reelection battles, be sort of the North Star as he accelerates his travel schedule, or at least has said that he wants to do that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, on your second question, you know, I’ve become quite careful about what I say about politics and campaigning from this podium, but the President himself has said &#8212; so I can point to that &#8212; that he is eager to go out there and hit the road for Democrats who are fighting for an agenda for the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, certainly tomorrow, when he is out in the Richmond area with Congresswoman Spanberger, this is an opportunity for him &#8212; to go back to your first question &#8212; to really talk about his view that the fact that Americans are forced to pay two to three times more for drugs than citizens in other advanced economies is unacceptable, it&#8217;s flat out wrong, and we need to act to stop the abuse of American families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He &#8212; as you&#8217;ve heard him say many times and I expect you would hear him say tomorrow, insulin, which was invented over 100 years ago, costs roughly $10 to make, but families are sometimes charged over $1,000 for that &#8212; for it.&nbsp; That&#8217;s unacceptable.&nbsp; It causes untold pain for thousands and thousands of families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Medicare being able to negotiate the cost of prescription drugs &#8212; I don&#8217;t know that it needs to be a new policy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good policy supported by many, many Americans, the vast majority across the country &#8212; Democrats and Republicans, independents. &nbsp;And we obviously want to continue to fight to get it done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, Iran announced today that they have &#8212; or said that they have developed a missile that can strike Israel or U.S. bases in the region.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you have a reaction to that and then, also, kind of, generally wanted to check in on where you thought the sort of progress on talks over a new nuclear deal are standing right now.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, in terms of where things stand: Special Envoy Malley and his interagency delegation have been in Vienna for the eighth round of talks.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve said, and this is a consistent &#8212; the report you referenced is consistent with this &#8212; Iran &#8212; our talks with Iran have reached an urgent point on mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA.&nbsp; A deal that addresses the core concerns of all sides is in sight, but if it is not reached in the &#8212; in the coming weeks, Iran’s ongoing nuclear advances will make it impossible for us to return to the JCPOA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So those talks and conversations are going &#8212; are ongoing.&nbsp; But I would say that, as I &#8212; as we noted back, I believe in December, the President asked his team to prepare a range of contingencies because we are at a pivotal point because of the progress that they have made in recent years as a result of the former president and his team pulling out of the nuclear deal.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, thank you.&nbsp; Does the President have a particular opinion about this trucker action going on in Canada right now? Because it does &#8212; it is affecting not only Ottawa but, obviously, some of these border crossings.&nbsp; And could it have &#8212; possibly have some impact on the U.S. economy &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; in the long run if this continues?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, we are watching this very closely.&nbsp; And because, as you kind of touched on here, the Ambassador Bridge is Canada&#8217;s busiest link to the United States and accounts for about 25 percent of trade between the two countries, and so the blockade poses a risk to supply chains for the auto industry because the bridge is a key conduit for motor vehicles, components, and parts; and delays risk disrupting auto production.</p>



<p>We are in close contact.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been doing a great deal of work on this.&nbsp; Liz Sherwood-Randall, our Homeland Security Advisor, convened a meeting just today.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in very close contact and coordination with the Customs and Border Protection team, and Canadian counterparts, Michigan Governor Whitmer, and industry stakeholders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are also monitoring very closely and engaged with auto companies on what the impacts could be of auto parts, which is what &#8212; what would come from Canada and the impact on the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also looking &#8212; tracking potential disruptions to U.S. agricultural exports from Michigan into Canada.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are a number of steps that we have proactively taken, I should say &#8212; the Customs and Border Protection team.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve worked with Canadian counterparts to route traffic from Ambassador Bridge to Blue Water Bridge.&nbsp; There is still a lengthy delay, but it is enabling some of these trucks and transports to get through.</p>



<p>They also opened all nine commercial lanes, including a fast lane at the port to process diverted traffic, and they&#8217;re working closely with relevant automakers and other public- and private-sector stakeholders to discuss alternative processing.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re working to ensure there&#8217;s movement.</p>



<p>The other issue &#8212; let me just touch on what you didn&#8217;t ask about but is an important component too &#8212; is there are workers who need to go across the bridge to get to Canada or to get to the United States.&nbsp; And the &#8212; we are &#8212; the workers &#8212; they go over the Ambassador Bridge, typically &#8212; they are being detoured to the Detroit-Windsor Tunnel, which is open, which &#8212; enabling them to move &#8212; move past.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re very focused on this.&nbsp; The President is focused on this.&nbsp; And we are working very closely with the team at DHS, with Canadian officials, and others to do everything we can to alleviate the impact.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President have an opinion on this action?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; An opinion on it?&nbsp; In what &#8212; tell me more what you &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In what the truckers are doing.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; About the &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The message they want to send.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we support peaceful protest, but we have concerns when those protests turn violent.&nbsp; And certainly, I think it&#8217;s important for everyone in Canada and the United States to understand what the impact of this blockage is &#8212; potential impact on workers, on the supply chain.&nbsp; And that is where we are most focused.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow-up on the border?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>I’ll come back to you.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I have a couple of questions on schools and &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; guidelines around COVID.&nbsp; You’re saying, you know, the CDC &#8212; its guidance remains that there be universal masking in schools and the White House supports that recommendation.</p>



<p>As you point out, some of these Democratic governors who are lifting mask mandates in schools, they are allowing local authorities to make some decisions.&nbsp; But the reality is: There are going to be a lot of parents who no longer have their children wear masks in schools.&nbsp; And given community transmission is still high across the country &#8212; I mean, the whole map on the CDC website is red &#8212; are you not concerned that these decisions are going to potentially lead to outbreaks in schools?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our focus continues to be to recommend everyone follow CDC guidance, right?&nbsp; And we know that wearing masks effectively reduces transmission, as much as people are understandably tired of wearing masks &#8212; we understand that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There were a number of other mitigation measures that schools have taken.&nbsp; Obviously, now kids age 5 to 11 are eligible to get &#8212; to be vaccinated.&nbsp; Testing so kids can remain in the classroom even if there is a case is something we have also talked about and supported.&nbsp; And funding from the American Rescue Plan ensured that there was capacity and ability to improve ventilation, social distancing, and take other steps that are also effective mitigation measures in schools.</p>



<p>But, again, you know, our view is that if a student or a parent chooses to wear a mask, they should be able to freely so that &#8212; and they should not be prevented from doing that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, one &#8212; this is happening as we still see this trend where there is a drop-off in the vaccination rate when you reach those who are under 18 &#8212; among adolescents, I think it’s just over half of adolescents are vaccinated &#8212; and an even bigger drop-off among those who are ages 5 to 11, with pretty high numbers still around vaccine hesitancy.</p>



<p>Why hasn’t the White House called for a vaccine requirement against COVID-19 for K-through-12 schools, which many public health experts say is really the only way that you will be able to protect students in the long term?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because those decisions have historically been up to school districts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; A couple of questions: On the Child Tax Credit, Mitt Romney just suggested that you consider a bipartisan path toward his alternative version of the program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Does he have 10 Republicans with him?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, he says it’s &#8212; he has a bipartisan group that’s been successful in the past and that he is going to try and get here.&nbsp; Has the White House engaged with him on this recently?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have been engaged with every member who is open to engaging and looking to move the President’s agenda forward?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is his version an acceptable alternative if he can get the votes to the White House?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have any specific reaction to his version, but I would just note that in order to get any component of the President’s agenda forward if it’s broken off of a reconciliation package, you’d need 60 votes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On COVID: Kristin Urquiza, who spoke at the nominating convention for the President, told us a couple of weeks ago that she is disappointed that the President hasn’t met and engaged more directly with people who are affected by COVID.&nbsp; So, we’re at over 100 &#8212; over 900,000 deaths now.&nbsp; Are there any plans for the President to host people at the White House who have been affected by COVID, whose families have been affected by COVID?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m happy to check and see if there is any plans.&nbsp; I would note that the President has spoken about COVID and his plans and his commitment to addressing the pandemic more than perhaps any other issue since he became President.</p>



<p>And more importantly than that to, I think, most Americans, he has taken very specific actions to ensure that vaccines are available, that tests are available, that masks are available, that schools are open, which &#8212; that is what impacts people’s lives on a daily basis.&nbsp; But I can see if there is any plans for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it the sense inside the White House that the decisions by Democratic governors to relax some of these mask guidelines is driven mostly by, as you said, the speed of politics and not the public health guidelines that are driving the federal government’s policy.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I didn’t actually make that assessment, but I would point you to all of them to ask them questions about what they based their decision-making on.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>But, again, we understand local leaders &#8212; we continue to advise local leaders, whether they’re governors or others, to make decisions based on the science and data about what’s happening in their communities &#8212; and what is going to keep in schools safe, what is going to keep kids in their &#8212; people in their communities safe.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>And we will continue to abide by what federal guidance is advising, which is based on the science and health experts in the federal government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the meeting later today with President Biden and the companies, how much is he relying on these companies to make clean energy decisions kind of on their own in the absence of climate legislation that is, you know, currently stalled or being renegotiated in Congress right now that we know would be necessary to reach the White House’s goals on clean energy?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think as many of these leaders have said &#8212; I mean, they know that the industry of the future is clean energy, and so there is an incentive for them to act and move in that direction.&nbsp; And, certainly, the President agrees with that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there are a number of steps, even as we’re working to continue to push to get Build Back Better passed, that we have already passed into law as a part of the infrastructure bill, for example, including clean charging &#8212; charging stations around the country, incentivizing the purchase of electric vehicles, which, of course, is a &#8212; is an industry that will help many of the American auto industry producers prosper over the course of time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, certainly, it&#8217;s where the industry is going.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s agreement between government and many of these industries about the opportunity for the United States to be a leader in the clean energy movement in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; I just have two foreign questions and a round of follow-ups.&nbsp; Starting with Build Back Better World, do we have any news on when that&#8217;s going to be officially launched?&nbsp; Have you identified any programs?&nbsp; Can you share any details?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve talked &#8212; the President has talked about this quite a lot on the global stage.&nbsp; Let me see if we can get an update from the NSC team about any new specifics on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Then I want to talk about something that Russian President Putin said &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the other day.&nbsp; He made what many Russian speakers interpreted as a rape joke directed at Ukraine.&nbsp; Given that diplomacy is all about talking, how does the administration view talk like this?&nbsp; Does it shorten the diplomatic off-ramp because it&#8217;s a pretty undiplomatic thing to say?&nbsp; And has the White House communicated to the Kremlin, you know, “Yo, that&#8217;s not cool”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that any joke about rape would certainly be something that everyone in this government would be outraged by, whether it&#8217;s happening from the mouth of a U.S. official or a foreign official.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note that we have never held back in our concern about the lack of truthfulness of some of the statements that come out of the mouth of President Putin and members of the Russian leadership, and also the bellicose rhetoric that has come out of their mouths.&nbsp; So, we have never held back on our concern.&nbsp; And certainly, that joke would not be something that we &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you reached out to the Kremlin?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more in terms of diplomatic discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, April.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, two topics.&nbsp; One, back on the HHS issue &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and pipes.&nbsp; You know misinformation has a terrible ripple effect.&nbsp; What is this administration doing?&nbsp; Because this has permeated a lot of corridors that people are taking this in.&nbsp; Are you or the administration or HHS planning on doing something beyond the statement to let people know that this is misinformation and correct it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, that&#8217;s a really important point, because I think there&#8217;s been a lot of misinformation and about particularly this issue.&nbsp; And &#8212; and it has really clouded over what is a hugely important issue in this country, which is a fight against the opioid epidemic and the need to have bipartisan approaches that are going to help communities that are impacted address it.</p>



<p>But, yes, we will certainly be building out our efforts to effectively communicate that we are not &#8212; that what &#8212; what is in a safe smoking kit, what is not in smoking kit &#8212; safe smoking kit, and what we are effectively trying to do with our harm reduction program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has damage &#8212; has a lot of damage already been done just by this information in certain communities, are you finding?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly have seen &#8212; and I think, April, one of the reasons we felt, even though we have never &#8212; this has never been a part of what has been funded, we felt it was important to put out a public statement from the federal government to make that clear, because we saw the spreading of misinformation and the fact that it was having an impact on a range of communities.&nbsp; And we felt, even though it was never true, that we needed to put out a proactive statement.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And on a second topic: I asked you on Monday about President Biden and his last &#8212; the last time he talked to Anita Hill.&nbsp; Do you have any more information?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You did ask me that.&nbsp; I don’t have an update on that.&nbsp; I will venture to see if I can get one today.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Is she part of the external group that is working with the White House on these nominations for Supreme Court?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are a broad range of individuals &#8212; legal experts, scholars, members of Congress of both parties &#8212; that are being consulted with.&nbsp; We have not put out that list of individuals publicly.&nbsp; I can see if there&#8217;s more information we can provide.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead, in the middle.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two quick questions.&nbsp; One, we&#8217;ve heard from the White House about this effort to reach out to Republican senators on the Supreme Court nomination.&nbsp; I wonder if you could explain a little bit, kind of, what the focus of those conversations are.&nbsp; Are you guys, you know, fielding suggestions on who the nominee should be?&nbsp; Are you giving them a shortlist and getting their reaction?&nbsp; I’m just kind of curious, sort of, what the focus of the outreach to Republicans is.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as the President has said, and we &#8212; I’ll just reiterate &#8212; we’re going to choose a nominee &#8212; he&#8217;s going to choose a nominee whose qualifications, record, character, and devotion to the Constitution and rule of law make them deserving of support on &#8212; from both sides of the aisle.&nbsp; And there are many candidates at the top of their fields who fit that profile and who have received bipartisan support in the past.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, these conversations are not uniform.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Sometimes &#8212; and the President is certainly seeking input, seeking feedback.&nbsp; But he is treating the process as he believes it should be treated, which is with seriousness, which is approaching it from a bipartisan manner and seeking engagement and advice from a range of officials, elected and non-elected.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, unrelated, but there was some reporting this week that Labor Secretary Marty Walsh has offered to help resolve the Major League Baseball lockout.&nbsp; And I wonder if the President has been in touch with him about that or if he has an opinion or a viewpoint on the lockout.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m happy to check on that.&nbsp; And my husband is also looking for an answer.&nbsp; So, I will &#8212; I will check on that.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, in &#8212; yesterday, in the event, you highlighted electric vehicles.&nbsp; Today, you&#8217;re highlighting the &#8212; the utility companies are here.&nbsp; Three percent of the market is electric &#8212; for vehicles &#8212; in the U.S.&nbsp; So, if Americans go out and buy a lot of electric cars, can the grid handle the load without using more coal power?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we&#8217;re trying to address this from many fronts &#8212; right? &#8212; as you know and you&#8217;ve seen in the President&#8217;s infrastructure legislation, which includes additional charging stations, which includes incentivizing and making it more affordable and accessible for Americans to purchase electric vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;re seeing is the increase in the market for electric vehicles increase year by year &#8212; right? &#8212; as they become more affordable, as there are more charging stations, as they are able to &#8212; as more Americans can see themselves driving electric vehicles.&nbsp; And this is certainly something not just the federal government but many of these automobile industry &#8212; companies are also seeing opportunity in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re all moving to &#8212; as the increase of the &#8212; as the market is increasing, as more Americans are purchasing these electric vehicles &#8212; to ensure there are the charging stations and the mechanisms needed for them to be driven.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; But can wind and solar handle that amount of load on the system?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we&#8217;re working to increase all of the &#8212; all of the components of what is needed to ensure that electric vehicles can be powered across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can I ask you a question on Africa?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hold on.&nbsp; I’ll come back to you.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; When the President met with governors last week, did any of them ask specifically for more guidance from the federal government as they were considering easing some of the COVID restrictions?&nbsp; And did any express any frustration that the CDC is not moving quickly enough for them?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m not going to speak for the governors; they can certainly speak for themselves.&nbsp; I can just speak for what our position is and what we&#8217;ve conveyed to the governors, which is exactly what I&#8217;ve outlined for all of you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President urged any governors to hold off on easing these restrictions?&nbsp; Has he had any direct conversations since then about what they&#8217;ve all started announcing this week?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to convey directly to governors our recommendation that they abide by federal public health guidelines, but also our understanding and &#8212; that they may make decisions based on what they feel is best for their communities.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has he had conversations this week with any (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any to read out for you.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; So, President Biden nominated Los Angeles Mayor Eric Garcetti to the U.S. Ambassador to India.&nbsp; Garcetti’s former top spokeswoman has filed a complaint with state, local, and federal prosecutors, demanding that he be prosecuted for perjury for repeatedly denying that he knew about another former aide’s alleged sexual misconduct.&nbsp; She&#8217;s saying that the mayor lied under oath during his testimony before a U.S. Senate committee considering his appointment to the ambassadorship.&nbsp; Is the President aware of this complaint?&nbsp; Has he spoken to the mayor?&nbsp; Does he plan to rescind Garcetti’s nomination?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I &#8212; there is no plans to rescind any nominations.&nbsp; I would point you to Mayor Garcetti’s office for any further comment.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a question on Africa &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; About the virus, again.&nbsp; Is the reluctance of the President now &#8212; I mean, there seems to be increased caution, to put it that way &#8212; the approach he is taking, compared to a lot of the others.&nbsp; Is there any link between that and perhaps having felt burned during the summer when we had this &#8220;independence from the virus&#8221; &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Are you referring to masks?&nbsp; Sorry.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, and &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I’m referring to the masks and the &#8212; his caution at kind of moving on as, obviously, a growing number of people are doing.&nbsp; Is this in any way linked to him feeling a little burned by what happened during the summer, when, you know, the Delta came pretty much as he was inviting people for a barbecue here to celebrate independence?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He’s basing his decision or &#8212; on what the advice of our health and medical experts continues to be, and the fact that they are continuing to evaluate and look at the data and the science.&nbsp; And that is a commitment he made to the American people at the beginning.</p>



<p>We also recognize that while hospitalization rates are coming down, there&#8217;s still high transmission rates throughout, basically, the entire country.&nbsp; And he is cognizant of that as well and the fact that we need to look at the totality of that and make recommendations based on what our science experts are conveying.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; One on Nord Stream, if I might &#8212; a quick one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He said very clearly &#8212; he promises &#8212; literally promises &#8212; to stop it &#8212; stop the Nord Stream if there&#8217;s an invasion &#8212; like a &#8212; like a full-blown invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If there isn&#8217;t a full-blown invasion, which obviously is at least as likely as there being one &#8212; and it could be, you know, a hundred different things that could be happening over the next month, year, two years &#8212; not to mention that Russia already occupies part of Ukraine and so on &#8212; what&#8217;s the rationale for supporting Nord Stream at all?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t support Nord Stream.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have been clear we oppose the Nord Stream 2 pipeline, which is a Russian geopolitical project that undercuts the energy security and national security of a significant part of the Euro-Atlantic community.&nbsp; That&#8217;s long been our position.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not online &#8212; the pipeline.&nbsp; The German regulators have said it is not currently on track to be approved until at least the latter half of 2022.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ll continue to work with Germany, Ukraine, and other allies and partners to implement the July 21st Joint Statement.</p>



<p>And again, if Russia invades Ukraine, Nord Stream 2 will not come online.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, do you have any comment on the series of bomb threats that are happening in D.C. schools right now?&nbsp; D.C. police are reporting that Dunbar, Theodore Roosevelt, Ron Brown High School, several others are now under bomb threat and evacuating schools.&nbsp; What do you say about that, especially after yesterday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any new information on these threats.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to see if there&#8217;s a new updated comment we can get for all of you.</p>



<p>Of course, we are in touch with local school districts, as we have been since yesterday, and our &#8212; and our Homeland Security experts will do everything we can to ensure that schools have the resources they need.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any new information on it.</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, Jen &#8212; a question on Africa.&nbsp; No question on Africa again.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been three months, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Thank you, everyone.</p>



<p>2:16 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr.’s Call with King Salman bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud of Saudi&#160;Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-s-call-with-king-salman-bin-abdulaziz-al-saud-of-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 20:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with King Salman bin Abdulaziz al-Saud of Saudi Arabia to discuss regional developments and issues of mutual concern, including Iranian-enabled attacks by the Houthis against civilian targets in Saudi Arabia. The President underscored the U.S. commitment to support Saudi Arabia in the defense of its people and territory&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with King Salman bin Abdulaziz al-Saud of Saudi Arabia to discuss regional developments and issues of mutual concern, including Iranian-enabled attacks by the Houthis against civilian targets in Saudi Arabia. The President underscored the U.S. commitment to support Saudi Arabia in the defense of its people and territory from these attacks and full support for UN-led efforts to end the war in Yemen. The President noted his commitment to ensuring that Iran can never obtain a nuclear weapon and briefed the King on ongoing multilateral talks to reestablish constraints on Iran’s nuclear program. The two leaders discussed matters pertaining to the Middle East region and Europe and agreed that their teams would remain closely coordinated over the coming weeks and months. Both leaders further reiterated the United States’ and Saudi Arabia’s commitment to ensuring the stability of global energy supplies.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr.’s Call with President Emmanuel Macron of&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-s-call-with-president-emmanuel-macron-of-france-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 20:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47019</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France.&#160; They discussed President Macron’s recent meetings in Russia and Ukraine. They also talked about ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts, undertaken in close coordination with our Allies and partners, in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders.&#160; ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France.&nbsp; They discussed President Macron’s recent meetings in Russia and Ukraine. They also talked about ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts, undertaken in close coordination with our Allies and partners, in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the University of&#160;Minnesota</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-university-of-minnesota/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 19:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Minneapolis, MN I teach writing at a community college. And one day, I had a student come in with her 4-year-old. The moment I locked eyes with my student, I could see her distress, and I knew exactly what happened: Her babysitter had fallen through but she couldn’t afford to miss the class. She set&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Minneapolis, MN</p>



<p>I teach writing at a community college. And one day, I had a student come in with her 4-year-old. The moment I locked eyes with my student, I could see her distress, and I knew exactly what happened: Her babysitter had fallen through but she couldn’t afford to miss the class. She set up her son with a box of crayons and some paper in the corner of the room, and I tried to give her a smile when I saw her looking at him nervously—praying he’d make it through. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Moms just do what we have to do, don’t we? If the carefully-planned matrix of work, and school, and drop-offs and pick-ups falls apart, you just figure it out.</p>



<p>When Joe took office one year ago, schools were shuttered. After heroic efforts to try to stay open, far too many child care providers were forced to close or lay off early educators. And millions of women had left the workforce.</p>



<p>Imagine that mom who went to drop off her children before work one morning and the doors were closed. Or who didn’t bring them in at all because she couldn’t risk her family getting sick. There was no vacation time to make up for missed work. There was no grandma to stay home with the kids. She needed that job. But she needed to take care of her children more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There was no choice—so she walked away. She kept her family safe—but it cost her something too. Security. Pride. A sense of purpose.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For millions of parents, the situation was dire and urgent. That’s why Joe made a major investment in child care through the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>We helped states like Minnesota safely keep open child care centers, and family child care providers—and boost pay for their workers. We supported high-quality providers that enrich children’s lives. And we helped make them more affordable.</p>



<p>Tim, you understand that child care is not only critical to families, it’s critical to our businesses and economy. Joe and I are grateful for your leadership—and for the friendship of you and Gwen. And I’m excited to hear more today about what you’ve done here in Minnesota to help families recover from the uncertainty and losses of the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Still, there’s a lot more to do. The challenges families face didn’t start with COVID-19. And we need fundamental changes if we hope to build back better than before. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why Joe believes in investing in high-quality, affordable child care. It’s why he wants to lower costs for families. It’s why he cares so much about making preschool universal for all 3- and 4-year-olds. And so do I.</p>



<p>I’ve never taught early education, but I’ve seen what a difference it makes in my community college classes. When kids have a strong start, it helps them learn and succeed for the rest of their lives. And it gives parents another safe, loving place to send their kids while they work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For the last few years, in every city I visited and at nearly every event—whether we were there to talk about military spouses, or vaccinations, or community colleges—people have told me that one of their biggest challenges is child care.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Families like yours need support. The President knows that and he’s working to make that support a reality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reliable, affordable, quality, child care and universal preschool would profoundly change people’s lives. And it is within our reach. That’s what we’re here to talk about today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, it’s my pleasure to introduce the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Secretary Becerra, you’ve worked for years to improve health care in America—and now, you’ve become a true champion for Joe’s child care goals. Thank you for your leadership.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/09/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-82/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 11:06 A.M. EST MR. ZIENTS: &#160;Good morning, and thanks for joining us.&#160; Today, we&#8217;ll start with an update from Dr. Walensky on the state of the pandemic and CDC’s COVID-19 surveillance efforts. Dr. Walensky. DR. WALENSKY:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Thanks, Jeff.&#160; I&#8217;d like to start by walking you through today&#8217;s data.&#160; The current seven-day&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:06 A.M. EST</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS: &nbsp;Good morning, and thanks for joining us.&nbsp; Today, we&#8217;ll start with an update from Dr. Walensky on the state of the pandemic and CDC’s COVID-19 surveillance efforts.<br><br>Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to start by walking you through today&#8217;s data.&nbsp;<br><br>The current seven-day daily average of cases is about 247,300 cases per day, a decrease of about 44 percent over the previous week.&nbsp;<br><br>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 13,000 per day, a decrease of about 25 percent over the previous period.<br><br>And the seven-day average of daily deaths are at about 2,400 a day, which is an increase of about 3 percent over the prior week.&nbsp;<br><br>This week, we reached a tragic new mark of 900,000 deaths in this country from COVID-19.&nbsp;<br><br>Each week, I share with you the burden of disease in the United States, including case counts, hospital admissions, and the number of deaths.&nbsp; Much of the data I readily share is because we have made huge strides in our ability to effectively monitor this virus, and new tools allow us to prepare and react to an evolving virus and inform response measures in near real time.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I&#8217;d like to walk you through just a few of the layers of surveillance we have in place, some that we have been expanding and developing over the past two years and others that are bedrocks of our public health work.&nbsp;<br><br>Let&#8217;s start at the local community level where our biggest question is: Can we quickly identify spikes in cases?&nbsp; As people with COVID-19 shed the virus, testing in wastewater or our sewage systems can help us monitor COVID-19 in communities and provide an early warning of increased COVID-19 cases to help communities prepare.&nbsp;<br><br>Last week, CDC publicly released national wastewater surveillance data, tracking more than 400 testing sites across the country in 212 communities, which we will double to more than 800 testing sites in the next four weeks.&nbsp;<br><br>On this map, you can see the testing sites that we monitor and trends in the levels of the virus.&nbsp; Communities in blue have decreasing levels of virus, while communities in red and orange have increasing levels.&nbsp;<br><br>This is a powerful tool that, when paired with traditional public health surveillance, can help us identify where the disease is spreading and how best to distribute resources.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve also made significant progress in syndromic surveillance, defined by the ability to identify symptoms and cases that are suggestive of COVID-19 disease.&nbsp; Through syndromic surveillance, we can answer questions about disease severity and patient populations with the highest burdens of disease &#8212; crucial information to inform guidance and prevention measures.&nbsp;<br><br>More than 6,000 healthcare facilities across the country, representing over 70 percent of emergency departments, contribute data to our syndromic surveillance and help us understand where and how the virus is having an impact.&nbsp;<br><br>In addition to monitoring where the virus is and how disease presents in the community, our genomic surveillance can quickly identify variants so that we can understand their impact.&nbsp; Each week, CDC analyzes genomic sequences from all 50 states and uses these sequences to understand the spread of variants across the country.&nbsp;<br><br>On this slide, you can see the projections of variant proportions for the last 14 weeks.&nbsp; Omicron, shown in pink and purple, now represents nearly 100 percent of viruses circulating in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>Our cohort studies and state-level surveillance data provide detailed and regular reports of how our vaccines are working in the real world among diverse populations, giving us faster and better data to know that our vaccines are working against new and emerging variants.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;ve heard me discuss many of these platforms before, like our hospital surveillance through CDC&#8217;s COVID-NET and IVY; our collaboration with seven integrated healthcare and public health research centers through VISION; surveillance of infection is essential in frontline workers in HEROES-RECOVER; and our nationwide surveillance of vaccine effectiveness in children and young adults in overcoming COVID-19.&nbsp;<br><br>Taken together, these studies provide us an in-depth and comprehensive understanding of how vaccines are working with participations in sites nationwide.&nbsp;<br><br>And importantly, COVID-19 vaccines are being administered under the most intensive vaccine safety monitoring effort in the United States&#8217; history.&nbsp;<br><br>Our nationwide vaccine safety networks &#8212; such as V-safe, which provides personalized and confidential health check-ins via text message &#8212; and other systems &#8212; such as VAERS, the Clinical Immunization Safety project, and the Vaccine Safety Datalink &#8212; empower us with the data of any rare side effects or reactions after vaccination or boosting.<br><br>This is a huge amount of data.&nbsp; CDC &#8212; along with our partners across government; state and local jurisdictions; academia; and healthcare &#8212; has cast a wide and comprehensive net over the country to follow the virus and its impacts in real time.&nbsp;<br><br>And we will continue these data as our guiding &#8212; using these data as our guiding source as we look to what comes next.<br><br>I know there will come a time when we move from a phase of crisis to a point where COVID-19 is not disrupting our daily lives.&nbsp; And as we all look forward to this next step, I want to instill in everyone that moving forward from this pandemic will be a process that&#8217;s led by our surveillance and our data.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m confident that CDC and our public health partners are well positioned to lead the way.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; And now, with that, I will turn things back over to you, Jeff.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thanks, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, let’s move to booster shots.&nbsp; We know that there are a number of different ways to view progress on boosters, depending on which data set you’re looking at.<br><br>For example, some people assess boosters as a proportion of all adults who are fully vaccinated, while others look at the total U.S. adult population, even though not every adult is eligible for a booster shot yet.<br><br>So, before I turn to Dr. Fauci on the effectiveness of booster shots, I want to review how we assess the available data and use the best available data to measure the progress we’re making on getting people booster shots.<br><br>CDC data aggregated from state health departments shows that more than 90 million booster shots have been administered.&nbsp; We know that that is likely undercounted as some people reported their booster as a first shot and others forgot their vaccination card altogether.<br><br>States have been matching data and have encountered some challenges across different channels, which has led to delayed reporting for booster shots in many states.<br><br>CDC is working with states to address these issues to improve the data.<br><br>At the same time, CDC conducts a weekly survey, which is a nationally representative survey of over 16,000 adults.&nbsp; Looking at the CDC survey results, you get a more up-to-date picture of the progress we are making on boosters.<br><br>Based on the latest CDC survey, we estimate over two thirds&nbsp; of all eligible adults and over 80 percent of all eligible seniors &#8212; those most at risk&nbsp; and most vulnerable &#8212; have received a booster shot.<br><br>CDC’s survey results are consistent with the Kaiser Family Foundation survey which shows 70 percent of eligible adults report they’ve gotten a booster.<br><br>So, we have a strong foundation to build on, with most eligible adults boosted.<br><br>In fact, we estimate at least two out of three adult &#8212; eligible adults in the U.S. are now boosted &#8212; two out of three eligible adult Americans with a booster shot.<br><br>And across the last two months, we’ve made important strides on equity, with the majority of booster shots going to people of color, in a very improvement from the prior two months.<br><br>The significant progress we made on boosters is one of the reasons why we were able to confront Omicron with fewer disruptions to schools and businesses than in prior surges.&nbsp; And we clearly need to keep driving this progress.<br><br>So , our message is clear: All eligible individuals should get their booster shot right away.&nbsp; Booster shots are free.&nbsp; They’re available at 90,000 convenient locations across the country and, as Dr. Fauci will discuss, critical to getting people the highest level of protection.<br><br>With that, over to you, Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Jeff.&nbsp; What I’m going to do now over the next couple of minutes is to just build on what Jeff said and talk to you, based on real data, why it is so critically important to get booster shots.<br><br>I&#8217;m going to talk about laboratory data, clinical trial data, and real-world data.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>So there are multiple &#8212; and I can’t show them all &#8212; in vitro studies that show that COVID-19 vaccine booster doses markedly increase the neutralization of variants, including what we&#8217;re dealing with currently, namely Omicron.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>This is the slide that shows the genomic mean titer of antibody, namely the proteins that neutralize the virus.&nbsp; If you look at the far left-hand side of the slide, seven months after people receive a second dose and before the booster, look how low the response is to Omicron, which is the bar that has the red circles.&nbsp; It&#8217;s 23.<br><br>One month after the booster, it goes way up into the highly protective zone of 850.&nbsp; And even six months after the booster, it is still at a high level of 136 &#8212; way above what it was seven months after the second dose.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s representative laboratory data.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>Now, a randomized controlled clinical trial showed the dramatic impact of the booster dose in preventing symptomatic disease.&nbsp; And the data are really striking.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll show you one clip of that on the next slide.<br><br>As you can see in red are individuals who&#8217;ve gotten two doses &#8212; it says placebo, but it&#8217;s two doses &#8212; without the booster.&nbsp; And this is a&nbsp; Pfizer study, but it really holds true with other products like Moderna.<br><br>If you look at the result in blue of the cumulative incidence of COVID-19 following a booster shot, the difference is dramatic.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>Now we&#8217;ll move to real-world effectiveness studies showing that booster doses reconstitute the waning protection, especially against severe disease, hospitalization, and deaths.<br><br>So, next slide.<br><br>So, here, we look at individuals less than six months after the second dose.&nbsp; And on the&nbsp; far left, you see when you&#8217;re dealing with Delta, it&#8217;s 90; when you&#8217;re dealing with Omicron, it&#8217;s 81.&nbsp; But more than six months after the second dose, it wanes with Omicron to 57, holding up a bit better with Delta.<br><br>But after the third dose, you get protection at 90 percent with Omicron, which&nbsp; is even better than after six months after the second dose.&nbsp; Again, another example of the critical importance of boosting.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>Here is another way of looking at it.&nbsp; When you look at symptomatic disease and hospitalizations, again, when you&#8217;re dealing with Omicron, on the far left, the protection against symptomatic disease is quite low at week 25, following two doses.&nbsp; If you look at the boost, it goes up substantially to 40 percent.&nbsp;<br><br>But the critical data are on the right-hand part of the slide.&nbsp; If you look at hospitalizations and look at two doses of the Pfizer BioNTech either at 2 to 4 weeks or 10 to 14 weeks, it’s still way up there at 75 percent.<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>And again, if you look at CDC data, which shows a dramatic reduction in the risk of hospitalization and death for people who’ve received a booster dose, we can see that on the next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is a summary of data: If you compare a fully vaccinated person with one who has received a booster shot, and look at the monthly rate of COVID-19 associated hospitalizations during a timeframe of December 2021, there was a 45-fold higher likelihood of an unvaccinated person in the age range of 50 to 64, and a 51-fold higher likelihood of an unvaccinated age 65 and older of being hospitalized when you compare it to an individual with a boost.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>When you look at death rate, again, the data are really rather striking.&nbsp; If you look at unvaccinated in red and look at the death rate per 100,000 compared to a fully vaccinated person who&#8217;s not been boosted &#8212; showing you why vaccinations even without boosts are important.&nbsp; But look what the booster does: It brings back the death rate per 100,000 to a remarkably low level.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we can only come to one conclusion on the last slide: that&nbsp; COVID-19 vaccines, booster shots can keep you out of the hospital and certainly can save your life.<br><br>Back to you, Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thanks, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp;<br><br>Before we open for questions, I want to highlight how far we&#8217;ve come in our fight against COVID.<br><br>Last week, we learned the U.S. economy created 6.6 million new jobs in the President&#8217;s first year in office.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the best 12 months of job creation in our nation&#8217;s history.&nbsp;<br><br>Notably, this includes 467,000 jobs created in January and 510,000 in December.&nbsp; Those were the two months when we were at the height of the Omicron surge.<br><br>The first time we faced a similar threat from COVID back in April of 2020, we lost around 20 million jobs in one month.&nbsp; Even as we face the extremely transmissible Omicron variant and saw a record number of cases, businesses stayed open and our economy kept growing stronger.&nbsp; That&#8217;s because we&#8217;re in such a different position today in terms of our ability to manage this virus.&nbsp;<br><br>We have over 210 million people fully vaccinated and vaccines freely available.&nbsp; And we have more tools like boosters, treatments, masks, and tests that give us additional layers of protection.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, fully vaccinated and boosted Americans are able to keep living their lives safely, even when this virus throws us a curveball.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re able to keep our kids in school and keep our businesses open.<br><br>As the President said on Friday, January was a tough month for this country, but we got through it together.&nbsp; Over the past three weeks, daily cases are down over 65 percent; hospital admissions are down 40 percent.<br><br>The President&#8217;s COVID plan is working.&nbsp; We&#8217;re moving toward a time when COVID won&#8217;t disrupt our daily lives, a time when COVID won&#8217;t be a constant crisis but rather will be something we can protect against and treat.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, let&#8217;s open it up for a few questions.&nbsp; Over to you, Kevin.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got a lot of questions today.&nbsp; So, let&#8217;s actually try to keep it to one question.&nbsp;<br><br>First, let’s go to Zeke Miller at the AP.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; In the last week, we&#8217;ve seen a number of Democratic-led &#8212; -run states move back towards normalcy, removing mask mandates.&nbsp; New York is expected to follow today.&nbsp; We saw Connecticut, other states lift mask requirements in schools.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;ve talked a lot about leading &#8212; the President trying to lead the nation out of the pandemic, but right now, the federal response seems to be following what a lot of states are doing.&nbsp; Is the White House planning for emerging &#8212; bringing the country out of the pandemic?&nbsp; And what would that plan look like?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thanks for the question.&nbsp; So while cases and hospitalizations, as Dr. Walensky showed, are trending downward, we do remain focused on fighting the Omicron surge.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s priority number one.&nbsp;<br><br>The President, as I just mentioned, has been clear that we&#8217;re moving toward a time when COVID won&#8217;t disrupt our daily lives, a time when COVID won&#8217;t be a constant crisis so we&#8217;re no longer fearing lockdowns and shutdowns, but getting back to safely doing what we all love.&nbsp; In doing so, we will rely on the powerful set of tools that have been built: the vaccines, the booster shots, treatments, and testing.&nbsp;<br><br>For the last several weeks, we&#8217;ve been working closely with Secretary Becerra, our team of doctors.&nbsp; And the White House COVID Response Team under the President&#8217;s leadership is reaching out to governors and outside public health experts and doctors and local public health officials on steps we should be taking to keep the country moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>We know that in different areas of the country, cases have fallen more significantly, and this will lead to different approaches and different timing.&nbsp; And we will continue to coordinate closely with state and local leaders.&nbsp;<br><br>Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Sabrina Siddiqui at the Wall Street Journal.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; This is a question for Dr.&nbsp; Walensky.&nbsp; I just want to follow up on current guidance around masks, because, you know, the last CDC recommendation was that there should be indoor masking in public settings where transmission is substantial or high.&nbsp; According to CDC data, that appears to still be the entire country &#8212; the case in the entire country where community transmission is high.&nbsp; So is that still the recommendation?<br><br>And furthermore, you&#8217;ve also recommended that there be universal masking in schools.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that a recommendation you stand by as states are also moving to drop &#8212; or to lift mask mandates for teachers and students in schools?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you, Sabrina.&nbsp; So we certainly understand the need and desire to be flexible, and we want to ensure the public health guidance that we&#8217;re providing meets the moment that we&#8217;re in.<br><br>As we&#8217;ve discussed and as you noted, cases and hospitalizations are falling.&nbsp; This is, of course, encouraging.&nbsp; And that leads us, of course, to have us look at all of our guidance based on the latest data and the science and what we know about the virus.&nbsp;<br><br>We also look, of course, as Jeff mentioned, to our hospitalizations, looking at the hospitals as a barometer of how they&#8217;re doing locally so those decisions can be made at the local level.&nbsp;<br><br>And, of course, we at CDC will keep the public informed about our guidance, and we will clearly communicate those recommendations to the public if and when they are updated.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; We’ll go to Cheyenne Haslett at ABC News.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, you mentioned the specific benchmarks on hospitalization that you&#8217;re looking to for when it will be a good time to change some of this guidance for unmasking, both in schools and generally in public for adults.&nbsp; What exactly will that benchmark be?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; So, Cheyenne, we &#8212; you know, in part of our review of the surveillance, we look at wastewater, we look at cases, we look at hospitalizations &#8212; we&#8217;ve been reporting hospitalizations &#8212; we look at deaths.&nbsp; And, of course, those decisions are made at the local level.<br><br>But at this time, we continue to recommend masking in areas of high and substantial transmission &#8212; that&#8217;s much of the country right now &#8212; in public indoor settings.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re, of course, taking a close look at this in real-time, and we&#8217;re evaluating rates of transmission as well as rates of severe outcomes as we look at updating and reviewing our guidance.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; We’ll go to Victoria Knight at Kaiser Health News.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for taking my question.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ve been talking to people who are immunocompromised, people who are disabled, living with chronic illnesses, and they&#8217;re all telling me that they&#8217;re feeling like they are being left behind, especially in light of a lot of states lifting their mask mandates, and they&#8217;re feeling like their needs are not being considered moving forward after Omicron.&nbsp; So what is your message to them?&nbsp; What do you expect them to do?&nbsp; Do they need to just stay in their houses?&nbsp; What is your message to people like that?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; So this is among the considerations that we take into account as we work on all of our recommendations.&nbsp; We, of course, have to make recommendations that are, you know, relevant for New York City and rural Montana.&nbsp; We have to make recommendations that are met &#8212; relevant for the public, but also for the public who is immunocompromised and disabled.&nbsp; And so, that &#8212; all of those considerations are taken into account as we work on our guidance.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Kaitlan Collins at CNN.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, you just said that you do continue to recommend masking indoors in areas of high transmission, and that you said that that&#8217;s most of the country right now.&nbsp; So are you seeing any data that supports the decisions of these governors to drop mandates?&nbsp; And when it comes to masking, should people be listening to the CDC or listening to their governors?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Kaitlan, we&#8217;ve always said that these decisions are going to have to be made at the local level and that policies at the local level will look at local cases, they’ll look at how local hospitals are doing, they’ll look at local vaccination rates.<br><br>And they, as I understand it, in many of these decisions are using a phased approach.&nbsp; Not all of these decisions are being made to stop things tomorrow, but they&#8217;re looking at a phased approach.<br><br>And so, what I would say is: Again, they have to be done at the local level.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m really encouraged that cases are continuing to drop dramatically, hospitalizations are continuing to drop dramatically as people are making these decisions and as we are working on our guidance.<br><br>So I&#8217;m encouraged to see those trends.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Sheryl Stolberg at the New York Times.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Sheryl?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you hear me?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Now we can, yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; Thank you for taking this question &#8212; it&#8217;s for Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, the states have been asking explicitly, governors have been asking explicitly for guidance from the CDC on mask-wearing and how to relax mitigation numbers.&nbsp;<br><br>Is the CDC prepared to provide guidance to the governors?&nbsp; And when will it do so?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Sheryl, thank you.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll simply go back to: Yes, we are prepared.&nbsp; We are working on that guidance.&nbsp; We are working on, you know, following the trends for the moment.&nbsp;<br><br>What I will say though is, you know, our hospitalizations are still high, our death rates are still high.&nbsp; So, as we work towards that and as we are encouraged by the current trends, we are not there yet.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Kristen Welker at NBC.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this call.&nbsp; I know that you have spoken in the past about the fact that we could be moving closer to having a vaccine for children under the age of five.&nbsp; And obviously, when you look at some of the polling, it&#8217;s potentially concerning: Just 3 in 10 parents of children under the age of five say that they&#8217;ll get their child vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Can you update us on your latest efforts once those vaccines are approved to reach those parents who are still skeptical?&nbsp; What should they know?&nbsp; And why should they have confidence in the vaccines once they are approved?&nbsp; What will your messaging be, and what are your latest outreach efforts?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, Dr. Fauci, maybe you can do a minute or two on the under-five vaccine status.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;ll talk some about both the operational issues and the &#8212; answering questions and building confidence work.&nbsp;<br><br>Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp;<br><br>Yes, the data from the trials on children from 6 months to 24 months, as well as those from 21 months to &#8212; up to the end of 4 years have been conducted by the pharmaceutical company, in this case, Pfizer.&nbsp;<br><br>The data have been submitted to the FDA, and the FDA VRBPAC, or their advisory committee, will be meeting on February 15th.&nbsp; I think people need to be assured that any decision that the FDA makes, as is historically always the case with them, will really be based on the scientific data of both safety and efficacy.&nbsp; And we can assure you that the decision will be based on that.&nbsp;<br><br>And if, in fact, approved, it will be approved on the fact that the data show clear efficacy and safety.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I&#8217;ll go back to you, Jeff, for the rest of that question.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thanks, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; So, operationally, we will be ready once FDA and CDC make their recommendations.&nbsp; As we talked about last week, this vaccine is specifically formulated for these young kids.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re launching a new program specially for kids under five.<br><br>The planning process is well underway.&nbsp; CDC is working with states to help them prepare.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve secured enough vaccine supply for all kids in this age group &#8212; all 18 million.&nbsp; We have enough needles, syringes, and kits.&nbsp; And these are all specially formulated, are made for this age group to send alongside the vaccine.<br><br>And we&#8217;re working closely, you know, with pediatricians and family doctors and children&#8217;s hospitals and pharmacies to make sure the vaccine is available at thousands of locations across the country &#8212; locations that parents know and trust.&nbsp;<br><br>We can start packing and shipping the vaccine once FDA makes its decision.&nbsp; So, we will be prepared for those parents that are eager to get their kids vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>I think the second part of your question is &#8212; there are parents that are &#8212; that do have questions, and we need to answer those questions.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve learned through our efforts across the last year that the best messengers are local messengers &#8212; local community groups and leaders, doctors, and other health practitioners.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we are working closely with HHS to line up that group and make sure that they have the materials that they need, the training they need to be able to answer the questions that parents have about getting their kids vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Josh Wingrove of Bloomberg.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, can you talk a little bit more about what you think the data show now of the need for a shot beyond the third dose, beyond a booster?<br><br>As you know, boosters are being given as early as five months &#8212; we are approaching five months now &#8212; some of the &#8212; first folks who got it.<br><br>What do we know about how often or if further shots will be needed going forward, and in particular, whether we might need specific types of shots for any variant?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah, thank you for that question.&nbsp; That&#8217;s obviously an issue that have been followed very closely.&nbsp; Because as I&#8217;ve said in answer to questions on previous press conferences &#8212; similar questions &#8212; is that you follow individuals for a period of time after the third dose and you measure a number of phenomenon.&nbsp; You measure laboratory phenomenon, but you measure the real-world data on the efficacy in preventing, for example, hospital visits, as well as hospitalizations.<br><br>And I believe that you&#8217;re going to be hearing data about that as they &#8212; data become available.&nbsp; And that should not be within a very long period of time.&nbsp;<br><br>I think you should be appreciative of the fact that when you&#8217;re talking about any decisions that will be made &#8212; and I&#8217;m not anticipating any of that now &#8212; but that has to be put into the context of whom you&#8217;re talking about.<br><br>For example, there may be the need for yet again another boost &#8212; in this case, a fourth-dose boost for an individual receiving the mRNA &#8212; that could be based on age, as well as underlying conditions.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t think you&#8217;re going to be hearing, if you do, any kind of recommendations that would be across the board for everyone.&nbsp; It very likely will take into account what subset of people have a diminished, or not, protection against the important parameters such as hospitalization.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.&nbsp; We look forward to the next briefing.&nbsp;<br><br>11:37 A.M. EST</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/COVID-Press-Briefing-2.9.22-clean.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/COVID-Press-Briefing-2.9.22-clean.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Deputy Press Secretary Sabrina Singh on Vice President Harris’s Travel to&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/statement-from-deputy-press-secretary-sabrina-singh-on-vice-president-harriss-travel-to-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Vice President Kamala Harris will travel to Munich, Germany to attend the February 18-20 Munich Security Conference.  Building on the Biden-Harris Administration’s intensive engagement with European allies and partners, the Vice President’s engagements in Munich will demonstrate our ironclad commitment to our NATO Allies, reaffirm our shared interest in upholding the principles that have underpinned European peace and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left"> Vice President Kamala Harris will travel to Munich, Germany to attend the February 18-20 Munich Security Conference.  Building on the Biden-Harris Administration’s intensive engagement with European allies and partners, the Vice President’s engagements in Munich will demonstrate our ironclad commitment to our NATO Allies, reaffirm our shared interest in upholding the principles that have underpinned European peace and security since World War II, and underscore our commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Senior Officials from the Federal Republic of&#160;Nigeria</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-senior-officials-from-the-federal-republic-of-nigeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 13:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met yesterday with Nigerian Presidential Chief of Staff Professor Ibrahim Gambari and Nigerian National Security Advisor Babagana Monguno at the White House.  Mr. Sullivan affirmed the Administration’s commitment to collaborate with Nigeria to tackle shared global challenges, including ending the COVID-19 pandemic, building a more inclusive global economy, and combatting&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met yesterday with Nigerian Presidential Chief of Staff Professor Ibrahim Gambari and Nigerian National Security Advisor Babagana Monguno at the White House.  Mr. Sullivan affirmed the Administration’s commitment to collaborate with Nigeria to tackle shared global challenges, including ending the COVID-19 pandemic, building a more inclusive global economy, and combatting the climate crisis.  The leaders discussed shared concerns about democratic backsliding and political instability in West Africa and the importance of ongoing efforts by the Economic Community of West African States to reverse military seizures of power and restore constitutional order in Burkina Faso, Guinea, and Mali.  Mr. Sullivan conveyed U.S. support for Nigeria’s important preparations to hold free and fair elections in 2023 and counter violent extremists and terrorist groups.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 8,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/08/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-8-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:41 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160;&#160;Okay.&#160;&#160;Well, happy Tuesday, everyone.&#160;&#160;As you all know &#8212; just a couple of announcements for all of you at the top.&#160;&#160;As you all know, the pandemic-induced global supply chain backlog has strained our transportation industry and created a critical shortage of truck drivers.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Almost two&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:41 P.M. EST<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Okay.&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, happy Tuesday, everyone.&nbsp;&nbsp;As you all know &#8212; just a couple of announcements for all of you at the top.&nbsp;&nbsp;As you all know, the pandemic-induced global supply chain backlog has strained our transportation industry and created a critical shortage of truck drivers.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Almost two months ago, the Biden-Harris administration launched a Trucking Action Plan to strengthen America&#8217;s workforce.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A key element of this plan is encouraging the trucking industry to recruit and retain well-trained drivers by creating a safe, welcoming, and stable career path with good-paying jobs and family-sustaining wages.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We can think of few Americans better prepared to take on this challenge than our nation&#8217;s veterans, since many have military trucking experience, are familiar with safety culture, and have maintenance skills.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Friday, the administration met with veteran service organizations representing nearly 4 million veterans to discuss ways that we and the industry could attract, train, place, and retain veterans in trucking jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And today, we&#8217;re pleased to announce the Departments of Labor, Transportation, Defense, Veterans Affairs, and the Small Business Administration will be raising awareness about 16 different federal programs that can &#8212; that can connect transitioning military personnel and veterans to rewarding careers in the trucking industry.&nbsp; A highlight of these efforts is the Department of Labor&#8217;s Registered Apprenticeship Program.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we see this as a win-win-win &#8212; getting more veterans to work, addressing the shortages in the trucking industry.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also wanted to note that, as you&#8217;ve heard the President talk about a fair amount, he&#8217;s committed to using every tool at his disposal to bring down prices.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re going to hear him talk and the administration talk a lot about this as the &#8212; as the week proceeds.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re working to ease supply chain bottlenecks and give consumers more choices.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we continue to push for legislation like Build Back Better and a competitiveness bill that will make our economy stronger, lower the costs of essentials, bring more manufacturing to the United States, and strengthen our supply chains.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This week, the President is also going to be meeting with business leaders and traveling in the country &#8212; to Virginia, as you know &#8212; to highlight his plan to address prices.&nbsp; While we&#8217;re made &#8212; we&#8217;ve made remarkable strides with the fastest economic growth since 1984 and the most jobs created in one year ever, he knows there&#8217;s more work to do to keep prices down.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He will al- &#8212; he also talked this afternoon, as you just all heard him do, about how we can build more in America, bring down costs through making more in America, and rebuilding our supply chains.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as I noted, tomorrow he&#8217;ll be hosting CEOs at the White House to talk about how Build Back Better can lower energy costs.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you know, he&#8217;s going to Virginia on Thursday to talk about lowering the price of prescription drugs.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With that, Colleen, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, a couple things.&nbsp; Do you have any information about a possible security threat at Dunbar High School where the Second Gentleman was?&nbsp; I think he was just taken from the event and it was postponed, but we don&#8217;t know &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates on this.&nbsp; We will venture to see if we can get to anything, even if it&#8217;s during the briefing.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It just happened, yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Excellent.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, second, the remaining Child Tax Credit is &#8212; you know, the Biden administration is encouraging people to use what&#8217;s left of the remaining tax credit.&nbsp; So, to what extent do you hope that you can show the benefits of the program to overcome skepticism about the program, kind of by getting this last bunch of money out there?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more thing after.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, one of the steps we&#8217;re trying to take here, which is &#8212; which is showcased by the fact that today the Vice President, Secretary Yellen, and Gene Sperling are hosting a Day of Action with over 100 nonprofits and community-based organizations to encourage all Americans to take advantage of critical tax credits, including the expanded Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit when they file their taxes this year.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Part of the reason we&#8217;re doing that is because we know how effective it is.&nbsp; We know that it helped cut child poverty by 40 percent last year.&nbsp; We know it helped give many families some extra breathing room at a time where the economy was still recovering.&nbsp; And studies show that the Child Tax Credit also helps working families with development &#8212; with developments and opportunities for their children.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s important to remember &#8212; and this one of the things they&#8217;ll be talking about today &#8212; that Americans that qualify for the extended Child Tax Credit will still receive half of the entire benefit when they file their taxes this year.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And yesterday, we launched a new version of ChildTaxCredit.gov to help Americans get the full Child Tax Credit as tax filing season begins.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, part of our effort here is to continue to talking about &#8212; continue talking about the benefits: how they&#8217;re helping working families; how they&#8217;re helping many women who need &#8212; who need an extra hand to cover childcare costs; and how they&#8217;re helping give people a little extra breathing room.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then lastly, if Dr. Lander &#8212; the President accepted his resignation last night, I think.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Or this morning.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Last night.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last night.&nbsp; I mean, not to go back to yesterday&#8217;s discussion, but should he have just fired him to begin with, if he was just going to offer his resignation anyway, and spare all of the criticism from yesterday?&nbsp; I mean, I don&#8217;t know, should there have been things done differently, I guess?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me reiterate something I said yesterday, because I think it&#8217;s important for people to hear that, from the outset, Dr. Lander&#8217;s behavior was unacceptable.&nbsp; Senior White House officials conveyed that to him directly at the conclusion of the investigation.&nbsp; And, of course, we talked about that yesterday.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what happened here is we took &#8212; we &#8212; as a part of the implementation of the Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy &#8212; something that we implemented and announced last May, or put out there last May &#8212; we implemented a process &#8212; including an investigation, including a meeting that Dr. Lander had with senior White House officials &#8212; to convey the severity of his actions and what steps he was expected to take and the fact that there would be complia- &#8212; he would be expected to be compliant.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you saw, we released Dr. Lander&#8217;s note last night to all of you &#8212; or his letter of resignation, I should say.&nbsp; It was made clear to him &#8212; through the course of the day yesterday, I suppose &#8212; that he could no longer lead OSTP effectively.&nbsp; And he conveyed that in his letter.&nbsp; The President accepted his resignation.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I think we&#8217;re now focused on looking forward.&nbsp; There&#8217;s obviously a lot of important work that OSTP will do, continue to do, and continue to lead on moving forward.&nbsp; And the President is eager to continue working with them.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A couple on Ukraine.&nbsp; President Macron says that he believes that he achieved this objective of preventing an escalation after his day with Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; What have the French shared with the White House about that meeting?&nbsp; And does the White House believe that we are, today, closer to seeing de-escalation as a result of this meeting than we were yesterday?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the meeting and the press conference, as you may have seen, ended very late last night.&nbsp; So, obviously, we are &#8212; will continue to be in very close contact with our French counterparts at a range of levels.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has spoken with &#8212; with President Macron twice in the last week.&nbsp; I expect he&#8217;ll be engaged with him soon, which we will, of course &#8212; to go back to Kelly&#8217;s question yesterday &#8212; make you all aware of.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would just say we encourage and we&#8217;re encouraged by any efforts at diplomacy.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t &#8212; we still don&#8217;t have any prediction of what President Putin will do.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t control what Russia will do next.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What we can do and what I think President Macron played a role in doing yesterday is making clear with our Allies and partners that there will be massive consequences should Putin choose to further invade Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But in terms of an assessment, we don&#8217;t have any new information or new prediction about where President Putin&#8217;s head is.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the White House not received a readout from the French on this?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We &#8212; we are &#8212; we remain in close touch with our counterparts, but I don&#8217;t have an update on any specifics of behind-the-scenes diplomatic talks.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more one Ukraine.&nbsp; We heard the President and the Chancellor yesterday emphasize this united front.&nbsp; We did not hear the Chancellor mention the phrase &#8220;Nord Stream 2.&#8221;&nbsp; What assurances did this White House get from Germany &#8212; the German government &#8212; about Nord Stream 2 and the future of that pipeline if Russia invades?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you heard the President very definitively say yesterday at the press conference: If Russia further invades Ukraine, there will no longer be a Nord Stream 2 and we will bring an end to it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You heard the German Chancellor also convey yesterday that we are working in lockstep and that we are very coordinated in our efforts.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of the specifics, we’ll let those conversations happen through diplomatic channels.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I would also reiterate that Nord Stream 2 is not currently operational.&nbsp; We agree that it is a point of leverage with President Putin and the Russians.&nbsp; German regulators have suspended certification of the pipeline.&nbsp; And we have been very clear privately, as we have been publicly, about the fact that it would not continue should Russia invade.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I have just one last one.&nbsp; Your reaction to the RNC declaring what happened on January 6th as &#8220;legitimate political discourse&#8221;?&nbsp; And Democrats on the Hill today are being very vocal about this.&nbsp; Hakeem Jeffries says the &#8220;C&#8221; in &#8220;RNC&#8221; stands for &#8220;cult.&#8221;&nbsp; Does the White House agree with that?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it’s clear to Americans that what happened on January 6th was not &#8220;legitimate political discourse.&#8221;&nbsp; Storming the Capitol in an attempt to halt the peaceful transition of power is not legitimate discourse, neither is attacking and injuring over 140 police officers, smashing windows, and defiling offices.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s telling to all of us that some leading Republicans have rejected that characterization, including the former President’s National Security Advisor and the Chief of Staff to the former Vice President, who, as he put it, had a front-row seat that day, including as rioters chanted for the former Vice President to be hanged.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, we certainly reject the notion that that was &#8220;legitimate political discourse,&#8221; as we think very &#8212; a large number of Americans would as well.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I want to ask you about this Army after-action investigation into the Afghanistan withdrawal that was obtained by the Washington Post.&nbsp; First of all, is this is a report that the White House has had an opportunity to review and absorb?&nbsp; And if so, were there any lessons that were learned from it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know, obviously, our national security team, as we said at the time, was going to conduct after-action reports as they would as it relates to the end of any conflict or any engagement of that sort.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, we have always believed that the end of a 20-year war was always going to have significant challenges.&nbsp; We &#8212; as you know and we talked about at the time, through the summer, we were pressing our system hard on whether we were meeting previously established tripwires that would require us to adjust operations at Embassy Kabul.&nbsp; That’s how we looked at it and evaluated it at the time.&nbsp;<br><br>The NSC led that process and convened regular interagency discussions.&nbsp; And, of course, earlier in the summer, we prepositioned U.S. forces in the region to be ready to facilitate a NEO in preparation of exactly that scenario.<br><br>I know I &#8212; I reiterate all of that because I know we haven’t talked about this in great detail in some time, so I just wanted to lay it all out there.<br><br>All that work, of course, took months of planning.&nbsp; But we always look at and assess &#8212; that’s why after-action reports are so important and so essential.&nbsp; In terms of additional reports out of any of these findings, I don’t have anything to report from here.&nbsp; I’d really point you to the Department of Defense.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But has the White House had an opportunity to review this particular report?&nbsp; (Inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, internal &#8212; internal discussions and internal reviews of any &#8212; of any after-action reports, I don’t have any updates on or assessments from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Among the criticisms from military commanders in the document is that, as late as early August of last year, the NSC, quote, &#8220;appeared to lack a sense of urgency&#8221; about planning for an evacuation because &#8220;it would signal [that] ‘we have failed.’&#8221;&nbsp; What’s your reaction to that criticism?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, again, earlier in the summer, we prepositioned U.S. forces to be ready to facilitate a NEO if needed &#8212; meaning an evacuation, if needed, of our embassy there.&nbsp; That is fact in terms of what was planning, what was done at the time.&nbsp;<br><br>And that &#8212; in advance of that, that required months of planning to ensure there were a range of contingencies planned for, as we always do, through the national security team and through the military team.<br><br>And as we prepared in the early summer to leave Afghanistan, we prepositioned military assets in the region that enabled us to execute one of the largest airlifts in history.<br><br>So, I would just say, if you look back at the specific planning steps we took, we did plan for a range of contingencies even while, as we talked about at the time, there wasn&#8217;t an anticipation that &#8212; that the Afghan National Security Forces would fall as they did or as quickly as they did.&nbsp; And that was not anticipated by anyone.&nbsp; But we still had done a range of contingency planning.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, broadly then, do you reject the assertion that was made by various military commanders in this report that they were trying to convince members of the administration of the urgency of planning for the evacuation, but that they were rebuffed?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, there was a range of contingency planning that was done in close coordination by all of the players on the national security team at the time to prepare for a range of options and a range of outcomes.&nbsp;<br><br>No one predicted, as we know and as we talked about a lot during the period of August and September, that the Afghan National Security Forces would fall at the pace they fell.&nbsp; But if you look back at the history of what we actually did and what planning was done, there was a range of planning &#8212; including positioning military forces, including ensuring that we had a plan for a NEO operation for evacuation at the time should that be needed.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we always look back and assess, but I would say the facts of what was planned for at the time show that we were preparing for a range of contingencies.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up real quick on this last exchange.&nbsp; That report did paint a pretty damning picture of the NSC and the State Department pretty much having blinders on while generals sounded the alarm over Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br><br>But we&#8217;re hearing sort of the same bleak, blunt assessments right now from the Pentagon about Ukraine.&nbsp; So, is there &#8212; I guess, any &#8212; is there any closer relationship between the White House and Pentagon &#8212; are the generals being listened to differently now &#8212; post Afghanistan, post this report?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s really important to separate the two.&nbsp; Because, first, we are not in a 20-year war with U.S. troops in Ukraine.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a very different circumstance.&nbsp; I would say that we believe and we continue to view our relationship &#8212; both from the White House, from the diplomatic team, and from the Defense Department &#8212; as one where we are closely coordinating, where there are healthy disagreements as there can be, and the President certainly welcomes them.<br><br>And the after-action reports are very important because you can look at and make assessments about anything you would change moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>But Ukraine and the circumstance &#8212; the situation on the border of Ukraine with Russian troops building up is not the same as ending a 20-year war.&nbsp; That is something the President had talked about for some time, where we were spending an enormous amount of not just money but blood of American service members for the &#8212; over the course of decades.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a different circumstance.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on this meeting between Putin and Macron yesterday, it sounds like the White House does not have a clear idea yet about whether there was in fact a deal or not for Russia to de-escalate or pledge, rather, not to go &#8212; give any further escalation.&nbsp; Obviously, the Kremlin denied reports that the French put out about having struck a deal.<br><br>If the U.S. is not aware of where things stand, doesn&#8217;t that signal that there&#8217;s a separate negotiating track happening between the Europeans and Russia right now that could put the U.S. at risk of being sort of shut out from that discussion?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not in any way.&nbsp; I completely disagree with what you just conveyed.&nbsp;<br><br>First of all, there are a range of diplomatic conversations happening all the time.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been the case for many weeks.&nbsp; The United States is a key player in the vast majority of those negotiations.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, there are important formats, whether it is bilateral leader-to-leader engagement, which President Macron was a part of yesterday; or the Normandy Format, which is something we fully support, which is the format that the Minsk agreement would be discussed through, which includes Ukraine, Russia,&nbsp;<s>Georgia</s>&nbsp;[Germany], and France.&nbsp; That&#8217;s another format that we fully support.<br><br>Those are conversations that have been happening.&nbsp; And typically, through a diplomatic process, there are a range of conversations that are happening at the same time.<br><br>Again, as I noted a little bit earlier, the President spoke with President Macron twice over the last week &#8212; including on Sunday, the day before he spoke with President Putin.&nbsp; And I expect to speak with him soon again.<br><br>But it&#8217;s also important to note that there are others &#8212; German &#8212; the German Chancellor, who was just here yesterday, is also meeting with President Putin tomorrow.&nbsp; And certainly, if there is diplomatic progress, we would welcome that.&nbsp; But we will believe it when we see it with our own eyes at the border.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the warships that moved into the Black Sea, there are some people who are fearing that this is another invasion force potentially targeting the city of Odesa.&nbsp; Obviously, the Kremlin is saying it&#8217;s just exercises.&nbsp; But is there a concern in the White House that, you know, while we&#8217;re buying time for this diplomatic push, that Putin is just bolstering his forces, building his forces while we&#8217;re all talking?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I know that my colleague, John Kirby, has spoken to this from the Pentagon, so I’d point you to his comments.&nbsp; But I would say that we are not &#8212; we are always going to leave the door to diplomacy open because we think as long as we don’t know what President Putin is going to do &#8212; and we don’t; and he has not invaded Ukraine at this point &#8212; then it is important to always keep that door open because that’s always the preferred path.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, we are not just talking; we have built, through 200 engagements &#8212; talking is engaged in part- &#8212; is an important part of it, I guess.&nbsp; But to build a &#8212; an agreement with our partners and allies in Europe about putting together a severe set of economic consequences should they decide to invade.&nbsp;<br><br>We have provided an enormous amount of security assistance to Ukraine to make sure they are prepared.&nbsp; So, we are working on a number of paths, as you should do, but diplomacy is always going to be the preferred path.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last one on masks.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When are we going to hear from the CDC on this guidance?&nbsp; California yesterday changed their guidance.&nbsp; Randi Weingarten &#8212; teachers union &#8212; is vocally asking for the White House and the CDC to weigh in.&nbsp; So when are we going to hear from the CDC about updating the guidance on masks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You’ll have to ask the CDC.&nbsp; The CDC moves at the pace of data and science.&nbsp; I would note that our goal remains continuing to ensure that there is guidance that helps school districts stay open.&nbsp; That’s our goal.&nbsp; We want kids to be in school.&nbsp; Ninety-eight percent of schools are open.&nbsp; That’s a very &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me finish.&nbsp; That’s a very good sign.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We know what works.&nbsp; The CDC is always going to be reviewing their guidance, including mask guidance.&nbsp; But in terms of when they will provide additional new guidance, that is up to them.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Do you believe then that the Democratic- led states who are breaking with the CDC on this guidance, that they&#8217;re not &#8212; that they&#8217;re throwing science away and that the CDC is &#8212; has access to different science somehow?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;We don’t look at it through that prism.&nbsp;&nbsp;These states, I think it’s important to note, they still allow for decisions to be made by local school districts.&nbsp;<br><br>Where we come up with concern &#8212; where we have great concern is if a kid or a parent chooses to wear a mask or a school district decides they should keep mask guidance in place and there are leaders who are preventing them from doing that.&nbsp;&nbsp;That is the place [case] in some other states.<br><br>But our hope is that states, leaders will look at the science and data about what&#8217;s going on, they’ll make decisions about local school districts.&nbsp;&nbsp;Local school districts have always made these decisions.&nbsp;&nbsp;That remains the case.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask about Supreme Court process.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About three weeks left before the President’s &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Who’s counting?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has any of this process moved to a point where you are requesting documents, background materials directly from those women who are among the potential choices?&nbsp;<br><br>And also, how are you facilitating the President in getting advice from allies and so forth, on the outside, who may want to pitch their favorite contenders?&nbsp; We&#8217;re certainly seeing lawmakers and others speaking publicly.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a little different than speaking directly to the President.&nbsp; How is that information getting to him?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me start with the second part, and then I&#8217;ll come back to the first, to the best of my ability.<br><br>So you all have seen that the President has met with, very publicly, both Chairman Durmin [sic] &#8212; Durbin and Ranking Member Grassley.&nbsp; The Chairman and the President and Vice President have also spoken with a number of members to engage with them, get their feedback.&nbsp;<br><br>I had also noted, I think yesterday, that the President has also spoken with a wide range of outside legal experts, as he&#8217;s seeking to consult and to get feedback and advice from them.&nbsp;<br><br>So, he is receiving and engaging with a range of people as he considers this process.&nbsp; I would note also that as he&#8217;s looking at the process, he&#8217;s reviewing not just bios, but he&#8217;s also reviewing cases.&nbsp; And he is looking at binders of cases because he is very &#8212; taking this approach very seriously.&nbsp; He&#8217;s taking a very thorough approach to it.<br><br>In terms of the process, that is &#8212; that is a part of the process, as you know, from covering these, Kelly &#8212; vetting documents &#8212; and that requires engagement with individuals.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics about where that sits.&nbsp; What I would reiterate from the &#8212; and those of you who’ve covered this know this well &#8212; is that we &#8212; later in the process &#8212; the very end of the process is typically when the President would interview candidates.<br><br>We remain &#8212; we remain on track to announce a nominee by the end of the month.&nbsp; But that is typically the very end of the process.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say that the field has narrowed a bit from the dozen or so that we were originally talking about?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is a natural part of the process, but I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics of the numbers.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Going back to the after-action report on the Abbey Gate investigation: It’s incredible what is in this report.&nbsp; Some of the military officials say things such as, “[The Department of State] did not get one message right to the Afghans during the NEO.”&nbsp; “Marines at Abbey Gate were forced to play God by identifying who would be allowed into the airfield.”<br><br>One of the reasons you do an after-action report, as you said, is to go back and assess.&nbsp; But isn’t it also to allow for accountability?&nbsp; Does he President intend to seek any accountability?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we’re going to allow a discussion internally to continue about any after-action report.&nbsp; I have no predictions beyond that at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaking of accountability &#8212; last night, accepting the resignation of Dr. Lander.&nbsp; It’s been postulated here in town that perhaps Dr. Lander would still be working for this administration if POLITICO hadn’t reported the story yesterday morning and if reporters in this room hadn’t asked about it yesterday.&nbsp; Is that a fair assessment?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, again, given that Dr. Lander made the decision himself to submit his resignation, that would be a question best posed to him.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the President was not involved?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, he was not.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And he did not seek Dr. Lander’s resignation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He did not.&nbsp; He made that decision himself.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Frontier has announced plans to buy Spirit Airlines.&nbsp; Is there any concern in this administration about reduced competition?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, broadly speaking, we always have a concern about reduced competition.&nbsp; But in terms of this potential merger, I don’t have any specific comment from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it under discussion, at least?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, you know, that would be reviewed by the Department of Justice and not from here.&nbsp; So I don’t have any additional comment from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; China, as has been widely reported, has largely missed its phase one purchase commitments.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been talk about administration officials voicing, this week, its disappointment over that and frustration.&nbsp; What is the President prepared to do on that front?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first that &#8212; hold on, I have some update on this.&nbsp; Let me just make sure I have the most up-to-date information.&nbsp; One moment.&nbsp; Thanks for your patience.&nbsp;<br><br>So, as you know and have been following this closely, Alex, the USTR has been in conversations with China about its performance regarding purchase commitments under phase one, which they did not meet in 2020 and did not meet in 2021.&nbsp;<br><br>And they have conveyed &#8212; and I would just reiterate on their behalf, the USTR officials &#8212; it is on China to show up and follow through on its commitment.<br><br>So, our &#8212; again, this is under the purview, as you know, of Ambassador Tai.&nbsp; We have expressed our concerns; we have them.&nbsp; In terms of specifically what the President would be prepared to do, we&#8217;re going to continue to engage with Ambassador Tai and the trade team to determine next steps.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, just to be clear, what is the President prepared to do though?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, the USTR, our &#8212; Ambassador Tai is the one who runs point on this.&nbsp; And I would point you to her for any additional comment on the current status.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Finally, there&#8217;s some talk on Capitol Hill about congressional staffers unionizing.&nbsp; Does the President support that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He does.&nbsp; He supports the right of any individual to seek to join a union, to collective bargain.&nbsp; And of course, Capitol Hill staffers are certainly individuals who are pursuing that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the staff been in touch with those folks?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our staff &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; been in touch with them?&nbsp; I would really point you to congressional leadership.&nbsp; I know Speaker Pelosi and her team have spoken to this as well.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So, truckers in Canada last night shut down the Ambassador Bridge, which carries about a quarter of U.S.-Canada trading goods.&nbsp; So what&#8217;s the administration&#8217;s response to this action?&nbsp; And what steps are being taken to ensure the free flow of goods?&nbsp; And also, any preventative steps being taken to address a possible blockade on the Michigan side of that bridge?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first start by saying: I know there&#8217;s been some suggestion &#8212; not by reporters necessarily at all &#8212; but that this congestion is related to the vaccine requirements.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not.&nbsp; I mean, I &#8212; I&#8217;m saying &#8212; I&#8217;m going to get to the protests.&nbsp; But the protests going on across Canada, which have spread to a bridge, are leading to sporadic congestion and blockages.&nbsp;<br><br>I would &#8212; just to go back to my point I was trying to make is that across &#8212; what we&#8217;ve seen with these requirements is, across indus- &#8212; a range of industries, vaccine &#8212; vaccination requirements have been implemented with no disruptions, have helped increase vaccinations.<br><br>These requirements help protect more people from COVID.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s been zero indication across these industries that they would lead to disruptions, including on this policy.&nbsp;<br><br>We, of course, support, as you know, the right to freedom of speech and protest.&nbsp; But we &#8212; and while we do see some of these congestions due to protests, this is clear that these disruptions have broadened in scope beyond the vaccine requirement implementation.&nbsp;<br><br>We &#8212; beyond that, we are, of course, in touch with our Canadian counterparts, but I don&#8217;t have any updates in terms of specific steps.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Ukraine: So, yesterday &#8212; in yesterday&#8217;s briefing, you mentioned that the Minsk Agreements would possibly be a part of these Macron and Putin talks.&nbsp; And now that it’s over, is the U.S. discussing directly with any of the parties the use of the Minsk Agreement as a possible way out of the conflict, as President Zelenskyy has suggested?&nbsp; Do you see that as, sort of, a fruitful pathway toward a diplomatic agreement?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we see the Minsk Agreements &#8212; which are discussed through the Normandy Format, which I was talking about a little bit earlier &#8212; as certainly a format to move things forward.&nbsp; And we stand ready to support these sincere efforts.&nbsp; And, again, we welcome calls for a diplomatic resolution to the conflict in eastern Ukraine, and the Minsk Agreement is a format that those could take place through.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I guess, you know, there’s been some suggestions that the Minsk Agreement would be unfavorable toward Ukraine if implemented in the way that the Russians want it implemented.&nbsp; So, is the U.S. coming down in any way on one side or the other?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are not.&nbsp; We just seem them as a format through which there could be discussion and continued engagement.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, lastly, quickly on competition.&nbsp; You know, Tyson Foods’ stock went up very high yesterday &#8212; I think its highest in about two years &#8212; on the back of record profits on rising meat pri- &#8212; partially on rising meat prices.&nbsp; So how is that posing a challenge to your administration’s efforts to address competition in that industry?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, just four large conglomerates control the majority of the market for beef, pork, and poultry products.&nbsp; And the data shows &#8212; and I think their record profits are evidence of this &#8212; that there have been increases in meat prices while the companies have generated recent record profits.&nbsp; And that’s a good example of it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I would just note, just if you look at historical precedent here: Fifty years ago, ranchers got over 60 cents for every dollar a family spent on beef; today, they get about 39 cents.&nbsp; Fifty years ago, hog farmers got 40 to 60 cents for each dollar they spent; today, it’s about 19 cents.&nbsp; And the big companies are still making major profits.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It certainly shouldn’t work that way.&nbsp; And as the President has said many times: Capitalism without competition isn&#8217;t capitalism, it’s exploitation.&nbsp; And we have continued concern about the lack of competition in these industries.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Mara.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I have a Lander and Ukraine question.&nbsp; First of all, will Rachel Wallace get her job back?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will have to check and see in the internal HR process.&nbsp; I’m happy to do that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, since you’ve made it clear that he was &#8212; he resigned, he was not fired, how does this comport with President Biden’s pledge to fire you, quote, “on the spot” if he found about any kind of mistreatment of employees?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, what we did early in the administration, after he made those comments &#8212; which I think that were the first or second day in office &#8212; was: Our team &#8212; our HR team, our legal team, others &#8212; worked to put in place a Safe And Respectful Workplace Policy.&nbsp;<br><br>And that policy, which is about a six-page document &#8212; I think we made it available to all of you, and we&#8217;re happy to reshare it if useful &#8212; that was the process through which there was an investigation into these allegations.&nbsp; There was a conclusion of that investigation.&nbsp; At the conclusion of that, Eric Lander &#8212; Dr. Eric Lander met with senior members of our officials who made clear what steps needed to be taken and that he would be required to be compliant with those.<br><br>So that was actually an implementation of the President&#8217;s commitment and in an effort to create a process for a large administration to maintain a healthy work environment and create a channel to address issues as they come up.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, “on the spot” meant “on the spot after an investigation&#8221;?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think in any workplace and one where &#8212; like the White House, you need to have a process and a process through which employees can present any concerns they have, any allegations they have, and that there&#8217;s a process that those can be seen through.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what happened in this case.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine, if you could explain to ordinary Americans who find the domestic politics of other countries very mystifying, why couldn&#8217;t Chancellor Scholz say the words “Nord Stream pipeline”?&nbsp; He was asked numerous times, not just in the press conference yesterday, but also later in interviews.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Why can&#8217;t spit out the words that President Biden said?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s what I can speak for, which is the U.S. government, of course, and President Biden and our commitment and agreement that if Russia invades, Nord Stream 2 will not move forward.&nbsp; It is still not operational at this point in time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; We know your position.&nbsp; I’m just asking if you can give us any insights into why Germany can&#8217;t say that.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I &#8212; you are a very industrious reporter, Mara, and I&#8217;m sure you can pose that question to the Germans as well.&nbsp; But I can only speak for our government, and I can &#8212; you heard the President say and reiterate many times yesterday how, you know, strong our relationship and our alliance is; how Germany is one of the most important alliances &#8212; allies we have in the world; how we have full confidence and faith in their commitment to implementing a strong outcome &#8212; or strong consequences should Russia invade.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; If I heard you correctly, earlier you were saying that President Biden was not involved in directly seeking Dr. Lander’s resignation.&nbsp; But can you clarify if he accepted the resignation because of the investigation or because of the public outcry around it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, if you go back to the letter that Dr. Lander submitted &#8212; this is very small type; I don&#8217;t know if this means I&#8217;m getting older &#8212; but, you know, what he conveyed in that letter was that he did not feel that it was possible to continue effectively in his role.&nbsp; He conveyed that, and he felt &#8212; and he also conveyed that he felt the office &#8211;the work of his office was too important.&nbsp;<br><br>And the President &#8212; that was &#8212; was that the result of the public response or the response of his team?&nbsp; You&#8217;d have to ask Dr. Lander that question.&nbsp; But the President accepted the resignation letter he submitted last night.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it sounds like the investigation was completed in December.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Actually, it was it was completed &#8212; the full process was completed at the very end of January.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, why was it &#8212; why did it not occur that there was any repercussions until after it became public?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there was an entire process that was &#8212; went &#8212; was underway, including a meeting with Dr. Lander conveying exactly what steps he would take, would be required to take, that he would be expected to be compliant with those requirements, and that his actions were absolutely unacceptable and would not be tolerated in this White House, and we wanted to prevent them from happening again.<br><br>So that process had under &#8212; had been undergone.&nbsp; It’s standard.&nbsp; And, of course, these things are reported sometimes, as they were &#8212; but to keep HR processes private, in part because you&#8217;re protecting the range of officials who came forward.&nbsp; And that is &#8212; that is the standard process.&nbsp; Sometimes officials speak publicly, as they did in this case, and that&#8217;s their prerogative.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, can you say when the President learned of the internal investigation and if he was briefed on it before this became a more public subject yesterday?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He was made aware in advance of the &#8212; after the conclusion of the investigation.&nbsp; But beyond that, I don&#8217;t have any updates on the timeline.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just one more.&nbsp; A few weeks ago, the President had talked about in his press conference about the desire to get out of Washington.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since then &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He’s still trying.&nbsp; He’s trying to get on that plane.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s my question, I guess.&nbsp; He’s had a trip to Pittsburgh.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He’s had a trip to New York.&nbsp; As you alluded earlier, he&#8217;s going to Virginia.&nbsp; Is this the robust kind of schedule that he&#8217;s looking for?&nbsp; Or is there something that&#8217;s keeping him in Washington?&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think there are a couple things that, obviously, every president juggles, and including this president is juggling right now.&nbsp; If he could spend every day on the road, he probably would do that.&nbsp; And, you know, any &#8212; when you&#8217;re traveling as president, you know, the world comes with you a bit.&nbsp;<br><br>But there&#8217;s certainly an open Supreme Court spot that he needs to fill and he takes very seriously.&nbsp; He wants to approach that very thorough &#8212; with a thorough approach.<br><br>Of course, he&#8217;s getting regular updates on Russia, Ukraine, from his &#8212; Russia and Ukraine and the buildup of troops on the border.<br><br>So there are a number of, of course, important priorities that, at times, can keep a president here and are &#8212; maybe are keeping the President here.<br><br>However, I think we&#8217;ll be getting out there more; he&#8217;ll be getting out there more in the country.&nbsp; Otherwise, maybe he&#8217;ll fire one of us &#8212; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s eager to do that.&nbsp; He wants to be out in the country.<br><br>And I think as we get to the period of time post State of the Union, I think you&#8217;ll see more of that.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just a quick follow-up on Kelly.&nbsp; Has the President spoken with Congressman Clyburn about his advocacy that has been very prominent for Judge J. Michelle Childs for the Supreme Court?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have any updates on specific members he’s engaged with beyond the ones I’ve &#8212; we’ve read out or you’ve seen publicly, though I would say members of our Supreme Court team &#8212; you’re very familiar with &#8212; have been engaged with a range of members, including Mr. Clyburn.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And back on Ukraine: What was the President’s response to this U.S. assessment that a Russian invasion of Ukraine could kill 25- to 50,000 civilians and cause a humanitarian crisis that would end up with 5 million refugees?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say we’re &#8212; I’m not going to get into intelligence assessments from here, obviously.&nbsp; But we, certainly, prepare for a range of contingencies and work and engage with our European partners and counterparts to prepare for them.&nbsp; And that relates to the potential for refugees; it relates to the potential for natural gas or oil shortages.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And those are part of the discussions the President is a part of, our Secretary of State is a part of, and that is why we are doing so much engagement at this point.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Nord Stream 2: The President was pretty confident yesterday that it would not go forward if Russia invaded Ukraine, even though the German Chancellor would not say that.&nbsp; So, I guess, logistically speaking, how would the President ensure that that would not happen?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m just not going to get into more specifics from here.&nbsp; But I can assure you that that is a commitment and one we will deliver on.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But would that include sanctions on anyone or any company that does business with the pipeline?&nbsp; What does that look like?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand why you’re asking, I just don’t have more details I can outline from here at this point.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In hindsight, does he regret waving sanctions on the company behind Nord Stream 2, as the administration did last year?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Nord Stream 2 is not operational at this point in time.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But does he &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And it remains a point of leverage.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it could quickly become operational.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it’s not &#8212; the German regulators have not approved it.&nbsp; So, it’s not operational.&nbsp; It hasn’t been.&nbsp; So, I don’t think we’re looking in the rearview mirror; I think we’re looking at it as a point of leverage with the Russians.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I guess the question is that Putin has been quite aggressive in his stance with Ukraine.&nbsp; He’s amassed over 100,000 troops on their border.&nbsp; He clearly is seeking to use leverage over them.&nbsp; So why let the pipeline go forward at all, regardless of invasion, given the tactics that he’s been using?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I would say that we &#8212; there’s a disagreement &#8212; I’m not sure this is what you’re asking, but &#8212; between us and some in Congress who suggest that sanctioning Nord Stream 2 now would be effective.&nbsp; We don’t agree.&nbsp; We believe that it is a point of leverage and that making clear it will not proceed if Russia invades is a point of leverage.&nbsp; And that’s why we’re proceeding on the path we are.&nbsp; We don’t think that approach would work.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s been some reporting that President Biden has kind of refused to mention Tesla when he’s talking about electric vehicles.&nbsp; There’s kind of been some reporting around that.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, he mentioned Tesla when he was talking about electric vehicles.&nbsp; Anything noteworthy there?&nbsp; Any change in how he approaches this?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would just note: I think we all know that Tesla is a major producer of electric vehicles; I think that’s fair to say, factually.&nbsp; And, certainly, the electric vehicle industry is one that we feel is a huge opportunity for the United States to move towards our clean energy goals and objectives, and a range of auto- &#8212; of automobile makers are a part of the effort.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; The House version of the China competition bill includes a measure that would require a broad screening process of outbound international investments into China &#8212; not in the Senate one.&nbsp; Does the White House support that particular measure?&nbsp; I know National Security Advisor Sullivan has discussed that in general.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, so, right now, as you know, they’re in conference, or they’re discussing.&nbsp; And we are looking at the impact of outbound U.S. investment flows that could circumvent the spirit of export controls or otherwise enhance the technological capacity of our competitors, which is something I think our National Security Advisor has touched on, in ways that would harm our national security, which we would certainly be concerned by.<br>We are in touch with Congress about the proposal and also our efforts broadly in this regard.&nbsp; But again, we’re going to keep working that through Congress, and that’s with leaders there.&nbsp; And that’s where the focus is at, at this point.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Does the climate of high oil gas prices influence how the White House, the administration approaches sanctions on Iran and Venezuela with an eye at getting more supplies into the market?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me just outline for you &#8212; and I know &#8212; I don’t know if Edward is here.&nbsp; Oh, there you are.&nbsp; He asked me this question yesterday, and I just wanted more detail, so I’m just coming back to it a little bit.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, the President is focused on doing everything we can to address the squeeze that we know gas prices can have on families.&nbsp; As he has said, supply of oil around the world should be keeping up with the demand as we’re exiting the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, there’s a couple of areas that we are focused on, and you’re familiar with them, but let me just outline them from here.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re engaging, one, internationally, both with oil-producing and oil-consuming countries.&nbsp; These discussions are happening right now; they’re ongoing.&nbsp; With oil-producing countries, we’re talking about prod- &#8212; proposed production increases.&nbsp; With oil-consuming countries, we’re talking about releases from strategic reserves.&nbsp; Of course, we’re not going to outline every conversation, but that’s largely how we’re approaching it.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two, the President is going to continue to use every tool at his disposal to reduce prices.&nbsp; We’ve already announced a historic release from the strategic petroleum reserve last fall 40 &#8212; of 50 million barrels.&nbsp; Forty million barrels of those barrels are contracted for delivery, including a num- &#8212; thirteen million that we just released in January.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, as you &#8212; this is not &#8212; it wasn’t that 50 million released at once; they’re continuing to be released.&nbsp; We saw a drop in prices, which fell more than 10 cents a gallon in the course of the holiday season after some of that initial release.&nbsp; And all options remain on the table.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Third, we’re focused on protecting consumers from abuse.&nbsp; We know markets have been volatile.&nbsp; Often, firms exploit market volatility to extract excess profits from consumers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re looking at every legal and regulatory authority we have available to ensure consumers are protected.&nbsp; That means responding to any sign of manipulation in the oil commodities markets or&nbsp;<s>gauging</s>&nbsp;[gouging] at the pump.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, we are looking at it.&nbsp; We are approaching it through all of those forums.&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s overarching view on prices, of course, is that he wants to address the squeeze on consumers; is that nobody &#8212; now that we &#8212; that even with barrels &#8212; even with those barrels released, prices are rising, and that&#8217;s because supply is not keeping up with the demand.&nbsp; We know that is the issue &#8212; the core issue.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Nobody should hold back supply at the expense of the American consumer, particularly as the recovery from the pandemic continues, and oil producers around the world have the capacity to produce at levels that match demand and reduce the high prices.&nbsp; That is what we are going to continue to convey.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one real quick point of clarification?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You announced that the &#8212; the cooperative releases are ready.&nbsp; And in a statement, you suggested that maybe those conversations are ongoing.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we assume then there may be future cooperative releases then?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All options remain on the table, but I don’t have anything to preview at this point in time.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, Jen, following up on the trucker question from earlier.&nbsp; Inspired by the so-called &#8220;Freedom Convoy&#8221; in Canada, a group of U.S. truckers say they&#8217;re planning a similar protest in Washington, D.C., possibly for March 1st, to oppose COVID vaccine mandates.&nbsp; That date is obviously &#8212; would coincide with President Biden&#8217;s State of the Union Address.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you know, the trucker convoy in Ottawa has been very disruptive and paralyzed parts of the city&#8217;s downtown.&nbsp; Is the administration making preparations to be ready for an upcoming &#8220;Freedom Convoy&#8221; planned for D.C.?&nbsp; And does the White House have any concerns about this similar &#8212; a similar protest happening here in the nation&#8217;s capital?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And do you mean, by &#8220;preparations,&#8221; like security preparations?&nbsp; Or do you mean &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, security preparations.&nbsp; Or is it on your radar?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;d have to check with our team on security preparations.&nbsp; I think what I would just reiterate here is that we know that requirements work.&nbsp; We have not seen a disruption as it relates to requirements to the industry.&nbsp; Where we have seen disruptions has been related to these convoys and protests.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now, everybody can peacefully protest; we fully support that.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s important to note where the disruption is occurring.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, on a different topic &#8212; and forgive me if I missed this earlier &#8212; does the White House plan to fill Dr. Lander&#8217;s position?&nbsp; How quickly would you want to nominate somebody?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We do.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update on the timing.&nbsp; But certainly, the President is confident in the expertise of the OSTP team and their ability to move forward on key components of the agenda they are responsible for.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my final topic: The White House has recently held kind of local ECD announcements here &#8212; with the Intel project two weeks ago in Ohio, today with the electric vehicle station facility in Lebanon, Tennessee.&nbsp; And so I&#8217;m trying to &#8212; I&#8217;m curious, what is the federal government&#8217;s role been in these sorts of announcements versus the governors of these two states, in terms of getting these projects?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;So, just so I understand your question, what are we &#8212; in terms of how do we get them the mon- &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, these are traditionally the kind of projects you might expect the governor to announce.&nbsp; Instead, we&#8217;re seeing them here in the White House.&nbsp; What kind of role is the Biden administration have &#8212; I mean, are you working in tandem with these governors?&nbsp; Or is it &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Typically &#8212; yes, exactly.&nbsp; And if the governor can attend, we typically invite them.&nbsp; And sometimes they&#8217;ve taken place in states.&nbsp; And, you know, I think it&#8217;s important &#8212; the President believes it&#8217;s important to lift up the ingenuity of American businesses and companies, and especially companies that are creating jobs here in the United States and putting people back to work. &nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Katie.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; As most people in this room have asked about, the President said yesterday that he would shut down Nord Stream 2 if there was a military invasion.&nbsp; He kind of defined it traditionally as &#8220;tanks on the ground.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>So if Putin attacks but doesn&#8217;t send massive forces over the border, perhaps through cyberattacks or through paramilitary forces, does the President feel the Western alliance could still present a united front, given his conversation with the Chancellor yesterday?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, we have a range of contingency.&nbsp; I certainly understand your question, but I don&#8217;t have anything more to detail here.&nbsp; Obviously, we don&#8217;t think Nord Stream 2 is a good deal or a good project; we&#8217;ve been very clear about that.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think, right now, what we&#8217;re focused on is what we think the right diplomatic tactic is, as it relates to deterrence, which is part of approach.&nbsp; And that includes making clear that Nord Stream 2 will not proceed, given, of course, President Putin and the Russians want it to proceed.&nbsp;<br><br>But we have a range of contingencies should Putin invade, should he take other additional steps, and we&#8217;re going to continue to work to be lockstep with our partners.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to clarify: So, if it&#8217;s a cyberattack or paramilitary or anything besides tanks, would he pull &#8212; well, I know it&#8217;s not operational, but would he stop Nord Stream from going forward?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t have anything more to update you on.&nbsp; We have a range of contingencies, depending on &#8212; if any steps that President Putin takes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then would he still keep the science advisor post &#8212; would that still be Cabinet level?&nbsp; I know that was a first &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; with him.&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The President said yesterday he believes President Putin still has a diplomatic off ramp &#8212; that de-escalation is still possible.&nbsp; But last month at the press conference, less than three weeks ago, the President said, about Putin, &#8220;My guess is he will move in.&nbsp; He has to do something.&#8221;&nbsp; Does he no longer believe that President Putin has to do something?&nbsp; And if that&#8217;s the case, what has changed in those couple of weeks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I mean, he either has to de-escalate or invade.&nbsp; Obviously, our preference is that he de-escalates.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m not sure &#8212; I think that&#8217;s what the President likely meant in the time.&nbsp; We still &#8212; we didn&#8217;t at the time, nor do we now have an assessment of him making a decision.&nbsp; Our &#8212; and we can&#8217;t control what Russia will do next.&nbsp;<br><br>What we can do is we can prepare.&nbsp; And we can prepare for a range of contingencies, and we can stay coordinated with our partners and Allies.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what our focus has been.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned at the top that the Thursday event in Virginia is prescription drugs.&nbsp; Can you tell us more about that?&nbsp; Where he&#8217;s going?&nbsp; Why Virginia?&nbsp; And will we have an announcement on prescription drugs?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I expect we&#8217;ll have more tomorrow as we get a little bit closer, but he&#8217;s going outside of Richmond to Congresswoman Abigail Spanberger&#8217;s district.&nbsp; I think she&#8217;s &#8212; she will be at the event as well, as I understand it.&nbsp; And certainly talking about the need to &#8212; to reduce the cost of prescription drugs, something that is bearing a lot of weight on seniors, on families across the country.&nbsp; It’s something that is still a initiative &#8212; a priority that we still have more work to get done.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On that Thursday trip, has the President invited the Republican Governor of Virginia to join him?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me check and see if we have more details on the specifics.&nbsp; It&#8217;s still all final &#8212; getting finalized.&nbsp; And I expect we’ll have more as we get closer to tomorrow, but I&#8217;ll see if we have any more we can get you after the briefing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if so, would he plan to talk to him about their, sort of, differences in opinion on masking at schools?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me just see who&#8217;s been invited to the event and who&#8217;s planning to attend.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll get you more details from there.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Another one on Ukraine.&nbsp; Yesterday, after meeting Putin, President Macron said that one of the options for Ukraine would be to get a status like the one Finland had during the Cold War &#8212; a status of strict neutrality.&nbsp; Is that also an action the President would consider?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I saw that President Macron said this morning that was not a formulation he used and that ending NATO&#8217;s “open door policy” would be a problem.&nbsp; We agree with that.&nbsp; And as we&#8217;ve said previously, we&#8217;re committed to the right of sovereign nations to make their own decisions about their security.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And maybe &#8212; we see there is a very intense diplomatic battle going on around Moscow.&nbsp; And does the President believe that it is really helpful or maybe that it creates, like, uncertainties around the situation and could ultimately benefit the Russians?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean President Putin engaging in diplomatic conversations?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In a lot of diplomatic conversations.&nbsp; And after every encounter, there is a press conference and there are new questions about “are the Allies really aligned?” &nbsp;Is there maybe concern that there is maybe too much going on?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think what you hear from the Allies time and time again is that we are aligned and we &#8212; there will be severe consequences.&nbsp; And that does not mean that consequences will be identical from every country.&nbsp; It means we agree that invading Ukraine, a sovereign country, is &#8212; violates global norms.&nbsp; And we have worked hard, through more than 200 engagements, to &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t happen by accident, I guess is my point &#8212; to ensure that we remain coordinated and closely working together.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Two topics.&nbsp; The first one is going to be the truckers and then Russia, but first the Canadian &#8212; the movement in Canada &#8212; the truckers.&nbsp; So, the Ottawa mayor has asked for 1,800 additional police officers to quell what he called the “insurrection.”&nbsp; You know that it&#8217;s been a rallying cry for the far right &#8212; this movement.&nbsp; And Prime Minister Trudeau yesterday accused the protestors to &#8212; of trying to blockade Canada&#8217;s economy and democracy.&nbsp; Does the White House share this perspective on the movement?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not how we&#8217;ve described it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you &#8212; you said yesterday, just again, that the CBP was not impacted by the movement at the moment.&nbsp; Now with what happened at the bridge, it has had an impact.&nbsp; Isn’t that &#8212; considering that now trade is concerned, shouldn&#8217;t the White House give more emphasis &#8212; put more emphasis on what&#8217;s going on on the other side of the border?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;ve ever deemphasized.&nbsp; I just think I was trying to convey that while there was kind of a view by some that it was related to vaccine requirements, it wasn&#8217;t; it was related to congestion created by the protests, which I think is for &#8212; important for people to understand.<br><br>In terms of what&#8217;s being done, of course we&#8217;re closely engaged.&nbsp; The Department of Homeland Security would be the right entity to talk to.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just the last question on Russia.&nbsp; Sorry.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Russian President yesterday with Emmanuel Macron commented, and I quote, “They’re trying” &#8212; “they” being the West, the U.S., NATO &#8212; “trying to calm us down with assurances that NATO is a peaceful and defensive organization.”&nbsp; But then he cited Iraq, Libya, Belgrade as counterexamples.&nbsp; What do you say to that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; NATO has always been a defensive alliance.&nbsp; It is Russia that is &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In Libya &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me finish my answer.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is Russia that is building up tens of thousands of troops &#8212; troops at the border, not NATO.&nbsp; We are working to plus-up support for our partners.&nbsp; They have the ability to deescalate, and we certainly hope they do that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Jen.&nbsp; This afternoon, the White House issued a statement criticizing Florida legislation that would restrict classroom discussion of sexual orientation or gender identity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s relatively rare for the White House to weigh in on state-level legislation.&nbsp; So can you speak about the decision to weigh in on this particular bill and why this issue rose to the level that the White House wanted to put something out there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, for those of you who weren&#8217;t following this &#8212; maybe all of you were &#8212; but let me first say that every parent, as one myself too, hopes that our leaders will ensure their children&#8217;s safety, protection, and freedom.&nbsp; And today, conservative politicians in Florida rejected those basic values by advancing legislation that is designed to target and attack the kids who need the support &#8212; support the most: kids from the LGBTQI+ community who are already vulnerable to bullying &#8212; and we&#8217;ve seen that in study after study &#8212; and violence, just for being themselves and just for being who they are.&nbsp;<br><br>Make no mistake: This is not an isolated action in Florida.&nbsp; Across the country, we&#8217;re seeing Republican leaders taking action to regulate what students can or cannot read, what they can or cannot learn, and most troubling, who they can or cannot be.&nbsp; This is who these kids are.&nbsp; And these &#8212; these legislators are trying to make it harder for them to be who they are.<br><br>So, we felt it was important to speak out against this action and speak really &#8212; and felt it was important to do that today.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House reaction to the Supreme Court, late yesterday, restoring an Alabama voting map that a lower court ruled was discriminatory?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; This is a very important story.&nbsp; So I would say that we need to make sure, as you&#8217;ve heard the President say, that our sacred voting rights are fully protected.&nbsp; We should be moving forward, not backward.&nbsp; That is always the view of the President, the Vice President, and this White House.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That means ensuring fair election maps that protect the rights of Black voters to have an equitable and meaningful opportunity to elect candidates of their choice as the Voting Rights Act and Supreme Court precedent have guaranteed for decades.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is deeply disturbing to us that the Supreme Court gave Alabama a free pass to use a map that &#8212; in 2022 &#8212; that three federal judges found to discriminate against Black voters.&nbsp; This is exactly what the Voting Rights Act is in place to prevent and what &#8212; and one of the reasons it’s so important to pass a reauthorization into law.&nbsp; Without &#8212; and they did this without the Supreme Court finding any reason to doubt that conclusion.&nbsp; That is concerning to us.&nbsp;<br><br>And certainly protecting people’s rights &#8212; not taking steps backward &#8212; is our objective.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The administration, as you know, through the Justice Department took legal action against Texas.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They challenged those maps perceived as being discriminatory.&nbsp; Given that voting rights legislation here in Washington has basically been put on pause for a number of reasons, has the White House considered any sort of unilateral or preemptive actions against states that might try to take similar steps as Texas and Alabama did?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I understand the question.&nbsp; I would point you to the Department of Justice.&nbsp; As you know, but for others, we’re not a party to this lawsuit, but I would point you to the Department of Justice.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; A couple on Dr. Lander.&nbsp; I want to be precise, first, I guess on his resignation, because you said it became clear to him yesterday.&nbsp; Was &#8212; did the President or anybody else in the White House encourage him to resign, or was this 100 percent totally voluntary?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This was a decision made by Dr. Lander.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And what does it say to the staff, I guess, in the administration that the President appeared happy to keep him in his role until essentially this became public and became untenable, at least in Dr. Lander’s mind?&nbsp; What does that say to the staff?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wouldn’t say that’s an accurate depiction of how the President feels or we feel.&nbsp; And so, I appreciate the opportunity to restate that Dr. Lander’s behavior was not acceptable at all, and the President did not view it as acceptable either.&nbsp;<br><br>There was a full process that was undergone; that was an implementation of the policies put in place last spring &#8212; the Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy.&nbsp; That included a thorough investigation.&nbsp; It included a meeting of Dr. Lander with individual &#8212; senior officials from the White House team.&nbsp; And it included specific steps he had to take to prevent this from happening ever again.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think what people should be assured of in the White House is that the President is committed to maintaining a healthy work environment, to creating a channel also to address any issues that come up, and that channel was created through this policy last May.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, are there any other senior White House staff or Cabinet members who have been subject to investigations like this?&nbsp; And can the White House commit to making them public in the future, given that it was a public scrutiny here that ended up in a resignation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I certainly understand the question, and we want to create an environment here that’s safe and people feel comfortable and they also the know the channel where they can express concerns as they have them.<br><br>But this is an HR process, and an internal process because of that, and we typically keep those processes private to respect the individuals &#8212; the privacy of the individuals who come forward, if individuals come forward.&nbsp; And that’s how we would proceed moving forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you can’t say “yes” or “no” whether there are other investigations similar to this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, those are private processes and HR processes.&nbsp; And if individuals choose to speak publicly, that, of course, is their prerogative.&nbsp; But as is true of any HR process in any company, we would certainly keep that process private as a policy.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any reevaluation of the workplace policies and goals here, given this &#8212; given everything that’s happened, I guess, here?&nbsp; Is there any feeling needing to go back and revisit whether those are effective and not effective?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, again, our objective is to prevent this behavior &#8212; unacceptable behavior from ever happening again.&nbsp;<br><br>And the Safe and Respectful Workplace Policy, which was implemented in this case, provides a channel for any individual to come forward if they have concerns, where their concerns can be addresses through a thorough process.&nbsp; And hopefully people know that.&nbsp; And it is part of an effort to maintain a healthy work environment.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Immigration reform seems like a nonstarter in the current Congress.&nbsp; But today, freshman Republican Congresswoman Maria Elvira Salazar presented an immigration reform bill that would legalize millions of undocumented.&nbsp; And she’s calling it a starting point.&nbsp; She’s got Republican backing.&nbsp; Will the President agree to invite her to the White House, listen to her ideas and incorporate them somehow?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President proposed an immigration bill on his first day in office, and certainly he’s eager to work with anybody who wants to put in place compr- &#8212; immigration reform policies that would create a safer system, a more effective system, a more humane system at the border.&nbsp; I’m not familiar with all of the specific details, but certainly we engage with a range of members about their policies.<br><br>Let me just do one last one here.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to ask for an update on how many COVID-19 rapid tests you’ve received from the President’s pledge to provide free testing.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Have been sent out?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Received to you and then sent out to Americans.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh.&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I know there’s a COVID briefing, I think tomorrow or Thursday.&nbsp; Let me check with them and see.&nbsp; I don’t have the numbers in front of me, but I can see if they’re in a position to provide an update on that.<br><br>Okay, everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Olympics &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; I think we’ve got to wrap up, but more tomorrow.&nbsp; Let’s do this again.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you finally take a question on Africa?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m often answering questions on Africa.&nbsp; I’m happy to do some more tomorrow.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We didn’t (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll look forward to talking to all of you tomorrow.&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>3:40 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
