<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:13:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>National Security Memorandum on The President’s Intelligence&#160;Priorities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/national-security-memorandum-on-the-presidents-intelligence-priorities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NATIONAL SECURITY MEMORANDUM/NSM-12 MEMORANDUM FOR THE VICE PRESIDENT              THE SECRETARY OF STATE              THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY              THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE              THE ATTORNEY GENERAL              THE SECRETARY OF COMMERCE              THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY              THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY              THE DIRECTOR OF THE OFFICE OF MANAGEMENT AND                 BUDGET              THE UNITED STATES PERMANENT REPRESENTATIVE TO THE UNITED NATIONS             &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NATIONAL SECURITY MEMORANDUM/NSM-12</p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE VICE PRESIDENT<br>              THE SECRETARY OF STATE<br>              THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY<br>              THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE<br>              THE ATTORNEY GENERAL<br>              THE SECRETARY OF COMMERCE<br>              THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY<br>              THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY<br>              THE DIRECTOR OF THE OFFICE OF MANAGEMENT AND<br>                 BUDGET<br>              THE UNITED STATES PERMANENT REPRESENTATIVE TO THE UNITED NATIONS<br>              THE DIRECTOR OF NATIONAL INTELLIGENCE<br>              THE DIRECTOR OF THE CENTRAL INTELLIGENCE<br>                 AGENCY<br>              THE CHAIRMAN OF THE JOINT CHIEFS OF STAFF<br>              THE DIRECTOR OF THE FEDERAL BUREAU OF<br>                 INVESTIGATION</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President&#8217;s Intelligence Priorities</p>



<p>The collection and analysis of timely and accurate intelligence is essential to our national security, foreign policy, law enforcement, and defense, and is critical to protecting and advancing the United States&#8217; vital interests.&nbsp; Global challenges posed by nation states and transnational threats alike demand the Intelligence Community (IC) use its resources in a coordinated manner that aligns with and is responsive to the&nbsp;President&#8217;s overall priorities and direction.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Section 1.&nbsp; President&#8217;s Intelligence Priorities. &nbsp;The President&#8217;s Intelligence Priorities (PIP) will continue to serve&nbsp;as the President&#8217;s primary mechanism for identifying and providing guidance to the IC on the intelligence topics and issues of highest importance.&nbsp; The PIP should inform the IC&#8217;s budgetary, personnel, and other resource allocations to ensure collection and analysis of intelligence that provides insights, warning, or other illuminating information on the priorities contained therein.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sec. 2.&nbsp; Process.&nbsp; Due to the evolving nature of the challenges we face as a Nation, I direct the following process to govern the development and execution of the PIP and ensure that it remains current and instructive:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The National Security Council (NSC) Deputies Committee, as described in NSM-2 or a successor directive, shall convene not less than every 2 years to update the PIP and recommend its approval by the President.&nbsp; Should there be a lack of consensus among the Deputies, the NSC Principals Committee shall review the PIP and recommend its approval by the President.&nbsp; Any lack of consensus among the NSC Principals Committee shall be&nbsp;presented to the President for decision.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b)&nbsp; The NSC staff will facilitate this review through a Restricted Interagency Policy Committee process, as necessary.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (c)&nbsp; The Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI), in close consultation with NSC staff, shall further establish and manage a robust National Intelligence Priorities Framework (NIPF) process which responds to the PIP and ensures that both the IC and additional departments and agencies that require intelligence are represented in the process of developing priorities.&nbsp; The ODNI shall also evaluate, on an ongoing basis, the IC&#8217;s responsiveness to the designated priorities within the PIP.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (d)&nbsp; The Director of National Intelligence (DNI) shall work&nbsp;with&nbsp;IC department and agency heads to ensure proper implementation of the PIP so that the President, through the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs (APNSA), is adequately informed of any challenges related to implementation.&nbsp; In response to emerging threats or crisis events, the DNI, in consultation with the APNSA, may increase the priority of any item within the NIPF to a Priority 1 for period(s) not to exceed 180 days each.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sec. 3.&nbsp; Definition.&nbsp; As used in this memorandum, the term&nbsp;&#8220;Intelligence Community&#8221; has the meaning specified in the&nbsp;National Security Act of 1947, as amended, and Executive Order&nbsp;12333, as amended.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sec. 4.&nbsp; Revocation.&nbsp; This memorandum supersedes National Security Presidential Directive/NSPD-26, which is hereby revoked.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden and President Lopez Obrador Joint&#160;Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/president-biden-and-president-lopez-obrador-joint-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 22:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States and Mexico affirm our broad and deep cooperation and commitment to building a more prosperous and secure future for the people of North America.&#160; As we face unprecedented global and regional challenges that require the concerted efforts of both our nations, we uphold democracy, inclusive growth, transparency, rule of law, and human&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States and Mexico affirm our broad and deep cooperation and commitment to building a more prosperous and secure future for the people of North America.&nbsp; As we face unprecedented global and regional challenges that require the concerted efforts of both our nations, we uphold democracy, inclusive growth, transparency, rule of law, and human rights as core values that underpin our shared security and prosperity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States and Mexico, together with Canada, represent an economic powerhouse.&nbsp; The foundation of North American competitiveness is the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement and we reaffirm our commitment to its full implementation for the benefit of working families, including by fully upholding its labor provisions and actively collaborating with stakeholders in the private sector and civil society.&nbsp; Through active coordination of our economic policies, we will make our supply chains more resilient and expand production in North America.&nbsp; We look forward to working on this and other relevant issues at the 10<sup>th</sup> North American Leaders Summit (NALS), which will take place in Mexico at the end of the year.</p>



<p>Increasing inflation impacts the wellbeing of families in both our countries, and requires strong, immediate, and concerted action.&nbsp; That is why we have committed to jointly combat inflation by accelerating the facilitation of bilateral trade and reducing trade costs.&nbsp; The United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement enhances the free flow of goods without barriers, which promotes innovation that boosts productivity and increases resilience, helping both countries fight inflation and supporting families.&nbsp; As part of joint efforts to improve food security, Mexico plans to purchase up to 20,000 tons of milk powder from the United States to assist Mexican families in rural and urban communities.&nbsp; In addition, Mexico will buy up to one million tons of fertilizer (ammonium sulfate) from the United States to distribute to subsistence farmers and continue to buy animal feed to assist small producers.</p>



<p><a></a>Borders that are more resilient, more efficient, and safer, will enhance our shared commerce.&nbsp; We are committed like never before to completing a multi-year joint U.S.-Mexico border infrastructure modernization effort for projects along the 2,000-mile border.&nbsp; The joint effort seeks to align priorities, unite border communities, and make the flow of commerce and people more secure and efficient.&nbsp; President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law includes $3.4 billion to undertake 26 major construction and modernization projects at land ports of entry on the northern and southern border.&nbsp; These land port modernization projects will create good-paying local jobs, bolster safety and security, and make the economy more resilient to supply chain challenges – all while serving as models for sustainability and innovation.&nbsp; Mexico has committed to invest $1.5 billion on border infrastructure between 2022 and 2024.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a></a>The next U.S.-Mexico High Level Economic Dialogue (HLED) in September will focus on strengthening mechanisms to create more secure and efficient corridors for trade and commerce, foster an environment that encourages investment to help generate more and better jobs for our people in both countries.&nbsp; We confirm our efforts to create a more inclusive workforce that is better educated, more competitive, and better trained to meet the needs of the 21<sup>st</sup> Century economy. We reiterate our commitment to conduct outreach to understand stakeholder considerations to increase investment and bolster supply chain resilience, specifically on strategic sectors like semiconductors and information and communication technologies.&nbsp; We will focus our development efforts on climate solutions and the development of southern Mexico, with its vast human potential and important opportunities for commerce, conservation, and clean energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Facing the shared challenges of climate change, we resolve to promote a business environment that advances a greener, cleaner North America, acknowledging the importance of investing in and promoting renewable sources of energy.&nbsp; We commit to tackle methane emissions from oil and gas and other sectors, accelerate the transition to zero-emission vehicles, and deepen our efforts to seek nature-based solutions, enabling our two countries to become global leaders in clean energies and actions to combat climate change.&nbsp; In support of the Global Methane Pledge and Global Methane Pledge Energy Pathway, Mexico and Pemex, in cooperation with the U.S., will develop an implementation plan to eliminate routine flaring and venting across onshore and offshore oil and gas operations and identify priority projects for investment.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><a></a>Through the Bicentennial Framework for Security, Public Health, and Safe Communities, we reaffirmed our commitment to work together to address major security issues affecting our nations, including the challenges of fentanyl, arms trafficking, and human smuggling, and to reduce levels of drug abuse and addiction.&nbsp; We committed to deepen our cooperation to combat transnational criminal organizations that foment violence in both our countries.&nbsp; We reaffirmed the robust operational efforts between law enforcement agencies to address these paramount security efforts.&nbsp; We pledged to establish a U.S.-Mexico operational task force to disrupt the flow of fentanyl into our countries.</p>



<p>Building on the commitments at the Summit of the Americas made by twenty-one countries in the hemisphere pursuant to the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection, we are taking immediate and coordinated steps to manage the flows of migrants arriving into our countries.&nbsp; We have joined efforts to address the underlying economic and security drivers of migration and, recognizing that development must be at the center of all migration policies, we will accelerate and expand international cooperation programs focused on the most marginalized communities. At the same time, we will maintain strong border enforcement policies while ensuring full protection of human rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a></a>The United States and Mexico reaffirmed our commitment to launch a bilateral working group on labor migration pathways and worker protections.&nbsp; We will work to promote greater worker protections as part of a labor mobility strategy for migrant workers who seek access to legal pathways. Mexico and the United States will also convene a working group to strengthen our cross-border response to child migration, a phenomenon that has significantly impacted both of our countries and puts youth in unnecessary peril.&nbsp; We also reaffirm our pledge to improve economic and social conditions throughout the region, creating dignified job opportunities as viable alternatives for potential migrants, and helping tackle the root causes of migration across the Americas.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The tragic deaths of migrants at the hands of human smugglers in San Antonio further strengthens our determination to go after the multi-billion-dollar criminal smuggling industry preying on migrants and increase our efforts to address the root causes of migration.  The Departments of Justice and Homeland Security and Mexico’s Attorney General’s Office have coordinated to arrest and prosecute those who endanger the lives of vulnerable migrants, including through the work of Joint Task Force Alpha and its Mexican partners.   This year our countries will celebrate 200 years of formal diplomatic relations.  As neighbors, friends, and family, we are united as two nations that share one future. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the Pacific Islands&#160;Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/12/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-pacific-islands-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 22:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 5:40 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Mr. Prime Minister.  It is my honor to join you, and thank you for inviting me to participate in this gathering. Prime ministers and presidents, Mr. Secretary General, distinguished guests, I am honored to be able to be with you today, virtually&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>South Court Auditorium<br><em>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></em></p>



<p>5:40 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Mr. Prime Minister.  It is my honor to join you, and thank you for inviting me to participate in this gathering.<br> <br>Prime ministers and presidents, Mr. Secretary General, distinguished guests, I am honored to be able to be with you today, virtually though it may be.<br> <br>The history and the future of the Pacific Islands and the United States are inextricably linked.<br> <br>We have historic bonds going back generations, and shared fights for freedom and for liberty.<br> <br>We share deep ties between our people.  And we are proud in the United States that there are 1.4 million people here that have Pacific Islander heritage, many of whom reside in my home state of California <br> <br>And as a daughter of California, I know firsthand the incredible contributions Pacific Islanders have made to our culture and to our country.  And we celebrate them, of course, as an integral part of the American story.<br> <br>The United States is a proud Pacific nation and has an enduring commitment to the Pacific Islands, which is why President Joe Biden and I seek to strengthen our partnership with you.<br> <br>We recognize that in recent years, the Pacific Islands may not have received the diplomatic attention and support that you deserve.  So today I am here to tell you directly: We are going to change that.<br> <br>Last year, President Biden was the first United States President to address this forum.  Secretary of State Blinken traveled to Fiji this year and launched our Indo-Pacific Strategy.  And in the months and years ahead, we plan to build on this foundation.<br> <br>We will significantly deepen our engagement in the Pacific Islands.  We will embark on a new chapter in our partnership &#8212; a chapter with increased American presence where we commit to work with you in the short and long term to take on the most pressing issues that you face.<br> <br>In recent months, we have discussed many of these issues with you.  We have consulted extensively and candidly.  The result is a series of actions that are responsive to your priorities and, we believe, will facilitate our engagement moving forward.<br> <br>To start, the United States will launch the process to establish two new embassies in the region: one in Tonga, one in Kiribati.  We will also appoint the first-ever United States Envoy to the Pacific Islands Forum.  We will return Peace Corps volunteers to the region.  And USAID is taking steps to expand its footprint to include re-establishing a regional mission in Suva, Fiji.<br> <br>All of these steps will enable us to increase our engagement, and develop and deliver concrete results.<br> <br>Today, I am also pleased to announce that we plan to triple U.S. funding for economic development and ocean resilience for the Pacific Islands.<br> <br>We will request from the United States Congress an increase from $21 million per year to $60 million per year for the next 10 years.  Sixty million dollars per year for the next 10 years.<br> <br>These funds will help strengthen climate resilience; invest in marine planning and conservation; and combat illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and enhance maritime security.<br> <br>I heard you speak of the South Pacific Tuna Treaty.  Regarding that treaty, we do believe it is a cornerstone of our political and economic cooperation, and we look forward to concluding negotiations.<br> <br>I want to particularly thank Monica Medina, our Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs, for her work on this issue and her leadership.  She is with you in Fiji today.<br> <br>President Biden and I consider our relationship with all of you to be a true partnership and a friendship based on mutual respect, mutual trust, and mutual benefit.<br> <br>We will engage transparently and constructively, which means we will listen, collaborate, and coordinate at every step of the way.  We will also work to empower a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum, which will strengthen your voice on the world stage as we continue to work together.<br><br>We will also better coordinate our efforts with allies and partners.  And to do that end, we recently launched the Partners in the Blue Pacific, which includes Australia, Japan, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, and, of course, the United States.<br> <br>All of this work recognizes that our partnership with the Pacific Islands spans a wide range of issues.<br> <br>With respect to the climate crisis, for example, you are on the frontlines of an existential crisis for our entire planet.  But you are on the frontlines, and the world’s emissions have an outsized impact on your nations.<br> <br>The evidence, of course, is that sea levels are rising.  The coral reefs that protect your islands and foster fisheries are bleaching.   And ocean warming is accelerating.<br> <br>This is why, as we work with the world to reduce emissions, we will continue to partner with you to build resilience, support adaptation, mobilize climate finance, and ensure sustainability of fisheries and marine resources.<br> <br>We also intend to expand our overall economic relationship with you.<br> <br>As part of that, we will pursue infrastructure projects that are sustainable, high quality, climate friendly, and, very importantly, that do not result in insurmountable debt.<br> <br>We will continue to stand with you to address the COVID-19 pandemic and work with you to prepare for the next one.<br> <br>We will also continue our leadership combatting illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing, because we know that it devastates fisheries and coastal states like yours.<br> <br>We also want to build on our existing work together with regard to food security, with regard to maritime security, education, and disaster relief. <br> <br>All of this work together presents an extensive agenda, but each of these issues is incredibly important to this region and to the United States.<br><br>And there is one last principle that I believe must guide our work.<br> <br>In this region and around the world, the United States believes it is important to strengthen the international rules-based order &#8212; to defend it, to promote it, and to build on it.<br> <br>These international rules and norms have brought peace and stability to the Pacific for more than 75 years &#8212; principles that importantly state that the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states must be respected; principles that allow all states, big and small, to conduct their affairs free from aggression or coercion. <br> <br>At a time when we see bad actors seeking to undermine the rules-based order, we must stand united.<br> <br>We must remind ourselves that upholding a system of laws, institutions, and common understandings &#8212; well, this is how we ensure stability and, indeed, prosperity around the world. <br> <br>We will continue to work with all of you, and all of our partners and allies, to craft new rules and norms for future frontiers grounded in our shared values of openness, transparency, and fairness.<br>All of us convened here, we &#8212; we recognize there is so much we can do together.  We have a strong foundation.  And we will build on this and embark on a new chapter, all in the spirit of partnership, friendship, and respect.<br> <br>President Joe Biden, myself, and our entire administration look forward to working with you as we chart our shared path together.<br> <br>This gathering is critically important to the United States.  And so I thank you again for the opportunity to address you and to be with you.  And I thank you. <br> <br><br>                              END                 5:50 P.M. EDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-73/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 22:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57305</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Cindy K. Chung, of Pennsylvania, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Third Circuit, vice D. Brooks Smith, retired. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Kelley Brisbon Hodge, of Pennsylvania, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania, vice Petrese B. Tucker, retired. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Kai N. Scott, of Pennsylvania, to be United States District&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Cindy K. Chung, of Pennsylvania, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Third Circuit, vice D. Brooks Smith, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kelley Brisbon Hodge, of Pennsylvania, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania, vice Petrese B. Tucker, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kai N. Scott, of Pennsylvania, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania, vice C. Darnell Jones II, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mia Roberts Perez, of Pennsylvania, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania, vice Timothy J. Savage, retired.</p>



<p>     John Frank Murphy, of Pennsylvania, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania, vice Lawrence F. Stengel, retired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: White&#160;House Announces over $40 Billion in American Rescue Plan Investments in Our Workforce – With More&#160;Coming</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/fact-sheet-white-house-announces-over-40-billion-in-american-rescue-plan-investments-in-our-workforce-with-more-coming/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris to deliver remarks at White House Summit and reinforce call for state and local leaders to invest American Rescue Plan funds to help more Americans secure good-paying jobs On Wednesday, the White House will announce that over $40 Billion in American Rescue Plan funds have been committed to strengthening and expanding&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>Vice President Kamala Harris to deliver remarks at White House Summit and reinforce call for state and local leaders to invest American Rescue Plan funds to help more Americans secure good-paying jobs</em></p>



<p>On Wednesday, the White House will announce that <strong><u>over $40 Billion in American Rescue Plan funds have been committed to strengthening and expanding our workforce</u></strong>. White House officials will highlight top American Rescue Plan workforce best practices from Governors, Mayors, and County Leaders across the country, and call on more government officials and private sector leaders to expand investments in our workforce. Vice President Kamala Harris will deliver remarks kicking off a half-day White House Summit. Since passage of the law, states, localities, community colleges, and local organizations have leveraged American Rescue Plan resources to deliver training, expand career paths, encourage more Registered Apprenticeships, provide retention and hiring bonuses in critical industries, and power efforts to help underserved Americans and those who face barriers to employment secure good jobs. These investments in the workforce – along with the American Rescue Plan’s direct payroll support that has saved or restored jobs across a broad set of industries – have contributed to a record 9 Million jobs added since President Biden took office in the fastest and strongest jobs recovery in American history.</p>



<p>The half-day White House Summit on the American Rescue Plan and the Workforce will feature remarks by Vice President Harris and Secretary of Labor Marty Walsh, a session on state American Rescue Plan workforce investments with North Carolina Governor Roy Cooper and Pennsylvania Governor Tom Wolf, as well as panels with Mayors, County Leaders, and Labor and Community Leaders on their model American Rescue Plan workforce programs. The Summit will focus on three major areas of American Rescue Plan investment:</p>



<p><strong>1. Building a Diverse and Skilled Infrastructure Workforce:</strong><strong> </strong>President Biden and Vice President Harris have launched the Administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-launches-the-talent-pipeline-challenge-supporting-employer-investments-in-equitable-workforce-development-for-infrastructure-jobs/">Infrastructure Talent Pipeline Challenge</a> to encourage immediate partnerships by the public and private sectors to ensure we have the diverse and strong workforce needed to help rebuild our infrastructure and supply chains here at home with the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. Today’s session will focus on innovative programs to meet this challenge like the DC Infrastructure Academy, with a special focus on Pre-Apprenticeship programs funded by the American Rescue Plan. Pre-Apprenticeship programs play a critical role in diversifying the talent pipeline by training, placing, and retaining workers through Registered Apprenticeships – which the North America’s Building Trades Unions (NABTU) has cited as having a return on investment for employers of as much as $3 for every $1 invested. The session will feature:</p>



<ul><li><em>Washington (DC) Mayor Muriel Bowser</em></li><li><em>Louisville (KY) Mayor Greg Fischer</em></li><li><em>Los Angeles County (CA) Supervisor Holly Mitchell</em></li><li><em>Franklin County (OH) Commissioner John O’Grady</em></li><li><em>NABTU Special Assistant to the President Melissa Wells</em></li></ul>



<p><strong>2. Strengthening Our Care and Public Health Workforce</strong><strong>: </strong>The pandemic exposed the fragility and importance of our care economy. As part of an unprecedented commitment to a stronger care workforce, the American Rescue Plan contains significant investments in public health and the care economy that will help provide better pay and career opportunities for care workers and make it easier for workers with child and elder care responsibilities to join and stay in the workforce. U.S. prime-age labor force participation has fallen behind that of its competitors, in part due to lack of family friendly policies. Studies show that access to care can be an important determinant of whether workers are able to join or remain in the labor force. Millions of families rely on paid child and elder care to work, while millions more struggle to afford or find available care. The demand for child and elder care remains high and will only grow, with a projected need for over a million additional home health care workers over the next decade. Studies have shown that quality pathways for nursing aides leads to better outcomes for patients and workers. The American Rescue Plan is helping deliver supports for quality pathways for these essential jobs.The session will feature: &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><em>Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration Carole Johnson</em></li><li><em>Erie (NY) County Executive Mark Poloncarz</em></li><li><em>Ramsey County (MN) Commissioner Mary Jo McGuire</em></li><li><em>Manchester (NH) Mayor Joyce Craig</em></li><li><em>Director of the Communities RISE Together Initiative at the Public Health Institute, Dr. Somava Saha</em></li><li><em>SEIU Secretary-Treasurer April Verrett</em></li></ul>



<p><strong>3. Expanding Access to the Workforce for Underserved Populations</strong><strong>: </strong>American Rescue Plan funds are being used to recruit more Americans facing barriers to employment – homelessness, disability, prior criminal justice involvement – and giving them pathways into the workforce. More than 600,000 people leave prison every year and confront significant challenges in accessing and sustaining stable, meaningful employment – a 2018 study estimated that formerly incarcerated individuals experience an unemployment rate of over 27 percent, exponentially higher than the overall national unemployment rate. Investments in expanding access to the workforce strengthen our economy by increasing labor force participation and tapping into the potential of more Americans, and research shows that certain programs – such as comprehensive reentry programs and summer youth employment programs – can significantly reduce crime. The session will feature:</p>



<ul><li><em>Harris County (TX) Commissioner Adrian Garcia</em></li><li><em>Memphis (TN) Mayor Jim Strickland</em></li><li><em>Employ Milwaukee CEO Chytania Brown</em></li><li><em>WRTP Big Step President Lindsay Blumer</em></li></ul>



<p><strong>To date, the Administration has worked with states, localities, and other American Rescue Plan recipients to identify over $40 Billion in </strong><strong>American Rescue Plan</strong><strong> funds being utilized to strengthen and expand our workforce:</strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Over $13 Billion in American Rescue Plan Workforce Investments Committed or Proposed by Over 1,000+ State, Local, Tribal, and Territorial Governments.</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Over $9 Billion in State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds committed or proposed investments in workforce programs.</u></strong> This includes hundreds of new workforce development and retention programs, including innovative partnerships with labor groups and other organizations to train and support a diverse workforce for good-paying jobs as well as premium pay programs for essential workers.</li><li><strong><u>Over $2 Billion in Child Care Stabilization state grants used to increase compensation for child care workers, strengthening workforce development and retention. </u></strong>States have directed or incentivized a commitment of at least $2 Billion from Child Care Stabilization program grants delivered to child care workers in the form of higher pay, hiring or retention bonuses, or other expanded benefits to date — reducing turnover, attracting new workers, and improving the quality, affordability, and availability of care options that enable parents to work.</li><li><strong><u>$2 Billion in Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) grants to fund the public health workforce.</u></strong><strong> </strong>Emergency funding for public health departments is expected to add thousands of new positions, including 2,400 new school health staff.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Over $16 Billion in Medicaid and Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) Funds for the Care and Healthcare Workforce.</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Over $9 Billion of Home and Community Based Services (HCBS) funds proposed for workforce.</u></strong> These include state plans to increase the pay and benefits of direct support professionals, train workers, and recruit, retain, and expand the workforce to meet the needs of Americans on HCBS waitlists and family caregivers.</li><li><strong><u>Over $7 Billion in health workforce investments funded by HHS programs.</u></strong><strong> </strong>These funds support staffing needs to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic, as well as longer-term investments to strengthen the health workforce and build capacity. These historic investments are recruiting, training, and retaining tens of thousands of additional public health workers over the next several years, including the first-ever Public Health AmeriCorps program which will train a new generation of public health leaders and includes 3,000 corps members in its first year.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Over $12 Billion in American Rescue Plan Education Funds to Strengthen the K-12 Educator Workforce and Expand Workforce Credentials.</u></strong><strong></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Over $7 Billion in Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief Funding to keep schools open safely, combat learning loss, and address mental health are planned to be spent on recruiting, retaining, and training school staff</u></strong>. Districts are expected to spend other funds on workforce efforts, including career and technical education that will help students succeed in the workforce. States across the country are also using a portion of funds to build the pipeline of education workers and provide career and technical education. Additional funds are supporting the hiring and the avoiding of lay-offs of school staff.</li><li><strong><u>At least $5 Billion to help students stay on track to graduate college and enter the workforce with additional credentials.</u></strong> The American Rescue Plan’s Higher Education Emergency Relief Fund provided nearly $40 Billion to colleges and their students, including to support learning and career training. Community colleges received $10 Billion, with roughly $5 Billion of these funds provided directly to students, allowing them to stay on track to graduate and enter the workforce with additional qualifications.</li></ul>



<p>In addition to investments outlined above, <strong><u>over $3 billion in additional, competitively awarded American Rescue Plan funding will be invested in the coming months</u></strong>, including:</p>



<ul><li>In 2022, CDC will award $3 billion through a new, first of its kind American Rescue Plan-funded grant program to strengthen the future public health workforce, including offering community health workers and others hired for COVID-19 response support in continuing their careers as public health professionals beyond the pandemic.</li><li>The Economic Development Administration will announce 25-50 grants through the $500 million Good Jobs Challenge to build and strengthen workforce systems that bring together employers and other key entities to train workers with in-demand skills that lead to good-paying jobs.</li></ul>



<p>__</p>



<p><strong>Summaries of American Rescue Plan Best Practices in Workforce Investments Highlighted by State and Local Leaders at White House Summit<a></a></strong></p>



<p><strong>1. North Carolina is committing American Rescue Plan funds to address the barriers holding back workers and expand opportunities for careers in high-growth fields offering good wages</strong><strong>.</strong> Governor Roy Cooper will explain that North Carolina is leading the way with innovative investments to increase compensation for care economy workers and establish and expand work-based learning opportunities in critical sectors. To improve recruitment and retention in care fields, the state is leveraging American Rescue Plan Child Care Stabilization program grants to incentivize and fund increased compensation for tens of thousands of child care workers in the state – reducing turnover and increasing the strength of the workforce – and investing over $200 Million annually utilizing American Rescue Plan-enhanced Home and Community Based Services funding to increase wages for direct care workers. North Carolina is also using American Rescue Plan resources to establish a new Direct Care Jobs Innovation Fund that will support initiatives that improve recruitment and retention among the direct care workforce, including training opportunities and workforce supports. Further, the state is investing American Rescue Plan funds in key workforce efforts, including establishing work-based learning programs supporting small businesses, helping individuals who are justice-involved or in substance use recovery enter the workforce, as well as filling critical infrastructure and supply chain jobs by investing in expanding truck driver training, apprenticeships in high-demand fields, and a work-based learning program in the construction trades across the NC Community College System.</p>



<p><strong>2. P</strong><strong>ennsylvania is delivering historic support to its care and healthcare workforce with American Rescue Plan funds. </strong>Governor Tom Wolf will discuss how the state is investing in expanded training and credentialing opportunities for direct care workers across the state, improving retention and quality of care. Using American Rescue Plan-enhanced Home and Community Based Services funds, these initiatives include increasing behavioral health provider rates to support state staff training, education, and recruitment, as well as creating an online education and training portal to strengthen supports to nursing professionals. The state is also delivering $225 Million statewide for healthcare retention and recruitment efforts, including payments to direct care staff as well as expanding a high-demand nurse loan forgiveness program. In addition, the state is providing nearly $190 Million through the American Rescue Plan to support retention bonuses, personnel development, and recruitment efforts for its child care workforce.<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Building a Diverse and Skilled Infrastructure Workforce</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>1. Washington, DC is expanding its DC Infrastructure Academy to fill growing DC infrastructure jobs</strong>. Mayor Muriel Bowser will describe the DC Infrastructure Academy, which is a key initiative of her administration, launched in 2018 to meet the need for skilled infrastructure professionals in the District. The school coordinates, trains, screens, and recruits residents to fulfill the needs of the DC infrastructure industry, matching graduates to infrastructure jobs with leading companies in this high-demand field. The city is investing over $4 Million to expand the program in preparation for the coming demand for infrastructure workers as a result of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br><br></p>



<p><strong>2. Los Angeles County, CA is investing $10 Million to bolster High Road Training Partnerships (HRTP) and its Worker Equity Fund</strong><strong>.&nbsp;</strong>Supervisor Holly Mitchell will describe LA County’s American Rescue Plan investment to enhance training programs in high-demand sectors such as construction, transportation and warehousing, manufacturing, technology, and more with an American Rescue Plan investment in High Road Training Partnerships. Bringing together industry, education and training providers, labor, and community groups, HRTPs focus on building long-term career pathways utilizing pre-apprenticeships and apprenticeships, provide family-sustaining wages, and require deep collaboration between employers, workers, education partners, and the workforce system. The pre-apprenticeship program deploys the Los Angeles-Orange County Building Trades Council’s Multi-Craft Core Curriculum and spans 8-10 weeks, and aims to enroll at least 480 individuals in all HRTPs with at least 350 individuals hired in permanent employment. This is part of Los Angeles County’s larger workforce development plan, which includes reducing workforce barriers for youth, enhancing job placement programming for justice-involved individuals and those experiencing homelessness, rapid re-employment, as well as a Worker Equity Fund that provides supportive services and flexible cash assistance for participants in the county’s workforce programs to mitigate barriers to successful participation.</p>



<p><strong>3. Franklin County, OH is committing over $11 Million in State and Local funds to support a number of job training assistance programs, including over $2 Million toward the Building Futures Pre-Apprenticeship Program. </strong>Commissioner John O’Grady will explain the county’s investment in Building Futures, a 12-week program designed to help low-income Franklin County residents pursue careers in the skilled construction trades, including electrical work, iron work, carpentry, painting, plumbing, and more, with a focus on recruiting populations that have been historically underrepresented in the trades. More than half of program graduates were TANF-eligible when they first enrolled. Most graduates have gone on to become apprentices and are earning an average wage of over $22 per hour plus benefits – with some earning as much as $30 and $40 an hour. The program, which was developed in partnership with the Columbus/Central Ohio Building and Construction Trades Council, Columbus NAACP, and the Columbus Urban League, provides both “hard skills” training, including safety certification and trade-specific instruction, as well as “soft skills” training, including interpersonal skills and financial literacy, as well as a weekly $250 stipend. Participants are also eligible to receive supportive services offered through Building Futures in average amounts of $1,500-$2,500, depending on a person’s individual needs, to help address barriers like transportation, housing, childcare, and more. At the end of each cohort, participants complete an entrance assessment to progress directly into a Building Trades apprenticeship program. The county also runs an American Rescue Plan-funded Driving Futures program, which fills critically needed positions as licensed drivers in Central Ohio’s construction industry.</p>



<p><strong>4. Louisville, KY is proposing an expansion of its successful Kentuckiana Builds construction program</strong><strong>.</strong> Mayor Greg Fischer will explain how he is answering the President’s call to action on the Talent Pipeline Challenge by proposing American Rescue Plan funds be deployed to expand the city’s pre-apprenticeship program, Kentuckiana Builds. The program is run by the Louisville Urban League in partnership with the Carpenters Union. The program helps diverse residents successfully complete a 6-week construction training program, which then provides them access to union apprenticeships in partnership with the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers and the Carpenters Union, as well as other basic construction roles. Since its inception, over 350 individuals have graduated from the program into good construction jobs. The proposed American Rescue Plan investment would enable the Kentuckiana Builds pre-apprenticeship program to serve additional participants. Beyond this proposed investment, Louisville has made a number of American Rescue Plan-funded investments in workforce, including a comprehensive reentry program for formerly incarcerated individuals.</p>



<p><strong>5. North America’s Building Trades Unions (NABTU) is working with state and local leaders to promote American Rescue Plan-funded Pre-Apprenticeship Programs as a critical pathway to Registered Apprenticeship Programs that will help fill the increased workforce needs of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. </strong>NABTU Special Assistant to the President Melissa Wells will describe how NABTU has closely partnered with state and local governments, construction industry employers, and non-profit organizations to invest American Rescue Plan funds in their Pre-Apprenticeship programs known as Apprenticeship Readiness Programs. This builds on NABTU&#8217;s work to create over 190 Apprenticeship Readiness Programs across the country in the last fifteen years, which are a pipeline to multi-year Registered Apprenticeship programs. These programs specifically focus on recruiting and training women, people of color, transitioning veterans, and the formerly incarcerated. NABTU operates over 1,600 Registered Apprenticeship training centers in the United States and graduates at least 50,000 apprentices each year &#8212; with over 80,000 graduated in 2019 alone.<br><br></p>



<p><strong><u>Strengthening Our Care and Public Health Workforce<br><br></u></strong></p>



<p><strong>1. Ramsey County, MN is supporting its care workforce through a $1 Million Public Health Career Pathways program and addressing a shortage of quality child care programs by offering new incentives and supports. </strong>Commissioner Mary Jo McGuire will describe Ramsey County’s Public Health Career Pathways program, which will increase the public health workforce and lift up low wage earners by offering careers as a registered nurse or community health worker. Selection priority is given to those who live in Ramsey County, are single parents, receiving public assistance, and/or are a member of an underrepresented group in the public health workforce. The program provides: college preparatory coaching and mentoring; reimbursement of tuition, expenses for transportation and/or child care, and other related academic costs; wages to allow participants to enroll full-time; and paid work time to complete coursework. To bolster the child care workforce, Ramsey County is providing bonuses of $1,000 per year and free professional development training to help providers remain open. Additionally, the county is recruiting additional child care educators in the neighborhoods most affected by the child care shortages, offering the training required to achieve a Child Development Associate credential at no cost. Participants will also receive mentoring support provided by experienced child care educators who currently operate high-quality programs and other necessary support for early childhood educators looking to open child care programs.</p>



<p><strong>2. Erie County, NY used $1.6 Million in American Rescue Plan funds to launch a Healthcare Careers Program</strong><strong>.</strong> County Executive Mark Poloncarz will explain that the county is providing educational grants for training in high-demand healthcare occupations, such of up to $10,000 per student. Students must be enrolled in an approved occupational program, meet certain income requirements, and must currently earn less than $25 per hour. Students enrolled in the program also receive a transportation allowance, child care assistance, and access to an emergency fund of up to $500 for emergencies. Since the program began in October 2021, more than 320 residents have already enrolled in programs offered by the County’s training partners (including Erie 1 BOCES, Trocaire College, D’Youville University, SUNY Erie and Villa Maria College). Given the program’s success so far, the county has dedicated additional funding to sustain and expand the program.</p>



<p><strong>3. Manchester, NH is investing $6 Million in a Community Health Worker (CHW) Program</strong>. Mayor Joyce Craig will discuss the city’s investment in the CHW program. The new team is multicultural and collectively speaks 11 languages, in addition to English (Spanish, French, Nepali, Hindi, Swahili, Kinyarwanda, Kurundi, Mandinka, Fula, Wolof, and Yoruba). CHW staff are participating in a CHW Certificate program hosted by the Southern New Hampshire Area Health Education Center. The program will also be working closely with the Harvard School of Public Health to provide occupational health and safety training and technical assistance. CHW staff are proactively working with local community groups and organizations in their assigned neighborhood areas in the City to best serve neighborhood concerns and needs. As this Program is a joint effort between the Manchester Health Department and Manchester Police Department, the two Departments will be creating a structure to support linkages and coordination of efforts across public health and public safety.</p>



<p><strong>4. The Communities RISE Together initiative, supported by WE in the World and the Public Health Institute, is using American Rescue Plan funding to recruit, hire, and train Community Health Workers to work with Black, Native American, Latinx, Asian American/Pacific Islander, immigrant/migrant, and low-income older adult populations in 200+ counties across the country. </strong>Director of the Communities RISE Together Initiative at the Public Health Institute Dr. Somava Saha will describe how RISE partners train and engage vaccine ambassadors and promotoras to serve as trusted messengers and connect community members with vaccines and well-being needs, while working to address underlying drivers of health inequities.&nbsp; Together, they have reached over 44 Million people through trusted, often nontraditional, messengers and channels and connected 200,000+ Americans to vaccines and supports like food, rental assistance, and social connection.</p>



<p><strong>5. Service Employees International Union (SEIU) is mobilizing workers across the country to ensure American Rescue Plan funding for HCBS continues to improve conditions for care workers – who are 90 percent women and disproportionately women of color – and to stabilize and grow the care workforce and expand access to high-quality affordable home and community-based care. </strong>SEIU Secretary-Treasurer April Verrett will describe how SEIU and its partners are working together to ensure states are using funds to transform care work into good, union jobs that provide benefits and pay enough to support a family. This will help to create a sustainable care workforce and lift entire families and communities who are supported by care work.&nbsp; SEIU and its partners are also working with states to expand training opportunities to both help existing caregivers build additional skills and develop a pipeline of new workers.<strong></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Expanding the Workforce by Helping Americans Overcome Barriers</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>1. Memphis, TN is investing over $20 Million in workforce programs, with a focus on youth employment – particularly for disconnected youth and youth with disabilities. </strong>Mayor Jim Strickland will describe the Opportunity R3 (Rethinking, Rebuilding, Rebranding) initiative, established with American Rescue Plan funds, which provides workforce readiness training for disconnected youth ages 16-24. According to one report, the Memphis metropolitan area has among the highest number of disconnected youth in the country, with over one in five youth neither working or in school. The R3 program helps participants develop a career and education plan, and guides participants on issues including job applications and resume work, communication and other soft skills, and financial management. The program also provides broader support to participants, including assisting with opening banking accounts, and has currently seen over 80 percent of graduates stay on track on their career or educational path. Additionally, the city is using American Rescue Plan funds to pilot “I Am Included,” a program for youth with disabilities. The program helps youth between ages of 14-18 with specific disabilities – including those who are deaf and hard of hearing or visually impaired, or with specific learning disabilities and intellectual disorders – develop soft and hard skills to prepare for gainful employment and other post-high school options. Topics discussed in the program include financial literacy, personal/professional development, conflict resolution, self-advocacy, goal setting, and mental health awareness. These programs are part of Memphis’ broader investment in workforce development, which includes several other youth employment training programs. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>2. Harris County, TX is committing over $2 Million in </strong><strong>American Rescue Plan</strong><strong> funds toward Employ2Empower (E2E), a workforce program that employs unhoused individuals living in encampments.</strong><strong> </strong>Commissioner Adrian Garcia will explain how American Rescue Plan funds have enabled the E2E program to expand from a one-precinct pilot into an expanded county-wide program, which is estimated to serve 160 individuals in four separate cohorts over 12 months. The initial precinct-level pilot compensated participants at $10 per hour, and the expanded E2E program employs these individuals for up to 32 hours a week, at a pay rate of $15 per hour, while providing access to resources to meet their basic needs. The work includes graffiti removal, illegal dumping abatement, and upkeep of public properties. Participants will also work alongside previously unhoused individuals who will serve as their Peer Mentors to provide motivation and support. E2E provides steady income and workforce development training, and connects participants to a pathway to a permanent housing solution, wrap-around services, and additional benefits, including ID services. The program implementation and management utilize inputs from Career and Recovery Resources (CRR), partner organizations, and the Harris County Sheriff’s Office. By utilizing lessons learned from the pilot program, the goal is to provide a consistent stabilizing experience for program participants, who require time and intensive support to alleviate the effects of experiencing homelessness. The program is a pre-employment program intended to support individuals in graduating into higher-skilled programs and addresses racial disparities in homelessness and unemployment by reaching out to marginalized groups with 48% of participants being African American.</p>



<p><strong>3. Employ Milwaukee and WRTP|Big Step are deploying American Rescue Plan-funded worker development programs by targeting underserved communities in Wisconsin. </strong>Employ Milwaukee CEO Chytania Brown will explain how the local workforce development board, with a $5 Million American Rescue Plan grant from Wisconsin, launched a new Skillful Transitions program aimed at connecting traditionally underserved groups to jobs. The program provides an individualized assessment of skills, experience, and job readiness, and provides job readiness training, skills training, and paid work experience across a variety of sectors, including construction, manufacturing, financial services, healthcare, and more. The program conducts targeted, specialized outreach to at-risk populations, including justice-involved individuals (pre- and post-release), veterans, individuals with disabilities, and human trafficking survivors. Employ Milwaukee also provides wraparound supports and targets high-unemployment and dislocated city residents for its other American Rescue Plan-funded programs, such as a $3 Million investment by Milwaukee into lead abatement certification training – where there is an overall goal of serving a majority of people of color with a special emphasis on opportunity youth.<br><br>President Lindsay Blumer of WRTP | BIG STEP, a non-profit workforce intermediary in Wisconsin, will describe how her organization has used American Rescue Plan funds to expand the workforce in construction, manufacturing, and adjacent emerging sectors. In three programs funded by Milwaukee and Wisconsin’s American Rescue Plan dollars – which include a manufacturing high school equivalency degree joint pre-apprenticeship, after-school youth construction career exploration and hands-on training, and a community resource navigator program – the organization focuses on recruiting those who are underserved or not traditionally represented in these occupations, such as those individuals who are justice-involved, veterans and/or identify as differently abled. Critically, once enrolled, the organization provides a variety of barrier remediation and supportive services, such as food share and child care vouchers, focused mentoring and tutoring, as well as legal support, such as driver’s license recovery. The organization directly connects participants with employers for access to family-sustaining waged careers. Close to 100 percent of its participants are considered underserved or traditionally unrepresented, with about 70 percent identifying as people of color and a majority as low-income.<br><br></p>



<p><strong>APPENDIX: Additional Examples of States, Cities, Counties, and Community-Based Organizations Using American Rescue Plan Funding to Invest in Our Workforce</strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Building a Diverse and Skilled Infrastructure Workforce<br><br></u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong>Syracuse, NY is expanding access to union job opportunities to prepare the local workforce for infrastructure and other jobs.</strong> The City is investing in the Syracuse Build Pathways to Apprenticeship Program to help residents gain access to pre-apprenticeship programs and credentials in high-demand sectors, including construction, electrical mechanics, HVAC, advanced/high-tech manufacturing, commercial driving, and software development. The program will help ensure the local workforce is ready for the I-81 viaduct project and other construction projects. The program is a collaboration of the Central and Northern New York Building Trades Council, CenterState CEO, and Syracuse Build, and teaches the nationally recognized North America’s Building Trades Unions (NABTU) Multi-Craft Core Curriculum. The comprehensive apprenticeship readiness training program focuses on women, people of color and veterans, and helps them gain access to the Building Trades’ registered apprenticeship programs.</li></ol>



<ul><li><strong>Gallatin County, MT is committing $2 million to start or expand up to seven new workforce training and education programs in the high-demand trades of construction, welding and fabrication, manufacturing, and healthcare.</strong> The program, which is operated through Gallatin College Montana State University, has a goal of enrolling over 450 additional students by 2024. As an example, the construction trades program includes concrete, framing, electrical, earthwork, equipment maintenance, and HVAC-R, with the aim of meeting new project demands due to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The program will recruit locally affected residents and place students into local jobs once trained, partnering with local industry partners for development, partnerships, and placements. Further, the program will provide training that will allow students to continue working in apprenticeships or provide certificates and degrees in an accelerated approach. The program will also provide evening childcare to students while they attend classes.</li><li><strong>Vermont is building a broadband workforce. </strong>The state is leveraging a portion of their $150 million Vermont Connectivity Broadband Fund to create a training program in partnership with the Vermont Technical College and a broadband installer apprenticeship program. The program, which has already graduated three classes of early participants, is aimed at helping people with insufficient- or low-income jobs transition into higher-paying fiber-optic technician careers. The program pays students while they attend training and offers wraparound services like childcare. In addition, Vermont is making other critical investments in workforce, including through practical nurse training and providing scholarships and wraparound supports for residents economically affected by the pandemic.</li><li><strong>Maine is leveraging American Rescue Plan funds toward its goal of 30,000 clean energy jobs by 2030, including through an apprenticeship program. </strong>The state<strong> </strong>is investing $5.5 million in a Clean Energy Partnership to provide career training opportunities, including apprenticeships, in Maine’s growing clean energy sector. This is part of Maine’s goal of 30,000 clean energy jobs in the state by 2030. The funding will expand existing and develop new apprenticeship opportunities for in-demand clean energy fields, with a focus on increasing apprenticeships among under-represented communities, and convene state agencies, private-sector partners, Maine’s community colleges, and labor organizations to develop programs and tools to grow the clean energy workforce in the state. This investment is part of Maine’s overall comprehensive investment into workforce through American Rescue Plan-funded Maine Jobs &amp; Recovery Plan, which includes a general expansion of high-quality pre-apprenticeships and apprenticeships in high-priority areas, including infrastructure (construction, broadband, logistics, trades) and manufacturing. This expansion is done in collaboration with Maine’s businesses and industry associations, unions, education and training providers, and community-based organizations.</li><li><strong>Wilmington, DE is expanding its high school construction training program. </strong>The city is leveraging American Rescue Plan funds to expand their Howard High School of Technology workforce development program, which includes funding high school and adult training in construction, plumbing, HVAC, and more. The city is connecting graduates from the Howard High School training program to jobs with local employers working on local revitalization projects, and soon Bipartisan Infrastructure Law-funded infrastructure projects &#8211; helping residents train for better jobs and helping employers access the talent they need to successfully complete these government projects. The city has also committed to using their local workforce for American Rescue Plan-funded neighborhood revitalization projects.</li><li><strong>Nassau County, NY is committing $10 million in workforce development initiatives, including through apprenticeship programs for various key skilled workers needed in the construction and building trades.</strong> The initiatives will also provide entrepreneurial skills training to support new women- and minority-owned businesses, and retraining and upskilling programs through Nassau’s local colleges and universities. These programs provide both job training and job placement, and will prioritize reaching residents in communities facing higher rates of unemployment.  </li><li><strong>The Mescalero Apache Tribe</strong> is investing in a workforce development program that will focus on vocational education by providing scholarships to both Tribal citizens and current employees to obtain certificates and further education in welding, carpentry, plumbing, and electrical – all jobs critical to carry out the Tribe’s COVID-19 recovery plan.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Strengthening Our Care and Public Health Workforce</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>A. HOME AND COMMUNITY BASED CARE</strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong>Colorado is developing a standardized curriculum and training program for home care workers</strong> to establish quality standards and increase specialized qualifications tied to wage increases. The state also plans to establish a training fund that will target high demand jobs and support specialization and advancement opportunities, including in behavioral health. Separately, Colorado is spending funds for training and improving employment outcomes to support reskilling, upskilling, or next-skilling, including providing access to short-term training to obtain in-demand industry-recognized credentials. The funding will also support grants that promote innovation to improve employment outcomes for workers and outreach to underserved and disproportionately impacted populations.</li><li><strong>California will expand training opportunities for its HCBS workforce.</strong> One-time training opportunities will include learning pathways in the areas of general health and safety and caring for recipients with specific needs. Training and stipends will also be available in order to both improve care quality, address worker shortages, and prevent unnecessary institutionalization.</li><li><strong>West Virginia is increasing pay to home and community-based care workers</strong>, including through incentives such as retention bonuses, hiring bonuses, and increased benefit packages. West Virginia also plans to provide specific training for respite providers on how to assist family members with their children’s behavioral health needs and competency-based training opportunities for the state’s direct-care in-home workforce.</li><li><strong>Georgia will increase compensation for home and community-based care workers and expand training opportunities. </strong>The stateplans to use American Rescue Plan funds to strengthen existing HCBS services by increasing rates, conducting a rate study for services provided in 1915(c) waivers, and engaging in workforce development and training.&nbsp; Georgia will also expand HCBS training and workforce development programs, including collaborating with GA&#8217;s Technical College System to strengthen the Certified Nursing Assistant training program and expand provider capacity.</li></ol>



<p><strong>B. HEALTHCARE</strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong>Chicago, IL is getting people back to work and building a healthcare career ladder. </strong>The city invested $56 million to hire local vaccine ambassadors/contact tracers/ supervisors and provide them with broader healthcare training. The ‘Earn and Learn’ program is building a community-based health workforce, building the skills of residents in communities most experiencing economic hardship in the healthcare jobs we need tomorrow, while supporting critical health needs in the community today.  More than 800 individuals have been hired through this program, with 90 percent of individuals residing in community areas of high or medium economic hardship.</li><li><strong>New York City, NY is building a corps of community health workers across the city,</strong> investing $50 million in expanding their Public Health Corps of Community Health Workers. These individuals will educate New Yorkers on health matters, connecting them to essential healthcare services and enabling them to meet their health goals. The Health Corps is supporting New Yorkers at the community level in clinics and organizations serving the neighborhoods most affected by COVID-19, helping fight against the health disparities exacerbated by COVID-19.</li><li><strong>San Diego County, CA has committed almost $30 million since the start of the pandemic, utilizing an estimated $8 million in American Rescue Plan funds to develop and deploy a new comprehensive Community Health Worker (CHW) model.</strong> During the COVID-19 pandemic, the County quickly mobilized CHWs to provide tailored outreach and education to residents who have been traditionally hard to reach due to factors such as linguistic and cultural differences, geographic isolation, or historic distrust of government. As trusted messengers, CHWs are connecting communities impacted by long-standing health disparities to needed services and systems of care. Over 250 CHWs have been deployed, who speak 26 languages, and serve all six regions of San Diego County. They focused on underserved and under-immunized communities, including Black and African American, Latino, refugee, and Asian and Pacific Islander communities.</li></ol>



<ul><li><strong>Rochester, NY is launching a Healthcare Workforce Resiliency Program.</strong> The city is launching a Healthcare Workforce Resiliency Program, which provides entry level healthcare workers with employment skills training and career pathway navigation to achieve licensure and/or certification. Academic assessment services and case management, including stipends and wraparound services, will be provided throughout the program.</li><li><strong>Kansas is retaining and recruiting healthcare workers. </strong>The state is investing $50mm in hospitals across the state to help retain dwindling workforce. Each of the 118 hospitals receiving the funding can individually decide to use the funding for either premium pay or for funding a custom program designed by the facility to improve the retention of nurses and other support personnel. </li><li><strong>Connecticut</strong> <strong>is creating new public health career opportunities for both students and existing workers.</strong> These include: establishing new paid public health research assistant and internship opportunities for students pursuing a public health master’s degree; providing staff that can support workforce development and training needs within local health offices; and offering training opportunities and curriculum to expose high school and undergraduate students to public health practice careers.</li><li><strong>Family Scholar House in Kentucky plans to hire 200 part-time AmeriCorps members to provide healthcare support and services to seniors and disabled individuals in healthcare facilities across Kentucky.</strong> These AmeriCorps members will develop healthcare knowledge and complete credentialing coursework, enabling them to work in memory care, skilled nursing, assisted living, and other healthcare-related environments.</li><li><strong>DeKalb County plans to hire 16 full-time AmeriCorps members to manage and operate programs across the county. </strong>The AmeriCorps members will provide capacity, support, and increased awareness of COVID-19 testing and vaccinations to support equitable health outcomes and COVID-19 recovery in underserved communities.</li><li><strong>The Association of Asian/Pacific Community Health Organizations used American Rescue Plan funds to establish the Community Health Worker Workforce Collaborative.</strong> The Collaborative has since hired, trained, and deployed more than 250 Community Health Workers who speak over 36 Asian, Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander languages in 12 continental U.S. states and Hawai’i.</li><li><strong>Vermont Trauma, Resilience, and Equity Education (VT-TREE) Initiative at University of Vermont</strong> <strong>is developing and expanding Vermont’s behavioral health workforce</strong>. These efforts are focused on children, adolescents, and transitional age youth. VT-TREE is recruiting social workers and counselors from historically underrepresented communities to obtain a Certificate of Graduate Study in Trauma Informed and Resiliency Based Practices.</li><li><strong>Loma Linda University</strong> <strong>is using American Rescue Plan funding for trainees to develop integrated behavioral health and child clinical skills. </strong>The training program teaches pediatric residents and behavioral health students to collaboratively offer mental health access.</li><li><strong>Hudson Headwaters Health Network in Queensbury, NY is a community health center that has used American Rescue Plan funds to strengthen its workforce. </strong>These efforts include<strong> </strong>recruitment and retention bonuses to maintain the existing healthcare workforce, and to recruit new providers in specialty areas like rheumatology and endocrinology. The health center has also used this funding for training in a variety of areas including customer service and de-escalation, wellness, and change management and leadership. </li></ul>



<p><strong>C. HISTORIC SUPPORT FOR CHILD CARE WORKERS</strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong>Maine is providing $2,400 for child care workers through monthly bonuses over the course of twelve months. </strong>Maine is requiring child care programs benefiting from American Rescue Plan Child Care Stabilization grant funds to provide at least $200 per month bonuses to an estimated 6,000 staff who directly care for children. As a result of investments of American Rescue Plan funds and other resources, including in strengthening its child care workforce, Maine has seen an increase in its licensed child care capacity since the start of the pandemic.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Michigan is delivering bonuses to more than 38,000 full- and part-time child care staff. </strong>Michigan is using American Rescue Plan funds to pay two rounds of $1,000 bonuses to full time staff members and $500 bonuses to part time staff members as part of its Child Care Stabilization program.</li><li><strong>Delaware is supporting the construction of an Early Childhood Innovation Center and expanded supports for child care professionals. </strong>Utilizing American Rescue Plan funds, Delaware is investing in the construction and launch of an Early Childhood Innovation Center at Delaware State University—a historically black, public university—that will provide career advancement opportunities for the child care workforce and expand financial support to help professionals pursue careers in early childhood education.</li><li><strong>Deschutes County, Oregon is investing in efforts to increase the supply of licensed child care workers as part of an effort to make child care more readily available.</strong> Deschutes County is leveraging American Rescue Plan funds to support efforts to quickly build up the supply of child care by training 275 new workers in the field while investing in the development of new and expanded child care facilities—aiming to create an additional 500 child care spots regionally. The county is investing in a program to fast-track workers through training programs at the local community college and university, as well as efforts to make it easier for interns pursuing credentials to qualify as head teachers upon completion of their programs, and supporting the annual recruitment, advising, education and supervision of teacher candidates.</li><li><strong>The State of Alabama</strong> <strong>is awarding bonus payments to over 10,000 child care workers</strong>. With Child Care Stabilization Grant funds provided in the American Rescue Plan, Alabama is providing quarterly payments of $1,500 for full-time staff and $750 for part-time staff for up to two years.</li><li><strong>The State of Kansas is providing more than 22,000 child care workers with bonus payments of up to $2,500.</strong> Kansas is committing $53 million in American Rescue Plan funds to supporting one-time bonuses of between $750 and $2,500 to an estimated 22,650 early childhood care staff members across the state.</li></ol>



<p><strong><u>Expanding Access to the Workforce for Underserved Populations</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong>Wisconsin is funding a comprehensive worker development program, including for incarcerated individuals. </strong>The state is investing in a $125 million comprehensive workforce program to help address the state&#8217;s post-pandemic workforce needs through a competitive grant program. Awards include up to $5.7 million to deliver workforce-ready curriculum through the University of Wisconsin Prison Education Initiative (PEI) to teach employable skills to students while incarcerated and continue supporting them post-release through program completion and career placement. Further, the state is investing up to $5.6 million through Gateway Technical College to offer a 4-week pre-HSED (High School Equivalency Diploma) program, followed by a 16-week Work Ready (WR) HSED program. This program encourages a collaborative approach to addressing the biggest regional workforce challenges, training workers in high-demand fields such as healthcare and manufacturing, providing innovative credentialing options, expanding childcare, and building the entrepreneurs of tomorrow. Additionally, Wisconsin is investing in the Worker Connection Program, which helps individuals overcome systemic barriers, navigate the workforce system, and match them with employers that ultimately leads to careers with growth potential, as well as the Worker Advancement Initiative, which uses the state’s workforce development boards to help unemployed individuals find subsidized opportunities through collaborations with local employers.</li><li><strong>Detroit, Michigan is establishing a Skills For Life program:</strong> The city is committing up to $75 million toward Skills for Life, which is a training, career readiness and education program potentially targeting thousands of unemployed or underemployed Detroit residents, specifically those experiencing housing insecurity, those lacking high school diplomas and/or post-secondary credentials, returning citizens, and other populations that face barriers to employment. Skills for Life combines education and training with wrap-around support services (e.g., childcare subsidies, transportation, construction tools) to help Detroiters rebound from the COVID-19 economic shutdown. The education side of the program assists participants with measurable skills gains, high school completion/GED attainment, an industry-recognized credential, an increase in functional reading or math competency levels, and other skill- and career-building activities. The work side of the program provides direct employment, job training, and other skill- and career-building activities, assists in removing barriers to employment and advancement, and provides disconnected workers with labor market on-ramps so they may earn income while building critical skills to improve prospects for long-term employment and job retention.</li><li><strong>King County, WA is connecting individuals experiencing homelessness with jobs and housing support.</strong> The County is investing over $30 million in American Rescue Plan funds to establish a program to promote economic recovery by connecting shelter residents with County or County-supported jobs for 6-12 months, as well as providing training for private sector jobs through County partnerships. The County also connects these participants with rapid rehousing providers and career services in an effort to navigate participants toward housing and employment stability. The program is intended to support several hundreds of individuals experiencing homelessness with these services, and will undergo a quantitative program evaluation.</li><li><strong>Bridgeport, CT is investing in job training and other wraparound support for returning citizens. </strong>The city is providing over $4 million for a Second Chance Re-Entry Employment Program, working with returning citizens and formerly incarcerated individuals to provide a continuum of care. This includes providing participants with workforce development, job training and placement, housing support, medical health services, mental health services, substance abuse treatment, education services, and more. As an example, the city has partnered with Women Against Mass Incarceration, which focuses re-entry services on women who are formerly incarcerated, an often underserved community in re-entry. The city is also working with the University of Bridgeport to provide free tuition for formerly incarcerated individuals as part of an advanced manufacturing certificate program.</li><li><strong>Seattle, WA is connecting youth with opportunities in the Port of Seattle.</strong> The city is providing youth and young adults (ages 16-24), particularly those who are Black, Indigenous, people of color (BIPOC) with employment or paid internship opportunities at the Port. To reach this population, the Port subcontracts with community-based organizations embedded in and serving Seattle&#8217;s BIPOC community. In total, Seattle is investing over $6 million in workforce development initiatives to support child care workers, connect residents in economically distressed communities with construction work, and provide career navigation services and wraparound support.</li><li><strong>Baltimore, MD is expanding many workforce efforts, including critical transitional jobs program and a re-entry program.</strong> The city is investing $30 million in workforce programs, including $5.2 million to expand Hire Up, a transitional jobs program that will create at least 220 six-month positions for low-income residents paying $15 per hour. The city is also investing $8.4 million in Youth Works, allowing the program to offer jobs to young people ages 14 to 21 year-round, $8.9 million in Train Up, offering job training in the fields of biotechnology, IT, health care and business services, and $2.9 million to provide various supports (such as legal services, adult education, and financial counseling) to residents participating in Hire Up or Train Up as well as supplement wages at small, minority- and women-owned businesses that hire residents. The city iscommitting over $17 million through the Mayor’s Office of Neighborhood Safety and Engagement toward job training assistance for violence prevention, including over $12 million for re-entry services. This impact will be tracked by the number of individuals participating in the program and the number of individuals transitioned into employment upon release.</li><li><strong>Portland, OR is connecting vulnerable populations to work. </strong>The city is committing $7 million of American Rescue Plan funds toward providing paid work opportunities and rapid re-careering services for Portlanders who are houseless, at risk of eviction, affected by increased violence or crime, or otherwise negatively impacted by the pandemic. Services will address the disproportionate economic impacts COVID-19 has had on people of color and other vulnerable populations currently disconnected from the workforce. The rapid re-careering training program, which is 12 weeks or less in duration, focuses on providing industry-specific trainings with employer partners who hire program graduates, in areas such as construction, waste and recycling hauling, entry-level clerical positions within hospitals and clinics, entry level IT careers, and banking customer service. For example, a new program to train residents as drivers for recycling and waste hauling companies serving the city has had success training and placing a high proportion of people with prior justice system involvement. The majority of these trainees are placed in jobs earning annual incomes of $60,000 or more. The city also operates a paid work and stipend program with local partners. Overall, the city has partnered with 11 service providing partners and 31 employer partners for these programs.</li><li><strong>Buffalo, NY is expanding the city’s youth employment effort</strong>, including broadening the Mayor’s youth employment program to accept more students, be available year round and compensate students for summer school in addition to summer employment opportunities. The city will also invest $3.5 million to establish a skills-based job readiness program that matches low- to moderate- income residents with specific employers and provides residents with the training to secure a career path. In combination with the subsidized employment programs and the scholarship program for the Northland Workforce Training Center, the City aspires to transform the talent development pipeline for employers while also giving residents real opportunities to secure long-term employment which pays a livable wage.</li><li><strong>Salt Lake County, UT is investing $10 million in </strong><strong>American Rescue Plan</strong><strong> funds toward a new job training program</strong> called Workforce Inclusion &amp; Successful Employment (WISE) to help thousands of low-income and diverse residents access training that launches them into high-paying jobs. The program focuses on outreach and connecting students with wraparound services such as mental health support, mentorship, childcare, and other needs that are often key to success. The county expects to show that the increased upfront expenses pay for themselves through long-term increases in income and reduced need for benefits.</li><li><strong>Cook County, IL is accelerating workforce development for youth, individuals who were formerly incarcerated, and people with disabilities. </strong>The County is investing $15 million to launch and expand programs to address the urgent hiring needs of employers, scale programs to connect young adults to sector-focused training and internships, provide employment programming to people who have been incarcerated and increase outreach and service navigation for people with disabilities and other barriers to employment. This includes the Opportunity Works program, which provides an 8-week, year-round paid internship program in high-demand, high-growth industries for out-of-work or out-of-school Cook County young adults, as well as Opportunity Summer, which is a 7-week paid summer internship program that provides a foundation for future full-time employment. The Opportunity Summer program was able to double its capacity due to American Rescue Plan funds. Further, the American Rescue Plan will allow for the Road Home program, which currently serves residents while they are incarcerated, to expand and serve those who have returned to the community but continue to face barriers to employment. In addition, the American Rescue Plan funds will also fund work to assist residents with a disability who face workforce development barriers. In concert with the Cook County Bureau of Economic Development, the Chicago Cook Workforce Partnership will administer this suite of programs and estimates that they will impact 500 businesses and 13,960 residents of Cook County.</li><li><strong>Gloucester, NJ is developing a transition to work program for students with disabilities. </strong>Project SEARCH is a transition to work program that takes place entirely within a host business, enabling participants to experience total workplace immersion and learn relevant, transferrable, and marketable skills geared towards their individualized employment goals. The project provides role models and mentors for students with disabilities while also creating more awareness in the county for workforce opportunities for individuals with disabilities.</li><li><strong>Maine is developing a peer workforce navigator pilot program to increase access to employment opportunities for communities most impacted by the COVID-19 pandemic. </strong>The COVID-19 pandemic suddenly and dramatically impacted the ability of many Mainers to support themselves and their families, particularly people in low- and moderate-income jobs, workers of color, workers with dependent care responsibilities, and workers with lower levels of educational attainment. Through a collaborative partnership with five organizations, including ethnic-based community organizations, worker groups, labor unions, and other community partners, the Peer Workforce Navigator program will assist individuals in communities hit hardest by the pandemic with addressing basic needs and finding employment. In this two-year pilot, peers employed by local community organizations will help a projected 3,000 individuals connect with employment, job training programs, and basic needs supports necessary to persist in work or education, such as child care, transportation, unemployment insurance, and other concrete resources.</li><li><strong>Los Angeles County, CA has committed $5 million to increase capacity for the Youth@Work program,</strong> which offers youth in priority populations, including but not limited to foster, probation, and LGBTQI+ youth, paid enrichment training and work experience in public, non-profit, and private organizations in high-growth industry sectors. The county is also dedicating over $2 million for job placement programming for individuals returning from serving sentences in jail or prison, with a focus on women and the LGBTQI+ community.</li><li><strong>Boston, MA is providing wraparound supports, including employment opportunities, to high-risk individuals in communities with highest rates of gun and gang violence in the city. </strong>The Office of Public Safety is directing funding to bolster services and programs for high risk, system-involved individuals that are underserved in communities with highest rates of gun and gang violence in the city. Specifically, the city is awarding grants to Boston nonprofits to increase or scale up programs that improve economic, education and health outcomes for participants by providing training, case management, mental health services, and employment opportunities, among other support services. Further, the city is also supporting SOAR Boston, the city’s gang intervention program, through workforce development and training.</li><li><strong>Iowa is committing $10 million for the Homes for Iowa program, where inmates at the Newton Correction Facility receive building trades skills training while constructing modular homes</strong>. The program is a public-private partnership that aims to reduce recidivism while helping solve Iowa’s housing shortage. The inmates participate in skills training, including an apprenticeship curriculum. They receive portable training certificates and are connected to Iowa employers upon release. The Homes for Iowa organization works closely with the state to develop wraparound services for participants of the program.</li></ol>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by the President on the Bipartisan Confirmation of Career Prosecutor Steve Dettelbach to be the First Senate-Confirmed ATF Director in 7&#160;Years</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/statement-by-the-president-on-the-bipartisan-confirmation-of-career-prosecutor-steve-dettelbach-to-be-the-first-senate-confirmed-atf-director-in-7-years/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 19:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I’ve made clear time and time again, the answer to the rise in crime my administration inherited is not to defund law enforcement; it’s to provide law enforcement with the resources and support they need to&#160; succeed in working effectively with the communities they serve. The Senate just took an important, bipartisan step by&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As I’ve made clear time and time again, the answer to the rise in crime my administration inherited is not to defund law enforcement; it’s to provide law enforcement with the resources and support they need to&nbsp; succeed in working effectively with the communities they serve.</p>



<p>The Senate just took an important, bipartisan step by confirming Steve Dettelbach, an extraordinarily qualified and decorated career prosecutor with strong support across the law enforcement community, to be the first permanent head of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives in over 7 years.</p>



<p>Steve’s distinguished prosecutorial experience spans over two decades at the Department of Justice under four different administrations, two Republican and two Democratic. His work and reputation have earned him the support of former ATF directors who’ve led the department over the last 40 years, in addition to a wide range of law enforcement organizations and leaders, including police chiefs and sheriffs across the country. He was also endorsed by the U.S. Conference of Mayors.</p>



<p>Following the passage of the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act, today’s vote is another important sign that both parties can come together to support law enforcement and stand up against the horrific scourge of gun violence. I thank the Senate for their support. And it is my hope that we can continue working together to keep Americans safe – especially our children – from mass shootings like those in Uvalde, Buffalo, and Highland Park, as well as the daily acts of gun violence that don’t make national headlines.</p>



<p>We have so much more to do. I will continue to call on Congress to build on this momentum and ban assault weapons, expand background checks, and pass safe storage laws. At the same time, my Administration will build on our record of taking historic executive action. And as ATF Director, Steve will play a leading role in ensuring robust implementation of the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act and driving forward other executive actions to fight crime and save lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President López Obrador of Mexico Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/12/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-lopez-obrador-of-mexico-before-bilateral-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 19:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;Oval Office 11:26 A.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Mr. President &#8212; my friend, my partner &#8212; it’s good to have you back to the White House. Over the last year and a half, we’ve devoted our teams to whole-of-government efforts focused on rebuilding the solid framework of the U.S.-Mexico relations. As I told you from the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;Oval Office</p>



<p>11:26 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212; my friend, my partner &#8212; it’s good to have you back to the White House.</p>



<p>Over the last year and a half, we’ve devoted our teams to whole-of-government efforts focused on rebuilding the solid framework of the U.S.-Mexico relations.</p>



<p>As I told you from the beginning &#8212; and I mean it &#8212; I see, we see Mexico as an equal partner.&nbsp; Our nations share close ties in family and friendship, and we’re united through our values and our history.</p>



<p>And for me and my administration, the U.S.-Mexico relationship is vital to achieving our goals of everything from the fight against COVID-19, to continuing to grow our economies, to strengthening our partnerships and addressing migration as a shared hemispheric challenge.</p>



<p>And addressing migration is a hemispheric challenge, a commitment captured in the Los Angeles Declaration adopted by the Summit of the Americas.</p>



<p>And, Mr. President, this is a relationship that directly impacts the daily lives &#8212; the daily lives of our people.&nbsp; And despite the overhyped headlines that we sometimes see, you and I have a strong and productive relationship and, I would argue, a partnership.</p>



<p>Today we’re going to be discussing our shared challenges we face and commitments on some of the major issues that we’re taking on together.&nbsp; One of those is migration.&nbsp; At historic levels throughout our hemisphere, like us, Mexico has become a top destination of migrants.&nbsp; And here’s what we’re going to do to address it together:</p>



<p>My administration is leading the way to creating work opportunities through legal pathways.&nbsp; And last year, my administration set a record.&nbsp; We issued more than 300,000 H-2 visas for Mexican workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also reached a five-year high in the visas we issued to Central Americans, and we’re on pace to double this in fiscal year for &#8212; this fiscal year for Central America.</p>



<p>I want to thank you, Mr. President, for also stepping up and increasing worker visas in Mexico for Central Americans.&nbsp; This is a proven strategy that fuels economic growth as well as reduces irregular migration.</p>



<p>And it doesn’t get much attention, but we’re also making historic investments in infrastructure modernization across our 2,000-mile border with Mexico.</p>



<p>My Bipartisan Infrastructure Law here in America is delivering $3.4 billion to major construction projects at the ports of entry between our two countries to make our border safer and more efficient for people, trade, and commerce.</p>



<p>And the American people should know, Mr. President, that you’re also making a significant investment on your side of the border to improve infrastructure to meet the needs of our times and the future.</p>



<p>And a very important point &#8212; another critical example is we are accelerating our efforts to disrupt the trafficking of fentanyl and other drugs that are literally killing.&nbsp; Fentanyl kills people.</p>



<p>We’ve had a major anti-smuggling operation underway since April, targeting human smugglers who traffic in people, drugs, and weapons.</p>



<p>Towards this effort, we’ve deployed 1,300 additional personnel, conducted 20,000 disruption operations, and we’ve made over 3,000 arrests, all since April.</p>



<p>And we have been conducting (inaudible) disruption operations along our shared border with our Mexican partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, Mr. President, we need every country in the region to join us in tracking this multibillion-dollar smuggling industry that’s preying on our most vulnerable, including the 53 souls who died in a tractor trailer in San Antonio last month.</p>



<p>President Obrador and I will also be talking about enhanced enforcement measures, including <s>reparation</s> [repatriation] efforts.&nbsp; And today we’ll agree on our next steps together on all these fronts, because we know we have to meet these challenges together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. President, again, welcome.&nbsp; And I look forward to our discussions after this introductory meeting.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; We’re so happy, President Biden, to be here at the White House once more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I send my greetings to the good, hardworking, the fine, and very progressive people of the United States.&nbsp; My greetings.</p>



<p>This is the second meeting in just eight months &#8212; the second meeting we are holding with you, Mr. President, here at the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes, but as you have already expressed, President Biden, this existing circumstances are demanding so many more things from us &#8212; for instance, having a closer relationship, closer ties of friendship and cooperation so that we can act together vis- à-vis the major challenges our two countries face.<br><br>And these are truly difficult times.&nbsp; No question about it.<br><br>First of all, we have the pandemic &#8212; the COVID-19 pandemic with the sequence of death, suffering, hardships, and damage &#8212; damage on the productive activities of our countries.</p>



<p><br>And now we have the war in the Ukraine.&nbsp; And as we know, it has not only constituted grief and destruction, but it made the economic crisis even worse.&nbsp; Yes, and this has resulted in inflationary spiral that the entire world is suffering.<br><br>Therefore, President Biden, I have come to see you to express, on behalf of the Mexican people, our disposal, our willingness to work together for the wellbeing of our nations.<br><br>This will not be the first nor the last occasion on which we close ranks to help each other, we know.</p>



<p><br>In spite of our differences and also in spite of our grievances that are not really easy to forget with time or with good wishes &#8212; they&#8217;re not easy to forget.&nbsp; However, on many occasions, we&#8217;ve been able to coincide and we&#8217;ve been able to work together as good friends and true allies.<br><br>During President Franklin D. Roosevelt&#8217;s administration, we were able to see a policy that we believe it was a very efficient and very fraternal policy.<br><br>Those were other times.&nbsp; However, we had circumstances that were quite similar to our existing circumstances.&nbsp; And from those policies, we should be extracting good lessons, because history is the master of life.<br><br>When President Roosevelt took office March 4th, 1933, the United States was going through one of the most profound social and economic crisis of its history.<br><br>That&#8217;s why with great definition, determination, and aplomb, since the first 100 days of its administration, he launched a whirlpool of initiatives that changed the country and gave new hopes to its inhabitants.<br><br>And throughout his administration, he also applied, he enforced a policy &#8212; a Good Neighbors policy.&nbsp; And this is something that was enforced and applied throughout the American continent.<br><br>Authenticity of this policy had, as its best example, respect for the sovereignty of Mexico.</p>



<p><br>At that time, President Lázaro Cárdenas’s administration was also launching very deep, very important reforms.</p>



<p>So then, in 1938, that&#8217;s when the oil expropriation took place in Mexico.&nbsp; However, differences were addressed and solved through a dialogue and collaboration with dignity.</p>



<p><br>This policy of respect for the sovereignty of our country, of the nations in general, gave us very good fruit.&nbsp; Yes, for instance, it created conditions which were very favorable conditions for the governments of the United States and Mexico to act as partners, as allies throughout the Second World War.</p>



<p><br>And this alliance went beyond &#8212; over and beyond mere cooperation in this bellicist effort.<br><br>When the United States went into the Second World War, thousands of Americans were recruited by the armed forces, and this meant that the agricultural field was left with no labor force.&nbsp; Farmers urgently needed labor force, as it also happens now in restaurants, factories, construction works, and out in the countryside as well.</p>



<p>At that time, under those circumstances in 1943, President Roosevelt recognized reality, and he decided to support the Bracero Program, through which thousands of Mexican agricultural laborers came into the United States legally to help in the production of foodstuffs, even during the construction of the railroad system in the United States.<br><br>1943 through 1946, 130,000 Mexican workers, farm workers were hired through this agreement signed by both governments.&nbsp;<br><br>Certainly, the program was not exempt from mistakes, abuses, and non-compliance.&nbsp; However, there is no doubt that it had very good results at the productive and labor levels.<br><br>It was a more secure framework with less human rights violations, especially with &#8212; compare that to current migration provisions.<br><br>Today, we&#8217;re proposing something similar to this program.</p>



<p><br>It is true that the USMCA is a treaty that’s already uniting and integrating our three countries.&nbsp; Our three countries &#8212; Mexico, the United States, and Canada.</p>



<p>However, there are still margins for us to intensify our bilateral relationship.&nbsp; For instance, high inflationary rates have to do with misadjustments of the world economy because of the pandemic and the war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, we should also recognize that for some time now, we haven’t been producing what we should be producing.&nbsp; In the last three decades, it was very comfortably accepted for China to become the factory of the world.&nbsp; And this was due to the fallacious idea that, with globality &#8212; with globality, it wasn’t necessary to continue our self-sufficiency in the production of foodstuffs, because we were able to produce energy and other goods.&nbsp; We didn’t have to do it; it wasn’t necessary because we could always import them as we needed them.&nbsp; So, self-sufficiency was not necessary.</p>



<p>However, the reality we live in now makes it necessary and indispensable for us to produce everything we consume in our countries and regions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without reaching an extremist position of closing our economies, we should remember that the development of our nations depends fundamentally on their productive capacity.</p>



<p>President Biden, I’m about to finish.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Let me say one thing.&nbsp; I can’t get over how that lovely lady is holding that camera steady all this time.&nbsp; (Inaudible.) (Laughter.)&nbsp; It’s amazing.</p>



<p>Sorry for the distraction.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Yes, I fully coincide with what you have proposed, President Biden.&nbsp; And I could summarize everything we&#8217;ve been saying in five basic items of cooperation.</p>



<p>Number one, since the energy crisis started, Mexico has used 72 percent of its crude and fuel oil exports to United States refineries &#8212; 800,000 barrels a day.</p>



<p>Therefore, we decided that while we’re waiting for prices of gasoline to go down in the United States &#8212; and I hope that Congress approves or passes your proposal, Mr. President &#8212;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; It has gone down for 30 days in a row.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; &#8212; of lowering &#8212; lowering prices, yes.&nbsp; That’s it.</p>



<p>In the meantime, while we’re waiting for prices to go down, we have decided that it was necessary for us to allow Americans who live close to the borderline so that they could go and get their gasoline on the Mexican side at lower prices.</p>



<p>And right now, a lot of the drivers &#8212; a lot of the Americans &#8212; are going to Mexico, to the Mexican border, to get their gasoline.</p>



<p>However, we could increase our inventories immediately.&nbsp; We are committed to guaranteeing twice as much supply of fuel.&nbsp; That would be considerable support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Right now, a gallon of regular costs $4.78 average on this side of the border.&nbsp; And in our territory, $3.12.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me clarify something, and I also want to take advantage of this opportunity to thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Most of this gasoline, we are producing it in the Pemex refinery that you allowed us to buy in Deer Park, Texas.</p>



<p>Two, we are putting at the disposal &#8212; or sending at the disposal of your administration over 1,000 kilometers of gas pipelines throughout the southern border with Mexico to transport gas from Texas to New Mexico, Arizona, and California for a volume that can generate up to 750 megawatts of electric energy and supply about 3 million people.</p>



<p>Three, even though the USMCA has made progress for the elimination of tariffs, there are still some others that could be immediately suspended.&nbsp; And we could do the same with some regulations, regulatory measures, and tedious procedures or red tape in terms of trade related to foodstuffs and other products so that we can lower prices for consumers in both our countries, always being very careful in the protection of health and the environment.</p>



<p>Four, starting a private-public investment plan between our two countries to produce all those goods that will be strengthening our markets so that we can avoid having importations from other regions or continents.</p>



<p>In our country, we shall continue producing oil throughout the energy transition.&nbsp; With the U.S. investors, we are going to be establishing gas-liquefying plants, fertilizer plants, and we shall continue promoting the creation of solar energy parks in the state of Sonora and other border states as well.</p>



<p>And we’re going to accomplish this with the support of thermal electric plants and also through transmission lines to produce energy in the domestic market, as well as for exports, to neighboring states in the American union, as for instance, Texas, New Mexico, Arizona, and California.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s also important to mention that, two months ago, we took the sovereign decision of nationalizing lithium in Mexico.&nbsp; This is a fundamental mineral, a fundamental input to advance in our purpose not to depend on fossil fuels.&nbsp; And this will be available for the technological modernization of the automotive industry among our great countries &#8212; the countries of the USMCA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Five, orderly migration flow and allowing arrival in the United States of workers, technicians, and professionals of different disciplines.&nbsp; I&#8217;m talking about Mexicans and Central Americans with temporary work visas to ensure not paralyzing the economy because of the lack of labor force.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The purpose of this plan would be to support and to have the right labor force that will be demanded by the plan you proposed and that was passed by Congress of using $1 trillion for the construction of infrastructure works.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it’s also indispensable that I say this in a very sincere fashion in the most respectful manner: It is indispensable for us to regularize and give certainty to migrants that have for years lived and worked in a very honest manner, and who are also contributing to the development of this great nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that your adversaries &#8212; the conservatives &#8212; are going to be screaming all over the place, even to Heaven.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be yelling at Heaven.&nbsp; But without a daring, a bold program of development and wellbeing, it will not be possible to solve problems.&nbsp; It will not be possible to get the people’s support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the face of this crisis, the way out is not through conservatism.&nbsp; The way out is through transformation.&nbsp; We have to be bold in our actions.&nbsp; Transform not maintain the status quo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On our part, we’re acting in good faith, with all transparency, because there shouldn’t be selfishness between countries, peoples that are neighbors and friends.&nbsp; On the other hand, integration does not signify hegemony or subjugation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, President Biden, we trust you because you respect our sovereignty.&nbsp; We are willing to continue working with you for the benefit of our peoples.&nbsp; Count with our support &#8212; count on our support and solidarity always.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Long live the United States. &nbsp;<em>Viva México lindo y querido.</em>&nbsp; Long live Mexico &#8212; dear Mexico, loved and beautiful Mexico.&nbsp; <em>Viva México.</em></p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, Mr. President, you’ve had a lot of important things to say, and we have much agreement.&nbsp; And some of the details, we&#8217;ll have a chance to talk about where the disagreement is.&nbsp; But the thrust of what you&#8217;re saying we agree with: We need to work closely together.</p>



<p>I might note, of all the major economies in the world, we&#8217;re the fastest growing.&nbsp; We, the United States, already the fastest growing in the world.</p>



<p>Just since I became President, we have created more jobs than any president ever has in the beginning of his administration &#8212; almost 8.5 million new jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Wages have risen five and a half percent.&nbsp; We are suffering from inflation imposed as a consequence of what’s going on in Ukraine, but we have the lowest rate of almost every major nation in the world.</p>



<p>Even last month, we created another three hundred and &#8212; I think &#8212; fifty-seven thousand new jobs.&nbsp; And it doesn&#8217;t mean we don&#8217;t have problems; we do.&nbsp; And we do believe &#8212; I do believe that, working with you, we can help solve both our problems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And China is not only not going to be the factory of the world.&nbsp; You&#8217;re in the factory of the world &#8212; the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp; We produce more agricultural product than anything close to what they do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not suggesting there are not problems.&nbsp; There are real problems, but they are solvable, as you pointed out.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m anxious for us to get into some detail about the explicit five points you raised and how we can make sure we work together on all five of those points.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I hope I&#8217;ve demonstrated my whole career I have the enormous respect for Mexico as an independent nation, a great nation, and I have great respect for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have liberals, moderates, conservatives, and extreme conservatives.&nbsp; I&#8217;m waiting for the Republican Party to come back to traditional conservative positions.&nbsp; We have to start to talk with them, to one another, in this country, with respect.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have enormous respect for you, and I&#8217;m ready to get to</p>



<p>work.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m going to find out how she holds that camera (inaudible).&nbsp; It’s amazing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:&nbsp; This is a journalist from Mexico.&nbsp; She&#8217;s exceptional.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; She is exceptional.&nbsp; Just holding that camera.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; At any rate &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:&nbsp; This is a tribute, homage to all of &#8212; all of the media here.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Women and men journalists, reporters.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p>12:12 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Names Twenty-First Round of Judicial&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/president-biden-names-twenty-first-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing five new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country —&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing five new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>For example, if confirmed, this slate would include:</p>



<ul><li>The first Asian American judge to serve on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit</li><li>The first Asian American and second Latina judge to serve on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s twenty-first round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his eighth slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 112.</p>



<p>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies. And he has won confirmation of the most lower court judges for the first year of a presidency since the Kennedy Administration.</p>



<p><strong><u>Circuit Court Press Bio</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Cindy K. Chung: Candidate for the United States Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Cindy K. Chung has served as the United States Attorney for the Western District of Pennsylvania since 2021. Ms. Chung served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Western District of Pennsylvania from 2014 to 2021. From 2009 to 2014, Ms. Chung served as a trial attorney in the Criminal Section of the Department of Justice’s Civil Rights Division. From 2003 to 2009, she served as an Assistant District Attorney in the New York County District Attorney’s Office. Ms. Chung served as a law clerk for Judge Myron Thompson on the United States District Court for the Middle District of Alabama from 2002 to 2003. She received her J.D. from Columbia Law School in 2002 and her B.A. from Yale University in 1997.</p>



<p><strong><u>District Court Press Bios</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Kelley B. Hodge: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Kelley B. Hodge is a partner at Fox Rothschild in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, where she has worked since 2020. Ms. Hodge was previously Of Counsel at Elliott Greenleaf in Blue Bell, Pennsylvania from 2016 to 2017 and 2018 to 2020. Ms. Hodge was the interim District Attorney for the City of Philadelphia from 2017 to 2018. From 2015 to 2016, she was the Title IX Coordinator and Executive Assistant to the President at the University of Virginia. From 2011 to 2015, she served as the Safe Schools Advocate under the Pennsylvania Commission on Crime and Delinquency.&nbsp;From 2004 to 2011, she worked in the Philadelphia District Attorney’s Office. Ms. Hodge was a public defender in the Richmond, Virginia Public Defender’s Office from 1997 to 2003. Ms. Hodge received her J.D. from the University of Richmond School of Law in 1996 and B.A. from the University of Virginia in 1993.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>John Frank Murphy: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>John Frank Murphy is a partner at Baker &amp; Hostetler in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, where has worked since 2007. Mr. Murphy has also been an Adjunct Professor at Rutgers Law School since 2014. Mr. Murphy served as a law clerk for Chief Judge Kimberly A. Moore on the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit from 2008 to 2009.&nbsp;Mr. Murphy received his J.D.,<em> cum laude</em>, from Harvard Law School in 2007, his M.S. and Ph.D. from the California Institute of Technology in 2002 and 2004, and his B.S., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Cornell University in 1999.</p>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong><u>Judge Mia Perez: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Mia Roberts Perez has served as a judge on the Philadelphia County Court of Common Pleas since her election in 2016.&nbsp;Judge Perez was previously in private practice at her own firm, Perez Law, from 2011 to 2016. From 2010 to 2011, Judge Perez was an associate at Friedman Schuman in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. She was an Assistant Defender at the Defender Association of Philadelphia from 2006 to 2010. Judge Perez received her J.D. from Temple University, Beasley School of Law in 2006 and her B.A. from Tufts University in 2003.</p>



<ol type="1" start="4"><li><strong><u>Judge Kai Scott: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Kai Scott has served as a judge on the Philadelphia County Court of Common Pleas since her election in 2015. Prior to joining the bench, Judge Scott was the Trial Unit Chief for the Federal Community Defender Office in the Eastern District of Pennsylvania from 2010 to 2015. Judge Scott was an Assistant Federal Defender from 2004 to 2010. From 1998 to 2004, Judge Scott was a Trial Attorney with the Defender Association of Philadelphia. Judge Scott served as a law clerk for Judge Donald Poorman of the Pennsylvania Bureau of Workers Compensation from 1996 to 1998.&nbsp;Judge Scott received her J.D. from the West Virginia University College of Law in 1995 and her B.A. from Hampton University in 1991.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Successful Counterterrorism&#160;Operation </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/statement-by-president-biden-on-successful-counterterrorism-operation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the men and women of the U.S. military and of our intelligence community successfully executed an airstrike against one of the top leaders of ISIS, Maher al Agal. His death in Syria takes a key terrorist off the field and significantly degrades the ability of ISIS to plan, resource, and conduct their operations in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the men and women of the U.S. military and of our intelligence community successfully executed an airstrike against one of the top leaders of ISIS, Maher al Agal.<br> <br>His death in Syria takes a key terrorist off the field and significantly degrades the ability of ISIS to plan, resource, and conduct their operations in the region. And, like the U.S. operation in February that eliminated ISIS’s overall leader, it sends a powerful message to all terrorists who threaten our homeland and our interests around the world.  The United States will be relentless in its efforts to bring you to justice.<br> <br>This airstrike represents the culmination of determined and meticulous intelligence work and stands as testament to the bravery and skill of our armed forces.  It also demonstrates that the United States does not require thousands of troops in combat missions to identify and eliminate threats to our country. <br> <br>On behalf of the American people, whose lives they protect every day, I thank them for their service, their dedication, their professionalism, and for the teamwork that led to this successful outcome. <br> <br>The American people — and our allies and partners — are safer today because of their actions. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official Previewing Vice President Harris&#8217;s Engagement With the Pacific Islands&#160;Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-previewing-vice-president-harriss-engagement-with-the-pacific-islands-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (July 11, 2022) MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; And thank you, everyone, for joining our call.&#160; Tonight’s call will be on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&#160; The contents of this call will be embargoed until Tuesday, July 12th, at 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time.&#160; Again, that’s Tuesday, July 12th, 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>(July 11, 2022)<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; And thank you, everyone, for joining our call.&nbsp; Tonight’s call will be on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The contents of this call will be embargoed until Tuesday, July 12th, at 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time.&nbsp; Again, that’s Tuesday, July 12th, 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time.&nbsp; And by participating in this call, you are hereby agreeing to these ground rules.<br><br>Our speaker today, for your awareness only, is [senior administration official], who hereinafter will be referred to as a “senior administration official.”<br><br>So, with that, I’ll turn it over to him for some brief remarks before opening up for questions.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [moderator].&nbsp; Hi, everybody, and thank you all for joining.&nbsp; As we announced earlier today, the Vice President will participate virtually in the Pacific Islands Forum leaders’ meeting July 12th, Washington D.C. time.&nbsp; The United States is not a member of the PIF, the Pacific Islands Forum, but the Vice President is honored to accept an invitation from Fijian Prime Minister Bainimarama, the current Chair of the PIF, to address the PIF leaders.<br><br>We think this invitation speaks to the longstanding and deep partnership the United States has with the Pacific Islands, and our mutual interest in strengthening our relationships.&nbsp; We have a very strong foundation with the Pacific Islands, including historic ties, deep people-to-people bonds, and shared interests and values.&nbsp; And we believe that we’re now embarking on a new chapter in this longstanding partnership.<br><br>In short, the Vice President will be announcing that we’re significantly stepping up our game in the Pacific Islands.&nbsp; After this call, we will share with you an embargoed factsheet.&nbsp; But I can tell you now that the Vice President has a significant set of deliverables that she’ll be announcing to the forum as part of this engagement.&nbsp;<br><br>This new chapter in our relationship will feature increased diplomatic presence on the ground throughout the region, and that’s what most of these announcements are about: our presence and our engagement.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re expanding our footprint and making sure that we have the people and the apparatus in place to deepen our cooperation on a day-to-day basis and to deliver concrete results.&nbsp; And these deliverables emerge from close consultations with the region in recent weeks and months, and we believe that this series of steps is responsive to their priorities.<br><br>So maybe just to summarize them for you: First, we will begin discussions to establish new U.S. embassies in Kiribati and Tonga.&nbsp; This was a top ask of the region, and we’re delivering because a close partnership requires the regular exchange that comes with having an embassy.&nbsp;<br><br>Second, we’re going to appoint the first-ever U.S. envoy to the Pacific Islands Forum in order to expand our diplomatic footprint, but also to help support a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum.&nbsp;<br><br>Third, we’re going to bring the Peace Corps back to the Pacific.&nbsp; This includes returning to countries where Peace Corps previously operated, as well as exploring expansion to new Pacific Island countries.&nbsp;<br><br>Fourth, USAID will work toward reestablishing a regional mission in Suva, Fiji, to improve its cooperation with Pacific Island countries.<br><br>And then finally, we plan to triple U.S. funding for economic development and ocean resilience in the region.&nbsp; This support will increase our funding from the current $21 million per year &#8212; dollar &#8212; 21 million U.S. dollars per year to $60 million per year, which we’ll be requesting from Congress for the next 10 years.&nbsp; And these funds &#8212; these additional funds will help strengthen climate resilience; invest in marine planning and conservation; combat illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and enhance maritime security.<br><br>As part of this initiative, we also look forward to concluding negotiations on an updated South Pacific Tuna Treaty, which is the cornerstone of our economic and political cooperation.&nbsp;<br><br>So I think, you know, when you look at that altogether, it’s quite the package of measures designed to underscore our commitment to this region and to facilitate partnership going forward.<br><br>The last point on the broader strategic dynamic at play &#8212; and we recognize there’s an intense interest in the Pacific Islands among other countries.&nbsp; And I would just say that what we’re putting on the table is a true partnership based on friendship and respect and transparency.<br><br>What we offer is an affirmative, positive agenda to take on short- and long-term challenges together, whether that’s the climate crisis; economic development; IUU &#8212; or illegal, unreported, and unregulated &#8212; fishing; maritime security; food security; or others.&nbsp;<br><br>With these announcements, the Vice President is putting in place the structure to really make progress on all of these areas that matter to us and to our partners in the region.&nbsp;<br><br>Everything we do with regard to the region will be in consultation with the region.&nbsp; We’ll listen and consult closely.&nbsp; That’s how President Biden and Vice President Harris approach our relationships all around the world.&nbsp; And we’ll continue to engage constructively and transparenc- &#8212; transparently with our Pacific Island partners every step of the way.<br><br>With that, I’m happy to take a few questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; If our moderator could inform our guests the instructions to ask a question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp; Hello?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; We hear you just fine.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, wonderful.&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; So I &#8212; you know, just heard that you announced several deliverables that the Vice President is going to announce tomorrow.&nbsp; Correct me if I’m wrong: I didn’t hear about the infrastructure or the Build Back Better World initiatives that President Biden announced during NATO Summit.<br><br>Is the infrastructure efforts going to expand to the Pacific Islands?&nbsp; And so, like we see that Solomon Island has had that security pact with China which worries the United States, of course.&nbsp; Is that part of the deal that we are going to offer more to counter China’s effort in those areas?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I mean, what I announced now is not part of the Partnership for Global Infrastructure Investment that the President announced with his G7 partners recently in Europe.&nbsp; But I think we’ve made clear that the PGII is a global fund and a global enterprise.&nbsp; And as we move forward, there are a lot of parts of the world, including this one, that I think you could expect us to look at in terms of infrastructure support.<br><br>So there haven’t been PGII announcements.&nbsp; It was just launched, as we noted, a couple of weeks ago.&nbsp; But of course, we’re going to be looking to support infrastructure development in this region.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, all.&nbsp; Thanks so much for the call.&nbsp; Just to kind of piggyback on that question broadly, I wonder if you can talk about just how the relationship between U.S. and China is factoring into these deliverables in the forum itself.&nbsp; I know you just said that you recognize that there’s an intense interest in the Pacific Islands, and, of course, a lot of that is about China’s interest in it.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, that’s clear and obvious, and that’s why I mentioned it.&nbsp; But I think our emphasis is on the positive part of our agenda rather than seeing this in terms of competition.&nbsp;<br><br>And we’ve made that clear around the world.&nbsp; We’re not asking countries to choose; we’re not asking countries not to have relations with China.&nbsp; It’s a big, important country.<br><br>We are focusing on our own engagement and our own interests and our own support.&nbsp; And of course, contrasts will be made and we’d like to think that contrast looks favorably on us where we’ve been a responsible security actor in the region and (inaudible) the entire Indo-Pacific for many decades and helping to preserve a free and open Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And we’ve got important, transparent, supportive economic relationships with these countries, and that’s what we’re trying to build on.&nbsp;<br><br>So this is not about countering any one country or China.&nbsp; It’s about the positive engagement that these leaders are asking for and we’re trying to be responsive to.&nbsp; And we’re very proud of what we’re able to announce in terms of strengthening those relationships.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, go right ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great, thanks.&nbsp; So last year when Biden addressed the forum, he mentioned that the U.S. would dramatically cut its emissions.&nbsp; And clearly, that hasn’t happened now.&nbsp; And with the recent Supreme Court ruling, as well as the death of the Build Back Better bill, there’s not a lot of concrete, significant climate pledges the U.S. can offer to the region, at least as of tomorrow.<br><br>How is this going to be addressed with the world leaders tomorrow?&nbsp; Clearly, climate is one of their primary concerns and they’re particularly anxious about the U.S. and Australia being able to deliver on some of its pledges.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I mean, one of the things I did announce, in terms of the increased assistance to these countries, does have to do with climate adaptation and resilience.&nbsp; Now, that’s not the same thing as global emissions cuts, but it is something they’re very interested and need, and we want to be supportive of.&nbsp; And certainly, in the immediate term, that is most important.&nbsp;<br><br>And I would just also stress the Biden-Harris administration remains absolutely committed to the Paris Climate Agreement and meeting those goals.&nbsp; It’s true that in the past year Congress hasn’t been as supportive as we might like and international progress on this issue hasn’t been what we might like, including support for developing countries from more advanced countries, which we’re strongly supportive of.&nbsp;<br><br>But this administration remains absolutely committed to those goals.&nbsp; We’re committed to helping the PIF, or the Pacific Islands, deal with the consequences of the climate crisis.&nbsp; And that’s going to be &#8212; you ask what our dialogue with them will be like.&nbsp; I’m sure they will raise it and we’ll together discuss how we can deal with the climate crisis.&nbsp; Because without it, these countries are among the most vulnerable in the entire world.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [Inaudible] in the Newsroom, New Zealand.&nbsp; To what extent does this package reflect U.S. hopes to restore stronger regional engagement in the Pacific Islands Forum from countries like Kiribati and the rest of Micronesia, especially around regional security?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, it definitely reflects our interest in engaging throughout the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; I think you’ve seen this administration be extraordinarily active throughout the Indo-Pacific in terms of &#8212; including in terms of creating new structures and building on existent ones &#8212; the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue; obviously, AUKUS; the new partnership for the Blue Pacific, which is not just U.S. but key partner countries, including Japan and the United Kingdom and Australia and New Zealand &#8212; all of us interested in the same thing, which is supporting the Pacific Islands and maintaining a free and open Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;<br><br>So, absolutely, it takes place in that context.&nbsp; And you mentioned Kiribati, which gives me an opportunity to comment on that issue.&nbsp; We are concerned by reports that Kiribati has decided to withdraw from the PIF.<br><br>We think, obviously, that the PIF is stronger when it is united.&nbsp; And that’s one of the whole points of the organization: that those countries can join together and speak as one in international fora, including on the critical issue of the climate crisis.<br><br>So I understand that discussions are still underway to reach an agreement that would allow Kiribati and others to remain in the PIF and keep it as strong as it should be.&nbsp; And we support those talks and hope they can come to a positive conclusion.&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, what &#8212; everything I’ve outlined in this call will go ahead regardless of how that situation emerges because we’re committed to doing everything I said, in terms of the economic assistance, the embassies and the envoy to the region, and the strengthened Tuna Treaty.&nbsp; But it will be even stronger, it will all be more successful if a way can be found to keep Kiribati and others in.&nbsp; So we’re very supportive of that.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, thank you to our speaker for taking the time, and thank you to all of you.&nbsp;<br><br>As we mentioned, this call is embargoed until Tuesday, July 12th, at 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time.&nbsp; And we will follow up with some written materials, which will also be embargoed as well, to those on this call.<br><br>So thank you again, everyone, and we’ll be in touch shortly.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
