<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 18:43:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/18/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Candace Bond, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Trinidad and Tobago Timmy Davis, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the State of Qatar Puneet Talwar, Nominee for Ambassador&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:<strong></strong></p>



<ul><li>Candace Bond, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Trinidad and Tobago</li><li>Timmy Davis, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the State of Qatar</li><li>Puneet Talwar, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Morocco</li><li>Nasser Paydar, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, Department of Education</li><li>Michael Lombardo, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Candace Bond, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Trinidad and Tobago</u></strong></p>



<p>Candace A. Bond currently serves as the President and CEO of AESA Inc., a Los Angeles-based company offering business advisory services in real estate and community development with an emphasis on environmental stability, governance, education, and health equity. Presently, she serves as a Board Member of California Head Start, is the Chair-Elect of the Board of the Greater LA Education Foundation, and is the Chair of the MLK Health and Wellness Community Development Corporation. Bond is a founding member of BioscienceLA, LA County&#8217;s Innovation and Catalyst Entrepreneurial Hub to accelerate growth and development of LA County&#8217;s bioscience industry. She also served on the Board of the Los Angeles County Office of Education, the nation’s largest regional education agency. Earlier in her career, Bond was the President and CEO of Infusion Media Partners, and VP and General Manager of Essence Entertainment. She is Chair of the Malibu Foundation and Board Member of Women Founders Network, and member of the Southern California Edison Clean Energy Access Working Group. She also serves on the California State Treasurer’s Housing, Economic Development, Jobs and Opportunity Zone Ad Hoc Committee. Bond earned her B.A from Harvard University and her MBA from Harvard University Business School.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Timmy Davis, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the State of Qatar</u></strong></p>



<p>Timmy T. Davis, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Counselor, most recently served as the Executive Assistant to the Secretary of State. Prior to that, Davis served as the U.S. Consul General for Basrah and Southern Iraq. His overseas tours include Guatemala City, Guatemala; Najaf, Iraq; Canberra, Australia; and Bogota, Colombia. His domestic assignments include Senior Watch Officer in the State Department Operations Center, Special Assistant to the Secretary of State, Director for Iraq at the National Security Council, Deputy Chief of Staff to the Special Presidential Envoy to Counter-ISIL, Senior Advisor to the Counselor of the Department, Chief of Staff to the Undersecretary for Political Affairs, and Acting Chief of Staff of the Department of State. Davis, who holds a Distinguished Honor Award and multiple Superior and Meritorious Honor awards, is also the recipient of the Department’s Ryan C. Crocker Award for Outstanding Leadership in Expeditionary Diplomacy, and the American Foreign Service Association’s William R. Rivkin Award for Constructive Dissent. A native of Virginia, Davis attended the University of Alabama. He served in the United States Marine Corps for nearly a decade, including operations in the Horn of Africa and Iraq, before joining the Foreign Service.&nbsp; Davis speaks Spanish and Arabic.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Puneet Talwar, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Morocco</u></strong></p>



<p>Puneet Talwar has held senior national security and foreign policy positions in the State Department, White House, and United States Senate. He is currently a Senior Advisor at the State Department. Previously, he has served as the Assistant Secretary of State for Political-Military Affairs, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director at the National Security Council, and as a Senior Professional Staff Member at the Committee on Foreign Relations in the United States Senate. Talwar’s public service also includes key roles in the U.S. House of Representatives and the State Department’s Policy Planning Staff.&nbsp; Outside of government, he has been a Senior Fellow at the Asia Society Policy Institute, a Visiting Scholar at the University of Pennsylvania Penn Biden Center, a Counselor to the conflict resolution NGO Inter Mediate, and a non-resident Scholar at Georgetown University’s Center for Security Studies. Talwar earned his B.S. Degree in Engineering from Cornell University and his M.A. in International Affairs from Columbia University. He is a member of the Council on Foreign Relations and a native of Washington, DC.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Nasser Paydar, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, Department of Education</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Nasser H. Paydar is Chancellor Emeritus of Indiana University–Purdue University Indianapolis (IUPUI) and Executive Vice President Emeritus of Indiana University (IU). An IU faculty member for more than 36 years, he has held various administrative and executive leadership positions at the university. Paydar joined IUPUI in 1985 as an Assistant Professor of Mechanical Engineering. From 1989 to 2003, he held a numerous positions in the school, including serving as Chair of the Department of Mechanical Engineering, Associate Dean for Graduate Programs, Associate Dean for Academic Programs, and Executive Associate Dean. From 2004 to 2007, he served as Vice Chancellor and Dean of Indiana University–Purdue University Columbus. Paydar was appointed Chancellor of Indiana University East in 2007, serving in that role until he returned to IUPUI in 2012, when he was named the campus’s Executive Vice Chancellor and Chief Academic Officer. He became IUPUI’s fifth chancellor in 2015.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As an IUPUI faculty member, he has served as principal and co-principal investigator on research grants from federal and state agencies and private companies, including Cummins Electronics, DePuy, the National Institutes of Health, the U.S. Army, and the U.S. Naval Air Warfare Center. His research in the area of solid mechanics, with applications in biomechanics and electronic packaging, has been published widely in scientific journals. Paydar earned bachelor’s, master’s, and doctoral degrees in mechanical engineering from Syracuse University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Michael Lombardo, Nominee for Member of the National Council on the Arts</u></strong></p>



<p>Michael Lombardo is the President of Global Television at Entertainment One, where he is responsible for the studio’s Scripted and Unscripted TV divisions across businesses in the US, the UK, and Canada. Lombardo oversees a slate of over 20 series in production worldwide, including <em>The Rookie </em>on ABC, <em>Cruel Summer</em> on Freeform/Hulu, <em>Yellowjackets</em> on Showtime, and <em>Graymail</em> on Netflix. Previously, Lombardo served as President of Programming at Home Box Office (HBO) for 12 years. During his tenure at HBO, Lombardo was responsible for managing all of HBO’s and Cinemax’s programming initiatives including HBO Films, HBO Sports, HBO Documentaries &amp; Family, and HBO Entertainment. He also oversaw the Marketing, Business Affairs, Legal, Scheduling, Research, and Production Departments.</p>



<p>After exiting HBO, Lombardo was an executive producer for multiple critically acclaimed TV and documentary series. He currently serves on the boards of The Los Angeles LGBT Center and The Saban Community Clinic. In February 2014, he was appointed a member of the Board of Trustees at the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts by President Obama. He has an AB degree from Cornell University and JD from the University of California at Berkeley. Lombardo resides in Los Angeles with his husband and two children.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden Jr. Call with President Xi Jinping of the People’s Republic of&#160;China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/18/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-president-xi-jinping-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 18:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Xi Jinping of the People’s Republic of China (PRC). The conversation focused on Russia’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine. President Biden outlined the views of the United States and our Allies and partners on this crisis. President Biden detailed our efforts to prevent and then respond to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Xi Jinping of the People’s Republic of China (PRC). The conversation focused on Russia’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine. President Biden outlined the views of the United States and our Allies and partners on this crisis. President Biden detailed our efforts to prevent and then respond to the invasion, including by imposing costs on Russia. He described the implications and consequences if China provides material support to Russia as it conducts brutal attacks against Ukrainian cities and civilians. The President underscored his support for a diplomatic resolution to the crisis. The two leaders also agreed on the importance of maintaining open lines of communication, to manage the competition between our two countries. The President reiterated that U.S. policy on Taiwan has not changed, and emphasized that the United States continues to oppose any unilateral changes to the status quo. The two leaders tasked their teams to follow up on today’s conversation in the critical period ahead.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Poison Prevention Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/18/a-proclamation-on-national-poison-prevention-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 15:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each year, more than 2 million poisoning cases are reported in the United States &#8212; some of which are tragically fatal, but many of which are preventable.&#160; While we have made great strides in the decades since National Poison Prevention Week was first observed 60 years ago &#8212; including a decline in unintentional poisoning &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Each year, more than 2 million poisoning cases are reported in the United States &#8212; some of which are tragically fatal, but many of which are preventable.&nbsp; While we have made great strides in the decades since National Poison Prevention Week was first observed 60 years ago &#8212; including a decline in unintentional poisoning &#8212; poisoning remains a risk, especially for children and older Americans.&nbsp; During National Poison Prevention Week, we raise awareness about the dangers posed by poisonous substances, precautions people can take to prevent an incident, and how to respond in a poison emergency.</p>



<p>     Each year, an average of 31 children die from unintended poisonings at home, and an estimated 75,000 children under the age of five end up in hospital emergency departments from poisoning.  Approximately 85 percent of unintentional poisonings take place in the home where medicines and harmful chemicals are stored.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To prevent children from unintentionally ingesting poisonous household products, it is important to keep these products out of their sight and beyond their reach. &nbsp;Items such as hand sanitizer, laundry detergent, medications, coin cell batteries, cleaning products, and liquid nicotine should be stored in child-resistant packaging.&nbsp; Medications should be safely secured, and if unused, properly discarded.&nbsp; For elderly Americans &#8212; particularly those who may have become isolated due to the pandemic &#8212; it is important that household products are secured in their original packaging and that medications are clearly labeled to avoid accidental ingestion or the mistaking of medications.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Health professionals working around the clock and responding to millions of calls each year at poison control centers are critical to our Nation&#8217;s response.&nbsp; They not only help the public in need of assistance or information, they are also a tremendous asset to health care providers, health departments, law enforcement, and first responders.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you suspect that you or someone else has been poisoned, do not wait for signs of poisoning. &nbsp;Immediately call the Poison Control Help line at 800-222-1222.&nbsp; For more information, go to poisonhelp.hrsa.gov.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Poison awareness, control, and education are essential to saving lives. &nbsp;During National Poison Prevention Week, we recommit to raising awareness about the dangers of accidental poisonings and taking the necessary precautions to prevent and respond quickly to these incidents and protect our loved ones.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To encourage Americans to learn more about the dangers of unintentional poisonings and to take appropriate preventive measures, on September 26, 1961, the United States Congress, by joint resolution (75 Stat. 681), authorized and requested the President to issue a proclamation designating the third week of March each year as &#8220;National Poison Prevention Week.&#8221;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, do hereby proclaim March 20 through March 26, 2022, to be National Poison Prevention Week. &nbsp;I call upon all Americans to observe this week by taking actions to safeguard their families and friends from poisonous products, chemicals, and medicines often found in our homes, and to raise awareness of these dangers to prevent accidental injuries and deaths.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighteenth day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the Presentation of the&#160;Shamrocks</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/17/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-presentation-of-the-shamrocks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 5:47 P.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, Happy Saint Patrick’s Day, everyone.&#160; It&#8217;s great to see you all here.&#160; And last year, because of the pandemic, the Taoiseach and I had to hold our meeting virtually.&#160; How you doing, pal?&#160; We got all the Irish here today.&#160; (Laughter.) And this is the first year&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>5:47 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, Happy Saint Patrick’s Day, everyone.&nbsp; It&#8217;s great to see you all here.&nbsp; And last year, because of the pandemic, the Taoiseach and I had to hold our meeting virtually.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How you doing, pal?&nbsp; We got all the Irish here today.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And this is the first year we’ve had to make some last-minute adjustments as well.&nbsp; Sadly, the Taoiseach and Ms. Martin are not able to join us today, but they both sent their love and their message for this occasion.</p>



<p>And I spoke with the Taoiseach at length this morning, and we had a virtual meeting &#8212; bilateral meeting.&nbsp; He is feeling well.&nbsp; And I share his disappointment that we weren’t able to have our meetings in person as we had planned.</p>



<p>This year marks the 70th year of Ireland sending shamrocks to the White House and &#8212; to celebrate the friendship between our nations and the bond &#8212; the bond that has been strengthened by generations of Irish Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Apparently, President Truman was away when the Irish ambassador dropped off the first bowl of shamrocks in &#8212; and that&#8217;s why I just removed his bust from my office.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; That&#8217;s a joke.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a joke.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a joke.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t do that.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t do that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure he would have been there had he known.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>A virtual meeting back then was sort of out of the question.&nbsp; But by the next year, President Eisenhower was able to accept in person.&nbsp; A joyful tradition was born at that moment when he accepted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, to everyone here today: Welcome back to the White House.&nbsp; It&#8217;s so nice to be able to have you all back inside the White House.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>There are so many friends here &#8212; so many friends here: Irish, Irish Americans, Americans who wish they were Irish.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>As my grandfather used to say &#8212; our grandfather &#8212; my sister Valerie is here, my daughter Ashley is here, my brother-in-law, my brother and my other sister-in-law, my niece.&nbsp; We&#8217;re all here.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m probably the only one old enough to remember my grandfather, Ambrose Finnegan, as well you might expect someone when they were that age.</p>



<p>And he used to have an expression.&nbsp; He&#8217;d say, “If you’re lucky enough to be Irish, you’re lucky enough.”&nbsp; And so &#8212; (laughter and applause).&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a lot of proud Irish American members in my administration.&nbsp; But there’s one person here I want to recognize in particular in my administration: my Secretary of Labor.&nbsp; I&#8217;d understand him if he spoke better &#8212; if he spoke Gaelic instead of Boston.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Where are you, Marty Walsh?</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Right here.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; There you are, Marty.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Marty Walsh.&nbsp; From Galway &#8212; his parents are from Galway.&nbsp; I tell you what, I &#8212; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; Like I said, if you spoke Gaelic, I&#8217;d understand it better than, you know, the (inaudible) and all of that.</p>



<p>Look, a proud son of two Irish immigrants to this country who found their way in America and to America, and dream through their union membership, and all the work that this man did to promote the union movement.</p>



<p>And to all the members of the House and Senate that are here &#8212; you have to hear me again, a lot of you.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I look at one Irishman, Bobby Casey, over here.&nbsp; He&#8217;s from &#8212; we&#8217;re from the same hometown: Scranton, Pennsylvania.&nbsp; Right, Bobby?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I knew Bobby&#8217;s dad well.&nbsp; He was a hell of a guy.&nbsp; And we lived literally four, five city blocks apart from one another.&nbsp; The problem is that I&#8217;m older than Bobby as his father was than me, so we&#8217;re right in the middle there.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the best thing Bobby has going for him is a magnificent wife and his mother is a saint.&nbsp; God love her.&nbsp; And tell Mom I said hi, will you?&nbsp; For real.</p>



<p>Look, our new ambassador to Ireland can’t be with us today, but I’m very pleased that Claire Cronin from Boston has officially begun her work in Dublin.</p>



<p>I just got off a video with her on &#8212; on the phone, and she was mildly tearful.&nbsp; She wanted to be here with everyone, but &#8212; and I wish you all are going to get to meet her.&nbsp; She&#8217;s really quite a person.</p>



<p>And usually, in Washington, as &#8212; I&#8217;m usually referred to as Jill Biden’s husband, which I&#8217;m proud of.&nbsp; But today, I’m Catherine Eugenia Finnegan Biden&#8217;s son.&nbsp; That&#8217;s who I am.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and Jimmy, Val, and I &#8212; we come by our love for Ireland honestly.&nbsp; It’s been more than 165 years since our great-great-grandparents left County Mayo and County Louth aboard a coffin ship to cross the Atlantic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, I want to ask my relatives from County Louth to stand up, the three of them.&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; Stand up, guys.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Now, you see this guy here on the end?&nbsp; He&#8217;s probably the single most famous rugby played in all of Ireland.&nbsp; And he scored the winning goal against the All Blacks when he beat them in Chicago.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And he&#8217;s my cousin.&nbsp; Good to have you, man.&nbsp; Good to have you.</p>



<p>And the Blewitts and Finnegans eventually settled in Scranton, Pennsylvania, where my grandparents &#8212; where my parents met and married.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where my mom, Catherine Eugenia Finnegan, was born and later, as I said, met Joseph Robinette Biden, the Sr.&nbsp;</p>



<p>His saving grace was his mother was a Hanafee &#8212; his mother&#8217;s side, they had a Hanafee from Galway.&nbsp; That saved him in the family.&nbsp; That saved him up in Scranton.</p>



<p>Being Irish, as my mother always told me, is about family, it’s about faith, and it’s about courage.&nbsp; Mom used to have an expression.&nbsp; My brother and sister will remember.&nbsp; She&#8217;d say, &#8220;Courage is the greatest of all virtues because without it, you could not love with abandon.&#8221;&nbsp; &#8220;Courage is the greatest of all virtues because without it, you could not love with abandon.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Growing up an Irish American gave me a pride that spoke both &#8212; to both continents.&nbsp; The heart and soul that drew it from old and new.&nbsp;&nbsp;And the conviction that everyone &#8212; everyone is deserving of being treated with dignity.</p>



<p>I was mentioning today: I think it&#8217;s fair to say &#8212; I can&#8217;t prove this, but I think it&#8217;s fair to say I&#8217;ve never heard the word &#8220;dignity&#8221; used as much as I have among the Irish.&nbsp; Because the deprivation of the &#8212; being treated with dignity is understood.&nbsp; Dignity.</p>



<p>One of my great-uncles wrote from Ire- &#8212; wrote from the United States, after he made it to America, one of those letter they used to call “Amerikay” letters back to his loved ones in Ireland, yearning for home.</p>



<p>He wrote, “If there was a road made of furze….&#8221;&nbsp; Furze is a yellow flower with thorns in it.&nbsp; &#8220;If there was a road….&#8221;&nbsp; He said, &#8220;If there was a road made of furze in America from America to Ireland, I’d walk it in my bare feet.&nbsp; I&#8217;d walk it in my bare feet.&#8221;</p>



<p>Our great-grandfather, Edward Francis Blewitt, was only the second Catholic ever elected to the state senate &#8212; we talked about this, Gov &#8212; in the state of Pennsylvania.&nbsp; The first one was in the early 1880s, and &#8212; but I think he was &#8212; he was the second.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he was elected &#8212; when he was elected office, he had a &#8212; my great-grandfather was &#8212; had an engineering degree from Lafayette College and he had the heart of an Irish poet.&nbsp; He wrote over 200 poems.&nbsp; And fortunately, our Uncle Ed left the poems.&nbsp; I have them all.&nbsp; I’ve had them bound.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he wrote a poem about “his Ireland.”&nbsp; I want to read one of his stanzas of the poem.&nbsp; He said: “From the fairest land, except my own…”&nbsp;nor sun &#8212; ‘neath these &#8212; excuse me &#8212;<br>“…‘Neath sun or star or moon, the citadel of Liberty, My mother’s land, aroon.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course,&nbsp;I am not the first Irish American descendent to &#8212; not by a long shot &#8212; to be in this &#8212; in the White House.&nbsp; Fully half of American presidents can claim some ancestral connection to Ireland, including the man who held this job&nbsp;when I was Vice President, Barack Obama.</p>



<p>But it was John F. Kennedy, our &#8212; and his &#8212;</p>



<p>Would you stand up, Ambassador?&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&#8212; our first Irish-Catholic president who visited Ireland in 1963 and said, quote, “Our two nations,&nbsp;divided by distance,&nbsp;have been united by history.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, that’s as true today as it was then.&nbsp; Today, those words feel particularly poignant as Ireland and the United States&nbsp;stand united at this momentous point of history.</p>



<p>Vladimir Putin &#8212; Vladimir Putin has launched an unconscionable war against Ukraine, against the very pillars&nbsp;of international peace and stability.</p>



<p>And as two nations that have fought for freedom, we recognize the courage and determination&nbsp;of the Ukrainian people who defend their liberty now.&nbsp; And they do.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Republic of Ireland and our nation have lived through war.&nbsp; We’re determined, though, to help the Ukrainian people, bring an end to Putin’s brutal assault, and restore peace to the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>As nations that have been marked by emigrants&nbsp;who departed Ireland in coffin ships and the immigrants who sought the safety&nbsp;of new beginnings in the United States, we are open &#8212; and our hearts are open and our arms&nbsp;are open &#8212; to help the more than 3 million Ukrainian refugees who have already fled Putin’s onslaught.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, as the Taoiseach and I affirmed earlier today, Ireland and the United States are going to stay united together with our partners around the world to keep the pressure on Putin and&nbsp;to strengthen our support for Ukraine.</p>



<p>And, by the way, Ireland is supporting the economic sanctions &#8212; taking a gigantic hit, a gigantic hit &#8212; proportionally, more than we have.&nbsp; It took a hell of a lot of courage for the Taoiseach and the Dáil to stand up and do what they did.&nbsp; And I really mean it.&nbsp; You know that, Mr. Ambassador.&nbsp; You know what it’s like.</p>



<p>We’ve also discussed how the United States and Ireland&nbsp;will take on all the challenges we face together.&nbsp;&nbsp;We’re working together to fight COVID-19 and to save lives around the world, to tackle the climate crisis, and to boost global economic recovery.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we’re working &#8212; for real &#8212; side-by-side&nbsp;in the United Nations Security Council, which they’re now members of,&nbsp;to address the humanitarian crisis not only in Ukraine but around the world.</p>



<p>And our nations both are deeply committed to protecting the hard-won gains of peace&nbsp;in Northern Ireland.&nbsp; The Good Friday Agreement&nbsp;has been the foundation of peace and prosperity&nbsp;in Northern Ireland for nearly 25 years, and it cannot change.&nbsp; Cannot change.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have made that point &#8212; and he’s a friend &#8212; to the Prime Minister of England and others: It cannot change.&nbsp; To preserve and extend those gains for all the people in Northern Ireland, <s>and</s> the European Union <s>to make</s> [and] the United Kingdom must continue to resolve challenges over the implementation of the Northern Ireland Protocols.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States stands ready to work with all the communities of Northern Ireland to ensure &#8212; to ensure its extraordinary economic potential and ensure that it’s realized.&nbsp; And we look forward to supporting&nbsp;the next Northern Ireland Executive&nbsp;after the upcoming Assembly elections, which are on their way.</p>



<p>History has proven that &#8212; what the people of Northern Ireland and their leaders can accomplish when they work together.&nbsp;&nbsp;Yeats wrote &#8212; can I quote an Irish poet?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; He wrote the line in one of his poems, “Hope that you may understand.”&nbsp; “Hope that you may understand.”&nbsp; Because for the Irish and for all us Irish Americans, the hoping is essential to understanding and to life, from our perspective.</p>



<p>Hope is what brought forth on the Emerald Isle a nation of poets and patriots, saints, scholars, artists, and engineers.&nbsp;&nbsp;Hope kept us looking toward the far horizon.&nbsp; It urges us &#8212; urges us to &#8212; over every obstacle.&nbsp; It tells us to try again when we fall short, to rise each time we fall.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our mom used to have an expression, “As long as you’re alive, you have an obligation to strive.&nbsp; And you’re not dead until you’ve seen the face of God.”&nbsp; And she meant it.&nbsp; She meant it.</p>



<p>Well, in my view, that’s the Irish of it.&nbsp; And hope is what brought us &#8212; the Irish American kid&nbsp;all the way from Scranton to Wil- &#8212; Scranton to the White House.&nbsp; And with a lifetime of history of hoping comes the deep understanding of what our nations&nbsp;and our people&nbsp;can accomplish.&nbsp; Hope was what brought us here.</p>



<p>And around the same time, my great-great-grandfather Owen Finnegan, a shoemaker, boarded a coffin ship in 1844 in the Irish Sea with another &#8212; near &#8212; five weeks after another shoemaker named Joseph Kearny from Moneygall arrived on another ship in America just five weeks earlier.&nbsp; That was President Obama’s great-great-grandfather.</p>



<p>They were both shoemakers not far from one another.&nbsp; When we were here &#8212; when I first got that &#8212; the genealogy done by the LDS &#8212; by the Mormon’s Church &#8212; the most extensive biological &#8212; archaeologic &#8212; most extensive records on genealogy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’m getting into biology here.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they said it was not sure they’d be able to see one another.&nbsp; But when I went over to Ireland, quote, with my family to go home to meet some of my relatives that I didn’t know &#8212; our relatives we didn’t know &#8212; they indicated the likelihood they were both shoemakers, both not far from one another, both leaving for America five weeks apart &#8212; it is not improbable that they’ve would’ve known one another.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They left everything behind, like all of your relatives, for an uncertain future.&nbsp; But I wonder, in all of their dreams, whether they could’ve ever dreamt that their two great-great-grandsons of shoemakers from Ireland would be sworn in as Presidents of the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I wonder.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s not about me.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about Barack.&nbsp; It’s about hope.&nbsp; Think about it.<br><br>But again, as my grandpop would say, “That’s the Irish of it.”<br><br>So I want to again thank the Taoiseach for making the trip to Washington, even though he cannot be with us today, and for continuing to strengthen the relationship between our two great nations.<br><br>And now, we have a special message from the Taoiseach.</p>



<p>(A video message from Prime Minister Martin is played.)<br><br>PRIME MINISTER MARTIN:&nbsp; Mr. President, First Lady, senators, representatives, ladies and gentlemen, as we gather this year to mark St. Patrick&#8217;s Day, an annual occasion that means so much to so many Americans and to Irish people everywhere, we do so in the consciousness that these are not normal times.<br><br>We are reminded by the appalling events in Ukraine that freedom and democracy can never be taken for granted. &nbsp;Each generation must be ready to stand up and defend them.<br><br>We are reminded also of the lengths that those who oppose democracy are prepared to go to stop others enjoying its benefits.<br><br>In the people of Ukraine, we are reminded of the boundless bravery and resolve of those who love their country and who value its freedom.&nbsp; And importantly, we are reminded of the importance of the shared values and principles which are the bedrock of the enduring friendship between our countries.<br><br>As we confront this crisis, I am reminded of the words of James Joyce, put into the mouth of his 20th century everyman, Leopold Bloom, in “Ulysses,” published a century ago this year by an American woman in Paris, Sylvia Beach.<br><br>Joyce wrote, “Force, hatred, history, all that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not life for men and women, insult and hatred.&nbsp; And everybody knows that it&#8217;s the very opposite of that that is really life.”&nbsp; And that is why we stand together to ensure that what Joyce described as “perpetuating national hatred among nations” shall not prevail in our time.<br><br>This ceremony has a long history.&nbsp; And yet, it has perhaps never meant as much to us as it does this year.&nbsp; And that is because, more than any other president of our times, your family&#8217;s story captures the overlapping stories of Ireland and American.<br><br>The shamrock presented to you today recalls the lives of the Blewitts of County Mayo and the Finnegans from County Louth.&nbsp; I took the opportunity to have the bowl inscribed especially for you in the Irish language, knowing how you would value that.<br><br>Your family&#8217;s perilous journey across the Atlantic, and those of the other Irish names that adorn your family tree, reflect the experience of the millions of Irish people who left their homeland in the 19th century to seek better lives for themselves.<br><br>The departure of so many people from our shores, many at a very young age, left a huge gap in our society and deposited oceans of pain in the hearts of those they left behind, longing for departed family members they never saw again.<br><br>In more recent times, our diaspora has been an inestimable source of strength to us in the search and achievement of peace and political progress in Northern Ireland.<br><br>Mr. President, I salute the immense contribution made by the Congressional Friends of Ireland, of which you were a founding member back in 1981.<br><br>Their efforts were instrumental in securing indispensable American support for the peace process that culminated in the Good Friday Agreement &#8212; an achievement in which I know that you and many other Americans take justifiable pride.<br><br>Your support, Mr. President, and that of our friends in Congress continues to be a vital importance as we seek to protect the Good Friday Agreement from the complications created by the British decision to leave the European Union.<br><br>The United States will always be an influential source of support for the cause of peace and reconciliation in Ireland, something for which we are deeply appreciative.<br><br>Mr. President, your family&#8217;s experience is not just woven into the story of Ireland its immigrants, it is also an integral part of the American story.<br><br>Your Irish ancestors and millions of others from Ireland and around the world strove in their lives to make America the country it is today.&nbsp;<br><br>Their labor, in many cases, literally built America.&nbsp; Theirs was no easy street.&nbsp; As the Irish poet Eavan Boland once wrote, “They would have thrived on our necessities.&nbsp; What they survived we could not even live…Their hardships parceled in them.&nbsp; Patience.&nbsp; Fortitude…And all the old songs.&nbsp; And nothing to lose.”<br><br>Irish Americans rose to occupy prominent positions in every walk of American life, including today in this White House, designed by an Irish architect, James Hoban.<br><br>Your country was transformed in the 50 years after the Civil War, at a time when immigration, including from Ireland, was at its peak.<br><br>For them and countless others like them, America became what Seamus Heaney calls “the further shore” where “the longed-for tidal wave of justice can rise up, and hope and history rhyme.”<br><br>Happy St. Patrick&#8217;s Day, and have a great evening.<br><br>(The video message from Prime Minister Martin concludes.)</p>



<p>(Applause.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Mr. Ambassador, you got to tell him how much he&#8217;s appreciated.&nbsp; Genuinely.<br><br>Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>Folks, now we have &#8212; I don&#8217;t know who&#8217;s going to do the introducing, but now we&#8217;re going to have entertainment that is all Irish.&nbsp; And so, you’ll get me to sit down &#8212; I sit down.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re going to clear the stage.<br><br>And as my &#8212; my father said &#8212; my father &#8212; our father used to have a band when he was a kid.&nbsp; He played the saxophone and the clarinet, and he could dance and he could sing.&nbsp; And he used to say, “Joey, I don&#8217;t know where the hell you came from.&nbsp; You have no lip&#8221; &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; &#8220;you have two left feet, and you can&#8217;t carry a tune in a wheelbarrow.”&nbsp; So I&#8217;m getting the hell off the stage.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p><br>6:09 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, March 17,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/17/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-march-17-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 23:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:55 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Sorry, I think I jumped the two-minute gun.&#160; I was just excited to see you all on St. Patrick&#8217;s Day.&#160; Okay, a couple of items for all of you at the top.&#160; Today, we wanted to highlight the strong unemployment claim data&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:55 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Sorry, I think I jumped the two-minute gun.&nbsp; I was just excited to see you all on St. Patrick&#8217;s Day.&nbsp;<br><br>Okay, a couple of items for all of you at the top.&nbsp; Today, we wanted to highlight the strong unemployment claim data out this morning.&nbsp; In a little over a year, President Biden has brought the American labor market back to one of its strongest positions in history, driving a robust recovery from the economic catastrophe he inherited.&nbsp;<br><br>The number of new jobless claims Americans filing for unemployment for the first time fell below the pre-pandemic average in 2019.&nbsp; And the number of Americans who have been receiving unemployment benefits for more than a week fell to the lowest level since 1970.&nbsp;<br><br>Three hundred thousand fewer Americans are receiving unemployment claims now than before the pandemic.&nbsp; That means more Americans are getting back to work and fewer are drawing governmental &#8212; government benefits.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>As we&#8217;ve said many times, the data can be volatile week to week or month to month, so it&#8217;s important to focus on the broader trends.&nbsp; And those trends show remarkable progress across our economy over the last year, including the fastest year of job growth in U.S. history with 7.4 million jobs created and unemployment down to 3.8 percent.&nbsp;<br><br>I also wanted to mark another historic milestone of 500 million vaccines that we have distributed to the world &#8212; an unprecedented campaign reaching 113 countries, something that has never been done before.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We did not get here by accident.&nbsp; This is a testament to the same whole-of-government effort we applied domestically, navigating logistical, legal, and regulatory processes to get lifesaving vaccines across the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>As we mark today&#8217;s milestone of delivering a half a billion vaccines to the world, let me be clear: Without additional funding from Congress to support getting shots into arms, USAID will have to cut short our crucial and effective efforts to turn vaccines into vaccinations.&nbsp;<br><br>Congress must promptly provide the administration with the urgent funding we need to continue the work of both vaccinating the world and protecting Americans at home.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Last thing I just wanted to note: As you saw this morning reported, Jeff Zients, who has served as our COVID Coordinator, will soon be leaving.&nbsp; So I just wanted to take a moment just to note his service and thank him from the President and all of us.<br><br>The President called on Jeff to lead our COVID-19 response because there is no one better at delivering results.&nbsp; I know this personally.&nbsp; I worked closely with him through many challenges over the course of many years in public service and government.&nbsp;<br><br>And the thing about Jeff is at every moment, at every opportunity, when there is a big challenge &#8212; a pile of manure sometimes &#8212; he dives right in to fix the challenge.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what he does.&nbsp; That is what he has done time and time again through his career in public service.&nbsp;<br><br>And he led this effort to stand up a mass vaccination campaign; achieve equity in vaccinations across communities; ensure that Americans have access to treatments, tests; and embark on an unprecedented global vaccine campaign that we celebrate &#8212; can celebrate today.&nbsp; It would not have happened without Jeff Zients in this job and in this role.<br><br>And we are stronger that he is &#8212; his service and the service of his deputy, Natalie Quillian, who&#8217;s also departing, has literally saved lives in this country.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So we want to thank them for their work, for their leadership, and we will miss them a great deal here.&nbsp;<br><br>Zeke, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp;&nbsp; First, on COVID, the President has had a couple of close calls over the last couple days &#8212; the Second Gentleman and the Irish Prime Minister last night.&nbsp; Has he been tested today?&nbsp; And did he test &#8212; is there a result of that test you can read out?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He was not tested today.&nbsp; He was tested last Sunday. &nbsp;Neither of these individuals were considered close contacts.<br><br>The doctors at the CDC determine what “close contacts” look like.&nbsp; And that &#8212; a close contact is someone who was less than six feet away from an infective &#8212; infected person for a cumulative total of 15 minutes or more over a 24-hour period.&nbsp; That is how they define it.&nbsp;<br><br>And, of course, our doctors look closely at that as well.&nbsp; And neither of these two individuals was &#8212; did he spend that amount of time with.&nbsp; And so, his weekly testing cadence remains as it has been; it has not changed.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know there are a number of particular precautions that exist, you know, to protect the President and keep him safe and healthy.&nbsp; The testing cadence here is not like most people &#8212; or it has &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s true.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but this broader issue, though, of, you know, the President coming into &#8212; maybe not CDC “close contact,” but having close exposure to some people, even for a brief amount of time, it sort of &#8212; you know &#8212; you know, getting into that bubble around the President.&nbsp; You know, this is something that people around the country are dealing with on a daily basis, but they don&#8217;t have the same sort of precautions that are here.&nbsp;<br><br>So, you know, if the President hypothetically were to come down with COVID, is that something &#8212; or any &#8212; or the First Lady or anyone else in this administration &#8212; is that a failure at this point?&nbsp; Or is this just a new fact of life that everyone has to sort of, you know, make &#8212; you know, make peace with at this point?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well &#8212; (a cellphone chimes) &#8212; that was very soothing.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know where that came from.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>I would say our view is: While we&#8217;ve made a significant amount of progress across the country in fighting the pandemic &#8212; with more than 75 percent of adults fully vaccinated, according to the definition of the CDC &#8212; and obviously, we&#8217;ve seen hospitalizations come down across the country, including Washington, D.C., the President was very clear when he made his remarks about COVID just a few weeks ago that we are still working &#8212; we still have work to do to address the pandemic, to fight the pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s exactly why we need additional funding to make sure we have the types of treatments, the types of testing mechanisms to make them free and available to Americans across the country, to make masks available so that people who are uninsured or people who don&#8217;t have the resources can tap into a lot of these &#8212; these effective treatments and effective prevention mechanisms.&nbsp;<br><br>I would say, for us, you&#8217;re right, the testing &#8212; the testing modes are a little bit different around here because we are around the President of the United States and the Vice President and, of course, the First Lady and the Second Gentleman.&nbsp; That means, before you see the President, if you are in for a meeting or you travel with him, you are tested.&nbsp; And everyone has different testing cadences, depending on their frequency of seeing him.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, in anticipation of the call between the President and President Xi tomorrow, has the U.S. government made a determination whether China has decided whether or not to, you know, sort of agree to Russia&#8217;s request to provide assistance for its invasion of Ukraine?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is it still a live ball that the President is going to warn President Xi of off of?&nbsp;&nbsp; Where are they in terms of making that decision?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, why don&#8217;t I give you a little bit more of a preview on the call, and hopefully it will answer exactly your question.&nbsp;<br><br>The President, as I think you&#8217;ve heard him say before and I&#8217;ve said, is a big believer in leader-to-leader diplomacy.&nbsp; And they have a lot to discuss, given the last time the President met with President Xi virtually was last November &#8212; a couple of months ago.<br><br>The meeting tomorrow, in terms of how we got here, came as a direct follow-up to the meeting national &#8212; our national Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, had with his counterpart.&nbsp; They talked about the two presidents meeting or engaging in the near future during that meeting.&nbsp; So, hence, it is happening tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>And that meeting, earlier this week, of course, came at an important moment in the conflict, but it also &#8212; in Ukraine, of course &#8212; it also covered issues beyond Russia&#8217;s invasion, and I would expect &#8212; of Ukraine &#8212; I would expect this meeting would as well, because there are obviously a range of issues that we continue to discuss with the Chinese and the President discusses, of course, when he speaks with President Xi.&nbsp;<br><br>But to go to your question, this is an opportunity for President Biden to assess where President Xi stands.&nbsp; There has been, of course, rhetorical support, or the absence of clear rhetoric and denunciation &#8212; or the absence of denunciation by China of what Russia is doing.&nbsp; This flies in the face, of course, of everything China stands for, including the basic principles of the U.N. Charter, including the basic principles of respect for sovereignty of nations.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so, the fact that China has not denounced what Russia is doing, in and of itself, speaks volumes.&nbsp; And it also speaks volumes not only in Russia or in Ukraine, but around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>And this call also comes as the &#8212; as Jake Sullivan&#8217;s meeting earlier this week, as we have made clear our deep concerns about China&#8217;s alignment with Russia and the potential implications and consequences of that.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So the President will also share his assessment of that during the call, but I don&#8217;t have another &#8212; an update for you on any internal assessment.&nbsp; That is just how we are approaching &#8212; or he is approaching the call tomorrow.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How specific is the President going to be in laying out the consequences for China if they do help Russia?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President is &#8212; never fails to be direct, including in his conversations with President Xi.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ll let the call happen, and I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll have more to read out for you after the call.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you have any idea what military equipment they are thinking about providing Russia?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any assessment of that from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And what do you make of the Putin comments basically calling for a purge of anti-war opponents?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think this is a clear sign that this war is not going how President Putin planned for it to go.&nbsp; And there has been an outpouring of courageous protests and many speaking out against the war, even within Russia.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, his effort to crack down on dissent, to crack down on the freedom of press, on the freedom of media, on the freedom of protest is actually quite consistent with what we&#8217;ve seen his approach to be over the course of the last several years.&nbsp; But I think it&#8217;s an indication of exactly that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Which side requested this call between President Biden and President Xi tomorrow?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It was discussed on the &#8212; during the call &#8212; during the meeting that our National Security Advisor had on Monday.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So are you saying it was mutually agreed upon?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They mutually agreed to move forward with it during that meeting.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Blinken just said that the U.S. is concerned China is considering directly assisting Russia by providing them with more military equipment to use in Ukraine.&nbsp; That is not something that we have heard from the administration before.&nbsp; And so, can I get you to speak to how high of a concern that is from the &#8212; for the White House right now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is a high concern, a significant concern, given our Secretary of State just conveyed that.&nbsp; And certainly, our concerns about China assisting, in any way, Russia as they invade a foreign country is of significant concern and would &#8212; the response to that would be consequences.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Before Russia invaded, the White House was pretty clear that if they did invade, there would be sanctions imposed on them as a result of that.&nbsp; With China, you&#8217;ve just said if they do help Russia, that there will be consequences, but you haven&#8217;t said specifically that they will be sanctions.&nbsp; Can you say, without saying what they are, that they will be sanctioned if they do help Russia with military equipment for this invasion?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to outline what the consequences would look like.&nbsp; And I &#8212; the President, obviously, will speak with President Xi tomorrow, and he&#8217;ll speak directly about that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on that point, just so I&#8217;m clear: I mean, I understand you don&#8217;t want to detail what the consequences could be, but the President in the phone call will make clear not just that there will be consequences but what those consequences could be to Xi?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll have more to read out after the call happens tomorrow.&nbsp; But we have not &#8212; our National Security Advisor, obviously, didn&#8217;t hold back in his conversation he had.&nbsp; Our Secretary of State did not hold back in his comments he just made publicly.&nbsp; And the President always takes the opportunity when he speaks with foreign leaders to be candid and direct.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said the phone call is going to be an opportunity to assess where Xi stands. &nbsp;Should we take that to mean that it&#8217;s not clear that the Chinese have made up their mind whether or not to assist the Russians?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think if you look at the last couple of weeks, Mary, you can see that they abstained from a vote in the U.N. Security Council, but they also &#8212; and they sp- &#8212; they had put out a comment during the Munich Security Conference defending the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine, but they also echoed some of the conspiracy theories about chemical weapons and U.S. and Ukrainian intentions.<br><br>So, for any country, it&#8217;s a question of where you want to be as the history books are written.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you believe that this is a sign that &#8212; or can you characterize at all your understanding of how low the Russians may be running on some military equipment, given that they seem to be turning to China for some help?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t provide an assessment on that from here.&nbsp; But, you know, I know my colleagues at the Department of Defense have conveyed clearly &#8212; and I&#8217;m happy to echo &#8212; that it&#8217;s not only not going as they planned; they have had challenges, obviously, with the operations of equipment, with the amount of equipment, even with MREs and food and other supplies.&nbsp; And, you know, that is what we have seen occur on the ground, but I don&#8217;t have a numerical summary from here.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; So, one of the clearest responses we have seen from the Chinese about their possibly helping Russia came from the Foreign Minister, Wang Yi, who told Spanish officials on a call, “China is not a party to the crisis, nor does it want the sanctions to affect China.”&nbsp; What sanctions are they talking about?&nbsp; Did Jake Sullivan specifically bring up the sanctions during the meeting in Rome?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to what he meant.&nbsp; You&#8217;d have to ask the Chinese.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, has the Chinese expressed the same thing to the U.S. &#8212; that they do not want to run the risk of being sanctioned?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would &#8212; the Chinese would speak for themselves.&nbsp; We typically don&#8217;t speak for others.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, just now, Secretary Blinken joined Ambassador Greenfield and the President in describing Putin’s actions as war crimes.&nbsp; I know that you said just yesterday that there is a legal process that is ongoing.&nbsp; How long does that process typically take?&nbsp; How much evidence do we need to collect?&nbsp; And can you clarify who will ultimately determine whether these are war crimes or not?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think Secretary Blinken, in his remarks, also gave some specifics about who from the State Department will be leading that effort.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a legal process where they review all of the evidence, and then they provide that evidence and data and information to the international bodies that oversee the investigations.&nbsp; And the international bodies that oversee the investigations would make determinations about violation of international law and whether it&#8217;s war crimes by their standards and what the consequences would be.&nbsp;<br><br>So we would be supporting those efforts.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you know how long that usually takes?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A legal process internally in the State Department?&nbsp; It can take some time.&nbsp; But again, I can&#8217;t &#8212; I would point to the State Department for any update they want to provide on the timeline.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And one more on Jeff Zients.&nbsp; He and Dr. Ashish Jha, who&#8217;s going to replace him, have such very different backgrounds and different skillsets.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what does that say about how the stage of the pandemic has evolved from then and now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I would say: What it says is that Jeff Zient&#8217;s superpower is that he is an operational and managerial guru of sorts and someone who has taken those skills to a range of jobs he&#8217;s had throughout his career, including in the Obama-Biden administration when he oversaw the fixing of Healthcare.gov and oversaw the fixing of the technology that was severely broken and outdated within government at that time.&nbsp;<br><br>So, when we came into this administration &#8212; I would remind you it&#8217;s now a long time ago &#8212; there was no real plan.&nbsp; We were left no plan by our predecessors.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;We needed to put in place a plan to not only get enough access to vaccines but also ensure there are enough vaccinators and vaccine locations.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a massive operational undertaking.<br><br>Right now, we&#8217;re at a point in the process where we have all of the tools and we know the operational systems that are needed.&nbsp; And so, right now, it&#8217;s the appropriate time.&nbsp; And Jeff, of course, made this decision on his own.&nbsp; He extended a couple of times to stay longer through some ups and downs in the pandemic.<br><br>We&#8217;re having a public health expert, somebody who&#8217;s as kno- &#8212; as well known as &#8212; Dr. Jha &#8212; is effective in communicating with the country about how we&#8217;re going to continue to approach and tackle the pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The President called Putin a “war criminal” yesterday.&nbsp; The Secretary of State just said that that was also his view today.&nbsp; So, given all of that, why are we still having Putin&#8217;s Russia broker the Iran nuclear deal talks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that it&#8217;s not in our interest for Iran to acquire a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; And Russia is a member of the P5+1.&nbsp; So, that is the pursuit of a deal that would be in our national security interests.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, basically we’re just stuck working with him?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think how the President and any of the P5+1 partners or Europeans or others look at this is: If we can achieve a diplomatic solution where we prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon &#8212; despite the efforts by former President Trump to pull us out of the deal, allowing Iran to move far- &#8212; move closer to acquiring a nuclear weapon, that would be good for our national security and good for global security around the world.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Iran Nuclear Agreement Review Act says that Congress is required to review any new agreement.&nbsp; This is obviously not the same agreement that Obama worked on in 2015.&nbsp; Does President Biden believe that this treaty needs the advice and consent of Congress?&nbsp; And if so, does he believe he has the votes to lawfully affirm it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, if &#8212; if and when we have a deal &#8212; and we don&#8217;t have a deal at this point; otherwise, you would all know &#8212; we would carefully consider the facts and circumstances of any U.S. return to the JCPOA to determine the legal implications, including those under the Iran Nuclear Review Act of 2015.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re committed to ensuring the requirements are satisfied.&nbsp; So, certainly, we would abide by that.<br><br>But we have been keeping members very updated.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been briefing them regularly.&nbsp; Brett McGurk conducted a call just a couple days ago.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been briefing them with a range of national security officials.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, has the IGRC &#8212; or &#8212; done any &#8212; or rather, the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, the IRGC &#8212; has it done anything to be eligible to be removed from the terror blacklist?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think you&#8217;re asking me this because it&#8217;s been out there as a possible discussion, but there&#8217;s no deal at this point.&nbsp; So, if and when there&#8217;s a deal, we&#8217;ll have a discussion about what&#8217;s in the deal.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Outside of the deal, though, does it take action to be removed from that terror blacklist?&nbsp; Do you have to do something to get off of it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You have to make a decision, yes.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I want to ask you a slightly different version of a question that I asked you yesterday &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; about the $800 million military assistance.&nbsp; I asked if you could tell us how quickly it would arrive.&nbsp; And I understand this is a complicated process.&nbsp; To flip it around a little bit, can you tell us how quickly will the first shipment be out the door?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve been doing shipments or deliveries every day or every couple of days.&nbsp; And obviously, the Department of Defense would have more specifics.&nbsp;<br><br>But we have effectively and successfully delivered $300 million in military assistance to the Ukrainians on the ground over just the last two weeks.&nbsp; And our effort would be to continue to rapidly provide infor- &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And of this &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; provide equipment.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; of this new tranche, this new $800 million announcement, can you give us &#8212; just characterize how quickly this round will start to be sent (inaudible)?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the operations of that would be led by the Department of Defense, so I would point you to them for more operational specifics.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to stay on the Department of Defense &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the Defense Secretary was speaking with his Slovakian counterpart who said that they were willing to send long-range S-300 surface-to-air missiles if the U.S. would backfill.&nbsp; Does the administration see this as a done deal, as something that is imminent, that would happen?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s the decision of any foreign country, as a sovereign country, to decide what equipment they want to provide.&nbsp; What we are mindful of is ensuring that we are maintaining &#8212; we have to be careful in our desire to support other countries, that we&#8217;re not inadvertently impacting NATO readiness or capabilities or our own.<br><br>And again, this is something the Department of Defense can most effectively speak to, but a lot of these military systems would &#8212; some of them require months to manufacture or to build.&nbsp; We just don&#8217;t &#8212; we don&#8217;t have a warehouse of just military equipment that&#8217;s ready to typically be sent all the time.&nbsp; So, that is a factor.&nbsp;<br><br>But we want to find a solution that both enables Allies and partners to provide the support they have available to Ukraine, while addressing the very real need to backfill their defense systems, which is often a significant challenge.&nbsp;<br><br>And we just want to make sure that if and when our Allies are donating material, including us, they&#8217;re not leaving a gap in their own defenses.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just, finally, Ukrainian refugees are being turned away at the southern border &#8212; I know you’ve gotten some questions about this &#8212; because of Title 42, obviously put in place in the early days of COVID-19.&nbsp; Where is the administration in trying to work around this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, right now, as I noted I think the other day, there are discussions about any ways we could be helpful in welcoming refugees into the United States, something the President &#8212; Ukrainian refugees, of course &#8212; we welcome many refugees, as you know &#8212; something the President is willing, of course; happy to do.<br><br>The role we&#8217;ve been playing to date, Kristen, has been really providing humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve provided $300 million in humanitarian assistance to the people in Ukraine and neighboring countries.&nbsp; A lot of that is going to help provide support to refugees.&nbsp; Three million in three weeks, which is a startling number, that are going to neighboring countries.&nbsp;<br><br>And the bipartisan funding bill the President just signed a couple of days ago provides more than $4 billion in humanitarian assistance, including $2.65 billion through the USAID International Disaster Assistance program, which provides everything from food, healthcare, other urgent support, and $1.4 billion for migration and refugee assistance to support refugees fleeing Ukraine.<br><br>But that is where &#8212; because the vast, vast majority of refugees want to stay in neighboring countries, that is where we have been focusing our energies at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has been clear that he welcomes those who do want to come here.&nbsp; But given this law, it &#8212; are there discussions about revoking Title 42?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The revocation of Title 42 wouldn&#8217;t be done in response to a war in a European country.&nbsp; It&#8217;s done by a decision &#8212; would be made by the CDC, and then it would be implemented when that is done.&nbsp; And it will be done, at some point, of course, with the interagency, including the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp;<br><br>But, you know, there is a range of discussions about if there are ways for Ukrainian refugees to come.&nbsp; Right now, they&#8217;d have to apply, obviously, through existing refugee programs where they would apply from a third country.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Given the COVID surge in China and the lockdowns that we&#8217;re seeing there, is supply chain issues and, you know, those getting worse, perhaps, going to be part of the call tomorrow at all, or is it focused on &#8212; mostly on Russia?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It will be focused on a range of issues.&nbsp; Certainly Russia and Ukraine &#8212; Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine will be a part of that, but our economic relationship with China, a range of issues of mutual concern will certainly be a discussion.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I will &#8212; we will have more to read out for you once the &#8212; once the meeting concludes tomorrow.<br><br>And this is, of course, an issue that we are watching very closely.&nbsp; While the ports, I believe, still remain open, one of the challenges we&#8217;ve seen on the ground and we are tracking very closely is the number of manufacturing facilities or the number of workers who are not working.&nbsp; Sometimes there&#8217;s a lag in what that impact can be in terms of the production of materials and how that impacts the supply chain.&nbsp; So, we are tracking that very closely.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But again, I expect this to be a wide-ranging conversation tomorrow.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more to read out once it&#8217;s concluded.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also, just to follow up on the President being around some people who’ve &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; now tested positive, why not just test the President every day at this point?&nbsp; The administration has done a lot in terms of, you know, saying certain actions are being done out of an abundance of caution.&nbsp; So, in this case, even if it doesn&#8217;t quite follow CDC guidelines or goes above and beyond, why not just do that because he&#8217;s the President?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because we&#8217;re guided by his medical doctor, and he has kept him at the same cadence.&nbsp; And if that changes, then we will change how often he&#8217;s tested.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is the cadence once a week?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Questions on a couple of different topics.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To try this a different way: Does the President have specific things he wants to accomplish in tomorrow’s conversation with President Xi?&nbsp; Are there specific deliverables he&#8217;s hoping to get out of it?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, this is, again, an opportunity for him to speak directly, leader to leader, about a range of issues.&nbsp; Of course, the invasion of Russia &#8212; Russia inva- &#8212; Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine will be a part of that, and what role or how &#8212; how President Xi sees the role of China in that conflict will be a part of that.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s also a range of other topics that they will discuss.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m purposely leaving some space for the President to have a direct conversation with his counterpart.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the COVID cases that &#8212; for example, with the Second Gentleman testing positive this week, why did the Vice President appear today &#8212; I understand she was masked &#8212; but in an event with other people around, when CDC guidance is currently that people who have been exposed should stay home and not interact with others for five days?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, she is fully boosted.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t actually believe that&#8217;s an accurate description of CDC guidance of having a close contact.&nbsp; We, obviously, all have had close contacts here.&nbsp;&nbsp; And you&#8217;re tested at a regular cadence.&nbsp; And she is abiding by that.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just to kind of follow up on that<br>bit on COVID: Is one of the reasons why the administration is not going &#8212; being extra cautious with the President and the Vice President, even though there is national security issue around this, in part to kind of lead by example for Americans to say, “You can get back to living your normal lives, and you shouldn&#8217;t be concerned that even if you get exposed to somebody just briefly, you shouldn&#8217;t freak out about that.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t need to test a bunch of times”?&nbsp; Is that basically the dynamic that you&#8217;re trying to say &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Look &#8212; oh, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; even though if the President &#8212; 79 years old &#8212; the President of the United States were to get COVID, it might be more serious than, you know, somebody in their twenties?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t know that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; We don’t.&nbsp; But (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But we also know that COVID impacts people of all ages and a range of &#8212; but we take &#8212; what we do here, Jen, is not &#8212; not exactly as you said.&nbsp; So I wouldn&#8217;t agree with your description there.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I would say we do take extra precautions, including individuals who are around the President being tested &#8212; that goes over and above, of course.&nbsp; He is the President of the United States, so we do take those additional steps.&nbsp; And we, of course, abide by what the recommendations and advice are of his medical doctor.&nbsp; And if that would be to do increased testing, we would certainly do that.&nbsp; But he does not feel that that is necessary at this point in time based on these recent contacts.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also wanted to ask about oil and gas companies and &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s been some reports, from the fourth quarter, of them increasing their stock buybacks.&nbsp; There was already, you know, a time when there was a spike in gas prices last year, I think in the fourth quarter.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re also just seeing the companies saying that they&#8217;re kind of reluctant to up production.&nbsp; And they kind of, in some ways, point to the administration&#8217;s policies overall in the sense that even if they were to up production, that, one, it takes months to get to market; and two, it doesn&#8217;t fit in with the overall approach that this administration is taking.&nbsp; So what do you say to that kind of viewpoint?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s hard for them to make the argument it&#8217;s anything other than business decisions on their part, and they have said that themselves.&nbsp;<br><br>The CEO of Occidental Petroleum said, quote, “We have no need and no intent to invest in production growth this year.”<br><br>The CEO of Marathon Oil said, quote, “Our cash flow-driven return of capital framework uniquely prioritizes our shareholders as the first call on cash flow generation, not the drill bit.”<br><br>The CEO of Pioneer Natural Resources said, quote, “We&#8217;re not going to change our growth rate.”&nbsp; “We think it&#8217;s important to return cash back to shareholders.”&nbsp; That&#8217;s a business decision.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The oil and gas industry right now is receiving profit &#8212; windfall profits; we&#8217;ve seen that.&nbsp; They publicly report their profits.&nbsp; They publicly report this information.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And instead of keeping up with current demand, too many of these companies, in our view, are making the calculated decision of returning money to investors and shareholders through buybacks and dividends, instead of expanding production enough in the short term, which is what we need.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, it&#8217;s a business decision, but I think there&#8217;s clear evidence of them acknowledging and even shouting that out.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I have a China question and, with full awareness of the news cycle, a St. Patrick’s Day question.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; All right.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; China question first.&nbsp; About a week ago, you said that for everything else, by and large, the White House saw China as still abiding by international sanctions.&nbsp; But on Russia, does that view still hold a week later?&nbsp; Is that generally how the White House views China?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a new assessment of that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re obviously watching very closely.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; St. Patrick&#8217;s Day.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given the fact that the President very much likes to share his pride of the Iri- &#8212; his Irish heritage but also the fact that &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He does.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; so many ceremonial&#8211;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; “More Irish than Irish.”&nbsp; Is that what he said?&nbsp; “Irish Americans consider themselves more Irish.”&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s true.&nbsp; I will confirm that.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But like that, and also the fact that so many of the ceremonial parts of the job &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; have been canceled over the past year, I&#8217;m wondering: Did he express particular frustration or sadness that the Oval meeting had to become yet another Zoom meeting today?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He was disappointed.&nbsp; He was looking forward to having the meeting today.&nbsp; And having meetings over Zoom, I think as we&#8217;ve all experienced, are not the same.&nbsp; Having spent a lot of time with the President, he is an extrovert, extrovert, extrovert and loves that engagement with people in person.&nbsp; And he was really looking forward to the meeting today.&nbsp;<br><br>There will be more in the future.&nbsp; We certainly understand we are still facing the pandemic.&nbsp; And there are more events that he has been able to participate in today to celebrate St. Patrick&#8217;s Day.&nbsp; So, fortunately, many of them still moved forward.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Yesterday, in his remarks to the Congress, President Zelenskyy called for the creation of this new global organization that he called “U-24. United for Peace,” described as an alliance that would supply assistance, including weapons, within 24 hours.&nbsp; I was wondering if the administration has a view on that idea.&nbsp; Is it something that you guys are discussing with Ukraine?&nbsp; And does the U.S. view this as Zelenskyy’s, kind of, alternative for Ukraine entering NATO?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, just to reiterate, it&#8217;s up to NATO to determine who enters NATO.&nbsp; And obviously, any country, we would support their aspiration to join NATO should they choose and they meet the requirements.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We, of course, did see him convey that in the speech.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have more details.&nbsp; We are very closely engaged with the Ukrainians and speak with them every day.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Beyond that, I would say: In terms of the delivery of weapons, we do it as quickly as we humanly possibly can through our system and in coordination with our NATO partners and Allies.&nbsp; But we know &#8212; we support a range of ideas being put out there.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll discuss it with the Europeans and others and see if there&#8217;s more to report out from there.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also wanted to try one more time on &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the President and COVID.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A lot of the questions are focused on testing, which you&#8217;re pretty clear that the testing cadence is not changing.&nbsp; As he looks particularly to a trip next week that is quite important &#8212; to Brussels and maybe elsewhere in Europe &#8212; is there anything else that he&#8217;s doing, I mean, as he&#8217;s having these &#8212; what the CDC does not consider a close contact but are certain people that he&#8217;s around and aware of &#8212; is anything about his behavior changing?&nbsp; Are there any other precautions that you guys are taking that are not testing-related?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have continued to take the same testing protocol &#8212; steps which are significant and go farther than CDC guidance goes.&nbsp; But beyond that, the te- &#8212; his testing cadence remains the same, and there haven&#8217;t been additional changes to our internal protocols.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The Kremlin responded to President Biden labeling Putin a “war criminal” yesterday by calling his remarks “unacceptable and unforgivable.”&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s reaction to getting criticism from Russia about the President&#8217;s remarks?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s pretty rich coming from a country where &#8212; whose actions are unforgivable in the eyes of the world &#8212; global community.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given that there&#8217;s an ongoing legal process and investigation by the State Department into whether there was, in fact, war crimes committed, what is the purpose of the President and now Secretary of State getting ahead of that investigation?<br><br>I know you said &#8212; or the Pr- &#8212; you said yesterday that the President was speaking from his heart.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that what this is &#8212; just speaking from their heart?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think Secretary Blinken was as well.&nbsp; And as you heard Secretary Blinken convey in his remarks, what we&#8217;re seeing &#8212; whether it is the destruction of a theater, where the words “children” or “kids” was written in Russian outside of the theater, according to photos; or whether it is the, you know, targeting of civilians, of hospitals, of maternity wards &#8212; if that&#8217;s not considered a war crime by human beings, what is?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And there is a legal process that is important to continue that we have at the State Department that is ongoing, that Secretary Blinken spoke about.&nbsp; And any of that information and data we gather would go to the international bodies that would have prosecuted war criminals in the past.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where that information would go.&nbsp; It wouldn&#8217;t be the United States doing that; it&#8217;s the international bodies that do that.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, we will continue to feed information into that.&nbsp;&nbsp;But, you know, I think it&#8217;s important to call out what we see happening on the ground, and I think that&#8217;s exactly what the President and the Secretary did.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Even though it would go to those international bodies, would the U.S. have a response if that investigation does conclude that there were war crimes?&nbsp; Would &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, typically, it&#8217;s an international response and it goes through these international systems for a reason.&nbsp; So we will continue to provide data and information to that process.<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, if I can have one more question on behalf of a colleague?&nbsp; There are growing calls from civil rights advocates and some lawmakers to pass Temporary Protected Status for Cameroon.&nbsp;&nbsp;Some have alleged a double standard in how the administration prioritizes pretominant [sic] &#8212; predominantly Black and brown countries when it comes to immigration.&nbsp; For example, it took seven months to grant TPS status for Afghanistan, but only took about a week to grant TPS to Ukraine.&nbsp; Is TPS for Cameroon something the administration is considering and looking at?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’d point you to the Department of Homeland Security, who oversees that process.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; This morning, Senator Mitch McConnell was talking about Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson on the Senate floor, and he was specifically talking about how some of her supporters have framed her experience as a public defender.&nbsp; He said, quote, “If any judicial nominee…does have special empathy for some parties over others, that&#8217;s not an asset.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a problem.”&nbsp; He also said the President is “deliberately working to make the whole federal judiciary softer on crime.”&nbsp; Do you have a response to that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He also said he expected her to get confirmed with some Republican votes.<br><br>What I would say, though &#8212; because there are others in the Senate who have made faulty accusations about Judge Ketanji&nbsp; Brown Jackson&#8217;s record and specifically about her record on child sex crimes, so let me just take the opportunity to clear that up &#8212; not that most people have confusion about it.&nbsp;<br><br>But in the vast majority of cases involving child sex crimes, the sentences Judge Jackson imposed were consistent with or above what the government or U.S. probation recommended.&nbsp; For example, there are &#8212; there are arguments that have been made out there by Senator Hawley and others that &#8212; where he took a snippet of a transcript out of context, when, in fact, Judge Jackson was repeating something a witness said in order to ask a question about their testimony.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So some who are accusing her of being, quote, “soft on crime” also failed to note that what was omitted is a sentencing commission report that&#8217;s been touted out there, was unanimously supported by a bipartisan Sentencing Commission.<br><br>She comes from a law enforcement family, has devoted her career to standing up for the rule of law, which is why she is endorsed by so many leading law enforcement organizations in the country.&nbsp; And attempts to smear or discredit her history and her work are not borne out in facts.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know Monday is a long ways away, given the news cycle &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s all relative.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Will the President stop at around 11:00 to watch the beginning of the hearing up on Capitol Hill?&nbsp; And will his schedule be adjusted around that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know what his schedule is yet.&nbsp; I&#8217;m certain that he will catch coverage or catch some of her hearings over the course of next week.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t know what his schedule looks like yet for Monday.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; You have already announced President Biden’s trip to Europe, to Brussels.&nbsp; But there were also reports about a possible trip to Poland.&nbsp; Can you confirm that such a trip is under consideration?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more details about his trip to announce at this point in time.&nbsp; As we have them, we will announce them all to you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; There are negotiations ongoing between Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; Does the White House support those negotiations?&nbsp; And what &#8212; what&#8217;s &#8212; how can you describe your involvement &#8212; the U.S. involvement in those talks between Russia and Ukraine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve been involved in a couple of ways.&nbsp; One, we&#8217;ve been leading the effort to build support in the global community to put in place sanctions that are crippling the Russian economy, to provide military support and economic support to the Ukrainians that strengthen their hand as they participate in these discussions and negotiations.&nbsp; And we also engage every day with Ukrainians to discuss.<br><br>Obviously, I would note that, as you know, our National Security Advisor also talked to his counterpart yesterday as well.&nbsp; But we are continuing to support the Ukrainians’ efforts.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>What our concern is, though, is &#8212; you know, these diplomatic talks &#8212; as they&#8217;re ongoing, we have seen no effort, no movement, no evidence that President Putin and the Russians are de-escalating.&nbsp; And that is really what we are going to continue to closely watch.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow-up on your point about Senator Hawley.&nbsp; Obviously, he&#8217;s consistently voted against the President&#8217;s nominees.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think he was a swing vote you guys were counting on.&nbsp; However, will his criticism, will the explosiveness of this line of attack &#8212; do you worry that it will affect your ability to win over other Republican votes?&nbsp; Is there any concern about this campaign upping the pressure on, say, Senators Collins and Murkowski, who may be more amenable to voting for (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not sure that someone who refused to tell people whether or not he would vote for Roy Moore is an effective and credible messenger on this.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to try again on President Biden and President Xi&#8217;s call tomorrow.&nbsp; If you won&#8217;t detail the consequences of what happens if China does start supporting &#8212; more support Russia, might you indicate whether there are any carrots that the administration has prepared to offer, perhaps tariff reductions?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, this is a conversation about where President Xi stands.&nbsp; It&#8217;s up to the Chinese to decide where they want to stand, where they want to be as the history books are written.&nbsp; So I think it&#8217;s more through that frame than it is about carrots.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then just one more &#8212; two more, actually.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As the administration continues to condemn and take action against Russia&#8217;s invasion on Ukraine, are there any plans to revisit, review, revoke the Trump administration&#8217;s recognition of Israel&#8217;s annexation on the Golan Heights and Morocco&#8217;s annexation of Western Sahara?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates on that front.&nbsp; I&#8217;d point to the State Department.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But at this point, can you &#8212; can you describe just the administration&#8217;s position on the difference between Russia&#8217;s invasion on Ukraine and Israel&#8217;s annexation of the Golan Heights?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’d point you to the State Department.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then one more.&nbsp; One more logistical question.&nbsp; Cambodia, the chair of ASEAN, has announced last week that the U.S.-ASEAN summit that the President is supposed to host on the 28th, I believe, is postponed.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t been able to get a confirmation from either you guys or State.&nbsp; Can you clarify on that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates on the schedule.&nbsp; I know we were working through the schedules of a number of leaders, so that&#8217;s always a challenge and a factor.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any updates.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So it’s still on the table?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates on it.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Two on COVID.&nbsp; There are some Americans who have received a second booster &#8212; i.e., for a fourth total shot.&nbsp; Is that something that the President has done or will do?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has not done that.&nbsp; If the CDC recommends it, he would get another booster.&nbsp; They have not.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, the White House Chief of Staff Ron Klain, in a tweet today, celebrated the idea that &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Uh-oh.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know who he is &#8212; said &#8212; and that he tweets.&nbsp; You said &#8212; he said &#8212; celebrated the idea that there is a low number of Americans in ICUs today because of COVID.&nbsp; But he also wrote, quote, there&#8217;s a “great risk of a new wave.”&nbsp; And there are &#8212; certainly, we&#8217;re seeing cases surge right now in China and in Europe.&nbsp; And one of the truisms of this pandemic: If it&#8217;s in Europe, it ends up here a few weeks later.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What precautions and preparations is the administration taking federally and encouraging states to take ahead of a possible new COVID wave?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, what we have seen &#8212; and I think you&#8217;re talking about the BA.2 variant &#8212; and we are closely watching and monitoring the situation both in Europe and in China &#8212; BA.2 is a more transmissible version of Omicron.&nbsp; But we do know the tools the United States has &#8212; including the mRNA vaccines, therapeutics, and tests &#8212; all are effective tools against this variant.<br><br>And China has not used mRNA vaccines, which is an important component of how we&#8217;re seeing the response there &#8212; or how it&#8217;s impacting people there.&nbsp; But BA.2 has been circulating a little different from Omicron, when we were going through that surge in November.&nbsp; It has been circulating here for some time.&nbsp; We currently &#8212; it may be higher than this, but as of earlier this week, there were about 35,000 cases in this country.&nbsp; And we expect some fluctuation, especially at this relatively low level.<br><br>But this is an example of where the President&#8217;s Preparedness Plan that we rolled out just a couple of weeks ago, which lays out what the tools are that we need to move forward safely, is important.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we&#8217;ve been conveying to governors, to go to your question, or leaders around the country and certainly members of Congress, is that just because COVID isn&#8217;t disrupting some of our lives in certain communities as much as it was a few weeks ago, it doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s gone; it&#8217;s not gone.&nbsp; And I think this variant is an example of that.<br><br>We do know what we need to manage it.&nbsp; But we are also at great risk of running out of money to do exactly that.&nbsp; And so that is a key part of what we&#8217;re communicating to governors, to members of Congress, and others about where we are with funding and the need to end some of these programs soon if we don&#8217;t get the funding we need.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a very short, quick follow-up.&nbsp; Is there concern, though, that this variant, which is more &#8212; it seems very transmissible &#8212; is coming at a moment when a lot of Americans are seeing waning protection from their boosters just because the timing of the shots, as well as the fact that mask guidelines and other restrict- &#8212; regulations have been lifted across the country?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I would point to our medical experts to answer that.&nbsp; I mean, it is more transmissible, but we know it can be treated.&nbsp; So I think what it is &#8212; is a reminder of is that while it has decreased in many parts of the country, it is not gone, and it means we still need to continue to take steps we can to fight the virus.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Japan hosts the largest number of U.S. military, about 50,000 troops, about a half a million Americans at any given time in Japan.&nbsp; And many Japanese remember, at that time, Vice President Biden came all the way to Japan about 10 years ago when there was a terrible disaster, but there&#8217;s been no interview with any Japanese media.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think we could arrange that?&nbsp; Just to assure them that the treaty is enforced.&nbsp; Especially the Senkaku, the southern islands, they&#8217;re very worried about &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President does have &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could we get a positive &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He does have a great deal of affection for Japan and has spoken, of course, with their &#8212; the current leader a couple of times.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to take your interview requests under &#8212; under advisement.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about the refugee situation in Ukraine.&nbsp; Does the White House see the refugee situation that was created in Afghanistan last year as different than the one created by Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the reason I say that is &#8212; is your policy response different?&nbsp; I hear you say that your understanding is that neighboring countries &#8212; that&#8217;s where people are going from Ukraine right now and not necessarily coming here.&nbsp; But, at some point, is that going to not be an option anymore?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s different, in part, for the reason you mentioned.&nbsp; That &#8212; in Ukraine, there are &#8212; while there have been 3 million refugees or about that number over the last couple of weeks, they have been &#8212;&nbsp;the vast, vast majority of them have moved into countries &#8212; neighboring countries who have set up really remarkable systems for welcoming these refugees at a really challenging and difficult time.&nbsp;<br><br>I know there&#8217;s been a lot of reporting from a lot of your networks in Poland and other places where they have had systems in place to welcome refugees.&nbsp; That has been the preference of a &#8212; of these refugees.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we have been providing our humanitarian assistance to these countries and to Ukraine directly, in order to help augment the support in &#8212; in the best way possible.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Every refugee circumstance is different and has different needs and requirements.&nbsp; And we try to adapt our own response from USAID or from our refugee and migration programming and funding to meet what the needs are in that conflict.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also wanted to ask, on a completely different topic: The President, in the State of the Union, said that he would sign an executive order on identity theft.&nbsp; And I think he called it &#8220;pandemic aid fraud&#8221; or something similar.&nbsp; Do you have an update on where that is?&nbsp; I know it hasn&#8217;t been published yet.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let&#8217;s see.&nbsp; What we know at this point in time is that &#8212; I mean, he talked about addressing unemployment fraud &#8212; right? &#8212; through the pandemic.&nbsp; And so, what we&#8217;re doing now is ensuring that we&#8217;re taking steps toward that.<br><br>Last week, the Department of Justice announced a new chief pandemic prosecutor.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working to escalate efforts to crack down on bad actors and support and augment that.&nbsp; But in terms of the executive order, I don&#8217;t have an update on the timeline on it.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead in the back.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, two questions: one foreign policy, one domestic.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I like the setup.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So are you &#8212; what do you make of the fact that there now appear to be Chechen and maybe Syrian regular forces fighting on behalf of Russia in Ukraine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any confirmation of that from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the domestic front, Kathy Hochul, the governor of New York, proposed today making changes to the state&#8217;s progressive bail reform law.&nbsp; And it looks like Mayor Adams, who I think we can describe as an ally of the President, would support those changes.&nbsp; So does this administration stand by it&#8217;s &#8212; what I would describe as a “wholesale endorsement” of bail reform?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to check on the specifics of the New York changes.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t looked into those.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to do that and talk to our Counsel&#8217;s Office about that, and we&#8217;ll get back to you.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the Chinese have been very public about how they&#8217;re going to continue their normal economic activity with Russia.&nbsp; Is the President going to press President Xi on that?&nbsp; And is he going to ask them to sort of back off their activity like the rest of the world?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that the conversation tomorrow will be a continuation of the conversation our National Security Advisor had with his counterpart earlier this week.&nbsp; And certainly, China&#8217;s alignment with Russia, in a range of ways, is and the potential implications and consequences of that are a central part of that conversation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, domestically, on another subject, the Congressional Progressive Caucus Recommendations for Executive Action are out, and they&#8217;re asking for a decision to declare a climate emergency and ban all U.S. exports of oil.&nbsp; Is that something that President is thinking about doing (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are a range of really good ideas out there.&nbsp; The President is looking at all of them.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you at this point in time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last quick one to start for the room: When is the President going to nominate a new Fed nominee?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that one of the most eminently qualified people ever to be nominated only withdrew her nomination, I think, 48 hours ago, 72 hours ago; it&#8217;s all running together.&nbsp;<br><br>He very much intends to nominate another eminently qualified person, but I don&#8217;t have an update on the timeline of that.&nbsp; Let the financial wires games begin.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; If the U.S. plans to still engage with Russia on the Iran nuclear deal and perhaps some of these other climate initiatives, what does President Biden expect Russia to bring to the table?&nbsp; I know what the goal is &#8212; that we don&#8217;t want Iran to have a nuclear weapon &#8212; but how does the President think that Putin will be helpful after the President rightfully turns him into a pariah on the global stage?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As it relates to the Iran nuclear deal?&nbsp; I think that our view on this is that it&#8217;s not, obviously, in our interest and it&#8217;s not in Russia&#8217;s interests either for Iran to acquire a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, while these negotiations &#8212; I mean, the people are back in their capitals at this point in time, as you know, but they&#8217;re, for all intensive purposes, ongoing.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>There have been roles and implementation that Russia has had in the past.&nbsp; But I think what we recognize is that it&#8217;s not in their interest either.&nbsp; And we will consider &#8212; continue pursuing the diplomatic path forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more.&nbsp; The New York Times has authenticated emails that appear to have come from a laptop abandoned by Hunter Biden in Delaware.&nbsp; The President previously said that the New York Post story about this was &#8220;a bunch of garbage&#8221; and that it was &#8220;a Russian plant.&#8221;&nbsp; Does he stand by that assessment?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;d point you to the Department of Justice and also to Hunter Biden&#8217;s representatives.&nbsp; He doesn&#8217;t work in the government.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; So, there are the recent peace talks going on between Ukraine, Russia, as was already mentioned.&nbsp; It seems that a couple of the things that are being floated &#8212; one, some sort of withdrawal by Russia, but they still hold on to these pieces of Ukraine they already have in the east and Crimea.&nbsp;<br><br>So, my first question is: Would the U.S. ever back that kind of deal if it&#8217;s something that Ukrainians agreed or felt they had to agree to?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re here to support the Ukrainians, but we&#8217;re not going to negotiate about a negotiation that has not &#8212; has not resulted in even the implementation of humanitarian corridors at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fair enough.&nbsp; But the other thing that&#8217;s been floated by Zelenskyy himself is that &#8212; he basically said the other day, “Ukrainians, get used to that we’re not going to be in NATO,&nbsp;they&#8217;re never going to want us.”<br><br>But then, he said, “What we would like is some kind of other security guarantees.”&nbsp; Is that something that you&#8217;re talking about to them?&nbsp; And what on Earth would that look like &#8212; &#8220;security guarantees&#8221;?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a de- &#8212; it&#8217;s a decision for President Zelenskyy and Ukrainians to make if they&#8217;re going to pursue membership in NATO, a decision for NATO to make if they&#8217;re going to be members, including &#8212; in terms of other security guarantees, we&#8217;re in touch regularly with them but I don&#8217;t have more information of what that would look like.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Couldn&#8217;t &#8212; the President isn&#8217;t talking about some kind of long-term new mechanism where the U.S. somehow or Western countries or Europe somehow protect &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s a little premature at this point in time.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I may, on &#8212; back to the weapons package.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Up until now, the administration has been really very tight lipped about what was being sent to Ukraine.&nbsp; Yesterday, that all changed.&nbsp; We got a whole laundry list.&nbsp; Is that a change in strategy, in messaging?&nbsp; Is that a message for &#8212; you talked before about the Russian troop morale, for example, or maybe a message to domestic critics of President Biden?&nbsp; What&#8217;s changed there?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we made a decision that we wanted to be very clear about what types of security assistance we&#8217;re providing and how it is helping Ukrainians fight the Russian &#8212; Russia&#8217;s war against them.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, yes, you could say that was a change &#8212; a decision to make that information available.&nbsp; And we don&#8217;t typically, to your point, outline all of those specifics publicly.&nbsp;<br><br>So &#8212; but we did determine &#8212; made a determination to do that because we felt it was important for all of you and the American public to fully understand the range of military and security assistance we&#8217;re providing, how it&#8217;s working, and how it&#8217;s helping them in this war.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But was Russian morale a factor in that sort of decision?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It was not, but it was more a decision about recognizing that everybody doesn&#8217;t always understand what many people in this room do when we say “security assistance” what that is and how it helps the Ukrainians fight this war.&nbsp;<br><br>And there is an understandable outpour of support, of compassion for the plight of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; And we want to provide as much detail as we can about how we&#8217;re trying to help them in this war.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if I may, you were asked about Hunter Biden&#8217;s laptop.&nbsp; You also, in October 2020, dismissed it as &#8220;Russian disinformation.&#8221;&nbsp; Do you stand by that assessment?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;d point to the Department of Justice and Hunter Biden&#8217;s representatives.&nbsp; I&#8217;m a spokesperson for the United States; he doesn&#8217;t work for the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead in &#8212; okay, we&#8217;ll do the last one here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I have two questions: one on North Korea and China.&nbsp; North Korea fired new missiles the day before yesterday.&nbsp; What is the &#8212; President Biden&#8217;s reaction on this?&nbsp; And how do you analyze the type of missiles?<br><br>I have a follow-up &#8212; second question.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we condemn North Korea&#8217;s missile launches.&nbsp; North Korea&#8217;s tests risk raising tensions and are destabilizing to the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; Our commitment to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan remains ironclad.&nbsp;<br><br>As we have said and North Korean officials, including Kim Jong Un, have publicly noted, we continue to seek diplomacy and are prepared to meet without preconditions.&nbsp; But North Korea continues to not respond.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; When the &#8212; President Biden talks with Xi Jinping, the President of China, tomorrow, do &#8212; he are going to discuss with President Xi Jinping regarding on North Korea&#8217;s missile provocations?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I expect there&#8217;ll be a range of topics discussed, including security in the region, but we&#8217;ll have more to read out when that conversation continu- &#8212; is done.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.<br><br>3:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden to Celebrate St. Patrick’s&#160;Day</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/17/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-to-celebrate-st-patricks-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 23:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49356</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The White House Thank you! It’s my pleasure to welcome all of you—so many good friends—to the White House! And we are pleased to welcome the Taoiseach of Ireland, Micheál Martin, and his wife Mary, as well as the Irish Delegation, to Washington, D.C. To love Joe Biden is to know Ireland. Picture me on our first few dates, dressed in bell bottoms and a peasant shirt.  I wore my hair down to my waist—and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The White House</p>



<p>Thank you! It’s my pleasure to welcome all of you—so many good friends—to the White House!<br><br>And we are pleased to welcome the Taoiseach of Ireland, Micheál Martin, and his wife Mary, as well as the Irish Delegation, to Washington, D.C.<br><br>To love Joe Biden is to know Ireland. Picture me on our first few dates, dressed in bell bottoms and a peasant shirt. <br><br>I wore my hair down to my waist—and at the time, so did most of the men I dated. <br><br>And then there was this Senator, handsome and buttoned up in his suit and loafers—casually quoting Yeats.<br><br>It was the last thing I expected—but in the end, he won me over. <br><br>It doesn’t matter when Joe’s ancestors left—a piece of that island was passed down to each generation in memories, and stories, and family lore, held close like a precious gem—an emerald heart that shines like the light after a storm.<br><br>It’s a loyalty that knows “family” means forever.<br><br>A faith—tried and tested by famine and war.<br><br>An optimism brave enough to leave the life you know behind, and find what’s waiting on distant shores.<br><br>He’s not alone, of course. <br><br>Like so many generations of immigrants, Irish Americans brought the best of their home with them on wind and steam ships so many years ago. <br><br>Ridiculed and despised, they found ways to create new traditions, while never letting go of the legacies that made them, enriching our country along the way.<br><br>So it’s fitting that we honor that heritage by celebrating Saint Patrick, a man who brought faith to Ireland, enriching it, too. <br><br>There has always been a divine spark in the open arms of welcome. <br><br>Yes, I got to know Ireland through the eyes of Joe Biden. <br><br>On St. Patrick’s Day, all Americans, no matter their background, fall in love with it too.<br><br>We reach for a legacy buried deep inside of us—or gifted second-hand.<br><br>We celebrate a spirit that defies struggle.<br><br>We recognize the rich tapestry of our history—threads of clover green amid the red, white, and blue. <br><br>Happy St. Patrick’s Day. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Regional Appointments for USDA, FEMA, and&#160;HUD</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/17/president-biden-announces-key-regional-appointments-for-usda-fema-and-hud-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) at the Department of Homeland Security, and the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD): Julia Wickard, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) at the Department of Homeland Security, and the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD):</p>



<ul><li>Julia Wickard, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Indiana</li><li>Jeffrey Holmes, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, New Hampshire</li><li>Steve Dick, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, South Dakota</li><li>Deidre Deculus Robert, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Louisiana</li><li>Lucas Ingvoldstad, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Nevada</li><li>Erin Oban, USDA State Director, Rural Development, North Dakota</li><li>Nikki Gronli, USDA State Director, Rural Development, South Dakota</li><li>Perry Hickman, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Virginia</li><li>Ryan Thorn, USDA State Director, Rural Development, West Virginia</li><li>Thomas Sivak, FEMA Regional Administrator, Region 5</li><li>Juana Matias, HUD Regional Administrator, Region 1</li><li>Candace Valenzuela, HUD Regional Administrator, Region 6</li></ul>



<p>These regional appointees will be critical to the President’s efforts to rebuild communities most impacted by the pandemic, the economic recovery, and climate change. They bring deep expertise in their issue areas as well as critical relationships with federal, state, tribal, and local leaders. And, consistent with the President’s commitment to building an administration that looks like America, these regional appointees represent the diversity of America and the communities they serve.<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE (USDA)</u></strong></p>



<p>The USDA’s Farm Service Agency implements agricultural policy, administers credit and loan programs, and manages conservation, commodity, disaster, and farm marketing programs in each U.S. State. Its mission is to equitably serve all farmers, ranchers, and agricultural partners through the delivery of effective, efficient agricultural programs for all Americans. State Executive Directors oversee this work, ensuring the needs of local constituents are met and that USDA resources are distributed equitably and fairly.</p>



<p>USDA’s Rural Development mission area is committed to helping improve the economy and quality of life in rural America. State Directors lead offices that offer grants, loans, and loan guarantees to help create jobs and support economic development and essential services.</p>



<p><strong><u>Julia Wickard, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Indiana</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Hailing from her family&#8217;s Hoosier homesteaded livestock and row-crop farm, Julia A. Wickard, her husband, and two children own and operate Wickard Livestock where they raise registered Angus cattle and Boer goats. Wickard embarked on a journey with the State of Indiana at the Indiana Department of Environmental Management (IDEM) in April of 2017 as the Government Affairs Director and Agricultural Liaison. Just a few short months following her arrival at IDEM, she was appointed as Assistant Commissioner in the Office of Program Support, while also maintaining her Agricultural Liaison role. Prior to IDEM, she served for eight years as the Indiana State Executive Director of the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s Farm Service Agency (FSA) where she led over 300 employees in 75 county offices in administering federal agricultural programs. She served as the Executive Vice President of the Indiana Beef Cattle Association, Chief Operating and Marketing Officer and Environmental and Natural Resources Director at the Indiana Farm Bureau Inc., and was the Environmental and Natural Resources Director in the Office of the Commissioner of Agriculture. She has worked for the Indiana Association of Soil and Water Conservation Districts, Inc. and served two members of Congress.</p>



<p>Wickard is a graduate of AgrIInstitute’s Indiana Agricultural Leadership Program and currently chairs the board of directors. She is a recipient of Indiana&#8217;s highest honor from the Governor of the State, the Sagamore of the Wabash, and in 2019 was recognized as a Purdue University Agricultural Sciences Education and Communication Distinguished Alumni. Wickard is active in her community and enjoys spending time with family and exhibiting cattle and goats in the state and across the country.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jeffrey Holmes, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, New Hampshire</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Jeffrey Holmes is a fifth-generation farmer from Langdon, New Hampshire on property owned by the family since 1873. The farm was home to registered jersey cattle for over 80 years. Commodities currently produced on the farm include hay, corn, maple, timber, and firewood. Holmes’ public service includes 22 years on the New Hampshire Farm Bureau (NHFB) Board of Directors with eight years as NHFB President, 15 years as the Langdon town moderator, FSA county committee member, and County Executive Director in the Cheshire-Sullivan County office. Holmes and his wife Lisa are the proud parents of two adult children, and are enjoying the arrival of a grandson born in 2021.</p>



<p><strong><u>Steve Dick, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, South Dakota </u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Steve Dick has served as the Executive Director of Ag United for South Dakota since January 2005. Within this capacity he worked with the South Dakota Farm Bureau, South Dakota Cattlemen, South Dakota Pork Producers, South Dakota Soybeans, South Dakota Corn Growers, South Dakota Dairy Producers, and the South Dakota Poultry Industries Association to organize events and activities connecting consumers with South Dakota farm and ranch families. Before joining Ag United, Dick served on Senator Tom Daschle’s (D-SD) staff for a total of ten years in South Dakota and Washington, DC. In his last position with Senator Daschle, he served as the Agriculture Outreach Coordinator.</p>



<p>A native of southeastern South Dakota, Dick operates his family’s farm near Canistota in McCook County where he grows corn and soybeans and feeds cattle. He has served on the boards for East Dakota Water Development District, South Dakota Ag Foundation, East Dakota Education Foundation, Sioux Valley Energy Operation Round-Up, and the West Central School District. He is a graduate of the University of South Dakota. Dick and his wife, Jeanne, reside in Hartford and are the parents to two children, Truman, a student at the University of South Dakota, and Eleanor, a student at West Central High School.</p>



<p><strong><u>Deidre Deculus Robert, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Louisiana</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Deidre Deculus Robert was born and raised in rural Mamou, Louisiana. She has been immersed in agriculture and rural development her entire life; her mother retired from the U.S. Department of Agriculture and father served on the Farm Services Agency State Committee. Robert has over two decades of legal, administrative, and executive management experience. Her legal career began in the Parish Attorney’s Office of the City of Baton Rouge-Parish of East Baton Rouge as an assistant city prosecutor. During her 11 years with the City-Parish, she advanced to become the first female African American section chief. She worked for over six years as an assistant attorney general with the Louisiana Department of Justice, where she served as deputy director of the Public Protection Division, deputy director of the Litigation Division, and special litigation counsel assigned to defend the Louisiana Judiciary.</p>



<p>Recently, Robert served as the executive counsel for the Louisiana Department of Transportation and Development. Her responsibilities included managing legislative affairs on the federal, state, and local levels and supervising the innovative procurement/alternative delivery, and human resources of the agency. She collaborated with state and local partners advance infrastructure needs including rail, broadband, and bridges throughout the state. Previously, Robert served as general counsel of the Southern University and A&amp;M College System, the only HBCU college system in the country. Robert has focused her passion for service with the Louisiana State Bar Association Diversity Committee and House of Delegates; the Louisiana Bar Foundation as a fellow and board member; the Louis A. Martinet Legal Society; Junior League of Baton Rouge; Arts Council of Greater Baton Rouge, and more. She and her husband James reside on their ranch in Glynn, Louisiana with their two sons.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lucas Ingvoldstad, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Nevada</u></strong></p>



<p>A native Nevadan born and raised in Reno, Lucas Ingvoldstad attended the University of Nevada, Reno where he earned his Master of Science degree in Land Use Planning Policy in 2011 and a Bachelor of Arts in Psychology in 2005. In 2016, Ingvoldstad was acknowledged as the Young Alumni of Year by the College of Science and Mackay School of Earth Sciences.</p>



<p>Ingvoldstad&#8217;s professional experience includes public policy, public affairs, legislative relations, stakeholder engagement, and business development. Ingvoldstad previously served as the Senior Director of Government and External Affairs for Eolus North America, a utility-scale renewable energy developer focusing on solar, wind, and battery storage projects throughout the Mountain West. Ingvoldstad directed legislative and regulatory strategies and closely engaged with elected officials and administrators to promote renewable energy development, to combat climate change and promote economic development.</p>



<p><br>Before joining Eolus, Ingvoldstad served as a senior advisor to U.S. Majority Leader Harry Reid (D-NV), where he focused on energy, agriculture, and natural resource issues. Ingvoldstad was responsible for regularly communicating with Nevadans and stakeholders on issues relating to energy, public lands, water, natural resources, and economic development, and worked directly with Native American tribes. Ingvoldstad developed strategic outreach initiatives by collaborating with local governments, industry, nonprofit organizations, and advocacy groups, and played a key role in organizing the Lake Tahoe Summits and the National Clean Energy Summits. In Ingvoldstad spare time, he loves spending time with family, is an avid cyclist, and enjoys being outdoors, backyard gardening, and cooking.</p>



<p><strong><u>Erin Oban, USDA State Director, Rural Development, North Dakota</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Erin Oban grew up in a farm family in Ray, North Dakota, a small, rural community in the heart of Bakken oil country. Oban moved to Bismarck to further her education and received a bachelor&#8217;s degree in Mathematics Education at the University of Mary. Oban’s professional career began as a middle school math and technology teacher before gaining experience in nonprofit management, politics, and public service. She is currently employed as the Director of Community Engagement with the Central Regional Education Association where she supports efficiencies and effectiveness in education through partnerships between school districts and local, regional, and statewide organizations and agencies to provide programs and services for the students, families, and educators in their communities.</p>



<p>Oban was elected in 2014 and re-elected in 2018 to represent central Bismarck’s District 35 in the North Dakota State Senate. Oban has become an effective and respected leader, rising most recently to the position of Assistant Senate Minority Leader. Throughout her two terms in the legislature, she has served on the Senate’s Education, Energy and Natural Resources, Agriculture, Government and Veterans Affairs, and Political Subdivisions Committees. Oban has been thrice elected by her peers to serve on the powerful Legislative Management Committee and was twice appointed with bipartisan support as chairwoman of the legislature’s Interim Education Policy Committees. Her leadership in the Senate on issues of importance has been recognized by many local and statewide associations. Oban makes her home in Bismarck with her husband, Chad, and their 5-year-old son, Evin.</p>



<p><strong><u>Nikki Gronli, USDA State Director, Rural Development, South Dakota</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Nikki Gronli grew up in Aurora, South Dakota. She received her Bachelor of Science degree from the University of Minnesota, and began her career in advertising and marketing in Minneapolis. She returned to South Dakota in 2001 and continued to work on some of the best-known brands in the region, including South Dakota Tourism. Gronli will be leaving her role as Marketing Specialist at SDN Communications where she oversaw the brand, traditional marketing, and educational events. This professional experience helped her achieve board positions with Dakota State University’s Cybersecurity Industry Advisory Board and formerly, President of the Department of Defense STARBASE program. In her current role, Gronli has been an advocate for broadband expansion in South Dakota. Gronli understands extending critical broadband infrastructure to under-served communities and tribal areas is key to diversifying South Dakota’s economy.</p>



<p>Gronli is active in her community through numerous board and committee positions such as Minnehaha County Housing Redevelopment Committee, Siouxland Heritage Museum Board, and LEAD South Dakota, and recently served as vice chair of the South Dakota Democratic Party and chair of the Minnehaha County Democratic Party. Gronli and her husband Brian live in the rural Dell Rapids area, where they raised their four now-grown children. They are proud grandparents of two. In their downtime, they enjoy travel, hiking, and fishing – even in the winter.</p>



<p><strong><u>Perry Hickman, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Virginia</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Perry M. Hickman grew up in Tappahannock, Virginia and still resides in this small rural community. Hickman is a 1985 graduate of Virginia Commonwealth University and received a Bachelor of Science Degree in Business Administration and Management with a concentration in Real Estate and Urban Land Development.</p>



<p>Hickman has more than 20 years of combined sales experience in mortgage lending and telecommunications services. Hickman started his federal career with USDA Rural Development in April 2008, and he has primarily worked in the Rural Development Community Programs division to assist rural municipalities, non-profit corporations, and Tribal entities that seek federal financial assistance to enhance their ability to provide essential services for the orderly development of a rural community. Hickman has been a Rural Development National Office Senior Loan Specialist where he planned Public, Private, Partnership (P3) events with commercial lenders and other private sector partners. Annually, these P3 events accounted for obligating more than $200 million of congressionally appropriated funds through the Rural Development Community Facilities Direct Loan Program. As the Virginia Community Programs Director, Mr. Hickman managed a $750 million portfolio.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ryan Thorn, USDA State Director, Rural Development, West Virginia</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Born, raised, and educated in West Virginia, Ryan Thorn grew up the son of a coal miner and learned early in life the importance of hard work, serving others, and dedication to creating opportunities for rural communities. Thorn has 15 years of professional experience in the private and public sectors, working in the fields of public and government affairs and economic development. He previously served more than five years as Economic Development Manager for the Office of U.S. Senator Joe Manchin III (D-WV). In this role, he worked with local, state, and federal stakeholders to attract new and expand existing businesses, strengthen public infrastructure, develop a skilled and ready workforce, and create economically diverse and resilient communities across the state. Thorn is the first in his immediate family to graduate from college and is an advocate for lifelong learning. He holds a master’s degree from West Virginia University, a bachelor’s degree from West Virginia Wesleyan College, and is a board member of the Southern West Virginia Community and Technical College Foundation.</p>



<p><strong><u>FEDERAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY (FEMA)</u></strong><br>Regional Administrators lead FEMA’s 10 Regional offices and&nbsp;coordinate directly with the FEMA Administrator to support state, local, tribal, and territorial (SLTT) communities in their geographic area of operations delivering frontline services across the spectrum of preparedness, mitigation, response, recovery, and continuity programs.&nbsp;The Regional Administrators play a critical role in delivering timely, efficient, effective, and accessible federal assistance.</p>



<p><strong><u>Thomas Sivak, FEMA Regional Administrator, Region 5</u></strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Thomas Sivak serves as the Deputy Director of Operations for Cook County, Illinois Department of Emergency Management and Regional Security. Sivak’s key areas of emphasis are preparedness, planning, logistical response capabilities, information sharing and operational coordination across 135 municipalities. Throughout Sivak’s 15-year emergency management and public safety career, he has proudly served both private and public sector organizations. He is skilled in and recognized as a subject matter expert in safety, security, emergency management, disaster relief, pandemic response, and coordination.</p>



<p>Throughout his career, Sivak has served in leadership roles during major Emergency Operations Center and incident management activations as a result of major incidents and events. These include the 2012 Super Bowl, 2018 Mercy Hospital Active Shooter Incident, COVID-19 pandemic, civil unrest in May and August 2020, and Presidential Election Consequence Management. Sivak is a Certified Emergency Manager through the International Association of Emergency Managers and a graduate of the Executive Leadership Program at the Naval Postgraduate School Center for Homeland Defense and Security. He holds a Master of Science in Public Service Leadership from DePaul University, a Bachelors of Arts degree from Marquette University, and is originally from East Cleveland, Ohio.</p>



<p>Region 5 serves Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, Ohio, and Wisconsin.</p>



<p><strong><u>DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT (HUD)</u></strong></p>



<p>Regional Administrators lead HUD’s 10 Regional Offices that directly serve state and local organizations. Regional Administrators oversee field offices across each state in their region and ensure the Department directly serves local communities. Regional Administrators play a key role in leading assignments of housing assistance funds within the region and coordinating those assignments with HUD headquarters.</p>



<p><strong><u>Juana Matias, HUD Regional Administrator, Region 1</u></strong></p>



<p>Juana Matias is a member of the Massachusetts Bar Association and served as the Chief Operating Officer for MassINC, a nonprofit, non-partisan public policy think and action tank and civic news organization. In this capacity, she oversaw the organization’s internal operations, policy and advocacy strategy, development, and communications, and served as the main spokesperson with elected officials, policy makers, and the media. She also led efforts to strategically advance MassINC’s research in policy areas which included the K-16 education continuum, housing choice, criminal justice reform, transit-oriented development, and racial and economic justice.</p>



<p>Previously, Matias served as the State Representative for the 16<sup>th</sup> Essex District, becoming the first Latina immigrant elected to the Massachusetts House of Representatives. During her time at the State House, she secured an 81% increase in local funding for her district, and sponsored key legislation that protected immigrant rights, stimulated the production of new affordable housing, promoted access to minority-owned and women-owned businesses, addressed inequities in our public-school systems, and expanded opportunities for working class Americans.</p>



<p>Region 1 serves Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, and Vermont.</p>



<p><strong><u>Candace Valenzuela, HUD Regional Administrator, Region 6</u></strong></p>



<p>Candace Valenzuela is a mother, an educator, and a former school board trustee. She credits HUD and public education with giving her the stability she and her family needed to thrive as she experienced food and housing insecurity throughout childhood. After becoming the first in her family to graduate college, Valenzuela has since devoted her life to fighting for opportunities for others. She first ran for her local school board to improve Texas schools, becoming the first Latina and first Black woman to serve on the Carrollton-Farmers Branch school board. While on the board, she worked to ensure that faculty and staff would be able to afford to live in the district they served, and that students would have a strong education to help them overcome life’s challenges. Valenzuela was the Democratic nominee for Congress in Texas’ 24<sup>th</sup> District in 2020. She previously worked as a development manager for Metrocrest Services, a half-century-old non-profit that has worked hard to fight hunger, housing insecurity, and unemployment in her community.</p>



<p>Region 6 serves Arkansas, Louisiana, New Mexico, Oklahoma, and Texas.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the Annual Friends of Ireland&#160;Luncheon</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/17/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-annual-friends-of-ireland-luncheon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 19:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rayburn RoomU.S. Capitol 12:43 P.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you very much, Nancy.&#160; That was very kind.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; Thanks. Father, before I begin &#8212; bless me, Father, for I’m about to sin.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; I &#8212; well, I just want you to know, I may be Irish,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rayburn Room<br>U.S. Capitol</p>



<p>12:43 P.M. EDT</p>



<p><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Nancy.&nbsp; That was very kind.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Father, before I begin &#8212; bless me, Father, for I’m about to sin.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I &#8212; well, I just want you to know, I may be Irish, but I&#8217;m not stupid.&nbsp; I married Dominic Giacoppa’s daughter.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Look, thank you very much, Nancy, for that very gracious and very over-the-top introduction.&nbsp; I appreciate it very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I just got off the &#8212; on the way up, before I came up here, I was on the Zoom, as we say, with the Taoiseach for about 45 minutes.&nbsp; And he is &#8212; he&#8217;s looking well, he feels well.&nbsp; He&#8217;s tested positive, but he feels well.&nbsp; He looks good.&nbsp; And he wanted to &#8212; I know the Ambassador is here to bring his regards, but he is &#8212; he&#8217;s really sorry he can&#8217;t be here, and he was looking forward to it, as was his wife.</p>



<p>You know, the good spirits and feelings, as well, that exist on St. Patrick&#8217;s Day seems to be one of those few times and not &#8212; well, not &#8212; I shouldn’t say “a few” &#8212; we should have more times like this where Democrats and Republicans get together, and we actually not only agree on one thing, but we remind ourselves we actually like each other.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a useful thing.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And, I &#8212;</p>



<p>You know, Yeats wrote, and I quote, “Talent perceives differences; genius, unity.”&nbsp; “Talents perceives differences; genius, unity.”&nbsp; And, you know, I think today we can add a fifth item to at least my Unity Agenda, and that&#8217;s support of our relationship between Ireland and the United States, which has taken on an even more intense and cooperative form than it ever has, because of Ireland&#8217;s neutrality.</p>



<p>On this issue, it brings together Speaker Pelosi, Leader McCarthy, Richie Neal &#8212; who is Irish, as we say where I come from, from the belt buckle to shoe sole &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and &#8212; and the leaders of both our parties, and all the Friends of Ireland.</p>



<p>I &#8212; you know, I&#8217;m the proud son of Catherine Eugenia Finnegan Biden.&nbsp; And like so many Americans of Irish heritage, I love Ireland and I was raised in a circumstance where you would have thought my whole family &#8212; none of &#8212; they came in 1844 and 1845, but you’d think they’d all lived in Ireland the last 60 years &#8212; the previous 60 years.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The &#8212; there&#8217;s &#8212; as I was talking to Taoiseach today, the Irish on St. Patrick&#8217;s Day think that &#8212; Irish Americans think they&#8217;re more Irish than the Irish.&nbsp; And &#8212; but that&#8217;s kind of how I was raised, like so many Americans of Irish heritage &#8212; like other people of other heritage as well.</p>



<p>I was &#8212; it was imbued in me to be proud of &#8212; proud of my heritage.  And, you know, the pride that was passed down to generations of our family, even though they&#8217;ve been here since the mid-1800s.  And it was just part of the air we breathed, especially up in Scranton and &#8212; where we lived with my &#8212; near my grandpop. </p>



<p>My grandfather, Ambrose Finnegan, used to say &#8212; and I mean this &#8212; he’d say, “Joey, if you’re lucky enough to be Irish, you&#8217;re lucky enough.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Every time something bad happened, I’d go, “I don’t &#8212; I’m not sure.”&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Anyway.</p>



<p>But because of being an Irish family, family was everything.&nbsp; My dad&#8217;s expression was, “Family is the beginning, the middle, and the end.”&nbsp; And &#8212; and he meant it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but, you know, the faith we share with one another and the resilience that we&#8217;ve all gone through, both in America and in Ireland, you know, are ones that we&#8217;ve been knocked down sometimes.&nbsp; Just knocked flat on our back.</p>



<p>And my &#8212; my mom&#8217;s expression, for real, was, “Joey, get up.&nbsp; Just get up.&nbsp; Get up.”&nbsp; It’s a simple proposition.&nbsp; It was sort of the Irish of it.&nbsp; You just get up, no matter what.&nbsp; Dust yourself off and move.&nbsp; Not &#8212; we&#8217;re not the only culture that has that view, but it was imbued in my family.</p>



<p>And the other one was that &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; my dad’s: “No one is better than you, and you&#8217;re no better than anyone else.”&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; “No one is better than you, but you’re no better than anyone else.”&nbsp; And it&#8217;s real.&nbsp; It&#8217;s real.&nbsp; Because we were taught never &#8212; as my mother would say, “Never bow, never bend, never yield.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the truth of the matter was that in the days when my parents and grandparents were growing up in the coal country of Scranton, being Irish was less than a badge of honor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My &#8212; my great grandfather Blewitt, my &#8212; on &#8212; my grandmother Finnegan’s maiden name &#8212; was only the second Catholic ever elected to the Senate in the state of &#8212; in the state of Pennsylvania.&nbsp; And that was 1907, and only the second one.&nbsp; The first one was in, I think, 1838 or 1840.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The point was that, like many cultures, like many folks, where you came from was either viewed as an asset or a liability.&nbsp; And where &#8212; you know, but the point is that everything that we were taught &#8212; and I&#8217;m sure all of you of Irish background, and other backgrounds as well, were taught that &#8212; that, you know, it&#8217;s all about striving for a better future; that you can do better &#8212; just simply do better. &nbsp;And, you know &#8212; and you can do it while you cherish the past. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, you don’t have to forget the past, or dis- &#8212; or disso- &#8212; disassociate yourself &#8212; yourself from it, but cherish it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, these are the values of immigrants not only from Ireland, but from &#8212; like my great-great-grandparents when they were brought here &#8212; brought themselves to the United States.&nbsp; But today, it&#8217;s only part of what it means to be Irish.&nbsp; There is an indelible part of it that is American, because the values are the same, in my view &#8212; the values built into our Constitution that we are the &#8212;</p>



<p>I &#8212; I &#8212; you heard me say last night: I think we&#8217;re the most unique country in the history of the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the only country based upon &#8212; organizationally &#8212; not geography, not ethnicity, not &#8212; not race, not religion, but on a notion, an idea that we hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men and women are created equal, endowed by their Creator, with certain inalienable rights: life, liberty.</p>



<p>I mean, that&#8217;s the basis of why we formed this country.&nbsp; No other country has ever been based on a notion like that.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve incorporated those notions, but the basis for their organization has been their ethnicity, their religion, their geography &#8212; whatever &#8212; but not here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know I say it, and many of you say &#8212; and I think people wonder whether we really mean it: I really think the source of our strength is our diversity.&nbsp; The source of our strength is our diversity.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, you know, there are values that immigrants from Ireland brought and &#8212; but they’re &#8212; as I said, they&#8217;re not only &#8212; they&#8217;re not only Irish values, they&#8217;re values, I think, of the vast majority of immigrants who come to the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m proud to say that the bond between Ireland and the United States, by the way, has grown deeper and stronger over the years.&nbsp; For real.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve navigated a once-in-a-century pandemic together.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve grieved the loss of too many people in both our countries.&nbsp; And we worked to rebuild our economies and taken on the challenge of renewing and strengthening our democracy, because &#8212; again, I apologize for repeating myself, but I know many of you’ve heard me say I think we&#8217;re at an inflection point in history.&nbsp; I think &#8212; and I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; And it occurs every several generations.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re in a genuine struggle between autocracies and democracies, and whether or not democracies can be sustained.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I &#8212; I&#8217;m going to be speaking to President Xi tomorrow.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll remind me that I told him &#8212; he remembers every damn thing I&#8217;ve said, unfortunately.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But all kidding aside, we talk about the idea he &#8212; that he does not believe demo- &#8212; democracies can be sustained in the 21st century because things move so rapidly, technology is changing so much, democracies don&#8217;t have time to arrive at consensus.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why autocracies will succeed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, you know, and now &#8212; you know, we &#8212; you have Ireland stepping up not only in terms of the relationship with us but, you know, the Good Friday Agreement is built on political and economic progress that we&#8217;ve made together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know some criticize me, but I&#8217;ve &#8212; I&#8217;ve be- &#8212; I have a good relationship with the Prime Minister of Great Britain, Boris.&nbsp; We always kid each other when we see each other.&nbsp; But the point is that I&#8217;ve made it clear that &#8212; I don&#8217;t think I just speak for myself &#8212; the Good Friday Agreements are firmly, firmly, firmly, firmly supported here in the United States.&nbsp; And we insist that it occur, they be maintained because it’s (inaudible) too hard.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The people of Northern Ireland have made significant changes as well.&nbsp; There&#8217;s movement, as you&#8217;ve mentioned &#8212; the young kids you talked about &#8212; Protestant and Catholic &#8212; talking to how &#8212; I mean, how they&#8217;ve never known anything but being able to get along.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I remember the first time I &#8212; on my parents’ 50th wedding anniversary, my brothers and sister, we got together and gave my &#8212; and we can work something out for you, Father &#8212; we gave my parents a &#8212; a trip to Ireland.&nbsp; And &#8212; but it coincided &#8212; I was going over to the Stormont talks.&nbsp; And so they said, “You take them, Joey.”&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And &#8212; but the point is that it was &#8212; it was an &#8212; a bit of an epiphany for my parents.&nbsp; They thought &#8212; you hear all the stories from your ancestors about this, that, and the other thing &#8212; some of it apocryphal, some of it real.&nbsp; But it was &#8212; it was really amazing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But when we took them to the north, it was interesting.&nbsp; We went up to the Stormont and &#8212; anyway, they &#8212; it was an interesting thing to watch &#8212; to watch the look on my mother&#8217;s face and my father&#8217;s face as we toured Ireland, to see both the things that they had heard that were consistent with what they heard, because you never know whether they &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s exaggeration about, “Well, when &#8212; when this happened and that happened.”&nbsp; But they came back more hopeful than they had ever been as opposed to &#8212; and that was a while ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my generic point is that, you know, now you have Ireland and Great Britain, and, you know, the Republic standing together against a murderous dictator, a pure thug, who is waging an immoral war against the people of Ukraine.</p>



<p>And, by the way, the Republic is paying a big price for this, a big number for supporting the strategy &#8212; for supporting the sanctions, including aircr- &#8212; a whole range of things.&nbsp; This &#8212; it’s not a minor contribution they’re making in this effort.&nbsp; It’s significant.</p>



<p>Ireland and the United States are working together.&nbsp; For the first time now, they&#8217;re on the United Nations Security Council.&nbsp; Ireland is a part of the Security Council now and the European Union.&nbsp; And Putin is paying a big price for his aggression.&nbsp; And &#8212; and they are part of the reason this cost is going so high.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s a little &#8212; you know, everybody talks about Germany having stepped up and changed the notions about being more &#8212; more leaning forward.&nbsp; But &#8212; and they have.&nbsp; Well, so is Ireland.&nbsp; So is Ireland &#8212; a neutral country.&nbsp; Ireland has stepped up and taking a hit for what they&#8217;re doing.</p>



<p>And you &#8212; look, you know, ladies and gentlemen, the relationship between Ireland and the United States is a dynamic and, I think, essential partnership that &#8212; as much as it&#8217;s ever been.&nbsp; And, you know, it&#8217;s sustained and strengthened by the Friends of Ireland, in this room and all across the country.&nbsp; And, you know, the connections that link our people stretch back through history, and they forward &#8212; well forward, I believe, in the future.</p>



<p>You know, we &#8212; we share a common goal: a future of a greater peace, greater hope, greater security, and a greater sense of who we are as countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, I &#8212; my &#8212; my mother&#8217;s expression, gotten from her grandfather, was, you know: As long as you&#8217;re alive, you have an obligation to strive.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re not dead until you’ve seen the face of God.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s what I think of when I think of Ireland.&nbsp; All the troubles they&#8217;ve been through, they have never, ever, ever quit.&nbsp; Never, ever, ever, ever quit &#8212; not once.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve gotten up.&nbsp; And now they&#8217;re beginning to at least have the benefits of all the hard work and labor they&#8217;ve engaged in, and they’re becoming a real actor, Mr. Ambassador, on the world stage and at the United Nations.</p>



<p>And so, I want to thank you, Mr. Ambassador, and I thank the Taoiseach today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I &#8212; I just &#8212; I should &#8212; I should probably tell you that my mother, when I took &#8212; when we went to Ireland, and we were &#8212; we were in the south, and my father was a real gentleman.&nbsp; And his greatest regret was he never had a college education.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if I were &#8212; if you or any one of you were coming back to Delaware with me and my dad were around or retired, and I didn&#8217;t call him to tell him I was bringing you over to introduce him so he had a chance to put on a coat and a tie &#8212; because he would only see you that way &#8212; that was my dad.</p>



<p>And as we were going to Ireland &#8212; FitzGerald was the Taoiseach &#8212; and we walked in to have a picture taken.&nbsp; And my dad had his brand-new blazer that had a &#8212; a patch on of&nbsp;my brother-in-law, Jack Owens &#8212; who&#8217;s Irish from &#8212; like you, Neal.&nbsp; And it was this patch &#8212; this crest.&nbsp; And it had Latin written on it.&nbsp; And I never took the time to look at it, although I had to take four years of Latin &#8212; three years of Latin in the Catholic high school I went to.</p>



<p>And Taoiseach &#8212; we’re having our picture taken, and he said, “Oh, Mr. Biden” &#8212; he said, “I agree.”&nbsp; And what it said in Latin was, “Don&#8217;t let the bastards get you down.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, we can&#8217;t let them get us down.&nbsp; You can&#8217;t let them get us down.</p>



<p>Thank you for allowing me to come back home, come up here and speak.&nbsp; And thank you, Nancy, for the nice compliments.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>SPEAKER PELOSI:&nbsp; As the President has to make a clean exit to go back to work, I wanted all of us to lift our glass to toast the President on this St. Patrick&#8217;s Day.</p>



<p>Mr. President, this is a toast that I learned from my grandchildren; I&#8217;ve said it to our colleagues here before.&nbsp; And it goes like this.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an Irish toast:&nbsp; Sing as is if no one can hear you.&nbsp; Dance as if no one can see you.&nbsp; Love as if you&#8217;ve loved &#8212; never loved before.&nbsp; And live as if heaven is on Earth.</p>



<p>So when I said to them, “Is that a toast that is a tradition in the Kenneally family?” they say, “No, that&#8217;s a sign that is in the Shannon Airport.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>To the President.&nbsp; Happy &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SPEAKER PELOSI:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Happy St. Patrick’s Day.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, my grandmother had one.&nbsp; She said, “May those who love us, love us.&nbsp; And those who don&#8217;t, may they turn their ankle so we know they&#8217;re coming by their limp.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;12:59 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Virtual Meeting with Taoiseach Micheál Martin of&#160;Ireland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/17/readout-of-president-bidens-virtual-meeting-with-taoiseach-micheal-martin-of-ireland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 19:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met virtually today with Taoiseach Micheál Martin of Ireland, upholding a longstanding White House tradition on St. Patrick’s Day that symbolizes the deep ties and historic partnership between our countries. The President expressed regret that he and the Taoiseach were unable to meet in person and wished him a speedy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met virtually today with Taoiseach Micheál Martin of Ireland, upholding a longstanding White House tradition on St. Patrick’s Day that symbolizes the deep ties and historic partnership between our countries. The President expressed regret that he and the Taoiseach were unable to meet in person and wished him a speedy recovery. The leaders discussed the coordinated international response to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified war in Ukraine, including the imposition of significant economic costs on Russia and the provision of humanitarian assistance to the people of Ukraine who are displaced by the conflict. They welcomed the growing trade and investment ties between our countries, as well as our close cooperation on shared global challenges, including through the United Nations Security Council. &nbsp;The leaders also underscored their enduring commitment to the Good Friday Agreement (also known as the Belfast Agreement) and the importance of preserving political and economic stability in Northern Ireland.</p>



<p>After the bilateral meeting, the President attended the traditional St. Patrick’s Day Speaker’s Lunch on Capitol Hill, hosted by Speaker of the House Nancy Pelosi. In the evening, the President and the First Lady will host at the White House the presentation of the shamrocks, a gesture of friendship and goodwill between the United States and Ireland that dates back to 1952.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Martin of Ireland Before Virtual Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/17/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-martin-of-ireland-before-virtual-bilateral-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 19:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 11:22 A.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, Taoiseach, I&#8217;m really deeply sorry you &#8212; for the inconvenience that we’re having to meet virtually again this year, although I did, at a little distance, for seven and a half minutes get to see you yesterday, but &#8212; and your beautiful wife.&#160; But &#8212; and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:22 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, Taoiseach, I&#8217;m really deeply sorry you &#8212; for the inconvenience that we’re having to meet virtually again this year, although I did, at a little distance, for seven and a half minutes get to see you yesterday, but &#8212; and your beautiful wife.&nbsp; But &#8212; and especially after your flying all the way here to Washington and with a lot going on up in the Hill and the rest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But just as we did last year, the tradition of this beautiful bowl, the tradition of these beautiful shamrocks I have here with me.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;re meeting in a moment when demands on unity in the world are really accelerating.&nbsp; And we have to be united, and we certainly are.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I &#8212; Putin&#8217;s brutality and what he&#8217;s doing and his troops are doing in Ukraine is just inhumane.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, you know &#8212; as you know, your predecessor and you occasionally kid me about always quoting Irish poets.&nbsp; But &#8212; but Yeats had a great line in “Easter Sunday, 1919” [sic].&nbsp; He said, “All has changed, changed utterly: A terrible beauty has been born.”&nbsp; He was talking about his Ireland and what was going to come, which had turned out to be better than &#8212; than worse.<br>&nbsp;<br>But all has changed.&nbsp; I think that your leadership on the global stage has really been noticeable and impressive.&nbsp; You&#8217;re now a member of &#8212; temporarily for the &#8212; as you are a member of the Security Council.&nbsp; Your leadership on the global stage within the EU as well. &nbsp;And &#8212; and your condemnation of Putin&#8217;s aggression and support of the &#8212; of the sanctions.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s costing Ireland.&nbsp; It’s costing Ireland.&nbsp; But as usual, you&#8217;re basing it on principle and moral standing of the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And &#8212; but I also want to emphasize this administration&#8217;s unequivocal support for the Good Friday accords &#8212; for the Good Friday Agreement.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve made that clear, as you probably heard, to the Prime Minister and others: I think it&#8217;s &#8212; too much blood, sweat, and tears have been shed to get that done.&nbsp; And this is no time to change it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we have a full agenda to discuss, I know.&nbsp; And &#8212; but deepening our cooperation &#8212; Ireland and the United States &#8212; bilaterally and through the European Union is &#8212; is &#8212; and taking on climate change, looking at economic opportunities we both have, and combating COVID combined is something that we&#8217;re going to work closely together on.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have a lot to talk about, but I&#8217;m talking too much.&nbsp; Let me yield the floor to you, Taoiseach.&nbsp; And &#8212; and you have my best wishes for &#8212; I know you&#8217;re looking good, feeling good, but I&#8217;m looking forward to you getting cleared as quickly as you can.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRIME MINISTER MARTIN:&nbsp; Well, thank you very much indeed, President.&nbsp; And last year, we met virtually across the Atlantic.&nbsp; This year, we&#8217;re meeting virtually across the road.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re getting closer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I&#8217;m feeling good.&nbsp; And I think that reminds us of the importance of vaccines, and &#8212; because vaccines prevent severe illness.&nbsp; And it reminds us of that can- &#8212; central message we give to people: Get vaccinated if you&#8217;re not vaccinated.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, of course, it is unfortunate, but it&#8217;s no more than that.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I share with you our horror at the barbaric attack on the civilians of Ukraine.&nbsp; And I want to take this opportunity to genuinely salute your leadership &#8212; it&#8217;s firm, it&#8217;s determined, it&#8217;s strong, it&#8217;s measured in the teeth of this crisis &#8212; and, particularly, your capacity to marshal like-minded democracies.&nbsp; The U.S., the European Union, the United Kingdom, the other &#8212; Canada, and other like-minded democracies are coming together to respond in an unprecedented way to this barbaric attack on the women and children of Ukraine.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our thoughts are with them and all the young people who are dying because of this unjustifiable and immoral war on their people by the regime of Vladimir Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;s extremely important that we keep this unity of purpose over the coming while.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Ireland stands ready to do everything we possibly can on the humanitarian front and in supporting the broadest and widest sanctions possible to keep the pressure on and to get this war ended, because there&#8217;s simply too much suffering.&nbsp; And it’s heartrending to see the appalling loss of life and also the terrible trauma on the children of Ukraine and their mothers as they flee this war zone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we&#8217;re very seized by this in Ireland.&nbsp; And the response has been &#8212; has been great to behold, in terms of the people of Ireland who want to do everything they possibly can here.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May I also just thank you again, in respect of the Good Friday Agreement, your steadfast support, and that of Speaker Pelosi and our friends on the Hill, in giving a very clear message in respect of how important the Good Friday Agreement is in respect of &#8212; of stability and peace on the island of Ireland.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And over the vast number of days, as I&#8217;ve been here, we&#8217;ve also witnessed once again that two-way, very robust economic relationship between the United States and &#8212; and Ireland.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a two-way relationship.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I met Irish companies yesterday who are creating 100,000 jobs in the U.S. now.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s because of that partnership between Ireland, Europe, and the U.S.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So I look forward to discussing these issues in greater detail.&nbsp; But, again, to say that it&#8217;s wonderful to meet with you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we met in Glasgow recently.&nbsp; We had a good chinwag there, in respect of a number of issues.&nbsp; But, again, that &#8212; that also illustrated that partnership between Europe and the U.S. in terms of the existential crisis of our time &#8212; climate change.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, great to have this opportunity to meet with you, President.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I want to say one thing while the press is here before they leave, and that is: What Ireland is doing now, what you are doing, taking in Ukrainian refugees, speaks so loudly about your principles.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s amazing, and I want to publicly compliment you for it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think you&#8217;ve already brought in over 7,000 or so refugees from Ukraine, and you&#8217;re prepared to do more.&nbsp; So you’ve &#8212; thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I just want to make sure everybody knows that.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; PRIME MINISTER MARTIN:&nbsp; It’s our duty.</p>



<p>11:29 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
