<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 20:58:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 27, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/27/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-27-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 20:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:51 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, I have a couple of notes for you at the top. Today, the Department of Health and Human Services, through the Health Resources and Services Administration, awarded $121 million in American Rescue Plan funding to support the work of trusted community-based&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:51 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, I have a couple of notes for you at the top.<br><br>Today, the Department of Health and Human Services, through the Health Resources and Services Administration, awarded $121 million in American Rescue Plan funding to support the work of trusted community-based efforts to increase vaccinations in underserved communities.<br><br>This is the second round of funding for community-based groups.&nbsp; Back in June, HHS awarded $125 million to similar groups for these efforts.<br><br>And these groups will undertake efforts such as mobilizing community outreach workers to educate and assist individuals in accessing and receiving COVID-19 vaccinations, organize pop-up or mobile vaccine locations, and assist in making vaccine appointments or arranging transportation and childcare assistance for vaccine appointments.<br><br>One grantee in Jacksonville, Florida &#8212; one of the states where there, as you know, has been the highest transmission rates &#8212; one of the highest transmission rates &#8212; will use the funding to establish a sustainable community-based workforce and infrastructure to maximize COVID-19 vaccine uptake, minimize disparities, and advance health equities in vulnerable populations.<br><br>Another grantee in Oklahoma will reach rural communities, including Hispanic community members, and will recruit and train community health workers.<br><br>I also wanted to give you a small preview of the President&#8217;s visit to ODNI this afternoon.&nbsp; As we announced earlier &#8212; last week, I guess it was &#8212; he will visit the Office of the Director of National Intelligence later this afternoon to meet with leaders of the Intelligence Community and to thank all of our intelligence professionals for their service to our nation.<br><br>After the meeting &#8212; after meeting with Director of National Intelligence Avril Haines, the President will tour the National Counterterrorism Center Operations Center with NCTC Director Christy Abizaid to see firsthand how we remain ever vigilant in fighting threats to our country.<br><br>He&#8217;s particularly proud of Director Haines and Director Abizaid, who are both the first Senate-confirmed women to hold these positions.<br><br>He will then address the intelligence community workforce to express his admiration and appreciation for their service.&nbsp; In his remarks, he will highlight the integral role our public servants play in shaping national security decision-making and protecting the American people.&nbsp; He will also underscore the importance of intelligence collection and analysis that is free from political interference or pressure.<br><br>And I think many of you have been on these trips with him.&nbsp; He&#8217;s visited a number of national security agencies, and it&#8217;s part of his effort to support the workforce.<br><br>Another item for you: The Justice Department has successfully blocked a merger between two of the three largest insurance brokers in the world &#8212; I know this had been reported on &#8212; Aon and Willis Tower Watson.<br><br>These companies provide insurance brokerage services to thousands of American businesses and charge billions a year for their services.<br><br>The merger would have raised prices for a wide swath of American businesses that need to use a broker to obtain insurance and benefit packages for their employers &#8212; employees, sorry.<br><br>Those higher insurance costs would ultimately have led Americans to pay more for all kinds of products and services, such as banking services, hospital care, cars, and trucks.&nbsp;<br><br>And the proposed merger, as the Justice Department explained in its complaint, was a clear and presumptive violation of the antitrust laws under established law.<br><br>So, these actions, which I&#8217;m &#8212; the reason I&#8217;m lifting them up &#8212; are very much in line with the Presi- &#8212; what the President was talking about when he called for more robust enforcement of the antitrust laws in his executive order to promote competition.<br><br>Last piece, I think, here &#8212; second to last piece, but hopefully useful: Tomorrow, the President will travel to Lehigh Valley, in Pennsylvania, where he will be emphasizing the importance of American manufacturing, buying products made in America, and supporting good-paying jobs for American workers during a trip to the Lehigh Valley Operations facility for Mack Trucks.&nbsp; The President will take a tour of the Mack Trucks facility and meet with local union members.&nbsp; More than 85 percent of the 2,500 employees at the Mack Trucks location are UAW members.<br><br>And a little bit about Mack Trucks, as you&#8217;re preparing for tomorrow: The company has been making vehicles for the military since at least World War One.&nbsp; There are more than 1,500 Mack Trucks in the federal fleets used by both military and civilian agencies.<br><br>He&#8217;ll also receive a briefing on the Mack Trucks electrical refuse truck.&nbsp; The company is currently piloting their electric dump trucks in New York City and North Carolina.&nbsp; And this is all a part of his effort to lift up and talk about his &#8220;Buy American&#8221; agenda as well as the infrastructure package.<br><br>Finally, I just wanted to note that, after additional engagement with a bipartisan group yesterday, we&#8217;re enthusiastic about getting the bipartisan infrastructure plan across the finish line and confident we&#8217;ll be there soon.<br><br>We were encouraged this morning by positive comments by Senator Romney.&nbsp; Our team remains hard at work, as do a number of the supporters on the Hill.<br><br>With that, go ahead, Alex.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I have a few questions on the CDC&#8217;s revised masking guidance &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that some vaccinated Americans should wear masks indoors where there&#8217;s risk of high transmission or currently high transmission.&nbsp; That covers, according to the CDC, about 63 percent of the country right now, which has significant or high transmission.&nbsp; So how will the White House get Americans to start wearing masks when they&#8217;ve gone for more than two months without them?&nbsp; Will we see President speak more about this?&nbsp; I mean, how exactly do you plan to push this publicly?<br><br>And then, along those same lines, on July 4th, the President gave his, sort of, &#8220;independence from the virus&#8221; speech.&nbsp; He declared, quote, &#8220;We are closer than ever to declaring our independence from a deadly virus&#8221; and, quote, &#8220;we&#8217;ve gained the upper hand on the virus.&#8221;&nbsp; Was that declaring premature victory?&nbsp; And are you at all concerned that those statements will make it tougher for you guys to implement this revised guidance now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, I know this is slightly awkward timing, but &#8212; and I know there&#8217;s a lot of reporting out there about the CDC guidance.&nbsp; It is not only appropriate for them to make the decisions, it&#8217;s also appropriate for them to officially announce their own guidance.<br><br>I will say, though, that how we view this, as you asked about, Alex &#8212; implementation of their guidelines that they&#8217;ll outline on a call with all of you later this afternoon &#8212; that we are still in the midst of a once-in-a-generation pandemic battling an ever-evolving virus.&nbsp;<br><br>We have said since the beginning of June that the Delta variant &#8212; a rising variant that had increasing &#8212; was clear from the beginning had great &#8212; a great deal of transmissibility &#8212; was a threat to people who were unvaccinated.&nbsp; We did more than a hundred interviews with officials conveying exactly that.&nbsp;<br><br>And the reality is: We are dealing with a much different strain of this virus than we were even earlier in the spring, back in May, when the masking guidance was done &#8212; provided by the CDC at that time.<br><br>That is their job.&nbsp; Their job is to look at evolving information, evolving data, an evolving historic pandemic, and provide guidance to the American public.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what they will do and what they will provide specific details on later this afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With respect to the President&#8217;s comments, though, do you, in retrospect, regret those comments?&nbsp; Do you think that that was wise at the time, considering, you know, they could make it tougher for Americans to take this seriously?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that, in the President&#8217;s remarks, he also made clear &#8212; and I&#8217;m quoting him &#8212; that today, &#8220;while the virus hasn&#8217;t been vanquished,” we &#8212; you know, he made clear that it was not over; that those who were unvaccinated were still at risk. &nbsp;<br><br>He made clear that you were protected from serious illness, disea- &#8212; or hospitalization if you were vaccinated.&nbsp; That remains the case.&nbsp; And he encouraged people who are not vaccinated to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>But, again, the role of the federal government and our public health officials is to continue to look at evolving data, evolving threats of a historic virus, provide that public health guidance to the American people to protect more people and save more lives.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what they&#8217;re doing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One quick one on infrastructure.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President met with Senator Kyrsten Sinema.&nbsp; Can you tell us anything about how that meeting went?&nbsp; And does he have other meetings planned with any of the primary negotiators or Democratic leadership on the bill as it gets to the &#8212; potentially, the finish line?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would expect &#8212; yes, the President saw Senator Sinema this morning.&nbsp; They are very much aligned on the path forward.&nbsp; Both feel optimistic about the path forward.&nbsp;<br><br>And clearly, both understand, having lived through many iterations of legislating and negotiating before, that it is always at the tail end when you have, you know, some of the trickiest discussions.&nbsp;<br><br>So &#8212; but they, again, remain quite positive about the forward momentum and the path we see the infrastructure package on at this point in time.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have any additional meetings to preview for you, but I will tell you that the President is somebody who just picks up the phone when somebody tells him it&#8217;s going to be constructive.&nbsp; That certainly, I think, will continue to happen as we work to get this across the finish line.<br><br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When the President travels, as in Lehigh County, will you be looking at the rate of infection there?&nbsp; And will that cause us to see any change in the President’s own masking posture or that of people in the entourage there?<br><br>And what should Americans &#8212; who should they look to for specific guidance about making these decisions, day to day?&nbsp; Do they need to be looking at a CDC website for the positivity rate in their community?&nbsp; Do they need to be looking to the White House for that guidance?&nbsp; What is your prescription for how Americans should adjust with these mask guidelines?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; First, we will, of course, be abiding by every aspect of the CDC guidelines on masking that they will provide this afternoon.&nbsp; And that does mean, as you conveyed, that we will be looking at the rates in different areas where the President may visit, and also the rates as they &#8212; if they move in Washington, D.C., and we will apply guidance accordingly.&nbsp;<br><br>That means we will be prepared to wear masks again if required, if the guidance is leading to that, as would the President.&nbsp; And that will continue to be the case.&nbsp;<br><br>And as it relates to the American public &#8212; I mean, our hope is certainly that elected officials, leaders, civic leaders, public health experts around the country will also look at the CDC guidance and they will be constructive partners and voices in sharing with their communities what steps they could take.<br><br>The CDC is going to have the map and the guidance to provide to the public on how this guidance applies to them, and that would be the most accurate place to seek information.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the “summer of freedom,” as the President described it, is that still operative now, given the change in the Delta variant?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first &#8212; I have this little handy chart; I suspected that we might talk a little bit about COVID today, understandably.&nbsp; And what I would note is that what has not changed is the fact that people are &#8212; who are vaccinated have a huge deal of protection from serious illness, from hospitalization, and from death.&nbsp; And I know Shannon &#8212; actually, I see her in the back there &#8212; asked a good question yesterday about the data, so I wanted to give you a little bit of a better understanding of how this data process works.&nbsp;<br><br>So the data that Dr. Walensky, the CDC Director, spoke to back in July was based on data up through the beginning of June &#8212; or the end of May, the beginning of June.&nbsp; That will be updated in August as it relates to individuals who are hospitalized or get sick, who are vaccinated, and those who are unvacc- &#8212; what hospitalizations look like as the percentage breaks down.<br><br>But this is all based on data from either state officials or health agencies &#8212; or the Florida Hospital Association, as it relates to the Florida-specific example here.<br><br>And how the information flows &#8212; to your question earlier yesterday, Shannon &#8212; is it goes from hospitals to states to the CDC.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m using this example to show you &#8212; because this kind of breaks through the reporting of this data &#8212; this is from hospital systems that will go to states.&nbsp;<br><br>And what you can see here: Florida, which is one of the states with the high- &#8212; one of the highest transmiss- &#8212; or one of the highest rates of COVID, I should say &#8212; officials have said that more than 95 percent of those who were hospitalized were not vaccinated.&nbsp; That is information from last week, or just a couple of days ago.<br><br>North Carolina: Unvaccinated make up more than 99 percent of new COVID cases in May and June.&nbsp; That&#8217;s from a few weeks ago, but still updated data.<br><br>Colorado: More than 96 percent of Colorado&#8217;s COVID hospitalizations, deaths in the first half of 2021 were among unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m using these examples because even as the masking guidance is put out later today by the CDC, we are still going to be sending a very clear message to the public that in order to protect yourself or save your life, save the lives of those around you, you need to get vaccinated.&nbsp; Masking is guidance, but &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, can I follow up &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; just on this data point?&nbsp; Because, yeah, I appreciate you looking into this.&nbsp; It seems the problem, from when I talk to doctors, though, is that the Delta variant is evolving in this situation so rapidly that even data from May or June might not be representative of what&#8217;s happening now.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This is from July.&nbsp; A number of these examples are from July.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It was only July 9th, I think, or mid-July &#8212; which I know isn&#8217;t that long ago, though, that the Delta variant became the dominant spread.&nbsp; So, you know, when I talk to hospitals in places like Nevada, Missouri, Kansas City, you know, those doctors are saying they&#8217;re seeing more like 1 in 10, which I know is still not a majority, but it&#8217;s different than some of these numbers.<br><br>You know, the situation in May and June, for the first half of the year when most people weren&#8217;t vaccinated, is much different than it is now.&nbsp; So, are you guys aware of that?&nbsp; Are you talking to people in some of the harder-hit areas about, like, what they&#8217;re seeing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Shannon, one, I think it&#8217;s really important to project data across a spectrum, right?&nbsp; Not from individual hospitals or individual cases.&nbsp; Because what people are really looking at or what we&#8217;re looking at is how it relates to across-state data.<br><br>Florida &#8212; this data is from four days ago.&nbsp; Florida is one of the states that has the highest rate; it accounts for about 20 percent of COVID cases in the country, from the last data I saw.&nbsp; This is from four days ago; 95 percent of those who were hospitalized were not vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s across-Florida data from the Florida Hospital Association.<br><br>Of course, we absolutely look at data, as does the CDC, and we&#8217;re going to continue to evaluate and assess.&nbsp; But because this data goes into what the CDC reports, I thought it would be relevant to all of you to see and understand how we look at the across-the-state data.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The CDC data showed, though, on July 6th, that the Delta variant was the prominent strain: 51.7 percent of cases.&nbsp; So, what took so long between then and now?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Even higher now, as you know.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what led to the change in guidance?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You &#8212; I’m sure you will get on the call with the CDC later this afternoon, and I think that’s a great question to ask them.&nbsp;<br><br>Our guidance is based on the public health experts and what they are advising in terms of steps that should be taken.&nbsp; I think it’s, though, important to note it has always been the case that the guidance has been, if you are not vaccinated, to wear a mask.&nbsp; That has not changed.&nbsp; That has been the case from the beginning.&nbsp; And also, to get vaccinated if you’re not vaccinated.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the President’s message was get vaxxed <em>or</em> masked, and now it’s get vaxxed <em>and</em> masked, in some cases.&nbsp; So does he regret sending the message that it was a binary choice there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Weijia, I think that those comments were back in May.&nbsp; And as I noted at the time, the Delta variant was a &#8212; was by no means a variant &#8212; the variant that it is today.&nbsp; It was not even a &#8212; I can look at the specific data, but it was &#8212; 99 percent of cases were not Delta at the time.&nbsp; That was based on guidance from the CDC.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, they&#8217;re changing their guidance, they&#8217;re changing their advice to the American public &#8212; their public health advice based on evolving data and an evolving, historic &#8212; vari- &#8212; virus.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what they should be doing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what is your message to Americans who are feeling whiplash right now?&nbsp; Why should they trust the same group of health officials who, just two months ago, told them they don&#8217;t have to wear a mask anymore inside?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because our goal is to save their lives, and our responsibility and the responsibility of public health officials is to continue to provide updated guidance, if it warrants, from an evolving virus.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on something related.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve said many times from the podium, as recently as Friday, that it is not the federal government&#8217;s role to mandate vaccines.&nbsp; Can you help us understand what changed between then and yesterday when that&#8217;s exactly what the VA did?&nbsp; And is it a sign of what&#8217;s to come for other agencies?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think the context of the question, which I think is important here, is: Can we mandate vaccines across the country?&nbsp; No, that&#8217;s not a role that the federal government, I think, even has the power to make.<br><br>The federal workforce is part of the workforce of the federal government; that&#8217;s different and very different from the question you just posed, in important context.&nbsp;<br><br>The VA is a huge provider of public health officials and to patients who are some of the men and women who served our country bravely as parts of the military &#8212; as members of the military.&nbsp; And this was a decision that followed, and was aligned with, I should say, the decision by 57 hospitals associations across the country to make sure we were taking &#8212; they were taking every step they could to protect the servicemen and women who seek health services at the VA.<br><br>I will also say, as a big employer &#8212; the federal government &#8212; it is also our responsibility to continue to look at ways that we can protect people and save lives.&nbsp; And so we will continue to look, agencies will continue to look, we will continue to look at what steps we need to take for our workforce.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks Jen.&nbsp; How closely has the President been monitoring the January 6th hearing on the Hill?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s his reaction to some of the testimony from the law enforcement officers today?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say &#8212; I know you didn&#8217;t ask me this question, but I know a number of us have watched the testimony this morning, which has been incredibly compelling, heart wrenching, and, you know, at moments, a reminder of the shameful events of January 6th and of the incredible bravery of the men and women of law enforcement who put themselves in harm&#8217;s way to protect the Capitol, our democracy, and members of Congress from both parties.&nbsp;<br><br>The President has had a range of meetings and briefings and engagements this morning.&nbsp; I know he&#8217;s intending to catch updates and clips, and certainly staff will share with him what they&#8217;ve seen as we&#8217;ve watched the briefings, but he has not been in a position, via his schedule, to watch the hearings this morning.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we anticipate a statement from him at the end of the day after he’s been updated on this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would not anticipate that, no.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one on vaccines before we move on.&nbsp; You know, you just said that the message for unvaccinated Americans has always been to wear a mask.&nbsp; But how concerned is the White House that the message that unvaccinated Americans will hear after this afternoon is that, even if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you now have to wear a mask in some settings, and then just say, “why bother then” on the vaccine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s the good news: We’re all here.&nbsp; You all are all here.&nbsp; You’ve got millions of people and Americans who watch your broadcasts and watch your shows and listen to you to hear what they should know about how to protect themselves and save their lives.&nbsp;<br><br>So our message to the American public is: We are at war.&nbsp; We continue to be at war with a virus and evolving pandemic.&nbsp; Our responsibility here is to always lead with the science and always lead with the advice of health and medical experts.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to provide information to all of you about how to protect yourself and save your lives.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re not saying that wearing a mask is convenient or people feel like it, but we are telling you that that is the way to protect yourself, protect your loved ones, and that&#8217;s why the CDC is issuing this guidance.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow on those two questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; What was &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll come back to you, April.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When was the White House told that this CDC guidance was changing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s been &#8212; it&#8217;s obviously a decision the CDC made.&nbsp; The President was briefed this morning by Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; But beyond that, we&#8217;ve been aware of their discussions with our public health officials.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the CDC is also going to recommend that children in schools all wear a ma- &#8212; that everyone in schools wear a mask regardless of vaccination status.&nbsp; But there are at least eight states that actually prohibit their districts from requiring a mask in schools.&nbsp; So what are parents who have children in those schools, in those states supposed to do?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, look, Kaitlan, I&#8217;m happy not to live in a state where that is the guidance.&nbsp; And this is new guidance that is being issued by the CDC today.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know how it will influence local elected officials in these states, but I certainly hope, for the health and wellbeing of the next generation, that they take a close look at the guidance.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more question.&nbsp; You just said you don&#8217;t think the federal government has the power to mandate vaccinations across the country, but they do have the power to mandate them within the government.&nbsp; So why is everyone who works in the federal government not mandated to get vaccinated?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first, Kaitlan, that we &#8212; you saw the VA announcement yesterday, which was really about public health and about protecting the patients, the men and women who have served our country.&nbsp; But we are going to continue to look at ways to protect our workforce and to save more lives.&nbsp; I just have nothing to preview for you at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we expect more vaccination mandates from federal agencies?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think a range of agencies and leaders will look at what steps they should take to protect their workforce and save lives.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just explicitly, when President Biden was presented with this latest guidance from CDC, what was his reaction?&nbsp; I mean, he welcomed the guidance back in May.&nbsp; What was his reaction this time?&nbsp; How concerned was he when he was told about this latest guidance?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Concerned in what way?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Concerned about, you know, how this will impact the administration&#8217;s ability to perhaps vaccinate those who don&#8217;t &#8212; do not want to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, first, that the President has always said that he is going to be guided by public health experts, by the CDC, and what our doctors are recommending.&nbsp; That has always been the case.&nbsp; And there have been discussions, as you would expect, for months now, from the beginning, about what steps need to be taken, should be taken to protect from an evolving virus.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he did not explicitly talk about, you know, “Let&#8217;s &#8212; maybe the administration should start worrying about, you know, how this impacts your messaging, the work that you&#8217;re doing on the ground”?&nbsp; Did he have anything to say about that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not how he looks at this.&nbsp; He looks at &#8212; as the President of the United States, at a time where we came in with a dangerous distrust in science and government and institutions, he felt &#8212; feels it&#8217;s important to be led by data and scientists, and will be helping &#8212; le- &#8212; helping lead the effort to implement this, of course, in the federal government.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I did have a follow-up to Kelly’s question there.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not just when he&#8217;s traveling, but just when he&#8217;s at the White House, and even for White House staff, is there any decision on whether he or staff will start wearing masks?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will be abiding by public health guidance.&nbsp; And if that is where we fall in the geographical guidance given by the CDC, we will also be following that masking guidance.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, first on crime: As shootings spike in Chicago, the superintendent of police there is blaming courts for releasing attempted murderers on electronic surveillance.&nbsp; Does the President agree with the superintendent, who was just here earlier this month, that ankle bracelets do not cut down on attempted murder?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have to tell you, I have not seen these comments or looked at the full context of them.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to do that after the briefing.&nbsp;<br><br>I think we know &#8212; from seeing, broadly, the rising crime or the rising gun violence across the country, including in cities like Chicago &#8212; that there needs to be greater assistance, greater efforts to make sure guns don&#8217;t get in the hands of criminals who could do harm, and more assistance to local police forces and community policing programs as well.<br><br>The President doesn&#8217;t just use that as rhetoric; he delivers it with action.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know he&#8217;s in discussions &#8212; or in discussions about reforming the police, generally.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got cops now saying that the courts are too soft.&nbsp; Some progressives, including Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, are saying the courts are too strict.&nbsp; So, what does the President think?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President &#8212; I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s a secret that the President disagrees at times with Congresswoman &#8212; the congresswoman about some aspects of policing.&nbsp;<br><br>He believes we need to reform our prison system to keep our community safe while addressing mass incarceration and by diverting nonviolent drug offenders and taking other steps that will improve rehabilitation and reduce recimit [sic] &#8211;recidivism.&nbsp;<br><br>If you &#8212; but he also believes, let&#8217;s be clear, if you commit a violent crime and are found guilty and pose a threat to society, you should serve that time.&nbsp; And when you get out, you should have the support you need to successfully reenter society.&nbsp; That&#8217;s his view.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the CDC guidance, why did the President say, “If you&#8217;ve been fully vaccinated, you no longer need to wear a mask.&nbsp; Let me repeat: If you are fully vaccinated, you no longer need to wear a mask” if it was possible that that was going to turn out not to be true?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, I think we&#8217;re all dealing with an evolving virus where there&#8217;s no playbook and no historic precedent.&nbsp; And what the American people should feel confident in is that we are going to continue to be guided by science, look at public health data in order to provide new guidance, if it&#8217;s needed, to save lives, to protect the American people.<br><br>When he made those comments back in May, we were dealing with a very different strain of the virus than we were &#8212; than we are today.&nbsp; And Delta is more transmissible.&nbsp; It&#8217;s spreading much more quickly.&nbsp; It was nearly non-existent in the United States back in May.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so my last one would be: You guys have been saying this is a pandemic of the “unvaccinated.”&nbsp; If that is coming from the CDC, is the President satisfied with the leadership at the CDC right now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President is satisfied with the fact that they are continuing to look at public health data and give &#8212; provide public health guidance to the American public about how they can protect their lives and the lives of loved ones around them.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if it’s a pandemic of the unvaccinated still, then why do vaccinated people need to put the masks back on?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, first of all, I would say again &#8212; just to go back to this chart, which I will handily point to again: If you are vaccinated &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Overwhelmingly, the unvaccinated.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; if you are vaccinated, your li- &#8212; it can save your life.&nbsp; And I think the clear data shows that this pandemic is killing, is hospitalizing, is making people very sick who are not vaccinated.&nbsp; That co- &#8212; still continues to be the case, regardless of what the mask guidance looks like.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if the vaccines work, which this sign says that they do, then why do people who had the vaccine need to now wear masks &#8212; the same as people who have not had it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because the public health leaders in our administration have made the determination, based on data, that that is a way to make sure they&#8217;re protected, their loved ones are protected.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s an extra step, given the transmissibility of the virus, that people &#8212; that they&#8217;re advising people to take.<br><br>Go ahead, Steve.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last year, when we went through this as a national discussion &#8212; talk about social distancing and shutdowns.&nbsp; Is this White House eyeing anything other than mask guidance?&nbsp; I mean, this week, you said you wouldn&#8217;t lift the travel restrictions.&nbsp; Is anything else coming?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we&#8217;re always going to be guided by the public health guidance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how the travel restrictions decision was made.&nbsp; But we are not &#8212; this is not guidance about businesses shutting down or communities shutting down.&nbsp; This is guidance to individuals about how they can protect themselves.<br><br>We&#8217;ve seen some communities &#8212; L.A. County, for example &#8212; where they have applied versions of mask guidance.&nbsp; It has not shut businesses down.&nbsp; It is meant to protect people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; That is the goal and the objective.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you about expedited removals &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; down at the border?&nbsp; As you know, there are advocates for immigrants who say that what this administration is now doing is taking away due process rights by empowering asylum officers to make decisions in the immediate moment for expedited removal.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your response to that criticism?&nbsp;<br><br>And on the other side of that coin, is it this administration&#8217;s view that most of the people who are claiming credible fear on the border are not entitled to asylum?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, no, that is certainly not our claim.&nbsp; We are &#8212; of course, people who are applying for asylum, who will go through the process, and if their case and their &#8212; may &#8212; warrants, they will be granted asylum.&nbsp; What this is, is that &#8212; I should say, those families process for expedited removal who claim fear will have the opportunity to present their cases before an immigration judge and request asylum or other forms of relief or protection from removal.&nbsp; So even &#8212; even those who are being processed.&nbsp;<br><br>What &#8212; the processing of migrants for expedited removal is a traditionally employed, lawful mean to secure our border, and it is a step toward our broader aim of having a safe and orderly immigration system.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say, at the same time, we continue to work to build a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system.&nbsp; We recently expanded the Central American Minors Program and made 6,000 H-2B visas available to Central Americans.<br><br>But we also want to be crystal clear: Attempting to cross into the United States between ports of entry or circumventing inspection of ports of entry is dangerous.&nbsp; It carries long-term conse- &#8212; immigration consequences.&nbsp;<br><br>But, no, we will still, of course &#8212; individuals who are applying for asylum, who warrant asylum, will be treated accordingly.<br><br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, does the President&#8217;s economic team see any ramifications to this masking policy?&nbsp; Are they concerned at all that it could affect consumer spending or any of the economic growth projections?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I will say, I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re quite at that point.&nbsp; The guidance, of course, is not, as you know, being released until later this afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>I will also say that as we&#8217;ve looked at, kind of, the economic impact of the Delta variant, one of the things we&#8217;ve looked at is that we have &#8212; one, we have programs in place that are meant to be implemented over the course of time to ensure that Americans are getting assistance, getting additional funding into their pockets as needed, which was a lesson learned from the past about ensuring that there wasn&#8217;t an abrupt halt to economic assistance as we&#8217;re going through a historic pandemic, still at war with it, and as we&#8217;re still going through an economic recovery.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s no significant signs at this point of the Delta variant’s impact in that sense.&nbsp; And we&#8217;d expect that much of the economic impact will be felt in communities with lower vaccination rates.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t expect to turn back the clock to what it was in March of 2020 or even six months ago.&nbsp;<br><br>But in terms of longer-term analysis, I don&#8217;t &#8212; we&#8217;re not at that point yet.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on the infrastructure talks &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the President obviously met with Senator Sinema, and he’s making calls on this.&nbsp; Does he see the end of the week as a more or less deadline to get a bipartisan deal on this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to be setting new deadlines today, but what I will tell you is that we were quite encouraged by the conversations overnight and into this morning.&nbsp; We see momentum.&nbsp; It&#8217;s moving in a positive direction.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard that from Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; That certainly is a good sign &#8212; and it&#8217;s only Tuesday.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the federal eviction moratorium is scheduled to expire at the end of the week, and millions of renters are still behind on payments.&nbsp; I know the administration has taken other steps to aid with assistance, but is there any discussion about an extension of that moratorium, especially as we&#8217;re seeing the Delta variant, you know, rear its head?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me just give you &#8212; I know you follow this closely, but for others, just as a reminder: On day one of the administration, as part of the American Rescue Plan rollout, the President did call on Congress to extend the eviction moratorium through September 30th of 2021.&nbsp; The final plan, of course, did not include that proposed moratorium extension, and so the CDC extended the moratorium administratively in January, March, and most recently in June for a final month.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s in place, as you noted, until <s>January 31st</s> [July 31st].<br><br>I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this point in time or &#8212; but certainly, we will be watching this closely, ongoing discussions about how we can continue to help renters.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just on another subject related to January 6th.&nbsp; Yesterday, the White House said that it would nominate Matthew Graves to be U.S. Attorney for D.C., and if confirmed, he would oversee the prosecutions of hundreds of people who were arrested for what happened on January 6th at the Capitol.&nbsp; Did the President or anybody else in the administration discuss those cases with Graves before his nomination?&nbsp; Did they seek any particular position on those cases, such as being aggressive and charging and prosecuting them?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more on this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check and see if there&#8217;s more we can convey about the personnel process.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on Peter&#8217;s point: Does President Biden have confidence right now in Director Walensky’s leadership?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And is a reason why Dr. Fauci briefed President Biden on the new CDC guidance and not Dr. Walensky &#8212; or Director Walensky?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think Dr. Fauci is likely in town, but also has provided briefings to the President on a regular basis, as has Dr. Walensky, throughout the course of the pandemic.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on a different topic: What is the White House doing to specifically win over support from Democrats on the nomination of David Chipman to lead the ATF?&nbsp; Senator Durbin just told us this morning that Democrats don&#8217;t have the votes, and Senator Tester also signaled this morning that the nomination could even be pulled.&nbsp; So does &#8212; is the White House still pushing through on that nomination?&nbsp; And what is the White House doing to whip up votes?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I’d first remind people, as you well know, but for others, that not only is he a veteran of the ATF, but he&#8217;s somebody who has been a supporter of smart gun reform measures that could save lives of people across the country.&nbsp; And we &#8212; the President felt quite confident in the &#8212; his qualifications and his ability to lead the agency at a time where it hasn&#8217;t been led for many years.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of our specific legislative strategy, I&#8217;d really have to talk to the team and see where things stand with that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick follow-up: Senate appropriators just announced a deal on a supplemental on Capitol Police security funding.&nbsp; It does include about a billion dollars for the Special Immigrant Visa program.&nbsp; Does the White House support that deal between Leahy and Shelby?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly have supported and advocated for additional funding for the Special Immigrant Visa program &#8212; something that is a huge priority to the President.&nbsp; I&#8217;d also reiterate, since you gave me the opportunity, that our first flight of Afghan SIV applicants will be coming into the United States this week, which is a very exciting step forward and will be the first of many.<br><br>In terms of the amount of funding, I would have to check with our legislative team on that as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, April.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Jen, a couple of questions.&nbsp; On COVID: Are we at a point where we are saying that there&#8217;s just no absolutes when it comes to what&#8217;s happening in this moment?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not at that point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because we&#8217;re possibly beginning to wear masks again in the building &#8212; in buildings, kids could possibly be wearing masks in schools, and those who are vaccinated are getting breakthrough COVID cases.&nbsp; So you&#8217;re saying &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think &#8212; here&#8217;s what we all have responsibility to do: is to provide the guidance and clear information that is being presented by public health officials to the American public &#8212; not to project confusion, but to alleviate the confusion.&nbsp; And it is &#8212; also, it&#8217;s incumbent upon the public health officials to continue to look at and evaluate and make recommendations based on data to save people&#8217;s lives and protect people from getting the virus, getting &#8212; being hospitalized or, of course, dying.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And a question on Johnson &amp; Johnson and on the testimony today.&nbsp;<br><br>Johnson &amp; Johnson is in the news again.&nbsp; This time, the National Council of Negro Women &#8212; who the President just had at his table &#8212; is suing Johnson &amp; Johnson because they targeted Black women, starting in the ‘90s, with talcum powder that is said to cause ovarian cancer.&nbsp; Is this administration concerned with the credibility, the integrity of Johnson &amp; Johnson, a company that is administering some of these vaccines in COVID?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, April, first, it&#8217;s ongoing litigation, as you noted, so of course I can&#8217;t speak to that.&nbsp; But I do think it&#8217;s important to note that the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine, which is entirely separate from baby powder, was approved by the gold standard, the FDA, which requires a rigorous look at the data and safety guardrails.&nbsp;<br><br>The FDA approved the distribution and the use of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine.&nbsp; And again, it&#8217;s entirely separate from the baby powder, talcum powder litigation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it’s still that same company, the brand.&nbsp; And people will associate &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But the FDA is a U.S. government entity and, again, the gold standard, and has a rigorous review process, so people should remain confident in the vir- &#8212; in the vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And lastly, on the January 6th Select Committee: Last week, President Biden said he “has faith in the American people to ultimately get to the right place.”&nbsp; And what is that “right place,” particularly when you hear testimony today from some of these police officers who &#8212; some are minority &#8212; some of the Black officers said Black officers fought a “different battle.”&nbsp; One officer said he was called the N-word &#8212; N-I-G-G-E-R &#8212; after answering questions of the rioters &#8212; the insurrectionists &#8212; as to who he voted for when he said he voted for Joe Biden.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, April, as I said a little bit earlier, I mean, today&#8217;s testimony &#8212; for anybody who watched it &#8212; it was a searing reminder of the shameful events of January 6th.&nbsp; And certainly that testimony, I think, will stick with people for some time to come.&nbsp;<br><br>And what the President meant is that he is confident in the American people to fight for democracy; to fight for voting rights; to fight for, you know, moving forward from the events that were a dark day in our democracy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he supports &#8212; strongly supports the actions by Speaker Pelosi and the efforts to get to the bottom of what happened on January 6th so that we can prevent it from ever happening again.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, we&#8217;ve got to wrap up guys, sorry.&nbsp; You got an event.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; Have a good day.&nbsp;<br><br>1:27 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Nine Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/president-biden-announces-nine-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 20:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following nine individuals to serve in key roles: William Valdez, Nominee for Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security Erik Hooks, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Federal Emergency Management Agency Lisa Gomez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Employee Benefits Security, Department of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following nine individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>William Valdez, Nominee for Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security</li><li>Erik Hooks, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Federal Emergency Management Agency</li><li>Lisa Gomez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Employee Benefits Security, Department of Labor</li><li>Adrienne Wojciechowski, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations, Department of Agriculture</li><li>Mark Gitenstein, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the European Union, with rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary</li><li>Laura S. H. Holgate, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the Vienna Office of the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador, and Representative of the United States of America to the International Atomic Energy Agency, with the Rank of Ambassador&nbsp;</li><li>Patricia Mahoney, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Central African Republic</li><li>Julissa Reynoso Pantaleon, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Spain and to the Principality of Andorra</li><li>Peter Hendrick Vrooman, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mozambique</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>William Valdez, Nominee for Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security</u></strong></p>



<p>William J. Valdez is a former career member of the Senior Executive Service at the Department of Energy and past President of the Senior Executives Association.&nbsp; He is currently the co-founder and Board President of the Alliance of Latinx Leadership &amp; Policy, which supports a leadership pipeline for Latinx professionals who want to pursue a career in public service.&nbsp; Valdez is a recognized thought leader in the management of government agencies and has worked for 27 years to improve the effectiveness of government, with a goal of providing maximum mission delivery on behalf of the U.S. taxpayer.&nbsp; A current focus is using technology to improve human capital, procurement, and financial management processes to free up Federal employees from paperwork and focus on delivering mission.</p>



<p>Valdez was raised in an Air Force family and is the proud father of three extraordinary professional women, and is Papi to four grandchildren.&nbsp; He and his wife Marlana Valdez live in Takoma Park, MD.&nbsp; Valdez was the recipient of a 2007 Presidential Rank Award (Meritorious) and is an elected Fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science.</p>



<p><strong><u>Erik Hooks, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Federal Emergency Management Agency</u></strong></p>



<p>In January 2017, Secretary Hooks was appointed by the Governor of North Carolina as the Secretary of Public Safety and the State’s Homeland Security Advisor.&nbsp; Secretary Hooks provides cabinet level leadership to the NC Division of Emergency Management and Homeland Security Section, the NC National Guard, the NC Office of Recovery and Resilience, the NC State Highway Patrol, the NC Alcohol Law Enforcement Division, the NC State Capitol Police, the Division of Adult Correction and Juvenile Justice, the Governor’s Crime Commission, and support divisions within the state’s Department of Public Safety. Secretary Hooks leads approximately 27,000 sworn and civilian public safety professionals as well as approximately 12,000 National Guard soldiers and Airmen.</p>



<p>A native of North Carolina, Secretary Hooks has more than 30 years of public safety experience. He is responsible for leadership coordination of homeland security and emergency management functions to provide comprehensive and coordinated preparedness, mitigation, prevention, protection, response and recovery for emergencies, disasters, and acts or threats of terrorism. As North Carolina’s State Administrative Agent, Secretary Hooks administers federal funds to state, local and tribal entities across North Carolina. Secretary Hooks chairs the North Carolina State Emergency Response Commission and coordinates law enforcement counterterrorism prevention, preparedness, and response training on a statewide basis resulting in a cohesive team response by both law enforcement and emergency first responders to acts of terrorism or a terrorist threat.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secretary Hooks has a master’s degree and undergraduate degree from North Carolina University. Additionally, he successfully completed the FBI National Executive Institute, and the Commandant’s National Security Program at the US Army War College. Secretary Hooks serves on the Executive Committee of the National Governors Homeland Security Advisors Council and is a member of the International Association of Chiefs of Police.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lisa Gomez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Employee Benefits Security, Department of Labor</u></strong></p>



<p>Lisa M. Gomez is a partner with the law firm Cohen, Weiss and Simon LLP and the Chair of the Firm’s Management Committee.&nbsp; Since 1994, she has developed her deep technical and practical experience in the multifaceted field of employee benefits law, representing various Taft-Hartley and multiemployer pension and welfare plans, single employer plans, jointly administered training program trust funds, a federal employees health benefit (FEHB) plan, supplemental health plans, and VEBAs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gomez serves as a Co-Chair of the Board of Senior Editors of the Bloomberg BNA treatise <em>Employee Benefits Law</em>. Gomez also served as the Union Co-Chair of the ABA Section of Labor and Employment Law Committee on Employee Benefits , as a member of the Programming Committee for the ABA Section of Labor and Employment Law Committee on Employee Benefits’ Midwinter Meeting, and as a Union Co-Chair of the ABA Section of Labor and Employment Law’s E-FLASH newsletter.&nbsp; She is a graduate of the American Bar Association Section of Labor and Employment Law’s Leadership Development Program and is currently the Union Co-Chair for that Program.&nbsp; She is a member of the International Foundation of Employee Benefit Plans and the AFL-CIO Union Lawyers Alliance.&nbsp; She is a frequent lecturer on topics such as health care reform, various health plan compliance issues, benefit claim and appeals procedures and litigation, subrogation, ethics, LGBTQIA+ benefits, multiemployer plan contribution enforcement, qualified domestic relations orders, and other topics.&nbsp; In 2014, she was inducted as a Fellow of The American College of Employee Benefits Counsel, Inc. in recognition of her over twenty years of practice in employee benefits law and her contributions to the field. Lisa is also a member of the Advisory Board of The Peggy Browning Fund, a non-profit organization devoted to advancing law students who wish to pursue careers protecting workers’ rights.&nbsp; She previously served as a volunteer mediator for the New Jersey Supreme Court, Law Division, Special Civil Part, Somerset County.</p>



<p>Lisa is admitted in the United States District Court for the Southern and Eastern Districts of New York and the District of New Jersey, as well as the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit.&nbsp; She is a graduate of the Fordham University School of Law (J.D. 1994) and Hofstra University (B.A. 1991).</p>



<p><strong><u>Adrienne Wojciechowski, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations, Department of Agriculture</u></strong></p>



<p>Adrienne Wojciechowski has worked in the Senate for 14 years and is currently serving as Professional Staff of the Agriculture Subcommittee of the U.S. Senate Appropriations Committee. In that capacity she leads the Subcommittee&#8217;s work on farm production, conservation, climate change, dairy, crop insurance, specialty crops and organic, local food systems, marketing, and research and education at land grant institutions. Prior to joining the Appropriations Committee, she served as a senior policy advisor for U.S. Senator Patrick Leahy of Vermont, advising the senator on agriculture, environment, forestry, and energy issues and as a professional staff member on the U.S. Senate Judiciary Committee. In that role she oversaw his work on the 2018 and 2014 Farm Bills, the Healthy, Hunger-Free Kids Act of 2010, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) portions of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, and supported his work on the 2008 Farm Bill.</p>



<p>Earlier in her career she was a government relations associate at The Nature Conservancy, leading efforts to strengthen federal agriculture and forestry programs to achieve cleaner water, healthier soil, improved habitat, and greater outdoor recreation opportunities. She is a graduate of the University of Maryland, College Park where she earned a Bachelor of Science in Agricultural and Resource Economics and a Bachelor of Arts in Government and Politics. Growing up in Maryland, Wojciechowski developed a passion for agriculture from her parents and her active involvement in 4-H, where she showed beef cattle.</p>



<p><strong><u>Mark Gitenstein, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the European Union, with rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary</u></strong></p>



<p>Mark Gitenstein is Senior Counsel at Mayer Brown LLP, and a former U.S. Ambassador to Romania. He has spent most of the last decade working on projects in Central and Eastern Europe.&nbsp; As Ambassador, he focused on fighting corruption and preserving democratic institutions, issues he continued to focus on through his work as a lawyer and with NGOs. Since his term as ambassador ended in 2012, he has returned to the region over two dozen times since then.</p>



<p>Earlier in his career, Gitenstein worked for 17 years in the U.S. Senate as Chief Counsel or Minority Chief Counsel of the Judiciary Committee, Chief Counsel of the Judiciary Committee’s Subcommittee on Criminal Justice, and Counsel for the Intelligence Committee.&nbsp; In 2008 he co-chaired then Senator Biden&#8217;s transition to the vice presidency. In 2021 he served as a senior advisor to and member of the advisory committee to the Biden presidential transition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gitenstein earned an A.B. at Duke University and a J.D. at Georgetown University Law School.&nbsp; He was awarded the Star of Romania, the nation’s highest civilian honor, by the President of Romania in 2012.</p>



<p><strong><u>Laura S. H. Holgate, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the Vienna Office of the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador, and Representative of the United States of America to the International Atomic Energy Agency, with the Rank of Ambassador&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<p>Laura S. H. Holgate is Vice President for Materials Risk Management at the Nuclear Threat Initiative, in Washington, D.C., where she leads NTI’s activities to prevent nuclear terrorism, including reducing quantities and enhancing security of nuclear and radiological materials around the world, promoting cooperation between the United States and key partners on nuclear and radiological security, and strengthening the global nuclear security architecture.&nbsp; She served as U.S. Representative to the International Atomic Energy Agency and Vienna Office of the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador, in 2016, and previously was Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for weapons of mass destruction terrorism and threat reduction on the National Security Council. In this role, she led the preparation of four Nuclear Security Summits and co-initiated the Global Health Security Agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Previously, Holgate directed the U.S. Department of Energy’s Office of Fissile Materials Disposition and was special coordinator for cooperative threat reduction at the U.S. Department of Defense.&nbsp; She is a co-founder of Gender Champions in Nuclear Policy, and serves on multiple advisory boards.&nbsp; Holgate received a B.A. at Princeton University, an M.S. from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, and spent two years on the research staff at Harvard University’s Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Patricia Mahoney, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Central African Republic</u></strong></p>



<p>Patricia Mahoney, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Benin. Previously she was an Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs and the Office Director of the Office of Mainland Southeast Asia, also in the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs. Earlier, Mahoney was the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Kampala, Uganda, and before that the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Kathmandu, Nepal. Mahoney also served as Director for South Asia at the National Security Council. Mahoney earned her B.A. cum laude from Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts and her M.A. from the University of Hawaii.&nbsp; She is a Distinguished Graduate of the National War College in Washington, D.C., receiving an M.S. degree in 2009.&nbsp; Ms. Mahoney speaks French, Thai, Nepali and Lao.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Julissa Reynoso Pantaleon, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Spain and to the Principality of Andorra</u></strong></p>



<p>Julissa Reynoso is an Assistant to the President and Chief of Staff to Dr. Jill Biden, and the Co-Chair of the Gender Policy Council at the White House.&nbsp; A former U.S. Ambassador to Uruguay, Reynoso also served as Deputy Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs.&nbsp; She is a former partner at the international law firm of Winston &amp; Strawn LLP, in New York, and served on the faculty of Columbia University School of Law and School of International and Public Affairs.&nbsp; Reynoso is widely published in English and Spanish on an array of issues including comparative law, regulatory reform, community organizing, immigration policy, and Latin American politics for both popular press and academic journals.&nbsp; She holds a B.A. in Government from Harvard University, a Masters in Philosophy from the University of Cambridge in the United Kingdom and a J.D. from Columbia University School of Law.&nbsp; She clerked for the Honorable Federal Judge Laura Taylor Swain.&nbsp; She is fluent in Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Peter Hendrick Vrooman, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mozambique</u></strong></p>



<p>Peter Hendrick Vrooman, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Rwanda.&nbsp; Ambassador Vrooman recently served as the Chargé d’Affaires and Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.&nbsp; Prior to that he served as the spokesperson for the U.S. Embassy in New Delhi; Director for Iraq on the staff of the National Security Council in Washington, D.C.; and Deputy Political Counselor in Tel Aviv and at the U.S. Mission to the United Nations.&nbsp; He also worked at the U.S. embassies in Baghdad, Beirut, and Djibouti, as well as the U.S. Liaison Office in Mogadishu, Somalia.&nbsp; In Washington, he was a Watch Officer in the Department of State’s Operations Center and the Desk Officer for Algeria in the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs.&nbsp; A native of New York, Ambassador Vrooman graduated from Harvard College with a B.A. in Social Studies and earned an M.S. in National Resource Strategy from the National Defense University’s Industrial College of the Armed Forces, now known as the Eisenhower School for National Security and Resource Strategy.&nbsp; Prior to joining the Foreign Service, he worked as the special assistant to the President of the American University in Cairo.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on CDC Guidance</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-cdc-guidance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I ran for President, I promised to be straight with you about COVID—good news or bad. And I promised to follow the science. That strategy has worked: in my first six months in office, we’ve given out over 300 million shots—and have 60% of adults fully vaccinated and nearly 70% started on vaccinations. Cases are down, and deaths&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>When I ran for President, I promised to be straight with you about COVID—good news or bad. And I promised to follow the science. That strategy has worked: in my first six months in office, we’ve given out over 300 million shots—and have 60% of adults fully vaccinated and nearly 70% started on vaccinations. Cases are down, and deaths are down dramatically. One estimate suggests that our rapid deployment of the vaccine has saved 100,000 American lives—perhaps more.</p>



<p>Today’s announcement by the CDC—that new research and concerns about the Delta variant leads CDC to recommend a return to masking in parts of the country—is another step on our journey to defeating this virus.&nbsp;I hope all Americans who live in the areas covered by the CDC guidance will follow it; I certainly will when I travel to these areas.</p>



<p>Today, the CDC also reaffirmed that we can safely reopen schools this fall—full time.&nbsp;Masking students is inconvenient, I know, but will allow them to learn and be with their classmates with the best available protection.</p>



<p>Most importantly, today’s announcement also makes clear that the most important protection we have against the Delta variant is to get vaccinated.&nbsp;Although most U.S. adults are vaccinated, too many are not.&nbsp;While we have seen an increase in vaccinations in recent days, we still need to do better.</p>



<p>On Thursday, I will lay out the next steps in our effort to get more Americans vaccinated. Vaccinations are free, safe, and effective to every American.&nbsp;They’ve been available to every adult in this country for more than three months—at locations within 5 miles of 90% of the US population.</p>



<p>By following the science, and by doing our part by getting vaccinated, America can beat COVID.&nbsp;In the meantime, more vaccinations and mask wearing in the areas most impacted by the Delta variant will enable us to avoid the kind of lockdowns, shutdowns, school closures, and disruptions we faced in 2020. Unlike 2020, we have both the scientific knowledge and the tools to prevent the spread of this disease.&nbsp;We are not going back to that.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Peru to Attend the Inauguration of His Excellency José Pedro Castillo Terrones</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-republic-of-peru-to-attend-the-inauguration-of-his-excellency-jose-pedro-castillo-terrones/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 14:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Peru to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Pedro Castillo on July 28, 2021, in Lima, Peru. The Honorable Miguel Cardona, United States Secretary of Education, will lead the delegation. Members of the Presidential Delegation: The Honorable Lisa&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Peru to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Pedro Castillo on July 28, 2021, in Lima, Peru.<br><br>The Honorable Miguel Cardona, United States Secretary of Education, will lead the delegation.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Members of the Presidential Delegation:</span></strong><br><br>The Honorable Lisa Kenna, United States Ambassador to the Republic of Peru</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Update from the Equitable Data Working Group</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2021/07/27/an-update-from-the-equitable-data-working-group/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 13:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OMB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OSTP]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By Alondra Nelson and Clarence Wardell III, Equitable Data Working Group The Equitable Data Working Group was established on the first day of the Biden-Harris Administration under Executive Order 13985, Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government, as part of the President’s commitment to a whole-of-government approach to advancing equity.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">By Alondra Nelson and Clarence Wardell III, <br><strong>Equitable Data Working Group</strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>The Equitable Data Working Group was established on the first day of the Biden-Harris Administration under Executive Order 13985, <em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/memorandum-on-restoring-trust-in-government-through-scientific-integrity-and-evidence-based-policymaking/">Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government</a></em>, as part of the President’s commitment to a whole-of-government approach to advancing equity. As the order notes, “a first step to promoting equity in Government action is to gather the data necessary to inform that effort.”</p>



<p>Because Federal data are often not available by race, ethnicity, sexual orientation and gender identity, disability, income, region, veteran status, or other crucial demographic variables, the Equitable Data Working Group is tasked with identifying inadequacies in our existing Federal data collection infrastructure and laying out a strategy for improving equitable data practices in the Federal government. Acquiring the necessary data, either through the collection of new data or by blending information from multiple data sources, is a critical step in ensuring equity is a central component of decision-making processes across the Federal government. Agencies have also begun to identify where data gaps are making it more difficult to conduct equity assessments of their policies, programs, and services.</p>



<p>The Equitable Data Working Group is a multi-disciplinary group, composed of government leaders in program policy, statistics, social science, data science, and information technology that is initially taking a case-study approach to the work, which will pave the way to lasting change. The end goal is regular systematic measurement of equity and inequities throughout the Federal government.</p>



<p>Our case study approach focuses our initial efforts on a set of well-defined questions that have historically been difficult to answer for lack of sufficient data. For instance, questions under consideration currently include:</p>



<ul><li>If we had data about the race, ethnicity, and gender of those using or not using unemployment benefits, could we better understand the impact of labor market cycles on underserved subpopulations?</li><li>Can we better understand the distribution of programs and services in underserved communities, particularly in response to climate-related crises?</li><li>What disaggregated data is needed to measure whether the CARES Act benefits and American Rescue Plan benefits were equitably distributed?</li></ul>



<p>In each instance, the group aims to focus on high-impact data collection and prioritize cases that could create immediate value for local communities, policymakers, and academic researchers, alongside broad impact across the Federal government. Our intent is for these initial case studies to highlight the specific challenges that need to be addressed to establish and sustain equitable data practices across the Federal government, and ultimately form the basis of broader recommendations for how these practices can illuminate equity considerations in program and policy design, implementation, and outcomes.</p>



<p>By exploring key policy questions dependent upon underutilized, inaccessible, or missing data, the Equitable Data Working Group will explore ways to leverage government data in order to measure and promote equity. For example, in some cases the data needed to respond to an issue may exist, but there are so many barriers that it is underutilized. Part of our charge is to look for ways to responsibly promote agency data sharing and matching, to the extent permitted by law, to create datasets needed to answer relevant questions. Accordingly, we may make recommendations requiring regulatory or legislative changes.</p>



<p>As the Equitable Data Working Group proceeds in our work, we recognize that it is necessary to consider challenges for unintentional disclosure of personal information and privacy protection. We must be able to collect and share data about underserved communities—including Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander; lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (LGBTQ+); and rural communities—in ways that do not exacerbate their vulnerability, particularly when using or providing public-use data with high levels of detail.</p>



<p>We will also highlight areas of particular importance to advancing equity outcomes where the Federal government needs to collect additional information, because the data needed to illuminate or respond to an issue are low-quality or do not exist. For instance, very few Federal surveys and datasets provide the ability to characterize the experiences and life outcomes of those who identify as LGBTQ+ Americans, making it challenging for Federal policymakers, researchers, and the American people to ensure equitable life outcomes for LGBTQ+ people. As a modest step toward ensuring Federal data practices reflect and include LGBTQ+ individuals and families, we worked with the Office of the Chief Statistician and the U.S. Census Bureau to begin the process of including questions about sexual orientation and gender identity for the first time in their Household Pulse Survey beginning this month. The Household Pulse Survey measures how the coronavirus pandemic is impacting households across the country from a social and economic perspective. By including questions about sexual orientation and gender identity, Federal agencies and researchers will gain critical new insights into the impacts that the COVID-19 pandemic and resulting economic crisis has had on LGBTQ+ Americans. Going forward, we intend to continue work with key Federal agencies to identify opportunities for appropriate and dignified data collection on sexual orientation and gender identity.</p>



<p>The Equitable Data Working Group will provide an initial report to Ambassador Susan Rice, Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy, by Fall 2021. The report will communicate specific barriers and gaps to equitable data identified through our case studies and direct consultation with agencies and external stakeholders. The report will also include recommendations as to how to address those barriers. In this vein, the Equitable Data Working Group is seeking to foster new partnerships between Federal agencies, academic and research partners, state, local, and tribal governments, community and advocacy groups, and other stakeholders, in order to leverage Federal data for new insights on the effects of structurally biased policies, and to advance capacity for multilayered, intersectional analysis of Federal datasets. We’re already seeing this happen across some agencies, including the <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/oasp/evaluation/currentstudies/Department-of-Labor-Summer-Data-Challenge" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Department of Labor’s Summer Data Challenge on Equity and Underserved Communities</a>, and we hope to help replicate these promising approaches.</p>



<p>We plan to keep the public updated on our work and regularly share examples of how the Equitable Data Working Group is working across Federal agencies, in consultation with the Chief Data Officers Council, Evaluation Officer Council and Interagency Committee on Standards Policy, and in partnership with communities and other stakeholders outside the Federal government. We recognize that many have worked for years to advance this work, and we are both excited about the promise that this moment holds and clear-eyed about the challenges that have stalled progress in the past. Our approach is intended to assess systemic barriers and stimulate long-term change that seeks to go beyond a one-time project. Further, we hope agencies will be able to use what we learn as they develop and commit to ongoing efforts to advance equity in their Action Plans due in January 2022. We are eager to learn from how others have approached this issue in their own organizations and sectors, and welcome input into our approach. We have been pleased to hear feedback from the public via the recent <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/05/05/2021-09109/methods-and-leading-practices-for-advancing-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Request for Information</a> on <em>Methods and Leading Practices for Advancing Equity and Support for Underserved Communities</em> through Government and we look forward to future engagement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Blueprint for a Fair, Orderly and Humane Immigration System</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-blueprint-for-a-fair-orderly-and-humane-immigration-system/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States can have an orderly, secure, and well-managed border while treating people fairly and humanely. In January, the Biden-Harris Administration launched a broad, whole of government effort to reform our immigration system, including sending to Congress legislation that creates a new system to responsibly manage and secure our border, provide a pathway to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States can have an orderly, secure, and well-managed border while treating people fairly and humanely.</p>



<p>In January, the Biden-Harris Administration <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/20/fact-sheet-president-biden-sends-immigration-bill-to-congress-as-part-of-his-commitment-to-modernize-our-immigration-system/">launched</a> a broad, whole of government effort to reform our immigration system, including sending to Congress legislation that creates a new system to responsibly manage and secure our border, provide a pathway to citizenship, and better manage migration across the Hemisphere.</p>



<p>In the six months since, the Administration has made considerable <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/action-the-biden-harris-administration-has-taken-to-address-the-border-challenge/">progress</a> to build a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system while continuing to call on Congress to make long overdue reforms to U.S. immigration laws. We successfully processed over 12,500 people who had been returned to Mexico under the Migrant Protection Protocols. We expanded lawful pathways for protection and opportunity, including the Central American Minors (CAM) program to reunite children with their parents in the United States. We strengthened collaborative migration management with regional partners, including through a new Human Smuggling and Trafficking Task Force to disrupt and prevent migrant smuggling and human trafficking operations. And we continue to deter irregular migration at our Southern border.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has accomplished this and more while reckoning with the prior Administration’s cruel and reckless immigration policies, which exacerbated long-standing challenges and failed to securely manage our border. Case in point: the total number of unique encounters at the Southern border to date this fiscal year remains below the total number of unique encounters to date during fiscal year 2019 under the Trump Administration.</p>



<p>Today the Administration is releasing a blueprint that outlines the next steps Federal agencies will be taking to continue implementing the President’s transformative vision for a 21st century immigration system that secures the border, fairly and efficiently considers asylum claims, strengthens regional migration management efforts in North and Central America, and addresses the root causes of migration from Central America. Success in building this fair, orderly, and humane immigration system won’t be achieved overnight, especially after the prior Administration’s irrational and inhumane policies, but this Administration has a blueprint to get there and is making real progress.</p>



<p>We will always be a nation of borders, and we will enforce our immigration laws in a way that is fair and just. We will continue to work to fortify an orderly immigration system.</p>



<p><strong>ENSURING A SECURE, HUMANE AND WELL-MANAGED BORDER</strong></p>



<p>The United States can allow people to exercise their legal right to apply for asylum while also reducing irregular migration and maintaining an orderly, secure, and well-managed border.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Making better use of existing enforcement resources. </strong>Since fiscal year 2011, U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s (CBP) discretionary budget has grown from $9.9 billion to $15 billion in FY 2021. The President’s Budget redirects resources from a needless border wall to make robust investments in smarter border security measures, like border technology and modernization of land ports of entry, that are proven to be more effective at improving safety and security at the border. These investments will serve as a force multiplier to the over 19,500 Border Patrol Agents currently helping secure our Nation’s borders and the over 25,500 CBP Officers working at our land, air, and sea ports. The investments will also facilitate more robust and effective security screening to combat human smuggling and trafficking and the entry of undocumented migrants.</li><li><strong>Improving the expedited removal process for those who arrive at the border.</strong> The Administration is working to improve the expedited removal process at the border to fairly and efficiently determine which individuals have legitimate claims for asylum and other forms of protection. Asylum and other legal migration pathways should remain available to those seeking protection. Those not seeking protection or who don’t qualify will be promptly removed to their countries of origin.</li><li><strong>Facilitating secure management of borders in the region </strong>by providing training and technical assistance, supporting the improvement of border infrastructure and technology, and promoting collaborative migration and border management approaches.</li><li><strong>Strengthening anti-smuggling and anti-trafficking operations </strong>by working with regional governments to investigate and prosecute individuals involved in migrant smuggling, human trafficking, and other crimes against migrants. In April 2021, DHS announced Operation Sentinel, a new operation targeting organizations involved in criminal smuggling.</li><li><strong>Bolstering public messaging on migration </strong>by ensuring consistent messages to discourage irregular migration and promote safe, legal, and orderly migration.</li></ul>



<p><strong>IMPLEMENTING ORDERLY AND FAIR PROCESSING OF ASYLUM APPLICATIONS</strong></p>



<p>The Administration is committed to fairly and efficiently considering asylum claims. Asylum and other legal migration pathways should remain available to those seeking protection. But those not seeking protection or who don’t qualify will be returned to their country of origin.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Establishing a dedicated docket to consider asylum claims.</strong> The Administration has set up a special immigration court docket to promptly and fairly consider the protection claims of certain recent arrivals.</li><li><strong>Further improving the efficiency and fairness of the U.S. asylum system </strong>by authorizing asylum officers to adjudicate asylum claims for those arriving at the border and establishing clear and just eligibility standards that harmonize the U.S. approach with international standards. The Administration has already begun to rescind Trump administration policies and decisions that unjustly prevent individuals from obtaining asylum. On June 16, the Department of Justice reversed two of the former administration’s rulings severely restricting asylum protections for victims of domestic and gang violence.</li><li><strong>Maximizing legal representation </strong>and legal orientation programs by working closelywith pro bono legal service providers. The President’s FY 2022 Budget requests $15 million to provide representation to families and vulnerable individuals, as well as $23 million to support DOJ legal orientation programs.</li><li><strong>Reducing immigration court backlogs</strong> by ensuring priority cases are considered in a timely manner and hiring more immigration judges. The FY 2022 Budget requests an additional 100 immigration judges and provides support for additional court staff to ensure the efficient and fair processing of cases.  The Department of Justice also restored the discretion of immigration judges to administratively close cases in another step to ensure priority cases are considered in a timely manner.</li></ul>



<p><strong>STRENGTHENING COLLABORATIVE MIGRATION MANAGEMENT WITH REGIONAL PARTNERS</strong></p>



<p>The United States seeks to expand U.S. and multilateral efforts to address the dire humanitarian situation in Central America and strengthen regional collaborative migration management.  The United States believes that all individuals should be able to have a safe, stable and dignified life within their own countries, while ensuring that asylum and other legal migration pathways remain available to those who need them.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing humanitarian support to address the acute needs that pressure individuals to abandon their homes</strong>.  U.S. efforts will address food insecurity and malnutrition, mitigate the impacts of successive droughts and food shortages, promote protection for vulnerable individuals, and provide materials to support rebuilding of homes and schools damaged by the hurricanes.  The United States will also work with the United Nations to mobilize international support for the deteriorating situation in the Northern Triangle. As part of these efforts, the United States in April <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/apr-27-2021-united-states-announces-increased-assistance-people-of-el-salvador-guatemala-honduras">provided</a> $255 million in assistance to meet immediate and urgent humanitarian needs for people in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, refugees, other displaced people, and vulnerable migrants in the region.</li><li><strong>Expanding access to international protection</strong> to provide safety to individuals closer to their homes by building and improving national asylum systems, enhancing efforts to resettle refugees, and scaling up protection efforts for at-risk groups.</li><li><strong>Establishing Migration Resource</strong> <strong>Centers</strong> in the Northern Triangle countries with the support of international organizations and in coordination with governments in Central America to provide referrals to services for people seeking lawful pathways for migration and protection.  The centers also provide referrals to reintegration support for migrants returned from the United States and other countries.</li><li><strong>Restarting and expanding the Central American Minors (CAM) program </strong>to provide children the opportunity to receive protection and reunite with parents in the United States. In March 2021, the United States reopened the CAM program and, in June 2021, expanded it to additional categories of eligible U.S.-based relatives who can petition for their children.</li><li><strong>Expanding refugee processing in the region</strong>, including in-country processing in Northern Triangle countries, and helping international organizations and local non-governmental organizations to identify and refer individuals with urgent protection needs to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program and other resettlement countries. The U.S. Department of State and Department of Homeland Security have resumed interviewing individuals via the Protection Transfer Arrangement (PTA) to expand protection for vulnerable nationals of El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.</li><li><strong>Expanding access to temporary work visas in the region.  </strong>DHS announced a supplemental increase of 6,000 H-2B visas for temporary non-agricultural workers from Honduras, Guatemala and El Salvador in FY 2021. The Administration is also exploring ways to enhance access to H-2A visas for temporary agricultural workers when there are insufficient qualified U.S. workers to fill these jobs, while ensuring strong labor protections for all workers.  The Administration will also encourage other governments to develop and expand regional labor migration programs that protect workers’ rights and allow access for individuals to find meaningful, temporary work.</li><li><strong>Reducing immigrant visa backlogs.  </strong>The United States aims to reduce the backlog of immigrant visa applications for Northern Triangle nationals as quickly as possible.</li></ul>



<p><strong>INVESTING IN CENTRAL AMERICA TO ADDRESS THE ROOT CAUSES OF MIGRATION</strong></p>



<p>We cannot solve the challenge at our border without addressing the lack of economic opportunity, weak governance and corruption, and violence and insecurity that compel people to flee their homes in the first place.  The impact of two major hurricanes in late 2020, a prolonged drought, and COVID-19 have aggravated these long-standing challenges.  The FY 2022 Budget requests $861 million to address the root causes of migration.    </p>



<ul><li><strong>Addressing economic insecurity and inequality </strong>by investing in programs that foster a business-enabling environment for inclusive economic growth; enhancing workforce development, health, and education; and building resilience to climate change and food insecurity so individuals can find economic opportunity at home. The U.S. will also work with stakeholders to increase trade and diversify industry, as well as with the private sector to build on the <em>Call to Action</em> to catalyze investments in the region and support economic development.</li><li><strong>Combatting corruption and strengthening democratic governance </strong>by working with governments, civil society, and independent media to improve government services, increase transparency, promote accountability and respect for human rights, sanction corrupt actors, and provide protection to at-risk youth, victims of violence, and other marginalized populations.</li><li><strong>Promoting respect for human rights, labor rights and a free press</strong> by working with governments and civil society to strengthen legal frameworks and build institutional capacity, hold perpetrators accountable, promote labor rights compliance, and ensure citizens have access to information from independent sources to inform their choices.</li><li><strong>Countering and preventing violence, extortion, and other crimes</strong> by strengthening accountable law enforcement, focusing on crime prevention, and encouraging regional cooperation to address shared criminal threats.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Combatting sexual, gender-based and domestic violence </strong>by working with governments and civil society to prevent and prosecute violence and support victims.</li></ul>



<p>While President Biden can implement significant parts of this strategy within his executive authority, <strong><u>Congress must also act.</u></strong>  Millions of noncitizens call our country home.  Immigrants are key a key part of our communities and make significant contributions to our economy.  Over the past year, millions of immigrants have risked their health to work side by side with other Americans to perform jobs that are essential to the functioning of the country.  They are Americans in every way but on paper.  The American public supports a path to citizenship and a fair and efficient legal immigration system that welcomes talent from around the globe and allows families to reunite and make a life in our country.</p>



<p><strong>Congress should pass </strong>through reconciliation or other means:</p>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">The U.S. Citizenship Act (H.R. 1177/S. 348)</span> that reunites families, gives businesses access to a workforce with full labor rights, and creates a path to citizenship for those already living and working in the United States.  These critical reforms, coupled with measures to address the root causes of migration from Central America, will relieve pressure at the border by dissuading irregular migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">The Dream and Promise Act (H.R. 6) and Farm Workforce Modernization Act (H.R. 1603)</span> to create a path to citizenship for Dreamers, TPS recipients, and farmworkers. Both bills passed the House with bipartisan support.  They will protect millions of families, children, and essential workers who live, work, study, and worship in our communities. </li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Meeting with Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi of Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/26/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-meeting-with-prime-minister-al-kadhimi-of-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi of Iraq to strengthen bilateral coordination under the Strategic Framework Agreement.&#160; Together they discussed expanded initiatives on climate, energy, education, and combatting the COVID-19 pandemic.&#160; They committed to a continued security partnership to ensure that ISIS can never resurge and to allow communities recovering&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi of Iraq to strengthen bilateral coordination under the Strategic Framework Agreement.&nbsp; Together they discussed expanded initiatives on climate, energy, education, and combatting the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; They committed to a continued security partnership to ensure that ISIS can never resurge and to allow communities recovering from terror to rebuild with dignity even as the United States shifts to a purely advisory role. The leaders reaffirmed their respect for Iraq’s democracy, the rule of law, and promoting a secure environment for Iraq’s upcoming elections in October. The leaders agreed on the vital importance of holding these elections on time, and welcomed the UN monitoring mission to support their full transparency and fairness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together, they discussed the important role of Iraq in the region and the significant diplomatic efforts led by Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi to improve and strengthen Iraq’s relationships in the region.&nbsp; They lauded the historic visit of Pope Francis to Iraq earlier this year, the trilateral summit with Egypt and Jordan, and the important role Iraq plays in promoting interfaith tolerance and the common bonds of humanity in the Middle East.&nbsp; They agreed that Iraq’s stability was central to the stability of the entire region.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and Prime Minister Mustafa Al-Kadhimi of the Republic of Iraq Before Bilateral Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/26/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-mustafa-al-kadhimi-of-the-republic-of-iraq-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 2:20 P.M. EDT&#160;PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, I&#8217;m honored to welcome the Prime Minister.&#160; We&#8217;ve known each other for some time.&#160; And welcome to the White House, welcome to the Oval, Mr. Prime Minister.&#160;&#160;Iraq has been a vital part for the &#8212; partner of the United States for some time now in the Middle East.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>2:20 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m honored to welcome the Prime Minister.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve known each other for some time.&nbsp; And welcome to the White House, welcome to the Oval, Mr. Prime Minister.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Iraq has been a vital part for the &#8212; partner of the United States for some time now in the Middle East.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve en- &#8212; I’ve engaged deeply in Iraq for my entire career back in the Senate, as Vice President, and as President. &nbsp;And I&#8217;ve worked with Iraq to &#8212; and matter of fact, my son Beau was in Iraq for a year with the Am- &#8212; with the Army National Guard.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the sacrifices that so many &#8212; so many have made to build the U.S.-Iraq partnership has been real, and it&#8217;s consequential.&nbsp; And my administration is committed to strengthening that partnership, Mr. Prime Minister.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the U.S-Iraqi Strategic Dialogue is about commitments that expand our cooperation on issues like healthcare, climate, energy.&nbsp; For &#8212; matter of fact, I wanted to tell you: I was told you &#8212; the half a million &#8212; 500,000 &#8212; doses of COVID vaccine we&#8217;re sending &#8212; I was told you were told they wouldn’t come for a while.&nbsp; They’ll be there in a couple of weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRIME MINISTER AL-KADHIMI:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; They’ll be there quickly. &nbsp;And &#8212; and, you know, we support strengthening Iraq’s democracy, and we&#8217;re anxious to make sure the election goes forward in October.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also committed to our security cooperation.&nbsp; Our shared fight against ISIS is critical for the stability of the region.&nbsp; And our counterterrorism cooperation will continue, even as we shift to this new phase we&#8217;re going to be talking about.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m looking forward to consulting with the Prime Minister today.&nbsp; We have a lot to talk about.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been a good friend.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m anxious to get going.<br>&nbsp;<br>Floor is yours, sir.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRIME MINISTER AL-KADHIMI:&nbsp;&nbsp;Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp;&nbsp;It&#8217;s a great honor to be here today with our American friends.&nbsp;&nbsp;We have strategic partnership.&nbsp;&nbsp;I&#8217;m happy to be here in Washington to discuss the future of our nation and how to improve this relation between our two countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>America, they help Iraq.&nbsp;&nbsp;Together we fight to defeat Daesh &#8212; ISIS.&nbsp;&nbsp;And I&#8217;d like to thank the American people on behalf of all Iraq’s people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Mr. President, I thank you for all the blood and treasure that America has given for a free and democratic Iraq.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, our relation is stronger than ever.&nbsp; Our partnership exists for economy, the environment, health, education, culture, and more.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m looking forward to work with you, Mr. President, to bring our two countries more closer for benefit of Iraq and United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>God bless our two countries.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: &nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, folks.<br>&nbsp;<br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.&nbsp;Whoa, whoa, whoa.&nbsp; Whoa. &nbsp;Hang on a second.&nbsp; If you want to talk about Iraq, ask me a question about Iraq.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How many troops would you like to see in Iraq by the end of this year?&nbsp; And how does the relationship changes, considering this is the last strategic dialogue that you have with Iraq and the Prime Minister?<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; This most recent dialogue you mean.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Correct.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve been talking a lot.&nbsp; Our foreign ministers, our Cabinet members have been talking.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking forward to seeing an election in October.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working very hard with the Iraqi government to make sure the U.N. and the GCC are &#8212; we have oversight; that there&#8217;s &#8212; these are full and fair elections.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ve been in &#8212; I&#8217;ve been in contact with Kadhimi.&nbsp; I have &#8212; anyway, I think things are going well.&nbsp; Our role in Iraq will be as a &#8212; dealing with not &#8212; it’s just to be available, to continue to train, to assist, to help, and to deal with ISIS as it &#8212; as it arrives.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re not going to be, by the end of the year, in a combat mission.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, Veterans Affairs.&nbsp; Mr. President, Veterans Affairs is going to have a mandate for its healthcare &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; You are such a pain in the neck, but I&#8217;m going to answer your question because we&#8217;ve known each other for so long. It has nothing to do with Iraq.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I take that as a compliment, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; (Laughs.) &nbsp;I&#8217;ll answer your question.&nbsp; Yes, Veteran Affairs is going to, in fact, require that all docs working in facilities are going to have to be vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>2:26 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe Biden on the Passing of Civil Rights Leader, Bob Moses</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/26/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-civil-rights-leader-bob-moses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 20:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaking in the spring of 1964 about his plans for Freedom Summer, Bob Moses summed up the heroic effort to register Black voters in the Deep South with a question: “What kind of society will we be?”  Throughout his remarkable life, Bob devoted his heart and soul to lead, teach, and organize generations of Americans&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Speaking in the spring of 1964 about his plans for Freedom Summer, Bob Moses summed up the heroic effort to register Black voters in the Deep South with a question: “<em>What kind of society will we be?</em>” <br><br>Throughout his remarkable life, Bob devoted his heart and soul to lead, teach, and organize generations of Americans to answer that question by making real the promise of our nation – that we are all created equal and deserve to be treated equally throughout our lives.<br><br>He did so with uncommon grace, calm, and humility despite every bullet, arrest, and unrelenting brutality he faced.<br><br>The violent and murderous response to the Freedom Summer he organized helped galvanize support for the landmark Voting Rights Act of 1965.  A celebrated educator by training and by heart, he understood education is a great equalizer and helped countless students, and our nation, realize their dreams and full potential.<br><br>From the polling stations of Mississippi and in classrooms of our nation, Bob always showed up and never, ever gave in. In his memory, let us continue his unfinished work and answer the question he asked us once before – to be a society that delivers on the promise of this nation.<br><br>With attacks on the right to vote unseen since the days of the Jim Crow system Bob helped to dismantle, I call on Congress again to pass the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act. Let us build the coalition of Americans of every race and background that he once formed to meet the urgency of the moment. And let us follow his towering legacy and ensure every American is treated with the dignity and respect they deserve.<br><br>Jill and I send our love and prayers to Bob’s wife, Janet, their four children, and their seven grandchildren.<br><br>May God bless Bob Moses.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 26, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/26/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-26-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 20:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1:04 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Happy Monday.&#160; Okay.&#160; Today, I wanted to start by providing a brief note on where we are with our battle against the pandemic at home.&#160;First, taking a step back: In December, the percentage of Americans willing to get a shot was in the 30s.&#160; We now have 70 percent&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1:04 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Happy Monday.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Today, I wanted to start by providing a brief note on where we are with our battle against the pandemic at home.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, taking a step back: In December, the percentage of Americans willing to get a shot was in the 30s.&nbsp; We now have 70 percent of adult &#8212; almost 70 percent, I should say, of adult Americans who have been vaccinated.&nbsp; That is a positive step forward, and it is an encouraging sign to us that we can still get more people vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Where we are today signals we&#8217;ve made pretty incredible progress with our vaccination effort.&nbsp; Sixty percent of adult Americans are fully vaccinated, including 80 percent of seniors.&nbsp; Nearly 90 percent of teachers have gotten a shot.&nbsp; Ninety-five percent-plus of physicians have been fully vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>For the second week in a row, last week the five states with the highest case rates &#8212; Arkansas, Florida, Louisiana, Texas, and California &#8212; had a higher rate of people getting newly vaccinated compared to the national average.&nbsp; Again, this is a positive trend.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And just one more recent proof point: In the reporting period from yesterday, nearly half a million Americans made the decision to get their first shot.<br>&nbsp;<br>Numbers like this signal to us people are understanding the urgency and importance of getting vaccinated, and rightfully so.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as you&#8217;ve heard me say in here a number of times, 162-plus million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; They have a very strong degree of protection against the variants.&nbsp; They are overwhelmingly avoiding severe illness, hospitalization, and, critically important, death.&nbsp; Unvaccinated individuals account for virtually all of the hospitalizations and deaths in the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And data out from the United Kingdom, which has experienced &#8212; experiencing its own surge in cases driven by Delta, showed hospitalization rates down 73 percent compared to December, when there were nearly identical case rates but almost no vaccinations.&nbsp; And what that means is the vaccinations are protecting people from hospitalizations in the United Kingdom, which is a positive sign.&nbsp; And deaths are down 93 percent &#8212; further proof that getting fully vaccinated is the best thing anyone can do to protect themselves and those around them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, we are seeing a significant rise in cases in certain parts of the country and amongst certain populations, and they&#8217;re concentrated primarily and overwhelmingly among the unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re hearing and you all are reporting on stories on those not getting vaccinated.&nbsp; Some of those&nbsp;&#8212; like a radio host in Tennessee &#8212; are saying from their hospital bed that they plan to be a strong advocate for the vaccine after recovering from severe illness because of COVID.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t want it to lea- &#8212; we don&#8217;t want that to be the breaking point for anyone, but we are seeing that across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, again, the reality is: It&#8217;s preventable.&nbsp; We welcome people&#8217;s questions around the country about vaccines and their efficacy.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll be here for people, whatever they want to talk about, as will people in local communities.&nbsp; But I just wanted to provide a quick update with all of your good questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Aamer, go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci said yesterday that recommending that the vaccinated wear masks is under active consideration.&nbsp; I was wondering where do things stand with that conversation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then also COVID-related:&nbsp;Considering that the administration is not moving at the moment to lift the restrictions on travel because of the Delta variant, is the administration weighing broader recommendations on telling Americans &#8212; and I know there are some places, like the UK &#8212; but, &#8220;Don&#8217;t go&#8221;?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say, for any of these recommendations, we are always going to be guided by our North Star &#8212; and that is the CDC and our health and medical experts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as I said last week, having an active &#8212; it would be actually surprising and odd if our health and medical experts were not having active &#8212; an active discussion about how to protect &#8212; best protect the American people.&nbsp; And there, of course, is an active discussion about a range of steps that can be taken, as there has been from the first day of this administration.<br>&nbsp;<br>Certainly, the surge in cases among unvaccinated, because of the Delta variant, prompts, you know, even more discussion about what actions can be taken.&nbsp; But we are going to &#8212; the CDC looks at data, they look at data across the country, in a range of regions across the country.&nbsp; And if they make an assessment, we will of course be here to follow their guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I may, just one more on tomorrow &#8212; I think it’s tomorrow&#8217;s visit to the ODNI.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any &#8212; what is the President going there to say, do?&nbsp; Is there any major announcements expected?&nbsp; And how much of this is about also sending a different or contrasting message with the previous President, who sometimes had some comments that were less than flattering about the intelligence community?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Let me just go back to your last question about the travel restrictions, if you don&#8217;t mind &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh &#8212; thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; because I just want to confirm it for those of you.&nbsp; So, given where we are today &#8212; and I think you&#8217;ve seen this, and those of you who have asked, we&#8217;ve confirmed this for &#8212; with the Delta variant, we will maintain existing travel restrictions at this point for a few reasons.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The more transmissible Delta variant is spreading both here and around the world.&nbsp; Driven by the Delta variant, cases are rising here at home, particularly among those who are unvaccinated, and appear likely to continue in the weeks ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>And to get to the other part of your question, the CDC just advised Americans against travel to the United Kingdom this past Monday, given the surge in cases.&nbsp; They will evaluate and make &#8212; and make recommendations based on health data.<br>&nbsp;<br>To your question about his &#8212; the President&#8217;s visit to ODNI tomorrow to see the Director of National Intelligence &#8212; first woman to lead the intelligence community in history, I&#8217;ll just note &#8212; yes, I think the President &#8212; one, he will go there to receive an update on their work, but also to thank them for their work during what has been, no doubt, a challenging time for members of the intelligence community over the last several years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;s someone who believes in the role of the intelligence community, of civil servants.&nbsp; He believes they&#8217;re the backbone of our government, and certainly he&#8217;ll make that clear.&nbsp; But, you know, I think you can all make the inherent contrast; I don&#8217;t think that will be a central part of his message tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; To follow up on masks, Dr. Fauci confirmed yesterday he was obviously part of the discussions.&nbsp; Is President Biden part of the discussions, as well, regarding whether to bring back the recommendations and/or any of his economic advisors?&nbsp; Just trying to understand who&#8217;s &#8212; who&#8217;s making the decision.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President receives regular updates from his COVID team.&nbsp; But the guidance &#8212; or the discussions are primarily between the health and medical experts about how we should proceed from here to address the rising cases in &#8212; from the Delta variant among unvaccinated and protect the American public.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything you can share about what they are considering &#8212; what are the pros and the cons for re-recommending masks for vaccinated people?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It &#8212; we don&#8217;t look at it through that prism.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t make these decisions or recommendations based on politics.&nbsp; They make them based on data.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So it&#8217;s quite simple: They look at data across the country.&nbsp; They make a determination about what steps they could recommend to protect more people and save more lives.&nbsp; And then, if they make a recommendation, as you&#8217;ve seen over the past several months, we will work to implement it.&nbsp; But it is not more complicated than that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; And one on Afghanistan.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In recent days, there have been several U.S. airstrikes against the Taliban.&nbsp; After the deadline for troop withdrawal on August 31st, will the U.S. continue to support Afghan forces in airstrikes?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve said we would maintain over-the-horizon capacity.&nbsp; Beyond that, I don&#8217;t have any other updates.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A group of healthcare professionals are saying that there should be mandates for all who work in the healthcare system because of what they say is an ethical need to do so, to be vaccinated.&nbsp; And we see that there are local communities that are bringing mask mandates or recommendations.&nbsp; So are we at a point where Americans should be looking to professional organizations, businesses, and local officials for guidance on what to do more than the federal government at this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say: We would hope that the guidance is aligned with &#8212; there are going to be localities that have higher vac- &#8212; higher rates of outbreaks that they may make additional recommendations.&nbsp; They may take steps to keep their community safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We certainly have seen, as you noted, that there are institutions, including across the health industry.&nbsp; As many of you have may have seen, today, 57 leading healthcare groups &#8212; including the American Medical Association, the American College of Physicians, the American Academy of Pediatrics, and the American Public Health Association &#8212; all called for all healthcare and long-term care employees to mandate employees be vaccinated against COVID.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, that is the healthcare industry where they are very much on the frontlines.&nbsp; And these actions, in our view, are meant to keep patients and employees safe.&nbsp; And, in fact, I expect our own federal healthcare providers may look at similar requirements, as they do with other vaccines.<br>&nbsp;<br>As it relates to what the American people should look to &#8212; look, the CDC is looking at data across the country.&nbsp; They provide broad public health guidance not based on politics, driven by science and data.&nbsp; And they make updates when they feel it is necessary to make updates, and then localities will apply that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you suggesting perhaps the VA would be making a similar recommendation or requirement?&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re hinting at there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; I think there&#8217;ll be more to &#8212; more to say in the coming days on that, Kelly.&nbsp; But I will tell you that we certainly believe that public &#8212; that health officials are on the frontlines of, you know, being vulnerable to getting COVID, and we certainly support these actions by these hospital associations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House view it as a benefit if employers, as varied as the NFL to hospitals, are trying to push vaccination?&nbsp; Would that close the gap, in your view, with some of those who&#8217;ve not yet done so for a variety of reasons?&nbsp; I mean, do you see this as another lever that might actually be helpful to the President&#8217;s goals?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It may.&nbsp; And beyond the President&#8217;s goals, it may save lives, and that&#8217;s the most important &#8212; important factor, in our view.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re seeing institutions, healthcare providers, colleges and universities, the NFL implement different approaches and steps to incentivize and increase vaccination rates.&nbsp; The more people are vaccinated, the more the country will be safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last one.&nbsp; Do you expect that for air travelers domestically in the United States who’ve been required to wear a mask by FAA regulation for a long time &#8212; that&#8217;s set to expire in September &#8212; should we anticipate that that would likely stay in place, given the Delta variant?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any &#8212; any guidance by our CDC.&nbsp; But certainly, they will continue to provide guidance on masks that keeps more people safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On COVID, Dr. Fauci says, “We&#8217;re going in the wrong direction.”&nbsp; Whose fault is that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, what he was referring to is the fact that because there&#8217;s still a large population of people in this country who are unvaccinated and we have the most transmissible variants that we&#8217;ve seen since the beginning of the pandemic that more people are getting sick with COVID.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s not &#8212; those numbers are not moving in the right direction.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s accurate and you can see it by data.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then on crime: It has been more than a month since the President announced his comprehensive strategy to prevent and respond to gun crime and ensure public safety.&nbsp; This weekend, in Chicago, 73 people were shot; 11 of them were killed.&nbsp; Does the President think his strategy is working?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think you and I both know that when there&#8217;s been rising crime rates across the country, including Chicago, for 18 months or more that, unfortunately, it&#8217;s not going to turn on a dime, and that we are working with Chicago &#8212; it&#8217;s one of the cities &#8212; one of the five cities we&#8217;re working with.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Department of Justice has a group in there to help address the transmitting &#8212; or, the selling of guns and get &#8212; that are getting into the hands of people who shouldn&#8217;t have them.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working closely with the mayor and local elected officials.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve benefited a huge amount from the federal assistance and funding that the President fought to include in the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And what our hope is is that we can work in partnership to bring crime down, save more people.&nbsp; In cities like Chicago, we know gun violence is a big driver of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And after a couple shootings here in D.C. last week, the Chief of Police blamed some of the crime on marijuana dealers.&nbsp; He said he knows that people know that marijuana laws have loosened up.&nbsp; Does the White House think that it may be time to get tougher on marijuana?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think as we look to the crime that has been happening in D.C. &#8212; again, one of the cities where we&#8217;ve seen rising violence over the past year and a half, one where we&#8217;re working in close partnership through both the DOJ Gun Trafficking Strike Forces and &#8212; as well as our Community Violence Prevent- &#8212; Intervention Collaborative, we&#8217;re looking to address a range of causes, but working in close partnership with the mayor and police &#8212; local police to bring crime down in our city.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Quick question on tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; January 6th’s Select Committee &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; first meeting takes place tomorrow here.&nbsp; It takes place tomorrow.&nbsp; Do you know if the President plans to watch any of it?&nbsp; And what are his expectations for the outcome?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, first, the President has called for, as you know, a full and independent investigation to the events of January 6th.&nbsp; And he continues to support Speaker Pelosi’s leadership of that work, including her decision to appoint Republican members who are similarly committed to this objective.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, in his view and our view, tomorrow&#8217;s hearing will be an opportunity to hear firsthand from the men and women in the Capitol Police and the Metropolitan Police Department who bravely protected our Capitol on that day.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>His goal is the same goal that Speaker Pelosi has, which is to get to the bottom of what happened and prevent it from happening in the future.&nbsp; And he trusts her leadership to do exactly that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will he be watching any of the hearings?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, he typically has quite a packed schedule.&nbsp; He does catch news clips, sometimes all of you are featured in them.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sure he will be kept abreast of the hearings and the work that&#8217;s happening on the Hill tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then a follow-up on COVID: We&#8217;re hearing from health experts who are increasingly voicing their concern for the FDA having yet to grant full approval to COVID vaccines.&nbsp; Folks are using phrases like “grave mistake,” “puzzling as to why they haven&#8217;t yet.”&nbsp; What is your understanding as to why we have not seen full approval yet from the FDA?&nbsp; And do you have any, kind of, expectation for when we might?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the FDA is the gold standard, in our view, and they move at the speed of science.&nbsp; They look at a range of data and they make sure that when they make conclusions and when they give full approval, they have confidence in the science and the data that backs that up.&nbsp; It wouldn&#8217;t be responsible to expedite that process at a faster speed than the science and data allows.<br>&nbsp;<br>Certainly, everyone is eager &#8212; as the mother of two children under 12 myself, I would love to have vaccines approved so I can get my kids vaccinated.&nbsp; We understand that completely and understand the desire to have full approval, of course, as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re hopeful to see that in the coming months as Sec- &#8212; as &#8212; I was going to call him “Secretary Fauci” &#8212; as Dr. Fauci has said.&nbsp; But again, we rely on them to determine their own timeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; “Coming months” are &#8212; does the White House believe that we could be losing valuable time in waiting for full approval if this is what&#8217;s keeping so many folks from getting<br>vaccinated at this point?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think what&#8217;s most important is that the FDA maintains itself as the gold standard in approving use of vaccines for approval.&nbsp; And the fact that they are always going to be driven by the speed of science, they&#8217;re going to have extensive data they look into, they&#8217;re going to have the best health and medical experts making that conclusion, that will maintain confidence over the long term.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, we all want to see vaccines fully approved, vaccines for kids under 12.&nbsp; I think every &#8212; most Americans would say that.&nbsp; But that we&#8217;re going to &#8212; it&#8217;s important they move at their own speed and the speed at the scientists.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On an international issue, I wanted to ask you about Tunisia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has dismissed the parliament, most of the government, and it&#8217;s been denounced by multiple parties as a coup.&nbsp; Does the White House see that as a coup and have any reaction to what&#8217;s happening there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, we&#8217;re concerned about the developments in Tunisia, which come as Tunisian authorities are seeking to stabilize their economy, confront a resurgence in the COVID-19 pandemic, and improve living standards for all Tunisians.<br>&nbsp;<br>We are in touch at a senior level, from both the White House and the State Department, with Tunisian leaders to learn more about the situation, urge calm, and support Tunisian efforts to move forward in line with democratic principles.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know and as you just asked about, these &#8212; there have been a lot of developments, even over the last 24 hours.&nbsp; A legal determination about a coup &#8212; a determination about a coup is a legal determination, and we would look to the State Department to conduct a legal analysis before making a determination.&nbsp; So there hasn&#8217;t been a conclusion on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then I just wanted to ask about the embassy in Tunis, which handles a lot of business for the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; region, including Libya, et cetera.&nbsp; Any changes, as far as operations there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve not been made aware of changes but, again, that would be a decision made by the State Department based on their diplomatic security advice on the ground.&nbsp; But &#8212; so I would send you to them for any &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then just on a different issue, you know, with people talking about COVID and what some of the impacts of this new surge that we&#8217;re seeing are going to be, there might be some economic impacts.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen some Wall Street banks bring down their forecasts for what GDP growth is going to look like for this year.&nbsp; If that continues to be an issue, would the White House consider more stimulus &#8212; the type that we saw earlier this year &#8212; $1,400 checks, et cetera?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think an important piece to note for all of you is that the way the American Rescue Plan was designed was for it to have lasting effects that would go over the series of several months, far beyond the initial months of implementation.&nbsp; So there are components of the American Rescue Plan that are still being implemented that will still be implemented for months to come.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a lesson we&#8217;ve learned from the past about how people will need assistance for a longer period of time than just a short window.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that there are areas &#8212; I mean, we&#8217;ve seen, obviously, data in the housing market &#8212; right? &#8212; where there are &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s an impact &#8212; an economic impact is on people being able to stay in rental properties or in their homes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are areas of continued implementation &#8212; I think you&#8217;re familiar with these, but I&#8217;ll just note them &#8212; including on the forbearance program that we have &#8212; we have implemented in recent months, where people will be able to apply &#8212; I&#8217;m just using this as an example because I think housing and being able to stay in your house has a big impact to the economy &#8212; people can still apply through the end of September and still benefit from forbearance for six months following and then even longer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, point is, there a number of programs &#8212; the Child Tax Credit, which as you know, we started implementing in monthly checks, but there&#8217;s still going to be a benefit through to next year &#8212; that are part of the American Rescue Plan that we will continue to implement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also say that there&#8217;s &#8212; when it comes to the economy, there&#8217;s no significant signs, according to our economists, at this point, that the Delta variant impact across the country.&nbsp; We&#8217;d expect that much of any economic impact would be felt in the communities with lower vaccination rates; that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doubling down on our efforts to ensure we&#8217;re reaching Americans with the vaccine where they are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s one of the notes that, I think, our Secretary of Commerce made last week as well.&nbsp; One of the biggest, most important steps people can take is to get vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one very quick one &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; about the meetings that Wendy Sherman &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; has been having in China.&nbsp; I know that both sides basically came out of those meetings saying that there were disagreements.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What does that tell us about the possibility for some kind of talks between Xi and Biden?&nbsp; I mean, you know, you kind of set this template that &#8212; you know, with Russia &#8212; that even if you have disagreements, you&#8217;re going to still have meetings at the highest level.&nbsp; So where does that stand and do you still see that as possible or likely?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say, broadly speaking, as it relates to diplomacy, that is how we feel.&nbsp; And it was important for Deputy Secretary Sherman to go to Beijing and have these meetings because we think it&#8217;s important for us to say directly to the Chinese officials in private what we say in public.&nbsp; It&#8217;s in our interest to be very clear to Beijing about where we stand and explain our concerns in detail.<br>&nbsp;<br>And our philosophy is that we should not avoid hard topics, and they are certainly a part of any discussion we have diplomatically.&nbsp; There are areas where we have concern we&#8217;re very straightforward about, whether it&#8217;s the crackdown on Hong Kong, ongoing genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang, abuses in Tibet, curtailing of media access.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are also areas where we might align: the climate crisis; counternarcotics; nonproliferation; regional concerns, including DPRK, Iran, Afghanistan, and Burma.<br>&nbsp;<br>A topic of &#8212; you know, the President continues to believe in face-to-face diplomacy.&nbsp; That is something he has long been an advocate for, and we expect there will be some opportunity to engage at some point.&nbsp; But it did not come up in the context of these meetings, and it wasn&#8217;t &#8212; that was not the purpose of these meetings.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kaitlan.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll go to you, Mike, next, and then we&#8217;ll go around the room.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions for you: One, does the President favor restrictions for unvaccinated people when it comes to restaurants, museums, concerts?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President favors using the CDC as his North Star and what the health and medical experts are going to advise on how to save more lives and protect people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, no, he doesn&#8217;t think that there should be restrictions on unvaccinated people, like some other countries have instituted?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He believes that we should be guided by the science and by the data, and so he will look to his health and medical team to advise on what steps we should take.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Iraq, what will the number of U.S. forces be by the end of this year, given the drawdown you&#8217;re going to confirm today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, one, it&#8217;s important to note that this is one in a series of strategic dialogues &#8212; or this has been an ongoing strategic dialogue.&nbsp; And at the early part of the strategic dialogue, we had about 9,000 troops.&nbsp; We are now at about 2,500 U.S. forces in Iraq.&nbsp; We are there, of course, at Iraq&#8217;s invitation to improve the capacity of Iraqi Security Forces and help them in the fight against ISIS.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, but the real &#8212; the real announcement today &#8212; or real news today, I should say, is about a change of mission.&nbsp; And the numbers will be driven by what is needed for the mission over time.&nbsp; So, it is more about moving to a more advising and training capacity from what we have had over the last several years.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; But regardless of the title and what their mission is, how many &#8212; what&#8217;s the number that we expect to be there by December, given it&#8217;s by the end of the year?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just say the most important part is that it is a change in mission, and that the mission is changing in Iraq, and that it will be driven by what is needed for the mission.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I&#8217;m not going to give you operational &#8212; nor will I have operational details.&nbsp; I would point you to the Department of Defense on that.&nbsp; But the first step is the change in mission, the end of combat &#8212; of a combat role in Iraq and moving to a more of a train, advise, and assist role.&nbsp; That is what the Iraqi leadership have conveyed they want to see on the ground.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two COVID-related questions.&nbsp; One on mandates, which we&#8217;re seeing obviously &#8212; as folks have said already here &#8212;&nbsp;more kinds of places embrace, whether they be local authorities or more businesses, or colleges and universities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>How much does the President and do the people around the President fear that his weighing in more heavily to embrace mandates by these other institutions &#8212; or even mandates that the federal government impose on the military or federal workers, or what have you &#8212; how much do you fear that that actually inflames the culture war and is counterproductive, and that people will harden their opposition to the idea of taking a vaccination because the President is the President and is &#8212; and, sort of, the more he weighs in, that it actually is counterproductive?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that&#8217;s an important point in that we look &#8212; we do not want to look at our objective of getting more people vaccinated through a political prism.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t.&nbsp; And the President certainly recognizes that he is not always the right voice to every community about the benefits of getting vaccinated, which is why we have invested as much as we have in local voices and empowering local trusted voices.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say, though, that mandates, as is evidenced by the hospital associations, those are meant to keep people safe across the country.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to judge our success here by whether we score political points.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to judge it by whether we are able to save more lives.&nbsp; And if the health and medical experts suggest those are &#8212; that&#8217;s the right way to go, then we will support that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, on the travel &#8212; the extension of the travel bans, is there a &#8212; is it an indefinite extension at this point?&nbsp; Is there an end date?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And given the concern about Delta that is leading the United States to keep those in place for now, does that suggest that Title 42, and the use of Title 42 at the southern border, is equally likely to be extended, at least for now, given the same concerns with the Delta virus, both here and abroad?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, nothing is indefinite because obviously our objective is to defeat the virus.&nbsp; So, no.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have a timeline to predict for you because it&#8217;s all about what success we have at getting more people vaccinated, getting more vaccines out to the world, and fighting the virus.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have never conveyed or announced a timeline for Title 42.&nbsp; So, nothing has changed in that regard.&nbsp; It remains in place, and it will remain in place as long as that is the guidance from our health and medical experts.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; On infrastructure, there&#8217;s a pretty robust blame game already going on this morning over the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tis the season.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; over the negotiations going awry.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m wondering if the White House is concerned that the negotiators will not finalize a deal soon.&nbsp; And how much time is President Biden willing to give these negotiators, considering we&#8217;re on a pretty tight timetable?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as is normal in the end stages of big negotiations, there are some outstanding issues.&nbsp; Democrats made an offer that was designed to resolve each of these outstanding issues, which involve proposed compromises on our part and theirs.&nbsp; As we always are at this point in the negotiations, we&#8217;re in close touch with Republicans and Democrats on the Hill about this, and confident &#8212; we remain confident, I should say, about reaching an agreement.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also interested in any Republican counteroffers.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I would say this is to be expected.&nbsp; We always know that there are &#8212; is some wrangling at the end of a process.&nbsp; I would say &#8212; tell you also that White House staff and negotiators worked through the weekend, as I think many of you know.&nbsp; The President worked the phones all weekend and is continuing to.&nbsp; We&#8217;re encouraged as we&#8217;ve reached the final issues that need to be worked out and are confident about the path forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, yes, time is not endless.&nbsp; We are certainly on a timeline here, and we will work closely with Leader Schumer to get it done.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you want to see something this week?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we&#8217;ve certainly conveyed &#8212; and, again, Leader Schumer has conveyed the need to move forward.&nbsp; And we are optimistic about the progress and focused on steadily moving forward.&nbsp; And we continue to see progress being made each day.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second question, on COVID: Is there any discussion at the White House, at this point, of President Biden getting a booster shot?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We would rely on the health and &#8212; the expertise of our health and medical experts, and that&#8217;s not a guidance that they are providing at this point in time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I know that you&#8217;ve said a lot about being guided by the science.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about the science that is driving the continuation of this kind of travel ban?&nbsp; The Delta variant is already dominant in the U.S., so how does keeping people from foreign countries out, like, protect people in the U.S.?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I&#8217;m not a doctor or a medical expert.&nbsp; I think that that would best be posed to a member of the CDC or one of our doctors.&nbsp; But I think their decision was made based on the fact that the Delta variant is more transmissible and is spreading around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yes, it is the dominant variant here in the United States. That doesn&#8217;t mean that having more people who have the Delta variant is the right step.<br>&nbsp;<br>They &#8212; and also, we see cases rising here at home, particularly among those who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; And again, they base their decisions on data, on health and medical expertise, and on a consideration of a range of factors, including keeping the American people safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the scientists who are making these decisions are medical experts.&nbsp; Is it the CDC that is making the decision?&nbsp; Like, who is the &#8212; who is making these decisions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is the CDC?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, I just wasn’t sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so &#8212; and also, on a separate issue, when it comes to the issues of, like, voting rights, police reform &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; there are civil rights groups, voting rights groups that are expressing frustration with the White House.&nbsp; They feel like it is not giving the priority that they feel like it should be, especially because of the rhetoric that has come from the President saying that this is &#8212; you know, that these issues are taking the country back and that these are really some of the biggest issues since the Civil War.&nbsp; And yet, they feel like there has not been movement and pressure to get something done &#8212; concrete, tangible &#8212; to get something done from the White House.&nbsp; What is your response to that frustration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say the President is also frustrated. He wants to sign a voting rights bill into law.&nbsp; He wants to sign police reform into law.&nbsp; He believes both are long overdue.<br>&nbsp;<br>It requires Congress moving forward on these pieces of legislation and sending them to his desk.&nbsp; The role he can play is he&#8217;s spoken out publicly about it multiple times, advocated for how this is a fundamental right people should have across the country is voting rights.&nbsp; He has worked in close coordination, as has our team, with civil rights groups and partnership.&nbsp; And he has conveyed to them, and I will convey again publicly: He is with them and stands with them in their frustration, their view that this is a vital step.&nbsp; But he needs Congress to send him legislation in order to sign it into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’m just going to jump around.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to jump around.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, no, sorry &#8212; I was going right here, to Nadia.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On Iraq, a senior White House official said that this Strategic Dialogue with Iraq is going to be the final one.&nbsp; So how does the White House envisage the relationship going forward?&nbsp; And how do you respond to criticism by Republican senators saying that you’re capitulating to the pro-Iran militias by announcing this withdrawal, as we expect later today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we feel this is a natural next step in these ongoing strategic dialogues and that we are moving to a phase not where we are ending our partnership; we are maintaining a presence in Iraq with a different mission, in coordination with leadership of, of course, the Iraqi leadership, and one where we feel we can continue to be quite constructive in fighting ISIS and fighting the dangerous threats from Iranian proxies.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is a shift in mission; it is not a removal of our partnership or our presence or our close engagement with Iraqi leaders.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, why has the President not nominated someone for FDA Commissioner yet?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s certainly eager to nominate someone.&nbsp; He wants to make sure we have the right person to nominate, and he&#8217;s not going to do it at a pace faster than having the right person to put forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has the White House had any additional staffers test positive for COVID-19?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think, again, our policy &#8212; just to reiterate it &#8212; which we announced last week, is that if there&#8217;s an individual who is &#8212; has close proximity to any of the four principles, as defined by the White House Medical Unit, in line with CDC guidelines on what that looks like, we will then make that information available and immediately public to all of you.&nbsp; So that has not been the case since we announced that policy, no.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just real quick.&nbsp; On &#8212; I know we&#8217;ve asked you a number of times about the mask recommendation for the vaccinated, and I know you have said overwhelming majority of the cases are in people who are vaccinated &#8212; or who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; But what is the level of concern about infections and people who are vaccinated?&nbsp; Because there are &#8212; we keep hearing reports of vaccinated people &#8212; you know, hospitals say that they&#8217;re seeing patients who are vaccinated coming in.&nbsp; What is the level of concern in the administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think we all have a responsibility to be very clear about the data and what it says and what it does not say.&nbsp; Ninety-seven percent of hospitalizations are for &#8212; with people who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; That remains the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>The data from the health and medical experts still continues to be that if you are vaccinated, you are protected and it’s very, very unlikely that you will get sick, you will get hospitalized as a result of getting a breakthrough case.&nbsp; That remains the case in data.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, there are individual cases.&nbsp; We expect there to be breakthrough cases; we know there will be.&nbsp; The more people who are vaccinated, the more, as a percentage of individuals who are vaccinated, who will get COVID.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the most important thing is that people are, across the country, largely protected from serious illness if they&#8217;re vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just &#8212; just one quick follow-up.&nbsp; So the 97 percent number &#8212; so the CDC said that that is from January to April.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a bit of an outdated number when you look at how many people have been vaccinated since then and the Delta variant.&nbsp; So why isn&#8217;t there any more updated information coming from the CDC about what the risk is now to people who are vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can certainly see what their cycles of data is.&nbsp; We rely on data across the country.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t rely on individual, anecdotal cases that are reported because sometimes they scare the public without being based on broad swaths of information that the public should look at and look at the whole assessment of.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think you&#8217;ve seen across the country, again, that they&#8217;ll &#8212; and hospital leaders have said this too &#8212; that the number of cases of people who are coming in &#8212; the vast, vast majority &#8212; are people who are not vaccinated.&nbsp; That continues to be the case from hospital systems across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I&#8217;m certainly happy to see if there&#8217;s more updated data that is available or when it might be available too.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Steve.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, I want to go back to this question about vaccine mandates.&nbsp; Has it been determined here that it would be inappropriate or illegal for the President to require federal employees, civilian or military, to be vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It hasn&#8217;t been determined that it would be illegal, no.&nbsp; But we have not made a determination about that, no.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So why not?&nbsp; I mean, the President today referred to the federal government as a &#8220;model employer.&#8221;&nbsp; It&#8217;s the largest single employer of Americans &#8212; civilian and military put together.&nbsp; Why couldn’t the federal government demonstrate to the country that model that you&#8217;re talking about encouraging in the private sector?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Steve, it is certainly prudent for the federal government to be looking at any steps, just like any employer is, to your point, of how we can incentivize people get &#8212; for getting vaccinated, protect more people, save more lives.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this point in time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Do you &#8212; does the administration view vaccine misinformation as a national security threat?&nbsp; And on top of that, is there any indication that there are mal-actors that are feeding misinformation in vaccines?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve talked about this a little bit in the past.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give it a new label, but what I will tell you and reiterate is that certainly misinformation is a factor.&nbsp; It travels through a range of mediums &#8212; some on social media; some on media; some through elected officials or public voices, unfortunately; and sometimes all of those pieces are connected to each other.&nbsp; That is a concern &#8212; a significant concern for us.&nbsp; Hence, we&#8217;ve spoken out against that.<br>&nbsp;<br>What was the last part of your question?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to know if the administration had seen the fingerprints of any kind of mal-actors, such as Vladimir Putin, feeding this misinformation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve said &#8212; I think maybe last week or the week before &#8212; that we did see some elements of misinformation around the effectiveness of mRNA vaccines previously from foreign actors.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t think we have a broader assessment than that at this point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about the OMB director.&nbsp; Does the administration have any potential nominee to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s a lot of interest.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates for you on that one.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, Jen.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you have any update for U.S. citizens overseas that have been patiently waiting to get vaccinated.&nbsp; Should they &#8212; do you suggest they fly back to the United States?&nbsp; Or should they wait in the countries they&#8217;re living in?&nbsp; Will the embassies be doing anything more to assist them?&nbsp; Or vaccines that have been donated to countries &#8212; should a portion of those be allocated for Americans?&nbsp; What &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a really good question.&nbsp; I know that we haven&#8217;t been working &#8212; at this point, to date, that I am aware of &#8212; through embassies on programs with American citizens.&nbsp; Let me check with the State Department and our COVID team, and see if there&#8217;s more on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yamiche, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks so much for taking my question.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve reiterated several times the President is following the science.&nbsp; Can you talk a bit about whether or not he&#8217;s concerned at all that the CDC might be taking too long to issue new mask mandates or even vaccine mandates now that we see cities like New York issuing vaccine mandates?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think it&#8217;s important to take a step back and remember what we&#8217;re talking about here.&nbsp; The CDC evaluates data from across the country, and they will make public health guidance.&nbsp; They will present public health guidance.&nbsp; They do that on a regular, periodic basis.&nbsp; They will continue to do that.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re always considering a range of options as we have been from the beginning of the administration; of course, we are, as we should be.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They are &#8212; they do not make laws.&nbsp; It is the guidance currently that if you are not vaccinated, you should wear a mask.&nbsp; It is the guidance currently that if you are over 12 years old, you should get vaccinated.&nbsp; And regardless, the most effective step we can take around the country is to get more people vaccinated.&nbsp; So that is where our focus needs to be, regardless of where the CDC may or may not land on any additional guidance.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When I talked to experts, they say vaccine mandates would be a big step toward getting more people vaccinated.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m just wondering when you see organizations, like nearly 60, coming out and saying, &#8220;Let&#8217;s at least mandate healthcare workers being vaccinated,&#8221; why isn&#8217;t the White House behind that?&nbsp; What science is telling the White House &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I just said we support the step they took.&nbsp; What I&#8217;m getting at is &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know, but &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; the CDC does not determine mandates.&nbsp; The CDC provides public health guidance on what can save people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; Getting vaccinated can save people&#8217;s lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, would it be fair to say that &#8212; I guess my question is: Does the White House at all see itself standing up &#8212; and maybe this is what you&#8217;re saying now &#8212; &#8220;Yes, there should be mandates specifically for healthcare workers or teachers or municipal workers.&#8221;&nbsp; Does the White House see that as a role that it should be taking?&nbsp; And is there any danger in not doing that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I just said a few minutes ago that we support the step of hospitals, and that that was a guide and could be a guide for us on what to do with our own healthcare workforce here from the federal government.&nbsp; Just to give you kind of a sense.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that 90 percent of teachers across the country are vaccinated.&nbsp; And that is, in part, because of prioritizing teachers early; on a number of them taking the responsible step &#8212; of course, 90 percent of them &#8212; to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That would be up to schools and localities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are certain powers that the federal government has and there&#8217;s certain powers the federal government does not have. But we&#8217;re talking about a couple of different things here.&nbsp; One is public health guidance by the CDC, which will be driven by data.&nbsp; That gives guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The laws will be implemented by others.&nbsp; They do not make laws; they give public health guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Then there are decisions by institutions, by localities, by hospital systems, who may make decisions about how they can protect their workforces.&nbsp; We certainly support that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can ask you one quick thing on January 6th?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just &#8212; I know you said that the President&#8217;s going to, obviously, be busy tomorrow.&nbsp; But could you talk a little bit more about what the President thinks about these four Capitol Police officers testifying before this committee?&nbsp; And does he have anybody else that he wants to see possibly testify if his goal is the same as Speaker Pelosi, as he said?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly he relies on the leadership of Speaker Pelosi in moving this process and this independent investigation forward.&nbsp; And the individuals who will be testifying were brave heroes on this day &#8212; a dark day in our democracy.&nbsp; The President absolutely believes that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note &#8212; it&#8217;s noteworthy that many of the Republicans in Congress who are the most vocal about supposedly supporting the police in law and order are the same ones who&#8217;ve dismissed and downplayed the shameful events of that day.&nbsp; I don’t think that should be lost on anyone either, especially given about 140 individuals were injured that day &#8212; enforcement officers &#8212; 100 law enforcement officers were injured that day, according to their own numbers and statistics.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think we have to wrap because you guys got to go and see the spray of the Iraqi Prime Minister.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:46 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
