<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 21:43:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of the President’s Discussion with the Senate Democratic Caucus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/14/readout-of-the-presidents-discussion-with-the-senate-democratic-caucus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 20:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon the President thanked the Senate Democratic Caucus for the groundbreaking work they had done to reach the budget resolution agreement announced last night, and highlighted that it would grow the middle class, generate strong economic growth, and create millions of jobs.&#160; He also touted the benefits of the historic bipartisan infrastructure framework that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This afternoon the President thanked the Senate Democratic Caucus for the groundbreaking work they had done to reach the budget resolution agreement announced last night, and highlighted that it would grow the middle class, generate strong economic growth, and create millions of jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>He also touted the benefits of the historic bipartisan infrastructure framework that forms the other half of his domestic economic agenda, describing how he’s travelling the country and making a case about it and that polling data show the framework resonating strongly with voters in both parties.<br><br>The President credited the Senators for their successful work to pass the American Rescue Plan, noting that economic experts have cited it as a leading cause for the record job creation that has taken place since he took office and the doubling of the rate of economic growth in forecasts. And he described the Build Back Better agenda as a follow on to the Rescue Plan, to ensure that we’re rebuilding a stronger, more inclusive and more resilient middle class.&nbsp;<br><br>He emphasized that what tied the economic policies they are working on together was that they were built from the bottom up, with a recognition for the role that a good job plays in peoples’ lives, the rising costs families have had to bear from child care, elder care, and tuition, and the fact that when working and middle class families do well, everyone does well.<br><br>He also discussed how the means for funding these critical investments is popular with the American people, who know that the wealthiest individuals and corporations often pay a lower tax bill than teachers and firefighters.&nbsp;<br><br>The President repeatedly hit on how the effects of climate change are undeniable, and that the public is demanding action that the budget resolution will deliver. And he also spoke to the urgent need to overcome anti-voter laws, especially in a time when autocracies are trying to undermine democracy around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before Meeting with Disabilities Advocates to Discuss Voting Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-meeting-with-disabilities-advocates-to-discuss-voting-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 20:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President’s Ceremonial Office 11:47 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, I want to thank these incredible leaders for joining us today, this morning.  The issue of voting rights in America is probably among the most serious and significant issues that we are facing at this moment.  And voting rights for people with disabilities is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Vice President’s Ceremonial Office</p>



<p>11:47 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, I want to thank these incredible leaders for joining us today, this morning.  The issue of voting rights in America is probably among the most serious and significant issues that we are facing at this moment.  And voting rights for people with disabilities is one of our highest priorities.<br><br>In that context, I have asked these leaders to join me to provide us with insight, with advice, and with perspective on not only how these emerging laws in various states will impact our friends and our neighbors and family members with disabilities, but also I am fully aware that even before these laws started to most recently emerge, we still weren’t doing a good job.<br><br>And so that will be part of this conversation as well.  And &#8212; but we know there are, across this country &#8212; first of all, there are people with disabilities across our country.  There are people who vote for a variety of issues, and this is not a community that’s a monolith, just like no community is. <br><br>But it is &#8212; it is an issue when we think about the convenience for all communities of voting by mail.  And when there are laws that are restricting or preventing vote-by-mail, what does that mean to the voters?  What does it mean to the people when we talk about the ability to vote early for every community?<br><br>I talked about, you know, anybody who’s working two or three jobs &#8212; what that means to them.  Let&#8217;s see the people in terms of how folks live their lives and how will these restrictions impact the people’s right to have their voice reflected through their vote.<br><br>When I think about the laws that are &#8212; are being passed that &#8212; that are impeding on the assistance folks might need to register their vote, what will that mean in terms of restriction, suppression of the voice of the people? <br><br>So these are the subjects that we will discuss today.  And &#8212; and I will also add that our administration’s executive order from March will improve accessibility, and that is a good step.  So, while there are many steps that I believe are &#8212; are going backward, there are some steps that are going forward. <br><br>And in particular, the President’s executive order will, one, require that federal websites include more information about voting, and also, that it will be language accessible.  We are making sure that the federal voter registration form is accessible, that it is not bulky, that it is not incomprehensible.  Accessibility, again, across the board. <br><br>And we are going to require the National Institute of Standards and Technology &#8212; it’s known as “NIST” &#8212; that they study barriers to voting for people with disabilities and provide recommendations.<br><br>And then, there is a very important component to this Friday on this topic &#8212; and I’m so glad that we’re meeting before Friday &#8212; which is that: We have issued a notice asking for input from people with disabilities to submit that input by the end of Friday, July 16th. <br><br>And so, folks can go to &#8212; I’m going to give you a website &#8212; www &#8212; what would I be, a member of government, without a website.  (Laughter.)  But www.regulations.gov.  I’m going to repeat that: www.regulations.gov.  And enter &#8212; and then we’ll provide all of this on the web &#8212; our website as well.  Enter uppercase “NIST-2021” &#8212; this year &#8212; dash and then three zeros and a three &#8212; “0003.”  And we’ll get that information to everybody in another form as well.  Okay?<br><br>     So, I will end my comments for now by saying, again, thank you to all of the leaders who are convened today.  You represent the experience, the life, and the voice so many Americans whose voices and whose perspective must be represented in all of these rooms at all of these tables.  Because if we are truly a democracy, it means that we have a representative government that reflects the experience and the life of all of the people in our country.  And I think we have a lot more work to do<br>in this regard as it relates to our &#8212; our fellow Americans with disabilities. <br><br>So, I appreciate you all.  And with that, let&#8217;s begin our discussion.<br><br>Q    Madam Vice President, do have any comment on your conversation with the Texas legislatures &#8212; legislators from yesterday?  And do you know if the President plans to meet with them at all?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  We’ve had an extensive meeting &#8212; I had an extensive meeting yesterday with, I think, some of the most courageous elected leaders that we could note at this moment.<br><br>I said it yesterday, and I&#8217;ll say it again: They took bold, courageous action, in line with the legacy of everyone from Frederick Douglass &#8212; who is over my right shoulder &#8212; when he fought for the right of Black men to vote in America; to the legacy that includes all of those women who marched down Pennsylvania Avenue for women&#8217;s right to vote; to all of those folks who shed their blood on the Edmund Pettus Bridge to make sure that we would, in 1965, pass the Voting Rights Act.<br><br>And now we have, in 2021, the Texas legislature &#8212; many of them traveling to Washington, D.C., at great sacrifice, both personally and political, to stand up for Americans’ right to vote unencumbered.<br><br>11:54 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian of France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/14/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-foreign-minister-jean-yves-le-drian-of-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23825</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian of France and reaffirmed the strong bilateral ties between our countries. They welcomed the outcomes of the U.S.-EU Summit and NATO Summit in June and pledged to work together to ensure the Alliance’s adaptation to diverse security threats. They exchanged views on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian of France and reaffirmed the strong bilateral ties between our countries. They welcomed the outcomes of the U.S.-EU Summit and NATO Summit in June and pledged to work together to ensure the Alliance’s adaptation to diverse security threats. They exchanged views on a range of shared foreign policy interests, including China, Russia, Iran, and Lebanon. They also discussed rising instability in the Sahel and their commitment to sustained counterterrorism cooperation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on President Joe Biden’s Participation in the APEC Leaders’ Virtual Retreat</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/14/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-president-joe-bidens-participation-in-the-apec-leaders-virtual-retreat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23801</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday July 16, President Joseph R. Biden Jr. will participate in the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Leaders’ Virtual Retreat, where Leaders will discuss ending the COVID-19 pandemic and supporting the global economic recovery, hosted by Prime Minister Ardern of New Zealand. The President’s participation will demonstrate U.S. leadership in the Indo-Pacific region and the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday July 16, President Joseph R. Biden Jr. will participate in the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Leaders’ Virtual Retreat, where Leaders will discuss ending the COVID-19 pandemic and supporting the global economic recovery, hosted by Prime Minister Ardern of New Zealand. The President’s participation will demonstrate U.S. leadership in the Indo-Pacific region and the President’s commitment to multilateral institutions.  As President Biden’s first engagement with many of the APEC Leaders, particularly those in Southeast Asia, he will emphasize the importance he places on the region as well as his vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific. He will provide an update to Leaders on what the U.S. is doing to serve as an arsenal of vaccines for the region and to support all those suffering from COVID-19. He will also advance an economic agenda that promotes our shared prosperity, leverages the economic potential in the region, and builds inclusive and resilient economies.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Senior Administration Official Travel to Uzbekistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/14/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-senior-administration-official-travel-to-uzbekistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security Dr. Elizabeth Sherwood-Randall will lead a U.S. delegation to a high-level international conference promoting prosperity, security, and regional connectivity between Central and South Asia in Tashkent, Uzbekistan. While in Uzbekistan, she will meet with leaders from across the region to discuss opportunities to bolster regional&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security Dr. Elizabeth Sherwood-Randall will lead a U.S. delegation to a high-level international conference promoting prosperity, security, and regional connectivity between Central and South Asia in Tashkent, Uzbekistan. While in Uzbekistan, she will meet with leaders from across the region to discuss opportunities to bolster regional economic development, enhance stability, and strengthen American partnerships. U.S. Special Representative for Afghanistan Reconciliation Ambassador Zalmay Khalilzad will join the delegation for diplomatic engagements with President Ashraf Ghani of Afghanistan and with leaders from the C-5 and other regional countries to discuss how to promote peace, security, and development in Afghanistan, and advance shared regional security interests, including counterterrorism cooperation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: U.S. Assistance to Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/13/fact-sheet-u-s-assistance-to-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 23:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Haiti is a partner of the United States and we have continually sought to provide support for Haiti’s safety, security, and development. In January 2021, the Biden-Harris Administration&#160;announced&#160;$75.5 million in bilateral development and health assistance for a wide range of issues, including democratic governance, health, education, agricultural development, and pre-election activities. The United States is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Haiti is a partner of the United States and we have continually sought to provide support for Haiti’s safety, security, and development. In January 2021, the Biden-Harris Administration&nbsp;announced&nbsp;$75.5 million in bilateral development and health assistance for a wide range of issues, including democratic governance, health, education, agricultural development, and pre-election activities. The United States is working with the Government of Haiti to deliver the first 500,000 doses of Moderna COVID-19 vaccines to the people of Haiti—the first major international delivery of COVID doses to Haiti, with plans to share more doses.<br><br>Since the 2010 earthquake, the United States has made available over $5.1 billion for assistance to Haiti to support life-saving post-disaster relief as well as longer-term recovery, reconstruction, and development programs.<br><br>The United States remains committed to helping the Haitian people build a better future and is doing so in the following areas:<br><br><strong>Investigation Assistance</strong></p>



<ul><li>In the aftermath of the assassination of President Moise, the Department of Justice, together with the Department of Homeland Security, is providing assistance to support the Haitian authorities in conducting a thorough investigation of the July 7 attack.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The Department of Justice, along with its U.S. government partners, will continue to support the Haitian authorities in its review of the facts and circumstances surrounding this heinous attack.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The Department of Justice will also investigate whether there were any violations of U.S. criminal law in connection with this matter.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Security Assistance</strong></p>



<ul><li>Strengthening Haiti’s law enforcement capacity is a key U.S. priority.&nbsp;We have provided $312 million in assistance between 2010-2020 alone to strengthen law enforcement and the capacity of the Haitian National Police to maintain peace and stability, and to respond effectively to civil unrest while respecting human rights.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>As a direct result of support to the HNP School, trained officers increased from less than 10,000 in 2010 to nearly 15,000 officers today.&nbsp;The Department of State supports seven embedded subject matter experts to specialized HNP units to enhance the institution’s capability to support safer communities, more secure borders, and to prevent civil unrest.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>In response to a recent request from the Government of Haiti for security support:<br><br>DHS is sending experts from the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) to work with their Haitian counterparts in improving aviation and critical infrastructure security, as well as to provide support securing the upcoming elections.<br><br>State is deploying an advisor to the HNP judicial police and bringing onboard an advisor to the HNP Inspector General.&nbsp; These advisors help the HNP improve the integrity of processing allegations of corruption, human rights abuses, and police misconduct.&nbsp; Their critical investigative capacity-building support will complement U.S. federal law enforcement assistance.<br><br>State is supporting training and procuring vehicles, radios, and protective equipment to build the capacity of the HNP to protect Haitians from violence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>We are also encouraging Haiti&nbsp;to&nbsp;take a holistic approach to countering gangs and are providing $5 million to strengthen&nbsp;the HNP&#8217;s&nbsp;capacity to work with communities to resist gangs.&nbsp; We&nbsp;encourage Core Group members and key international partners to consider contributing to combatting insecurity in Haiti.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Elections Assistance</strong></p>



<ul><li>USAID is currently supporting pre-election activities that are intended to lay the foundation for upcoming legislative and presidential elections. USAID is providing more than $3 million to the Consortium for Elections and Political Processes Strengthening, which includes the National Democratic Institute, International Republican Institute, and International Foundation for Electoral Systems.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>These activities include focusing on improving electoral administration, strengthening the competitiveness of political parties, educating voters on electoral processes, promoting electoral transparency, and ensuring inclusive voter participation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>USAID is providing technical assistance to Haiti’s Provisional Electoral Council (CEP) through this Consortium to build the capacity of electoral authorities to conduct credible elections. This includes technical assistance for strategic planning, information technology, and training for CEP staff, Communal Electoral Office and Departmental Electoral Office staff.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Health and Humanitarian Assistance</strong></p>



<ul><li>The United States also provides urgent humanitarian assistance via independent UN and NGO partners to help the most vulnerable people in Haiti. An estimated 4.4 million people in Haiti need humanitarian assistance as a result of years of civil unrest, economic instability, and recurrent natural disasters including hurricanes, droughts and a devastating earthquake in 2010.&nbsp; While humanitarian assistance does not address the root causes of Haiti’s economic and political situation, it does help alleviate suffering and meet urgent needs of the Haitian people.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Improving access to primary health care services:</strong>&nbsp;USAID is the largest bilateral health donor in Haiti. Our assistance has increased access to and quality of basic healthcare in 164 clinics reaching over 4 million of the most vulnerable among Haiti’s population of 11 million.&nbsp; With our support, the country is containing the spread of HIV, reducing the prevalence rate to under two percent in the past decade.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>USAID support underpins the public health sector:</strong>&nbsp;USAID represents 25% of total health spending in Haiti.&nbsp; These investments benefit the entire health system by ensuring quality health services are available to the population, with a focus on children, mothers, and other vulnerable populations, while strengthening the capacity of the Haitian government to manage the public health care system.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Improving nutrition through food fortification:</strong>&nbsp;With USAID support, all Haitians now have access to staple foods fortified with iron, folic acid, zinc, vitamin A, and iodine. These nutrients are essential to reduce the number of people with dietary deficiencies, improve child health outcomes, and will help generations of Haitians grow to be healthier, more productive members of their communities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Vaccinating children against the diseases that drive child mortality:</strong>&nbsp;Ninety-four percent of infants between 0 and 11 months have received their full complement of routine vaccinations in USAID-supported areas, thereby preventing diseases such as diphtheria, tetanus, and pertussis, compared to the national vaccine coverage rate of 41 percent.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Ensuring pregnant mothers receive the care they need:</strong>&nbsp;In areas that receive USAID health investments, 89 percent of pregnant women gave birth with the assistance of a skilled health care worker (a significant factor in reducing maternal and child deaths), while this rate was only 42 percent nationally.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Reducing HIV rates and ensuring HIV care and treatment during the COVID-19 pandemic:</strong>&nbsp;USAID has helped reduce the HIV prevalence rate in Haiti to under 2% in the past decade. We offer life-saving antiretroviral treatment to more than 80% (123,000) of people living with HIV (PLHIV).&nbsp; USAID has helped Haiti to adopt innovative drug distribution and dispensing methods, and limit unnecessary COVID-19 risk exposure to PLHIV. These methods include multi-month dispensing, community drug distribution, group services such as psycho-social support groups, and mothers’ clubs implemented remotely online or by phone.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Modern Teaching Facility provides world-class training for health professionals:</strong>&nbsp;USAID completed a modern teaching facility for doctors and nurses housing the Faculty of Medicine and Pharmacy, School of Nursing, and Lab Technician School, which now provides training to more than 1,000 students each year.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Re-building the premier teaching hospital in Haiti:</strong>&nbsp;USAID and the French government are helping to rebuild Haiti’s national teaching hospital (HUEH), the country’s main public tertiary hospital which collapsed due to the 2010 earthquake. USAID contributed $25 million towards the reconstruction and are planning to offer an additional $10 million towards its completion that is scheduled for 2024.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Southern Clinic Rehabilitation:&nbsp;</strong>USAID support resulted in the rehabilitation of five clinics in the south of Haiti impacted by Hurricane Matthew, enabling approximately 100,000 people to receive clinical care services.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Temporary Protected Status (TPS)</strong></p>



<ul><li>In May, DHS announced a new designation of Haiti for Temporary Protected Status (TPS) for 18 months. Secretary Mayorkas made this decision after consulting with interagency partners and carefully considering the extraordinary and temporary conditions in Haiti, including the political crisis and human rights abuses; serious security concerns; the COVID-19 pandemic’s worsening of a dire economic situation and lack of access to food, water, and healthcare; and the continuing negative effects of the 2010 earthquake. Such conditions prevent Haitian nationals and habitual residents from returning safely.<br> </li><li>Both existing TPS beneficiaries and new applicants must have been continuously residing in the United States since May 21, 2021, to be eligible for TPS. The TPS designation does not benefit Haitian nationals attempting to enter the United States after May 21, 2021. The United States is continuing to strictly enforce existing immigration laws and border security measures. Those who have newly arrived in the United States after the May 21, 2021, announcement are not eligible for TPS.<br> </li><li>We anticipate that the Federal Register notice putting the Secretary’s designation of Haiti for TPS for 18 months into effect will be published within the coming days.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on Protecting the Sacred, Constitutional Right to Vote</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/13/remarks-by-president-biden-on-protecting-the-sacred-constitutional-right-to-vote/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 21:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Constitution CenterPhiladelphia, Pennsylvania 2:46 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160;&#160; Thank you.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; I see an awful lot of good friends out there.&#160; Please have a seat if you have one.&#160; I &#8212; let me begin by saying I used to be important.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; I used to be the chairman of the board of this place.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">National Constitution Center<br>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>2:46 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I see an awful lot of good friends out there.&nbsp; Please have a seat if you have one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; let me begin by saying I used to be important.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I used to be the chairman of the board of this place.&nbsp; And Jeffrey Rosen allowed me to do that for a while.</p>



<p>But thank you all for being here.&nbsp; I truly appreciate it.&nbsp; Governor, it&#8217;s above and beyond the call.&nbsp; Mr. Mayor, I’d compli- &#8212; I thought you were a great mayor &#8212; still think you are &#8212; but your judgment in fiancées is even stronger.&nbsp; And &#8212; but &#8212; but all of you.&nbsp; And a good friend, Bobby Brady.&nbsp; I see so many friends out.&nbsp; Al Sharpton &#8212; Al, how are you, pal?&nbsp; It&#8217;s great to see you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m going to get in trouble here because I&#8217;m going to recognize my congresswoman from the state of Delaware, Lisa Blunt Rochester &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and her sister who used to run my office.&nbsp; Stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Well, folks, good afternoon. &nbsp;There&#8217;s a serious subject I&#8217;d like to talk about today.&nbsp; I&#8217;m here in Philadelphia at the National Constitution Center &#8212; the city and the place where the story of &#8220;We the People&#8221; &#8212; &#8220;We the People&#8221; began.</p>



<p>It’s a story that’s neither simple nor straightforward.&nbsp; That’s because the story is the sum of our parts, and all those parts are fundamentally human.&nbsp; And being human is to be imperfect, driven by appetite and ambition as much as by goodness and grace.</p>



<p>But some things in America should be simple and straightforward.</p>



<p>Perhaps the most important of those things &#8212; the most fundamental of those things &#8212; is the right to vote.&nbsp; The right to vote freely.&nbsp; (Applause)&nbsp; The right to vote freely, the right&nbsp; &#8212; the right to vote fairly, the right to have your vote counted.&nbsp; The democratic threshold is liberty.&nbsp; With it, anything is possible.&nbsp; Without it, nothing &#8212; nothing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for our democracy and the work &#8212; and to deliver our work and [for] our people, it’s up to all of us to protect that right.  This is a test of our time and what I’m here to talk about today.</p>



<p>Just think about the past election.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A 102-year-old woman in Arkansas who voted for the first time on the very spot she once picked cotton.</p>



<p>A 94-year-old woman in Michigan who voted early and in person in her seventy-se- &#8212; 72nd consecutive election.&nbsp; You know what she said?&nbsp; She said this election was, quote, “the most important vote that we ever had.”</p>



<p>The daughter who voted in the memory of her dad who died of COVID-19 so others wouldn’t have the experience of pain and darkness and loss that she was going through.&nbsp; Patients out there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the parents &#8212; the parents who voted for school their children will learn in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sons and daughters voted for the planet they’re going to live on.</p>



<p>Young people just turning 18 and everyone who, for the first time in their lives, thought they could truly make a difference.</p>



<p>America &#8212; America and Americans of every background voted.&nbsp; They voted for good jobs and higher wages.&nbsp; They voted for racial equity and justice.&nbsp; They voted to make healthcare a right, not a privilege.</p>



<p>And the reason that Americans went to vote and the lengths they went to vote &#8212; to be able to vote in this past election were absolutely extraordinary.&nbsp; In fact, the fact that so many election officials across the country made it easier and safer for them to be able to vote in the middle of a pandemic was remarkable.</p>



<p>As a result, in 2020, more people voted in America than ever &#8212; ever in the history of America, in the middle of a once-in-a-century pandemic.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>All told, more than 150 [million] Americans of every age, of every race, of every background exercised their right to vote.</p>



<p>They voted early.&nbsp; They voted absentee.&nbsp; They voted in person.&nbsp; They voted by mail.&nbsp; They voted by drop box.&nbsp; And then they got their families and friends to go out and vote.</p>



<p>Election officials, the entire electoral system, withstood unrelenting political attacks, physical threats, intimidation, and pressure.&nbsp; They did so with unyielding courage and</p>



<p>faith in our democracy.</p>



<p>With recount after recount after recount, court case after court case, the 2020 election was the most scrutinized election ever in American history.&nbsp; Challenge after challenge brought to local, state, and election officials; state legislatures; state and federal courts &#8212; even to the United States Supreme Court not once, but twice.</p>



<p>More than 80 judges, including those appointed by my predecessor, heard the arguments.&nbsp; In every case, neither cause nor evidence was found to undermine the national achievement of administering this historic election in the face of such extraordinary challenges.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Audits, recounts were conducted in Arizona, in Wisconsin. In Georgia, it was recounted three times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s clear.&nbsp; For those who challenge the results and question the integrity of the election: No other election has ever been held under such scrutiny and such high standards.</p>



<p>The Big Lie is just that: a big lie.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The 2020 election &#8212; it’s not hyperbole to suggest &#8212; the most examined and the fullest expression of the will of the people in the history of this nation.&nbsp; This should be celebrated &#8212; the example of America at its best.&nbsp; But instead, we continue to see an example of human nature at its worst &#8212; something darker and more sinister.</p>



<p>In America, if you lose, you accept the results.&nbsp; You follow the Constitution.&nbsp; You try again.&nbsp; You don’t call facts “fake” and then try to bring down the American experiment just because you’re unhappy.&nbsp; That’s not statesmanship.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s not statesmanship; that’s selfishness.&nbsp; That’s not democracy; it’s the denial of the right to vote.&nbsp; It suppresses.&nbsp; It subjugates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The denial of full and free and fair elections is the most un-American thing that any of us can imagine, the most undemocratic, the most unpatriotic, and yet, sadly, not unprecedented.</p>



<p>From denying enslaved people fu- &#8212; full citizenship until the 13th, 14th, and 15th Amendments after the Civil War; to denying women the right to vote until the 19th Amendment 100 years ago; to poll taxes and literacy tests, and the Ku Klux Klan campaigns of violence and terror that lasted into the ‘50s and ‘60s; to the Supreme Court decision in 2013 and then again just two weeks ago –- a decision that weakened the landmark Voting Rights Act; to the willful attacks &#8212; election attacks in 2020; and then to a whole other level of threat &#8212; the violence and the deadly insurrection on the Capitol on January 6th.</p>



<p>I just got back from Europe, speaking to the G7 and to NATO.&nbsp; They wonder &#8212; not a joke &#8212; they wonder, Gov &#8212; they ask me, “Is it going to be okay?”&nbsp; The citadel of democracy in the world, &#8220;Is it o- &#8212; going to be okay?&#8221;</p>



<p>Time and again, we’ve weathered threats to the right to vote in free and fair elections.&nbsp; And each time, we found a way to overcome.&nbsp; And that’s what we must do today.</p>



<p>Vice President Harris and I have spent our careers doing this work.&nbsp; And I’ve asked her to lead, to bring people together to protect the right to vote and our democracy.&nbsp; And it starts with continuing the fight to pass H.R.1, the For the People Act.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>That bill &#8212; that bill would help end voter suppression in the states, get dark money out of politics, give voice to the people at the grassroots level, create a fairer district maps, and end partisan political gerrymandering.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last month, Republicans opposed even debating, even considering For the People Act.&nbsp; Senate Democrats stood united to protect our democracy and the sanctity of the vote.&nbsp; We must pass the For the People Act.&nbsp; It’s a national imperative.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We must also fight for the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act to restore and expand &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to restore and expand voting protections and prevent voter suppression.&nbsp; All the congresswomen and men here &#8212; there’s a bunch of you &#8212; you knew John, many of you.</p>



<p>Just weeks ago, the Supreme Court yet again weakened the Voting Rights Act and upheld what Justice Kagan called, quote, “a significant race-based disparity in voting opportunities.”</p>



<p>The Court’s decision, as harmful as is, does not limit the &#8212; Congress’ ability to repair the damage done.&nbsp; That’s the important point.&nbsp; It puts the burden back on Congress to restore the Voting Rights Act to its intended strength.</p>



<p>As soon as Congress passes the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act, I will sign it and let the whole world see it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That will be an important moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the world is wondering &#8212; the world is wondering &#8212; and Dwight knows what I’m talking about, for real.&nbsp; You know, the world is wondering, “What is America going to do?”</p>



<p>But we also have to clear-eyed about the obstruction we face.&nbsp; Legislation is one tool, but not the only tool.&nbsp; And it’s not the only measure of our obligation to defend democracy today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, Attorney General Merrick Garland announced that the United States Department of Justice is going to be using its authorities to challenge the onslaught of state laws undermining voting rights in old and new ways.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The focus &#8212; the focus will be on dismantling racially discriminatory laws, like the recent challenge to Georgia’s vicious anti-voting law.</p>



<p>The Department of Justice will do so with a voting rights division that &#8212; at my request &#8212; is doubling its size in enforcement staff.&nbsp; (Applause)</p>



<p>Civil rights groups &#8212; civil rights groups and other organizations have announced their plans to stay vigilant and challenge these odious laws in the courts.</p>



<p>In Texas, for example, Republican-led state legislature wants to allow partisan poll watchers to intimidate voters and imperil impartial poll workers.&nbsp; They want voters to dive [drive] farther and be able to be in a position where they wonder who’s watching them and intimidating them; to wait longer to vote.&nbsp; To drive a hell of lot lo- &#8212; excuse me &#8212; a long way &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; to get to vote.&nbsp; They want to make it so hard and inconvenient that they hope people don’t vote at all.&nbsp; That’s what this is about.</p>



<p>This year alone, 17 states have enacted &#8212; not just proposed, but enacted &#8212; 28 new laws to make it harder for Americans to vote, not to mention &#8212; and catch this &#8212; nearly 400 additional bills Republican members of the state legislatures are trying to pass.</p>



<p>The 21st century Jim Crow assault is real.&nbsp; It’s unrelenting, and we’re going to challenge it vigorously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While &#8212; (applause) &#8212; while this broad assault against voting rights is not unprecedented, it’s taking on a new and, literally, pernicious forms.</p>



<p>It’s no longer just about who gets to vote or making it easier for eligible voters to vote.&nbsp; It’s about who gets to count the vote &#8212; who gets to count whether or not your vote counted at all.&nbsp; It’s about moving from independent election administrators who work for the people to polarized state legislatures and partisan actors who work for political parties.</p>



<p>To me, this is simple: This is election subversion.&nbsp; It’s the most dangerous threat to voting and the integrity of free and fair elections in our history.&nbsp; Never before have they decided who gets to count &#8212; count &#8212; what votes count.</p>



<p>Some &#8212; some legi- &#8212; state legislatures want to make it harder for you to vote.&nbsp; And if you vote, they want to be able to tell you your vote doesn’t count for any reason they make up.</p>



<p>They want the ability to reject the final count and ignore the will of the people if their preferred candidate loses.</p>



<p>And they’re trying &#8212; not only targeting people of color, they’re targeting voters of all races and backgrounds.&nbsp; It’s with a simple target: who did not vote for them.&nbsp; That’s the target.</p>



<p>It’s unconscionable.&nbsp; I mean, really, I &#8212; it’s hard to &#8212; it’s hard to declare just how critical this is.&nbsp; It’s simply unconscionable.</p>



<p>We’ve got to shore up our election system and address the threats of election subversion, not just from abroad &#8212; which I spent time with Putin talking about &#8212; but from home.&nbsp; From home.</p>



<p>We must ask those who represent us at the federal, state, and local levels: Will you deny the will of the people?&nbsp; Will you ignore their voices?</p>



<p>We have to ask: Are you on the side of truth or lies; fact or fiction; justice or injustice; democracy or autocracy?&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it&#8217;s coming down to.</p>



<p>Which brings me to perhaps the most important thing we have to do: We have to for- &#8212; forge a coalition of Americans of every background and political party &#8212; the advocates, the students, the faith leaders, the labor leaders, the business executives &#8212; and raise the urgency of this moment.</p>



<p>Because as much as people know they&#8217;re screwing around with the election process, I don&#8217;t think that most people think this is about who gets to count what vote counts &#8212; literally, not figuratively.&nbsp; You vote for certain electors to vote for somebody for President.&nbsp; State legislator comes along &#8212; under their proposal &#8212; and they say, &#8220;No, we don&#8217;t like those electors.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to appoint other electors who are going to vote for the other guy or other woman.&#8221;</p>



<p>Because here’s the deal: In 2020, democracy was put to a test &#8212; first by the pandemic; then by a desperate attempt to deny the reality and the results of the election; and then by a violent and deadly insurrection on the Capitol, the citadel of our democracy.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve been around a long time in public life.&nbsp; I thought I&#8217;ve seen it all or most of it all.&nbsp; But I never thought I&#8217;d see that, for real.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in spite of what you see on television &#8212; and you saw it &#8212; you have senators saying it was just a day at the Capitol, just people visiting the Capitol.</p>



<p>Folks &#8212; but we met the test.&nbsp; Because of the extraordinary courage of election officials &#8212; many of them Republicans; our court system; and those brave Capitol police officers &#8212; because of them, democracy held.</p>



<p>Look how close it came.&nbsp; I mean, for real, how close it came.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to face another test in 2022: a new wave of unprecedented voter suppression, and raw and sustained election subversion.&nbsp; We have to prepare now.</p>



<p>As I’ve said time and again: No matter what, you can never stop the American people from voting.&nbsp; They will decide, and the power must always be with the people.</p>



<p>That’s why, just like we did in 2020, we have to prepare for 2022.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll engage in an all-out effort to educate voters about the changing laws, register them to vote, and then get the vote out.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll encourage people to run for office themselves at every level.</p>



<p>We will be asking my Republican friends &#8212; in Congress, in states, in cities, in counties &#8212; to stand up, for God&#8217;s sake, and help prevent this concerted effort to undermine our elections and the sacred right to vote.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Have you no shame?&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Whether it’s stopping foreign interference in our elections or the spread of disinformation from within, we have to work together.</p>



<p>Vice President Harris and I will be making it clear that there’s real peril in making raw power, rather than the idea of liberty, the centerpiece of the common life.</p>



<p>The Founders understood this.&nbsp; The women of Seneca Falls understood this.&nbsp; The brave, heroic foot soldiers of the Civil Rights Movement understood this.&nbsp; So must we.</p>



<p>This isn’t about Democrats and Republicans; it’s literally about who we are as Americans.&nbsp; It&#8217;s that basic.&nbsp; It’s about the kind of country we want today, the kind of country we want for our children and grandchildren tomorrow.&nbsp; And quite frankly, the whole world is watching.&nbsp; Folks &#8212; (applause).</p>



<p>I’m not being sentimental.&nbsp; I’m not preaching to you.&nbsp; I’m just giving it to you straight, as I promised I would always do &#8212; lay things out on the line and honor your trust with trust [truth].</p>



<p>So hear me clearly: There is an unfolding assault taking place in America today &#8212; an attempt to suppress and subvert&nbsp;the right to vote in fair and free elections, an assault on democracy, an assault on liberty, an assault on who we are &#8212; who we are as Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For, make no mistake, bullies and merchants of fear and&nbsp;peddlers of lies are threatening the very foundation of our country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It gives me no pleasure to say this.&nbsp; I never thought in my entire career I’d ever have to say it.&nbsp; But I swore an oath to you, to God &#8212; to preserve, protect, and defend the Constitution.&nbsp; And that’s an oath that forms a sacred trust to defend America&nbsp;against all threats both foreign and domestic.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>The assault on free and fair elections is just such a threat, literally.  I&#8217;ve said it before: We&#8217;re are facing the most significant test of our democracy since the Civil War.  That&#8217;s not hyperbole.  Since the Civil War.  The Confederates back then never breached the Capitol as insurrectionists did on January the 6th.</p>



<p>I’m not saying this to alarm you; I’m saying this because you should be alarmed. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m also saying this: There’s good news.&nbsp; It doesn’t have to be this way.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t have to be, for real.&nbsp; We have the means.&nbsp; We just need to show the will &#8212; the will to save and strengthen our democracy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We did it in 20- &#8212; we did it in the 2020.&nbsp; The battle for the soul of America &#8212; in that battle, the people voted.&nbsp; Democracy prevailed.&nbsp; Our Constitution held.&nbsp; We have to do it again.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>My fellow Americans, it requires fair-mindedness; devotion to justice; corny as it sounds, a love of country.&nbsp; It requires us to unite in common purpose, to declare here and now: We, the people, will never give up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We will not give in.&nbsp; We will overcome.&nbsp; We will do it together.&nbsp; And guaranteeing the right to vote, ensuring every vote is counted has always been the most patriotic thing we can do.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just remember, our late friend John Lewis said, &#8220;Freedom is not a state; it is an act.&#8221;&nbsp; &#8220;Freedom is not a state; it is an act.&#8221;&nbsp; And we must act, and we will act.&nbsp; For our cause is just, our vision is clear, and our hearts are full.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>For &#8220;We the People,&#8221; for our democracy, for America itself, we must act.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops and all those stand watch over our democracy.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But act.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to act.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>3:10 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at &#8220;Whitmer for Michigan&#8221; Finance Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/13/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-whitmer-for-michigan-finance-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 21:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TCF CenterDetroit, Michigan THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Greetings, everyone.&#160; I am so honored, as I&#8217;ve always been, to share a stage with Gretchen Whitmer.&#160; And she and I have shared many stages over a great amount of time through the &#8212; some of the highs and the lows of what our country has experienced.&#160; And I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">TCF Center<br>Detroit, Michigan</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Greetings, everyone.&nbsp; I am so honored, as I&#8217;ve always been, to share a stage with Gretchen Whitmer.&nbsp; And she and I have shared many stages over a great amount of time through the &#8212; some of the highs and the lows of what our country has experienced.&nbsp; And I will tell you what I know you all know, as longstanding friends and supporters of hers: She&#8217;s an extraordinary, courageous, brilliant, committed leader not only for Michigan, but she is a national leader.<br><br>And I was with the President this morning in the Oval Office for a couple of meetings, and I said, “I&#8217;m heading to Detroit,” and he said, “Give Gretchen all my best and remind everyone of what you and I…” &#8212; meaning he and I &#8212; “…have talked about,” which is the President and I stand with Gretchen Whitmer.&nbsp; We stand with her.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we will continue to stand with her.<br><br>Her leadership has been the leadership during some of the most difficult times our country could imagine &#8212; extraordinary &#8212; during this pandemic where we saw an incredible loss of life, a loss of jobs, a loss of hope.&nbsp; And she never &#8212; she never waned.&nbsp; She got up every morning &#8212; she gets up every morning fighting for the people of Michigan.<br><br>I will tell you, she made many a call to the President and to me during this time, talking about the needs of the people of Michigan.&nbsp; She is one of those rare leaders who puts what&#8217;s right ahead of what&#8217;s popular to represent the people as they should expect a governor to represent them.&nbsp; That&#8217;s who she is, and that makes some people really fearful because that&#8217;s some strong, powerful stuff to be that kind of leader.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br><br>And so, this is not going to be an easy election, and that&#8217;s why I&#8217;m here this early in the process to say we need you to do everything you can to reelect her as governor of this beautiful, great state and put everything you have into it.<br><br>When I was here &#8212; the last time I was here was actually Election Day 2020, and we were together that day.&nbsp; And I said then what remains true: Michigan is a bellwether for the United States.&nbsp; What you do here, what happens here is a reflection of who we are as a country.&nbsp;<br><br>And when we&#8217;ve got a governor of a state &#8212; the chief executive of the state &#8212; who concerns herself, yes, everything from what we need to do to fix the darn you-know-what to &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and then you could insert whatever words you choose, right? &#8212; to what is important in terms of the future of working people in America, the future of the workforce, the future of families.<br><br>One of the reasons that we are partners with this governor &#8212; with your governor &#8212; and will continue to be is, on the issue of COVID, about an embrace of science and the importance of talking fact, and then having an administration who is thinking about and is smart around what we do to get the information to people, much less get the vaccine to people.&nbsp;<br><br>Why are we committed to this governor?&nbsp; Because she understands that when we did what we did with the Child Tax Credit, we will lift half of America&#8217;s children out of poverty, and she stands for lifting children out of poverty.&nbsp; When &#8212; (applause).<br><br>And isn&#8217;t it &#8212; isn&#8217;t it an interesting thing that I have to say that anyone stands with lis- &#8212; lifting children out of poverty?&nbsp; But it&#8217;s not actually a given.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not actually a given.<br><br>She supports the Child Tax Credit and the expansion of it, infrastructure.&nbsp; She was one of the people that we consulted in thinking about what would be in our package &#8212; that is now the subject of bipartisan support &#8212; around what we need to do to uplift, upgrade America&#8217;s infrastructure, which is not only about roads and bridges, but it&#8217;s also about high-speed Internet &#8212; something that she knows well because, of course, this state is Detroit, and it is urban areas and it is rural areas.<br><br>We have talked about what we need to do to support childcare workers.&nbsp; Understanding &#8212; she and I have talked about it &#8212; women in the workforce, so many who had to leave during the course of the pandemic.&nbsp; Childcare remaining one of the biggest barriers to women not only going back to work, but ever entering the workforce or staying in the workforce, even before the pandemic.&nbsp; These are the issues that we will continue to work with her on.<br><br>And so, I am here to thank you all, but to say that, &#8220;Let&#8217;s make sure that we are committed, as she is, to the work that has yet to be done.&#8221;&nbsp; She is committed and determined to deliver results, decisive in a crisis.&nbsp; She is ambitious about the future.&nbsp; And she sees with an incredible amount &#8212; and this is one of the things, Gretchen, I&#8217;ve always admired about you: You maintain fight while you also maintain an incredible sense of optimism.&nbsp; You &#8212; that&#8217;s really who you are; that&#8217;s your nature.&nbsp; I &#8212; I really &#8212; I noticed that from the very first time that we had a conversation about what it means to hold elected office and to represent the people.&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s the kind of leadership we want.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the kind of leadership we need.<br><br>So, I want to thank you all again.&nbsp; November 8th, 2022, seems like a long way off, but it&#8217;s practically around the corner.&nbsp; And as we all know, right now, you know, people are excited about the fact that we might see light at the end of the tunnel in terms of the pandemic, and it&#8217;s summer, and folks have a lot of things that are on their mind, a lot of priorities, and they may not be thinking much about the election right now, but we need to remind people of what&#8217;s at stake.&nbsp;<br><br>And there&#8217;s so much at stake and elections matter.&nbsp; Elections matter.&nbsp; And who is the governor of the great state of Michigan matters to the people of this state and the people of our country.<br><br>So, I will close where I started, which is to say thank you all for the support you&#8217;re giving and the pledge, I know, for the continuing support to see this through.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s make sure we talk to everyone we know and we remind them that their voice matters, their vote matters, their participation matters, and that Governor Gretchen Whitmer matters.<br><br>Thank you all.<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre En Route Philadelphia, PA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/13/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-en-route-philadelphia-pa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 20:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1:43 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; In the birthplace of American democracy, President Biden will articulate how to meet the greatest threat to the right to vote and the integrity of our elections since the Civil War, renew his call for vital legislation to overcome the rash of anti-voter legis- &#8212; laws motivated by the Big Lie,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1:43 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; In the birthplace of American democracy, President Biden will articulate how to meet the greatest threat to the right to vote and the integrity of our elections since the Civil War, renew his call for vital legislation to overcome the rash of anti-voter legis- &#8212; laws motivated by the Big Lie, and underline the all-of-government efforts the Biden-Harris administration launched to use the powers of the executive branch to protect and advance the sacred constitutional right to vote.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President will highlight that the greatest irony of the 28 voter suppression laws that have been passed across 17 states this year alone is that the 2020 election stands as a model for the trustworthiness and precision of our system, given that over 80 judges, including judges appointed by his predecessor, threw out every challenge to it.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President will give Democrats credit for unanimously voting to advance the For the People Act and decry the Republican obstruction of its path, and he will reiterate that the work to pass it and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement are only beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>He will also blast the denial of the right to vote as grounded in autocracy, under- &#8212; undemocratic and un-American and unpatriotic.<br>&nbsp;<br>And he will note that while voter suppression &#8212; that vote &#8212; while voter suppression that these 21st century Jim Crow laws represent is sadly not unprecedented in American history, these new insidious moves to empower partisans over independent election authorities, in terms of who counts the votes, are new and extremely dangerous.<br>&nbsp;<br>Such efforts, which could allow partisans to throw out the votes of anyone for made-up reasons, are the most significant threat to today to the integrity of our elections and to the security of the right to vote.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President will call for a new coalition made up of advocates, activists, students, faith leaders, labor leaders, and business execs &#8212; executives to overcome this un-American trend and meet the moment as far as turnout and voter education.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President will repeat that these are the most egregious attempts to harm the integrity of our democracy since the Civil War, but that if we show the will to save and strengthen our democracy, this can be turned back.</p>



<p>Also, this week, the Vice President will meet with the Texas legislators who broke quorum to block legislation that would have made it significantly harder for the people of Texas to vote.</p>



<p>There is growing bipartisan momentum in Congress as we look towards the &#8212; the historic framework that came together &#8212; the bipartisan framework &#8212; that this is the product of hard work &#8212; which was a product of hard work by Democrats and Republicans and which would make the most significant investment in our roads and bridges since the creation &#8212; the creation of the Interstate Highway System; connect every American to broadband, including in underserved rural areas; stop our children from drinking poisoned water that can impact them for life; secure our leadership in the clean energy economy; and make the biggest investments in American rail since Amtrak.</p>



<p>As Senator Portman said yesterday, people want to see our infrastructure be improved.&nbsp; They&#8217;re tired of waiting in traffic during their rush-hour commute.&nbsp; People are tired of worrying about lead pipes.&nbsp; It&#8217;s very popular because it&#8217;s something people know &#8212; know is needed.</p>



<p>And just this morning, the U.S. Conference of Mayors, on a bipartisan basis, wrote to both chambers of Congress, advocating for quick passage of the framework.&nbsp; They wrote, &#8220;The bipartisan infrastructure framework is crucial to making meaningful progress on one of the most pressing and unifying challenges facing our country…&nbsp; we believe that this framework deserves bipartisan support in the United States Senate and United States House of Representatives.&#8221;&nbsp; The American people are calling out for these investments, and we&#8217;re going to deliver.</p>



<p>One last thing, following up on Jen&#8217;s announcement of us continuing to read out some of the innovative activities we are doing to get more Americans vaccinated: Tomorrow, Olivia Rodrigo will come to the White House to meet with the President and Dr. Fauci, and record videos about the importance of young people getting vaccinated, including answering important questions young people have about getting vaccinated.&nbsp; The videos will be featured on Olivia&#8217;s channels &#8212; 28 million-plus followers across the channels and the White House social pages.<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, I will take the first question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yesterday, Senator Sanders &#8212; Bernie Sanders came out of the White House and said, in essence, to ask him &#8212; meaning the President &#8212; to stay the negotiations on the reconciliation bill &#8212; in particular, where things stand with a topline number.&nbsp; Can you give us an update on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; They &#8212; look, the President and Senator Sanders &#8212; who have worked closely together and they have, as you know, a friendship, a relationship &#8212; they agree that the budget resolution must include key priorities, including universal pre-K, extending the Child Care Tax Credit, tax incentives and rebates for electric &#8212; electric vehicles.<br>&nbsp;<br>Senator Sanders is continuing to negotiate a resolution package, and the President is confident that we’ll pass something similar to his Build Back Better agenda.&nbsp; We leave that process to &#8212; to Congress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was there a discussion of a topline figure?&nbsp; Senator Sanders had suggested up to $6 trillion.&nbsp; Where does the President stand on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing more that I can read out.&nbsp; He is leaving that to Congress on &#8212; on those pieces of the pieces of legislation, including the monetary component of it as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President going to mention the filibuster today in his speech?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; As you could imagine, the President &#8212; the President believes that we have to make the filibuster work the way it used to.&nbsp; He has talked about this.&nbsp; As a senator for 36 years, he understands how this process works.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have to make people stand there and command floor; this is the talking filibuster that he has spoken to many times.&nbsp; From 1970 to 1971, it was invoked 58 times.&nbsp; Last year alone, there were five times that many.&nbsp; For example, it used to be you had to stand there and talk and talk and talk until you collapse.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; People got tired of talking, filibuster broke down, and we were able to break the filibuster, get a quorum, and vote.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, his position hasn&#8217;t changed on this.&nbsp; He sees this as a, you know, Senate procedural process.&nbsp; But he has talked about the talking filibuster many times.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President plan to meet with the Texas Democrats that are in Washington?&nbsp; And does he think they are doing the right thing by fleeing Texas?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I’ll say this, Weijia: The Texas legislation is part of a concerted attack on our democracy being advanced in state houses across the country on the basis of the same repeatedly disproven lies that led to the assault on our nation &#8212; nation&#8217;s Capitol on January 6th.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President&#8217;s message in Philadelphia today is simple and straightforward: The most funda- &#8212; foundational right is the right to vote freely and fairly, and have that vote counted.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The fact of the matter is that the Texas legislation would make it harder to vote in a state where it is already too hard for many to vote.&nbsp; As you&#8217;ve heard from the President, he has said that the Texas anti-voter bill is part of an assault on democracy that we&#8217;ve seen far too often this year, and often disproportionately targeting Black and brown Americans.&nbsp; It&#8217;s wrong and it&#8217;s un-American.<br>&nbsp;<br>I don’t have a specific announcement on when he will be meeting &#8212; or if, I should say &#8212; with the Texas legislators, but he applauds their courage.&nbsp; And this adds to the urgency for passage of the For the People and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act, along with the all-of-government effort we have launched, and the movement he’s calling for today &#8212; to overcome this moment with voter turnout and voter education.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know &#8212; you said the Vice President is going to meet with the Democrats.&nbsp; Do you have any more information on that &#8212; when and where it will be?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t.&nbsp; It’s going to be sometime this week she’ll be meeting with them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, do you have any updates on either Haiti or Cuba?&nbsp; The President, yesterday, said that, you know, he’s looking at options to support folks in both those countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you mentioned, Justin, the President said yesterday, “We are careful- &#8212; we are closely following the developments in Haiti in the wake of the horrific assassination of the &#8212; of their President that recently took place.”&nbsp; We reiterate our deepest condolences to the family of President Moïse and to the Haitian people, and wish First Lady Martine Moïse a swift recovery.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And to echo the President: The people of Haiti deserve peace and security, and Haiti’s political leaders need to come together for the good of their country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you all know, the President dispatched a high-level interagency expert delegation to assess the situation and to determine whether United States can offer our support.&nbsp; We are in close consultation with the Haitian government.&nbsp; And we will &#8212; he said, even yesterday, he&#8217;ll have more to share in the upcoming days.<br>&nbsp;<br>As for Cuba, yesterday, as well, the President recognized the protests that are happening in Cuba, calling them “remarkable,” saying that the Cuban people are demanding their freedom from an authoritarian regime.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President reiterated that the United States stands firmly with the people of Cuba as they assert their universal rights.&nbsp; And he called on the government of Cuba to refrain from violence or attempts to silence the voice of the people of Cuba.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, a number of Democratic senators have said that not every part of President Biden&#8217;s infrastructure package &#8212; particularly under reconciliation &#8212; should have to be paid for.&nbsp; So, does the White House still believe that the infrastructure plans have to be offset or is it open to some parts of it in the package not being paid for?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the bipartisan framework is a historic agreement that brings together Democrats and Republicans to invest in our nation&#8217;s future in a way that hasn&#8217;t been done in decades.&nbsp; The President offered his own ideas about how to pay for this investment through reforming the corporate tax code, and the Republicans offered theirs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The offsets are reasonable and responsible compromise.&nbsp; He sees this as also being fiscally responsible.&nbsp; After all, there is good evidence that the infrastructure investment, like that in this legislation, can help &#8212; can help fact &#8212; can, in fact, help pay for itself over the long run by expanding the economy, creating good jobs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Studies done after the framework was announced have corroborated that.&nbsp; And these offsets are on top of those savings, and the savings claimed from long-term economic growth is smaller than what it would &#8212; likely to occur.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re landing.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The websites of this Russian gang who might have been responsible for the Kaseya hack reveal they are shut down.&nbsp; Are you aware of this?&nbsp; Do you have anything on this?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t have anything &#8212; anything further to share on that.&nbsp; I don’t have anything to share (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, yesterday, Jen said she was going to double check on the U.S. delegation in Haiti.&nbsp; Do you know if all the members have returned?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, all the members have returned from the delegation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No problem.&nbsp; All right?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think we’re okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:55 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces 11 Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/13/president-biden-announces-11-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 20:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 11 individuals to serve in key roles: Rahul Gupta, Nominee for Director of National Drug Control Policy Gabe Camarillo, Nominee for Under Secretary of the Army, Department of Defense Alan Estevez, Nominee for Under Secretary for Industry and Security, Department of Commerce&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 11 individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Rahul Gupta, Nominee for Director of National Drug Control Policy</li><li>Gabe Camarillo, Nominee for Under Secretary of the Army, Department of Defense</li><li>Alan Estevez, Nominee for Under Secretary for Industry and Security, Department of Commerce</li><li>Jeff Lane Flake, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Turkey</li><li>Kent Doyle Logsdon, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Moldova</li><li>Atul Gawande, Nominee for Assistant Administrator of the Bureau for Global Health, United States Agency for International Development</li><li>Lisa Wang, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Enforcement and Compliance, Department of Commerce</li><li>Chester John Culver, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation</li><li>Rich Trumka, Jr., Nominee for Commissioner of the Consumer Product Safety Commission</li><li>James A. Diossa, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation</li><li>Terrence K. Wright, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Rahul Gupta, Nominee for Director of National Drug Control Policy</u></strong></p>



<p>Rahul Gupta, MD, MPH, MBA, FACP, is the Chief Medical and Health Officer and Senior Vice President at March of Dimes. In his role, Dr. Gupta provides strategic oversight for March of Dimes’ domestic and global medical and public health efforts. He currently also serves as clinical Professor in the Department of Medicine at Georgetown University School of Medicine as well as adjunct professor in the Department of Health Policy, Management and Leadership in the School of Public Health at West Virginia University and visiting faculty at Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A practicing primary care physician of 25 years, Dr. Gupta previously served under two Governors&nbsp; as the Health Commissioner of West Virginia. As the state’s Chief Health Officer, he led the opioid crisis response efforts and launched a number of pioneering public health initiatives, including the Neonatal Abstinence Syndrome Birthscore program to identify high-risk infants. Dr. Gupta also led the development of the state’s Zika action plan and its preparedness efforts during the Ebola Virus Disease Outbreak.</p>



<p>A national and global thought leader and a driver of innovative public policies on health issues, Dr. Gupta serves as an advisor to several organizations and task forces on local, national and international public health policy. The son of an Indian diplomat, Rahul was born in India and grew up in the suburbs of Washington, D.C. At age 21, he completed medical school at the University of Delhi. He earned a master’s degree in public health from the University of Alabama-Birmingham and a global master’s of business administration degree from the London School of Business and Finance. He is married to Dr. Seema Gupta, a physician in the Veterans Administration for over a decade. They are the proud parents of identical twin sons, Arka and Drew.</p>



<p><strong><u>Gabe Camarillo, Nominee for Under Secretary of the Army, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Gabe Camarillo is a lawyer who served in various positions in the Department of Defense during the Obama-Biden administration.&nbsp; In 2015, Mr. Camarillo was appointed as Assistant Secretary of the Air Force (Manpower &amp; Reserve Affairs) overseeing all manpower and reserve component matters affecting over 670,000 military and civilian personnel.&nbsp; From 2012 to 2015, he served as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Army (Acquisition, Logistics &amp; Technology), where he helped lead the Army’s research and development and modernization portfolio.&nbsp;&nbsp; From 2010 to 2012, Mr. Camarillo previously served as the Special Assistant to the Assistant Secretary of the Army (Acquisition, Logistics &amp; Technology).</p>



<p>Mr. Camarillo is currently a Senior Vice President at SAIC and previously held other leadership positions in the company.&nbsp; He has also worked as a lawyer in private practice, specializing in commercial litigation, campaign finance and government ethics.&nbsp; He received his law degree from Stanford Law School and his undergraduate degree from Georgetown University, where he previously served as an adjunct professor at Georgetown University’s School of Public Policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Alan Estevez, Nominee for Under Secretary for Industry and Security, Department of Commerce</u></strong></p>



<p>Alan Estevez, a recognized leader in the defense and aerospace community, joined Deloitte Consulting as a national security strategy and logistics executive in June 2017 after completing a 36 year career with the Department of Defense. Mr. Estevez served as the Principal Deputy Under Secretary of Defense (Acquisition, Technology &amp; Logistics) from 2013 to 2017. Mr. Estevez developed, implemented and managed acquisition, contracting, installation, and logistics programs and policies that increased combat effectiveness as well as the department’s efficiency and buying power.</p>



<p>Prior to his last appointment, Mr. Estevez held several key positions within the Office of the Secretary of Defense, including as the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Logistics and Materiel Readiness. In this position, he was responsible for providing world class military logistics support to the men and women of the United States Armed Forces. He was the first career Federal official to hold this position. Mr. Estevez also served as the Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Logistics and Material Readiness. Mr. Estevez has been honored numerous times, including three Department of Defense Distinguished Public Service Medals and the Distinguished Civilian Service Medal.</p>



<p>Estevez holds a Bachelor of Arts in political science from Rutgers University and a Master of Science in national resource strategy from the Industrial College of the Armed Forces at the National Defense University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jeff Lane Flake, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Turkey</u></strong></p>



<p>Jeff L. Flake is currently a Distinguished Fellow at Arizona State University and a Distinguished Fellow at the Sorensen Center for Moral and Ethical Leadership at Brigham Young University.  He also serves on the Senior Advisory Committee at Harvard’s Institute of Politics.  Flake was a Member of Congress for 18 years, representing Arizona in the U.S. Senate (2013-2019) and the U.S. House of Representatives (2001-2013), where he served on the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and the House Foreign Affairs Committee.  A frequent public speaker, he is also a former contributor for CNN and CBS News.  Flake is a Director of Taylor Morrison, a home builder in Scottsdale, Arizona, and a former Executive Director of the Goldwater Institute in Phoenix, Arizona.  Early in his career, he was Executive Director of the Foundation for Democracy in Namibia.  He speaks Afrikaans.  He earned a B.A. in International Relations, and an M.A. in Political Science, at Brigham Young University.  He is a recipient of the Gold Medal of Honorary Patronage from the University Philosophical Society, Trinity College, Dublin, Ireland.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kent Doyle Logsdon, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Moldova</u></strong></p>



<p>Kent Doyle Logsdon, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, is Chief of Staff to the Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy and the Environment.&nbsp; Previously, he served as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of Energy Resources, and was the Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Berlin, Germany, serving as Chargé d’Affaires, a.i. from January 2017 to May 2018.&nbsp; Prior to that, Logsdon was the Executive Assistant to the Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources, and Deputy Executive Secretary of the State Department.&nbsp; Previous positions include Director of the Operations Center, Director of the Office of Russian Affairs, and Deputy Chief of Mission in Tbilisi, Georgia.&nbsp; Logsdon also served in Kyiv, Ukraine; Bangkok, Thailand; Almaty, Kazakhstan; Islamabad, Pakistan; and Stuttgart, Germany.&nbsp;&nbsp; He holds a Master’s Degree from the University of Virginia and a Bachelor’s Degree from the University of Notre Dame.&nbsp; The recipient of a Presidential Meritorious Service Award, Logsdon speaks Russian, Ukrainian, Thai and German.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Atul Gawande, Nominee for Assistant Administrator of the Bureau for Global Health, United States Agency for International Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Atul Gawande, MD, MPH, is the Cyndy and John Fish Distinguished Professor of Surgery at Brigham and Women’s Hospital, Samuel O. Thier Professor of Surgery at Harvard Medical School, and Professor of Health Policy and Management at Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health. Dr. Gawande is also founder and chair of Ariadne Labs, a joint center for health systems innovation at Brigham and Women’s Hospital and the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, and of Lifebox, a nonprofit organization making surgery safer globally. During the coronavirus pandemic, he co-founded CIC Health, which operates COVID-19 testing and vaccination nationally, and served as a member of the Biden transition COVID-19 Advisory Board. From 2018 to 2020, he was CEO of Haven, the Amazon, Berkshire Hathaway, and JPMorgan Chase health care venture. He previously served as a senior advisor in the Department of Health and Human Services in the Clinton Administration.</p>



<p>In addition, Atul has been a staff writer for The New Yorker magazine since 1998 and written four New York Times best-selling books: Complications, Better, The Checklist Manifesto, and Being Mortal. He is the winner of two National Magazine Awards, AcademyHealth’s Impact Award for highest research impact on health care, a MacArthur Fellowship, and the Lewis Thomas Award for writing about science.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lisa Wang, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Enforcement and Compliance, Department of Commerce</u></strong></p>



<p>Ms. Wang has been a partner with Picard, Kentz and Rowe LLP since 2016.&nbsp; She specializes in international trade law matters, including antidumping and countervailing duty litigation and trade policy issues.&nbsp; Previously, Ms. Wang was a Senior Attorney in the Office of the Chief Counsel for Trade Enforcement and Compliance at the U.S. Department of Commerce, and an Assistant General Counsel in the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative.&nbsp; Before that, she spent three years as the Senior Import Administration Officer for the U.S. Embassy in Beijing, China, and was an associate with Dewey Ballantine LLP.&nbsp; She earned her JD from the Georgetown University Law Center, and her BS from Cornell University.&nbsp; Ms. Wang is married to Timothy Kovacs, where they reside in Washington, D.C. with their two young daughters.</p>



<p><strong><u>Chester John Culver, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation</u></strong></p>



<p>Chet Culver served as the 40<sup>th</sup> Governor of Iowa from 2007 to 2011. Under his leadership, Iowa successfully managed a $6 billion annual budget, earned a “Triple A” bond rating, and built up one of the largest budget surpluses in the nation. As governor, Culver led Iowa to become the renewable energy capital of the United States.</p>



<p>A public servant for over 25 years, Culver previously served on the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Board during the Obama Administration. He also served as the Secretary of State of Iowa from 1999 to 2007 and was a former teacher and coach in his community. Culver founded the Chet Culver Group, an energy sector consulting firm, in 2011.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rich Trumka, Jr., Nominee for Commissioner of the Consumer Product Safety Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Rich Trumka Jr. is General Counsel &amp; Staff Director of the Economic and Consumer Policy Subcommittee of the U.S. House of Representatives’ Committee on Oversight and Reform.&nbsp; In this position, he works on oversight and investigations related to consumer protection, consumer product safety, and public health.&nbsp; Trumka previously served as Assistant Attorney General in the Consumer Protection Division of the Maryland Office of the Attorney General.&nbsp; Prior to that, he was a litigation attorney in private practice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trumka received his bachelor’s degree in Industrial and Labor Relations from Cornell University, and his J.D. from Georgetown University Law Center.&nbsp; After law school, Trumka served as a judicial law clerk to Judge Berle M. Schiller of the Eastern District of Pennsylvania.&nbsp; Trumka and his wife, Jessica, live in Maryland with their son and daughter. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>James A. Diossa, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation</u></strong></p>



<p>James A. Diossa served two terms as Mayor of the City of Central Falls, Rhode Island. Upon taking office in 2012, James became the youngest mayor in the state’s history and the city’s first Latino mayor. Assuming leadership of a postindustrial urban city in the midst of municipal bankruptcy proceedings, he sought to tackle these challenges head-on. Through hard work and the development of strategic partnerships, James turned Central Falls around, stabilizing the city’s finances and raising its long-term bond rating to investment grade. He also secured millions of dollars in federal, foundation, and private sector funding to improve the city’s quality of life and infrastructure. Most recently, James led efforts to partner with the neighboring city of Pawtucket to create a unified response to the COVID-19 pandemic, which included organizing a volunteer corps and engaging the former head of the Rhode Island Department of Health to serve as the city’s Chief Health Strategist.</p>



<p>James previously served on the Central Falls City Council, where he organized citywide efforts to save the city’s only library from closing and stopped the US Postal Service from closing the city’s only post office. He holds a Bachelor&#8217;s Degree in Criminal Justice from Becker College. Born and raised in Central Falls, Rhode Island, James is the proud son of Colombian immigrants and a lifelong soccer enthusiast.</p>



<p>James is currently a Senior Advisor at Brown University’s The Policy Lab. His lifelong partner Sandra and James have a beautiful daughter, Arianna Hallel.</p>



<p><strong><u>Terrence K. Wright, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation</u></strong></p>



<p>Terrence K. Wright, of Wilmington, Delaware, is a 1982 graduate of The American University in Washington, DC. From 1982 to 2009, Mr. Wright served in various positions on the staff of United States Senator Joseph R. Biden, Jr., both in Washington, DC, and in Wilmington, Delaware.</p>



<p>Upon his retirement from the Senate in 2009, Mr. Wright was appointed by Delaware Governor Jack Markell to the Delaware Heritage Commission, a state agency which promotes the study of the History of Delaware.&nbsp; He has since been reappointed by the current Governor, John C. Carney, Jr., and was Chairman of the Commission’s Observance of the Sesquicentennial of The Civil War.&nbsp; In that capacity, he was the Executive Producer of the Commission educational film, entitled, “Delaware and Gettysburg: The Story of Delaware, Delawareans, and The Battle that Determined America’s Future.”</p>



<p>Mr. Wright in currently serving on New Castle, County, Delaware’s Council Redistricting Commission, which is charged with redrawing the County’s Councilmanic boundaries in light of the 2020 Census.&nbsp; He served in the same capacity after the 2010 Census. Additionally, Mr. Wright is currently the Chairman of the Eastern Brandywine Hundred Coordinating Council, a community organization dedicated to local history and community planning in the communities along the Delaware River in northern Delaware.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
