<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 19:23:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Sixteenth Operation Fly Formula Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/president-biden-announces-sixteenth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 19:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 1 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Nestlé Health Science Alfamino® and Alfamino® Junior formula on July 10 and 11 Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing two flights, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 1 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Nestlé Health Science Alfamino® and Alfamino® Junior formula on July 10 and 11</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing two flights, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Nestlé Health Science amino acid based formula from Switzerland to John F. Kennedy Airport in New York on July 10 and 11. This delivery will include approximately 100,000 pounds of Nestlé Health Science Alfamino® and Alfamino® Junior formula, the equivalent of over 1 million 8-ounce bottles. The product, which is designed for children with cow’s milk protein allergies (CMPA), will be distributed primarily to hospitals and home health care providers.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Nestlé can export additional infant formula into the U.S. Nestlé will import both standard and specialty infant formulas including Nestlé NAN® SupremePro 1, Nestlé NAN® SupremePro 2, Nestlé NAN® EXPERTpro SensiPro Premium Instant Starter Formula, Nestlé Health Science Alfamino® and Alfamino® Junior, Vitaflo PKU start™, Gerber® Good Start® Gentle and Gerber® Good Start® Extensive HA®. Over time Nestlé plans to bring approximately 42 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. By July 10, Operation Fly Formula will have transported more than 44 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents to the U.S.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img width="801" height="481" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/finalformula.png" alt="" class="wp-image-56992" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/finalformula.png 801w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/finalformula.png?resize=615,369 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/finalformula.png?resize=768,461 768w" sizes="(max-width: 801px) 100vw, 801px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Protecting Access to Reproductive Health Care&#160;Services</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/08/remarks-by-president-biden-on-protecting-access-to-reproductive-health-care-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 19:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56988</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 12:04 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning, everyone.&#160; Before I speak to the Supreme Court extreme decision overturning Roe, I want to comment on one piece of good news &#8212; economic good news today. Today, the Labor Department reported that we added 372,000 jobs last month &#8212; 372,000.&#160; Here’s why it’s important: Our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>12:04 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Before I speak to the Supreme Court extreme decision overturning Roe, I want to comment on one piece of good news &#8212; economic good news today.<br><br>Today, the Labor Department reported that we added 372,000 jobs last month &#8212; 372,000.&nbsp;<br><br>Here’s why it’s important: Our private sector has now have recovered all the jobs lost during the pandemic and added jobs on top of that.&nbsp; We have more Americans working today in the private sector than any day under my predecessor, more today than any time in American history &#8212; today.<br><br>In the second quarter of this year, we created more jobs than any quarter under any of my predecessors in nearly 40 years before the pandemic.<br><br>Think about that.&nbsp; At a time when our critics said the economy was too weak or having already added more jobs in my &#8212; we had already added more jobs my first year as President of any president in history, we still added more jobs in the past three months than any administration in nearly 40 years.<br><br>Now, look, I know times are tough.&nbsp; Prices are too high.&nbsp; Families are facing a cost-of-living crunch.&nbsp;<br><br>But today’s economic news confirms the fact that my economic plan is moving this country in a better direction.&nbsp;<br><br>The unemployment rate is near a historic low of 3.6 percent.&nbsp; Private sector jobs are at a record high.<br><br>Gas prices, still way too high, have fallen now 25 days in a row, and this week we saw the second-largest single-day decrease in gas prices in a decade.&nbsp;<br><br>We still have a lot of work to do.&nbsp; I’m not suggesting &#8212; there’s a lot more work to do.&nbsp; But I am suggesting we’re making progress.&nbsp; The program is working.<br><br>Now, with the Vice President, Secretary Becerra, and Deputy Attorney General Monaco, I want to talk about an executive order I’m signing to protect reproductive rights of women in the aftermath of the Supreme Court’s terrible, extreme, and, I think, so totally wrongheaded decision to overturn Roe v. Wade.<br><br><s>In</s> [It] both formalized actions I announced right after the decision, as well as adding new measures today.<br><br>Let’s be clear about something from the very start.&nbsp; This was not a decision driven by the Constitution.&nbsp; Let me say it again: This was not a decision driven by the Constitution.&nbsp; And despite what those justices in the majority said, this was not a decision driven by history.<br><br>You’ve all probably had a chance to the read the decision and the dissent.<br><br>The majority rattles off laws from the 19th century to support the idea that Roe was historic- &#8212; was a historical anomaly because states outlawed abortion in the 1880s, toward the end.&nbsp; But that’s just wrong.<br><br>The truth is today’s Supreme Court majority that is playing fast and loose with the facts.&nbsp; Even 150 years ago, the common law and many state laws did not criminalize abortion early in pregnancy, which is very similar to the viability line drawn by Roe.<br><br>But the Dobbs majority ignores that fact.&nbsp; And the Dobbs majority ignores that many laws were enacted to protect women at the time when they were dying from unsafe abortions.<br><br>This is the horrific reality that Roe sought to end.&nbsp; The practice of medicine should not &#8212; emphasize &#8212; should not be frozen in the 19th century.<br><br>So, what happened?<br><br>The dissenting opinion says it as clear as you can possibly say it.&nbsp; And here’s the quote: “Neither law nor facts nor attitudes have provided any new reason to reach a different result than Roe and Casey did.”&nbsp; And that’s has changed &#8212; excuse me &#8212; and “All that has changed is this Court.”&nbsp; End of quote.&nbsp; “All that has changed is this Court.”<br><br>That wasn’t about the Constitution or the law.<br><br>It was about a deep, long-seething antipathy towards Roe and the broader right to privacy.&nbsp; As the justices wrote in their dissent, and I quote, “The majority has overruled Roe and Casey for one and only one reason: because it has always despised them, and now it has the votes to discard them.”&nbsp; End of quote.<br><br>So, what we’re witnessing wasn’t a constitutional judgment.&nbsp; It was an exercise in raw political power.&nbsp; On the day the Dobbs decision came down, I immediately announced what I would do.<br><br>But I also made it clear, based on the reasoning of the Court, there is no constitutional right to choose.&nbsp; Only the way &#8212; the only way to fulfill and restore that right for women in this country is by voting, by exercising the power at the ballot box.<br><br>Let me explain.&nbsp; We need two additional pro-choice senators and a pro-choice House to codify Roe as federal law.&nbsp; Your vote can make that a reality.<br><br>I know it’s frustrating and it made a lot of people very angry.&nbsp; But the truth is this &#8212; and it’s not just me saying it; it’s what the Court said: When you read the decision, the Court has made clear it will not protect the rights of women.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; Period.<br><br>After having made the decision based on a reading of a document that was frozen in time in the 1860s, when women didn’t even have the right to vote, the Court now &#8212; now &#8212; practically dares the women of America to go to the ballot box and restore the very rights they’ve just taken away.<br><br>One of the most extraordinary parts of the decision, in my view, is the majority writes, and I quote, “Women…” &#8212; it’s a quote now, from the majority &#8212; “Women are not without electoral or political power.&nbsp; It is noteworthy that the percentage of women who registered to vote and cast a ballot is consistently higher than the percentage of the men who do so.”&nbsp; End of quote.<br><br>Let me repeat the line: “Women are not without electoral…” and/or political &#8212; “or” &#8212; let me be precise; not “and/or” &#8212; “…or political power.”&nbsp;<br><br>That’s another way of saying that you, the women of America, can determine the outcome of this issue.&nbsp;<br><br>I don’t think the Court or, for that matter, the Republicans who for decades have pushed their extreme agenda have a clue about the power of American women.&nbsp; But they’re about to find out, in my view.<br><br>It’s my hope and strong belief that women will, in fact, turn out in record numbers to reclaim the rights that have taken from them by the Court.<br><br>And let me be clear: While I wish it had not come to this, this is the fastest route available.&nbsp; I’m just stating a basic, fundamental notion.<br><br>The fastest way to restore Woe [sic] &#8212; Roe is to pass a national law codifying Roe, which I will sign immediately upon its passage at my desk.<br><br>And we can’t wait.&nbsp; Extreme Republican governors, extreme Republican state legislatures, and Republican extremists in the Congress overall &#8212; all of them have not only fought to take away the right &#8212; our rights &#8212; but they’re now determined to go as far as they can.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Now the most extreme Republican governors and state legislatures have taken the Court’s decision as a green light to impose some of the harshest and most restrictive laws seen in this country in a long time.&nbsp; These are the laws that not only put women’s lives at risk, these are the laws that will cost lives.&nbsp;<br><br>What we’re witnessing is a giant step backwards in much of our country.&nbsp; Already, the bans are in effect in 13 states.&nbsp;&nbsp; Twelve additional states are likely to ban choice&nbsp;in the next coming &#8212; in the coming weeks.&nbsp; And in a number of these states, the laws are so extreme they have raised the threat of criminal penalties for doctors and healthcare providers.&nbsp; They’re so extreme that many don’t allow for exceptions, even for rape or incest.&nbsp; Let me say that again: Some of the states don’t allow for exceptions for rape or incest.&nbsp;<br><br>This isn’t some imagined horror.&nbsp; It’s already happening.&nbsp; Just last week, it was reported that a 10-year-old girl was a rape victim in Ohio &#8212; 10 years old &#8212; and she was forced to have to travel out of the state, to Indiana, to seek to terminate the <s>presnency</s> [pregnancy] and maybe save her life.&nbsp; That’s &#8212; the last part is my judgment.&nbsp; Ten years old.&nbsp; Ten years old.&nbsp; Raped, six weeks pregnant.&nbsp; Already traumatized.&nbsp; Was forced to travel to another state.&nbsp; Imagine being that little girl.&nbsp; Just &#8212; I’m serious &#8212; just imagine being that little girl.&nbsp; Ten years old.<br><br>Does anyone believe that it’s the highest majority view that that should not be able to be dealt with, or in any other state in the nation?&nbsp; A 10-year-old girl should be forced to give birth to a rapist’s child?&nbsp; I can tell you what: I don’t.&nbsp; I can’t think of anything as much more extreme.<br><br>The Court’s decision has also been received by Republicans in Congress as a green light to go further and pass a national ban.&nbsp; A national ban.&nbsp; Remember what they’re saying.&nbsp; They’re saying there’s no right to privacy, so therefore it’s not protected by the Constitution, so leave it up to the state and the Congress, what they want to do.&nbsp;<br><br>And now my Republican friends are talking about getting the Congress to pass a national ban.&nbsp; The extreme positions that they’re taking in some of these states.&nbsp; That will mean the right to choose will be illegal nationwide if, in fact, they succeed.&nbsp; Let me tell you something: As long as I’m President, it won’t happen, because I’ll veto it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So the choice is clear.&nbsp; If you want to change the circumstances for women and even little girls in this country, please go out and vote.&nbsp; When tens of millions of women vote this year, they won’t be alone.&nbsp; Millions and millions of men will be taking up the fight alongside them to restore the right to choose and the broader right to privacy in this nation, which they denied existed.&nbsp; And the challenge from the Court to the American women and men &#8212; this is a nation.&nbsp; The challenge is: Go out and vote.&nbsp; Well, for God’s sake, there’s an election in November.&nbsp; Vote, vote, vote, vote.&nbsp; Consider the challenge accepted, Court.&nbsp;<br><br>But in the meantime, I’m signing this important executive order.&nbsp; I’m asking the Justice Department that, much like they did in the Civil Rights era, to do something &#8212; do everything in their power to protect these women seeking to invoke their right:&nbsp;<br><br>In states where clinics are still open, to protect them from intimidation.&nbsp;<br><br>To protect the right of women to travel from a state that prohibits seeking the medical attention that she needs to a state to provide that care.&nbsp;<br><br>To protect a woman’s right to the FDA-approved &#8212; Federal Drug Administration-approved medication that’s been available for over 20 years.&nbsp;<br><br>The executive order provides safeguards to access care.&nbsp; A patient comes into the emergency room in any state in the union.&nbsp; She’s expressing and experiencing a life-threatening miscarriage, but the doctor is going to be so concerned about being criminalized for treating her, they delay treatment to call the hospital lawyer who is concerned the hospital will be penalized if a doctor provides the lifesaving care.&nbsp; It’s outrageous.&nbsp; I don’t care what your position is.&nbsp; It’s outrageous, and it’s dangerous.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why this executive order directs the Department of Health and Human Services &#8212; HHS &#8212; to ensure all patients, including pregnant women and girls experience pregnant &#8212; experiencing pregnancy loss get emergency care they need under federal law, and that doctors have clear guidance on their own responsibilities and protections no matter what the state &#8212; no matter what state they’re in. &nbsp;<br><br>The executive order protects access to contraception &#8212; that I’m about to sign.&nbsp;<br><br>Justice Thomas himself said that under the reasoning of this decision &#8212; this is what Justice Thomas said in his concurring opinion &#8212; that the Court “should reconsider the constitutional right to contraception &#8212; to use contraception even among married couples.&nbsp;<br><br>What century are they in?&nbsp; There used to be a case called &#8212; <s>Connecticut v. Griswold</s> [Griswold v. Connecticut], which was declared unconstitutional in the late ‘60s.&nbsp; It said a married couple in the privacy of their bedroom could not decide to use contraception.<br>Right now, in all 50 states and the District of Columbia, the Affordable Care Act guarantees insurance coverage for women’s health services, including &#8212; including free birth control.&nbsp; The executive order directs HHS to identify ways to expand access to reproductive health services, like IUDs, birth control pills, emergency contraception.&nbsp;<br><br>And equally important, this executive order protects patient privacy and access to information, which looking at the press assembled before me, probably know more about it than I do.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not a tech guy.&nbsp; I&#8217;m learning.<br><br>But right now, when you use a search engine or the app on your phone, companies collect your data, they sell it to other companies, and they even share it with law enforcement.&nbsp; There’s an increasing concern that extremist governors and others will try to get that data off of your phone, which is out there in the ether, to find what you’re seeking, where you’re going, and what you&#8217;re doing with regard to your healthcare.&nbsp;<br><br>Talk about no privacy &#8212; no privacy in the Constitution.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no privacy, period.<br><br>This executive order asks the FTC to crack down on data brokers that sell private information to extreme groups or, in my view, sell private information to anybody.<br><br>It provides private health information &#8212; it protects private health information in states with extreme laws.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And the executive order strengthens coordination at a federal level.&nbsp; It establishes a task force, led by the White House Department &#8212; and the Department of Human Services, focused specifically on using every federal tool available to protect access to reproductive healthcare.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You know, let me close with this: The Court and its allies are committed&nbsp;to moving America backward with fewer rights, less autonomy, and politicians invading the most personal of decisions.&nbsp;&nbsp;Remember the reasoning of this decision has an impact much beyond Roe and the right to privacy generally.&nbsp;<br><br>Marriage equality, contraception, and so much more is at risk.&nbsp; This decision affects everyone &#8212; unrelated to choice &#8212; beyond choice.&nbsp; We cannot allow an out-of-control Supreme Court, working in conjunction with the extremist elements of the Republican Party, to take away freedoms and our personal autonomy.&nbsp;<br><br>The choice we face as a nation is between the mainstream and the extreme, between moving forward and moving backwards, between allowing politicians to enter the most personal parts of our lives&nbsp;and protecting the right to privacy &#8212; yes, yes &#8212; embedded in our Constitution.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This is a choice.&nbsp; This is a moment &#8212; the moment &#8212; the moment to restore the rights that have been taken away from us and the moment to protect our nation from an extremist agenda that is antithetical to everything we believe as Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, I&#8217;m going to sign this executive order.&nbsp;<br><br>The executive order is “Protecting Access to Reproductive Health Care Services.”<br><br>(The executive order is signed.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what does Prime Minister Abe’s death last night say about the security situation in Japan?&nbsp;<br><br>And can you give us an update on your thinking about lifting China tariffs, please?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me &#8212; I &#8212; I tried to put a call in to &#8212; to the present Prime Minister.&nbsp; And he was &#8212; it was very late there at night.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll be talking there in the morning.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to be stopping to sign the condolence book at the Japanese embassy on the way to the CIA.&nbsp;<br><br>This hasn’t happened to Japan in decades &#8212; in decades, I&#8217;m told, all the way back to the late ‘30s or mid-‘30s.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a homemade weapon.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve only seen a photograph of it.&nbsp; The Justice Department is going to be going in and giving me more detail later as they find out the detail.&nbsp;<br><br>But the fact is that one thing did strike my &#8212; get my attention: that this is the first use of a weapon to murder someone in the &#8212; in Japan.&nbsp; And I think we have thus far have 3,000 &#8212; I &#8212; don’t hold me to the number &#8212; 688 or &#8212; I mean, between 3- and 4,000 cases.&nbsp; They have one.&nbsp; One.&nbsp; One.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so &#8212; but we&#8217;re going to learn more about &#8212; as time goes on, about motive, about, you know, the whole &#8212; but Japan &#8212; Fumio, the present Prime Minister, is a very solid guy.&nbsp; Japan is a very, very stable ally.&nbsp;<br><br>And we &#8212; I do not believe it&#8217;s likely to have &#8212; but I don&#8217;t know yet &#8212; likely to have any profound, destabilizing impact on Japanese security or Japanese solidarity.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all so very much.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The one on tariffs as well, sir.&nbsp; Can you just give us your thoughts on China ta- &#8212; lifting China tariffs?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I haven’t made that decision.&nbsp; We’re going through them one at a time.<br><br>12:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Minnesota Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/08/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-minnesota-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 19:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56985</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Minnesota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, straight-line winds, tornadoes, and flooding from May 8 to May 13, 2022. Federal funding is available to state, tribal,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Minnesota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, straight-line winds, tornadoes, and flooding from May 8 to May 13, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storms, straight-line winds, tornadoes, and flooding in the counties of Aitkin, Big Stone, Cass, Chippewa, Cottonwood, Douglas, Grant, Kandiyohi, Lac qui Parle, Lincoln, Morrison, Nobles, Pope, Redwood, Renville, Stearns, Stevens, Swift, Todd, Traverse, Wadena, Wilkin, and Yellow Medicine.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Brian F. Schiller as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Protecting Access to Reproductive Healthcare&#160;Services</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/08/executive-order-on-protecting-access-to-reproductive-healthcare-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 16:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it&#160;is&#160;hereby ordered as follows: Section 1.&#160; Policy.&#160; Nearly 50 years ago, Roe v. Wade, 410 U.S. 113 (1973), articulated the United States Constitution&#8217;s protection of women&#8217;s fundamental right to make reproductive healthcare decisions. &#160;These deeply&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it&nbsp;is&nbsp;hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1.&nbsp; Policy.&nbsp; Nearly 50 years ago, <em>Roe v. Wade</em>, 410 U.S. 113 (1973), articulated the United States Constitution&#8217;s protection of women&#8217;s fundamental right to make reproductive healthcare decisions. &nbsp;These deeply private decisions should not be subject to government interference. &nbsp;Yet today, fundamental rights &#8212; to privacy, autonomy, freedom, and equality &#8212; have been denied to millions of women across the country.</p>



<p>Eliminating the right recognized in <em>Roe </em>has already had and will continue to have devastating implications for women&#8217;s health and public health more broadly. &nbsp;Access to reproductive healthcare services is now threatened for millions of Americans, and especially for those who live in States that are banning or severely restricting abortion care. &nbsp;Women&#8217;s health clinics are being forced to close &#8212; including clinics that offer other preventive healthcare services such as contraception &#8212; leaving many communities without access to critical reproductive healthcare services. &nbsp;Women seeking abortion care &#8212; especially those in low-income, rural, and other underserved communities &#8212; now have to travel to jurisdictions where services remain legal notwithstanding the cost or risks.</p>



<p>In the face of this health crisis, the Federal Government <a></a>is taking action to protect healthcare service delivery and promote access to critical reproductive healthcare services, including abortion. &nbsp;It remains the policy of my Administration to support women&#8217;s right to choose and to protect and defend reproductive rights. &nbsp;Doing so is essential to justice, equality, and our health, safety, and progress as a Nation.</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; Definitions.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The term &#8220;agency&#8221; means any authority of the United States that is an &#8220;agency&#8221; under 44&nbsp;U.S.C. 3502(1), other than one considered to be an independent regulatory agency, as defined in 44 U.S.C. 3502(5).</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The term &#8220;reproductive healthcare services&#8221; means medical, surgical, counseling, or referral services relating to the human reproductive system, including services relating to pregnancy or the termination of a pregnancy.</p>



<p>Sec. 3.  Protecting Access to Reproductive Healthcare Services.  (a)  Within 30 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit a report to the President:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; identifying potential actions:</p>



<p>(A)&nbsp; to protect and expand access to abortion care, including medication abortion; and</p>



<p>(B)&nbsp; to otherwise protect and expand access to the full range of reproductive healthcare services, including actions to enhance family planning services such as access to emergency contraception;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;identifying ways to increase outreach and education about access to reproductive healthcare services, including by launching a public awareness initiative to provide timely and accurate information about such access, which shall:&nbsp;</p>



<p>(A)&nbsp; share information about how to obtain free or reduced cost reproductive healthcare services through Health Resources and Services Administration-Funded Health Centers, Title X clinics, and other providers; and&nbsp;</p>



<p>(B)&nbsp; include promoting awareness of and access to the full range of contraceptive services, as well as know-your-rights information for those seeking or providing reproductive healthcare services; and</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; identifying steps to ensure that all patients ‑- including pregnant women and those experiencing pregnancy loss, such as miscarriages and ectopic pregnancies &#8212; receive the full protections for emergency medical care afforded under the law, including by considering updates to current guidance on obligations specific to emergency conditions and stabilizing care under the Emergency Medical Treatment and Labor Act, 42 U.S.C. 1395dd, and providing data from the Department of Health and Human Services concerning implementation of these efforts. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;To promote access to reproductive healthcare services, the Attorney General and the Counsel to the President shall convene a meeting of private pro bono attorneys, bar associations, and public interest organizations in order to encourage lawyers to represent and assist patients, providers, and third parties lawfully seeking these services throughout the country.</p>



<p>Sec. 4. &nbsp;Protecting Privacy, Safety, and Security.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; To address potential heightened safety and security risks related to the provision of reproductive healthcare services, the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall consider actions, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, to ensure the safety of patients, providers, and third parties, and to protect the security of clinics (including mobile clinics), pharmacies, and other entities providing, dispensing, or delivering reproductive and related healthcare services.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; To address the potential threat to patient privacy caused by the transfer and sale of sensitive health-related data and by digital surveillance related to reproductive healthcare services, and to protect people seeking reproductive health services from fraudulent schemes or deceptive practices:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Chair of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) is encouraged to consider actions, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law (including the Federal Trade Commission Act, 15 U.S.C. 41 <em>et seq</em>.), to protect consumers&#8217; privacy when seeking information about and provision of reproductive healthcare services.</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall consider actions, including providing guidance under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act, Public Law 104-191, 110 Stat. 1936 (1996) as amended by Public Law 111-5, 123 Stat. 115 (2009), and any other statutes as appropriate, to strengthen the protection of sensitive information related to reproductive healthcare services and bolster patient-provider confidentiality.</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, in consultation with the Attorney General, consider actions to educate consumers on how best to protect their health privacy and limit the collection and sharing of their sensitive health-related information. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(iv)   The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Chair of the FTC, consider options to address deceptive or fraudulent practices related to reproductive healthcare services, including online, and to protect access to accurate information.</p>



<p>Sec. 5. &nbsp;Coordinating Implementation Efforts.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Director of the Gender Policy Council shall establish and co-chair an Interagency Task Force on Reproductive Healthcare Access (Task Force). &nbsp;Additional members shall include the Attorney General and the heads of other agencies as determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Director of the Gender Policy Council.&nbsp; The Task Force shall work to identify and coordinate activities to protect and strengthen access to essential reproductive healthcare services.&nbsp; In addition, the Task Force shall coordinate Federal interagency policymaking, program development, and outreach efforts to address barriers that individuals and entities may face in seeking and providing reproductive healthcare services.&nbsp; The Department of Health and Human Services shall provide funding and administrative support as may be necessary for the performance and functions of the Task Force.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall provide technical assistance, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, concerning Federal constitutional protections to States seeking to afford legal protection to out-of-State patients and providers who offer legal reproductive healthcare.</p>



<p>Sec. 6.&nbsp; General Provisions.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 8, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on the Death Of Abe&#160;Shinzo</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/08/a-proclamation-on-the-death-of-abe-shinzo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 16:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The longest serving Prime Minister in Japan&#8217;s history, Abe Shinzo was a proud servant of the Japanese people and a faithful friend to the United States.  He worked with American Presidents of both parties to deepen the Alliance between our nations and advance a common vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific. Even in the moment&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The longest serving Prime Minister in Japan&#8217;s history, Abe Shinzo was a proud servant of the Japanese people and a faithful friend to the United States.  He worked with American Presidents of both parties to deepen the Alliance between our nations and advance a common vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific. Even in the moment he was attacked and killed, he was engaged in the work of democracy, to which he dedicated his life.  </p>



<p>As a mark of respect for the memory of Abe Shinzo, former Prime Minister of Japan, by the authority vested in me as President of the United States by the&nbsp;Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States of America, I&nbsp;hereby order that the flag of&nbsp;the United&nbsp;States shall be flown at half-staff at the White&nbsp;House and upon all public buildings and grounds, at all military posts and naval stations, and on all naval vessels of&nbsp;the Federal Government in the District of Columbia and throughout the United&nbsp;States and its Territories and possessions until sunset, July 10, 2022. &nbsp;I also direct that the flag shall be flown at&nbsp;half-staff for the same length of time at all United&nbsp;States embassies, legations, consular offices, and other facilities abroad, including all military facilities and naval vessels and&nbsp;stations.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-seventh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Biden on the June&#160;Jobs Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-june-jobs-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 13:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we learned that our private sector has recovered all of the jobs lost during the pandemic, and added jobs on top of that. This has been the fastest and strongest jobs recovery in American history, and it would not have been possible without the decisive action my Administration took last year to fix a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we learned that our private sector has recovered all of the jobs lost during the pandemic, and added jobs on top of that. This has been the fastest and strongest jobs recovery in American history, and it would not have been possible without the decisive action my Administration took last year to fix a broken COVID response, and pass the American Rescue Plan to get our economy back on track.</p>



<p>In the second quarter of this year, we created more jobs than in any quarter under any of my predecessors in the nearly 40 years before the pandemic. We have more Americans working in the private sector today than any day during Donald Trump’s Presidency – more people than any time in our history.</p>



<p>The historic strength of our job market is one reason our economy is uniquely well positioned to tackle a range of global economic challenges – from global inflation to the economic fallout from Putin’s war. No country is better positioned than America to bring down inflation, without giving up all of the economic gains we have made over the last 18 months.</p>



<p>Of course, having added a record number of new jobs, and achieved historically low levels of unemployment, additional job growth from this strong position will be slower. That is not a bad thing, because our economy should move to stable growth for the years ahead.</p>



<p>The best way to achieve that goal is for Congress to pass legislation that lowers costs for families – from prescription drugs to utility costs – while reducing the federal budget deficit, in addition to passing the Bipartisan Innovation Act.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Killing of Former Japanese Prime Minister Abe&#160;Shinzo</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-killing-of-former-japanese-prime-minister-abe-shinzo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 12:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am stunned, outraged, and deeply saddened by the news that my friend Abe Shinzo, former Prime Minister of Japan, was shot and killed while campaigning. This is a tragedy for Japan and for all who knew him. I had the privilege to work closely with Prime Minister Abe. As Vice President, I visited him in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I am stunned, outraged, and deeply saddened by the news that my friend Abe Shinzo, former Prime Minister of Japan, was shot and killed while campaigning. This is a tragedy for Japan and for all who knew him. I had the privilege to work closely with Prime Minister Abe. As Vice President, I visited him in Tokyo and welcomed him to Washington. He was a champion of the Alliance between our nations and the friendship between our people. The longest serving Japanese Prime Minister, his vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific will endure. Above all, he cared deeply about the Japanese people and dedicated his life to their service. Even at the moment he was attacked, he was engaged in the work of democracy. While there are many details that we do not yet know, we know that violent attacks are never acceptable and that gun violence always leaves a deep scar on the communities that are affected by it. The United States stands with Japan in this moment of grief. I send my deepest condolences to his family. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden to Sign Executive Order Protecting Access to Reproductive Health Care&#160;Services</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-sign-executive-order-protecting-access-to-reproductive-health-care-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two weeks ago, the Supreme Court issued a decision that overturned Roe v. Wade and eliminated a woman’s Constitutional right to choose.&#160; This decision expressly took away a right from the American people that it had recognized for nearly 50 years – a woman’s right to make her own reproductive health care decisions, free from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Two weeks ago, the Supreme Court issued a decision that overturned <em>Roe v. Wade </em>and eliminated a woman’s Constitutional right to choose.&nbsp; This decision expressly took away a right from the American people that it had recognized for nearly 50 years – a woman’s right to make her own reproductive health care decisions, free from government interference.&nbsp; Fundamental rights – to privacy, autonomy, freedom, and equality – have been denied to millions of women across the country, with grave implications for their health, lives, and wellbeing. This ruling will disproportionately affect women of color, low-income women, and rural women.<br><br>President Biden has made clear that the only way to secure a woman’s right to choose is for Congress to restore the protections of&nbsp;<em>Roe</em>&nbsp;as federal law. Until then, he has committed to doing everything in his power to defend reproductive rights and protect access to safe and legal abortion.<br><br>Today, President Biden will sign an Executive Order Protecting Access to Reproductive Health Care Services. This Executive Order builds on the actions his Administration has already taken to defend reproductive rights by:</p>



<ul><li>Safeguarding access to reproductive health care services, including abortion and contraception;<br></li><li>Protecting the privacy of patients and their access to accurate information;<br></li><li>Promoting the safety and security of patients, providers, and clinics; and<br></li><li>Coordinating the implementation of Federal efforts to protect reproductive rights and access to health care.</li></ul>



<p><strong>SAFEGUARDING ACCESS TO REPRODUCTIVE HEALTH CARE SERVICES</strong><br><br>The President has directed the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to take the following actions and submit a report to him within 30 days on efforts to:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect Access to Medication Abortion.</strong>&nbsp; HHS will take additional action to protect and expand access to abortion care, including access to medication that the FDA approved as safe and effective over twenty years ago. These actions will build on the steps the Secretary of HHS has already taken at the President’s direction following the decision to ensure that medication abortion is as widely accessible as possible.<br></li><li><strong>Ensure Emergency Medical Care.</strong>&nbsp; HHS will take steps to ensure all patients – including pregnant women and those experiencing pregnancy loss – have access to the full rights and protections for emergency medical care afforded under the law, including by considering updates to current guidance that clarify physician responsibilities and protections under the Emergency Medical Treatment and Labor Act (EMTALA).&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Protect Access to Contraception.</strong>&nbsp; HHS will take additional actions to expand access to the full range of reproductive health services, including family planning services and providers, such as access to emergency contraception and long-acting reversible contraception like intrauterine devices (IUDs). &nbsp;In all fifty states and the District of Columbia, the Affordable Care Act guarantees coverage of women’s preventive services, including free birth control and contraceptive counseling, for individuals and covered dependents. The Secretary of HHS has already directed the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to take every legally available step to ensure patient access to family planning care and to protect family planning providers.<br></li><li><strong>Launch Outreach and Public Education Efforts.&nbsp; </strong>HHS will increase outreach and public education efforts regarding access to reproductive health care services—including abortion—to ensure that Americans have access to reliable and accurate information about their rights and access to care.<br></li><li><strong>Convene Volunteer Lawyers.</strong>&nbsp; The Attorney General and the White House Counsel will convene private pro bono attorneys, bar associations, and public interest organizations to encourage robust legal representation of patients, providers, and third parties lawfully seeking or offering reproductive health care services throughout the country.&nbsp; Such representation could include protecting the right to travel out of state to seek medical care. Immediately following the Supreme Court decision, the President announced his Administration’s position that Americans must remain free to travel safely to another state to seek the care they need, as <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/attorney-general-merrick-b-garland-statement-supreme-court-ruling-dobbs-v-jackson-women-s">the Attorney General made clear in his statement</a>, and his commitment to fighting any attack by a state or local official who attempts to interfere with women exercising this right.</li></ul>



<p><strong>PROTECTING PATIENT PRIVACY AND ACCESS TO ACCURATE INFORMATION</strong><br><br>The President’s Executive Order takes additional steps to protect patient privacy, including by addressing the transfer and sales of sensitive health-related data, combatting digital surveillance related to reproductive health care services, and protecting people seeking reproductive health care from inaccurate information, fraudulent schemes, or deceptive practices.&nbsp; The Executive Order will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect Consumers from Privacy Violations and Fraudulent and Deceptive Practices.</strong>&nbsp; The President has asked the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission to consider taking steps to protect consumers’ privacy when seeking information about and provision of reproductive health care services.&nbsp; The President also has directed the Secretary of HHS, in consultation with the Attorney General and Chair of the FTC, to consider options to address deceptive or fraudulent practices, including online, and protect access to accurate information.</li><li><strong>Protect Sensitive Health Information.</strong>&nbsp; HHS will consider additional actions, including under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA), to better protect sensitive information related to reproductive health care. The Secretary of HHS has already directed the HHS Office for Civil Rights to take initial steps to ensure patient privacy and nondiscrimination of patients, as well as providers who provide reproductive health care, including by:<br><ul><li>Issuing <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-professionals/privacy/guidance/phi-reproductive-health/index.html">new guidance</a> to address how the HIPAA Privacy Rule protects the privacy of individuals’ protected health information, including information related to reproductive health care. The guidance helps ensure doctors and other medical providers and health plans know that, with limited exceptions, they are not required – and in many cases, are not permitted – to disclose patients’ private information, including to law enforcement.&nbsp;<br></li><li>Issuing <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-professionals/privacy/guidance/cell-phone-hipaa/index.html">a how-to guide</a> for consumers on steps they can take to make sure they’re protecting their personal data on mobile apps.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong>PROMOTING SAFETY AND SECURITY</strong><br><br>The Executive Order addresses the heightened risk related to seeking and providing reproductive health care and will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect Patients, Providers, and Clinics.</strong>&nbsp; The Administration will ensure the safety of patients, providers, and third parties, and to protect the security of other entities that are providing, dispensing, or delivering reproductive health care services.&nbsp; This charge includes efforts to protect mobile clinics, which have been deployed to borders to offer care for out-of-state patients.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>COORDINATING IMPLEMENTATION EFFORTS</strong><br><br>To ensure the Federal government takes a swift and coordinated approach to addressing reproductive rights and protecting access to reproductive health care, the President’s Executive Order will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Establish an Interagency Task Force.</strong>&nbsp; The President has directed HHS and the White House Gender Policy Council to establish and lead an interagency Task Force on Reproductive Health Care Access, responsible for coordinating Federal interagency policymaking and program development.&nbsp; This Task Force will also include the Attorney General.&nbsp; In addition, the Attorney General will provide technical assistance to states affording legal protection to out-of-state patients as well as providers who offer legal reproductive health care.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>EXECUTIVE ORDER BUILDS ON ADMINISTRATION’S ACTIONS TO PROTECT ACCESS TO REPRODUCTIVE HEALTH CARE</strong><br><br>In addition to the actions announced today, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken the following steps to protect access to reproductive health care and defend reproductive rights in the wake of the Supreme Court decision in <em>Dobbs</em>.&nbsp; On the day of the decision, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-supreme-court-decision-to-overturn-roe-v-wade/">the President strongly denounced the decision</a> as an affront to women’s fundamental rights and the right to choose In addition to action mentioned above, the Biden-Harris Administration is:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting Providers and Clinics.&nbsp; </strong>The Secretary of HHS directed all HHS agencies to ensure that all HHS-funded providers and clinics have appropriate training and resources to handle family planning needs, and <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/06/30/hhs-announces-new-grants-to-bolster-family-planner-provider-training.html">announced nearly $3 million in new funding</a> to bolster training and technical assistance for the nationwide network of Title X family planning providers.<br></li><li><strong>Promoting Access to Accurate Information.</strong>&nbsp; On the day of the Supreme Court’s decision, HHS launched <a href="https://reproductiverights.gov/">ReproductiveRights.gov</a>, which provides timely and accurate information about reproductive rights and access to reproductive health care.&nbsp; This includes know-your-rights information for patients and providers and promoting awareness of and access to family planning services, as well as guidance for <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/ocr/complaints/index.html">how to file a patient privacy or nondiscrimination complaint</a> with its Office for Civil Rights.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Providing Leave</strong><strong> for Federal Workers Traveling for Medical Care.&nbsp; </strong>The Office of Personnel Management <a href="https://www.opm.gov/policy-data-oversight/pay-leave/leave-administration/fact-sheets/sick-leave-faqs.pdf">issued guidance</a> affirming that paid sick leave can be taken to cover absences for travel to obtain reproductive health care.<br></li><li><strong>Protecting Access to Reproductive Health Care Services for Service members, DoD Civilians, and Military Families.</strong>&nbsp; The Department of Defense (DoD) issued a memo to the Force, DoD civilians and military families on ensuring access to essential women’s health care services. The memo reiterates that the Department will continue to provide seamless access to reproductive healthcare for military and civilian patients, as permitted by federal law.&nbsp; Military providers will continue to fulfill their duty to care for Service members, military dependents and civilian personnel who require pregnancy termination in the cases of rape, incest, or to protect the life of the mother.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>For up-to-date information on your right to access reproductive health care, visit </em><a href="http://www.reproductiverights.gov"><em>www.reproductiverights.gov<br><br></em></a>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine&#160;Jean-Pierre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/07/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3:41 P.M.&#160;EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &#160;Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; I&#8217;m sorry it took me a couple more &#8212; less [more] than a two-minute warning; more like a five-minute warning.&#160; You guys would appreciate it: I bumped into Simone Biles and I thought I&#8217;d say hello to her.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; I think you guys would have done the same.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>3:41 P.M.&nbsp;EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &nbsp;Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry it took me a couple more &#8212; <s>less</s> [more] than a two-minute warning; more like a five-minute warning.&nbsp; You guys would appreciate it: I bumped into Simone Biles and I thought I&#8217;d say hello to her.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I think you guys would have done the same.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can she come out here?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; She&#8217;s &#8212; I believe she&#8217;s on the White House North Lawn doing some interviews.&nbsp;<br><br>Anyway, good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; It’s good to see everyone.&nbsp; Happy Thursday.&nbsp; Okay, I &#8212; I do have a couple of things that I want to share with all of you.<br><br>So this week has been marked by honoring service to our nation through Presidential Medals of Honor and Freedom.&nbsp; And I think some of you may have been in the room on Tuesday and today.&nbsp; I don’t think there was a dry eye in the room.&nbsp; It was just such a beautiful, impactful, powerful moment.&nbsp;<br><br>But on Tuesday &#8212; just to recap just a little bit: On Tuesday, the President bestowed our nation’s highest military honor to four Vietnam veterans &#8212; recognition that was very, very long overdue.<br><br>And today, as we all just saw &#8212; some of you may have &#8212; may have been in the room &#8212; we saw 17 individuals spanning different backgrounds, careers, contributions to the United States receive the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the highest &#8212; the nation’s highest civilian honor.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden has long said that America can be defined by one word, and that is “possibilities.”&nbsp; These Americans demonstrate the power of possibilities and embody the soul of the nation: hard work, perseverance, and faith. <br><br>Today, the Department of Transportation announced nearly $1 billion in funding from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to 85 airports across the United States to modernize their terminals.<br><br>For example, in Orlando, we’re &#8212; we are investing $50 million to construct four new gates, increasing capacity and providing ADA-compliant facilities.&nbsp;<br><br>At Pittsburgh International Airport, we’re investing $20 million in building a new terminal, which will include improved security screening and baggage inspection systems.&nbsp;<br><br>And when all is said and done, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will pour $5 billion into similar terminal projects and $25 billion total to airport-related infrastructure across the country.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So investing in terminals is not something the federal government typically takes on; usually it’s local airports and owners and airlines who tend to do that.&nbsp; But thanks to the President’s Infrastructure Law, we are able to step up and make these kinds of investments that will benefit traveling Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>Finally &#8212; lastly, Senator Mitch McConnell is holding hostage the bipartisan package &#8212; a bipartisan package &#8212; the Bipartisan Innovation Act, which would make more in America and strengthen our competitive edge with China.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s doing all &#8212; all of this &#8212; he&#8217;s putting this in hostage, this bipartisan law, to protect the Big Pharma’s profit.&nbsp;<br><br>It is outrageous.&nbsp; And here’s the thing: We must do both and we can do both.&nbsp;<br><br>I remind &#8212; I remind you and all others that &#8212; when Leader Mitch McConnell himself agreed last fall that bipartisan negotiations shouldn’t be paused for other priorities, saying, and I quote, “Republicans have been negotiating in bipartisan good faith to meet the real infrastructure needs of our nation.&nbsp; The President cannot let congressional Democrats hold a bipartisan bill hostage over a separate and partisan process.”<br><br>I want to be clear here, though: Negotians [sic] have been &#8212; negotians [sic] have been productive, and in recent weeks, negotiators made progress in key issues of the Bipartisan Innovation Act.&nbsp;<br><br>So we are ready to finish up this process, negoti- &#8212; of negotiating and pass this bill.&nbsp; It&#8217;s now or never to do this.&nbsp; Other countries aren&#8217;t waiting.&nbsp; They are offering tax incentives for companies to invest in new manufacturing lines.&nbsp; Companies are currently making their investment decision.&nbsp;<br><br>And here&#8217;s the bottom line: We got to get this done.&nbsp; We can do both.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I say to Mitch McConnell: Let&#8217;s get this done.&nbsp;<br><br>All right, with that, Aamer, what&#8217;s your question &#8212; your first question?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; With Prime Minister Johnson&#8217;s resignation today &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t like to get into other country&#8217;s politics, but more substantively, what does this mean going forward?&nbsp; Big ally.&nbsp; You basically have a caretaker, lame-duck Prime Minister now.&nbsp; But this is a very difficult time in Europe, obviously.&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s efforts to keep Europe paddling or rowing the same way on Ukraine is top of mind now.&nbsp; Is there any concern that this becomes a little bit more difficult when you have a big partner like Prime Minister Johnson in the position he&#8217;s in?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: Our alliance with the United Kingdom continues to be strong.&nbsp; Our special relationship with the people in the country will continue to endure.&nbsp; None of that changes.&nbsp;<br><br>And I will mi- &#8212; I will remind you: A week ago &#8212; just a week ago today, when the President was in NATO &#8212; in Madrid for a historic NATO Summit, as you heard him speak at the press conference and you saw what happened, you saw a reassurance, a reaffirmation of NATO countries saying, again, what they are going to continue to do: continue to support Ukraine in their effort to defend their democracy against Putin’s brutal war.</p>



<p>And so that is not going to change.&nbsp; And not only that, you saw an &#8212; a potential expanding of NATO, with two additional countries, which is incredibly important &#8212; something that the President has worked very hard on these last several months, who has also led on this effort.</p>



<p>You saw other alliances make a commitment to increase their security assistance.&nbsp; And so, all of that &#8212; what you’re seeing currently today, because of the leadership of this President, is a more &#8212; a more unified NATO.&nbsp; And I don’t think that changes at &#8212; at all.</p>



<p>And you saw him at the G7, in Germany, where you saw him with the &#8212; you know, the G7 leaders &#8212; the same.&nbsp; You saw a &#8212; a committed &#8212; a committed alliance amongst &#8212; amongst friends, amongst other countries on everything that they’re going to work on together to push American’s intr- &#8212; America’s interest, and also what &#8212; the interest of other countries as we look at the global challenges ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Just one more on &#8212; now that Brittney Griner has pleaded guilty, what is the next steps that the administration is contemplating?&nbsp; Does the President support Bill Richardson going over to Moscow to try to fashion her release?</p>



<p>And would the &#8212; would the administration entertain a trade of Russian detainees in American custody for Mrs. Griner, particularly the arms dealer, Viktor Bout?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, just to be clear &#8212; so I&#8217;ve said this before, but I want to state it again: We believe that the Russian Federation is holding &#8212; is wrongfully detai- &#8212; has wrongfully detained Brittney Griner.&nbsp; And she is in intolerable circumstances right now.&nbsp; And we are going to do everything that we can.</p>



<p>The President has this top of mind to make sure that we get Brittney home safely and also Paul Whelan.&nbsp; That is an important &#8212; important priority of the President.</p>



<p>And he &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve been clear from day one: When it comes to U.S. nationals who are being held abroad, who are being held wrongfully &#8212; detained wrongfully, who are being held hostage, we are going to do everything that we can, use every means that we have to bring them home.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to lay out exactly the steps that we&#8217;re going to take, as you can imagine why.&nbsp; We want to make sure that we do this safely.</p>



<p>As you know, the President wrote a letter to Brittney Griner.&nbsp; He spoke to her wife yesterday.&nbsp; And so, Secretary Blinken &#8212; just on the letter, because I know people were asking me; I think people saw this already &#8212; the letter was delivered to her.&nbsp; He tweeted: U.S. Embassy in Moscow “officials again attended Brittney Griner’s trial today and delivered to her a letter from President Biden.&nbsp; We will not relent until Brittney, Paul Whelan, and all &#8212; and all other wrongfully detained Americans are reunited with their loved ones.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that is the focus of the Secretary of State, that&#8217;s the focus of the pres- &#8212; national &#8212; national security team, and his focus as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, a follow on that, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I didn’t &#8212; oh, it was April?&nbsp; I’ll come back to you, April.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On that note, Paul Whelan&#8217;s family says that they have not heard directly from President Biden.&nbsp; Does the President have plans to call the Whelan family as well?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have a call right now to announce or to preview for you today.</p>



<p>Look, we can&#8217;t even begin to imagine what his family is going through.&nbsp; I know these are devastating times for them, and they have been &#8212; they have been working very hard to get their &#8212; their brother home.&nbsp; This is &#8212; I&#8217;m talking about Elizabeth Whelan and her brother &#8212; and his brother, David Whelan.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll list out a couple of things that we have done as far as communicating with the family, which I think is very important to share.</p>



<p>So, yesterday, White House staff joined the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs on a call with Elizabeth Whelan.&nbsp; And Secretary Blinken and National Security Advisor Sullivan have also called her to offer support and reaffirm the President&#8217;s commitment to bringing Paul home.</p>



<p>The SPEHA office has a biweekly phone call with &#8212; with Elizabeth Whelan to provide updates and pass information on pro- &#8212; on progress in securing Paul&#8217;s release and to secure he is well supported while he remains in prison.</p>



<p>Department of State representatives in D.C. and at Embassy Moscow have regular phone calls with Paul Whelan.&nbsp; Consular officials last visited him on June 17th, so just a few weeks ago, and they hold regular calls with the Whelan family on the case to address any concerns that the family or Paul have raised regarding his treatment.</p>



<p>Again, this is some &#8212; this is a situation &#8212; these cases &#8212; the President is getting regularly updated.&nbsp; This is at top of mind.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a call to preview for you, but we have been in regular contact with his family.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just quickly: Griner’s guilty plea &#8212; what kind of impact does this have on the negotiations to try to bring her home?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It will have no impact on &#8212; on any of the negotiations.&nbsp; The President, the national security team, the State Department, the Special Envoy that I just spoke about &#8212; we&#8217;re going to do everything that we can to bring home Brittney Griner safely and to also make sure that we bring Paul Whelan back home as well.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Can you share any more about what the President conveyed in his letter to Brittney Griner?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the President, as you know, was deeply moved, as you can imagine &#8212; I know some of you read her letter as well &#8212; was deeply moved by &#8212; by her handwritten note.&nbsp; He wanted her to know and to reassure her that we are doing &#8212; that he is doing everything that he can to bring her home.</p>



<p>You know, in her letter, she talked about what July 4th meant &#8212; means for her this year and what freedom means for her this year, and that is touching.</p>



<p>And so, again, we are going to do &#8212; he is going to do everything that he can to make sure she gets home safely.&nbsp; This is top of mind.&nbsp;<br><br>And he had a &#8212; you know, a very &#8212; I would say, a very deep &#8212; and he sees it as an important conversation with &#8212; with her wife, as well, yesterday.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just to follow up on some of the reaction from Paul Whelan&#8217;s family.&nbsp; Some of the members of his family are asking sort of what does it take for their family to get a call with the President.&nbsp; You saw Trevor Reed’s family protest outside of the White House.&nbsp; They had a meeting with the President.&nbsp; We saw the family of Brittney Griner criticize the Biden administration, saying that they may not be doing enough when it comes to her case, and then get a phone call with the President.&nbsp; How can this administration assure the Whelan family that their pleas are being heard and taken seriously?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean &#8212; so, look, I just laid out all of the things, all of the &#8212; kind of all of the conversations that we have been having for &#8212; with the Whelan family.<br><br>Look, again, we cannot &#8212; I cannot imagine what they&#8217;re going through right now.&nbsp; We understand this is a very tough moment in time, and it has been, especially for him, for these past several years.<br><br>But we want to assure them &#8212; the Whelans and the Griner family and all other U.S. nationals’ families who are &#8212; U.S. nationals who are being detained, wrongfully detained, or held hostage abroad &#8212; that this President is doing everything that he can to make sure that they come home safely.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to use any &#8212; every means that we have.&nbsp; Clearly, we cannot negotiate in public.&nbsp; That is not something that we&#8217;re going to do.&nbsp; But we are committed to making sure they all get home safely.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just a quick follow-up on Boris Johnson.&nbsp; Has the President had a chance to speak to him since he announced his decision?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a call to read out for you.&nbsp; As I mentioned just moments ago, he saw Boris Johnson in Madrid, at NATO, most recently and also at the G7 in Germany.&nbsp; And I think you guys were all there.&nbsp; They had a pretty friendly and close interaction.&nbsp; And they have, you know, reaffirmed their commitment to, you know, agenda that matters to both &#8212; to both the United Kingdom and to the United States.&nbsp; And we believe our alliance with the United Kingdom will continue to be strong.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he plan to speak to him, Karine?&nbsp; Before he leaves &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick question on Roe.&nbsp; We did see the President meet a bunch of governors earlier this week.&nbsp; And if you can talk a little bit about sort of the events, including meetings or speeches, that the President is planning, you know, to give or attend or be a part of in the coming days that involve him talking about reproductive rights.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say this: The President is not done speaking on how he&#8217;s going to continue to fight for women&#8217;s freedoms and women&#8217;s rights, especially after this extreme decision that we saw come down on Roe by the Supreme Court.&nbsp; He is committed to this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of this President.&nbsp;<br><br>I could assure you, you will hear more from him.&nbsp; I’m just not going to give a timeline from here.<br><br>But look, here&#8217;s the thing: The President has been very clear he&#8217;s going to do everything that he can, that he has the legal authority to do from here in the &#8212; from the executive side.&nbsp; But we believe and he believes that the way that Roe goes into law or gets codi- &#8212; codified is if Congress acts.&nbsp; Right? We have to make sure that we get Congress to act.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to call on that to make sure that that happens.<br><br>And, you know, this is &#8212; this is such a critical time, as we see Republicans trying to take away those rights, as we see Republicans talking about a national ban.&nbsp; This is &#8212; this is what&#8217;s happening on the other side.&nbsp; And so, we have to continue to use our political capital, if you will, to fight as hard as we can and to make sure we do the work that we need to have pro-choice congressional members in Congress.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So on that point, Karine, we understand the White House was working on an executive order.&nbsp; Is that still happening?&nbsp; Is the White House continuing to work on an executive order, or has the White House dropped that plan?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;ll say this: The President is going to do everything in his legal authority to continue to fight for freedom and for &#8212; for rights &#8212; women&#8217;s rights, in particular, as we&#8217;re speaking about Roe.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of him.&nbsp; But I assure you, you will hear from him in a short order.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we could expect an executive order?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; In a short order.&nbsp; He will &#8212; he will speak to this himself.&nbsp; I’m not going to get ahead of the President.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; To what extent has Brittney Griner’s public profile and kind of the posture and push around her shifted the administration’s strategy as it pertains to her case specifically?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I will say this, Phil: We&#8217;ve been working on this for months.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been working with her and &#8212; and having conversations with her family and the people who love her for some time.&nbsp;<br><br>Secretary Blinken &#8212; I have mentioned his regular contact with the family and friends.&nbsp; National Security Advisor Sullivan most recently spoke to &#8212; to the family twice in the past, I would say, 10 days.&nbsp; This has been top of mind for the national security team, for the State Department.<br><br>And again, not just &#8212; not just Brittney Griner &#8212; which is top of mind for him; clearly, he just wrote her a letter and spoke to <s>his</s> [her] wife yesterday &#8212; but for all U.S. nationals that are being held abroad, detained &#8212; wrongfully detained and held hostage.&nbsp;<br><br>This is something that this administration has been working on since last year to make sure that we do everything that we can to bring &#8212; to bring folks home.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On a different topic.&nbsp; Oil prices have dropped pretty significantly.&nbsp; At the pump, they’ve started to fall as well.&nbsp; Do you believe that the drop is durable?&nbsp; Do you believe that this is sustainable, that we have turned a corner?&nbsp; Or should Americans expect that it might pop back up again?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, what we believe is the lower &#8212; the lower gas prices that we&#8217;re seeing, the prices starting to come down is a good thing.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; It&#8217;s a cooldown, if you will.<br><br>But we believe that more work still remains and that we need to do more work.&nbsp; The President believes that.&nbsp; Part of that is retailers need to pass on their lower cost to consumers.&nbsp; Wholesale gas prices are down by $1 per gallon.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard me talk about this over the past month. But retail gas prices have only come down by about 20 cents over the same period.&nbsp; So, more work needs to be done.<br><br>You know, you &#8212; I&#8217;ve heard this phrase, “Don&#8217;t &#8212; we can&#8217;t sit on our laurels,” if you will.&nbsp; We got to continue to do the work.&nbsp;<br><br>And one of the things that the President will continue to call on is this gas holiday tax &#8212; this 90-day suspension of &#8212; on the federal gas tax, which we think is an easy thing to do.&nbsp; There are pieces of legislation right now in the House, in Congress, that can be easily picked up and passed.&nbsp;<br><br>And so that&#8217;s what the President is calling &#8212; calling for Congress to do.&nbsp; We think it will have an important effect on American families and give them that little bit of breathing room that you hear the President talk about.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more quick one.&nbsp; Does the President &#8212; there seems to be a view on Capitol Hill that August is the deadline for the reconciliation package.&nbsp; Does the President view the month of July as the be-all, end-all as it pertains to that?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, I&#8217;m not going to go into negotiations or negotiate from public, as you hear us say often.&nbsp; What I will say is that independent economists have shown that this would fight inflation as we&#8217;re talking about high gas prices, as we&#8217;re talking about inflation for the long haul, and protect Americans’ finances in the short term.<br><br>So, we think this is something that is going to help Americans, American families, and we&#8217;re going to continue to have the negotiations.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to have the conversations to make sure we deliver for the American public.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So no deadline from here?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here.&nbsp; I’m not going to give a deadline from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Mike.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I could ask about two administration officials.&nbsp; First of all, given the revelations that my colleagues wrote about regarding the actions of the IRS over the last several years, does the President retain the confidence &#8212; does the &#8212; does the IRS Commissioner have the President&#8217;s confidence?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: We don&#8217;t comment on enforcement actions taken by the IRS.&nbsp; So just the first thing &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; I &#8212; no, I know.&nbsp; I’m &#8212; I just want to &#8212; since you gave me the opportunity, Michael, I want to take it.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So any &#8212; any questions on that I would refer &#8212; refer you to the IRS.&nbsp; That&#8217;s for anyone who has any questions on that.<br><br>As you know, the IRS Commissioner &#8212; his term is up in November.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any updates on that.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to anything more besides, you know, we would refer you to the IRS on that specific thing.&nbsp;<br><br>And he is going to be up in November.&nbsp; So I will leave it there.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; but, between now and November, the President still is confident that he&#8217;s able to fairly and, you know, without bias, you know, do the things that a &#8212; that the IRS does objectively?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, again, I&#8217;m going to say that he is up in November.&nbsp; He is a commissioner.&nbsp; He does &#8212; he is the Commissioner of the IRS, part of the administration.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to leave it at that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then on the Director of the Secret Service who just announced resignation today &#8212; obviously, the Secret Service has been in the news of late, given the &#8212; some of the testimony in front of the January 6th Committee as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Do &#8212; is there any relationship between the Director’s departure now and the timing of some of those revelations from the committee?&nbsp; Did the White House know about his intention to retire before &#8212; before the &#8212; that testimony last week, I guess?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, Michael, I would say that there&#8217;s no relations at all.&nbsp; This has been in talks for several months &#8212; I &#8212; for his &#8212; his retirement &#8212; I believe, since April &#8212; so before the January 6th hearing.&nbsp;<br><br>And for &#8212; as I &#8212; as I know, he is headed to the private sector.&nbsp; So it is not connected at all.&nbsp; This has been in talks for some time now &#8212; his &#8212; his retirement.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Actually, I&#8217;m going to go &#8212; I know, April, I said I was going to come to you on, I think, Brittney Griner.&nbsp; Was that your &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and on something else.&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Brittney Griner: I talked to Cherelle Griner last night.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And now this morning&#8217;s decision.&nbsp; And we understand that, according to sources close the case, it was Brittney’s decision and it was an informed decision that was discussed over several weeks to make this decision to plead guilty.&nbsp; Was the White House ever in any understanding that this was going to be the case this morning?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on &#8212; I cannot speak about her case in public.&nbsp; I cannot speak about the process of her decision.&nbsp; That is something that she should speak to, which sounds like she has spoken to you about that.&nbsp;<br><br>But we from &#8212; from &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, (inaudible) with the case.&nbsp; But she talked about &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, got it.&nbsp; Un- &#8212; understood.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; not wanting to watch this morning.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Understood.&nbsp; But we cannot do that from here.&nbsp; It is &#8212; it is a personal matter.&nbsp; It is a &#8212; it is a legal matter that we cannot speak to from &#8212; from here, or the podium.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say that &#8212; I think I was just asked about if this verdict &#8212; her verdict will change anything that we&#8217;re doing: It will not.&nbsp;<br><br>We will continue to make this a top priority, in making sure that we bring her home safely.&nbsp; That is a commitment that we have made to her, to her family, and also to other U.S. nationals as we&#8217;re trying to bring them back home.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the hope that this guilty plea will be viewed favorably by the Russians to help her come home sooner or her sentencing be less?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, April, I appreciate the question.&nbsp; I cannot &#8212; that was a legal advice, clearly, that Brittney received from her &#8212; from her lawyers.&nbsp; I cannot speak to why the decision was made.&nbsp; I cannot speak to the minds of the Russian Federation.&nbsp;<br><br>I &#8212; that is not for me to do.&nbsp; What I can say is what we&#8217;re going to do here &#8212; here.&nbsp; And what the President wants to do is making sure that we bring home these U.S. nationals who are wrongfully being held abroad and also held hostage.&nbsp; It is important that we get them home safely.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mrs. Griner says she wants to come for a face to face that the President offered.&nbsp; Any dates yet?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And two other questions on two other subjects really fast.&nbsp; As you talked about and as we&#8217;re still reeling and trying to figure out still what happens after Roe v. Wade in the states, et cetera &#8212; after the overturn of Roe v. Wade: In October, a case is supposed to be before the Supreme Court on affirmative action when it comes to education admittance &#8212; admittance on race.&nbsp; And there is a thought that it could be overturned with the way this Court has been overturning longstanding action cases.</p>



<p>What is the White House&#8217;s thought on this?&nbsp; And is there a plan?&nbsp; Are you preparing for this, as many law organizations are preparing amicus briefs, friend of court briefs in favor of keeping these admittance &#8212; racial admittance procedures?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, April, the President has been very clear about these extreme decisions that the Supreme Court has been making &#8212; not just on Roe, but EPA and other decisions that have come down most recently.&nbsp; This is another one that you&#8217;re talking about, in October.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, the President has been also clear &#8212; is that we have to take action.&nbsp; We &#8212; that, you know, Americans have to make sure that they take their voices to the ballot box.&nbsp; That is the way that we are going to be able to &#8212; to fight back in a way that&#8217;s effective, in a way that&#8217;s going to make a difference.<br><br>We have Republicans who are doing extremes.&nbsp; The President calls them “Ultra-MAGA.”&nbsp; They are a part of the Ultra-MAGA wing who are trying to take away the rights of the American people.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what they&#8217;re trying to do.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, we have to do everything that we can.&nbsp; American public has to do everything that they can to make sure that their voices are heard at the ballot box.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the President is going to continue to speak to, and that&#8217;s what the President is asking for people to do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last question, on the Secret Service Director.&nbsp; Is equity and inclusion still a part of the President&#8217;s hiring practices when he looks at that spot?&nbsp; Because you have never had a Black man or someone of another color, I guess, be the head of that organization.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the &#8212; of the process.&nbsp; But as you know, this is a President that prides on making sure that we have equity, that we have inclusion.&nbsp; You see that up and down his administration.&nbsp; He wants to make sure that we have an administration that looks like America.&nbsp; And so that is a priority for him.&nbsp;<br><br>I cannot speak to that particular vacancy &#8212; potential vacancy.&nbsp; That is something that &#8212; a decision has not been made, and so I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Tam.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you.&nbsp; Back when the President did sort of the small signing ceremony for the gun legislation, he said that he was going to do a bigger ceremony later.&nbsp; Is that still in the books?&nbsp; And can you give any sort of a preview of his message?&nbsp; A lot has happened since he signed that bill, and outside advocates are pushing him to go even further.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And he wants to go further.&nbsp; I mean, he has said that.&nbsp; He has been very clear on saying that as much as he welcomed the bipartisan gun reform legislation that he signed into law right before he left for Europe, he had said we need to do more.&nbsp; He has been very clear on that.&nbsp;<br><br>You got to remember, this is a President that led on the effort of making sure &#8212; on banning assault weapons back in 1994, which sunset 10 years later.&nbsp; That &#8212; it was a priority for him then, and it continues to be a priority for him now.<br><br>If you think about what we have seen over the last several weeks &#8212; you think about Buffalo, you think about Uvalde, you think about Highland Park &#8212; you think about the same story that they have over and over again, which is a weapon of war being unleashed on our &#8212; in our communities.&nbsp;<br><br>And how &#8212; and it&#8217;s not just those communities.&nbsp; You think about Parkland, you think about Orlando, Las Vegas, Sandy Hook.&nbsp; It&#8217;s assault rifles.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, you &#8212; it has &#8212; it &#8212; and you think about what it&#8217;s done to families and communities.&nbsp; These are assault rifles that, you know &#8212; that bodies are too mutilated for families to even recognize, that they have to do a DNA test.<br><br>That should not be happening in our streets.&nbsp; It should not be happening in our streets.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the President believes that we need to ban assault weapons.&nbsp; This is something that he has talked about, again, for years.&nbsp; It is something that he wants to see happen.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to continue to call on.&nbsp;<br><br>On your first question on if we&#8217;re going to have an event: Yes, we will have an event.&nbsp; You will hear from us soon on when that will be.&nbsp; But, yes, he is &#8212; that is going to happen at some point.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And yesterday, he &#8212; in his remarks in Ohio, it sounded like a midterm message.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, just a little bit.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It was fun.&nbsp; It was fun.&nbsp; It was great.&nbsp; It was great to see.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are we going to see more of that?&nbsp; What is your sense of how much travel will be ramping up for the President, if at all?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; yeah, we don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this &#8212; at this time.&nbsp;<br><br>But, look, you know, this is something that the President &#8212; you&#8217;ve heard him say this himself: He wants to get out there.&nbsp; He &#8212; you know, you see him out there with &#8212; with the American people, and it is a lively time.&nbsp; It is a &#8212; it is definitely an exciting time to see him, and they get excited.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s able to push his message or talk about his message, his platform directly to the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>And if you think about &#8212; yesterday, it was about pensions; it was about union pensions.&nbsp; It’s about how we&#8217;re &#8212; what &#8212; the work that the American Rescue Plan has done to make sure that we protect those pensions.&nbsp; And so that is such an important message for the American people to hear.&nbsp; And not just in Ohio, in many other country &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, and many other states across the country is going to be affected by the American Rescue Plan as well when it relates to union pensions and other items as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Since you started the briefing talking about McConnell holding the Bipartisan Infrastructure &#8212; sorry &#8212; Innovation Act hostage, has the President reached out directly to any Senate Republicans to convince them and make the case for why they should support this bill?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; we don&#8217;t have any calls to read out.&nbsp; As you know, his Office of Leg Affairs is in constant communication, and not just his Office of Leg Affairs; we have other departments, offices in the White House that are constantly talking to congressional leaders and staff on issues that &#8212; on these types of legislations that we believe are important to the American public.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to read out.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I figured you would say that, but what is the path forward if you know that there is Republicans that support this bill but you need to get 10 of them to go ahead with you over the objections of McConnell?&nbsp; Like, what are you doing?&nbsp; And are you confident that there are actually 10 who would do that?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, we have seen and I said at top: We have seen progress.&nbsp; We wanted to make that clear, even though you heard me call out Mitch McConnell.&nbsp; We have seen some progress.&nbsp; What I was calling out is the hypocrisy that we have seen from Leader &#8212; from Leader McConnell on this.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, you know, the President and bipartisan members of Congress, you know, they &#8212; who share &#8212; who share the same goal, and we understand that.&nbsp; It is to reach a final agreement that meets our economic and national security objectives.&nbsp; And we want to do this by this summer.&nbsp; We feel confident in that.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to work to make that happen.&nbsp;<br><br>We know companies are making decisions now on where to invest this year.&nbsp; So the time is now to act.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I said if it doesn&#8217;t happen now, it won&#8217;t.&nbsp; So we are going to do everything we can to make sure that we make this happen.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one follow-up to Michael&#8217;s question on the IRS commissioner.&nbsp; You noted that his term is up in November.&nbsp; Are you insinuating that you won&#8217;t renominate him?&nbsp; And if so, why not fire him now?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; That is a decision for the President to make, and I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of that decision.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Peter.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Why do you think it is the 88 percent of people in this country polled by Monmouth think the country is on the wrong track?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: The President understands what the American people are going through.&nbsp; He understands that gas prices are high because of Putin’s tax hike, because of the war that Putin &#8212; the brutal war that Putin has taken on in Ukraine, and their brave fight to fight for their democracy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re seeing here.&nbsp; And also the food insecurity &#8212; the food cost has skyrocketed.&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s why the President has done everything that he can to blunt those high prices.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he&#8217;s tapped into the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; We saw a historic amount of barrels coming out a day &#8212; 1 million a day.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why he is doing the bio- &#8212; the home- &#8212; homegrown biofuels &#8212; the ethanol 15 &#8212; making that available this summer, which is not normally available this summer, so that we can try and bring down those costs.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why he&#8217;s going to continue to work to make sure we lower those costs.&nbsp;<br><br>Look &#8212; but, again, we understand what the American people are feeling.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing everything that we can.&nbsp; We have a plan.&nbsp; Here&#8217;s the thing: We have a plan.&nbsp; Republicans do not have a plan.&nbsp; What they want to do is take away rights from the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But do you think it&#8217;s possible that your plan just is not popular with the American people right now?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s that our plan is not popular with the American people.&nbsp; We know that the American people are feeling the high costs.&nbsp; We understand what they are feeling.&nbsp; Because &#8212; because when you look at inflation; when we look at where we are economically &#8212; and we are in a strong &#8212; we are stronger economically than we have been in history; when you look at the unemployment numbers of 3.6 percent; when you look at the jobs numbers &#8212; more than 8.7 million of new jobs created &#8212; that is important.&nbsp;<br><br>But we understand that gas prices are high, and we understand that food costs are high.&nbsp; And that is because of a once &#8212; once-in-a-generation pandemic and also Putin&#8217;s war.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s just the facts.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So if you think that the &#8212; your plan is popular with the American people, is it just that the plans are not being communicated properly, and is that why the Communications Director is leaving?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, that&#8217;s where you were going with this question.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Oh, that&#8217;s very slick there of you, Peter.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, why is she really leaving?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean &#8212; well, she said why she is leaving.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, let me just say something.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, but &#8212; is it &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Wait.&nbsp; Wait.&nbsp; No, no, no, no.&nbsp; You&#8217;re asking me &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is it a coincidence that at a time that a historic number of people think the country is on the wrong track, somebody who has been a part of Biden world for as long as just about anybody here says that she is leaving?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, first, let me just say I explained that we understand what the American public is feeling.&nbsp; The President is doing everything in his power to lower costs, to blunt gas prices, as he has been doing.&nbsp;<br><br>And we have &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Then why make a change?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; we have done that.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I just want to speak about Kate for a second because I think this is really important.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve known Kate since 2007.&nbsp; She is a friend and she is a colleague.&nbsp; She is exceptionally talented, and she will be greatly missed.<br><br>Her smart skills and hard work helped get the President elected and has helped us accomplish so much since we&#8217;ve been here.&nbsp;<br><br>And like I said, on a personal note, she&#8217;s a good friend and a colleague, and we&#8217;re going to miss her.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, you&#8217;re asking me &#8212; basically, you&#8217;re asking me her leaving and what does that mean &#8212; right? &#8212; to the administration?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I don&#8217;t think her leaving will have&nbsp;&nbsp; effect on what we&#8217;re trying to do.&nbsp; Because, look, she leaves behind a talented team and communications department, and the President will name a new communications director.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing new here.&nbsp; These things happen.&nbsp;<br><br>And I do want to call out a data by Brookings showing that turnover in this administration is below the historical average, going back to Reagan.&nbsp;<br><br>So, what we&#8217;re seeing here is not unusual.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re seeing here is &#8212; is normal.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re going to continue to do is we&#8217;re going to communicate with the American people in a truthful way, and we&#8217;re going to do that every day.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just a different topic.&nbsp; The largest labor union in the country, the National Education Association, had been proposing a resolution for future contracts to replace the word “mother” with “birthing parent.”&nbsp; What does the President think about proposals like that one?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re not the NEA.&nbsp; And I would refer you to their team about that particular sp- &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Vice President just spoke at that conference, though.&nbsp; The First Lady is a teacher.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President says he&#8217;s the most pro-labor &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; She&#8217;s a member of &#8212; she’s &#8212; she’s &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; President ever.&nbsp; Does he &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; support proposals like that one?&nbsp; Does he think that is a &#8212; an important priority for &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And the First Lady is a proud member of the NEA.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to speak about a &#8212; an organization&#8217;s policy or change of policy.&nbsp; I am not their spokesperson.&nbsp; That’s not something that I&#8217;m going to do.&nbsp;<br><br>Yes, the Vice President was there on Tuesday.&nbsp; She spoke at NEA.&nbsp; And when they did &#8212; when they did regular order &#8212; when they did their regular business, she left.&nbsp; So she was also not part of that discussion.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, this is a policy change.&nbsp; That is not something that I can speak to.&nbsp; I refer you to NEA.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So I have a question on the federal district judge appointment in Kentucky.&nbsp; So, earlier today, Governor Andy Beshear said that it&#8217;s been plenty of time for the administration to tell his office whether, you know, the White House is rescinding the appointment of Chad Meredith.&nbsp; I guess, what&#8217;s your reaction to that?&nbsp; And why haven&#8217;t you rescinded that appointment yet?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You &#8212; I believe your colleague asked me this question last week, or &#8212; gosh, not even last week; a couple days ago.&nbsp; Every &#8212; every day feels like long days.&nbsp;<br><br>But look &#8212; and I said this on Tuesday, and I&#8217;ll said this &#8212; I&#8217;ll say this to you, which is, like, we do not comment on vacancies.&nbsp; This is a vacancy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not something that we&#8217;re going to comment on.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t comment on executive branch or judicial vacancy.&nbsp;<br><br>We have not made a nomination yet.&nbsp; And so, one of the things that we are very proud of, which you hear us talk about, is like &#8212; is that we have more federal judges &#8212; we have done more federal judges during this administration than any of the last three presidency.<br><br>It includes making sure that we do history-making first to help our judiciary represent the diversity of America, and we&#8217;re going to continue to do that.<br><br>I’m &#8212; I just &#8212; is not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to speak to an open vacancy.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; The Veterans Affairs currently doesn&#8217;t offer any abortion services in any exceptions.&nbsp; But VA Secretary McDonough has told Congress &#8212; he told them in April that the VA has statutory authority to provide abortion services, that the law permits it.&nbsp; So does the President agree with the VA Secretary that the department can take this action?<br><br>MR. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the administration and the VA are committed to providing healthcare to veterans, and the VA continues to offer reproductive healthcare services to their veterans as well.<br><br>As you note, current regulation doesn&#8217;t allow for the VA to provide abortions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to review, we&#8217;re going to continue to explore every possible option to protect women&#8217;s rights and access to reproductive health.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, we&#8217;re going to continue to review.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given that &#8212; that it’s based on regulation, though, I mean, is the President considering at all any kind of executive action to direct the VA, given that its regulation (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have anything specifically on the VA.&nbsp; We have talked about the President reviewing executive actio- &#8212; actions.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of what those actions are going to be.<br><br>But like I said, you know, we&#8217;re going to continue to review and look at our options here.&nbsp; And, you know, the President is going to continue &#8212; he did use his executive authority when the decision came down, within hours of the decision that came down &#8212; the Roe being striked down.&nbsp;<br><br>And so those authorities we believed were &#8212; were impactful for the moment, when you’re talking about providing safe medication, FDA-approved medication so women can make decisions on their healthcare &#8212; medication, which is what majority of women use when they are looking to make that decision on an abortion, which is a very personal decision.&nbsp; And also, women who have to travel as well, making sure that DOJ protect their rights.&nbsp;<br><br>And we think that those are incredibly impactful, incredibly important.&nbsp; And like I said, the President is going to continue to look at all his options.<br><br>Let me come back here, okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; (Inaudible)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, you’ve mentioned a few times in this briefing the importance of electing candidates that are supportive of access to abortion.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if the President feels that that is the Democrats’ best path forward at this point in getting some sort of legislation passed that would legalize abortion access &#8212; that it really is up to what happens this November and nothing can really get done before then.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak to any political election process and what strategy we&#8217;re taking.&nbsp; What I can say is the President has been very clear he is going to do everything that he can to protect freedoms and rights for women and the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>As we know, the Supreme Court, as we saw what Clarence Thomas wrote, they&#8217;re going to go further.&nbsp; And that is something we should really listen to and pay close attention to.&nbsp; And it is going to happen.&nbsp; This is something that the President has said.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, what I would say is: He&#8217;s been very clear.&nbsp; We need &#8212; we need Congress to act.&nbsp; We need to codify Roe, make that the law of the land.&nbsp; That is the best way &#8212; the best way we&#8217;re going to protect rights and freedoms.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; and if it doesn&#8217;t happen in Congress, he has &#8212; he has asked the American public to take their voices to the ballot box to make sure to do what you just asked me &#8212; to make sure that we have pro-choice members in Congress.<br><br>All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll see you tomorrow.</p>



<p>4:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden and First Lady Jill&#160;Biden on the Retirement of United&#160;States Secret Service Director Jim&#160;Murray</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/07/statement-from-president-joe-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-on-the-retirement-of-united-states-secret-service-director-jim-murray/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 19:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Director Jim Murray has led a long and distinguished career in federal and military service for three decades, including the last three years as Director of the United States Secret Service. Jim embodies the meaning of service over self, and protected the families of U.S. Presidents like they were part of his own. We are incredibly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Director Jim Murray has led a long and distinguished career in federal and military service for three decades, including the last three years as Director of the United States Secret Service. Jim embodies the meaning of service over self, and protected the families of U.S. Presidents like they were part of his own. We are incredibly grateful for his service to our country and our family.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
